<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  YouTubes</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-09T13:10:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/youtube/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/youtube" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:10:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:10:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google updates YouTube ad targeting terms to remove hate speech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qB9Un6kPoAhiCH1f6exVnFZymcY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102249/acastro_180806_1777_youtube_cancel_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fipdk5"&gt;Google says it has blocked several terms associated with hate speech from being used as ad keywords on YouTube videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxd96b"&gt;The move follows a &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2021/04/09/google-blocks-advertisers-from-targeting-black-lives-matter-youtube-videos"&gt;report by &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which found that advertisers could search for terms like “white lives matter” and “white power” when deciding where to place ads on YouTube: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6y5Psj"&gt;Google offered advertisers hundreds of millions of choices for YouTube videos and channels related to White supremacist and other hate terms when we began our investigation, including “all lives matter”—a phrase frequently used as a dismissive rejoinder to Black Lives Matter—and “White lives matter”—which the Southern Poverty Law Center &lt;a href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/white-lives-matter"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; as both a neo-Nazi group and “a racist response to the civil rights movement Black Lives Matter.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Hl5ici"&gt;At the same time, &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; found, Google was blocking advertisers from using terms such as “Black Lives Matter” to find videos and channels to run ads against. After &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; reached out to YouTube parent company Google for comment, it says the company actually &lt;a href="https://github.com/the-markup/investigation-youtube-ad-placements"&gt;blocked more racial and social justice terms&lt;/a&gt;, including “Black excellence” and “civil rights.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6S0Nw0"&gt;“We take the issue of hate and harassment very seriously and condemn it in the strongest terms possible,” a Google spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Though no ads ever ran against this content on YouTube, because our multi-layered enforcement strategy worked during this investigation, we fully acknowledge that the terms identified are offensive and harmful and should not have been searchable. Our teams have addressed the issue and blocked terms that violate our enforcement policies. We will continue to be vigilant in this regard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HFEFOQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We fully acknowledge that the terms identified are offensive and harmful and should not have been searchable”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rNAm0T"&gt;YouTube says it has several layers of protection in place to prevent offensive or harmful ads from running on its platform, and that it regularly removes videos containing hate speech. Last year, the company says it blocked or removed more than 867 million ads for trying to evade its detection systems and more than 3 billion bad ads in total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p2Zp4h"&gt;Google says it does not publicly disclose how it develops its enforcement tools, so that so-called bad actors can’t circumvent its rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnONCO"&gt;YouTube has battled hate speech on its platform for several years, with mixed results. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/5/18652576/youtube-supremacist-content-ban-borderline-extremist-terms-of-service"&gt;2019, it banned white supremacist content&lt;/a&gt;, and the company said it would restrict channels from monetizing videos that “repeatedly brush up against our hate speech policies,” preventing them from running ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vwVWJ2"&gt;In a blog post last June, &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/inside-youtube/susan-wojcicki-my-mid-year-update-youtube-community"&gt;YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki said&lt;/a&gt; the company’s hate speech policy “specifically bans videos alleging that a group is superior based on qualities like race, gender, religion, or sexual orientation in order to justify discrimination, segregation or exclusion.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375702/google-updates-youtube-ad-targeting-hate-speech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375702/google-updates-youtube-ad-targeting-hate-speech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-08T17:25:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-08T17:25:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTuber records himself trespassing at SpaceX’s Starship facilities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A man standing in front of a large silver rocket" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b8n23QGGLXjhirjnZoKVdUiE9f0=/143x0:2624x1654/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69098076/Screen_Shot_2021_04_08_at_3.26.23_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A still from the video originally uploaded to the YouTube channel Loco VlogS.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Loco VlogS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bdr6ac"&gt;A YouTuber recorded himself entering SpaceX’s Starship rocket facilities in south Texas last month, freely sauntering on site. No security stopped him from wandering around the underside of SN11, the 16-story-tall rocket prototype that would launch and explode just a few days later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tV3xxY"&gt;The video was posted to a small YouTube channel called Loco VlogS, which is run by “Caesar.” Caesar did not respond to multiple emails and DMs asking for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXLcrC"&gt;For space enthusiasts, SpaceX’s sprawling rocket campus in Texas just a few miles north of the Rio Grande is a tantalizing museum of rocketry just laying out in the open, housing millions of dollars worth of tech — some of which SpaceX has pitched to the Air Force and NASA. It doesn’t have the towering walls or advanced security one might expect a company to have for safeguarding sensitive (and potentially dangerous) rocket hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cd3Uwy"&gt;Development of Starship, the centerpiece of Elon Musk’s goal to ferry humans and cargo to the Moon and Mars, is aided in part by a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/30/21242837/nasa-spacex-blue-origin-dynetics-human-lunar-landers"&gt;$135 million NASA contract&lt;/a&gt; to help mature its design under the agency’s Human Lunar Landing system program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imwjhq"&gt;“NASA takes safety and security very seriously,” said Monica Witt, spokeswoman for the agency. “The Human Landing System contracts include requirements for the contractors to appropriately safeguard information, software, and hardware. SpaceX notified NASA that they investigated this incident.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zD4X3E"&gt;Caesar entered the rocket site and seemingly moved around SpaceX hardware and equipment with ease, recording closeups of Starship SN11’s Raptor engines. The video garnered 5 likes and at least 100 dislikes, as well as a barrage of comments from pissed-off SpaceX fans, before he deleted it, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u-QKLgcN0ig"&gt;different YouTube account&lt;/a&gt; that archived the video. In a classic YouTube move, Caesar posted an apology video a few days later on April 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yU2nP9"&gt;“Yes it was wrong, yes it was illegal,” he said &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZKOldPkX9MY"&gt;in the apology video&lt;/a&gt;. “But in my eyes, in that time of moment, I didn’t really think about that... What went through my mind was, ‘Okay, I’m never gonna get this opportunity again.’ So I went for it. And, well, this happened.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcnmSt"&gt;The Federal Aviation Administration, which regulates launches and launch infrastructure for the sake of public safety, said it was aware of the video and brought it to SpaceX’s attention&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;“Maintaining the physical security of a launch facility is an important aspect of ensuring public safety,” a spokesman said. SpaceX did not respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W65wM2"&gt;The site has had similar security issues before. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/spacex-fan-jailed-cameron-county-texas-boca-chica-launch-site-2019-10"&gt;a SpaceX fan was arrested&lt;/a&gt; after posting pictures of himself near another Starship prototype to social media.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22372649/youtuber-trespassing-spacex-texas-starship-facilities"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22372649/youtuber-trespassing-spacex-texas-starship-facilities</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-08T14:45:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-08T14:45:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Take a ride on this man’s model train set</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hpAhMhDP0rV4GOmW_NY3YSVBHUk=/1009x0:4894x2590/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69096932/Screen_Shot_2021_04_08_at_9.56.23_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XZWWj9"&gt;Some people spent the pandemic writing the next &lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;, others lamenting the fact that they weren’t. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/4/17/21201878/quarantine-productivity-social-distancing-coronavirus-pandemic-covid-19-capitalism-ep-thompson"&gt;It doesn’t really matter&lt;/a&gt;. There are plenty of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22167393/pandemic-tech-tiktok-zoom-facetime-google-2020"&gt;inspiring pandemic projects&lt;/a&gt; to go around, but one of the most striking (and brain-breaking) has to be &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQTfo32EjvY"&gt;this model train video&lt;/a&gt; created by Jason Shron of the YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/rapidotrains/featured"&gt;Rapido Trains&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oIr15j"&gt;Shron is a devoted train enthusiast and talented model maker. But his model train project re-creating the Canadian VIA rail line connecting Toronto to Montreal is really a treasure only a lot of time (due to COVID-19 lockdowns) and passion (from a lifetime appreciation of the rail) can create. Just look at this video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="C0qDL5"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fQTfo32EjvY?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2fk0dq"&gt;That’s footage shot from one of Shron’s model trains, superimposed over the window of a human-scale VIA train model. It looks, concerningly, like a rail train ride. But you might now be wondering: where did Shron get a human-sized model train? Well, he built that, too — in his basement: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2ZxRCI"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YjMnWdIWjWs?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VdulKp"&gt;You have to commend the attention to detail here. Not only do the models look great — Shron sourced real train seats and other equipment for his human-sized re-creation — but the sound design really sells it. The last time I rode a train was over a year ago now, but the gentle air-conditioned hum, soft creak as the train rides the tracks, white noise of other people talking, and sudden whoosh of another train passing is unmistakable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJ72v2"&gt;It’s almost too real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u5q8Hm"&gt;Consider the implications: if Shron can re-create a train line to almost perfect scale (and a human-sized train car for that matter), where does it stop? Why not a model home with a model train set inside? Or a model town containing the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJKYa0"&gt;I’m not talking &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/20/18150216/welcome-to-marwen-review-steve-carell-robert-zemeckis"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Marwen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; I’m more thinking &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XIizh6nYnTU&amp;amp;t=16s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synecdoche, New York&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe we were so focused on wringing our hands about the frankly ridiculous popularity of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/2/11837874/elon-musk-says-odds-living-in-simulation"&gt;simulation theory&lt;/a&gt; that we ignored the other kind of simulation theory. That a kind man with a deep respect for one of the greatest forms of human transportation (don’t text airplanes, my phone is off), could have built a perfect, fake world around us without us ever knowing. Because then, what’s really real, you know? Am I? Are you?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tj6zpq2pc8jGpwah5egX8mdTJ9I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22430085/jason_shron_in_his_basement_railcar.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: The Toronto Star&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The smiling face of a brilliant hobbyist OR the man who runs our small model world? You be the judge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oryHJM"&gt;Anyway, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQTfo32EjvY"&gt;the video is very relaxing&lt;/a&gt;. You should give it a watch.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/8/22373948/model-train-canadian-via-line-youtube"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/8/22373948/model-train-canadian-via-line-youtube</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-06T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-06T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube claims it’s getting better at enforcing its own moderation rules</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DkGOSv04BaRdDsjLWYfvxFtdr8Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69083827/acastro_180321_1777_youtube_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dlrimL"&gt;YouTube wants the world to know that it’s doing a better job than ever of enforcing its own moderation rules. The company says that a shrinking number of people see problematic videos on its site — such as videos that contain graphic violence, scams, or hate speech — before they’re taken down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHGKrz"&gt;In the final months of 2020, up to 18 out of every 10,000 views on YouTube were on videos that violate the company’s policies and should have been removed before anyone watched them. That’s down from 72 out of every 10,000 views in the fourth quarter of 2017, when YouTube started tracking the figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dnsPo7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The figure measures enforcement of YouTube’s own rules&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FfuGsm"&gt;But the numbers come with an important caveat: while they measure how well YouTube is doing at limiting the spread of troubling clips, they’re ultimately based on what videos YouTube believes should be removed from its platform — and the company still allows &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies"&gt;some obviously troubling videos&lt;/a&gt; to stay up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9zXuiE"&gt;The stat is a new addition to &lt;a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/youtube-policy/removals?hl=en"&gt;YouTube’s community guidelines enforcement report&lt;/a&gt;, a transparency report updated quarterly with details on the types of videos being removed from the platform. This new figure is called Violative View Rate, or VVR, and tracks how many views on YouTube happen on videos that violate its guidelines and should be taken down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUoi3C"&gt;This figure is essentially a way for YouTube to measure how good it’s doing at moderating its own site, based on its own rules. The higher the VVR, the more problematic videos are spreading before YouTube can catch them; the lower the VVR, the better YouTube is doing at stamping out prohibited content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vPxJWc"&gt;YouTube made a chart showing how the figure has fallen since it started measuring the number for internal use:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The chart shows VVR starting at 0.63% - 0.72% in Q4 2017 and falling steeply over the next year to 0.23% - 0.27% before leveling out around 0.16% - 0.18% in the following years." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fXUNkg7fbA6LzmbdtNF5a6---W0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22422381/VVR_Graph_1440x1080.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: YouTube&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A chart from YouTube showing VVR since measurements started.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UcA1yL"&gt;The steep drop from 2017 to 2018 came after YouTube started relying on machine learning to spot problematic videos, rather than relying on users to report problems, Jennifer O’Connor, YouTube’s product director for trust and safety, said during a briefing with reporters. The goal is “getting this number as close to zero as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuaGap"&gt;Videos that violate YouTube’s advertising guidelines, but not its overall community guidelines, aren’t included in the VVR figure since they don’t warrant removal. And so-called “borderline content” that bumps up against but doesn’t quite violate any rules isn’t factored in either for the same reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VQMoJv"&gt;O’Connor said YouTube’s team uses the figure internally to understand how well they’re doing at keeping users safe from troubling content. If it’s going up, YouTube can try to figure out what types of videos are slipping through and prioritize developing its machine learning to catch them. “The North Star for our team is to keep users safe,” O’Connor said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22368505/youtube-violative-view-rate-transparency-stat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22368505/youtube-violative-view-rate-transparency-stat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-01T16:12:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-01T16:12:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube stars the Stokes Twins avoid jail after pleading guilty over fake bank robbery pranks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-ENTERTAINMENT-YOUTUBE-CRIME" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z1X-yexegmLn8rHc5Vrc4Ukv-cU=/0x0:2178x1452/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69062893/1232048551.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Delmas / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z8TJmy"&gt;Alan and Alex Stokes, twin brothers who rose to fame on YouTube filming prank videos, pleaded guilty to misdemeanor false imprisonment and reporting false emergencies in connection with a pair of now-removed videos they filmed in the fall of 2019 in which they pretended to have just robbed a bank. The 23-year-old brothers were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21356403/stokes-twins-youtube-felony-charge-bank-robbery-prank-video"&gt;charged in August of last year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ktdx8i"&gt;They faced a maximum of five years in prison if convicted on all counts, leading to the guilty plea in exchange for reduced sentences, according to a &lt;a href="http://orangecountyda.org/civica/press/display.asp?layout=15&amp;amp;Entry=6126"&gt;press release dated March 31st&lt;/a&gt; by the office of the district attorney of Orange County, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SyIFUD"&gt;“The guilty pleas were in exchange for a judge reducing the felony false imprisonment charge to a misdemeanor. Prosecutors objected on the record and in a trial brief to the court’s offer to reduce the felony charge to a misdemeanor,” the press release states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8wzfnq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These crimes could have easily resulted in someone being seriously hurt or killed.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dsuinD"&gt;Both received a sentence including 160 hours of community service and one year of probation in addition to both having to pay restitution. The Stokes brothers are also barred from returning to the University of California Irvine, where they filmed one of the prank video, and they were also ordered not to produce any more videos “that mimic criminal behavior.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECCuIT"&gt;The videos in question involved the Stokes brothers dressing in black garb with face masks filming themselves interacting with strangers, some of whom were distraught at the prospect of encountering what they believed were on-the-run criminals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isb0Rz"&gt;In one poorly thought-out situation filmed for the videos, the brothers called an Uber driver and demanded they be taken somewhere. The driver refused, but he was later questioned by law enforcement who initially approached the man with their guns drawn, mistakenly believing he was involved after numerous bystanders called law enforcement on the brothers for thinking they were attempting to carjack the driver. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hmGURr"&gt;The brothers pulled this prank twice in the same day on October 15th, 2019, choosing to film the second of the two videos at the University of California Irvine after already having been questioned and released by police elsewhere in Orange County earlier in the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hIQh71"&gt;“These crimes could have easily resulted in someone being seriously hurt or killed,” Orange County District Attorney Todd Spitzer said in a statement. “An active bank robbery is not a casual police response and these police officers were literally risking their lives to help people they believed were in danger. It is irresponsible and reckless that these two individuals cared more about increasing their number of followers on the internet than the safety of those police officers or the safety of the innocent Uber driver who was ordered out of his car at gunpoint.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q6MEtV"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/StokesTwins/videos"&gt;Stokes Twins YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; remains active with more than 6.6 million subscribers. The most recent video, titled “FUNNY April Fool’s Pranks on Friends!,” was posted two days ago, and it’s already amassed 1.4 million views. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22362685/stokes-twins-bank-prank-guilty-youtube-alan-alex-sentence-robbery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22362685/stokes-twins-bank-prank-guilty-youtube-alan-alex-sentence-robbery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-01T06:13:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-01T06:13:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube is relaxing some rules about ads on drug-related videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dY9SugOhPM8_9K-37U6fssO83fQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69059189/acastro_180403_1777_youtube_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ds6gTM"&gt;From this month, Google is updating some of its YouTube ad guidelines about drug-related videos. In a &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9725604?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=9153642"&gt;support document&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/even-youtube-is-chilling-out-on-weed-1846594023?rev=1617228974804"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Google says it’s “expanding monetization on educational, documentary or news content that may include violent interactions with law enforcement, recreational drugs and drug-related content, or sensitive events.” The update means more drug-related videos should be eligible to have ads placed next to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkRkDn"&gt;You can see the exact changes by comparing a backup of YouTube’s &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210324202410if_/https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278#zippy=%2Cguide-to-self-certification"&gt;old content guidelines from last month&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278#zippy=%2Cguide-to-self-certification"&gt;guidelines that are live now&lt;/a&gt;. The guidelines break down drug-related content into three categories: videos where uploaders can turn ads on, videos where ads should be turned off, and videos where they can be turned on “but only brands who opt in will run ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9JYqm9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As New York becomes the sixteenth state to legalize use of marijuana&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jBfOCG"&gt;The biggest change is a new bullet point that’s appeared in the first section, covering videos where ads can be turned on. This now covers videos focusing “on the purchase, fabrication, or distribution of drugs, such as the fabrication of home-made opioids” and “news reports about cannabis farms” that do not glorify drug use. Previously, advertisers had to opt-in to run ads against this kind of content, restricting the amount of ad revenue they could make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bslg7s"&gt;There are also a couple of bullet points that have disappeared entirely from YouTube’s list of videos where ads have to be turned off altogether. These are videos “focusing on drug consumption (including its effects) without educational or documentary context,” or which contain “promotion of regulated legal drugs or substances that can induce a high (e.g. cannabis and derivatives THC and CBD).” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhQ5S2"&gt;Although these exact descriptions haven’t been added to any of the other sections, YouTube has slightly amended the wording in its section describing opt-in advertiser content, which now covers “content focusing on the display or effects of drug consumption; or the creation or distribution of drugs or drug paraphernalia in a comedic, non-educational, or non-documentary context.” The exact status of content around legal highs is less clear, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hnk6SP"&gt;The individual changes are minor, but they should make it easier for YouTube creators to approach the topic of drugs in their videos without worrying about ad revenue. They reflect a broader acceptance of drugs in the United States that include New York recently becoming the sixteenth state to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360455/new-york-marijuana-legalization-conviction-expungement"&gt;legalize the recreational use of marijuana&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361707/youtube-drug-related-content-educational-documentary-news-monetization-ads"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361707/youtube-drug-related-content-educational-documentary-news-monetization-ads</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T18:42:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T18:42:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube has removed Steven Crowder from its Partner Program indefinitely</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GyFxfeZ2NIrOkeCWFoOrlI80dXY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69051444/Screen_Shot_2021_03_18_at_4.38.41_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Steven Crowder’s YouTube channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2G4rWQ"&gt;Two weeks ago, after YouTube revealed its definition of hate speech was so narrow &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies"&gt;that it couldn’t remove a wildly racist tirade&lt;/a&gt; for being wildly racist, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies"&gt;we wondered out loud&lt;/a&gt; what it would take for YouTube to stop promoting conservative commentator Steven Crowder as an official YouTube Partner and allowing him to profit from those tirades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5pfv9P"&gt;Today, we have a partial answer: YouTube has officially suspended Steven Crowder’s main channel from the YouTube Partner Program indefinitely, which includes removing his ability to run ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1p4gpN"&gt;It’s also banning him from uploading videos for a full week after his latest infraction: a now-removed video that reportedly challenged the legitimacy of the vote in Nevada. YouTube has a policy against false claims that the election was stolen. Crowder &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/steven-crowder/after-being-suspended-youtube-steven-crowder-announces-his-plan-evade-it-his-other"&gt;has already announced his intent&lt;/a&gt; to upload videos to his other Crowder Bits channel, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xzpvzm"&gt;Here’s YouTube’s statement (including links):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="bac7lX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to monetize on YouTube, channels must comply with the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/1311392?hl=en"&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTube Partner Program policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, which include our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/intl/en-GB/about/policies/#community-guidelines"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community Guidelines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/48182?ctx=checklist"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google AdSense program policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278?hl=en"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advertiser-Friendly Guidelines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Channels that repeatedly violate our policies are suspended from the partner program. In addition, we removed a video from Steven Crowder’s channel for violating our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2801973?hl=en"&gt;&lt;em&gt;presidential election integrity policy &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;and applied a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2802032?hl=en"&gt;&lt;em&gt;strike&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, meaning uploads are suspended for one week. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="oBnnom"&gt;While YouTube isn’t telling us which straw broke the camel’s back when it comes to the YouTube Partner Program (and his ability to run ads), the company did point us towards two specific guidelines around &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=9153642#Controversial_sensitive"&gt;controversial issues and sensitive events&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=9153642#Harmful_dangerous"&gt;harmful and dangerous acts&lt;/a&gt;. I would have guessed that awful, racist tirades would have already broken the YouTube Partner Program’s &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=9153642#Hateful"&gt;hateful and derogatory content&lt;/a&gt; policy, but I guess I shouldn’t read too much into that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mzc9ck"&gt;It’s not the first time Crowder’s been removed from the YouTube Partner Program. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/5/18654196/steven-crowder-demonetized-carlos-maza-youtube-homophobic-language-ads"&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt;,  it took him &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365601/youtube-steven-crowder-monetization-reinstated-harassment-carlos-maza"&gt;just over a year to come back&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nsbk4s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inexplicably, YouTube says extremely racist Steven Crowder video isn’t hate speech","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies"},{"title":"YouTube will let Steven Crowder run ads after year-long suspension for harassment","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365601/youtube-steven-crowder-monetization-reinstated-harassment-carlos-maza"},{"title":"Carlos Maza is back on YouTube and ready to fight   ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tech/2020/1/31/21112724/carlos-maza-steven-crowder-vox-youtube-harassment-policies-breadtube"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359191/steven-crowder-youtube-partner-program-suspension-demonetize-ads-strike-ban-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359191/steven-crowder-youtube-partner-program-suspension-demonetize-ads-strike-ban-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T17:59:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T17:59:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube is experimenting with hiding dislikes to protect creators’ well-being</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7s4RirOX9iMkRcEc-0mNwnWO-Hc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69051226/acastro_180321_1777_youtube_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CyXNup"&gt;YouTube &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube/status/1376942486594150405?s=20"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; it’s experimenting with hiding dislikes to discourage “dislike mobs” from deliberately downvoting videos from creators and channels. The experiment is a different implementation than the solutions the company had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/1/18207189/youtube-dislike-attack-mob-review-bomb-creator-insider"&gt;previously discussed&lt;/a&gt;, but it is similar to other attempts platforms like Instagram have taken to nip targeted attacks in the bud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JuDtVC"&gt;In the current setup, stats for both likes and dislikes are viewable in a creator’s individual &lt;a href="http://studio.youtube.com"&gt;YouTube Studio&lt;/a&gt; page, but only likes will be displayed publicly on a video. In &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/104325801?hl=en"&gt;a support article&lt;/a&gt; explaining the test, YouTube says that dislikes can negatively impact a creator’s well-being and “may motivate a targeted campaign of dislikes on a creator’s video.” Basically, the idea is that seeing a dislike number and watching it go up could be enough motivation to join in and make the number larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ngXt4J"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;   In response to creator feedback around well-being and targeted dislike campaigns, we're testing a few new designs that don't show the public dislike count. If you're part of this small experiment, you might spot one of these designs in the coming weeks (example below!). &lt;a href="https://t.co/aemrIcnrbx"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aemrIcnrbx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— YouTube (@YouTube) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube/status/1376942486594150405?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="shLUNG"&gt;Creators rely on likes and dislikes as a form of feedback to guide their creative output, but much like purposefully giving a game a bad review on Steam, it’s easy to turn what could be a useful feature into another surface for abuse. When YouTube &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EEdlaJo5YV8"&gt;first announced&lt;/a&gt; it was looking into addressing problems with dislikes, it was considering three ideas: hiding the numbers for both likes and dislikes, adding more friction to disliking something through requiring extra interaction, or removing likes and dislikes entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUsbYC"&gt;This test does half of what the first option promised, and it makes a certain amount of sense. If dislike numbers are the problem, why not just hide them and see what happens? Instagram experimented with a similar kind of test when it decided &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/8/20956091/instagram-testing-hiding-likes-us-bullying-mosseri"&gt;to hide likes on posts&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously, likes are inherently positive, but chasing a high like count can have its own negative impact on creators whose livelihoods depend on closely monitoring interactions with their posts and appearing well-liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmd8t8"&gt;YouTube isn’t testing hiding dislikes on all creators’ videos, but if you notice them on your page or you have an opinion as a viewer, &lt;a href="http://yt.be/help/feedback"&gt;YouTube is collecting feedback&lt;/a&gt; on its site.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358992/youtube-hiding-dislikes-experiment-creator-review-bomb"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358992/youtube-hiding-dislikes-experiment-creator-review-bomb</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T16:42:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T16:42:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube denies employee request to remove rap song with anti-Chinese lyrics</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bGczVJldUO-M8w3RSFlobXcCW5I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69050807/acastro_180322_1777_youtube_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mfs8IO"&gt;YouTube is facing employee calls to remove a rap song that allegedly encourages violence against Asians, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-30/youtube-refuses-to-remove-anti-asian-song-drawing-staff-ire?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vcEwIU"&gt;Rapper YG’s “Meet the Flockers” is a detailed description of a burglary — a relatively common trope in rap music — but it opens with a specific reference to Chinese communities: “find a Chinese neighborhood, cause they don’t believe in bank accounts.” In light of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22274325/asians-racism-coronavirus-oakland-san-francisco"&gt;recent rise in street violence against Asians&lt;/a&gt;, a group of YouTube employees argued that message was straightforwardly dangerous, ultimately asking the Trust &amp;amp; Safety team to remove the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBEA0v"&gt;But YouTube ultimately declined to remove the song, citing &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/inside-youtube/look-how-we-treat-educational-documentary-scientific-and-artistic-content-youtube/"&gt;the platform’s exception&lt;/a&gt; for “educational, documentary, scientific, and artistic” (or EDSA) content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGerpX"&gt;“While EDSA is not a free pass for any content, there are likely thousands of music videos that would otherwise violate policies... were it not for these sorts of EDSA exceptions,” executives wrote in an open letter to employees. “Removing this video would have far-reaching implications for other musical content containing similarly violent or offensive lyrics, in genres ranging from rap to rock.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pqbIY1"&gt;It’s not the first time “Meet the Flockers” has generated controversy. Largely ignored on its release in 2014, the song became &lt;a href="https://www.gq.com/story/yg-meet-the-flockers-controversy"&gt;a point of controversy for Chinese communities two years later&lt;/a&gt; after circulating in social media channels, with &lt;a href="https://abc7.com/yg-meet-the-flockers-knock-burglaries/1958131/"&gt;some police departments&lt;/a&gt; even blaming the song and a subsequent unauthorized music video for specific home burglaries. Concern became so heated that &lt;a href="http://sfist.com/2016/09/28/jane_kim_wants_youtube_to_remove_an.php"&gt;San Francisco supervisor Jane Kim&lt;/a&gt; called on YouTube to remove the video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oxa5wi"&gt;YouTube also declined to take action in response to the 2016 controversy, although the uploader later voluntarily removed the music video. The song remains on YouTube through the official YG account, played over a static album cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m8gcMQ"&gt;Reached for comment, YouTube emphasized the importance of open disagreement within its workforce. “YouTube has an open culture and employees are encouraged to to share their views, even when they disagree with a decision,” a representative said. “We’ll continue this dialogue as part of our ongoing work to balance openness with protecting the YouTube community at large.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GcyPeq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358804/youtube-yg-song-meet-the-flockers-anti-asian-violence"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358804/youtube-yg-song-meet-the-flockers-anti-asian-violence</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-29T16:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-29T16:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile is already shutting down its live TV service, partners with YouTube TV and Philo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nkjNGeYXyH83iWeu69Bj9WlB2G4=/179x0:2249x1380/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69044385/Screen_Shot_2021_03_29_at_3.19.01_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pzT0Ue"&gt;Only five months after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21535264/tmobile-tvision-live-internet-tv-streaming-service-price"&gt;announcing its TVision streaming service&lt;/a&gt;, T-Mobile today shared news that TVision’s three bundles of live channels will all shut down at the end of April. The development comes as part of T-Mobile’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22120959"&gt;new partnership with Google and YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, which it’s making out to be a huge deal. The carrier says YouTube TV will now fill the role of its “live TV solution.” It’s also positioning Philo TV as the replacement for its base offering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6Up7y"&gt;The Live, Live Plus, and Live Zone services that were available with TVision will go dark on April 29th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GWpsbg"&gt;T-Mobile is giving a free month of YouTube TV to customers who had signed up for one of the TVision Live packages, and all T-Mobile subscribers will be eligible to save $10 on the usual monthly rate of $64.99; so if they want the service, it’ll cost $54.99 per month. They can also get three free months of YouTube Premium. On Philo’s side, customers can also get $10 off the usual price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5VIIhE"&gt;“YouTube TV is a leader in this space,” T-Mobile said in today’s press release. “It offers the same great flexibility, robust content and convenience that TVision customers love.” The message is clear: T-Mobile is teaming up with a company that has been in this game longer and is already familiar with everything it takes to make streaming, watch-anywhere TV work — even if it feels like the costs keep climbing higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rkan9Q"&gt;In what comes off as an attempt to sugarcoat a short-lived misstep, T-Mobile says its “TVision initiative was launched to give customers new choices and help millions cut the cord, while expanding appeal for the company’s forthcoming wireless home Internet service.” That doesn’t quite match the usual brazen “Uncarrier” tone that &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20201027005931/en/"&gt;T-Mobile had back in October&lt;/a&gt;, when CEO Mike Sievert said “just like we changed wireless for good, now we’re gonna change TV for good.” At the time, T-Mobile said TVision Live was “a total game-changer for anyone who wants live news and sports.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYIAnX"&gt;Sievert has now changed his tune. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fun-carrier%2Fturns-out-tv-is-better-with-friends&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F29%2F22356978%2Ft-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In a blog post today&lt;/a&gt;, he acknowledged that TV is better “with friends,” and went into more detail on what led to T-Mobile’s revamped approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4znjJL"&gt;This shift may surprise some given last year’s TVision streaming services launch. But innovation seldom follows a straight line. Since launching the TVision initiative, we’ve learned a lot about the TV industry, about streaming products, and of course, about TV customers. We also saw trends that made us take a fresh look at how to best do in video what we always do: put customers first. With our TV software provider encountering some financial challenges and with our broader, strategic partnerships with Google and Philo, we saw an opportunity to deliver unique value to our customers and strengthen the TVision initiative with the best partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7VKXEW"&gt;This industry is incredibly fragmented, with new streaming services launching all the time, and we’ve concluded that we can add even more value to consumers’ TV choices by partnering with the best services out there, negotiating incredible streaming media deals for T-Mobile customers, and helping our customers navigate the increasingly complex streaming world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="O8PqJk"&gt;Sievert describes the new arrangement as “a big upgrade,” adding that “YouTube TV offers more than twice as many channels as TVision Live, and Philo offers nearly twice as many channels as TVision Vibe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vCCJ3h"&gt;TVision Live had started at $40 / month, with Live Plus and Live Zone each increasing by another $10. As other internet TV providers know, it’s unlikely that T-Mobile would’ve been able to hang on to those lower tiers for long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SeLpTJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Ftvision%2Fservices%2Fvibe&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F29%2F22356978%2Ft-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TVision Vibe&lt;/a&gt; — a $10-per-month service that provides on-demand access (but not live streams) to shows from AMC, Discovery, MTV, and other networks — is also being phased out. Same goes for TVision Channels, which lets customers aggregate their subscriptions from Showtime, Stars, and Epix. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Ftvision%2Fservices%2Fhub&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F29%2F22356978%2Ft-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TVision Hub 4K streaming dongle&lt;/a&gt; will remain available, and it sounds like YouTube TV will now get a prominent spot on that device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="51iACF"&gt;You can look at this as a retreat on T-Mobile’s part, but I think its decision is probably the right one. YouTube TV remains the streaming TV service to beat, and there just wasn’t enough about TVision to make it stand out among YTTV and other competitors. Any price advantage was never going to last. Above all else, T-Mobile is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22297311/tmobile-5g-mid-band-magenta-max-unlimited-data"&gt;still touting its strong 5G network advantage&lt;/a&gt;, as evidenced by the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced"&gt;Magenta Max data plan&lt;/a&gt; it announced in late February. The plan is the only one among major carriers to lift any deprioritization limits on data usage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RAubD5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 29th, 4:25PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The article has been updated with more details on T-Mobile’s revamped TV approach, with new details on Philo’s role in the initiative and a blog post from T-Mobile CEO Mike Sievert. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356978/t-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356978/t-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
