<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-16T13:31:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T13:31:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T13:31:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is reportedly going to make more of its own chips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CqPpYNbvftEmMdmVKKeMhMRR8yI=/0x0:2028x1352/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70282304/vpavic_210916_4760_0082.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uziLaj"&gt;Apple is reportedly working to design more chip components in-house, with the company said to be establishing a new office with the aim of replacing components that Apple currently sources from Broadcom and Skyworks, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-16/apple-builds-team-in-new-office-to-bring-wireless-chips-in-house"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9yzwE"&gt;The new office is said to be in its early stages but will eventually focus on “wireless radios, radio-frequency integrated circuits and a wireless system-on-a-chip,” in addition to “semiconductors for connecting to Bluetooth and Wi-Fi,” &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12mJgk"&gt;While the A-series and M-series SoCs that contain the CPU and GPU for Apple’s iPhones and Macs get most of the attention, there are tons of additional chips inside those devices, handling things like power management, USB connectivity, wireless charging, and more. As &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FGuide%2FiPhone%2B13%2BPro%2BFull%2BChip%2BID%2F144993&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22839850%2Fapple-office-develop-chips-in-house-broadcom-skyworks" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iFixit’&lt;/em&gt;s iPhone 13 pro teardown&lt;/a&gt; documents, Skyworks and Broadcom supply a significant portion of the iPhone’s third-party circuitry — parts that Apple, it seems, would prefer to design on its own to create more bespoke solutions for its hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="E4HLXA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple wants to rely less on third-party suppliers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ETAvVH"&gt;One of the most prominent examples of third-party chips is the iPhone’s modem, which is currently manufactured by Qualcomm (but had previously been the subject of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/16/18410985/apple-qualcomm-settle-royalty-dispute-patent-licensing-terms-high-fees"&gt;years-long legal battle&lt;/a&gt; that briefly saw Apple switch to using Intel parts). Apple has made no secret about its ambitions to develop its own 5G chips instead of paying for Qualcomm’s chips, either: the company bought Intel’s smartphone modem business in 2019 for around $1 billion and is said to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/24/22800144/apple-own-iphone-modem-2023-tsmc-4nm"&gt;looking to switch over&lt;/a&gt; to its own in-house modems for the iPhone as early as 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6uxU8"&gt;That Apple is looking to build more of its own chips may not just be about exercising a greater level of control and hardware integration, though: it could also be about getting a better handle on part supply. Right now, Apple is already feeling the impact of the ongoing global chip shortage with supply issues for parts from suppliers like Broadcom, which forced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723209/apple-iphone-13-chip-shortage-manufacturing-report"&gt;Apple to slash its manufacturing targets back in October&lt;/a&gt;. Building its own chips could help Apple alleviate some of those issues in the future, assuming it’s able to continue to work well with its manufacturing partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UO2mYA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839850/apple-office-develop-chips-in-house-broadcom-skyworks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839850/apple-office-develop-chips-in-house-broadcom-skyworks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T06:58:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T06:58:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s P50 Pocket is a stylish clamshell foldable launching this month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T6aRiNRkhbtH8SI2cHbl8CHI_Vk=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280496/001RBNXygy1gxfadt3cfyj61hc0u07ee02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The P50 Pocket appears to have a small external circular screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0qbOuv"&gt;Huawei is set to announce a new foldable phone later this month called the Huawei P50 Pocket, according to a post on the company’s &lt;a href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/4714230723379666"&gt;official Weibo account&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike its previous Mate X foldables, which fold from a device the size of a tablet into a smartphone, the P50 Pocket has a clamshell design that folds out to the size of a smartphone. It’s a similar design to Samsung’s Z Flip devices, or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/13/21135809/motorola-razr-review-foldable-flip-phone-verizon-price-camera-display-battery"&gt;Motorola Razr&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seNxZo"&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/em&gt; photoshoot of the P50 Pocket &lt;a href="https://m.weibo.cn/status/L6h3qlP5V"&gt;posted on Weibo&lt;/a&gt; makes it look like a stylish little foldable. It appears to have a similar dual-ring camera bump to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras"&gt;Huawei P50&lt;/a&gt;, but its lower ring has been repurposed to work as a small external screen, which appears to be able to show notifications or work as a camera viewfinder.  &lt;a href="https://chinese.engadget.com/huawei-p50-pocket-harper-s-bazaar-teaser-062427696.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget China &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that the phone has a side-mounted fingerprint sensor for security, and available colors include silver and gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CHx8kttYuRFP1szeWEDe4IcW4o8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100949/001RBNXygy1gxfat5sa7jj60u01400xc02.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h-wP6CpbfxKSh99T9kPa0fzo3QI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100953/p50_pocket_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Blj1lZbnmPp8RDE0ZmK9qtfqg3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100951/001RBNXygy1gxfadtvk2hj61400u0n0g02.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zHDMhrpvEkBdgIl-peKwOf8iduE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100952/001RBNXygy1gxfadvhl0cj61400u0q8202.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TYT7cw"&gt;Huawei is of course no stranger to foldable devices, and has previously released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18239565/huawei-mate-x-foldable-phone-hands-on-design-mwc-2019"&gt;Mate X&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21145519/huawei-mate-xs-foldable-phone-news-features-quad-layer-screen-hinge-kirin-990-5g"&gt;Mate XS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22294983/huawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price"&gt;Mate X2&lt;/a&gt;. But these use a folding form-factor that some have compared to a hotdog bun. In contrast, the new P50 Pocket looks to be using what’s been called a hamburger-style design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMxwvt"&gt;Huawei’s post only mentions a Chinese launch, and it’s unclear if or when the P50 Pocket could see a global release. We might be waiting a while, though. Huawei is yet to offer its latest flagship smartphone, the P50, outside of China following its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras"&gt;launch in July&lt;/a&gt;, and the company is still subject to US sanctions that both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20993148/huawei-mate-30-no-american-components-manufacturers"&gt;limit its ability to source hardware components&lt;/a&gt; and mean it can’t &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/21/21147919/google-addresses-huawei-services-ban-android-trump-sideload-apps"&gt;preinstall Google’s apps and services&lt;/a&gt; on its phones.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839272/huawei-p50-pocket-china-launch-foldable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839272/huawei-p50-pocket-china-launch-foldable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T17:56:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T17:56:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>We didn’t need an AR version of Snake, but AT&amp;T just gave us one anyway</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lyvzLeI-kJr3MWN6golqBER8L38=/0x50:2100x1450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279143/5g_snake_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warp Speed Worm is an AR filter for Instagram and Messenger and has tenuous connections to 5G at best.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VBq5av"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T has re-imagined the classic Snake game in a new, interactive, and wholly unnecessary way in an effort to promote the capabilities of its 5G network. Called &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/facebook-warp-speed-worm.html"&gt;Warp Speed Worm&lt;/a&gt;, it’s an AR effect that can be used on Instagram and Facebook Messenger video calls.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ugd5HQ"&gt;Snake was, of course, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/27/14749896/nokia-3310-snake-gameplay-preview-mwc-2017"&gt;game of choice&lt;/a&gt; on your early Nokia phone. Or, depending on your age and general level of apathy toward high school mathematics, you may recognize it as the game you played on your TI-83 graphing calculator while you were supposed to be learning about coefficients. Not that I know anyone who would do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuUZ0r"&gt;In any case, this newest contribution to the great Snake game &lt;em&gt;genre&lt;/em&gt; is an AR filter in which the titular worm is controlled by your head movements. You can play with friends, which AT&amp;amp;T would like you to do on their 5G network, or you can be a total doofus and play on your own using the camera in the Instagram app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="upPDP3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can play with friends, which AT&amp;amp;T would like you to do on their 5G network&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mmjSwD"&gt;It’s sort of cute — you tilt your head left or right to direct the worm to pick up little game controller icons. As you’ll recall from AP Calculus, the more the worm eats, the longer it gets. When the worm inevitably eats itself, the game is over, and a sad little dead worm crown appears on your head. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9n6WIF"&gt;I gave the game a try by myself after struggling to understand how to save and use an AR group effect on an Instagram video call. I’ll admit that I missed the physical controls of my calculator and that my neck creaks alarmingly loud when I tilt it repeatedly. I also can’t comment on how AT&amp;amp;T 5G would have enhanced the experience — it worked just fine on my home Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837902/att-5g-ar-snake-warp-speed-worm-messenger-instagram"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837902/att-5g-ar-snake-warp-speed-worm-messenger-instagram</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T12:13:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T12:13:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s Concept Stanza converts your chicken scratch to digital text</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A worker holds the Dell Concept Stanza in their left hand in portrait mode at a white marble table in a cafe setting. On the screen are some drawings and notes. In their right hand is a black stylus." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oW0lH-srKEIieThxb6c_FZ5tdx4=/313x0:3688x2250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70277284/Concept_Stanza___lifestyle_image___over_shoulder___embargoed_until_Dec_15.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here it is.&lt;/em&gt; | Dell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ar234k"&gt;Dell has shown off a new concept device that (let’s be honest) may never actually come out — but it’s a lot of fun to play with. The Concept Stanza is an 11-inch tablet that’s meant to simplify the process of taking notes at work. The idea is that if you write on the Stanza and then double tap your notes, they’ll be instantly converted to digital text. Connect it to a computer, and your notes will show up on the big screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSK333"&gt;Now, this is obviously not a revolutionary use case — devices like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21372109/samsung-galaxy-note-20-ultra-review-camera-price-photos-s-pen-notes"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Notes&lt;/a&gt; can convert handwritten notes to digital ones already. But the big difference with the Stanza is that it’s &lt;em&gt;just &lt;/em&gt;for writing — there are no cameras, speakers, or ports on the device, in an effort to create what Dell describes as a “distraction-free experience.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dy6yaj"&gt;Dell’s tablet can also recognize more than letters. You can draw a line through text to delete it and can theoretically digitize shapes (such as Venn diagrams) as well. Separately, the Stanza can serve as an external monitor to extend your screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Dell Concept Stanza mounted horizontally on a stand with the stylus magnetically attached to the top, on a desk with a cup of pens and a row of notebooks in the background. The screen displays BioFrame 2.0 software." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7PymGJgdq4gVXkxZTmeWfXHeI2w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098700/Concept_Stanza___docked___embargoed_until_Dec_15.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s the stylus, magnetically attached.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRfjb9"&gt;I got to try the Stanza out for a few brief minutes. It was a comfortable writing experience — the stylus is compact and the tablet’s screen is smooth. The device correctly interpreted all of my (fairly messy) writing. In English, that is — though we were told that the device is supposed to support a whole bunch of languages, I tried writing some things in Chinese and Korean characters that it did not recognize. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3EsY8B"&gt;So, work in progress. Since the Stanza is still in the concept stage, there’s no pricing and availability yet, and no guarantee that it’s going to become a real thing you can buy. But it could certainly be a nifty tool for boardroom and classroom use. It’s the rare concept device that I think seems pretty ready to go — though I hope it figures out how to do multiple languages at once. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837685/dell-concept-stanza-tablet-digital-text-stylus-writing-notes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837685/dell-concept-stanza-tablet-digital-text-stylus-writing-notes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T04:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T04:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo’s Find N is an impressive first folding phone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0ZzSQzXdM8-wFdPii7o44wIryOU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70275102/IMG_1126.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uTXtZn"&gt;After teasing its first folding phone &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825716/oppo-find-n-foldable-inno-day-2021"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, Oppo is revealing the Find N in full today. Oppo’s chief product officer Pete Lau told reporters in a briefing that the company has been working on this phone since 2018, with the final Find N the result of six generations of internal development. I can believe it — I’ve been using it since last week, and it’s a surprisingly impressive and refined product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kVj84z"&gt;The Find N features a similar design to Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold series, with a large, squarish folding OLED panel on the inside and a smaller screen on the outside that can be used when the phone is closed. The 120Hz inner display is 7.1 inches diagonal and has a slightly landscape 9:8.4 aspect ratio, unlike the Z Fold display, which is taller when unfolded. This means you don’t have to rotate the phone 90 degrees (with the fold horizontal) to watch videos at their largest size. There are dual stereo speakers located at the bottom of the phone, too, which further improves the experience of quickly opening the phone up to watch a video.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m-nndZxBUp20mF0mJ7FCF9phG3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098015/IMG_1128.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Find N’s hinge lets the phone stay unfolded between 50 and 120 degrees.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JoK22U"&gt;The screen looks great. Lau confirmed that it’s a Samsung-made panel, but says Oppo has heavily customized it and holds its own patents. The screen is protected by UTG (ultra-thin glass) and Oppo rates it for 200,000 folds, the same as Samsung. The crease in the panel is wider but much less visible than in the Galaxy Z Fold 3 because it wraps around a unique teardrop-shaped hinge that Lau says is also heavily patented and costs $100 to build alone. Another benefit of this design is that the phone folds shut without leaving a gap between the two halves of the display. You can feel the crease under your finger, but it’s difficult to see in regular use from all but the widest of viewing angles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Yp2CI"&gt;The outer screen is much more like a regular smartphone than the Z Fold’s. At 5.49 inches with an aspect ratio of 2:1, it’s actually very usable — if it weren’t for the folded device being twice as thick as a regular phone, it’d feel like the compact Android flagship that no-one else is making. The hinge does make for a larger bezel on the left side of the screen, of course, but it’s not intrusive. My biggest complaint about the outer screen is that it’s only 60Hz, which wouldn’t necessarily be a problem but feels jarring when the bigger, much smoother inner screen is right there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dkm5lU786QVPT2JBjJ87YUqRewc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098016/IMG_1130.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Find N’s outer display works pretty much like a regular phone, albeit quite a small one.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="J3Hw5a"&gt;The rest of the Find N’s spec sheet is what you’d expect from a 2021 Android flagship. There’s a Snapdragon 888 processor and up to 12GB of RAM and 512GB of storage. The main camera is 50 megapixels, using the same Sony IMX766 sensor from the OnePlus 9 Pro and Oppo Find X3 Pro, and is joined by a 16-megapixel ultrawide and a 13-megapixel 2x telephoto. The battery is 4,500mAh and can be charged at 33W with a SuperVOOC cable or 15W wirelessly. There’s also 10W reverse wireless charging and standard Qi support. A fingerprint sensor is located in the power button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OStCPU"&gt;Oppo isn’t quite as ambitious as Samsung with its custom software for multitasking, but there are a few gestures that help make the most of the bigger screen. You can pinch with four fingers to collapse a full-screen app into a smaller floating column, or split the screen in half with a two-finger swipe down. Oppo has also customized many of its own apps with features designed for the folding screen — for example, if you prop it open at an angle, the music app can display lyrics on the top half. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y3bCiHdLkmMLZJgsQj5XCWP8jFU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098017/IMG_1127.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Find N’s back panel curves similarly to the Find X3 Pro.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8iBTGO"&gt;One obvious concern is durability, and it’s one that I can’t speak to after having had such a short time with the Find N. But I can speak to the design, and I think Oppo has a winner here. The Find N is sleek and easy to use whether it’s open or closed — it strikes the balance between both configurations better than any other foldable phone to date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx0hET"&gt;I would say that the Find N should have Samsung worried, but unfortunately Oppo is only going to sell it in China, a country where Samsung phones have almost no presence. It’ll go on sale from December 23rd for a surprisingly low price of 7,699 yuan (about $1,200) for a model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. 8,999 yuan (about $1,400) gets you a 12GB/512GB model. For comparison, the iPhone 13 Pro Max starts at 8,999 yuan in China, so while the Find N isn’t exactly cheap it’s well within mainstream flagship phone territory. The Galaxy Z Fold 3, meanwhile, starts at $1,799 in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837149/oppo-find-n-hands-on-announcement-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837149/oppo-find-n-hands-on-announcement-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T17:38:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T17:38:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s not-Chromecast Google TV dongle adds an ethernet jack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ALQF0b48xhB7FxbBoVrATC1QY_Q=/0x0:2058x1372/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70273722/tvision_hub.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TVision Hub offers 4K streaming and ships with a voice-control remote&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: T-Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Gk6wc5"&gt;T-Mobile’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356978/t-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv"&gt;TVision streaming service was not long for this world&lt;/a&gt;, but its name lives on in the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Ftvision%2Fservices%2Fhub&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F14%2F22834584%2Ft-mobile-tvision-hub-google-tv-chromecast-dongle-ethernet" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TVision Hub&lt;/a&gt; — a $50 dongle with Google TV. It appears to function a lot like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control"&gt;Google’s own Chromecast&lt;/a&gt;, but along with some T-Mobile branding, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/12/14/tmobile-google-tv-ethernet-dongle/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt; that it offers a feature you won’t find on Google’s streaming dongle: an ethernet jack. That direct internet connection may be a real benefit if your home Wi-Fi signal isn’t quite up to the task of streaming 4K video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="38xndx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://tmo.report/2021/12/t-mobile-releases-new-tvision-hub-for-some-reason/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The T-Mo Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; spotted the device last week on T-Mobile’s website, which is a new version of the streaming dongle launched with the TVision service. It comes with a remote bearing Netflix, YouTube, and Google Assistant buttons and connects with accessories like game controllers and headphones via Bluetooth or USB-C. Like Chromecast, it supports 4K HDR streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x2Ke8J"&gt;T-Mobile (probably wisely) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356978/t-mobile-tvision-live-plus-zone-shutting-down-youtube-tv"&gt;shuttered its streaming TV subscription service&lt;/a&gt; just six months after it launched, opting instead to partner with YouTube TV and Philo. While the service is gone, it seems that the company wasn’t ready to let go of the TVision branding. The TVision Hub is available now for $50 and is offered free with a new home internet line. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834584/t-mobile-tvision-hub-google-tv-chromecast-dongle-ethernet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834584/t-mobile-tvision-hub-google-tv-chromecast-dongle-ethernet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nomad adds magnets to its Base Station wireless charger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0-NCiB5ih0nq1SmsE7K1Go1l4fw=/0x0:5899x3933/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70269880/856500018928_Lifestyle_10.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nomad Base Station Hub with magnetic alignment&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nomad&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2D1pWM"&gt;Nomad is updating its line of wireless chargers with the latest version of the Base Station Hub. A multi-device charger that can wirelessly charge up to two devices at the same time, plus charge two more devices through its USB ports, the new Base Station Hub now has embedded magnets to help align devices in the right spot on the pad. The new Hub costs $119.95 and is &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergeNomadBaseStation121421/https://nomadgoods.com/products/base-station-hub-magnetic" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for purchase starting today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMjCHA"&gt;Aside from the magnets, the new Hub is very similar to &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergeNomadBaseStation121421/https://nomadgoods.com/products/base-station-hub" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nomad’s prior version&lt;/a&gt;. It has three charging coils under a leather pad that are each capable of up to 10W charging (iPhones will be limited to 7.5W). On the back of the charger is an 18W USB-C port and a 7.5W USB-A port for other devices. Nomad also sells an attachment that affixes to the back of the Hub and holds an Apple Watch charger (not included) that you plug into one of the USB ports on the back or a separate brick. It’s less elegant than the multi-device chargers that have Apple Watch chargers built in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8BAkh"&gt;The biggest challenge with wireless charging pads is making sure your phone or device is put in the right place to actually charge. That’s where the magnets in the new Hub come in: they make it easy to tell when your compatible iPhone (12 or newer), AirPods, or even a Google Pixel 6 is in the right spot to charge efficiently. The magnets are not as strong as those in Apple’s MagSafe charger or most MagSafe accessories — they aren’t designed to hold your phone in place if an earthquake happens. But they do noticeably attach and align the phone in the right place when you put it down, which is the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zytiU21ytftKWHObC2sfBOyWuQg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23085820/856500018928_G.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nomad&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under the Base Station Hub’s leather pad are three charging coils surrounded by magnets, which help align compatible devices so they charge efficiently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="11PnIJ"&gt;The Base Station Hub is not as ambitious as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21399941/nomad-base-station-pro-review-wireless-charger-aira-freepower-price"&gt;Nomad’s old Base Station Pro&lt;/a&gt;, which used a complex array of charging coils and was meant to let you just plop your phone down wherever and have it charge. But that device had significant limitations and compatibility issues with phones that used MagSafe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="obtjdT"&gt;Ultimately, when it comes to wireless chargers, the most important thing is knowing that your device will charge when you place it down. The new Base Station Hub makes that just a little bit easier than before.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833200/nomad-base-station-magnet-edition-wireless-charger-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833200/nomad-base-station-magnet-edition-wireless-charger-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T11:49:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T11:49:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Former FCC officials are worried about air safety fears delaying 5G rollout</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yy5gINqsvBIFWWrMcbOmPWXC7lk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70269778/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PJOxGH"&gt;US mobile carriers are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft"&gt;delaying their 5G rollout&lt;/a&gt; thanks to an ongoing spat between two government agencies, and it doesn’t look like the situation will be resolving soon. As &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-13/six-former-fcc-chiefs-concerned-over-aviation-agency-5g-stance?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a group of six former FCC chiefs have sent a letter dated this Monday saying they were “concerned about the Federal Aviation Administration’s (FAA) recent efforts to revisit the FCC’s 2020 decision” to open up the C-band to 5G applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dIBL4R"&gt;At heart, the argument is between the federal agencies tasked with regulating airplanes and airwaves: the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and Federal Communications Commission (FCC). The agencies disagree about whether it’s safe to allow 5G equipment to operate within a portion of the electromagnetic spectrum known as the C-band. The FAA says that doing so threatens the safety of aircraft, as 5G signals could interfere with the operation of certain altimeters (used to measure height above the ground). The FCC is complying with the FAA’s requests, but some third-party experts say these air safety fears are overblown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="67hVg7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The FAA position threatens to derail the reasoned conclusions reached by the FCC”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sMUkCx"&gt;“The FAA position threatens to derail the reasoned conclusions reached by the FCC after years of technical analysis and study,” said the authors of the recent letter, former FCC chiefs Ajit Pai, Tom Wheeler, Mignon Clyburn, Julius Genachowski, Michael Copps, and Michael Powell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xepu8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports that the letter was sent to current FCC chair Jessica Rosenworcel and Evelyn Remaley, acting assistant secretary of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (another agency involved in telecoms regulation). The letter reportedly encourages the FCC and the FAA to work together in finding a solution for this problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYOfDx"&gt;As a result of the FAA’s objections, Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T have delayed the expansion of their 5G networks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft"&gt;until at least January 5th&lt;/a&gt;. That expansion was set to use the C-band spectrum, which the FAA says threatens aircraft safety. And just last week, the FAA ruled that certain aircraft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822875/5g-faa-rule-c-band-landing-airport-bad-weather-visibility"&gt;would not be able to land using guided and automatic systems&lt;/a&gt; because of worries these programs could be affected by 5G equipment. The result of this may well be flight delays, thought it’s impossible to say how widespread these problems could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aw2btY"&gt;But for some industry watchers, the delay to the 5G rollout isn’t just frustrating — it’s nonsensical. They argue that a key FAA study supposedly showing 5G interference with altimeters doesn’t really support the agency’s claims, and note that 40 other countries have already approved or operate 5G equipment in the worrisome C-band without any trouble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14ZEqE"&gt;“Either physics works differently in the US, or the report at the center of this controversy needs to explain why [interference] hasn’t shown up in any other country where deployments are either authorized or have already taken place,” writes Harold Feld, a senior vice president of the consumer advocacy group Public Knowledge, in an &lt;a href="https://wetmachine.com/tales-of-the-sausage-factory/what-the-eff-faa-my-insanely-long-field-guide-to-the-faa-fcc-5g-c-band-fight/"&gt;excellent explainer on the spat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EGcE71"&gt;How, exactly, the two agencies will find a resolution and stop fighting over the airwaves is unclear. In a statement reacting to the FCC letter, the FAA told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;: “[W]e continue to work with federal agencies and the wireless companies.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834080/5g-rollout-delay-faa-fcc-letter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834080/5g-rollout-delay-faa-fcc-letter</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>LastPass is going to become an independent company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-HIpULz4Izv-8h5Jq0rbcESdWcw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70268897/acastro_210217_1777_passwords_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LogMeIn is making LastPass an independent company.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eOfXkZ"&gt;LogMeIn plans to spin out password management tool LastPass as a standalone company, it announced Tuesday. With the change, LastPass is promising that customers will receive enhancements on an “accelerated timeline” next year. “With a team solely dedicated to its continued innovation and growth, [LastPass] will be able to deliver even more strongly for users,” a spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CdyvAY"&gt;LastPass, which LogMeIn purchased &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/9/9486343/logmein-buys-lastpass-for-125-million"&gt;for $125 million in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, is a popular password management tool; it’s used by “more than 30 million users and 85,000 businesses worldwide,” according to LogMeIn, and “the significant majority” of its business is corporate customers. LogMeIn’s emphasis on LastPass’ corporate use in its press release could suggest the standalone company is going to focus more on that audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abDw3C"&gt;The change arrives almost a year after LastPass &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285531/lastpass-free-tier-mobile-computer-device-premium-family"&gt;added significant restrictions to its free tier&lt;/a&gt;. LastPass now limits free users to only viewing and managing passwords on mobile devices &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; your computer. To access your passwords on all your devices, you need to be on a paid plan. If you’re still on LastPass’ free plan and want to move to another password manager, we’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295354/lastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho"&gt;a guide you can follow right here&lt;/a&gt;. LogMeIn has also been criticized for tripling the price of LastPass Premium &lt;a href="https://www.bruceb.com/2019/06/lastpass-learns-the-wrong-lessons-about-price-increases-from-logmein/"&gt;between 2017 and 2019&lt;/a&gt;, though a spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; there are “no plans” to change LastPass’ pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAberS"&gt;The shift is taking place nearly two years after LogMeIn agreed to sell itself to &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/lastpass-parent-company-sold-to-private-equity-firms"&gt;two private equity firms for $4.3 billion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833319/lastpass-independent-company-logmein"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833319/lastpass-independent-company-logmein</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T04:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T04:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo announces Air Glass ‘assisted reality’ device</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LUTMMFUjNxNB3mfUvNkzsXAGqaY=/47x0:1874x1218/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70268392/3._OPPO_Air_Glass_Weather_Notification.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2OECP5"&gt;Oppo has announced the Air Glass, an AR device that’ll go on sale early next year. Oppo describes the Air Glass as an “assisted reality” product, as opposed to augmented reality, meaning it projects 2D information into your field of view rather than overlaying 3D objects onto the real world. (Yes, sort of like Google Glass.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZB2rG"&gt;The Air Glass has a Qualcomm Snapdragon 4100 processor and weighs just 30g (about 1oz) in total. Oppo says it should last for 3 hours of active usage and 40 hours on standby. There are two frame designs, a silver half-frame and a black full-frame, and each is available in two sizes. The inside of the frame has a magnetic port that allows it to be attached to more conventional glasses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzzcU6"&gt;The waveguide display uses a tiny projector with Micro LED tech capable of up to 3 million nits peak brightness, though Oppo says the actual brightness will be up to 1,400 nits in average conditions. It can be operated via touch, voice, hand tracking, and head tracking, as well as through a Smart Glass app on a smartphone running Oppo’s ColorOS 11 or above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lC-mTEjw8u4q7kiM-3yEWhgA6-8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086596/4._OPPO_Air_Glass_Teleprompter.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FcQK7P"&gt;Oppo’s proposed use cases for the Air Glass are relatively modest. The company says it can be used for notifications and directions, as you’d expect, as well as features like teleprompting and real-time translation. The display is monochrome with either 16 or 256 levels of grayscale depending on the mode, so the Air Glass isn’t going to be beaming rich content into your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s1nrgz"&gt;That said, it probably isn’t going to be a mature, mainstream product, either. Oppo says the Air Glass will receive a “limited release” in Q1 2022, and at least at first it’ll be only sold in mainland China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkNTm1"&gt;The Air Glass was announced as part of Oppo’s ongoing annual Inno Day event. Oppo also revealed its first in-house NPU chip to boost machine learning-related imaging performance; it’s called the MariSilicon X and will feature in Oppo’s next Find X flagship in the first quarter of next year. Last week Oppo confirmed the debut of its first folding phone, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825716/oppo-find-n-foldable-inno-day-2021"&gt;the Find N&lt;/a&gt;, though that hasn’t broken cover just yet. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833796/oppo-air-glass-ar-glasses-announced-china-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833796/oppo-air-glass-ar-glasses-announced-china-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
