<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-19T14:51:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T14:51:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T14:51:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 9 RT is reportedly on the way, but not for North America or Europe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iRhACtAz2Fq9RI5-MNtmbh7OlKk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69749115/ajohnson_210623_4644_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus N200, a sub-$300 phone, is the kind of budget device the company is offering in the US.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AOzJfA"&gt;OnePlus may be getting ready to launch another variant of its 9-series phones, the 9 RT, &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oneplus-9-rt-october-oxygenos-12"&gt;according to an &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt; source&lt;/a&gt;. Based on the report, it looks to be a slightly upgraded version of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22348430/oneplus-9r-specs-price-availability"&gt;the OnePlus 9R&lt;/a&gt;, which was launched earlier this year with more modest specs than the flagship 9 and 9 Pro. That model never made it to North America, and it seems this will also be the case for the 9 RT. Like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22586815/oneplus-nord-2-5g-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;the Nord 2&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577770/oneplus-base-9-pro-north-america-us-canada"&gt;the 9 Pro base model&lt;/a&gt;. But who’s keeping track?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqvGAG"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;, the OnePlus 9 RT will launch in October with a Snapdragon 870 processor, 120Hz OLED, a 4,500mAh battery, and OxygenOS 12 out of the box. For its main rear-facing camera, it will reportedly use the 50-megapixel sensor behind the same (very good) ultrawide as in the 9 and 9 Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7dodMO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OgEhY8"&gt;The OnePlus 9 RT will debut in China and India, according to &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;, and there are no plans to make it available in North American or European markets. That’s not too surprising, and it tracks with OnePlus’ recent strategy of limiting US releases to the high-end likes of the 9 and 9 Pro, along with the budget-oriented N200 and N10 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LxyUYs"&gt;It’s possible that OnePlus sees an opportunity to gobble up some of the budget market share &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375938/lg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola"&gt;formerly occupied by LG&lt;/a&gt; and has focused its US strategy accordingly. In any case, it looks increasingly clear that bringing midrange devices like the Nord 2 and upper-midrangers like this rumored 9 RT to the US aren’t part of the company’s strategy. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632475/oneplus-9-rt-launch-rumor-android-12"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632475/oneplus-9-rt-launch-rumor-android-12</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>GM and AT&amp;T are teaming up to bring 5G to Chevy, Cadillac, and GMC cars by 2024</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WkzfhWvzwOugACCEJ7PzffaU8l8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69746864/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="b1GbrA"&gt;General Motors and AT&amp;amp;T are partnering to bring 5G connectivity to “millions” of vehicles over the next decade. The improved connectivity will mean better software performance, enhanced navigation, and faster music and video streaming capabilities, company officials said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Z8AfB"&gt;Starting with model year 2024, all Chevrolet, Buick, Cadillac, and GMC vehicles will come equipped with 5G. In addition, all of GM’s current model year 2019 and newer vehicles, which are equipped with 4G LTE, will experience “faster connectivity speeds and many of the same performance benefits of future 5G-equipped vehicles” thanks to GM’s fifth-generation cellular network architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vp45w4"&gt;In other words, cars made in 2019 and beyond will have improved data speeds and software performance, as well as reduced transmission latency, thanks to this new effort by GM and AT&amp;amp;T. But that will depend on when AT&amp;amp;T’s network is ready to take on millions of new customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OCyEdF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;5G has the potential to be 100 times faster than 4G&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pdVYLB"&gt;5G, so named because it is the fifth generation of cellular technology, has the potential to be 100 times faster than 4G LTE, according to Ericsson, but for many smartphone owners, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;it’s been a mixed bag&lt;/a&gt;. The infrastructure is taking longer to build than originally expected, and most smartphones that claim to use 5G aren’t any faster than 4G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmTFcw"&gt;That’s why GM and AT&amp;amp;T are waiting until 2024 before rolling out the new 5G-equipped vehicles. “It’s really not a function of what’s missing in the vehicles,” said Thomas DeMaria, executive director of 5G connectivity at GM. “It’s more around the maturity of the 5G technology, and also the readiness of 5G.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TkSswj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"5G: everything you need to know","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21284203/5g-need-to-know-health-safety-radiowave-spectrum-verizon-att-tmobile-cellular-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9sR1Zo"&gt;In the interim, GM’s 4G LTE-equipped vehicles starting with model year 2019 and newer will migrate to run over AT&amp;amp;T’s new 5G core infrastructure. According to the automaker, that will align with the timing of GM’s rollout of 5G, which will start with model year 2024. “As the new network infrastructure is built out over the next several years, we will test and learn to see if these improvements can be realized sooner,” a GM spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GDtu3y"&gt;In addition to better data speeds, customers can also expect better security when using their cars to make phone calls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wmT8Ci"&gt;“What 5G enables versus 4G LTE, number one it’s complying with the overall 5G standards, which are much higher than 4G LTE,” Gregory Wieboldt, AT&amp;amp;T’s senior VP for global business and industry solutions, said in a call with reporters. “And it’ll offer more privacy for the identity and stronger encryption for your call and your data, because it’s run on a smarter network software platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FL4Ntb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568437/halo-driverless-car-tmobile-5g-las-vegas"&gt;Self-driving cars are often held up as the ultimate application of 5G&lt;/a&gt;. For example, the low latency of 5G can help deliver safety information to an autonomous vehicle’s AI “brain” before it is even visible to a human driver. But in the US, at least, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;our networks just haven’t met the bar yet&lt;/a&gt; to make it a reality. GM and AT&amp;amp;T downplayed the significance of their rollout of 5G for autonomous vehicles at this time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TJNS8v"&gt;“The network in the vehicle systems are increasingly relying on what I would call data augmentation,” DeMaria said. “So autonomous functions, ADAS [advanced driver assist systems] functions and other connected services, including navigation systems, increasingly are relying on supplemental data coming in from the network. So we’re going to continue to see that trend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WbtpZJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631247/gm-att-5g-car-chevy-cadillac-gmc-2024"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631247/gm-att-5g-car-chevy-cadillac-gmc-2024</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T03:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo introduces true continuous zoom lens for smartphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/toE_dzxwC9P3Co72BH6oie-1zzs=/79x0:945x577/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69746137/OPPO_Continuous_Optical_Zoom_2021.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DWxcjX"&gt;Oppo has held a “Future Imaging Technology Launch Event” online today to make some camera-related announcements, following the reveal of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced"&gt;“next-generation” under-display selfie camera&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o7VVzV"&gt;Oppo is known for demonstrating camera tech in prototype form long before it hits the market. The company was the first to demonstrate &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/3/1/14755916/oppo-5x-zoom-camera-prototype-hands-on-mwc-2017"&gt;periscope telephoto cameras&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/26/18759380/under-display-selfie-camera-first-oppo-announcement"&gt;under-display cameras&lt;/a&gt;, for example, both of which are increasingly common on high-end devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1fNJC898kmxEfv5pPpmBaudV1ks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792007/OPPO_Continuous_Optical_Zoom_2021.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EZNGtf"&gt;The first new announcement is a telephoto lens with continuous optical zoom. Unlike periscope telephoto lenses used today, the lens elements move throughout the 85-200mm-equivalent zoom range meaning that the images should be crisp at every focal length without the need for digital zoom, cropping, or artificial sharpening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9vdWh"&gt;Vivo announced a similar product for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/28/21157292/vivo-apex-2020-concept-phone-cameras-screen-specs"&gt;Apex 2020 concept phone&lt;/a&gt;, but the range was a lot more limited — roughly 130-195mm-equivalent. This Oppo module starts at 85mm, a common focal length for portrait headshots, which should make it a lot more versatile. Oppo points out that using one camera across more focal lengths ensures more consistent performance in terms of color and white balance, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFgrzy"&gt;Unfortunately, Oppo isn’t saying when it might ship this camera on a commercial device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Iz6fs-jJ9tMine1rDM_KXWE74-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792004/OPPO_s_Five_axis_OIS_lens_shift.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="u7Agmo"&gt;The next announcement is a five-axis optical image stabilization system that makes use of both lens-shift and sensor-shift techniques as well as movement data from the phone’s gyroscope. Lens shifting is used for more gradual stabilization, while sensor shift is applied in more dramatic situations, and includes the ability to roll the sensor as well as along the X and Y axes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNKRKd"&gt;Oppo says this allows for three times better stabilization than you can achieve with regular OIS camera modules, which is also what Vivo says about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326786/vivo-x50-pro-plus-gimbal-camera-global-india-release-price"&gt;gimbal-style systems it’s been shipping since last year&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the zoom lens, though, Oppo is confirming a release timeframe for the OIS system — it’ll start appearing in Oppo phones in the first quarter of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fBwdFXdBMyMtwUj9nDFKlbQmzSc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792003/Illustration_of_OPPO_s_next_generation_RGBW_Sensor_pixels.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WBVnIM"&gt;Oppo’s last major announcement is a new image sensor that uses an RGBW sub-pixel layout, adding extra white subpixels for what the company claims is a 60-percent increase in light sensitivity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sV5Kcx"&gt;Oppo acknowledges that earlier attempts at RGBW sensors had their limitations, but it thinks the new effort should make a big difference due to more advanced manufacturing processes and improved demosaicing algorithms. It’ll be available pretty soon, too — the company says it’ll appear in phones shipping in Q4 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631974/oppo-continuous-zoom-lens-smartphone-camera-tech-event"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631974/oppo-continuous-zoom-lens-smartphone-camera-tech-event</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T16:49:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T16:49:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile data breach exposed the personal info of more than 47 million people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="T-Mobile network advertises seen on a Jumbotron in Times..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SeY8vHs9AcZ2ShHiYHqB1aj5rMU=/0x30:4793x3225/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69741585/1229111902.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by John Lamparski/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YPCyBJ"&gt;T-Mobile has &lt;a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/network/additional-information-regarding-2021-cyberattack-investigation"&gt;released more information&lt;/a&gt; about its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach'"&gt;most recent data breach&lt;/a&gt;, and while the company’s findings fall short of the reported 100 million records, the numbers are staggering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unYsU5"&gt;While saying its investigation is still ongoing, the company confirmed that records of over 40 million “former or prospective customers” who had previously applied for credit and 7.8 million postpaid customers (those who currently have a contract) were stolen. In its last earnings report (&lt;a href="https://s24.q4cdn.com/400059132/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/NG_TMUS-06_30_2021-EX-99.1.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;), T-Mobile said it had over 104 million customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FoGq9b"&gt;The data in the stolen files contained critical personal information included first and last names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and driver’s license / ID numbers — the kind of information you could use to set up an account in someone else’s name or hijack an existing one. It apparently did not include “phone numbers, account numbers, PINs or passwords.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LMVzP9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile found out about the breach based on a forum post&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="96Jzp9"&gt;That isn’t the end of it, either, as over 850,000 prepaid T-Mobile customers were also victims of the breach, and for them, the exposed data includes “names, phone numbers, and account PINs.” Affected customers have already had their PINs reset and will receive a notification “right away.” There was also unspecified information accessed for inactive prepaid accounts. However, T-Mobile says, “No customer financial information, credit card information, debit or other payment information or SSN was in this inactive file.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jZ2JEM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KlIcW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers trust us with their private information and we safeguard it with the utmost concern. A recent cybersecurity incident put some of that data in harm’s way, and we apologize for that. We take this very seriously, and we strive for transparency in the status of our investigation and what we’re doing to help protect you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="AUHUn2"&gt;The notice includes boilerplate language saying that “We take our customers’ protection very seriously,” but it rings especially hollow from T-Mobile considering that this is at least the fourth data breach exposed in the last few years, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/3/22211839/t-mobile-customers-call-records-hacker-security"&gt;one in January&lt;/a&gt;. According to the company’s statement, its investigation began based on a report of someone claiming in an online forum that they had compromised T-Mobile’s servers. A spokesperson for the FCC says in a statement that “Telecommunications companies have a duty to protect their customers’ information. The FCC is aware of reports of a data breach affecting T-Mobile customers and we are investigating.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMaLXg"&gt;A Twitter account advertising stolen data for sale &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/"&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; the attack affected all 100 million customers and included IMEI / IMSI data for 36 million customers that could uniquely identify specific devices or SIM cards, but T-Mobile’s announcement does not confirm that is the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oyYN5X"&gt;T-Mobile has &lt;a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/brand/data-breach-2021"&gt;added a page on its site&lt;/a&gt; where customers can go for information as well as shortcuts to change their PINs and passwords. It’s offering two years of free identity protection services from McAfee, recommends postpaid customers change their PIN, and mentions its Account Takeover Protection capabilities to prevent SIM-swapping attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NCfIm1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"T-Mobile says unauthorized access to its data occurred, not clear if customer info involved","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627641/t-mobile-data-breach-unauthorized-access-servers-customer-info"},{"title":"T-Mobile investigating report of customer data breach that reportedly involves 100 million people ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rGID8K"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 18th, 4:49PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added link and information regarding T-Mobile’s dedicated site, and its apology statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HSJwhc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 19th, 10:30AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from the FCC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T09:34:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T09:34:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon Unite is coming to iOS and Android on September 22nd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SryW1KH7hwYGXhcF8baJVZQF6HM=/44x0:535x327/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69741238/pokemon_unite_169.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8ZU538"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt;, the five-versus-five MOBA game that released in July for the Nintendo Switch, will debut on iOS and Android devices on September 22nd. The Pokémon Company shared today during a livestream that you can pre-register for the mobile game now on your respective devices (&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1512321575"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemonunite"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;). You’ll be notified when it’s officially available to download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJqIX3"&gt;Whether you play &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt; on mobile or a Nintendo Switch, the game will offer cross-platform play to broaden who you can play alongside or against. By linking your account on both the Switch version and the mobile game, you’ll be able to have cross-progression, which will allow you to play the game with your saved data and characters on whichever device is more convenient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fsiC8W"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Pokémon Unite turns monster battles into a team sport","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590249/pokemon-unite-nintendo-switch-hands-on-esports"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="YwfkfK"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonUNITE?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#PokemonUNITE&lt;/a&gt; is coming to mobile on September 22!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pre-register for special rewards! &lt;a href="https://t.co/r671Bs31el"&gt;pic.twitter.com/r671Bs31el&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Pokémon UNITE (@PokemonUnite) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonUnite/status/1427979767182102533?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630466/pokemon-unite-pre-register-mobile-ios-android-date-phone-tablet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630466/pokemon-unite-pre-register-mobile-ios-android-date-phone-tablet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T06:38:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T06:38:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung confirms it’s removing ads from its stock apps later this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung’s One UI on the Galaxy S21 Ultra" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PIC6twemoCU-toVQEoHayEe1l_k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69740638/vpavic_210119_4377_0157.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The $1,199 Galaxy S21 Ultra, which showed ads in its default apps.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f39xKq"&gt;Samsung has confirmed that it will stop showing ads in default apps including Samsung Weather, Samsung Pay, and Samsung Theme. It follows comments made by its mobile chief TM Roh in an internal town hall meeting &lt;a href="https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20210817140800017"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Yonhap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “Samsung has made a decision to cease the advertisement on proprietary apps including Samsung Weather, Samsung Pay, and Samsung Theme,” the company said in a statement given to &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; “The update will be ready by later this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ObzCj"&gt;“Our priority is to deliver innovative mobile experiences for our consumers based on their needs and wants,” the company said. “We value feedback from our users and continue our commitment to provide them with the best possible experience from our Galaxy products and services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="J6jD8T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Samsung has made a decision to cease the advertisement on proprietary apps”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ypoQ1j"&gt;In our review of this year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;, we said it was unforgivable that Samsung would choose to show the “kind of ad that’s normally at the bottom of a crappy, overloaded website” in its default weather app. Yes, it’s been possible to dodge or disable these ads and switch to non-Samsung versions of each app, but you shouldn’t be expected to have to do that after spending $1,199 on a flagship smartphone. They’re part of the reason why Samsung’s otherwise clean One UI software has started to feel messy over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2xeRB"&gt;Samsung did not share a specific date for when the ads would be removed from its software, but &lt;em&gt;Yonhap &lt;/em&gt;previously reported that the change will be made via a forthcoming One UI software update. &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/08/17/samsung-ads-removal-report/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; has published&lt;/a&gt; a collection of screenshots if you want to see just how bad Samsung’s apps currently look.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630332/samsung-ads-default-stock-apps-weather-pay-theme-confirmed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630332/samsung-ads-default-stock-apps-weather-pay-theme-confirmed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T05:00:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T05:00:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus updates its overkill gaming phones with Qualcomm’s new overkill processor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Rzppsh87OfdfCkOC3FJDdPovzE=/0x0:1145x763/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69740485/msedge_5BtFPuHiJl.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ROG Phone 5S Pro has a small display on its rear.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jQXU7w"&gt;When you’re selling high-spec gaming-focused phones, it makes sense to have the most powerful processor possible. At least, that’s the only explanation I can come up with for why Asus would announce its new Snapdragon 888 Plus-powered ROG Phone 5S lineup, just months after releasing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;the original ROG Phone 5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XnwlOA"&gt;There are two new S-branded phones, the &lt;a href="https://rog.asus.com/phones/rog-phone-5s-model/"&gt;ROG Phone 5S&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://rog.asus.com/phones/rog-phone-5s-pro-model/"&gt;ROG Phone 5S Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Aside from its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22550723/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-plus-cpu-ai-performance-mwc-2021"&gt;888 Plus processor&lt;/a&gt;, more responsive 360Hz touch-sampling rate, and increased &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.asus.com%2Ftw%2FMobile%2FPhones%2FROG-Phone%2Ffilter%3FSeries%3DROG-Phone&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F18%2F22630283%2Fasus-rog-phone-5s-pro-gaming-smartphone-android-price-release-date-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;maximums of 18GB RAM and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt;, the 5S appears to be &lt;a href="https://rog.asus.com/compareresult?productline=phones&amp;amp;webpathname=ROG-Phone-5s,ROG-Phone-5&amp;amp;id=130291,120644"&gt;a very similar device to the ROG Phone 5&lt;/a&gt;. That means it’s also got a 6.78-inch 144Hz display, 6,000 mAh battery, and triple rear cameras with a 64-megapixel main sensor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xOQSRu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Both feature more responsive displays&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U1uY3d"&gt;The ROG Phone 5S Pro is a similar upgrade. It’s also been bumped up to the 888 Plus, has the same faster touch-sampling rate, and up to 18GB of RAM. Otherwise this is a very similar gaming-focused phone to the 5 Pro, complete with neat additions like extra touch sensors on its back and side to offer more controls while gaming. Check out our review of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;ROG Phone 5 Ultimate&lt;/a&gt; from earlier this year for an idea of how these features work in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhIeyg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2021/08/16/asus-rog-phone-5s-5s-pro-launched-18gb-ram-snapdragon-888-plus/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Gizmochina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the two new phones are only available to order in the Taiwanese market for now, where they’ll ship next week on August 24th. The Asus ROG Phone 5S starts at NT$ 29,990 (around $991), while the 5S Pro starts at NT$ 37,990 (around $1,364). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FQFtGV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lcb8xN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630283/asus-rog-phone-5s-pro-gaming-smartphone-android-price-release-date-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630283/asus-rog-phone-5s-pro-gaming-smartphone-android-price-release-date-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-17T16:43:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-17T16:43:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>There’s still a place for the Note in Samsung’s Galaxy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung has filled out its S-Pen ecosystem of apps nicely." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/avsTsud09fJpQdJ5U6vR6EzyvvU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69738502/dbohn_201004_4226_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wJ5Xmw"&gt;For the first time in many years, August will come and go without the introduction of a new Galaxy Note smartphone from Samsung. Instead, with their lower prices and improved durability, the company is giving its latest foldables — the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617206/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-features-specs-price-hands-on"&gt;Galaxy Z Fold 3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617226/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-features-price-foldable-hands-on"&gt;Galaxy Z Flip 3&lt;/a&gt; — a firm push into the mainstream phone market. With the Z Flip selling for a penny under $1,000, it’s certain to stand out from the iPhone and Samsung’s own Galaxy S21 devices that cost a similar amount (or more).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjvXvv"&gt;But for repeat buyers of Notes past and present, it does feel like there’s something missing. We’re talking about the brand that established Samsung as the leading manufacturer of huge phones. Yet the company has completely skipped producing a new Note this year and has tried to explain it away with a simple “not this time around.” For now, the lineup isn’t gone; last year’s Note 20 and Note 20 Ultra will remain for sale in 2021. The latter remains a legitimately excellent phone today, so even with Samsung hitting pause for a year, at least there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HeKddK"&gt;Samsung’s stance on the Note’s future is vague enough that it leaves room for an eventual return &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620397/samsung-fold-flip-future-galaxy-s-past"&gt;if foldables don’t become the next big thing&lt;/a&gt;. But I’d argue that at least one traditional Galaxy phone with a stylus should remain in the company’s plans regardless. It’s too soon to move on from everything that Samsung was doing so right, and tacking S Pen support onto its other flagship phones doesn’t quite live up to the Note’s legacy. And there are several reasons for the company to give it another go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PmckpE"&gt;People seem to like stylus phones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UJXu2I"&gt;The Note is no doubt the de facto stylus smartphone, but other companies have also found success. Motorola has said the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/16/21222512/moto-g-stylus-power-review-price-features-specs-android-10-camera"&gt;Moto G Stylus&lt;/a&gt; quickly became the most popular device in the G-series after its release, and that was enough for the company to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22538663/motorola-moto-g-stylus-5g-review-specs-screen-price"&gt;produce a 5G-capable sequel&lt;/a&gt; this year. And before LG’s complete exit from the smartphone market, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301223/lg-stylo-6-review"&gt;its Stylo phones&lt;/a&gt; were some of its more popular mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkdzYW"&gt;You can’t overstate the importance of a built-in silo for storing the stylus away when it’s not being used. On the Note, the S Pen is there when you need it — for drawing, signing a PDF, or whatever else — and then it’s gone and completely unobtrusive when you don’t. No add-ons or special phone cases required. Those latter solutions only add friction that can take away from the whole appeal. Using a phone case is perfectly fine, and most people do, but trying to incorporate a stylus slot there is far from ideal if you’ve got normal-sized hands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZAfKgY"&gt;The Note deserves a better swan song than the Note 20&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MEFoBH"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21372109/samsung-galaxy-note-20-ultra-review-camera-price-photos-s-pen-notes"&gt;Galaxy Note 20 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; was true to the line’s usual recipe of stellar build quality, high-end specs, and a giant screen. But the regular Note 20 was a poorly executed misfire. Samsung’s strategy of pursuing a slightly lower price point made sense, but there were enough compromises with last year’s regular Note that it was difficult to recommend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NitFnM"&gt;Most glaring of all was that it had a 60Hz display, when even cheaper Samsung phones like the Galaxy S20 FE had evolved to smoother refresh rates. The cameras were worse, it had a plastic back, and all of these tradeoffs were made to reach a still-expensive price of $999.99. In the eyes of many Note fans, it was a frustrating mismatch, and they rejected the Note 20 for it. Marques Brownlee went so far as to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Exk34o-MMIE"&gt;call it the “Nope 20.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nEbqoh"&gt;This was particularly disappointing after Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20845028/samsung-galaxy-note-10-review-s-pen-camera-specs-features-price"&gt;got it right the year prior with the Note 10&lt;/a&gt;, which wasn’t saddled with the same number of disappointing concessions. That device felt like it was meant to be a mini version of the larger, flagship Note 10 Plus. But the Note 20 came off more as an example of what happens when a company cuts too many corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Pgg2cE"&gt;A case is an imperfect solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="REO0KF"&gt;Samsung hyped the addition of S Pen support when it announced the Galaxy Ultra S21 earlier this year. And the experience of &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; the stylus seems to be on par with a Note. But then you’ve got to &lt;em&gt;put&lt;/em&gt; it somewhere, and that’s where there’s no substitute for an actual Note. Without a designated slot on the phone itself, Samsung’s solution was to make a case that could keep the S21 Ultra and S Pen together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PryxSk"&gt;However, it came with a downside: worse ergonomics. As Dieter wrote in his &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;S21 Ultra review&lt;/a&gt;, the phone can feel more manageable in your hands than an iPhone 12 Pro Max because it’s taller and narrower. That easier-to-hold advantage is diminished somewhat by Samsung’s silicone case for the S Pen. Since there’s a permanent holding spot for the stylus on the case’s left side, the device is noticeably larger.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xBtMX0cXBulzWbcDrZk12pk-S1A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788254/2D9400D9_EDF5_4457_B7EF_1DAB684961DE.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung bundled the S Pen with a case for the S21 Ultra.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kgCiau"&gt;For the Z Fold 3, Samsung came up with a case design that places a holster at the hinge. I think this will work out better, since the Fold is more narrow than most smartphones (including the S21 Ultra) when closed — so it won’t feel as unwieldy even with the added space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P9L1q7"&gt;But unless third-party case makers come up with their own options, you’ll be limited to that one specific Samsung case if you want to carry the S Pen with minimal risk of it being lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tNbHhi"&gt;Selling the S Pen separately makes it feel like an afterthought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8x3gkZ"&gt;Even though it went to the trouble of creating a “Fold Edition” S Pen with a retracting spring tip, Samsung won’t be bundling that with its latest flagship foldable. Rather, you’ve got to buy it (or the pricier S Pen Pro) separately. The Fold Edition comes bundled with its specially designed case for $79, while the S Pen Pro is sold standalone for $99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="42tNGI"&gt;An S Pen still comes included with many of Samsung’s latest tablets and laptops. But making it an added purchase on top of the $1,800 Z Fold 3 will probably lead some people to pass on it entirely. If the Fold is meant to usher in a new era of smartphone productivity, why not toss the Fold Edition stylus and case in the box? Maybe that’d ease the sting of not getting a phone charger, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tuuVsG"&gt;Another Samsung stylus phone could be great if done right&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="e68mX2"&gt;I hope that last year’s models won’t be the end of the line for the Galaxy Note. Samsung still hasn’t come up with an alternative that matches the coherence and convenience of a phone designed with the stylus in mind from the very beginning. But where should the company go from here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrc7lm"&gt;I could see Samsung choosing the “special edition” route (think Apple’s iPhone SE, but high end) and releasing a new, top-spec Note every few years for the diehard fans that will pay top dollar for their giant slab of glass and S Pen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aon35j"&gt;But an even better development would be if the stylus trickled down to at least one of Samsung’s popular A-series phones and brought more people into the experience — for much less money. That’d be a clear sign that Samsung is committed to the S Pen, even if the Galaxy Note itself remains on hiatus. The benefits of a stylus shouldn’t be reserved for the $1,000-and-up tier. You’d want a high refresh display since that does genuinely improve the responsiveness of drawing and note-taking. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"&gt;The Galaxy A52 already checks off that box&lt;/a&gt;, so we know it’s possible even if the company wants to keep costs down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W8BfJJ"&gt;Part of the problem with the Note 20 was Samsung’s messaging: it tried to pass off midrange hardware as something more premium. The pushback and so-so reviews shouldn’t have come as a surprise. But Samsung wouldn’t need to over-sell a Galaxy A-series phone with a stylus: it could be a hit all on its own merits. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22627058/samsung-galaxy-note-stylus-z-fold-3-a-series"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22627058/samsung-galaxy-note-stylus-z-fold-3-a-series</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-17T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-17T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Google Pixel 6 won’t ship with a charger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro lineup" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WWtKPEFDCN0HQefeC0SXQdK8RF0=/448x0:7198x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69736930/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google joins Apple and Samsung by ditching the in-box charger.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hXmmGZ"&gt;Google is the latest manufacturer to bid farewell to the in-box charging brick, saying it expects the Pixel 5A will be the last phone to include one. That means the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; won’t include one when they arrive this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yWjePu"&gt;The company says that most people already have a USB-C charging brick, so there’s no longer a need to include one with its phones. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231954/samsung-to-gradually-remove-chargers-earbuds-from-future-phones"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; made similar arguments when they announced they would no longer be offering an in-box charger. That may be true, but it’s likely that the cost savings of not including a charger played a big role in those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TBzBgs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google Pixel 5A review: boring, but better than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/e/22392246"},{"title":"This is the Pixel 6","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TamQFmgoPzsQwYDmuZj0BqSq-WM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22781448/ajohnson_210813_4713_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google says it expects the Pixel 5A to be the last phone to include the charger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aAa6hI"&gt;There’s also an environmental argument for ditching the charger: fewer redundant chargers being shipped to customers theoretically reduces e-waste. That’s tough to prove, though, and potentially just means that the greenhouse gas emissions of producing and shipping accessory chargers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519466/apple-iphone-12-chargers-airpods-greenhouse-gas-emissions-e-waste"&gt;will be spread around between more companies&lt;/a&gt; as people buy them from third-party manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vxa6t"&gt;One thing seems certain, though: with these three major phone manufacturers committed to removing the charger, smaller companies will have an easier time following suit and doing the same. While phone shoppers may feel like it’s a case of paying the same price and getting less, this is likely a reality that we’ll all have to make peace with, so hold your wall chargers tight.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628702/google-pixel-6-charger-not-included"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628702/google-pixel-6-charger-not-included</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-17T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-17T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Pixel 5A comes with a bigger battery and screen, smaller price tag</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vCRMtLNtw-FxlEYDSAOV8ZwR-_I=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69736882/Pixel_5a_5G_Product_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Google Pixel 5A features a 6.34-inch display and IP67 water-resistance rating.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LVJd9p"&gt;Google has officially revealed the Pixel 5A 5G, a phone it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;kind of announced in April&lt;/a&gt; to contradict rumors that it had been canceled. It comes with a short list of updated features compared to its 4A 5G predecessor, including a slightly bigger screen, a much bigger battery, and an IP67 rating for water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2UkhGL"&gt;Few though they may be, these are some important tweaks to an already good midrange phone, and the best part is that the price has gotten smaller: in the US it will cost $449, which is $50 less than the Pixel 4A 5G’s introductory price. The 5A goes on sale in the US and Japan on August 26th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dLQBUh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google Pixel 5A review: boring, but better than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/e/22392246"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dUk7QBzrXEbAutV8xElm6bDgbU8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22786010/Pixel_5a_5G_Lifestyle_Charging__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 5A supports wired charging only, and Google says it’s the last Pixel phone that will ship with a charger in the box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dFP4Ys"&gt;The Pixel 5A’s screen gets a slight boost to 6.34 inches, a small increase over the 4A 5G’s 6.2-inch display. It’s still a 1080p OLED with a standard 60Hz refresh rate, despite rumors of a faster 90Hz display. The battery gets an increase to 4,680mAh, up from 3,885mAh, which Google says will last through a full day of typical use or two days using Extreme Battery Saver mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94D0WL"&gt;The 5A is also the first A-series Pixel to get an official water resistance rating. With IP67 protection, the phone is able to withstand immersion in up to three feet of water for up to 30 minutes. That’s an uncommon feature in the under-$500 class where IP ratings are scarce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KozyrT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10704284"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xagOMn"&gt;The Pixel 5A works on all major US carrier networks and continues to offer support for sub-6GHz 5G. Unlike last year, Google will not sell a mmWave-compatible version of the phone. That’s no great loss — mmWave 5G is very fast, but range is highly limited and hard to find. Unfortunately, the 5A is also missing support for C-band 5G frequencies, which Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T will start using at the end of this year to bolster their struggling nationwide 5G networks. Google says it could add the necessary software support later, but won’t commit to doing so at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9NKf7G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the Google Pixel 5 won’t be sold through any of the major wireless carriers in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b0wE2W"&gt;Other specs remain unchanged from the previous model. It still uses a Snapdragon 765G chipset with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage. The 12.2-megapixel main and 16-megapixel ultrawide rear cameras and 8-megapixel selfie camera are the same. There’s a rear fingerprint scanner for biometric unlock, an honest-to-god headphone jack, and an 18W charger included in the box (Google says this will be the last Pixel phone to offer one). The phone will ship with Android 11 and is guaranteed Google’s standard three years of OS platform updates and security patch support. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/08GvuipPmUn5G-8Opsns7neL2YM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22786075/Pixel_5a_5G_Cases_Lineup.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Case options for the Google Pixel 5A.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tZCRck"&gt;Unlike the 4A 5G, the Google Pixel 5 won’t be sold through any of the major wireless carriers in the US. Instead, it’ll be offered directly from the Google Store and through Google Fi. It will be sold in just one finish — “mostly black” — with four colorful case options available separately to spice things up.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22627253/google-pixel-5a-specs-price-screen-battery-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22627253/google-pixel-5a-specs-price-screen-battery-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
