<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-10T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-10T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-10T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The search is over: smart trackers from Apple, Samsung, and Tile compared</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It’s never been easier to keep track of your keys&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Yn4hTB"&gt;This year will go down in history as the year we entered the golden age of Not Losing Your Stuff. Well, in addition to some other historic milestones, somewhere in the top 100 hits of the year will be the introduction of smart tracker tags from two major mobile device manufacturers: Samsung and Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1LL5zg"&gt;Tracking tags have been around for a while now, and Tile has been the best-known brand in the space. With new options from the two most popular US phone manufacturers entering the picture, tracking tags may be poised to go mainstream. If you’re thinking of picking one up but unsure where to start, then you’re in the right place. We tried out three top tracking tags — the Samsung SmartTag Plus, Apple AirTag, and Tile Pro — to see how they compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xXXOP8"&gt;First, a word about the very real privacy concerns about these tracking devices. Since their introduction, critics have noted that they could all too easily be used as tools for stalkers, since they’re easy to hide in someone’s bag or car. These concerns were amplified when Apple’s AirTags arrived, given how ubiquitous Apple’s Find My network is. Apple built in certain anti-stalking safety measures at launch, but &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-best-thing-about-apples-airtags-is-also-the-scaries-1846786338"&gt;reporters quickly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/05/05/apple-airtags-stalking/"&gt;identified ways&lt;/a&gt; that these safeguards fell short. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="CXhCa4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With new options from the two most popular US phone manufacturers, tracking tags may be poised to go mainstream&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2AwmYL"&gt;The company has addressed some issues, like shortening the length of time before an AirTag will sound an alert when it’s separated from its owner, and is working on an app that will allow Android users to find unwanted AirTags near them. But some potential for misuse will remain even with more safety measures in place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="au3ILG"&gt;Apple (justifiably) attracts more scrutiny for its safety practices given the size and effectiveness of its tracking network, but it’s hardly alone in its somewhat reactive attitude toward stalking concerns. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392924/samsung-smartags-tracker-bixby-privacy-smartthings"&gt;Samsung introduced a SmartThings app feature&lt;/a&gt; that scans for unfamiliar SmartTags, and Tile says it’s working on a similar feature. It doesn’t help that these devices more or less live inside their own manufacturer’s walled garden — a unified, cross-platform approach is sorely needed. Anyway, it’s illegal (and highly immoral) to track someone without their knowledge, so don’t do it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ayjCuN"&gt;Per usual, adding new tech to your life involves more terms and conditions to agree to. However, in this case you may have already accepted them when you set up your Apple or Samsung phone. Tile’s app, which you must download to use the Pro, presents its own separate set of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thetileapp.com%2Fen-us%2Fterms-of-service&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22570161%2Fapple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pfRRvwHF0x2ZIq0H7G1fIytsSkI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22702210/ajohnson_210702_4659_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tile has been the best-known brand in the tracking tag space until now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="vB8PcA"&gt;Personal trackers are nothing new — GPS and cellular options have been around for quite some time, and offer more precise, real-time location tracking. They also tend to come with a higher price tag, recurring subscription or wireless data fees, and require more battery power. This newer class of Bluetooth trackers are more practical for most people, with battery life measured in months rather than days and smaller, keyring-friendly form factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YhiUx0"&gt;Essentially, the three tags compared here all do the same thing. Pair it to your phone, attach it to something you want to keep track of, and you’re ready to go. When the tracker is within Bluetooth range of your phone, you can have the tag play a sound to help locate it. All three devices support out-of-range finding with their own particular device user networks, and they all include the same kind of user-replaceable CR2032 coin cell battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlEXn2"&gt;Their main difference is whether or not they include AR-assisted finding by way of Ultra Wideband (UWB) connectivity: the Samsung and Apple tags have this and the Tile Pro does not. To take advantage of the AR feature, you’ll need a phone with UWB; on the Apple side that’s an iPhone 11 or newer, and for Samsung it’s a Galaxy Note 20 Ultra, Z Fold 2, S21 Plus, or S21 Ultra. There are also compatibility differences: Apple’s tracker only works with iOS devices and Samsung’s only works with Galaxy devices (no, you can’t register it through the SmartThings iOS app, I tried), whereas Tile works on both iOS and Android.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OMzWKLcxkNQ7oNoAy-D1TFh941U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22702209/ajohnson_210702_4659_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirTag is the least expensive of the bunch, but without a built-in keyring hole you may need to buy a holder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KkUjYi"&gt;Apple AirTag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="K8LyRt"&gt;The AirTag comes in just one flavor: a small, $29 disc shape. It’s the only one of the three to include an official IP67 rating, meaning it can survive a dunk in a bit of water. It also allows you to store your contact information so it can be read by any phone with NFC (near-field communication) — even Android phones. Setup is dead simple — just bring the tag near your iPhone and you’ll be prompted to pair the two. It’s also a little less expensive than the other two, but there’s no hole built in, so if you want to attach it to a set of keys you’ll need to pay a little more to add a holder. (We don’t really recommend drilling a hole into it, though &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FGuide%2FHow%2Bto%2BDrill%2Ba%2BKeyring%2BHole%2Bin%2Ban%2BAirTag%2F143068&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22570161%2Fapple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iFixit has a guide&lt;/a&gt; if you insist.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="S0KD9T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10644655"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OP3rsJ"&gt;When it’s outside the Bluetooth range of your phone, the AirTag taps into the massive network of iPhone devices using Find My to provide an approximate location. This is a huge benefit, especially in the US where iPhones abound. As long as your item is in a place with &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;, it will likely be “seen” by an iPhone nearby. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XmpgHp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As long as your item is in a place with &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;, it will likely be “seen” by an iPhone nearby&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nkECyk"&gt;In-range, AR-assisted finding does a good job of tracking down an object that’s out of sight. A big, easy-to-follow arrow appears on screen when the signal is strong enough (you’ll be prompted with a vague message to move around if you’re too far for a strong signal) and guides you in the right direction. I had no problem locating a tag under a couch cushion in my house. It would be helpful if the “weak signal” message indicated if the signal got stronger as you move around (Samsung’s AR finding does this) but that’s my only complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0q41aP"&gt;If you’d like to altogether avoid the headache of leaving something behind, Apple is adding a separation alert feature in iOS 15 that may help. Once set up, it will send a notification if it detects that your iPhone (and by extension, you) have gone out of range and left it behind. Tile also offers this feature with its Premium subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Zu4DCPNye2enQZo0XfHl_FbQL0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22702211/ajohnson_210702_4659_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartTag Plus includes AR-assisted finding for objects in close range.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="07bZ8a"&gt;Samsung SmartTag Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="dHJGkw"&gt;The $39 SmartTag Plus is Samsung’s UWB-equipped tag; there’s also a non-UWB version for $10 less. The SmartTag Plus offers broadly similar Bluetooth-range finding and AR-assist as the AirTag, with a few differences. AR finding mode provides a view through the phone’s camera with guiding arrows that appear on the screen, which is a little more helpful than Apple’s arrow-only guide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="doXMn8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10644672"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vDi1au"&gt;You can also use the button on a SmartTag as a kind of remote starter for smart home automations if you’re invested in Samsung’s SmartThings ecosystem. On the downside, the SmartTag has the shortest battery life rating of the three trackers compared here: up to 165 days (less than six months) compared to about a year for the Tile and Apple options. SmartTags don’t offer separation alerts at the moment either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="QZmIv6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the SmartTag gave me an accurate enough location that I could have driven up I-5 myself and located the tag&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yBoLCQ"&gt;Out-of-range, the SmartTag Plus relies on other Galaxy devices that have chosen to participate in Samsung’s Galaxy Find network — Galaxy phone users aren’t opted in by default, and need to give consent in the SmartThings app. Samsung says that as of April 2021, there were &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1745743505176533597" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;more than 70 million “helper devices” participating globally&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F04%2Fapples-find-my-network-now-offers-new-third-party-finding-experiences%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22570161%2Fapple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple counts hundreds of millions of users&lt;/a&gt; in its Find My network. There are simply fewer people in the US with Galaxy phones than iPhones, so it can’t quite compete with the AirTag, but that’s a moot point anyway since nobody is likely to be comparison shopping between the two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c2tdm2"&gt;Experiences will vary — more so than with an AirTag — but at least in the northern suburbs of Seattle, there were enough Galaxy Find users out and about to track a tag on a cross-town journey with multiple stops. Knowing the actual location of the object, er, spouse who agreed to let me track him, the SmartTag did identify his position accurately at two of three stops. It only returned a location a couple of times when he was on the interstate getting to his destination, but in a fairly busy business park and at a restaurant, the SmartTag gave me an accurate enough location that I could have driven up I-5 myself and located the tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eNM85lo7N16YWsKU7QsiGNbEksk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22702206/ajohnson_210702_4659_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tile’s tags work with both iOS and Android devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="quRzYe"&gt;Tile Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="6mesvM"&gt;Tile has been the tracking tag category heavyweight of the last few years — at least until Samsung and Apple showed up. The Pro is the company’s highest-specced model at $34, with a bigger Bluetooth range (400 feet) and a louder maximum ring volume than other current Tile tags. There’s no Ultra Wideband here, and thus no AR-assisted finding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yAgNuq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10644691"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="btTY78"&gt;Separation alerts are available as part of Tile’s $29/year Premium subscription, but all of the essential features are included with your Tile tag purchase, including out-of-range finding. This “community find” feature relies on other Tile users — and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424837/tile-amazon-sidewalk-support-release-date-2021-bluetooth-tracking-airtags" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;as of June 14th, Amazon’s Sidewalk network&lt;/a&gt; — the way Samsung and Apple’s trackers rely on other Galaxy phones and iPhones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8WzYkQ"&gt;Even with help from Sidewalk, the Tile Pro’s peer-location network seems to lag behind Samsung and Apple’s. On the same journey up I-5 that the SmartTag Plus took, the Tile Pro returned a location ping less frequently, and only got one of the stops on the trip precisely right (it was close but across the street on another one) where the SmartTag was accurate on two locations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="mUmqjJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Even with help from Sidewalk, the Tile Pro’s peer-location network seems to lag behind Samsung and Apple’s&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8OJlei"&gt;This was honestly a better performance than I was expecting, though Seattle probably has more than its usual share of Sidewalk-supporting Amazon devices for obvious reasons. Even if it’s an atypical result, it’s fair to say that the community find feature would work well enough to tell you that you really &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; lose something, even if it’s less likely that you’ll be able to hunt down its exact location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xbsdOV"&gt;I do have one minor complaint to lodge against the Tile app: the subscription upsell. A couple of app menus include features that are only available with the Premium plan, and tapping them brings up a page prompting you to start a free trial to access them. I expect to see those kinds of things during setup, or if I’m using a free app like Strava, but it’s a little annoying from something I’ve already paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlbF1T"&gt;Tile also offers its trackers in a couple of different form factors, including a wallet-friendly Slim version and a small adhesive-backed Sticker tag. There are plenty of third-party cases and holders for AirTags in particular if you want to adapt it for different objects, but you can’t buy an AirTag or a SmartTag in a fundamentally different shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="btAqHr"&gt;AirTag or Tile Pro?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XqsNHq"&gt;If you have an iPhone, there’s a very simple answer to this question: just get the AirTag. The Apple Find My network is so extensive (at least in the US) that you’ll have the best chance of tracking down something the tag is attached to. Maybe there’s an exception to this recommendation if you really want Tile’s subscription features or mix of form factors, but by and large this is a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RWH2Kx"&gt;SmartTag Plus or Tile Pro?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pbD9SM"&gt;If you have a Samsung phone you’ll probably be better off with the SmartTag Plus. The Galaxy Find network isn’t as robust as Apple’s, but it’s still ahead of Tile’s. If you already use smart home devices in Samsung’s SmartThings network, then there’s even more reason to choose SmartTag since it can act as a remote control for automations. The shorter battery life is a shame and the lack of separation notifications stinks, so if those are sticking points you could consider the Tile Pro. Otherwise, the SmartTag Plus (or non-UWB version, depending on your phone) is the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YS3j0F"&gt;Tile or… ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FHfboY"&gt;If you don’t have an iPhone or a Galaxy device, your choice is between the Tile Pro and… everything else. Tile’s out-of-range network can’t compete with the number of devices Samsung and Apple have in our pockets, but it seems to be getting a healthy boost from Sidewalk, and can only get better as more people add Echo and Ring devices to their homes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="7nh3V8"&gt;If community finding features are less important, &lt;a href="https://chipolo.net/en/pages/products" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chipolo is worth a look&lt;/a&gt;. We didn’t test it in this batch, but it does include separation notifications without an annual fee. Overall, the Tile Pro feels like a good compromise between paying for something more expensive and power-intensive like a cellular tracker, or a more basic, Bluetooth-only tracker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ohQ20t"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22570161/apple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22570161/apple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-09T06:51:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-09T06:51:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>FCC listing suggests Google’s midrange Pixel 5A 5G could arrive soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Pixel 4A 5G. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1vItYDZyWz3VU7JuzK7brdMDv_c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69560207/akrales_201013_4137_0244.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last year’s Pixel 4A 5G.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jhqppv"&gt;The Pixel 5A 5G, Google’s midrange counterpart to last year’s Pixel 5, has been spotted in the &lt;a href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&amp;amp;RequestTimeout=500&amp;amp;calledFromFrame=Y&amp;amp;application_id=oAxfJo9QrxqKKX41nUtsiA%3D%3D&amp;amp;fcc_id=A4RG1F8F"&gt;FCC’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&amp;amp;RequestTimeout=500&amp;amp;calledFromFrame=Y&amp;amp;application_id=oAxfJo9QrxqKKX41nUtsiA%3D%3D&amp;amp;fcc_id=A4RG4S1M"&gt;database&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting a release might not be far away. &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/07/08/pixel-5a-makes-a-stop-at-the-fcc-before-heading-to-your-pocket/#disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which first saw the two listings, reports that none specifically mention the name “Pixel 5A” but that at least one of the three model numbers (GR0M2) lines up with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1372276648784060426"&gt;previous reports&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;barely announced&lt;/a&gt; phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wwUsjO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; speculates that one of the models (G1F8F) is the version of the phone destined for release in the US based on its wireless frequency bands, but reports that this version doesn’t offer support for mmWave 5G networks. In contrast, the Pixel 4A 5G offered mmWave support when used with compatible carriers. The other two models could be the phone’s international versions&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Nh1UQI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s expected to be powered by a Snapdragon 765G&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PxxJmC"&gt;Otherwise the listings don’t offer many new details compared to what’s already been rumored about the phone. The Pixel 5a will reportedly be powered by a &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/21/google-pixel-5a-5g-chip/"&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 765G&lt;/a&gt; processor, will be equipped with a &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/22/google-pixel-5a-renders-leak/"&gt;6.2-inch OLED 1080p display&lt;/a&gt;, and will include a headphone jack like Google’s previous A-series Pixels. Two rear cameras are expected — a main camera and an ultrawide — based on the recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403350/pixel-5a-leaked-camera-sample-ultrawide-12-2-megapixel-f-2-2-exif-data"&gt;leak of an ultrawide camera shot&lt;/a&gt; apparently taken by the unreleased phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1uTanV"&gt;The big question now is when we’ll see Google officially detail the phone beyond simply confirming it exists. When it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;pre-announced the phone earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; in response to rumors it had been cancelled, Google didn’t give an exact release date, and merely said it would be coming “later this year.” It would also only officially confirm a release in the US and Japan but, as &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; notes, it would be strange to produce two international versions of the handset if Japan is the only non-US market for the device. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22569798/google-pixel-5a-fcc-listing-leak-features-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22569798/google-pixel-5a-fcc-listing-leak-features-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-08T17:18:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-08T17:18:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s $1,500 smartphone is for its biggest fans with more money than sense</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XGI-NKPrdzpQ8oC1JiKE3Hhh9Jc=/159x0:1794x1090/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69558412/Screen_Shot_2021_07_08_at_4.32.08_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nHjlp0"&gt;Qualcomm — the company behind the Snapdragon processors and modems that power almost every major Android smartphone — is &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/snapdragoninsiders/news-forums/get-ready-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-designed-you-mind"&gt;making its own phone&lt;/a&gt;. Or rather, the company is partnering with Asus on a custom device officially called the “&lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/snapdragoninsiders/smartphone"&gt;Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders&lt;/a&gt;,” a $1,500 phone that’s designed to showcase the chip company’s technology. And, as the name suggests, Qualcomm will be selling the phone directly to members of its &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/onq/2021/03/01/welcome-snapdragon-insiders-our-new-community-tech-enthusiasts-who-deserve"&gt;Snapdragon Insider fan community&lt;/a&gt;, which Qualcomm launched earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iV2uV2"&gt;It’s an interesting idea, but unfortunately, the Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders doesn’t look like it does anything different, when it comes to actually taking advantage of Qualcomm’s technology, than any other Android flagship — which is particularly disappointing given the $1,500 price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7lcXyO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A standard flagship spec sheet&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wd5udE"&gt;The spec sheet here follows with what you’d expect from a flagship Android phone in 2021: the Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders runs Android 11, has 512GB of storage, 16GB of RAM, a 6.78-inch, 144Hz Samsung OLED panel with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21335252/corning-gorilla-glass-victus-drop-scratch-resistant-apple-samsung"&gt;Gorilla Glass Victus&lt;/a&gt;, and a rear fingerprint scanner (using Qualcomm’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223494/qualcomm-ultrasonic-fingerprint-reader-samsung-galaxy-s21-announcement"&gt;3D Sonic Sensor Gen 2&lt;/a&gt; technology, of course.) If any of that sounds familiar, it’s likely because the new Qualcomm-branded device seems to share a lot in common with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;Asus’ ROG Phone 5 Ultimate&lt;/a&gt; from earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="piIxCu"&gt;The processor, naturally, is Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 888, which feels like a curious choice given that the company has already announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22550723/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-plus-cpu-ai-performance-mwc-2021"&gt;more powerful 888 Plus model&lt;/a&gt;. Given the mammoth price tag and the promise of being an ultimate Qualcomm phone, it’s an odd miss for the Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UopcG9"&gt;The battery offers 4,000 mAh of power, and isn’t the biggest we’ve seen in a smartphone, but it does support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/27/21340587/qualcomm-quick-charge-5-standard-usb-c-pd-pps-battery-fast-phones"&gt;Qualcomm’s Quick Charge 5 standard&lt;/a&gt;, although not at its full potential, maxing out at 65W for charging, not the 100W-plus speeds the spec is theoretically capable of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rsM1w1"&gt;The back of the phone features a triple camera setup, with familiar parts from other Asus phones. The main camera features a Sony IMX686 64-megapixel image sensor — the same found in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21408307/asus-zenfone-7-pro-review"&gt;last year’s Zenfone 7 Pro&lt;/a&gt; — while the ultrawide sensor uses an older 12-megapixel Sony IMX363 sensor (also used in previous Asus phones, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496686/pixel-5-camera-comparison-sensor-specs-features"&gt;as well as multiple Google Pixel phones&lt;/a&gt;.) Lastly, there’s an 8-megapixel telephoto lens with 3x optical zoom to round out the camera setup, and a 24-megapixel front-facing camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WcLaBA"&gt;Qualcomm is promising that the triple camera array will offer a “professional-quality camera” experience, but it won’t push the Spectra 580’s triple ISP to its limit, either. While the phone can shoot 8K at 30 frames per second, and 4K at 30 or 60FPS, it can’t manage shooting three simultaneous 4K HDR video streams or shoot three 28-megapixel photos at once — two of the biggest claims Qualcomm made when it introduced the Snapdragon 888 last December. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yVZKo8hdlQ2E-9-aBJOKu3A62wY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22706881/e_BF3KMUZWs_HD.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UJN7QL"&gt;The Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders will be one of the first phones to offer Qualcomm’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313214/qualcomm-snapdragon-sound-announced-high-res-audio"&gt;new Snapdragon Sound classification&lt;/a&gt;, which promises hi-fi music playback at up to 24-bit 96kHz. Qualcomm is also including some Master &amp;amp; Dynamic earbuds in the box to help take advantage of that; what appears to be a pair of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.masterdynamic.com%2Fproducts%2Fmw08-active-noise-cancelling-true-wireless-earphones&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F8%2F22568641%2Fqualcomm-asus-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-technology" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MW08 earbuds&lt;/a&gt; with a Snapdragon logo on them. (Those headphones sell for $299 usually, which may help ease the sting of the $1,499 price tag here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpwYlp"&gt;Another area that the Snapdragon-branded phone might stand out is with 5G support. Qualcomm boasts that the phone will offer “the most comprehensive support for all key 5G sub-6 and mmWavebands and combinations in a single device.” There’s also support for Wi-Fi 6 and Wi-Fi 6E, and Bluetooth 5.2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IlymJ5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An expensive option for Qualcomm fans&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M3jnUc"&gt;In addition to the phone and headphones, Qualcomm is also including a 65W Quick Charge 5.0 charge, USB-C to USB-C and USB-C to USB-A cables, and a rubber bumper for the phone. But even with all that, the Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders looks like a tough sell — there are plenty of top-tier Android phones that offer the same (or better) specs for far less money, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="klyo7T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"},{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra review: the real deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bmCphp"&gt;It’s not even particularly successful at its main job as a Qualcomm showcase: the Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders doesn’t feature the company’s latest and greatest processor, and doesn’t push Qualcomm’s technology further than any other major Android phone. Sure, it does have a glowing Snapdragon logo on the back, but that hardly seems worth the premium Qualcomm is asking its most enthusiastic fans to pay here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pjg0mk"&gt;The Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders will be available this August in the US, China, UK, and Germany to start, with launches for more regions in the works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GvxGYp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568641/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-technology"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568641/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-technology</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-08T14:22:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-08T14:22:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Startup Halo will bring driverless car service to Las Vegas later this year on T-Mobile 5G</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sQ4bVX2CCwAEhHYpxBXBIULu4AQ=/0x23:3000x2023/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69557369/21CM0192_05_060221_1040v2m_sm.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo says it will use remote drivers to operate its vehicles over T-Mobile 5G.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: T-Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GdySA9"&gt;Driverless car startup Halo has announced a new service coming to Las Vegas later this year: a fleet of remotely operated electric vehicles, using T-Mobile’s 5G network. It’s potentially a big step toward fulfilling the promise of 5G remote driver tech, with a significant catch: the cars don’t operate &lt;em&gt;solely&lt;/em&gt; on T-Mobile 5G. While it’s the primary network they’ll use (mid- and low-band 5G, specifically, with LTE as a fallback), they will also rely on other networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pWiKV"&gt;The idea is simple enough: Halo employs remote drivers to operate the vehicles, delivering them to waiting customers who then get behind the wheel and take the car to their destination. When the trip has ended, the car moves on to its next pick-up under remote control. Halo is also currently operating test drives with safety drivers in vehicles, which it says it won’t include when the service launches for paying customers. That’s easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xag8xZ"&gt;There’s no shortage of driverless and autonomous vehicle pilot programs in Las Vegas; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/21/17718018/lyft-aptiv-self-driving-cars-las-vegas-5000-trips"&gt;Lyft has operated a driverless taxi service&lt;/a&gt; in the city, and more recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22291682/motional-fully-driverless-autonomous-cars-las-vegas"&gt;Motional has been testing autonomous rides&lt;/a&gt; without a backup driver behind the wheel. Halo’s service is a little different, using a remote driver, along with an “Advanced Safe Stop” mechanism to automatically bring the car to a halt if a hazard is detected. The company says that ultimately it hopes to achieve full autonomy, and that in the meantime its vehicles are designed to “learn” from their human operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UW4YRK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"I took a gamble by riding in a self-driving Lyft in Las Vegas","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/8/16860590/self-driving-lyft-las-vegas-ces-2018"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="f66CMo"&gt;Fully remote driverless vehicles have been one of the promises of 5G, and it’s a use case that actually demands the speed and low latency that 5G connectivity is capable of delivering. But in the US, at least, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;our networks just haven’t met the bar yet&lt;/a&gt; to make it a reality. This new service is a step in the right direction, but it seems we’re not quite at full 5G remote operation yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zlq7l"&gt;It won’t exactly be a widespread service at first, either. Halo says that it will operate in “urban parts of the Las Vegas Valley” at launch and doesn’t disclose how large of an area it will cover, just that it plans to later expand to more parts of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phRERG"&gt;Oh, and it’s probably a coincidence, but Las Vegas is also set to be the stage for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295777/dish-network-5g-q3-2021"&gt;Dish Network’s first 5G rollout&lt;/a&gt; this summer, a venture that T-Mobile is supposed to be helping to facilitate &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/12/21134278/sprint-tmobile-merger-court-ruling-opinion-decision-explainer-carriers-antitrust"&gt;per its Sprint acquisition deal&lt;/a&gt;. If T-Mobile’s 5G network can indeed support a fleet of remotely operated vehicles, it’ll be thanks in part to the addition of Sprint’s spectrum. Before we get carried away by the possibilities of driverless cars, let’s spare a thought for the fourth wireless carrier we’re still missing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568437/halo-driverless-car-tmobile-5g-las-vegas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568437/halo-driverless-car-tmobile-5g-las-vegas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-08T05:23:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-08T05:23:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus admits to throttling popular apps to save battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro (top) and OnePlus 9" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/huCXNrOJELXUlJp4vIz_9kp-KpQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69554977/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0061_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JbIu1k"&gt;OnePlus has confirmed that it deliberately reduces performance in “many of the most popular apps” in order to improve battery life on its latest OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro phones. The issue arose following &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16794/oneplus-9-performance-examination/"&gt;testing by &lt;em&gt;Anandtech’s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Andrei Frumusanu, who called the situation “rather baffling” after discovering slowdown in a wide range of prominent apps from Google’s Play Store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NLyXdg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anandtech&lt;/em&gt;’s conclusion is that OnePlus is “blacklisting popular applications away from its fastest cores, causing slowdown in typical workloads such as web browsing.” The site tested Chrome and Twitter performance extensively, but concluded that the slowdown “applies to pretty much everything that has any level of popularity in the Play Store.” That’s said to cover all Google apps, all Microsoft Office apps, and all notable social media apps and web browsers, though some complex games like &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt; are reportedly unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="T24grs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zEHInm"&gt;Some phone manufacturers have been caught in the past &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/10/1/4791354/samsung-rigging-benchmark-scores-galaxy-note-3"&gt;artificially boosting performance&lt;/a&gt; so that their devices run unreasonably fast in benchmarks. That isn’t quite what’s happening here; while benchmark apps seem to be running within expectations, it’s the performance of “regular” apps that’s been reduced. Nevertheless, popular testing tool GeekBench &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/geekbench/status/1412433598200823810"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; OnePlus’ approach as “benchmark manipulation” and has removed the OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro from its Android benchmark chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qiwDjh"&gt;OnePlus &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/oneplus-9-pro-performance-throttling-popular-apps/"&gt;confirmed to &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that this is intended behavior designed to improve battery life. Here’s the full statement: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="sT9NBw"&gt;“Our top priority is always delivering a great user experience with our products, based in part on acting quickly on important user feedback. Following the launch of the OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro in March, some users told us about some areas where we could improve the devices’ battery life and heat management. As a result of this feedback, our R&amp;amp;D team has been working over the past few months to optimize the devices’ performance when using many of the most popular apps, including Chrome, by matching the app’s processor requirements with the most appropriate power. This has helped to provide a smooth experience while reducing power consumption. While this may impact the devices’ performance in some benchmarking apps, our focus as always is to do what we can to improve the performance of the device for our users.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jINyzh"&gt;OnePlus’ statement implies that the performance is only affected in benchmark results, which is essentially the opposite of what &lt;em&gt;Anandtech&lt;/em&gt; has found. Unless, of course, the intended user experience is for most popular apps to be slowed down, and the “impact” is on benchmark results that are higher than they ought to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wxXoFe"&gt;It is worth noting that the performance tweaks may well not make much difference to the user’s overall experience. “I wouldn’t blame anybody if they hadn’t necessarily noticed the performance discrepancy — I hadn’t immediately noticed it myself beyond the device’s extremely slow momentum scrolling speed setting,” Frumusanu writes. “However, having it side-by-side to a Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra, or a Xiaomi Mi 11 (Ultra) and paying attention, I do very much notice that the OnePlus 9 Pro is less responsive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgSmJl"&gt;What’s clear is that OnePlus is taking an unusual approach to power management on the 9 Pro — Frumusanu says it “certainly represents the first case of a vendor implementing application and benchmark detection in this manner” — and that’s something you might want to be aware of before dropping the cash on the company’s latest flagship.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568107/oneplus-9-pro-battery-life-app-throttling-benchmarks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568107/oneplus-9-pro-battery-life-app-throttling-benchmarks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T15:38:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T15:38:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android app tests your phone’s waterproof seals without a drop of water</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XCS5gxdAqWXzkLdSSTgiXlDoeXk=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69552625/cat-s60-5945.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Water Resistance Tester is designed to check waterproofing, which can degrade over time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rxsGxm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ray.waterresistancetester"&gt;Water Resistance Tester&lt;/a&gt;, available on the Google Play store and &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/07/07/app-claims-to-test-your-phones-water-resistance-without-a-plunge/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, falls firmly into the category of “neat stuff we didn’t know you could do with an app.” It tests the integrity of your Android phone’s IP67/IP68 rating by accessing the device’s barometer. Just download the free app, follow the prompts to press down firmly on the screen, and you’ll get a swift pass/fail grade. It’s simple, geeky, and practical, which is a combination we love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QgsEMX"&gt;Developer Ray Wang says he created the app to help people check the state of their devices’ waterproof sealing after a repair or as it degrades over time. Obviously, don’t take a passing grade as a free pass to chuck your phone into a lake. That said, it appears to work reliably, based on &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/samsung/comments/oev1rt/app_water_resistance_tester_app/"&gt;feedback from Reddit users&lt;/a&gt; and Play store reviewers — as well as our own quick testing. An IP68-rated Galaxy Note 20 Ultra passed the test at first, but when we popped out the SIM card tray, it failed — as you’d expect. A TCL 20 Pro 5G, which has no IP rating, failed. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P6q89K60ouf5x0LGd_Onz3YT2p8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22704069/water_resist_screens.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In our testing, a TCL phone (left) without an IP rating failed, as expected, while the IP68-rated Galaxy Note 20 Ultra (middle and right) passed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="43xJs7"&gt;This app &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/search?q=waterproof%20test&amp;amp;c=apps&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;isn’t the first of its kind&lt;/a&gt;, but some of the existing waterproof test apps on the Play store appear to have been designed for older phones with a different style of waterproofing than used in phones today, and may not work accurately now, according to user reviews. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFMhNp"&gt;In any case, this new app seems to work well, and it’s free unless you want to tip the developer $1 to remove a small ad at the bottom of the screen. Not a bad price to pay for a little bit of geeky fun.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567127/water-resistance-tester-app-android-sealing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567127/water-resistance-tester-app-android-sealing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T13:43:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T13:43:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon has its own version of spatial audio and it’s already pushing it on phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XdA7Nx_txiaOx-y7u2tg4yvul0g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69552002/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h7fivc"&gt;You know spatial audio is having quite a moment when wireless carriers decide to create their own implementations of it. Verizon has announced a new sound feature it’s calling “Verizon Adaptive Sound,” and the company claims it “produces a brilliant spatial surround experience regardless of what headphone, soundbar, or earbud brand you use or what application you’re watching or listening to.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNuXwO"&gt;The audio trick, which Verizon says has been in the works since 2019, is coming to Motorola phones first, including the new Motorola One 5G UW Ace that goes on sale July 8th. The Motorola Edge Plus also just received a firmware update that seems to add this feature, &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/07/05/motorola-edge-update-adds-something-called-verizon-adaptive-sound/"&gt;as noted by &lt;em&gt;Droid Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6jFwE"&gt;Verizon Adaptive Sound is integrated right into the settings menu on Android devices in the sound section. From there, you can adjust sliders for treble, bass, voice enhancement, and spatial surround sound. For those who’d prefer to ignore VAS completely and hear everything as normal, it can toggled on or off in settings. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lrjWt6xY5uE9XG2fHYt6KgndHCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22703786/Screen_Shot_2021_07_07_at_12.57.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Verizon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YhXV3I"&gt;“While some technology solutions have attempted to provide premium sound experiences to some specific (usually expensive) devices and to a limited subset of content, most devices and content experiences have been relegated to a disjointed, sub-optimal, and lowest-common-denominator-like experience,” a Verizon spokesperson said by email, in an obvious reference to Apple, Sony, and Amazon. “We wanted to change that.” Some devices that offer 360-degree audio do indeed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22360437/sony-srs-ra5000-speaker-review-360-audio-features"&gt;come at a premium&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gHGt2H"&gt;Verizon Adaptive Sound is based around “an innovative software and cloud-based solution,” a spokesperson said. That’s on the vague side, so I’ve asked the carrier for more specifics on exactly how it works and what it does. Is this just some kind of gimmicky, fake virtual surround effect? Or does it mix down Dolby Atmos channels (when available) to make the sound profile, similar to Apple’s spatial audio? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vLxleo"&gt;Apple spatial audio works with AirPods earbuds and the AirPods Max headphones to create immersive surround sound — with head tracking — when watching TV shows and movies in supported apps. The company has more recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;added spatial audio to its Apple Music service&lt;/a&gt;, though the results are very inconsistent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWaUx8"&gt;Verizon’s big talking point seems to be universal support across hardware and streaming services. But until we can give Verizon Adaptive Sound a try ourselves on one of these Moto devices, we can’t say how it compares to existing approaches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h9kqCY"&gt;The feature “will be made available on a broader portfolio of new devices in the future, as well as some existing devices via an over-the-air software update,” according to Verizon. My initial hunch was that we’ll mostly see this on entry-level and midrange 5G phones, but the carrier told me it won’t be specific to budget devices. Does that mean Verizon will force this into the sound settings of something like Samsung’s Galaxy S21? For now, Motorola is the only partner being named. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567035/verizon-spatial-audio-adaptive-sound-motorola"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567035/verizon-spatial-audio-adaptive-sound-motorola</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T08:28:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T08:28:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple and Google crowd out the competition with default apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z-BajpgSWY_z9XLxnIOLTmw66pc=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550154/Google_Apple_App_Dominance2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A new study shows how Apple and Google’s preinstalled apps dominate their mobile platforms&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="wJfzM4"&gt;If you use an iPhone or Android phone, chances are the majority of your most-used apps were made by Apple and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysNYXF"&gt;That’s the takeaway from a new Comscore study that ranks the popularity of preinstalled iOS and Android apps, such as Apple’s Messages, alongside apps made by other developers. The results show that the majority of apps people use on their phones in the US come preinstalled by either Apple or Google. The first-of-its-kind report was commissioned by Facebook, one of Apple’s loudest critics, and shared exclusively with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BHrZWT"&gt;Preinstalled services dominate when it comes to basics like weather, photos, and clocks, according to the report, suggesting these categories will be difficult for other apps to compete in. Defaults don’t win out exclusively, though: Apple Maps and Music don’t appear on the iOS list at all, and Gmail makes the iOS list several entries below Apple Mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="c5cAMz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple and Google are increasingly under scrutiny for favoring their own services&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PzYrnI"&gt;The timing, as Facebook likely intentioned, is apt: Apple and Google are increasingly under scrutiny for how they favor their own services over competitors like Spotify. US lawmakers are currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529857/democrats-antitrust-big-tech-facebook-amazon-google-apple-competition-package-bills"&gt;reviewing a new set of bills&lt;/a&gt; designed to curb the power of Big Tech, including legislation that could potentially bar Apple and Google from giving their services the upper hand against rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDvTGa"&gt;The pushback stems from how Apple and Google bundle their apps and services with their mobile operating systems in ways that some of their competitors think is unfair. The criticism is harsher against Apple, given that it more tightly controls the apps that come preinstalled on the iPhone and doesn’t allow developers to circumvent its App Store.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dzrZxb"&gt;At the same time, it has been difficult to know how popular these preinstalled apps are relative to apps made by third-party developers since Apple and Google don’t disclose user numbers for their default apps. Research firms regularly track the popularity of apps that are available for download in app stores, but Comscore’s study is the first real attempt at charting how default mobile apps compete against other developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="TCKt1W"&gt;&lt;div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/6523915"&gt;&lt;script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tknLNo"&gt;You can view the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22313379"&gt;full interactive version here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9sO-_nhMbJmafmbNBALEFxq300A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22702366/VRG_Data_Top20Apps_BarChart_Vert2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CDcIg6"&gt;To make the report last December, Comscore used data it regularly gathers from apps and websites alongside a survey of roughly 4,000 people asking about the default apps they used during the month of November. The results show that 75 percent of the top 20 apps on iOS in the US were made by Apple, while Google made 60 percent of the top apps on Android. The top four apps on both platforms were made by their respective parent company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hheye"&gt;Facebook is the only outside developer with more than one app on the iOS list and the only developer with three apps on the list for Android. Randomly, a staggering 78 million people used Apple’s Calculator app — more than the users of Gmail on Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mcH7KS"&gt;Facebook paid for the Comscore study to show the “impact of preinstalled apps on the competitive app ecosystem,” according to company spokesman Joe Osborne. The social network’s executives have long criticized Apple’s limitations on third-party developers for hindering their ability to distribute mobile games and compete effectively with iMessage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="iJJVIt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple called the report “seriously flawed”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pBAsdA"&gt;Apple rejected the report’s findings. “This Facebook-financed survey from December 2020 was narrowly tailored to give the false impression that there’s little competition on the App Store,” an Apple spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “In truth, third-party apps compete with Apple’s apps across every category and enjoy large scale success.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VXdn9R"&gt;The spokesperson said the survey’s methodology was “seriously flawed in a number of ways” and that the results contradicted Comscore’s recent &lt;a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Rankings#tab_mobile_apps/"&gt;April 2021 rankings&lt;/a&gt; on app usage. But those rankings didn't attempt to factor in the usage of all preinstalled apps like the Facebook-commissioned study did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVl9oD"&gt;Google did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MknSY7"&gt;Besides Comscore showing app usage in the US for a particular window of time, there are a couple of other quirks in its methodology to note: it did not include browsers such as Apple’s Safari or Google’s Chrome in the rankings or what it calls “embedded operating system features” like Siri. And results for Android weren’t gathered by specific phone manufacturers, meaning app usage isn’t broken out for Samsung phones relative to the Google Pixel, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="05S9u9"&gt;Still, the report points to the power platform owners have over what apps are used on their devices. It’s not just the app stores that serve as gatekeepers, but the phones themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22549338/apple-google-apps-comscore-study-facebook"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22549338/apple-google-apps-comscore-study-facebook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-05T14:44:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-05T14:44:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>The OnePlus 9 is on sale — and it’s an even better deal at $649</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0XoJzbpw0mSnKeUGflvNB8t8miA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69543226/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0070_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 9 misses some of the high-end features on the more expensive Pro model, but it’s a better overall buy for most people.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u8wNGQ"&gt;The OnePlus’ latest flagship phones are marked down at several retailers, &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/07/05/grab-a-oneplus-9-for-the-price-it-probably-shouldve-been-at-launch/"&gt;as spotted by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad-Wireless/dp/B08Y73NTXY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;normally $729 OnePlus 9 down to $649&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad-Wireless/dp/B07XM7WVS8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro (usually $1069) to $969&lt;/a&gt;. We think that the more basic 9 is already the better buy than the 9 Pro for most people, and the extra $80 off the retail price makes it an even sweeter deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gwH0B6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;The OnePlus 9 gives up surprisingly few features&lt;/a&gt; compared to its more expensive sibling — you still get a Snapdragon 888 processor, display with 120Hz refresh rate, and an excellent 50-megapixel ultrawide camera. You’ll have to make do with an unstabilized main camera, plastic rather than aluminum frame, and slower wireless charging. Considering that you save more than $300 off the price of the premium model, these downgrades feel like things most of us could live with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="f9yVX6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0zv63j"&gt;A word of caution if you’re ready to add the OnePlus 9 to your virtual cart: while it’s fully compatible with Verizon and T-Mobile 4G and 5G networks, it’s 4G only on AT&amp;amp;T. That’s not a big deal now (actually, you’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18277484/att-fake-5g-e-network-lte-study"&gt;probably better off sticking with its 4G&lt;/a&gt; at the moment). However, AT&amp;amp;T’s 5G network should improve over the next couple of years as the company starts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;employing its new C-band frequencies&lt;/a&gt;, which the 9 and 9 Pro support. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22564077/oneplus-9-pro-sale-price-screen-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22564077/oneplus-9-pro-sale-price-screen-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-05T01:43:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-05T01:43:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xiaomi’s Mi 11 Ultra is getting an ultra-limited release in India</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ixpGO5NDQgFFdSFUavpoihg_A3w=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69541768/DSCF7720_2.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LbPe5P"&gt;Xiaomi’s Mi 11 Ultra is finally going on sale in India in limited quantities. The company had announced its latest flagship smartphone all the way &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356128/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-lite-5g-announced-specs"&gt;back in March&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s been near-impossible to buy one outside of China ever since. The phone sold out instantly in the UK in May, suggesting very limited stock, and last month Xiaomi &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/XiaomiIndia/status/1400042494792921089"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the Indian launch would be delayed “due to circumstances beyond our control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgoLQA"&gt;Now, Xiaomi has announced details of how people in India will actually be able to buy one, as long as they’re willing to jump through a few hoops. Customers will need to buy an “ultra gift card” for Rs. 1,999 (~$27) &lt;a href="https://in.event.mi.com/in/mi-11-ultra-register"&gt;on the Mi.com website&lt;/a&gt;, which can later be redeemed against the price of the Mi 11 Ultra and includes some bonuses like two free screen replacements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0QVgbI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;⚡️&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mi11Ultra?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Mi11Ultra&lt;/a&gt;⚡️&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Register for the first sale by purchasing the ultra gift card, get guaranteed access to sale &amp;amp; other benefits  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  2 Free Screen Replacements&lt;br&gt;  Ultra Merchandise Superfan Box&lt;br&gt;  Times Prime Annual Membership&lt;br&gt;  Extra F-code&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Know more: &lt;a href="https://t.co/GGbHaZvU2d"&gt;https://t.co/GGbHaZvU2d&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/61x4jYCREP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/61x4jYCREP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mi India (@XiaomiIndia) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/XiaomiIndia/status/1411280371396669440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="18WscM"&gt;The Mi 11 Ultra itself starts at Rs. 69,999 (~$940) in India. Xiaomi hasn’t said how long the gift cards will be available for, how many phones it’ll make available for purchase, or when they’ll ship, but it’s describing the release as a “limited-quantity sale.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W3ELbM"&gt;Xiaomi’s key selling point for the Mi 11 Ultra over its (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310843/xiaomi-mi-11-review-samsung"&gt;very good&lt;/a&gt;) non-ultra sibling is an all-new camera system. The main camera has a large 1/1.12-inch 50-megapixel sensor, and there are also 48-megapixel ultrawide and telephoto modules. All of this is housed in a gigantic camera bump complete with a secondary OLED screen that can serve as a viewfinder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eco7pE"&gt;I’ve been using the Mi 11 Ultra for a while now — stay tuned for our review.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22563584/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-release-date-sale-price-india"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22563584/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-release-date-sale-price-india</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
