<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-07T18:37:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T18:37:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T18:37:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Text messages sent to Google Fi users with Hangouts went missing last week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jRW9YUGdVb_9LAGEBKxFyGe8gqg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69092218/acastro_210104_1777_google_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pwlPyW"&gt;A Google Fi user in Hawaii received a couple text messages Monday night wishing him a happy Easter. The problem is, those messages had been sent on Easter Sunday, but only made it through more than a day later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSQ6XV"&gt;Google is now informing Fi users who receive text messages through Hangouts that messages sent to them may have gone missing between March 31st and April 5th. The company said there was a service “interruption” that impacted “a small number of people.” Google says it has now resolved the issue and is sending through the delayed messages. Missing messages should appear in Hangouts by the end of today, April 7th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Hdcy2S"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google has now disabled texting from Hangouts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="20M2IH"&gt;Fi users have for years been able to send and receive calls and messages through Hangouts, but Google announced plans years ago to strip those features out as it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/22/18193303/google-hangouts-end-transition-october-gsuite-chat-meet"&gt;transitioned Hangouts&lt;/a&gt; into yet another Google communications app. The features appear to have been disabled within the last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrVcU1"&gt;But the interruption occurred before the service was fully shut down, and so Google is still working to patch the delayed messages through to Hangouts. A Google spokesperson confirmed the service interruption to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;and said affected users are being contacted. SMS messages will be delivered to Messages by Google or another default messaging app &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/fi/answer/9984024?hl=en#zippy=%2Cstep-transfer-or-sync-your-text-messages%2Cif-you-used-hangouts-for-your-text-messages"&gt;going forward&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WcLjzZ"&gt;Delayed messages can cause real problems for senders and receivers. In November 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/8/20955771/delayed-text-messages-valentines-day-syniverse-total-number-growth-carriers"&gt;more than 168,000 messages&lt;/a&gt; were delivered that had originally been sent on Valentine’s Day 2019, nine months earlier. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/7/20953422/text-messages-delayed-received-overnight-valentines-day-delay"&gt;People received confusing, context-free messages&lt;/a&gt; — in some cases, messages came through from people who had died in the months between. The issue was caused by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974692/valentines-day-text-message-delay-explanation-sms-syniverse-carriers"&gt;a server failure at Syniverse&lt;/a&gt;, a firm that routes text messages between carriers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEpXKN"&gt;Google has been in the process of shutting down Hangouts for years, so it’s possible there weren’t many users left using the service in conjunction with Fi. Even the Fi user in Hawaii — who, full disclosure, is a friend of mine — said they knew they should have switched a while ago and decided not to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4QRDP0"&gt;“I intentionally put myself in this spot,” Jason Bennett, who received the delayed Easter messages, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; “&lt;/em&gt;I wanted to see what happened when it went offline.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ehhdh9FzpYFcUKMi0dCFz0bL9MY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22427972/fi.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The body of an email sent to Fi users whose messages were delayed.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372437/google-fi-text-message-delays-hangouts-shutdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372437/google-fi-text-message-delays-hangouts-shutdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T18:16:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T18:16:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lil Nas X’s ‘Twerk Hero’ is a real game where you shake a virtual butt to Montero</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Q8wSKzrjUr0jT_wQ09vL-Aa09E=/0x2:1445x965/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69092064/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_3.13.05_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5yBtLm"&gt;Rapper Lil Nas X has just released a free rhythm game that has you twerking to his new song “Montero (Call Me By Your Name).” Yes, the main mechanic is twerking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWeuza"&gt;It’s a free browser game, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.monterocallmebyyour.name"&gt;play it right now at this link&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to get an idea of how the game works, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LilNasX/status/1379913998695419905"&gt;check out this video he tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. Or just use your imagination. It’s exactly what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MoSnst"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PLAY HERE: &lt;a href="https://t.co/pUlUJYhY3O"&gt;https://t.co/pUlUJYhY3O&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/I660hJr9du"&gt;pic.twitter.com/I660hJr9du&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— nope   (@LilNasX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LilNasX/status/1379914189125218305?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Sj5Fv4"&gt;I tried it briefly before writing this post, and I have to admit that I had a hard time lining up my twerks with the on-screen arrows. (What a sentence. Also hi Dad, who gets email notifications whenever I publish a &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; story.) But the game says I somehow got 43 of the 50 arrows, and a rating of two and a half stars out of three. I’ll take it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QqZSD"&gt;The new game is Lil Nas X’s latest internet-savvy stunt to help promote the new song. He also collaborated with internet collective MSCHF to release the “Satan Shoes,” which were custom Nikes that supposedly have a drop of blood in them. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357225/nike-sues-lil-nas-x-unauthorized-satan-shoes-mschf"&gt;Nike sued MSCHF&lt;/a&gt; over the shoes, seeking a temporary restraining order, but MSCHF said it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361961/mschf-nike-unauthorized-satan-shoe-lawsuit-response-restraining-order"&gt;no intention&lt;/a&gt; of shipping the 666th pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="aLA8Ha"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"MSCHF will not ship its 666th pair of Satan Shoes after Nike lawsuit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361961/mschf-nike-unauthorized-satan-shoe-lawsuit-response-restraining-order"},{"title":"Nike sues over Lil Nas X’s ‘unauthorized Satan Shoes’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357225/nike-sues-lil-nas-x-unauthorized-satan-shoes-mschf"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372657/lil-nas-x-twerk-hero-montero-call-me-by-your-name-browser-free-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372657/lil-nas-x-twerk-hero-montero-call-me-by-your-name-browser-free-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T17:33:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T17:33:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some OnePlus 9 Pro owners say their phones are overheating too easily</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kr4j8aTv2AP9bty0YLCt0jitcXk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69091858/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0065.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus says the excessive overheating warnings some 9 Pro owners are reporting will be addressed soon with a software update&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o2Z0yp"&gt;A number of OnePlus 9 Pro owners say they’re getting persistent overheating warnings, often with use of the camera app. &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/04/07/oneplus-9-pros-are-overheating-but-a-fix-is-planned/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; spotted the mounting number of reports, many of which are collected in &lt;a href="https://forums.oneplus.com/threads/unified-oneplus-9-pro-battery-heating-and-charging-feedback-thread.1412143/"&gt;a thread on OnePlus’ support forum&lt;/a&gt; and often mention use of the camera app in connection with the warnings. OnePlus tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;this is a known issue and that a fix will be coming via software updates “over the next few weeks.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N7luEV"&gt;Some 9 Pro owners reporting the problem say that the warning appears even with light use of the phone’s still photo or video recording capabilities, and in some cases the phone will prohibit any more photo taking until it cools back down. Others mention the problem arising around or soon after initial setup. We didn’t encounter the issue while testing the OnePlus 9 Pro for our review, and we haven’t seen it crop up with use since then either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sLBHmo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="erWQ7N"&gt;OnePlus gave a lot of thought to heat dissipation in the 9 Pro’s design, which is an especially important consideration for the phone’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22335032/oneplus-9-pro-fast-wireless-charging"&gt;fast wireless charging feature&lt;/a&gt;. To ensure that the phone remains a safe temperature during wireless charging, the 9 Pro includes thicker copper and a larger heat sink than its predecessor. It’s also equipped with two 25W battery cells, which helps control heat in addition to improving charging times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDgpI1"&gt;While it seems the phone is well equipped to deal with heat on the hardware side, users’ description of the problem and the response from OnePlus indicate something might be wrong on the software side. Until that fix arrives, the company encourages 9 Pro owners experiencing problems to &lt;a href="https://forums.oneplus.com/feedback"&gt;submit a bug report through its forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IbuNNt"&gt;Related: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hLxciF"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro review|100985" data-volume-uuid="42559d64a" data-volume-id="100985" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-821" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372171/oneplus-9-pro-overheating-battery-camera-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372171/oneplus-9-pro-overheating-battery-camera-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T15:53:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T15:53:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s first crack at a Clubhouse competitor is a new Q&amp;A platform called Hotline</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l1Q1yzgJNWkQS8Rg76fR8uh__2A=/11x0:1216x803/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69091193/Hotline_StoryHeader.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LhkRYg"&gt;Facebook’s experimental app development division, the NPE Team, has released a new Q&amp;amp;A platform that borrows concepts from buzzy, audio-only social network Clubhouse but with dashes of live-streaming thrown in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrncyZ"&gt;The platform is called Hotline, and it featured its &lt;a href="https://hotline.co/nick-huber-ama"&gt;first Q&amp;amp;A with investor Nick Huber&lt;/a&gt; earlier today, according to a &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebook-tests-hotline-a-qa-product-thats-a-mashup-of-clubhouse-and-instagram-live/"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A website for the service is online now and allows sign-ins via Twitter, but it features only a waitlist and a tool for applying to host your own show. &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch &lt;/em&gt;says Facebook has created designs for mobile versions of the app, though those do not appear to be live at this moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y9qTxS"&gt;News of Facebook building its own version of Clubhouse &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276645/facebook-clubhouse-social-audio-app-develop"&gt;first surfaced in February&lt;/a&gt;, though Hotline is said to be a different product than the ongoing Clubhouse competitor being built by the team behind the video chat platform Messenger Rooms, &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch &lt;/em&gt;reports. Twitter has been openly testing its Spaces alternative, too, putting more pressure on Clubhouse as whispers of a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-06/clubhouse-is-said-to-discuss-funding-at-about-4-billion-value"&gt;new funding round valuing the company at an eye-popping $4 billion valuation&lt;/a&gt; surfaced earlier this week. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aByTi5MopJNfcE7LjozN7wVTQds=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22427545/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_1.03.41_PM.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kUTr0N"&gt;Hotline works differently than Clubhouse and Spaces. It allows hosts to use video and to schedule more formal presentations with Q&amp;amp;A built in, rather than the more open-ended, audio-only conversations that take place on Clubhouse. Hotline also allows hosts to record their sessions in both audio and video formats, &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch &lt;/em&gt;says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FTZhyh"&gt;The core Q&amp;amp;A component of Hotline involves the hosts fielding questions from the audience supplied via text, while audience members can then upvote which questions they want answered and then respond to the ongoing conversation with emoji reactions. Hosts can also bring individuals from the audience up onto the virtual stage to ask their question live and potentially engage in a longer conversation. In that way, Hotline events seem designed more like a cross between a radio show and a Twitch stream, where the audience is asked to weigh in here and there but control of the conversation remains firmly with the host. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c89qsF"&gt;The project is being led by Erik Hazzard, who joined Facebook when his app tbh, a platform for sending anonymous compliments to your friends, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/16/16485428/facebook-tbh-to-be-honest-acquisition-ios-app"&gt;acquired in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/2/17528896/facebook-tbh-moves-hello-shut-down-low-usage"&gt;shut tbh down&lt;/a&gt;, despite Hazzard’s success attracting millions of users to the platform. But it sounds like his expertise in creating these new mobile experiences is now being put to good use at Facebook as part of the NPE Team, which in the past has released music-making apps like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174882/facebook-collab-app-store-release-date-price"&gt;Collab&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303604/facebook-rap-app-bars-experiment"&gt;Bars&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KkmSX4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Clubhouse defined a format — now it has to defend it","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22362980/clubhouse-social-audio-facebook-twitter-android"},{"title":"Clubhouse’s new direct payments let you toss a coin to creators, and they get 100 percent","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22368929/clubhouse-direct-payments-creators-stripe"},{"title":"Clubhouse announces accelerator program for creators on its platform","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330281/clubhouse-accelerator-creators-davison-app"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372190/facebook-hotline-clubhouse-competitor-q-and-a-app-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372190/facebook-hotline-clubhouse-competitor-q-and-a-app-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T12:51:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T12:51:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile is upgrading all monthly subscribers to unlimited plans for free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dwufsc3BdVRH2LL_gTqjhtMKIcM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69089880/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MVkFA8"&gt;T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fun-carrier%2Ft-mobiles-next-un-carrier-move-5gforall&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22371868%2Ftmobile-unlimited-plans-postpaid-upgrade-automatically-offer-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday that it will upgrade all existing postpaid phone plan customers to unlimited plans for free. It’s also announcing a promotion for customers of competing carriers interested in switching to T-Mobile, so AT&amp;amp;T or Verizon plan owners on fixed data plans can trade in their phones for a free Samsung Galaxy A32 5G smartphone and a T-Mobile unlimited plan with 5G access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6dYpG"&gt;“Today, 60 million Americans are stuck on limited data plans from Verizon or AT&amp;amp;T … most with limited or no 5G access. With the Great Unlimited Trade-Up, those people can trade up to both unlimited data and full access to T-Mobile’s expansive 5G network — including Ultra Capacity and Extended Range — all at the same or better price than the Carriers’ offer for limited data plans today,” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fun-carrier%2Ft-mobiles-next-un-carrier-move-5gforall&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22371868%2Ftmobile-unlimited-plans-postpaid-upgrade-automatically-offer-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reads a press release&lt;/a&gt; the company put out this morning in connection with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband"&gt;5G home internet service announcement&lt;/a&gt;. “And if you’re an existing T-Mobile postpaid customer — including all former Sprint customers — still on a limited data plan, you’re covered, too. You’re getting an upgrade to unlimited. For free,” reads the announcement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DfngR1"&gt;T-Mobile is making a substantial push to sign up new subscribers and get more existing ones onto its 5G network, and today’s announcements mark some of its most aggressive marketing yet with its offer of free phones and free unlimited plan upgrades. Of course, as with many carrier deals like these, there’s the fine print. For the trade-up promotion to the Samsung A32 5G, for example, T-Mobile says “you get a free 5G smartphone after 24 monthly bill credits and pay only the sales tax,” so it’s important to keep that in mind when considering a promotion to switch networks and trade in an old device. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371868/tmobile-unlimited-plans-postpaid-upgrade-automatically-offer-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371868/tmobile-unlimited-plans-postpaid-upgrade-automatically-offer-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T11:22:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T11:22:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile launches long-promised 5G home internet service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iPVyBkgVdh-YWJU9KBvlXTXYbv4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69089240/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;T-Mobile first began piloting wireless home internet over LTE in 2019. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZegUuC"&gt;After a long pilot period, T-Mobile is making its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fisp&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22312155%2Ft-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;5G home internet service&lt;/a&gt; a reality today. The company made the announcement on a live stream today, teased as its next Uncarrier move, and it says 30 million homes are now eligible for the service — 10 million of which are in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZIDGQ2"&gt;The service costs $60 per month, or $65 without autopay, which is $10 more per month than when the pilot program was introduced. The service comes with no data caps, hardware rental fees, or annual contracts, and customers self-install their own equipment. T-Mobile says most customers will experience speeds of 100Mbps, and all eligible customers should see average speeds of 50Mbps. Depending on coverage in your area, it will either use a 4G or 5G signal, whichever is faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ascxGi"&gt;But there’s an important caveat: home internet customers are subject to data slowdowns during times of network congestion, which could be a serious deterrent for some customers who live in dense areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HB1E69"&gt;T-Mobile’s talk of 5G home internet dates back to 2019, when the company was making its case to the Federal Communications Commission why it should be allowed to acquire Sprint. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/7/18254853/tmobile-sprint-merger-5g-home-internet-service-promises"&gt;claimed that gaining access&lt;/a&gt; to Sprint’s network would be a necessary step in offering high-speed in-home wireless internet. According to the company, this would allow T-Mobile to offer an alternative to the dominant ISPs and bring faster internet to underserved rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="detQu9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="2h75wy"&gt;Before the ink was dry on the deal, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18275640/tmobile-lte-wireless-home-internet-service-pilot-launch"&gt;T-Mobile started piloting the service&lt;/a&gt; over its existing LTE network. It started small, as an invitation-only deal for 50,000 households. As of last month, the pilot included 100,000 households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RCLeHM"&gt;Testing a pilot program in select cities is one thing; opening up that service to 5G customers across the country is another. T-Mobile is certainly confident that its network can handle it, and with good reason: that spectrum it acquired from Sprint &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22297311/tmobile-5g-mid-band-magenta-max-unlimited-data"&gt;has given it a leg up&lt;/a&gt;, especially compared to Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T. Maybe when it’s done fulfilling &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; promise from its Sprint acquisition talks, it can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295777/dish-network-5g-q3-2021"&gt;work on its promise to help Dish&lt;/a&gt; become that fourth wireless carrier that we’ve been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung is bringing its lowest-cost 5G phones to the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eNy7tQ3zzU7D1HzCcoipD2oNM0o=/0x1:2000x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69088752/Galaxy_A02S_A12_A32_A42_5G_5G_A52_5G_Lineup.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Five new A-series models will debut in the US this month, from the entry-level A02s up to the midrange A52 5G.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C4wNQQ"&gt;Until now, we’ve known almost everything about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334392/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-a72-specs-price-camera"&gt;Samsung’s newest Galaxy A-series phones&lt;/a&gt; (which were announced recently at the company’s Unpacked event) except for a couple of key details: which models would be sold in the US and for how much. That’s the announcement Samsung made today, with three low-cost 5G phones leading the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5cIkjQ"&gt;The Galaxy A52 5G, A42 5G, and A32 5G will all go on sale in the US later this week, with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231420/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-europe-cheapest-5g-phone"&gt;sub-$300 A32&lt;/a&gt; clocking in as Samsung’s lowest-cost 5G model to date. They’ll each ship loaded with Android 11 and with charging bricks included in the box. Also arriving Stateside soon: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21628573/samsung-a12-a02s-phones-budget-price-specs-2021"&gt;entry-level Galaxy A12 and A02s&lt;/a&gt;, each costing under $200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4QvV6M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10432345"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2LYuk9"&gt;The A52 5G is the highest specced A-series model US customers will see this year; the A72, which was unveiled at the same Unpacked event, is missing from today’s list. The A52 5G follows up on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21251569/samsung-galaxy-a51-review-price-screen-camera-battery-life"&gt;last year’s solid A51 model&lt;/a&gt; and includes a 6.5-inch OLED with 120Hz refresh rate, a Snapdragon 750G processor, IP67 water resistance rating, and a 4,500mAh battery. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8pAGFLFoROgD83eL_GtiW2VvuNI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424833/Galaxy_A52_5G_Awesome_Black_Front_Back.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy A52 5G features a stabilized main camera, IP67 weather resistance, and a 120Hz screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="726Ua2"&gt;Its camera hardware is also a step up from the other models in this bunch, including a 64-megapixel main camera with optical image stabilization. The A52 5G supports sub-6GHz 5G only (no mmWave), and like the other two 5G models, it supports C-band frequencies at a hardware level. It will be sold with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage for $499 starting on April 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gGqZrgSgCd2Gxqqitc7DCtn1-mI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424847/GalaxyA42_5G_Variants.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The A42 5G supports sub-6GHz and mmWave 5G.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wrCzlm"&gt;The A42 5G is the only model of the bunch to support mmWave 5G in addition to sub-6GHz. It also features a 6.6-inch OLED with standard 60Hz refresh rate, and like the A52 5G, it will use a Snapdragon 750G chipset. The A42 5G features a 48-megapixel main camera and doesn’t include an IP rating. It will include 4GB of RAM and 128GB of storage and is going on sale for $399 starting on April 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6X-DqtsUzJueeQ8sMP0LUxnmmX8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424854/Galaxy_A32_5G_Awesome_Black_Front_Back.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy A32 5G is Samsung’s least expensive 5G model to date.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k6jEFV"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy A32 5G skips out on quite a few features in order to hit its low price point. It includes an LCD rather than OLED — a 6.6-inch panel with 90Hz refresh rate — and uses a MediaTek 720 processor rather than a Snapdragon chipset. It will include 4GB of RAM and a skimpy 64GB of storage, thankfully expandable by microSD. It will sell for $279 starting on April 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m-Vc98jOIvuWYPmFTFnFYQKl_ig=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424856/Galaxy_A12_Black_Front_Angled.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The A12 offers a 6.5-inch LCD.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7igkht"&gt;Rounding out the set are the LTE-only, budget-oriented A12 and A02s, each featuring a 6.5-inch LCD with standard refresh rate and a 5,000mAh battery. The A12 gets a 16-megapixel main camera and a 5-megapixel ultrawide and will offer 3GB of RAM. The A02s includes a 13-megapixel main camera without the ultrawide and offers just 2GB of RAM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DlVP9f"&gt;Both phones will ship with Android 10 and (thankfully) offer storage expansion via microSD; with just 32GB of built-in storage each, some extra space will be a necessity. The Galaxy A12  will sell for $179 starting on April 9th; the Galaxy A02s will cost $109.99 and arrive on April 29th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JIuR0V"&gt;All of these A-series devices will be sold unlocked by Samsung, though the company could only confirm that the A52 5G would be available this way on April 9th; all others would be coming at some point later this spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LAsXdC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370189/samsung-galaxy-a52-a42-a32-5g-a12-a02s-price-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370189/samsung-galaxy-a52-a42-a32-5g-a12-a02s-price-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-06T17:13:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-06T17:13:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Gazelle brings back its phone trade-in program two months after discontinuing it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12, in blue." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0wTxK49NyoGux2ayro6iaVNjl9U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69086084/vpavic_4243_20201018_0121.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hj8AnD"&gt;Trade-in provider Gazelle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/30/22206779/gazelle-smartphone-used-trade-in-program-shut-down"&gt;exited the online trade-in business&lt;/a&gt; back in February, and now the company says it’s changing its mind. Gazelle is back to accepting online trade-ins of iPhones, Samsung phones, Google Pixel devices, and iPads and other tablets on its website, the company confirms to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The program resumed accepting new offers on April 5th, a Gazelle representative clarified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oDePCQ"&gt;“Earlier this year, we announced that we will no longer be offering our trade-in option on Gazelle. After careful consideration, including feedback from customers like you, we have decided to keep Gazelle Trade-In going. Today, we are happy to say, ‘We’re back, baby!’” reads an email Gazelle sent to prospective customers and shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Gazelle Trade-In is a pioneer of the electronics trade-in space and we are happy to continue building on our legacy by offering a simple process and immediate payouts for those unwanted devices.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bk0Fcj"&gt;Gazelle emerged as one of the leading trade-in providers of the smartphone era. But its business model didn’t fare as well when the US mobile phone business underwent major shifts away from two-year contracts and outright device purchases and toward phone leasing and carrier and device maker trade-in programs like Apple’s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8v5QVq"&gt;Gazelle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/30/22206779/gazelle-smartphone-used-trade-in-program-shut-down"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; back in December of last year it would end its online phone trade-in program on February 1st, 2021, though the company said at the time it would continue to operate its in-person trade-in kiosks through parent company ecoATM. Gazelle did confirm in the email sent to customers that it will not be bringing back its rewards program. “We will continue to evaluate the market conditions and will inform you if this changes,” the email reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLDJFV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370595/gazelle-trade-in-program-is-back-returns-iphone-samsung-smartphone-selling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370595/gazelle-trade-in-program-is-back-returns-iphone-samsung-smartphone-selling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-06T15:11:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-06T15:11:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this feature on how India’s digital revolution started with missed calls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="INDIA-ECONOMY" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2ygzgFnXJjndxRvgNs35f9_Mc5E=/0x3:8367x5581/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69085277/1231334394.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by JEWEL SAMAD/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KREkbs"&gt;Leaving a missed call on someone’s phone usually signals that you should call them back — but at one point in India, it was communication in its own right. &lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/the-rise-and-fall-of-missed-calls-in-india/"&gt;A new feature by Atul Bhattarai&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Rest of World&lt;/em&gt; examines the Indian culture that grew up around missed calls — and the startups that took advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jeXSb9"&gt;In basic terms, a “missed call” means dialing a person but hanging up before they can answer. Hanging up without talking let users send a basic message (“I called”) without getting charged for minutes or SMS messages — like paging someone without a pager. Bhattarai focuses on ZipDial, a company that turned missed calls into a robust advertising business and a way to experience some of the features of online life without paying for data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6V18Uz"&gt;As Bhattarai writes, using missed calls to communicate came about because of the high cost of cellphone data and limited access to high-speed internet. Calling long enough to connect to someone else’s phone and then hanging up or not picking up on the other end avoided being charged for the call. These missed calls could mean a variety of things, like letting a friend know you’re on your way or a loved one know that you miss them. “The fact that the missed call demanded only basic numeric literacy made them accessible to the third of India’s population that was illiterate,” Bhattarai explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bu1ehq"&gt;ZipDial combined the missed call trend and preexisting SMS services into a kind of a one-stop shop for cellphone owners who wanted basic internet functionality. ZipDial would partner with a brand and set up a hotline that people could call for services like sports scores or celebrity tweets. All it took was “signing up” with a missed call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jINvf7"&gt;Bhattarai also highlights a proto-Spotify algorithmic playlist service called Kan Khajura, which delivered new music in 15-minute calls. “Kan Khajura’s central appeal was that it could be accessed anywhere and anytime, unlike the radio and TV,” Bhattarai writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pkuUeq"&gt;Those businesses became unsustainable as mobile data became cheaper, and ZipDial ceased operations in 2016. But Bhattarai argues the services helped bridge the offline-online gap in a period before internet service providers and physical infrastructure caught up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vWi18q"&gt;You can read the full feature on &lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/the-rise-and-fall-of-missed-calls-in-india/"&gt;ZipDial’s missed call empire&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Rest of World.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hndTjJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22370007/india-missed-calls-zipdial-pre-internet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22370007/india-missed-calls-zipdial-pre-internet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-06T13:52:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-06T13:52:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Signal is testing a payments feature that lets you send cryptocurrency to friends</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7krYp4GTId4FksGKcsb8NJz0nNM=/48x0:2073x1350/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69084630/payments_hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Signal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bYv2gU"&gt;Signal &lt;a href="https://signal.org/blog/help-us-test-payments-in-signal/"&gt;announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; it’s now testing a new peer-to-peer payments system in the beta version of its apps. Appropriately called Signal Payments, the new feature right now supports only one protocol: the MobileCoin wallet and its companion cryptocurrency MOB. MobileCoin has a close relationship with Signal co-founder and CEO Moxie Marlinspike, who advised the company prior to its &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/mobilecoin-a-cryptocurrency-involving-signal-founder-moxie-marlinspike-just-raised-venture-funding/"&gt;most recent round of funding announced last month&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uc7YcI"&gt;“The first payments protocol we’ve added support for is a privacy focused payments network called MobileCoin, which has its own currency, MOB,” wrote Jun Harada, Signal’s head of growth and communication, in a &lt;a href="https://signal.org/blog/help-us-test-payments-in-signal/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “As always, our goal is to keep your data in your hands rather than ours; MobileCoin’s design means Signal does not have access to your balance, full transaction history, or funds. You can also transfer your funds at any time if you want to switch to another app or service.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L6_fQUckH7quKkzlE6YPQUuKLaQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424615/payments_product.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Signal&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7rOAFc"&gt;The company says those interested in trying out the feature must live in the UK for now, and those who qualify can sign up for MobileCoin and access the feature through the &lt;a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007318471-How-do-I-join-Signal-s-beta-"&gt;Signal beta&lt;/a&gt;. “This is a beta feature in a &lt;a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007318471-How-do-I-join-Signal-s-beta-"&gt;beta build&lt;/a&gt;, but for those in the United Kingdom living life on the edge, please help us test and give feedback,” Harada writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="krJspx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Professor Steve Hanke and investor Nic Carter on the two sides of the bitcoin debate","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22367951/bitcoin-future-nic-carter-steve-hanke-interview-decoder-podcast"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370213/signal-payments-cryptocurrency-crypto-mobilecoin-wallet-mob-beta-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370213/signal-payments-cryptocurrency-crypto-mobilecoin-wallet-mob-beta-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
