<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-26T14:56:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T14:56:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T14:56:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Boost Mobile is offering customers an Android 11 phone for $35</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7a1_2zLWm3xpWkXsv4WjEKXFW2s=/0x1:2353x1570/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69346801/WikoRide3_crop.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wiko Ride 3 offers a 6.09-inch display and Android 11 out of the box.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Wiko Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5umbsn"&gt;With T-Mobile’s older CDMA network shutdown looming and no sign of a delay in sight, Boost Mobile customers looking for a new 4G phone just got a very affordable new option: the Wiko Ride 3. It’s currently marked down to $34.99 from a full retail price of $99.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OATL1x"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/boost-mobile-wiko-ride-3-affordable-android-11-phone-specs-features-price_id132374"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phone Arena&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, that promotional pricing somewhat unusually applies to existing customers rather than new ones. It’s unusual but not unexpected: the CDMA network shutdown could leave many Boost customers in need of a new phone. These customers might also start shopping around for a new carrier, so Boost has some extra incentive to offer current customers a good deal. Meanwhile, anyone switching from another carrier can get the Wiko Ride 3 for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9CP3Th"&gt;It’s not unheard of to find a phone at this price, especially through MVNOs, but they’re often refurbished devices or run a previous Android OS generation. The Ride 3 stands out by offering Android 11 right out of the box — the current generation, at least for a little while longer, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;Android 12&lt;/a&gt; arrives this fall. Other specs include a 6.09-inch 720p screen, 13-megapixel main camera, and a 3,400mAh battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="j9E1FV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Ride 3 stands out by offering Android 11 right out of the box&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XR6uB1"&gt;Boost Mobile was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;acquired by Dish Network&lt;/a&gt; as part of last year’s T-Mobile / Sprint merger deal, and it operates on T-Mobile’s networks — including an older 3G CDMA network that Dish says many Boost customers still rely on. T-Mobile plans to shut down this network at the beginning of 2022; Dish contends the shutdown is earlier than expected, calling it an anti-competitive move that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;could leave many of its customers without service&lt;/a&gt; and accusing T-Mobile of trying to poach those customers in the process&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVJ582"&gt;Dish has called on federal and state governments to intervene and delay the shutdown, but in the meantime, it appears to be stocking up on low-cost options for customers who may soon need a new 4G device. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454954/wiko-ride-3-boost-mobile-price-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454954/wiko-ride-3-boost-mobile-price-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T15:23:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T15:23:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>The affordable Nokia G10 is coming to the US with a great support policy </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-oi9I7P-KVhAD_xvug49ZfCuhVc=/0x0:3242x2161/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340974/nokia_G10_DTC_DESIGN_desktop.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HMD Nokia G10 offers big battery life and two years of Android OS platform updates.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: HMD&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BvUpmj"&gt;HMD’s Nokia G10 is coming to the US with a big battery, a low $149 price, and a surprisingly good security support schedule. &lt;a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/nokia-g10-price-release-date-availability-us_id132341"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phone Arena&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the G10 — &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nokia-Android-Unlocked-Smartphone-6-52-Inch/dp/B093QPTSK7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for preorder&lt;/a&gt; now at Amazon — will go on sale directly through Nokia’s website later this week. The G10 was first announced in Europe last month alongside &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22371937/hmd-nokia-x20-x10-g20-g10-c20-c10-android-phones-release-date-news-features"&gt;five other midrange devices&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wjuST1"&gt;Low-cost Android phones aren’t typically known for great software support. It’s common for manufacturers to offer only two years of security updates on an infrequent schedule and typically just one (or no) OS platform updates. HMD is breaking with that norm by offering two years of OS platform updates — Android 12 and 13 in this case — and three years of security updates, a policy that should see the G10 through a few years of use. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bR8p2017Y-BtAPtfc8-gQQNjAqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22539021/nokia_G10_emotional_range.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: HMD&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G10 is offered in the “dusk” color pictured here as well as a dark blue “night” flavor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jElELM"&gt;The Nokia G10’s other specs include a 6.5-inch 720p display, huge 5,050mAh battery, MediaTek G25 chipset with 3GB of RAM, 32GB of storage, and a 13-megapixel rear camera accompanied by 2-megapixel macro and depth sensors. It’s expected to go on sale Thursday, May 27th at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_int%2Fnokia-g-10&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22453332%2Fhmd-nokia-g10-price-availability-security-updates" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nokia.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453332/hmd-nokia-g10-price-availability-security-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453332/hmd-nokia-g10-price-availability-security-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T13:22:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T13:22:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now buy Asus’ gaming-ready ROG Phone 5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k21J-gQWk1woZxBGM5nLi9PVksc=/0x0:1875x1250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340185/Screen_Shot_2021_05_25_at_9.54.34_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3x5FZD"&gt;Asus’ ROG Phone 5 is now available in the US &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM210000001/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-Phone-5---6.78%E2%80%9D-FHD%2B-2448x1080-HDR-144Hz-Display---6000mAh-Dual-Cell-Battery---64MP%2F13MP%2F5MP-Triple-Camera-with-24MP-Front-Camera-%E2%80%9316GB-RAM---256GB-Storage-5G-LTE-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Cell-Phone"&gt;from its official store&lt;/a&gt;, with a price tag of $999.99. It’s Asus’ latest maxed-out gaming phone, with all of the top-notch specifications: a Snapdragon 888 Plus, 144Hz display, front-facing speakers, and a massive 6,000mAh battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpw3uf"&gt;Asus says the Ultimate and Pro versions of the phone will be available later this year. We &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;reviewed the Ultimate in March&lt;/a&gt; and found that it was a good phone that went a little — okay, maybe a lot — overboard with its specs. The vanilla version available for sale today, though, is perhaps a bit more reasonable: it “only” has 16GB of RAM (as opposed to the Ultimate’s 18GB), has half the storage (256GB instead of 512GB), and features an RGB logo on the back instead of an entire OLED screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpyEWY"&gt;The other thing the regular version is missing is the extra touch-sensitive buttons that provide an alternative to touchscreen controls (though it does still have two of the ultrasonic sensors). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="csxmTC"&gt;For those who want more buttons, though, there’s always &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM250000006/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-Phone-5-and-Gamepad-Bundle"&gt;the gamepad bundle&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM220000003/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-AeroActive-Cooler-5"&gt;AeroActive Cooler 5 accessory&lt;/a&gt;, which has two buttons built in. They do cost extra — with the gamepad bundle coming in at $40 more than just the phone and the cooler costing $70 — but that’s still likely going to be way less than shelling out for the Ultimate version.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453190/asus-rog-phone-5-gaming-mobile-available-pro-ultimate-later"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453190/asus-rog-phone-5-gaming-mobile-available-pro-ultimate-later</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Arm introduces its first Armv9 architecture CPUs and GPUs, previewing 2022’s Android flagships</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UQtctN5cpbxAkLhtLsVhGMx5twU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69338562/acastro_200804_1777_arm_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JV7M44"&gt;Arm has introduced its latest CPU and GPU designs, including its flagship Cortex-X2 and Cortex-A710 CPUs and Mali-G710 GPU. The new CPU and GPU designs aren’t just Arm’s latest chip blueprints, though; they’re also its first designs to utilize &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357951/arm-armv9-architecture-security-artificial-intelligence-performance"&gt;its new Armv9 architecture&lt;/a&gt;, its first in a decade, which means big jumps in performance, along with new security and AI features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDVqss"&gt;Most consumers probably aren’t familiar with the exact Arm cores inside their phones or computers, but Arm’s designs — and particularly, &lt;a href="https://www.arm.com/why-arm/technologies/big-little"&gt;its big.LITTLE configuration&lt;/a&gt; of combining powerful high-performance cores and battery-saving high-efficiency cores — are common to virtually every Android phone. That means the designs introduced here are effectively a preview of what the best Android phones of 2022 will look like. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_-g5zLO6cvSlF-CBmAkGMeX0tGc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22536988/Screen_Shot_2021_05_24_at_5.33.20_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xxxyD1"&gt;Arm is introducing three new CPU designs this year. First, the Cortex-X2: it’s part of Arm’s Cortex-X custom program that lets partners help design specialized cores for their specific use cases. A successor to last year’s Cortex-X1, it’s also the most powerful design in the lineup, promising up to 16 percent improved performance compared to last year’s model. There’s also the Cortex-A710, the new “big” core, promising up to 30 percent better power efficiency and 10 percent better performance than last year’s Cortex-A78. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aABO4h"&gt;But Arm isn’t just upgrading the performance cores. For the first time in four years, it’s also introducing a new “LITTLE” high-efficiency core, the Cortex-A510, which replaces the Cortex-A55 design that’s been used for major phones since it was introduced in 2017. And it’s here that Arm’s promising the biggest jumps: up to 30 percent better performance, and 20 percent better power efficiency compared to the old model. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SLdqJ0xKZeRVkh1dwYpFy6XepIQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22536990/Screen_Shot_2021_05_24_at_5.33.28_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4FsJt4"&gt;The new Armv9 designs together should result in a big jump in performance once they make their way to chips, too. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21678359/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-processor-first-look-5g-performance-ai-photography"&gt;Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 888&lt;/a&gt;, for example, uses partially customized versions of last year’s flagship Arm Cortex-X1 and Cortex-A78 as its four “big” cores and the roughly four-year-old Cortex-A55 design for its “LITTLE” cores. &lt;a href="https://www.arm.com/company/news/2021/01/arm-powerful-compute-and-graphics-platform-at-the-heart-of-the-new-samsung-exynos-2100#:~:text=The%20Cortex%2DX1%20is%20Arm's,relative%20to%20our%20standard%20CPUs."&gt;Samsung’s flagship Exynos 2100&lt;/a&gt; uses a similar configuration, too, along with Arm’s Mali-G78 GPU design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5YvR4"&gt;The new CPU core designs promise to blow both of those chips out of the water: Arm says that a CPU cluster made up of the Armv9 designs (a single Cortex-X2, three Cortex-A710 cores, and four Cortex-A510 cores) should offer up to 30 percent better peak performance (thanks to the Cortex-X2), 30 percent better overall efficiency (from the Cortex-A710), and 35 percent better “LITTLE” performance from the Cortex-A510 when compared to a comparable Armv8.2 cluster like the ones mentioned above. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hNze8sR9HFrM864ia-uogQqaXdw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22536991/Screen_Shot_2021_05_24_at_5.33.45_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="i2baXX"&gt;Arm is also introducing three new GPUs. There’s the flagship Mali-G710, which promises 20 percent better gaming performance and 20 percent better power efficiency; the Mali-G510, designed as a midrange option for more affordable devices; and the entry-level Mali-G310. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Iek8yO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A preview of the best Android phones of 2022 &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZVaZIP"&gt;The overall goal is to provide a variety of designs for a wide range of use cases. A computer might rely more heavily on Arm’s Cortex-X2 CPUs and a discrete GPU solution for graphics; a leading smartphone, a CPU cluster of Arm’s range of CPU designs and Mali-G710 GPU; or a smartwatch with fewer demands that just uses a Cortex-A510 and Mali-G310. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="00rexU"&gt;It’ll be some time before the new Arm designs show up in phones or devices: Arm still has to give the designs to its partners, who’ll then need to incorporate them into their own semiconductor products (typically announced toward the end of the year), and then those chips have to make their way to phone manufacturers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvVlS7"&gt;So it’ll likely be the beginning of 2022 before the new Arm CPU and GPU designs appear in any phones — and that’s assuming the global semiconductor shortage doesn’t push out next year’s products even further. But it’s still an exciting sneak peek at the potential of what might be coming next in the future of smartphones. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22448107/arm-armv9-architecure-cortex-x2-a710-cpu-mali-g710-gpu-android-2022-designs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22448107/arm-armv9-architecure-cortex-x2-a710-cpu-mali-g710-gpu-android-2022-designs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-24T20:36:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-24T20:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Evidence is piling up that Netflix wants to be the Netflix of games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gORAwq_MiM3G9uBXYL-m5ARGfHU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69337057/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DFgGfT"&gt;Netflix has dipped a toe in gaming on occasion, with perhaps the hugely-successful “choose your own adventure”-style film &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/2/18165182/black-mirror-bandersnatch-netflix-interactive-strategy-marketing"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;as the most prominent example. But the streaming giant may be expanding further into gaming with a new bundle for Netflix subscribers, according to several reports over the past few days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bDsDM0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; had the &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/netflix-seeks-executive-to-expand-game-efforts"&gt;first report on Friday&lt;/a&gt;, writing that Netflix wants to hire an executive to oversee new gaming efforts, and that the company is considering a bundle of games similar to Apple Arcade. (Hours later, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/netflix-looking-hire-executive-gaming-expansion-information-2021-05-21/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; corroborated&lt;/a&gt; that a gaming exec is a planned hire at Netflix.) The company has also chosen not to include ads in the games, according to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;. But &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; also said that Netflix’s plans are still “very much in flux.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CsUhBQ"&gt;In a report published Monday, however, &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt; shared more details from &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/netflix-gaming-expansion-cde0f3ae-15de-4378-b2b8-fd0aaf0e91f6.html"&gt;its own reporting.&lt;/a&gt; An &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt; source said to think of the upcoming service, which would be offered to Netflix subscribers, as “a smaller Apple Arcade” bundle that would include both licensed Netflix IP and games commissioned from indie studios. The service could be a ways out, though, “possibly launching in 2022.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWEmB4"&gt;While Netflix hasn’t publicly confirmed the potential expansion of its gaming efforts, in a statement published by both &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22447410/netflix-executive-games-expansion-the-information-report"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the company left the door open to the idea that it is indeed planning to do more with gaming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="029bIB"&gt;Our members value the variety and quality of our content. It’s why we’ve continually expanded our offering — from series to documentaries, film, local language originals and reality TV. Members also enjoy engaging more directly with stories they love — through interactive shows like &lt;em&gt;Bandersnatch&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;You v. Wild,&lt;/em&gt; or games based on &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;La&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Casa de Papel&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;To All the Boys&lt;/em&gt;. So we’re excited to do more with interactive entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="HLKHeC"&gt;Netflix has &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of titles based on popular video games that are out now or in the works, such as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/7/15938192/netflix-castlevania-review-animated-video-game-adaptation"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Castlevania&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21403849/netflix-resident-evil-tv-series-original-live-action-announcement"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21026537/the-witcher-netflix-review-henry-cavill"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21075927/netflix-the-witcher-viewer-numbers-length-metrics-q4-2019-earnings"&gt;one of Netflix’s biggest shows&lt;/a&gt;), so the company clearly sees the value of video games as IP. It’s not outlandish to think that the company would want to market its series through new games, or, in the ultimate ouroboros, make a new game that eventually becomes a new &lt;em&gt;Netflix&lt;/em&gt; show in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqC2vE"&gt;Netflix seemed to be on its way in 2019 — it had partnered with Telltale Games on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18510849/stranger-things-secret-games-telltale-studio-closed"&gt;a secret &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; game that died before it was announced&lt;/a&gt;, with a source telling &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that “Netflix was just getting into the space and didn’t really have a games group in place yet.” Telltale’s &lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Story Mode&lt;/em&gt; did survive, though, and is still at least partially playable &lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80227995"&gt;on Netflix now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3ApuPF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The tragic end of Telltale Games","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/4/17934166/telltale-games-studio-closed-layoffs-end-the-walking-dead"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="hovQyS"&gt;Many companies are trying to build a service that’s “Netflix, but for games.” Apple Arcade and Xbox Game Pass are just two that come to mind. But these reports and Netflix’s curious non-denial suggest Netflix might like to eat its own lunch this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22452173/netflix-gaming-subscription-service-executive-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22452173/netflix-gaming-subscription-service-executive-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-24T10:38:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-24T10:38:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T CEO John Stankey says it was ‘time to unleash’ WarnerMedia assets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/keerova78wvOEK4_45X2nqNjxwU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69333921/acastro_180322_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ng1etn"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T CEO John Stankey said Monday that the company’s focus on its connectivity business in the US meant it didn’t have the global reach to grow a global streaming business with WarnerMedia, and the company decided it was “time to unleash the media assets” of WarnerMedia to Discovery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BnvHOq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439964/at-t-warnermedia-discovery-merger-spin-off"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T announced on May 17th&lt;/a&gt; that it would spin off its WarnerMedia business to merge it with TV company Discovery. The resulting entity, which has yet to be named and is still awaiting regulatory approval, will be a competitor in the cable space and for streaming content giants like Netflix and Disney; WarnerMedia owns HBO, CNN, Cartoon Network, TBS, TNT, and the Warner Bros. movie studio, while Discovery has a number of channels that focus more on reality TV, including HGTV, Animal Planet, Food Network, and TLC. Each also has its own streaming platform in HBO Max and Discovery Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNqL7r"&gt;“What’s become clear is that the opportunity for direct relationships with customers is truly going to be a global opportunity,” Stankey said of the streaming sector. “As a result of that, when you look at the opportunity to grow a fantastic subscriber base we kind of looked at this and said, ‘it’s time to unleash the media assets to go and seize a multi-hundred-billion-dollar opportunity.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3T019"&gt;Streaming is “a little bit of a different shareholder base and management base than what we’d typically have” as part of AT&amp;amp;T’s more traditional lines of business, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="osveBA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/23/business/dealbook/att-agrees-to-buy-time-warner-for-more-than-80-billion.html"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T acquired WarnerMedia&lt;/a&gt; (which was known as TimeWarner at the time) in 2016 for $85.4 billion. The deal was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/14/17466518/att-time-warner-acquisition-closes"&gt;approved in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJeOzq"&gt;Stankey made the comments during the JP Morgan Global Technology, Media and Communications Conference. He bristled slightly when interviewer John Cusick, a JP Morgan analyst, asked him about his vision for the future of AT&amp;amp;T, noting “you’ve reversed nearly six years of strategic change at AT&amp;amp;T in three months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P5sgVR"&gt;Stankey said he would “contest the characterization that we did it in three months,” adding, “We don’t wake up one day and say ‘hey today’s the day I think we ought to go find a transaction.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jkxV5p"&gt;But with less than three years from when the WarnerMedia deal was approved to the time AT&amp;amp;T decided to spin it off, the change in direction struck many as sudden, but it also seemed to make sense. Telecom companies have tried to run media businesses with limited success; earlier this month, for instance, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22416854/aol-yahoo-sale-apollo-venetian-hotel-verizon"&gt;Verizon sold AOL and Yahoo&lt;/a&gt; for less than half of what it paid a few years prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shdcxS"&gt;And as &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post’&lt;/em&gt;s Steven Zeitchik noted in &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/05/22/discovery-warner-media-att-spinoff/"&gt;his analysis of the deal&lt;/a&gt;, AT&amp;amp;T did little to court business in Hollywood during the time it owned WarnerMedia. The surprise announcement in December that WarnerMedia would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;release all of its 2021 theatrical movies on HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; drew widespread &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22162918/christopher-nolan-tenet-hbo-max-warner-bros-streaming-service-cinematic-releases"&gt;criticism&lt;/a&gt; from the entertainment industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSpVQS"&gt;Still, Stankey claimed Monday that AT&amp;amp;T’s ownership of WarnerMedia helped to grow HBO Max and HBO’s linear channel to a combined &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/hbo-max-hbo-reaches-44-2-million-subscribers-4165569/"&gt;44 million US subscribers&lt;/a&gt; in the year since HBO Max launched. “I think realistically, HBO Max would not be where it is today if not for the strength of the two combined companies,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451111/att-ceo-stankey-unleash-assets-warnermedia-discovery-hbo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451111/att-ceo-stankey-unleash-assets-warnermedia-discovery-hbo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-24T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-24T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon is offering customers free Apple Arcade or Google Play Pass for up to a year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NbGxCieqwryDJ_uVp_c1udB_CF0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69333468/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kLwTrr"&gt;Verizon has a new deal for new and existing unlimited plan subscribers starting May 25th: up to &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836598-14068036?sid=Verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fplans%2Funlimited%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a year of Apple Arcade or Google Play Pass&lt;/a&gt;, free of charge. Specifically, customers who pay for the Play More Unlimited and Get More Unlimited plans get 12 months of either app subscription service for free, while all other unlimited plans get six months. It’s worth noting that both free options are longer than the ones Apple or Google offer themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pccJT7"&gt;The $80 per month Play More plan or $90 per month Get More plan (that’s the price for a single line) also come with other benefits to sweeten the deal. Play More comes with an “unlimited” mobile hotspot with up to 15GB of 5G data, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/17/21371902/verizon-unlimited-plans-free-disney-plus-espn-hulu-bundle"&gt;the Disney Bundle&lt;/a&gt; (Hulu, Disney Plus, ESPN Plus), six months of Apple Music, and 12 months of Discovery Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5MdnOH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Not quite unlimited, but the add-ons are nice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E7CmXf"&gt;Meanwhile, Get More offers an “unlimited” mobile hotspot with up 30GB of 5G data, the Disney Bundle, a continuous subscription to Apple Music, and 12 months of Discovery Plus. Verizon frequently offers all sorts of other promotions so you can check &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/plans/?adobe_mc=MCMID%3D39986104348088388961888296802413619485%7CMCAID%3D304EA1F622850B1E-40001414C26A22B2%7CMCORGID%3D843F02BE53271A1A0A490D4C%2540AdobeOrg%7CTS%3D1621640023&amp;amp;mboxSession=4b9bd75675694d1c8939eaadd9212408" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt; for the most up-to-date deals. (Each plan only guarantees 50GB of 5G/4G data at most, so none of them are technically “unlimited.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGn63Y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/23/20878843/google-play-pass-bundles-350-android-games-and-apps-for-4-99-per-month"&gt;Google Play Pass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18280589/apple-arcade-gaming-subscription-release-date-pricing-features"&gt;Apple Arcade&lt;/a&gt; are similar conceptually — pay monthly for access to a selection of the best apps from a platform without in-app purchases — but differ meaningfully in what they actually offer. Apple Arcade is focused on games and by far has some of the most interesting exclusives. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/26/21026128/apple-arcade-best-games-iphone-ipad"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grindstone &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Card of Darkness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were early favorites, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22383403/fantasian-review-apple-arcade-rpg-iphone-ipad"&gt;the recent addition of &lt;em&gt;Fantasian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a JRPG from the creator of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt;, is also well worth subscribing for, even if you have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxAtTn"&gt;Play Pass is a bit more holistic as an offering, but might be worth it if you’re new to Android. Google includes popular games &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; apps in the service, spanning everything from a farming sim like &lt;em&gt;Stardew Valley &lt;/em&gt;(normally $4.99) to a utility app like AccuWeather (free, but includes in-app purchases). It also offers a larger selection than Apple Arcade, with &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/03/31/google-play-pass-800/#:~:text=Google%20Play%20Pass%20now%20offers%20more%20than%20800%20Android%20apps%20and%20games&amp;amp;text=Google%20introduced%20Play%20Pass%20in,of%20the%20%244.99%20monthly%20membership."&gt;now over 800 apps and games&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8a0jgO"&gt;Neither Apple Arcade nor Google Play Pass are particularly expensive on their own at $4.99 per month each, but their free trials also aren’t as long as what Verizon is offering. Apple will toss in three months of Arcade for free if you purchase a new Apple device, but otherwise offers a one-month free trial. Google also only offers a one-month free trial for Play Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rk9jdR"&gt;If you’re interested in Verizon’s deal, but want a better understanding of what’s available to you, check out our lists of the best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22178231/apple-arcade-iphone-ipad-best-games-2020"&gt;Apple Arcade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22170029/best-play-pass-games-google-android-phone"&gt;Play Pass&lt;/a&gt; games.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/5/24/22448129/verizon-unlimited-plans-free-apple-arcade-google-play-pass"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/5/24/22448129/verizon-unlimited-plans-free-apple-arcade-google-play-pass</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-23T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-23T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Kyocera DuraForce Ultra 5G UW review: extreme durability for an extreme price</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A pricey phone built to withstand the elements&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="RqQfv2"&gt;The Kyocera DuraForce Ultra 5G is a rugged phone that doesn’t require you to give up too many modern conveniences to gain the benefits of extreme durability. It’s common for rugged phones to feature older processors and lack modern features — these phones often have specialized uses, like barcode scanning or taking payments, and more or less just need to keep working in harsh environments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgtCHM"&gt;The DuraForce Ultra 5G includes both the durability of a rugged phone and modern features like 5G, wireless charging, a high-quality processor, and dual rear cameras. At $899, it’s an expensive phone — you can buy a very nice non-rugged phone for that much — but if durability is a must and you don’t want to sacrifice performance or convenient features, the DuraForce 5G is (quite literally) a solid choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EUeitz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10511069"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LCwS5H0Rr6eSgsG4CWaocFtUhG8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22526443/ajohnson_20210514_4587_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="W7VFuv"&gt;Kyocera DuraForce Ultra 5G rugged features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="bgM0jd"&gt;Pick up the DuraForce Ultra 5G and you’ll know right away that you have a rugged device in your hands. The top and bottom of the phone are wrapped in thick plastic bumpers, the sides feature a texturized finish, and at 278g (9.8oz) it’s much heavier than your standard smartphone. The screen itself isn’t very big — just a 5.45-inch 1080p LCD panel — but the sizable bezels and thick chin make it a chunky device overall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sdguzi"&gt;Despite its dimensions it’s actually easy to use one-handed, since the screen itself is relatively small. The phone will fit in a jacket pocket, but it’s too bulky for any of my jeans pockets. Haptics are aggressive, even at the “medium” default setting, which is a good thing in a phone you might be using with gloves. Otherwise, you can turn touch vibrations down to low or off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKFwdX"&gt;The phone is both IP65 and IP68 rated, meaning there’s generous protection against water intrusion both from jets and immersion (up to 6.5 feet for up to 30 minutes). The DuraForce Ultra 5G meets the Military Standard 810H specifications and includes protection against vibration, blowing dust and sand, extreme temperatures, drops from five feet onto concrete, high altitudes, and plenty of other hostile conditions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="6wpa1D"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Aside from some minor scuffs acquired in the driveway test, the DuraForce Ultra 5G merely shrugged at my efforts and kept on working just fine&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hJWRm2"&gt;I couldn’t test it against all of those conditions, but I did subject the phone to plenty of abuse including an hourlong stay in the freezer, water immersion for 30 minutes in the kitchen sink, exposure to sand, and a drop from about five feet onto driveway asphalt. Aside from some minor scuffs acquired in the driveway test, the DuraForce Ultra 5G merely shrugged at my efforts and kept on working just fine. Kyocera does include a two-year warranty with purchase, so as long as you use the phone within the conditions it’s rated to withstand, you shouldn’t be putting your purchase at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpGg8x"&gt;In addition to rugged features, the DuraForce Ultra 5G is just loaded with buttons. There’s a power button with embedded fingerprint sensor, three programmable keys, and a large volume rocker that’s easy to press with gloves on. I frequently pressed one of the programmable buttons accidentally when I grabbed the phone — they’re in easy reach when you’re using the phone, but that unfortunately means a lot of unintentional presses, too. These buttons do require a long press to bring up whatever shortcut function you’ve assigned to them, so a brief press won’t do anything. You can also assign any of them to “do nothing” when pressed if you’d rather not use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FLffBgLPWI_Llf-npqmIGqOt0UY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22526445/ajohnson_20210514_4587_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GXpg0z"&gt;Kyocera DuraForce Ultra 5G screen, performance, and battery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="E8kAww"&gt;Aside from the obvious difference in appearance and ergonomics, the DuraForce Ultra 5G handles pretty much the way any other Android device does. The screen looks a little low on contrast in comparison to your standard display — likely because the panel is optimized for viewability in bright sunlight. That’s probably more important to the phone’s target user than a rich multimedia viewing experience, and the panel is indeed usable even in very bright direct light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sccb8"&gt;The screen’s protective “Sapphire Shield” remained free of scratches during my testing, but it does pick up reflections easily outside, more so than other phones with Gorilla Glass. It wasn’t enough to bother me, but someone planning to use the phone outside in bright light often might find it distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l13Zen"&gt;The DuraForce Ultra 5G ships with Android 10; Kyocera says it will provide an update to 11, but that the timeframe is still being determined. Android 10 is fine for now, but given that Google is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;readying Android 12 for the public&lt;/a&gt;, it’s definitely a step behind. Kyocera says it will provide a minimum of two years of security updates, which is a common if not terribly generous policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="EKwQAE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This model works with both widely available sub-6GHz frequencies and hard-to-find but much faster mmWave spectrum&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HPDPTP"&gt;The DuraForce Ultra 5G uses a Snapdragon 765G processor with 6GB RAM, which puts overall performance on par with a midrange phone. There’s some slight stuttering when scrolling quickly through screens with lots of images and video, and a noticeable pause after taking a photo in the camera app, but other than that it keeps up well — especially considering the lower performance bar in the rugged class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4mjmbC"&gt;There’s a 4,500mAh battery built into the DuraForce Ultra 5G. It’s a comparatively large battery for the class, and it got me through a full day of moderate to heavy use. The phone supports Qi wireless charging, which is uncommon among rugged phones. The phone was a little finicky on my stand-style Belkin wireless charger, but it eventually worked when set on the charger in landscape orientation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrNjuL"&gt;And of course, there’s one of the DuraForce Ultra 5G’s namesake features: 5G. This model works with both widely available sub-6GHz frequencies and hard-to-find but much faster mmWave spectrum (also called Ultra Wideband by Verizon, hence the UW in the phone’s name). It’s only sold through Verizon in the US, which makes sense: the company has been pushing mmWave much harder than the other major carriers and does offer more coverage, though it’s still relatively scarce. Verizon’s 5G network is kind of lackluster overall at this point, though it will improve over the next couple of years. It’s a good feature to have on a phone you’re going to hang onto for a while, but definitely don’t buy this (or any phone, really) just for mmWave since you’ll probably have a hard time finding a signal anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9K8_BvBox1IIgUPqGHpe6gIS1iE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22526441/ajohnson_20210514_4587_0003.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SstD0A"&gt;Kyocera DuraForce Ultra 5G camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="nEfbUr"&gt;The DuraForce Ultra’s rear camera array consists of a 24-megapixel f/1.8 standard wide and a 16-megapixel f/2.2 ultrawide, plus a time-of-flight sensor. Around front, there’s an 8-megapixel f/2.0 selfie camera. That’s a cut above what’s offered on many rugged phones. Picture-taking likely isn’t a high priority for prospective DuraForce Ultra owners, and image quality is certainly not up to what you’d find on conventional $900 phones, but it does the job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SUrxOC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10511127"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HkQEvB"&gt;Photos in good light look fine, if a bit on the low-contrast, washed-out side. Exposure and color can shift noticeably between two images taken with the same camera at slightly different angles, and I noticed some odd misses here and there, like a blurry shot of a static subject where it looked like the camera had tried to apply too much HDR. But most of the time in bright light, photos are perfectly fine, and a cut above what I’d expect from a rugged phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VPE5GH"&gt;There’s also a mode that will overlay live information on your still image or video about whatever extreme situation you happen to be in, including location, altitude, speed, and G-force. Extreme activities are generally not recommended in your second trimester of pregnancy, so I didn’t really test this out. I imagine if you’re into something like mountain biking or climbing and you want to record that kind of information with your activity, you probably have a better way of doing so already. In any case, it’s there, and it’s definitely more of a casual, fun feature than it is practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RdoMQqBzgM7hSRn2TD79gBmGDB8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22526440/ajohnson_20210514_4587_0002.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="lwm3nQ"&gt;If you’re merely curious about living a rugged phone lifestyle, the DuraForce Ultra 5G isn’t for you. The phone’s extremely hardy specifications would be appealing to anyone who’s nervous about dropping their phone or occasionally brings their phone to rough environments like beaches or backcountry camping. If that’s you, spend your $900 on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone"&gt;good standard phone&lt;/a&gt; (many are IP68 rated) and a rugged case. You’ll get better performance, a better camera, timelier software updates — basically, a lot more for the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="uGUklv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The inclusion of 5G, wireless charging, and processing power that’s a cut above the rest of the class makes it a good tool on and off the job site&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jansg3"&gt;If you need a rugged phone on the job as a frontline worker, first responder, or construction worker, for example, then the DuraForce Ultra 5G makes a lot more sense — especially if it’s going to be your primary phone off the job and you’d really like some extra bells and whistles. The inclusion of 5G, wireless charging, and processing power that’s a cut above the rest of the class makes it a good tool on and off the job site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8gd8RS"&gt;However, $900 is an awful lot to spend on a phone, and I think that very specific kind of customer for this phone is a pretty small group. You could buy a less expensive rugged phone with more limited functionality like &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/kyocera-duraforce-pro-2/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kyocera’s own DuraForce model from last year&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"&gt;darn good midrange phone&lt;/a&gt; for around the same price. You probably can’t get mmWave 5G that way, but that’s no great loss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Z3Jnx3"&gt;Still, the DuraForce Ultra 5G represents a convenient option for a particular type of person if two phones feels like too much fuss. It certainly handled everything I threw it at, and functioned well as a daily companion for more pedestrian tasks like scrolling social media and navigating trips across town. If extreme durability is a must and you don’t want to give up too much to get it, then the DuraForce Ultra 5G is a good choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z7POyJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="8YXrSG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10511100"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22446490/kyocera-duraforce-ultra-5g-uw-review-price-specs-screen-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22446490/kyocera-duraforce-ultra-5g-uw-review-price-specs-screen-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-21T04:08:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T04:08:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Smaller Pixel 6 leaks with flat screen and fewer cameras</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dWmKknsp9GG8QoIu3cza5DLzSH8=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69321632/PIXEL_6_5K3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jw8QBm"&gt;Yesterday &lt;em&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/em&gt; released CAD renders of what is supposedly Google’s next flagship phone, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen"&gt;the Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and now the noted leaker has followed up with details and images of the smaller model, &lt;a href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/google-pixel-6-renders-design-exclusive/"&gt;posted at &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The so-called Pixel 6 looks like it’ll adopt the same distinctive design as the Pro, with one colorway featuring orange and white sections broken up by a glossy black bar that houses the camera bump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27MzEy"&gt;You’ll find one fewer camera in that bump, according to the leak — it’s said to be a dual-camera setup, presumably a regular wide and an ultrawide. The 6 Pro, on the other hand, appears to include a periscope telephoto lens. Both phones are depicted with a single centrally aligned hole-punch selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wKCqlx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A 6.4-inch display without curved edges&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="On1SQc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt; says that the Pixel 6 has a 6.4-inch display with flat edges, unlike the curved 6.67-inch panel used in the 6 Pro. The 6 reportedly also has wireless charging, an in-display fingerprint sensor, and bottom-firing stereo speakers, with dimensions of 158.6mm x 74.8mm x 8.9mm. The &lt;em&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/em&gt; renders match up with designs shown off by &lt;em&gt;Front Page Tech&lt;/em&gt;’s Jon Prosser &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VzupAfbY8a4"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h2e31s"&gt;There’s no word on exactly when the Pixel 6 will launch, but Pixel phones do have a habit of leaking (or even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18663172/google-pixel-4-camera-sensor-design-official-photo"&gt;being announced by Google&lt;/a&gt;) well before their eventual release date, so we could well be waiting until fall. At this point, it’s almost a surprise that leakers managed to beat Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352032/google-pixel-5-4a-5g-price-release-date-specs"&gt;to the punch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWRPbb"&gt;Google has also said it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;planning to release a Pixel 5A phone&lt;/a&gt; later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T16:00:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T16:00:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Pixel 6 Pro could have a curved screen and a triple rear camera, new leak suggests</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9E-SsriP6IB3EtdUWxmBEjxESQ8=/400x0:4720x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319100/PIXEL_6_PRO_5K3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newly leaked renders suggest that Google isn’t playing it safe anymore with its next generation of Pixel devices.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: OnLeaks and digit.in&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aYaYqP"&gt;New images from reputable leaker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/onleaks"&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://www.digit.in/news/mobile-phones/exclusive-google-pixel-6-pro-rednders-leak-display-design-camera-59483.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;digit.in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) show what may be a bold step forward for Google’s Pixel series. The Pixel 6 Pro, as pictured in the alleged renders, could offer a 6.67-inch curved display and a rear triple-camera array — a Pixel first — including a periscope-style telephoto lens. OnLeaks later followed up via &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt; with supposed renders of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"&gt;smaller Pixel 6 phone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0Zh5G"&gt;This report also says that the 6 Pro will use an OLED screen, though there’s no confirmation of refresh rate, and will measure around 163.9 x 75.8 x 8.9mm. It’s expected to offer dual speakers and support wireless charging — features that are both available on the Pixel 5. There are some obvious differences in design, too, with the camera array moved to a raised, horizontal stripe across the back of the device and a bright accent color on the panel above it. There’s no confirmation with this leak whether the 6 Pro will include the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364543/google-pixel-6-custom-in-house-processor-gs101-whitechapel-arm-report"&gt;rumored, Google-designed “Whitechapel” SoC&lt;/a&gt; (system on a chip).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UC-GcKR-HRuFxfKOQmvNX-DYtno=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528954/PIXEL_6_PRO_5K1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OnLeaks and digit.in&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Renders show a rear triple-camera array including a periscope telephoto lens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MhZnlx"&gt;The naming shift from “XL” to “Pro” could also indicate a new relationship between the standard and big-screen models. In previous generations (the Pixel 5 never got an XL counterpart), the XL model was a “same phone, bigger screen” affair. Ditching that moniker for “Pro” could indicate that it’s both a bigger and higher-end device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kTkQGB"&gt;Google has taken a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;conservative approach recently&lt;/a&gt; to its Pixel hardware and design. This hasn’t been an entirely bad thing, and it’s earned Google’s handsets a reputation for simple, affordable design with great cameras and software. But if these renders are the real deal, then the company appears to be making a move to challenge other flagships with higher-end hardware. For now, there’s no confirmed release date for the Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro, but we’d expect Google to stick with its typical fall timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UoiiaR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, May 21st, 4.30AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added a link to the later story on the smaller Pixel 6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
