<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-23T18:42:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T18:42:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T18:42:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Docking a Surface Pen to your Surface Duo 2 phone will cost $65</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WyMvP5DuGsg6ky5Zp8t8PBo_Wzo=/0x250:3000x2250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69900827/Surface_Duo_2_with_Pen_under_embargo_until_September_22.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9XWxjW"&gt;Microsoft has a new phone of its own, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684814/microsoft-surface-duo-2-price-specs-features-release-date"&gt;Surface Duo 2&lt;/a&gt;, arriving October 21st — and if you buy an optional “Surface Duo 2 Pen Cover,” you’ll be able to magnetically dock and wirelessly charge the company’s optional &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;$130 Surface Slim Pen 2 stylus&lt;/a&gt; and use it with the Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9PYcA"&gt;The need for a special cover &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688403/surface-pro-8-duo-studio-x-go-true-price-keyboard-pen-stylus-bundle"&gt;wasn’t quite made clear&lt;/a&gt; during the company’s presentation last week, nor a price or release date, but &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/surface-duo-2-elusive-pen-cover-price-availability"&gt;Microsoft confirmed to &lt;em&gt;Windows Central &lt;/em&gt;today&lt;/a&gt; that it’ll cost $65 on October 21st. While that’s the same day the Surface Duo 2 is slated to launch, it strangely didn’t go up for pre-order alongside the phones, and still isn’t available to add to a cart now. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-duo-2-pen-cover%2F8P0W0GNK1WFT" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can find its product page here&lt;/a&gt;, with the Pen Cover listed as “Coming soon.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IdYBcp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how much buying into Microsoft’s pro Surface vision actually costs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688403/surface-pro-8-duo-studio-x-go-true-price-keyboard-pen-stylus-bundle"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Z6BUYc"&gt;The listing says it adds 32g (0.07oz) worth of weight to the phone, and shows that it’s not a full case, but rather a half shell combined with a couple of floating bumpers.  It’s also listed as being compatible with the original Surface Slim Pen, but it’s not clear whether it docks or charges the older pen, or (hopefully) both. You can get it in both colors (it seems to blend quite nicely with the phone) and it’ll have a fabric lining to protect the finish of your device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KUQomC0Nm_vagSQDCa7WLyCXFnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871089/surface_duo_pen_stick.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LQ2jLb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686707/microsoft-surface-duo-2-phone-design-specs-features-photos-hands-on"&gt;Here’s our first hands-on with the Surface Duo 2&lt;/a&gt;; We’ll have a full review further down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TTquPW"&gt;Microsoft says the original Surface Duo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690003/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11-update-release-date"&gt;will get an update to Android 11&lt;/a&gt; by year’s end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UQqraY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690565/surface-duo-2-pen-cover-price-release-date-slim-pen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690565/surface-duo-2-pen-cover-price-release-date-slim-pen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T16:58:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T16:58:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nokia’s new G50 is a $300 5G phone with a big battery and two years of OS upgrades</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-KxYIa3RB9oWPphcH1iu4V4w3Ic=/0x125:3000x2125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69895204/Nokia_G50___Beauty_1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G50 has a triple rear camera system.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nokia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sK3V8q"&gt;Nokia has a new midrange phone coming to the US and a number of global markets. The new G50 costs $299 and has all the ingredients to be competitive as a midrange phone, with a 6.82-inch HD+ display, big battery, audio jack and 18W fast charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MOnRac"&gt;This G-series phone is similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22372444/hmd-nokia-x20-specs-release-date-price-news-quad-camera"&gt;Nokia X20&lt;/a&gt; that was announced back in April 2021, but the G50 has a bigger screen and battery and comes in a version specifically designed for the North American market (AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile). Unsurprisingly, it supports the slower 5G Sub 6, which means this phone will work on T-Mobile’s 5G network, but not on Verizon’s mmWave network, and will only get 4G reception on AT&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9lJF9"&gt;Like other 5G phones in the $300 range, the Nokia G50 is powered by the modest Snapdragon 480 chip, so don’t expect the fastest performance or smoothest gaming experience on this phone. It has 4GB of RAM, 128GB of storage, as well as a microSD slot in case you need to backup your photos or sideload an app. Compared to Motorola’s identically named &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350611/motorola-g100-g50-launch-price-specs"&gt;G50&lt;/a&gt;, the Nokia has a slightly bigger HD+ 6.82-inch display that is capable of 450 nits of brightness and has a v-shaped notch around its front 8-megapixel camera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xulu-7vTpb5_FiBSErLXKOC0beI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22870595/Nokia_G50_Emotional_copy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nokia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G50 comes in two colors, a blue and a pink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k2WTe5"&gt;On the back of the Nokia G50 is a triple-camera array, arranged in a circle. You’ll probably use the 48-megapixel standard camera the most, while the 5-megapixel Ultrawide and 2-megapixel depth sensor cameras can bring some fun perspectives to your shots but will likely be of noticeably lower quality. Its front selfie camera also offers video stabilization to help sharpen your blurry Tik Tok videos and a Night Selfie mode to brighten your low-light selfies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dJBrqy"&gt;According to HMD Global, the maker of Nokia phones, the Nokia G50 will ship with Android 11 and receive two years of OS upgrades and three years of monthly security updates. In other words, this budget phone won’t turn into a brick in a few years, which is good for the environment and for consumers who want to get more use out of their phones before upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32jfJ0"&gt;The Nokia G50 is preloaded with Spotify and a 30-day trial of ExpressVPN and is available in Ocean Blue or Midnight Sun. It’s available for preorder starting today, September 22nd, at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FNokia.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F22%2F22687760%2Fnokia-g50-phone-battery-android-upgrades" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nokia.com&lt;/a&gt; and will ship on September 30th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KG6xoB"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O7V9xD0KdvI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687760/nokia-g50-phone-battery-android-upgrades"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687760/nokia-g50-phone-battery-android-upgrades</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T11:26:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T11:26:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Surface Duo 2 has all the features that were missing the first time around</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z42YUkT_VnzI-6knHhQnGJ8r5lA=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69893260/Surface_Duo_2___Front___Back_under_embargo_until_September_22.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Surface Duo 2&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QgsWeg"&gt;Microsoft has officially announced the new Surface Duo 2, its second attempt at an Android-powered folding phone. The Duo 2 retains the head-turning design of the first-generation model, but it specifically addresses &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21428763/microsoft-surface-duo-review"&gt;many of the complaints we had&lt;/a&gt;. This time around, Microsoft is putting a legit camera on it, supporting 5G, using a current processor, and is throwing in bigger screens — things that are all quite nice to have on expensive phones. Microsoft says the Duo 2 will be &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeSurfaceDuo2092221&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-duo-2%2F9408kgxp4xjl%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available starting on October 21st&lt;/a&gt; for $1,499.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tczJZJ"&gt;The Surface Duo 2, which is available in the same white color as the first-gen plus a new black option, has two 5.8-inch, 1344 x 1892 OLED displays connected by a hinge that allows you to open it like a book or prop it up like a tent. It’s a markedly different approach from what Samsung is doing with its folding phones, which have a single large screen that gets folded in half. Combined, the two Duo 2 displays measure 8.3 inches diagonally and both of them feature a faster 90Hz refresh rate. A slight curve on the screen allows it to be viewed when the Duo 2 is closed, showing you time and missed notifications. Covering the screens is Corning glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Am-qVTAAXoT0PrOda_FOFzF6bY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869965/Surface_Duo_2___Modes_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Duo 2 maintains the unique design of the first model.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xtppzUsJYDXp1-B7atPOX1httEg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869992/Surface_Duo_2_with_Pen_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The screens have a slight curve that lets them be visible when the Duo 2 is closed — Microsoft is using it as a notification panel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nmPlcG"&gt;Inside one half of the device is the Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 processor — a significant upgrade over the 855 chip that was in the first version. It also supports 5G connectivity, another upgrade from the 4G radio that was in the first Duo. Microsoft says it’s the thinnest 5G device on the market. Paired with the processor is 8GB of RAM (2GB more than the first gen) and between 128GB and 512GB of storage. Other hardware upgrades include NFC but no wireless charging, two things that were annoyingly omitted from the first Duo. Microsoft hasn’t specified how big the battery is, but it claims the usual line of “all day battery life.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kkGoGQQg36hoLpGkZ52I7iyqxms=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869830/lcimg_bcba6eed_01d5_42ab_96a7_8816551f23c4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Duo 2 has a triple rear camera system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hvqLI8"&gt;The original Surface Duo was laden with a single camera above the right screen, and frankly, it was terrible and one of the weakest points of the hardware. This time around, Microsoft has installed a proper three-camera system on the outside of the Duo 2, with a standard wide, ultrawide, and telephoto camera system. All three cameras have 12-megapixel resolution, with the wide and telephoto lens also featuring optical image stabilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkgpXk"&gt;Like the prior Duo, the Duo 2 supports pen input with Microsoft’s line of Surface Pens. You can magnetically stick the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt; to the outside of the Duo 2 to keep it with you on the go and it will charge while it’s sitting there. (But again, no wireless charging for the phone itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OXqFrjBdDb6T-zzpYZZzhFNy74M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869954/Surface_Duo_2___Editing_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Duo 2 works with Microsoft’s new Surface Slim Pen 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ap0L9g"&gt;Of course, the main pitch with the Duo line of products is productivity, since it’s essentially two standard smartphones connected by a hinge. That’s not changing this year and Microsoft says it has come up with more optimizations for sharing information between the two screens and spreading a single app across them. The company says 150 games, including &lt;em&gt;Asphalt Legends 9&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Modern Combat 5&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Dungeon Hunter 5&lt;/em&gt;, are optimized for using one screen as a controller while viewing the game itself on the other screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5TR4N7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder the Surface Duo 2","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22684018/microsoft-surface-duo-2-preorder-how-to-buy-price-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="iVixqE"&gt;But those promises were also made for the first Duo, and software support was where it really fell apart. Microsoft’s demos look impressive, but they did the first time around, too, so we’ll remain very skeptical until we’re able to test it out first hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2KbD3a"&gt;The Duo 2 is running Android 11 at launch, even though the original Duo is still saddled with Android 10 and Microsoft didn’t indicate when it might get the update to 11. Check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686707/microsoft-surface-duo-2-phone-desig-specs-features-photos-hands-on"&gt;hands-on with the Duo 2 here&lt;/a&gt; and stay tuned for our forthcoming review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OX9pbn"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gzk7kc"&gt;Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="LnmjkC"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Microsoft Surface Duo 2 hands-on #Shorts|104004" data-volume-uuid="c756ccf08" data-volume-id="104004" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-297" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684814/microsoft-surface-duo-2-price-specs-features-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684814/microsoft-surface-duo-2-price-specs-features-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T17:02:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T17:02:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Google Pixel 6 Pro may have been leaked in a brief hands-on video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google’s new Pixel 6 phones, regular and Pro" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SAHQ3fry4N3AD_R8tjhn_Eu_z2g=/448x0:7198x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890456/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WVVTzX"&gt;Google got ahead of any possible news leaks about the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;announcing the phones&lt;/a&gt; back in August, including that they would run on the company’s long-in-development Tensor chip. But it’s possible that some leakers have recently got hold of an actual unit. A video posted to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1440385355258028032"&gt;Twitter by @thisistechtoday&lt;/a&gt; may be showing off a pre-production version of the Pixel 6 Pro, complete with its triple rear camera array. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOCKvP"&gt;Of course, Google hasn’t been coy about sharing what the device will look like — even installing &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/first-look-google-puts-pixel-6-and-6-pro-on-display-at-its-nyc-store"&gt;dummy units in its NYC store for people to ogle&lt;/a&gt;. To that end, the device that’s spun around in this short clip looks like what we’ve seen so far — the strange Google logo placeholder notwithstanding. The phone in this video appears to have a hole-punch selfie camera, and all of its buttons are located along its right edge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G1CaYO"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I think this may be the first hands on video leak of a Google Pixel 6 Pro. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;FYI: The logo would indicate that this is likely an early production test unit, so that means there may be some differences between what you see here and the actual production device. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/teampixel?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#teampixel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4QSvdktqA7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4QSvdktqA7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— M. Brandon Lee | THIS IS TECH TODAY (@thisistechtoday) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1440385355258028032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6hP7jt"&gt;Just like the Pixel 6 Pro renders that Google shared, the phone in this video appears to have a &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0w_6uZBFl8F94sDwJAiydSFMAr4=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22755095/Pixel_6_Pro_Group_Image__Transparent_.png"&gt;metallic and glossy rail&lt;/a&gt; surrounding its raised camera bar, as opposed to the Pixel 6’s &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lGTDiRqYZ_v7B0qBMCPFTj6yxMo=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22755096/Pixel_6_Group_Image__Transparent_.png"&gt;darker, matte-textured &lt;/a&gt;rail. Admittedly, it’s tough to tell for sure in this footage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWDObJ"&gt;So while it isn’t as if we haven’t seen what the phone looks like, what’s notable in this video is that the display is powered on, which is an angle on the Pixel 6 or 6 Pro that we &lt;em&gt;haven’t&lt;/em&gt; seen much of, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664341/google-pixel-6-real-world-photos-october-19th-launch-date-rumor"&gt;outside of this new ad&lt;/a&gt;. Admittedly, though, it’s a rather boring glimpse, showing the same screen you see during the Android 12 setup process. The Pixel 6 Pro will have a 6.7-inch QHD+ screen with a 120Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kA26HW"&gt;We still don’t know exactly when Google plans to fully take the wraps off the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro or when it will share prices and a release date. But it ought to be soon, perhaps sometime in October, if previous years are any indication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="8bVh6t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Retailer leak suggests Google’s Pixel 6 will have 23W wireless charging","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22651097/google-pixel-6-pro-stand-23w-wireless-charging"},{"title":"Google’s first folding Pixel is apparently still on track for a 2021 reveal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"},{"title":"Google’s rumored Pixel 6 Tensor processor sounds extremely weird","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676099/google-pixel-6-tensor-processor-rumor-arm-cortex-x1-core-mystery-strange"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686534/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-display-screen-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686534/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-display-screen-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus says no 9T this year, 2022 flagship will run merged Oppo OS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ej-Aw0wIGriVZxekKUBKuHPgdzk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69881985/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0041_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021’s OnePlus 9.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KQLNEl"&gt;OnePlus CEO Pete Lau has confirmed that the company doesn’t plan to release its traditional T-series device in the second half of this year. He also announced that next year’s OnePlus flagship phone would run on a newly unified operating system, following the company’s integration with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538105/oneplus-oppo-merge-integration-ownership-bbk"&gt;fellow BBK Electronics subsidiary Oppo&lt;/a&gt;. OnePlus announced it would be merging the codebases of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560765/oneplus-oxygenos-coloros-oppo-android-updates"&gt;Android-based OxygenOS operating system with Oppo’s ColorOS&lt;/a&gt; in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="piK8i5"&gt;This means we’re unlikely to see a OnePlus 9T following up this year’s OnePlus 9. Despite the similar names, the company’s T-series phones have offered significant upgrades over its flagships from earlier in the year. For example, the 8T had around double the charging speeds of the 8, while the 7T bumped the original 7 display to a higher 90Hz refresh rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XCVMSE"&gt;“This year we will not be launching a T-series product,” Lau said via a translator in a roundtable interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and other journalists. This will be the first year without a T-series device since OnePlus adopted the release schedule with the OnePlus 3T in 2016. Since then, like clockwork, OnePlus has released a new T-series phone in the latter half of each year, culminating in last year’s OnePlus 8T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qclhlz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This year we will not be launching a T-series product”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AL8dUt"&gt;In what is effectively a merger between OnePlus and Oppo, the two companies will be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560765/oneplus-oxygenos-coloros-oppo-android-updates"&gt;unifying the underlying codebases of OxygenOS and Oppo’s ColorOS&lt;/a&gt;. The two Android-based operating systems will continue to have their own branding and unique features, Lau said, but the code underpinning them will be the same, and they’ll be developed by a unified team. The way OnePlus describes it, the approach will result in an operating system that’s “fast and smooth” and “clean and lightweight” like OxygenOS, while also being “reliable” and “smart and feature-rich” like ColorOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sa1Iiz"&gt;Lau said the codebase integration of the two operating systems was completed in June, and that it’s already helping to allow for more frequent software updates. But we’ll have to wait until next year to see the first OnePlus flagship launch with the newly integrated operating system. It won’t just be new OnePlus phones getting the new OS — it will also come to OnePlus’s older devices is they’re still scheduled to receive support. These support periods include three major updates for flagship phones, two for most Nord devices, and one for Nord N phones. Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22443128"&gt;Oppo announced&lt;/a&gt; that the OnePlus 9 series will receive a beta of the new software in October, followed by the OnePlus 8 series in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUUm1X"&gt;OnePlus tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that integrating its operations with Oppo was necessary to make it more efficient, and would streamline its R&amp;amp;D resources “to support more products and work more efficiently.” As well as integrating the two company’s operating systems, OnePlus also said it would be integrating its Warp Charge fast charging standard with Oppo’s SuperVOOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Twy7Da"&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-16/chinese-smartphone-giant-cuts-jobs-after-going-up-against-apple?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that Oppo’s merger with OnePlus is creating redundancies, including within its ColorOS development unit, as the two BBK subsidiaries pool resources. As many as 20 percent of staff across some software and device teams are reportedly being cut, according to the report. The cuts are reportedly the result of Oppo expanding too rapidly in recent years, moving aggressively into new countries and product categories with big bets that haven’t payed off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PmOB7c"&gt;During our briefing, however, which took place prior to the publication of &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s report, OnePlus’s Lau played down the possibility of merger-related layoffs. “[Redundancies haven’t] been something that’s come up during the merger,” Lau said via a translator, “We have a focus on bringing together the OnePlus and Oppo teams to be able to bring together the strengths of both sides into the merged entity.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22677640/oneplus-9t-cancelled-oppo-coloros-oxygenos-merger"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22677640/oneplus-9t-cancelled-oppo-coloros-oxygenos-merger</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T05:18:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T05:18:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google reportedly has a second foldable in the works</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cxim-Tpgm0VyRYWxUi4KayOnBhc=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69881709/dseifert_4711_samsung_z_flip_3_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s recent foldable, the Z Flip 3, is more hamburger than hotdog.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dCt8oQ"&gt;Google appears to be internally testing a second foldable Pixel smartphone, according to &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/09/18/pixel-fold-jumbojack-android-12-1/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;’s sources&lt;/a&gt;. The device is said to be under development with the codename “Jumbojack,” that’s referenced in a future version of Android 12 which &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; identifies as “Android 12.1.” This is the latest foldable codename we’ve heard about at Google, following reports of another device called &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"&gt;“Passport.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZ5d9v"&gt;Not much is known about what form Jumbojack could take, but &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; has a couple of key details. It seems to have two screens, with one that deactivates when the device is folded. That suggests we’re looking at a similar design to Samsung’s foldables, which combine a small external screen with a larger internal folding display. There’s no word on screen sizes or internal specs, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AnrUvZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A “hamburger style” design?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cZTjcr"&gt;Interestingly, there’s speculation that the Jumbojack codename could be a reference to Jack in the Box’s Jumbo Jack cheeseburger, an implication that the phone will fold “&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nostalgia/comments/cgyc1v/folding_paper_hot_dog_and_hamburger_style/"&gt;hamburger style&lt;/a&gt;” like a Z Flip as opposed to “hotdog style” like a Z Fold. But, much like the foodstuffs, that speculation is best taken with a good pinch of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FnHDK5"&gt;Unlike Passport, which reliable leaker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1439827216343474176"&gt;Evan Blass reported this morning&lt;/a&gt; is still scheduled to launch before the end of the year, there’s no indication about when or even if Jumbojack will see a commercial release. There’s a possibility it might just be an internal prototype, designed to help build foldable functionality like improved multitasking into Android itself. Regardless, its existence suggests Google is more serious about foldables that it initially appeared as the company gears up to produce its first true flagship competitor with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ywx2nC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 20th, 7:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added corroboration from Blass that Google’s “Passport” foldable is still expected to launch before the end of the year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZM9BaM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G3fuYu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYdUUg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ix95hi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gIxf6u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683566/google-jumbojack-foldable-passport-android-12-1-code-discovery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683566/google-jumbojack-foldable-passport-android-12-1-code-discovery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-17T11:58:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-17T11:58:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Man who unlocked nearly 2 million AT&amp;T phones gets 12 years in prison</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ffA3FMgQnYuDOhWIF_-ao2nzJ9c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69872392/acastro_170629_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Man who pleaded guilty in a phone-unlocking case sentenced to prison | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pV3pLw"&gt;A man who the Department of Justice says unlocked AT&amp;amp;T customers’ phones for a fee was sentenced to 12 years in prison, in what the judge called “a terrible cybercrime over an extended period,” which allegedly continued even after authorities were on to the scheme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBuDgD"&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/fraudster-sentenced-prison-long-running-phone-unlocking-scheme-defrauded-att"&gt;news release from the DOJ&lt;/a&gt;, in 2012, Muhammad Fahd, a citizen of Pakistan and Grenada, contacted an AT&amp;amp;T employee via Facebook and offered the employee “significant sums of money” to help him secretly unlock AT&amp;amp;T phones, freeing the customers from any installment agreement payments and from AT&amp;amp;T’s service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3xzJDB"&gt;Fahd used the alias Frank Zhang, according to the DOJ, and persuaded the AT&amp;amp;T employee to recruit other employees at its call center in Bothell, Washington, to help with the elaborate scheme. Fahd instructed the AT&amp;amp;T employees to set up fake businesses and phony bank accounts to receive payments, and to create fictitious invoices for deposits into the fake accounts to create the appearance that money exchanged as part of the scheme was payment for legitimate services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQH2QO"&gt;In 2013, however, AT&amp;amp;T put into place a new unlocking system which made it harder for Fahd’s crew to unlock phones’ unique IMEI numbers, so according to the DOJ he hired a developer to design malware that could be installed on AT&amp;amp;T’s computer system. This allegedly allowed him to unlock more phones, and do so more efficiently. The AT&amp;amp;T employees working with Fahd helped him access information about its systems and other employees’ credentials, allowing his developer to tailor the malware more precisely, the DOJ said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2ePck"&gt;A forensic analysis by AT&amp;amp;T showed Fahd and his helpers fraudulently unlocked more than 1.9 million phones, costing the company more than $200 million. Fahd was arrested in Hong Kong in 2018 and extradited to the US in 2019. He pleaded guilty in September 2020 to conspiracy to commit wire fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LfQ3wT"&gt;It’s not clear from the DOJ release whether anyone besides AT&amp;amp;T was harmed as a result of the scheme; there’s no mention of customers’ phones being otherwise compromised or any personal data being accessed. We’ve reached out to the DOJ to clarify whether any AT&amp;amp;T customers were affected. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679359/man-unlocked-att-phones-sentenced-prison-fraud"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679359/man-unlocked-att-phones-sentenced-prison-fraud</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-17T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-17T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 9 software update pays homage to the Hasselblad XPan camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OZhkicbL2_QIPVHCCEJhAMJ1jyw=/934x0:3210x1517/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69871178/OnePlus9__XPan_BW_02_Horizontal.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sample photo captured using the Hasselblad XPlan Mode, on the OnePlus 9 Pro.&lt;/em&gt; | OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FdkfP2"&gt;OnePlus is finally putting its camera partnership with Hasselblad to good use — by bringing the look and feel of Hasselblad’s cinematic XPan camera to the OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro, via a software update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yan7a"&gt;This is a happy surprise because the 9 Series’ cameras did not initially live up to the hype surrounding OnePlus’ multiyear collaboration with the historic camera brand. Although Hasselblad’s contribution to these phones was limited to helping OnePlus tune its camera colors and providing input on its interface earlier this year, as Allison Johnson noted in her &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;OnePlus 9 review&lt;/a&gt;, “the Hasselblad color tuning is fine but nothing remarkable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJMYB5"&gt;This update adds an XPan Mode for the OnePlus 9 Series camera, alongside some much needed practical patches. The XPan Mode replicates the focal lengths, colors, and processing of the original XPan camera for the phone, allowing you to capture wide aspect ratio images from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro (top) and OnePlus 9" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_UfNp20O_8zgIzOiysC0tStFCjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388886/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0061_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro and OnePlus 9 work with Hasselblad to fine-tune their cameras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Hkbskn"&gt;The Hasselblad XPan was the first dual-frame 35mm camera on the market that lets photographers capture wide, panoramic shots at the time of capture. It has a physical switch that helped photographers switch seamlessly between shooting single frames and (wide) photos across two frames, so they don’t have to risk losing all their photos by changing film between different sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RqEPos"&gt;Just like the camera, the XPan Mode will capture photos with a 65:24 (8:3) aspect ratio. “The images taken on XPan Mode are cropped from the [OnePlus 9 Series] 48MP main camera and 50MP ultra-wide camera instead of the default 12MP mode,” according to the press release. That should result in 20-megapixel-plus files, once the crop is applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="BJ3IPA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi Pro ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0kdb9C"&gt;There’s also the option to shoot panoramic photos at either 30mm or 45mm focal lengths, mimicking the Hasselblad camera’s classic lenses. You can, of course, compose and preview their shots by toggling between the two views within the OnePlus camera app. These images will be high resolution as well — 7552 × 2798 resolution on 30mm and 7872 × 2916 resolution on 45mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y8TfJo"&gt;Taking advantage of the OnePlus 9 Series’ 2-megapixel monochrome camera, the XPan Mode will take black and white photos by default, but you will be able to switch to full color to capture images. Hasselblad has also created custom black-and-white and color profiles for the XPan Mode. These sample XPan images from OnePlus certainly look promising: cinematic black-and-white with plenty of drama, and expansive panoramas with a more natural color palette for which OnePlus is known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZqbigJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10757042"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ljiSNe"&gt;In case these film camera touches aren’t enough for you photo aficionados, OnePlus even added in animation to mimic the negative film being developed into an image, when you press the shutter button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sSrUmz"&gt;If this is just the first glimpse of OnePlus’ partnership with Hasselblad, then I’m excited to see what else these companies can come up with in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qf6mvv"&gt;Other fixes that are included in this OTA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="da5X5a"&gt;Optimize the wireless charging experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EWccKR"&gt;Update Android security patch to September 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jy6t0N"&gt;Fix known issues and improved stability &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="38H18F"&gt;Optimize HDR frame retrieving algorithms and reduced noise in multiple scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kPeI6z"&gt;Fix the over-sharpening issues in auto mode scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rQfIwD"&gt;Improve stability of auto white balance in auto mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BI8lHP"&gt;Optimize auto white balance when shifting between the main and ultrawide camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pkhulR"&gt;Reduce over-brightening of images on Nightscape Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gfSDhn"&gt;Improve the dynamic range in low-light conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4pUgSh"&gt;Improve success rate when shooting moving objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L4dEUb"&gt;Update the memory optimization solution and reduced the launch time of the native camera app by up to 50 percent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="51W2Mq"&gt;Reduce lag in camera preview and optimized the shutter lag in some scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="YJC4jT"&gt;This update will be rolling out to OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro starting today, September 17th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MOYbxI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22676350/oneplus-9-camera-update-hasselblad-xpan-film-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22676350/oneplus-9-camera-update-hasselblad-xpan-film-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-17T05:01:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-17T05:01:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo shows off new ColorOS 12 following OnePlus merger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L5l0v5noQYXZNExABezXYdFqHlI=/0x1:1440x961/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69870883/New_UI_Design_2.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="00FTRV"&gt;Oppo has announced ColorOS 12, the latest version of its Android-based operating system. The update will come to OnePlus phones as well as Oppo’s own phones in China, where OnePlus has used ColorOS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344054/oneplus-9-oppo-coloros-in-china-hydrogenos"&gt;since early this year&lt;/a&gt;. OnePlus recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560765/oneplus-oxygenos-coloros-oppo-android-updates"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would be combining the codebase of its OxygenOS with ColorOS due to the two companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22543184/oppo-oneplus-merger-brand-pete-lau-bbk-memo"&gt;merging several operations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pPTVrI"&gt;ColorOS 12 doesn’t look hugely different to 11, but it makes more use of contrasting colors and white space, with lower information density across many screens. Icons have been subtly redesigned to make more use of depth and texture. Oppo says it’s improved more than 300 animations throughout the UI while also making use of an AI engine to reduce lag and stuttering.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E4rYXrbNSJZcM-juHwxvwB1H_5w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857281/Omoji_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wWMgvI"&gt;ColorOS 12 is based on Android 12 and adopts its upgraded privacy tools, like adding a notification in the status bar when apps activate the camera or microphone. As for new features, Oppo is adding the ability to operate its phones through a Windows 10 or 11 laptop, more tools to the sidebar that can be swiped in from the edge of the screen, and a strangely familiar 3D avatar feature called... Omoji. Yep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mWGmJ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Oppo Find X3 Pro review: the Chinese phone to beat","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22411538/oppo-find-x3-pro-review"},{"title":"Leaked memo confirms OnePlus will become an Oppo sub-brand","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22543184/oppo-oneplus-merger-brand-pete-lau-bbk-memo"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="UQdiPD"&gt;ColorOS 12 will first be available on a new “Photographer Edition” of Oppo’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22411538/oppo-find-x3-pro-review"&gt;excellent Find X3 Pro flagship phone&lt;/a&gt;. In October, there’ll be a limited public beta in China for the Find X3 series and the OnePlus 9 series, expanding to earlier models in November and December. Overall, Oppo says that more than 110 models of phone and 150 million users worldwide will be able to upgrade to ColorOS 12.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679087/oppo-oneplus-coloros-12-update-announced-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679087/oppo-oneplus-coloros-12-update-announced-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-16T17:14:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-16T17:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hundreds of T-Mobile stores will be able to fix phones soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="T-Mobile Data Breach Affects 40 Million People" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/19ADhN7Y624a9A-3P9RN9ehAdP8=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69869166/1334909491.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="li5Bon"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fdevices%2Ft-mobile-adds-in-store-repairs-and-more-device-protection-benefits-for-customers&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F16%2F22677969%2Ft-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile announced&lt;/a&gt; that 500 of its retail stores would start offering repair services starting on November 1st. The company says technicians will provide same-day fixes using manufacturer-approved parts to customers who subscribe to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fdevices%2Fphone-protection-plans&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F16%2F22677969%2Ft-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its Protection&amp;lt;360&amp;gt; service&lt;/a&gt;, which also includes device replacement in case of loss or theft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RPKppu"&gt;T-Mobile is also improving that device protection plan by letting customers make five claims in a 12-month period, up from the previous limit of three. The claims are handled by Assurant and come with a deductible based on what kind of phone you have and what kind of claim you’re making. Still, it’s likely to be cheaper than buying five new phones if you wind up having &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/s-1WxfsJzPM?t=33"&gt;an 18-karat run of bad luck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZuvseH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Assurant technicians will be handling the in-store repairs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cSZCc0"&gt;Interestingly, this change has echoes of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587790/t-mobile-sprint-acquisition-dish-promises"&gt;contentious T-Mobile / Sprint merger&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;a href="https://mytmoclaim.com/media/3234583/CL05179-0821-TMO_NW_Buckslip_Brochure.pdf"&gt;a brochure for Protection&amp;lt;360&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;, T-Mobile pitches the changes as providing “the same key features you enjoyed under the Sprint Complete plan” and lists the five claims and walk-in repairs as benefits that were previously available. At one point, Sprint had around 1,300 repair centers according to a support document (though T-Mobile tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it currently has 450), making T-Mobile’s 500 stores a little less impressive. As of fall 2020, when the merger was completed, the carrier &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sprint.com%2Fen%2Flandings%2Fwelcome-to-your-new-experience%3Famp%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F16%2F22677969%2Ft-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported having over 7,500 retail locations&lt;/a&gt;, so there’s room for expansion. T-Mobile says that its current repair locations will cover “nearly every major city” in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PkYMLf"&gt;Still, it’s good to see that T-Mobile is at least looking to continue providing in-person repair services. While the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570826/president-joe-biden-executive-order-right-to-repair"&gt;battle for right-to-repair&lt;/a&gt; rages, a trend of the mobile industry making repairs more widely available is spreading. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18691649/best-buy-apple-iphone-mac-ipad-repairs-all-stores"&gt;Best Buy started offering authorized repairs&lt;/a&gt; for iPhones, and Apple has made progress on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357187/apple-independent-repair-program-in-over-200-countries"&gt;expanding its Independent Repair Provider program&lt;/a&gt; (though the program has gotten pushback for some of its requirements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2a2uvd"&gt;If you’re looking to add T-Mobile’s protection plan to your service to take advantage of in-person repair, the restrictions are worth noting. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fdevices%2Fprotectionandlt360andgt-and-device-protection%23heading5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F16%2F22677969%2Ft-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The company says&lt;/a&gt; you can only enroll within 30 days of a qualifying event, like buying a T-Mobile device or bringing your own device to the network. There may also be an inspection process to make sure your phone is working before it's covered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RT74Xw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 16th, 6:48PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added additional information on the number of Sprint and T-Mobile repair centers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/16/22677969/t-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/16/22677969/t-mobile-retail-store-repair-protection-program-increased-claims</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
