<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-02T17:15:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T17:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T17:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new always-on smartphone camera is a potential privacy nightmare</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lACklgffxG8nz2hmhVQIaneWy-g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214589/akrales_190819_3594_0298.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The front-facing camera on a Samsung smartphone. Next year’s Qualcomm processor will allow these cameras to always scan for your face, even when you’re not using the phone.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CytRJa"&gt;“Your phone’s front camera is always securely looking for your face, even if you don’t touch it or raise to wake it.” That’s how Qualcomm Technologies vice president of product management Judd Heape &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3H6tfcZLHfg?t=10758"&gt;introduced the company’s new always-on camera capabilities&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"&gt;Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor&lt;/a&gt; set to arrive in top-shelf Android phones early next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5nmar7"&gt;Depending on who you are, that statement can either be exciting or terrifying. For Qualcomm, it thinks this new feature will enable new use cases, like being able to wake and unlock your phone without having to pick it up or have it instantly lock when it no longer sees your face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SzXm3P"&gt;But for those of us with any sense of how modern technology is used to violate our privacy, a camera on our phone that’s always capturing images &lt;em&gt;even when we’re not using it&lt;/em&gt; sounds like the stuff of nightmares and has a cost to our privacy that far outweighs any potential convenience benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="TBcjBh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A camera that looks for your image even when you’re not using it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eyu2fQ"&gt;Qualcomm’s main pitch for this feature is for unlocking your phone any time you glance at it, even if it’s just sitting on a table or propped up on a stand. You don’t need to pick it up or tap the screen or say a voice command — it just unlocks when it sees your face. I can see this being useful if your hands are messy or otherwise occupied (in its presentation, Qualcomm used the example of using it while cooking a recipe to check the next steps). Maybe you’ve got your phone mounted in your car, and you can just glance over at it to see driving directions without having to take your hands off the steering wheel or leave the screen on the entire time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrZO2W"&gt;The company is also spinning it as making your phone &lt;em&gt;more secure&lt;/em&gt; by automatically locking the phone when it no longer sees your face or detects someone looking over your shoulder and snooping on your group chat. It can also suppress private information or notifications from popping up if you’re looking at the phone with someone else. Basically, if you’re not looking at it, your phone is locked; if it can see you, it will be unlocked. If it can see you &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; someone else, it can automatically lock the phone or hide private information or notifications from displaying on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ngEJ0r"&gt;But while those features may sound neat and perhaps even convenient, I’m not convinced that having an always-on camera is worth the tradeoff in privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V6biDe"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3H6tfcZLHfg?rel=0&amp;amp;start=10758" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xrqwzE"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;The always-on camera features are discussed at hour three of Qualcomm’s four-hour presentation introducing the Snapdragon Gen 1 system-on-chip.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qwLEwb"&gt;Qualcomm is framing the always-on camera as similar to the always-on microphones that have been in our phones for years. Those are used to listen for voice commands like “Hey Siri” or “Hey Google” (or lol, “Hi Bixby”) and then wake up the phone and provide a response, all without you having to touch or pick up the phone. But the difference is that they are listening for specific wake words and are often limited with what they can do until you do actually pick up your phone and unlock it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xePhtk"&gt;It feels a bit different when it’s a camera that’s always scanning for a likeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vTo21a"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An always-on camera is a step beyond the always-on microphones already in our phones&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wRk5tL"&gt;It’s true that smart home products already have features like this. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/9/20855944/google-nest-hub-max-review-assistant-smart-display-price-specs-features"&gt;Google’s Nest Hub Max&lt;/a&gt; uses its camera to recognize your face when you walk up to it and greet you with personal information like your calendar. Home security cameras and video doorbells are constantly on, looking for activity or even specific faces. But those devices are in your home, not always carried with you everywhere you go, and generally don’t have your most private information stored on them, like your phone does. They also frequently have features like physical shutters to block the camera or intelligent modes to disable recording when you’re home and only resume it when you aren’t. It’s hard to imagine any phone manufacturer putting a physical shutter on the front of their slim and sleek flagship smartphone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgoU53"&gt;Lastly, there have been many reports of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322122/verkada-hack-150000-security-cameras-tesla-factory-cloudflare-jails-hospitals"&gt;security breaches&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21028092/amazon-ring-camera-hack-password-security-privacy-access-2fa"&gt;social engineering hacks&lt;/a&gt; to enable smart home cameras when they aren’t supposed to be on and then send that feed to remote servers, all without the knowledge of the homeowner. Modern smartphone operating systems now do a good job of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22634128/privacy-android-12-dashboard-apps-sensors"&gt;telling you when an app is accessing your camera or microphone&lt;/a&gt; while you’re using the device, but it’s not clear how they’d be able to inform you of a rogue app tapping into the always-on camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G3UlWw"&gt;In his presentation, Heape said that “always-on camera data never leaves the secure sensing hub while it’s looking for faces,” implying that the data isn’t sent to the cloud and that apps on the phone won’t be able to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXVxf3"&gt;In a follow up conversation after this article was originally published, Heape further clarified how the system works on a technical level. The always-on camera is part of a chain that includes a new low-power image signal processor (ISP) and a machine learning step. All three stages — the camera, the ISP, and the machine learning — are “hardened”, according to Heape, he says that it isn’t possible to inject code into the chain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPTcLp"&gt;The always-on camera is limited to a VGA (640 x 480 pixel) resolution, even though it uses the phone’s existing front-facing camera, and the rest of the phone’s systems — the main processor, cellular radios, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, etc — are turned off. Heape said this low-power ISP “cannot capture photos or video” and  “no image or video is stored” in this process, it only scans to detect if there is a face or not. If the machine learning algorithm determines a face is detected, the rest of the phone’s systems are awakened to authenticate the user and unlock the phone or deny access to it. “It is impossible in the low power state to get an image out of it,” says Heape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G6VI9c"&gt;The system does not have a way to inform you that its always-on camera is running, like other facial recognition systems use. Heape said that an OEM could choose to add an indicator such as an LED light if they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AjTYfM"&gt;Another Qualcomm Technologies vice president of product management Ziad Asghar told my colleague Chaim Gartenberg that users will also be able to disable the always-on camera feature or possibly even select which features they want to use and which they don’t. “The consumer has the choice to be able to pick and choose as to what is enabled and what’s not enabled,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TP4UtH0DVT_0Q539UAZ_GsuJDKM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16257180/vpavic_190510_3415_0161.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 7 Pro hid its entire camera system in a motorized pop-up module. Perhaps it’s time to bring this idea back.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SFe78n"&gt;It’s also possible that the smartphone manufacturers using the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 won’t even enable this feature at a hardware level. Since Qualcomm doesn’t actually make the smartphones its chips go in (outside of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568641/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-technology"&gt;one-off novelties&lt;/a&gt; that aren’t widely purchased), companies like Samsung, OnePlus, and Xiaomi can customize which features are enabled on their phones and which aren’t. Heape said that an OEM can request a Snapdragon chip with the feature disabled at the hardware level. Some of those companies already bypass Qualcomm’s image processing components in favor of their own solutions — it’s not hard to see them just skipping the criticisms of privacy concerns and forgoing this feature as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="0jhcqA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An unsettling and uncomfortable precedent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UPTiXp"&gt;But even if it’s not found in every phone next year, the mere presence of the feature means that it will be used by someone at some point. It sets a precedent that is unsettling and uncomfortable; Qualcomm may be the first with this capability, but it won’t be long before other companies add it in the race to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5e4X5"&gt;Ultimately, it comes down to a level of trust — do you trust that Qualcomm has set up the system in a way that prevents the always-on camera from being used for other purposes than intended? Do you trust that the OEM using Qualcomm’s chips won’t do things to interfere with the system, either for their own profit or to satisfy the demands of a government entity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UJm86m"&gt;Even if you do have that trust, there’s a certain level of comfort with an always-on camera on your most personal device that goes beyond where we are currently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lugMRK"&gt;Maybe we’ll just start having to put tape on our smartphone cameras like we already do with laptop webcams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naQ17K"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 5:15PM ET, December 2nd, 2021:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; After this article was published, Qualcomm vice president of product management Judd Heape gave further information about how the always-on camera system works on a technical level. The company also clarified that the system does not identify the faces it detects; that is handled by the phone’s existing facial identification authentication systems. The article has been updated with this new information and the headline has been changed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22811740/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-always-on-camera-privacy-security-concerns"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22811740/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-always-on-camera-privacy-security-concerns</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T23:06:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T23:06:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple may have a problem with iPhone demand as well as supply</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Mini and iPhone 13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6Pt_bloSZ8pfkCa6qYK5dcV02U=/0x0:2002x1335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70218007/vpavic_210916_4760_0240.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4oAmLl"&gt;Apple is indicating to its iPhone 13 component suppliers that it may not order as many units as expected due to a drop in demand, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-02/apple-tells-suppliers-iphone-demand-has-slowed-as-holidays-near"&gt;report in Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCBnNe"&gt;While the company had already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723209/apple-iphone-13-chip-shortage-manufacturing-report"&gt;cut&lt;/a&gt; orders for the year to 80 million — down from a target of 90 million — it was reportedly planning to make up for much of the drop next year. Now, though, Apple is said to have told manufacturing partners that this may not happen and they might not see the expected boost in orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpdk2u"&gt;Like almost every other technology company, Apple has been dealing with supply issues brought on by the global semiconductor shortage. CEO Tim Cook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751418/apple-q4-2021-earnings-supply-constraints-chip-shortage"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the company’s last quarterly earnings took an estimated $6 billion hit due to the shortage as well as the impact of COVID-19 on manufacturing in Southeast Asia, and Apple was expecting an even bigger impact on this current holiday quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0UmohO"&gt;If Bloomberg’s report is accurate, though, it suggests that the iPhone 13 range might not meet Apple’s initial expectations even without the supply crunch. The original plan to assemble 90 million units for 2021 reflected a forecast of increased demand, as Apple usually orders around 75 million iPhones for the year of each launch. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22813347/apple-iphone-demand-suppliers-chip-shortage-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22813347/apple-iphone-demand-suppliers-chip-shortage-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:02:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:02:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>HMD Global backs out of Nokia 9 PureView Android 11 upgrade, blames camera system</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nokia 9 PureView" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OgDw6J8vmWJnNazmzV-cxiM1vRg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216530/bfarsace_190210_3229_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia 9 PureView was launched in 2019 with a rare five-camera system.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tcIFwQ"&gt;HMD Global is not only reneging on its promise to bring Android 11 to the Nokia 9 PureView, but it is also dangling a discount for a new phone at customers who just found out their current devices are no longer supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RboZRa"&gt;These are customers who paid between $599 and $699 for the premium Nokia 9 PureView back in 2019 after it made quite a splash with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/2/24/18234962/nokia-9-pureview-cameras-5-features-specs-multiple-price-release-date-photos-hands-on-mwc-2019"&gt;quintuple rear camera array at World Mobile Congress&lt;/a&gt; that year. At the time, Nokia was even known as the best phone brand for receiving fast software updates, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/2/20844444/android-updates-still-take-forever-study-says"&gt;according to Counterpoint Research&lt;/a&gt;, so customers understandably might have felt they could trust Nokia and HMD Global. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HD1C0N"&gt;As one of the devices in the &lt;a href="https://www.android.com/intl/en_in/one/"&gt;Android One program&lt;/a&gt;, the Nokia 9 PureView runs a near-stock version of Android 9 and is supposed to get at least two years of OS upgrades and three years of security updates. Although the phone got upgraded to Android 10 in December 2019, it has not received any other OS updates since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHL5As"&gt;HMD Global said it is unable to update the Nokia 9 PureView with Android 11 because “[i]ncompatibilities between the camera and the software would have led to a compromised experience that does not meet our high standards,“ &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-9-upgrade&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to its statement&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps because its quintuple cameras were co-developed with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/12/21289574/light-camera-company-exits-smartphone-business"&gt;Light, the camera company that has quit smartphone photography&lt;/a&gt;, HMD Global just cannot overcome this technical challenge. That said, the company said the phone will continue to receive security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uImLeyLTb-iHesU6EO6GZjGjQEs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/14130617/bfarsace_190213_3229_0067.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;HMD blames the 9 PureView’s unique camera array for being unable to update it to Android 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iGvNKt"&gt;Rather than let current owners trade in their now-unsupported devices, HMD Global comes across as trying to profit on those affected customers by asking them to buy a new Nokia phone. “[F]or those of you looking to make the jump to Android 11,” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-9-upgrade&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to its website for Nokia 9 PureView owners&lt;/a&gt;, “we’re offering a 50% discount on Nokia XR20, or another device depending on regional availability.” First of all, the midrange &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-xr-20%3Fsku%3DVMA750D9FI1CN0&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nokia XR 20&lt;/a&gt; is hardly a substitute for the premium Nokia 9 PureView, and you need to jump through some hoops just to get that discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VE7U5O"&gt;At a time when Android phone makers are trying to differentiate themselves by modeling after Apple’s four-year-plus software support for iPhones, cases like HMD Global backpedaling on the Nokia 9 PureView’s update just remind us not to take these promises too seriously. Bigger companies like Samsung might have more resources to deliver on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;four years of security updates&lt;/a&gt; for its huge portfolio of devices, but smaller outfits like HMD Global and &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/motorola-software-updates-rant/"&gt;Motorola just don’t have a good track record&lt;/a&gt;. While software support is something to consider when making a phone buying decision — especially when we’re holding onto our phones longer between upgrade cycles — it should not be &lt;em&gt;the &lt;/em&gt;deciding factor for an Android because it just might not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YwO2fv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pmzOZe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811988/hmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811988/hmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T15:46:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T15:46:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Honor 60 announced in China with vlogging-focused gesture controls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uW00EkpePKhkR1gC7X0Eem4Tkd0=/0x1:5999x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216451/HONOR_60_All.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Honor 60 series.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Honor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DIHeSZ"&gt;Honor, the former Huawei sub-brand that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570744/huawei-honor-sale-announced-us-sanctions"&gt;split from the Chinese tech giant last year&lt;/a&gt;, has announced its latest handsets for the Chinese market. The Honor 60 and Honor 60 Pro are two midrange handsets powered by Qualcomm’s recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22740748/qualcomm-snapdragon-695-778-plus-480-680-5g-4g-smartphone-chips"&gt;Snapdragon 778G Plus processor&lt;/a&gt;, but otherwise, they’re very similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536512/honor-50-series-pro-release-date-news-features-google-mobile-services-apps-play-store"&gt;Honor 50 series phones&lt;/a&gt; released earlier this year, right down to having similar dual-ring camera bumps on the rear of each phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ythUCQ"&gt;A notable new feature for both new phones is support for hand gesture controls, which let you perform actions like making the “Okay” gesture or raising your hand to perform camera controls like switching between its front and back cameras, or enabling picture-in-picture mode. The phone can recognize five hand gestures in total, and Honor says features like these make vlogging “easier than ever.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pfNLCL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Releasing in China on December 10th&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TlilDF"&gt;Honor is far from the first smartphone company to have added hand gestures like these, with everyone from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20907715/google-pixel-4-motion-sense-gesture-controls-radar-sensor-project-soli-demo-features"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/sg/support/mobile-devices/how-to-use-palm-gesture-to-take-selfie-on-samsung-mobile-device/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/9/18301982/lg-g8-thinq-review-android-phone-snapdragon-855-6-gb-ram-z-camera-sensor"&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt; having experimented with similar features. These controls tended to be laggy and inexact in the past, so Honor’s tech has a lot to prove. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KKJIeD"&gt;Both phones have triple rear camera setups for when you get filming. On the 60 Pro, there’s a 108-megapixel main camera, a 50-megapixel combined ultrawide and macro camera, and a 2-megapixel depth sensor. The big improvement here is with the ultrawide, which was only 8 megapixels on the 50 Pro. The 60 Pro also has a high resolution 50-megapixel selfie camera. Meanwhile, the regular Honor 60 has a lower resolution 32-megapixel front-facing camera, triple rear cameras with a lower resolution 8-megapixel ultrawide, and no mention of macro photography capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KBeyi"&gt;Both phones have 120Hz curved OLED displays, though the 60 Pro’s is slightly bigger (at 6.78 inches) and curves around all four sides of the device, &lt;a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/honor_60_pro_arrives_with_snapdragon_778g_50mp_ultra_wide_cam_honor_60_gets_a_larger_120hz_display-news-52093.php"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;GSMArena&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, while the Honor 60 has a 6.67-inch display that curves around its left and right sides. Internally, both phones have 4,800mAh batteries, a small increase from the 4,000 and 4,300mAh batteries found in the 50 Pro and 50. Both charge at a maximum of 66W, which is in line with the Honor 50, but a slight downgrade from the Honor 50 Pro’s 100W fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQEXKc"&gt;Honor has yet to confirm a global launch for the phones, but it’s worth noting that if either phone were to release outside of China, they’d be able to come preinstalled with Google’s apps and services, just like the Honor 50. Huawei, meanwhile, is still subject to US sanctions that prevent it from shipping phones with Google’s proprietary software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0kJAgh"&gt;The Honor 60 series has only been announced for the Chinese market so far, with no confirmed plans for a global launch. But there was only a matter of months between the launch of the Honor 50 in China and its release in the rest of the world, so we shouldn’t have too long to wait if there’s a global release coming. In China, both phones will be available on December 10th. The Honor 60 will start at ¥2,699 (around $424), while &lt;em&gt;GSMArena&lt;/em&gt; notes the Honor 60 Pro starts at ¥3,700 (around $581). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811963/honor-60-pro-china-release-date-news-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811963/honor-60-pro-china-release-date-news-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T12:48:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T12:48:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify Wrapped 2021 is here to take over your social media</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Spotify Wrapped 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KswJpE7orzWXqd1hpuu52f7VTY0=/0x131:1216x942/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215366/PR_2021_Minutes.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Spotify Wrapped 2021 | Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u1KAT4"&gt;Spotify &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-12-01/the-wait-is-over-your-spotify-2021-wrapped-is-here/"&gt;has released its eagerly anticipated&lt;/a&gt; Wrapped experience revealing the most listened to artists and albums for (most of) 2021. This year, it’s adding even more social media-friendly features that help you share your favorite music with a customized movie, aura, or playing cards. Naturally, you can share Spotify’s auto-created images on your timeline and, for the first time, directly to TikTok. It’s sure to spark discussions with friends and provide valuable marketing for Spotify that competitors like Apple and YouTube can’t seem to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUsBKX"&gt;Here’s how to find your Spotify 2021 Wrapped experience. To get all of the interactive features, you’ll need to open the Spotify mobile app — it’s not available on the desktop or web version. If you’re on an iPhone or Android device, just &lt;a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/wrapped/"&gt;click this link&lt;/a&gt; and it should open the correct page inside the app. If you’re not seeing it yet, try refreshing the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jltz5g"&gt;If you don’t have Spotify or aren’t seeing it yet, these are some of the new features it’s added in 2021 to promote sharing: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLOJRP"&gt;The Movie feature gives you selected songs for your biopic formatted for your opening credits theme, the moment of reflection, the dance-off, or the big game. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature 2021 the movie" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nQdoibudIa5PFHmDxDtlxudgBJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055547/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.25_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new 2021: The Movie feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zN4Hxg"&gt;Spotify users can also get a visualization of their audio aura based on their top two music moods. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature audio aura" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/clHxQVlyD--Vhxxz3Sa3g8ho1tY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055536/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.18_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new audio aura feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yifiwY"&gt;Spotify also released a data-based game that you can play and share with your friends called  Playing Cards. In the style of two truths and a lie, players can look at statements about another user’s listening history and guess which one is a lie. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature playing cards" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5GIpeq6msDmeYiI-0cqU3PGSgZQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055538/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.32_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new Playing Cards feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qKYhzT"&gt;Spotify is also using Wrapped to expand the blend feature that was released this year by letting users blend their Spotify Wrapped and share the results on social media. Also available is Spotify’s 2021 Wrapped hub, which includes both personalized and editorially curated content and playlists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcsNUw"&gt;Other than TikTok, Wrapped cards are directly shareable to Snapchat, Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUWieq"&gt;So what about people who don’t use Spotify? Apple Music users like me can’t enjoy Spotify Wrapped, but we have access to &lt;a href="https://music.apple.com/replay"&gt;Apple Music Replay&lt;/a&gt; which includes a compilation of a user’s most played songs and lists most listened to artists and albums, plus an option to listen to playlists dating back to 2015. Of course, if you’re seeking your own unique version of today’s Wrapped interactive experience, then 2021 is just another year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20997218/spotify-wrapped-year-end-decade-review-apple-music-streaming-audio-service"&gt;reminding you of what you’re missing&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MB3MSI"&gt;Other music streaming services like YouTube Music and Tidal have released their own versions to commemorate a user’s listening history. &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/30/youtube-music-2021-recap/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out that some YouTube Music subscribers &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/30/youtube-music-2021-recap/"&gt;have spotted a 2021 Recap&lt;/a&gt; that includes playlists and stats. Tidal &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tidal-releases-my-2020-rewind-for-members-to-look-back-at-their-year-in-music-301182905.html"&gt;released its My 2020 Rewind&lt;/a&gt; feature last year on December 1st but has yet to release an updated 2021 version. As far as other streaming services, they might be waiting until the end of December to take a look back on the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T10:05:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T10:05:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung refreshes two budget A-series phones with 5G and higher prices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy A13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fMVe7Us2BfT5wo5TScRlxJDJnaU=/120x0:4620x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214532/GalaxyA13_5G_Green_Lockup_RGB_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy A13 will be an AT&amp;amp;T exclusive starting December 3rd, 2021, before being available on T-Mobile and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="http://Samsung.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; in early 2022.&lt;/em&gt; | Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ArTaVC"&gt;With 2022 and CES just around the corner, Samsung is ready to introduce new updates to its popular and budget-friendly A-series, which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749880/samsung-q3-2021-earnings-record-revenue-memory-mobile"&gt;helped keep sales strong&lt;/a&gt; for the Korean company despite supply woes for the flagship Galaxy S21. This time around, both the Galaxy A13 5G and A03S are getting a bit more expensive while confirming some new hardware and 5G connectivity for the A13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r26Tc7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Galaxy A13 5G&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pC9P83"&gt;Unlike the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21628573/samsung-a12-a02s-phones-budget-price-specs-2021"&gt;4G-only Galaxy A12&lt;/a&gt;, the new A13 will be able to access 5G networks, specifically, with the sub-6GHz bands available on T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T. The A13’s 5G readiness partly explains its new $249.99 price. That’s a whopping $70 increase from its $179.99 predecessor and slightly cheaper than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs"&gt;$279.99 Galaxy A32 5G&lt;/a&gt; with similar specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PE9zXH"&gt;Its higher price makes it possible to bring some premium features to the A13, as the relatively low-resolution 6.5-inch Infinity-V HD Plus display will feel smoother with its 90Hz adaptive refresh rate. This is up from the standard 60Hz of the A12 and keeps pace with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547482/oneplus-nord-n200-5g-review-screen-price-specs"&gt;$239.99 OnePlus Nord N200 5G&lt;/a&gt; that offers a 1080p display with 90Hz refresh. Thanks to its more up-to-date MediaTek Dimensity 700 processor, the A13 is better equipped to multitask and handle various mobile games than the &lt;a href="https://nanoreview.net/en/soc-compare/mediatek-helio-p35-vs-mediatek-dimensity-700"&gt;A12, which shipped last year with a chipset from 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The A13 also promises an updated triple-camera system with a 50-megapixel main camera, plus a macro and a depth sensor for bokeh effects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy A13 5G’s side fingerprint sensor" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yKa0PfMZkzh5p2eF9xR6aNNf5MQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055054/GalaxyA13_5G_Black_RSide_RGB.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy A13 5G features a fingerprint sensor embedded into its power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wxgMx2"&gt;It’s a bit disappointing that the A13 will only have 64GB of internal memory — yes, its microSD slot will support up to a 1TB card — and Samsung has not specified how much RAM this model has (the A12 had 3GB RAM). That said, you’ll be able to plug wired headphones into its 3.5mm audio jack, make contactless payments via NFC, enjoy a 5,000mAh battery, and use the side fingerprint sensor to unlock your phone (there is no face unlock option). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y3iXvD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Galaxy A03S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fP8FvF"&gt;Samsung is not revealing nearly as many details about the upcoming Galaxy A03S, only confirming that the A03S will cost $159.99 when it ships in 2022, while the base A02S debuted at just $109.99 last year. With scant details about the A03S’s new hardware to justify this $50 price increase, the press release hints that it’ll have “a long-lasting battery, triple camera system, and fingerprint security.” You can probably expect an updated processor from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21628573/samsung-a12-a02s-phones-budget-price-specs-2021"&gt;A02S&lt;/a&gt;, and perhaps 32GB of storage in the base model, but you’ll have to wait for CES or a potential Samsung Unpacked event to find out more, including what it looks like because we don’t have pictures of it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWXuoD"&gt;Both phones will ship with Android 11, but it’s unclear whether they will receive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;four years of regular security updates&lt;/a&gt; like Samsung has guaranteed for some A-series phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E3zlTZ"&gt;The new A13 5G will be an AT&amp;amp;T online exclusive starting on December 3rd, 2021, with T-Mobile and Samsung.com following suit in early January 2022. If you prefer the ultra-budget A03S, you’ll need to wait until early January 2022, when it’ll be available on AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, Verizon, and Samsung.com. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3KejH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810665/samsung-galaxy-a13-5g-a03s-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810665/samsung-galaxy-a13-5g-a03s-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chip is here to power the Android flagships of 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-FP9dyJyaIVdY_TvNUruvjV_Cx0=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70212202/Snapdragon_8_Gen_1_Mobile_Platform__Key_Visual__Angle_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SuNSYq"&gt;Qualcomm has a new flagship smartphone processor: the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1, announced at the company’s annual Snapdragon Tech Summit, giving an early preview at the brains behind the most powerful smartphones of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9IvvH"&gt;The successor to last year’s Snapdragon 888, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 is the first chipset to bear Qualcomm’s new naming scheme (which the company had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/22/22796541/qualcomm-snapdragon-branding-naming-scheme-changes-updates"&gt;previously teased last week&lt;/a&gt;), ditching the triple-digit numbering system that Qualcomm has previously used for new, generation-based monikers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cB2M3v"&gt;As is the case every year, Qualcomm is promising some major improvements in the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1, with better performance, camera technology, AI capabilities, security, and 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="u2juAI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;20 percent better CPU performance and up to 30 percent CPU power efficiency&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Od6QyN"&gt;Let’s start with the hard specs. As expected, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 is the first chip from Qualcomm to use the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22448107/arm-armv9-architecure-cortex-x2-a710-cpu-mali-g710-gpu-android-2022-designs"&gt;latest Armv9 architecture from Arm&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, the new eight-core Kryo CPU will feature a single prime core based on the Cortex-X2 at 3.0GHz, along with three performance cores based on Cortex-A710 at 2.5GHz, and a quartet of efficiency cores based on the Cortex-A510 design at 1.8GHz. Additionally, the new chip jumps to a 4nm process, from the 5nm process on which the Snapdragon 888 was built. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HJ3LTB"&gt;All told, Qualcomm promises that the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 will offer up to 20 percent better performance and up to 30 percent more power efficiency over last year’s model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gYm24t"&gt;Meanwhile, the new Adreno GPU (much like the Gen 1’s Kryo CPU, Qualcomm didn’t give a specific number for the updated hardware here) promises to offer 30 percent faster graphics rendering, in addition to 25 percent better power efficiency compared to the Snapdragon 888. It’ll also offer a new GPU control panel for fine-tuning how games are running on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X4juexRZOAnmC4QbR2ZCXAq0eqc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053637/Snapdragon_8_Gen_1_Block_Diagram.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Qualcomm&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OkrJfj"&gt;Making its debut on the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274127/qualcomm-x65-5g-modem-10gbps-speeds-ai-tuning-software-updates"&gt;Qualcomm’s Snapdragon X65 modem&lt;/a&gt;, which promises a whole suite of 5G features and firsts. As Qualcomm’s fourth-generation 5G modem, it builds on the existing mmWave and sub-6GHz compatibility that came before, adding support for up to 10Gbps speeds and the latest 3GPP Release 16 specification. As is always the case, you almost certainly won’t actually see that kind of speed in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5nkUO"&gt;The Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 also supports Wi-Fi 6 and Wi-Fi 6E, Bluetooth LE Audio (a first for Qualcomm), and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652655/qualcomm-aptx-lossless-announced-snapdragon-sound"&gt;company’s Snapdragon Sound technology&lt;/a&gt; for enabling AptX Lossless wireless audio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wzUiT6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;18-bit RAW photos and 8K HDR video — if your camera can handle it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9bnlut"&gt;As is traditional for Qualcomm’s top-tier processor, the company is putting a big emphasis on its beefed-up camera capabilities, which the company is bundling together for the first time under a new “Snapdragon Sight” brand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RMw4vp"&gt;While the Spectra ISP is once again a triple ISP system, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 upgrades things up to an 18-bit system (up from 14 bits on the 888). That translates to 4,096 times more camera data and up to four additional stops of dynamic range for very bright or very dark scenarios. The triple ISP (image signal processor) also allows for things like shooting 240 12-megapixel photos in a single second or simultaneously shooting in 8K with HDR while snapping 64-megapixel stills thanks to an increased 3.2-gigapixel per second throughput.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxZitX"&gt;Qualcomm is also offering more high-end camera features out of the box, including support for shooting in 8K video with HDR 10 Plus and shooting in 18-bit RAW (assuming your phone has the camera hardware to actually pull it off). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uxU45a"&gt;The 8 Gen 1 also features a variety of other imaging improvements, including better dark mode pictures that can use data from up to 30 images in a single shot (up from six images on the 888). There’s also a host of better AI processing techniques, with improved auto-exposure, auto-focus, and auto-face detection technology, a dedicated “bokeh engine” for adding portrait effects to 4K video, and an “ultrawide engine” that can de-warp and remove chromatic aberrations from shots. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WcfdqVR73HgJz6eUJCWh9VGLo2Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053641/Snapdragon_8_Gen_1_Chip_Image.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3IESWU"&gt;Qualcomm is also adding a &lt;em&gt;fourth&lt;/em&gt; ISP, located in the dedicated sensing hub on the SoC: unlike the triple ISP for the primary camera, the new ISP is designed specifically to power an always-on camera that’s active at all times. Qualcomm has some big ambitions for what developers can do with the always-on camera, like automatically shutting off your screen when you put your phone down or if it detects someone trying to read over your shoulder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MR5cbn"&gt;And while the idea of an always-on camera raises some obvious security concerns, Qualcomm argues that the feature is intended to help make using your device &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; secure, with any camera data for the always-on camera staying locally on-device in the chip’s secure enclave. Additionally, customers will be able to opt in to using the always-on camera, much in the same way that they can choose whether to use an always-listening microphone feature for voice assistants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w34JYb"&gt;Still, though, the added capability — and how manufacturers implement it into their devices, if they do at all — will be something to watch when the first chips with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 roll out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O377mH"&gt;On the AI side of things, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 features Qualcomm’s latest Hexagon processor, with its seventh-generation AI engine, which the company says is four times faster than its predecessor and up to 1.7 times more power efficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wTFjT"&gt;The company showed off a variety of use cases that the boosted AI performance can enable, including the aforementioned camera functionality, a “Leica Leitz Look mode” that emulates Leica lens effects, and improved detection of where you’re holding your phone for optimizing antenna performance. Additionally, Qualcomm is adding AI-powered sampling to offer a DLSS-style effect for improving mobile games, something that it says will happen automatically when gaming on the 8 Gen 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VpVaCh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Four times better AI performance compared to last year’s model&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IyRwV5"&gt;Lastly, there are security improvements. The Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 adds a new hardware-level layer of security with a “dedicated Trust Management Engine,” in addition to offering support for the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/android/security/android-ready-se"&gt;Android Ready SE standard&lt;/a&gt;, enabling support for digital car keys, driver’s licenses, IDs, and e-money wallets. There’s also built-in iSIM support for directly connecting to cellular networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9agPT"&gt;Despite the new branding, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 doesn’t appear to break the mold for Qualcomm’s chips, offering the usual generational upgrades we’ve come to expect from the company’s annual flagships. Still, in a world where bespoke chips like Google’s Tensor or Apple’s A-series processors are becoming increasingly popular, it’s good to see that Qualcomm has no intention of slowing the pace on its own top chips, even as the competition heats up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ouwCZ"&gt;And with the first Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 smartphones expected before the end of 2021, it won’t be long before we’ll be able to see just how powerful Qualcomm’s latest chip is for ourselves. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T06:53:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T06:53:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rocket League’s mobile spinoff is now available worldwide</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sOSllyutfYuou4i0YGiHSCVd-K4=/0x0:1998x1332/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70208606/msedge_IPE3MxMO6w.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Px9y0k"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rocket League Sideswipe&lt;/em&gt;, a mobile version of the popular car-based soccer game, is now available on iOS and Android. The game started &lt;a href="https://www.rocketleague.com/news/rocket-league-sideswipe-preseason-begins-today/"&gt;rolling out on November 15th&lt;/a&gt; in Oceania, but is now available worldwide, albeit in a “pre-season” mode ahead of Season 1’s kickoff at an unannounced later date, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/29/rocket-league-sideswipe-android-ios-launch/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQxQ2n"&gt;The free to play game, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22345184/rocket-league-sideswipe-android-ios-announced"&gt;first announced in March&lt;/a&gt;, is a simplified version of the original &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; released in 2015. The biggest change is that the mobile version is played in 2D, rather than offering a fully three-dimensional stadium to drive around. You control your car with a virtual joystick on the left side of the screen, while buttons on the right handle jumping and boost. with touch controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="O1fs8k"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Rocket League Sideswipe. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now Available Worldwide on iOS and Android. &lt;a href="https://t.co/LL5qUjdoCl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/LL5qUjdoCl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rocket League Sideswipe (@RLSideswipe) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLSideswipe/status/1465446286841331715?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="teQGbr"&gt;Unlike in regular &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, the car’s boost auto-regenerates, so there’s no need to seek out recharging pads, and teams are limited to a maximum of two players per side. Available game styles include the game’s standard soccer mode as well as a basketball-style “Hoops” version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iNQed9"&gt;If that sounds tempting, you can download &lt;em&gt;Sideswipe&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/rocket-league-sideswipe/id1549027048"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Psyonix.RL2D&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809506/rocket-league-sideswipe-ios-android-release-global"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809506/rocket-league-sideswipe-ios-android-release-global</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-29T23:03:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-29T23:03:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Many T-Mobile customers report they can’t call Verizon, AT&amp;T, or other T-Mobile numbers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="t-mobile and sprint logos" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/18z3CIQwo9-gyoN1laOQjG7pRgY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70207225/acasatro_180430_1777_sprint_Tmobile_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8VCvk2"&gt;T-Mobile customers have been reporting issues making and receiving calls all afternoon, with problems frequently linked to Verizon numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nrdSdS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Verizon and T-Mobile both say their networks weren’t at fault&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1ddNNO"&gt;This all started around 2PM ET this afternoon, with hotspots showing in most major metro areas on &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/verizon/map/"&gt;Downdetector&lt;/a&gt;. Initial reports suggested Verizon might be having issues, but Verizon spokesperson Kevin King tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that its network is operating “business as usual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iCDgao"&gt;T-Mobile declined to provide a quote from a named spokesperson, but a representative sent the following message from the company’s media relations address: “We have no indication that this is a T-Mobile network issue but we have taken steps to reroute our customers and have been in close contact with Verizon throughout the day as they work to resolve this. We apologize to any customers who were impacted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8wFwb0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;User reports indicate T-Mobile is having problems since 1:49 PM EST. &lt;a href="https://t.co/LExjRid785"&gt;https://t.co/LExjRid785&lt;/a&gt; RT if you're also having problems &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TMobiledown?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TMobiledown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Downdetector (@downdetector) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/downdetector/status/1465392459878473745?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OrxYbzS3_AgTsqJ9RG-s72c6ODY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051143/tmobile_down_detector.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Downdetector&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Downdetector map showing T-Mobile outage concentrated along the East Coast and Midwest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ea0pOV"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ImJustShaffe/status/1465433658697916416?s=20"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mayBmimi/status/1465431151397511172?s=20"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DragonMom98/status/1465434236001861632?s=20"&gt;users&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter have been complaining about the outage, with T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rvajustin/status/1465433455337029633?s=20"&gt;customers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Dan_Leite11/status/1465431612817092611?s=20"&gt;frequently raising&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/7oneeight/status/1465430886783070215?s=20"&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; about calling other networks and, in some cases, even other T-Mobile customers. The reported problems range from instantly dropped calls, to “all circuits are busy” messages, to lag even when people are able to get a connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHG3kC"&gt;A test call between one T-Mobile prepaid number and a Verizon number worked for us, but posts across social media continue to note issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YDPT6G"&gt;We haven’t seen widespread reports of AT&amp;amp;T issues, other than from T-Mobile customers who are having problems calling out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U4NUP8"&gt;It’s still unclear precisely what was causing the issues, or even who felt its impact. However, as T-Mobile indicated, by later in the evening the number of reported issues dropped sharply and things seem to be returning to normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2jyzK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 29th, 11PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added statement from T-Mobile and notes that the issue seems to be going away.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2IEirs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808526/t-mobile-outage-verizon-att-call-cant-connect"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808526/t-mobile-outage-verizon-att-call-cant-connect</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-28T09:10:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-28T09:10:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Z Flip 3 is up to $500 off at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1vJ1e6XX8032Pqgdd0I-F7Qm4Qw=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70200959/dseifert_4711_samsung_z_flip_3_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rQ5Rvk"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Flip 3 is the company’s lowest-priced foldable yet at its normal $999.99, but today you can get the trendy phone for way, way less than that. In an early &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22796645/cyber-monday-2021-early-deals-sales-tech-laptops-phones-tvs-headphones-gaming"&gt;Cyber Monday 2021 deal&lt;/a&gt;, the unlocked Z Flip 3 is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf5XF4x8a5W" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available from Best Buy for $599.99&lt;/a&gt; if you activate service on the device with your purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UglclJ"&gt;That’s a colossal $400 discount from the Flip 3’s regular price and brings it on par with something like the Pixel 6. Google’s phone is terrific, but it certainly doesn’t have the cool factor of a folding screen. Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T customers can both get that price for a limited time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1Ya367"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10890426"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1nrHXB"&gt;In certain cases, you can save even more. Activating a new line of service on T-Mobile / Sprint brings the price down to $499.99 for the unlocked Z Flip 3. If you can deal with some carrier bloatware, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf5XSZjbTWp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Verizon model&lt;/a&gt; is also discounted to $499.99 if you’re eligible for an upgrade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="lllbdG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Cyber Monday deals happening now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22796645/cyber-monday-2021-early-deals-sales-tech-laptops-phones-tvs-headphones-gaming"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KxuzHf"&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22631125/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review of the Z Flip 3&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll find that my colleague Dan Seifert praised Samsung’s first truly mainstream foldable for its excellent screen, snappy performance, water resistance, and compact size when folded up. If there’s one weak point of the phone, its battery life is merely average among the competition. But there’s no denying the sleek look of this thing — and that cream color still looks just as fantastic now as when Samsung announced it, though the deal applies to the black, green, and lavender colors if those are more your style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qEMdL2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/28/22806048/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-cyber-monday-deal-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/28/22806048/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-cyber-monday-deal-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
