<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-22T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EA announces new Battlefield mobile game launching in 2022 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SJanE04kl2-chP6eJeoS4Fw4JSg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69168446/bfv_standard_16x9.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: EA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="luxSg9"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Battlefield&lt;/em&gt; series is headed to mobile devices. The hugely popular shooter franchise will make its debut on smartphones and tablets in a new game that’s set to release in 2022. The game will be developed by Industrial Toys in partnership with longtime &lt;em&gt;Battlefield&lt;/em&gt; developer DICE, which is owned by Electronic Arts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NemQTF"&gt;“Make no mistake, this is a standalone game,” Oskar Gabrielson, the general manager of DICE, said in a blog post. “A completely different game from the one we’re making for console and PC, designed specifically for the mobile platform. It’s being built from the ground up by iToys to make &lt;em&gt;Battlefield-&lt;/em&gt;on-the-go a reality and you can expect a fully-fledged, skill-based experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHn9JQ"&gt;Shooters are some of the biggest hits on mobile right now, and EA is likely looking to capitalize on that popularity with the introduction of a mobile &lt;em&gt;Battlefield&lt;/em&gt; title. &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; had a colossal launch week when it debuted in 2019, reportedly racking up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/9/20906035/call-of-duty-download-number-biggest-launch-ever"&gt;more than 100 million downloads&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, which was released in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350782/pubg-mobile-one-billion-downloads-tencent"&gt;just surpassed one billion total downloads in March&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wr9qsM"&gt;Gabrielson also reiterated that DICE is hard at work on the next &lt;em&gt;Battlefield&lt;/em&gt; game for consoles and PC, which is planned for release later this year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396717/ea-battlefield-mobile-smartphones-tablets-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396717/ea-battlefield-mobile-smartphones-tablets-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here is the purple iPhone 12, which is purple</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iW_qOjdrAN-ln6gAgylVTAJ-pe0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69168438/vpavic_4547_20210421_0022.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A purple iPhone 12&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qNuuh3"&gt;Apple managed to surprise us during its live stream event earlier this week by announcing a new iPhone. Well, a new &lt;em&gt;color&lt;/em&gt; for the iPhone 12 and iPhone 12 mini: purple. Apple sent one to us along with some sample AirTags and so we have duly taken some photos of this, a purple iPhone 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZrgmXw"&gt;It’s a lightish shade of purple. One might be tempted to call it lavender, but to me it’s a bit more like a lilac or maybe a wisteria. It lacks the redness you’d expect in a mauve or the blue tones you’d see in a violet. There are many &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lavender_(color)"&gt;shades of purple&lt;/a&gt;, but this one is what Apple went with and I like it. It’s unmistakable even at a distance, whereas the light green iPhone 12 models could be mistaken for off-white in certain light. I am also glad it doesn’t have a fancy name. It’s just “purple.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CnU4Uy"&gt;The purple iPhone 12 is in all other ways the same as the other colors of the iPhone 12: it is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;very fast, has a very nice screen, 5G, and great cameras&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just a little more royal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vm9dd1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"AirTag location trackers are smart, capable, and very Apple","url":"https://www.theverge.com/e/22160734"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bv3Zmf"&gt;Here are some more photos of the purple iPhone 12.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YOmK6ckgo_twcY4Y_CrwuU_9k8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461376/vpavic_4547_20210421_0021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A purple iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/19OjBOS6ZAdPsv34rQtI_1Uou-g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461373/vpavic_4547_20210421_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A purple iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dQ9RU05H_YXlP2tEu9sLTRtfPwY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461375/vpavic_4547_20210421_0014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A purple iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1IzK_tnF0wKXTFUD0OVDwwF-q1c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461374/vpavic_4547_20210421_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A purple iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12 and an AirTag" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NlEu_OJbEG0hRBZmi0h-G8lHJ70=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461392/vpavic_4547_20210421_0119.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A purple iPhone 12 and an AirTag.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XlwYOe"&gt;Alongside the purple iPhone, Apple also released its AirTags location trackers. Here’s a first look at those:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fvG4GE"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirTags: the most Apple|101806" data-volume-uuid="791d9753f" data-volume-id="101806" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-587" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22396502/purple-iphone-12-color-photos-shade-hue-lilac-lavender"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22396502/purple-iphone-12-color-photos-shade-hue-lilac-lavender</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T12:44:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T12:44:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung will help you turn your old Galaxy phone into a smart home sensor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HMKZW7exSYWuuiHTrP72mMxRLlc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69163892/Galaxy_Upcycling_at_Home.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The feature can alert you to the sound of a crying baby or turn on a lamp when light levels dip.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cXHVnM"&gt;Samsung has launched a beta program to help put some older Galaxy phones to new uses. Owners of certain phones can download an update to turn the device into a smart home sensor with some neat functions — it can detect the sound of a crying baby or turn on a lamp when it gets dark. The program is limited to certain models launched in 2018 or later, which is fairly limited, but it’s a nice, accessible offering that could help users get a little more use out of their old devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iczh9A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-introduces-latest-innovations-for-a-better-normal-at-ces-2021"&gt;Announced at CES&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, the company is launching the program in the US, UK, and Korea starting today. By downloading a software update through the &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/support/owners/app/smartthings" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SmartThings app&lt;/a&gt;, users can access two basic functions. The first is an audio sensor that detects the sound of a baby crying, pet barking or meowing, or a knock at the door. When it detects one of these, it sends an alert to your phone with a recording of the sound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mb2b7M"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Galaxy S, Note, and Z-series phones launched from 2018 onward are eligible&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HX79N0"&gt;The other function is a light level sensor that can turn on a connected light automatically when brightness levels in a room fall below a certain threshold. Samsung says the update includes battery optimization necessary to keep the phone powered and functioning as a sensor for long periods of time, though the company doesn’t specify how long it would be able to run between charges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E93Ex7"&gt;Galaxy S, Note, and Z-series phones launched from 2018 onward are eligible, provided they’re running Android 9 or later. Samsung says more devices will be supported in the future, which hopefully includes more budget-oriented devices that owners may be less likely to trade in. And if those limited functions don’t appeal, there’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21542079/phone-reuse-android-iphone-how-to"&gt;a lot more you can do with your old phone&lt;/a&gt; if you don’t mind a DIY approach.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395694/samsung-galaxy-phone-upcycle-smart-home-sensor-iot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395694/samsung-galaxy-phone-upcycle-smart-home-sensor-iot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T12:33:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T12:33:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus’ gaming triggers for Android and iOS phones are now available in India</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="OnePlus Gaming Triggers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9IBv8bhhJPS1DIoqPBTiuPKee3Y=/0x0:1061x707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69163839/oneplustriggers2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These can snap onto any phone thinner than 11.5mm&lt;/em&gt; | OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DJWt7y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeteLau/status/1384771145606451205"&gt;OnePlus CEO Pete Lau tweeted pictures&lt;/a&gt; of some attachable gaming triggers the company has created, and they’re made for more than just OnePlus’ phones. &lt;a href="https://www.slashgear.com/oneplus-gaming-trigger-may-confuse-your-senses-23665133/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;SlashGear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2021/03/oneplus-mobile-gaming-trigger-accessory-oneplus-9-pro-video-games.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Headlines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;noticed them being teased during the unveiling of the OnePlus 9 back in late March, but they’re available online now &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.in%2Fproduct%2Foneplus-gaming-triggers&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22395588%2Foneplus-gaming-triggers-ios-android-phone-mobile-controller" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in India from the OnePlus site&lt;/a&gt; for 1,099 rupees, which converts to roughly $15. OnePlus hasn’t confirmed that these gaming triggers will be releasing globally, and the company wouldn’t comment on pricing and availability when I reached out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SAJVet"&gt;These triggers can be clipped around the edge of most phones (any Android or iOS device, so long as they’re less than 11.5mm thick with a case on). If you want to do some mobile gaming but hate touch controls, these could provide a more intuitive, controller-like alternative to tapping on your screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bQs958"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We designed the OnePlus gaming triggers to be solid, responsive, pleasingly “clicky,” and, yes, beautiful. We also made sure they work with many other phones—because the best product design is one that leaves you free to make your own choices. &lt;a href="https://t.co/hJNa4Dsa5s"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hJNa4Dsa5s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Pete Lau (@PeteLau) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeteLau/status/1384771145606451205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f227p8"&gt;Each trigger appears to have just one shoulder button with an Omron switch that Lau says are “pleasingly clicky” to tap. Some of the pictures make it seem like there’s also a rear trigger, which would give you a second button to map, but OnePlus didn’t provide any further details on how the mechanism worked when I asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLkTjQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.in%2Fproduct%2Foneplus-gaming-triggers&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22395588%2Foneplus-gaming-triggers-ios-android-phone-mobile-controller" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to the product page&lt;/a&gt;, these triggers are interchangeable and can be fastened to your phone in whatever way is most comfortable to you. To use them, though, your game of choice needs to allow for deep customization of its touch controls, to the level of allowing you to move touch-activated zones to where these triggers’ conductive silicon pads clip onto your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n6DdWb"&gt;If you’re serious about mobile gaming, these triggers could level the playing field if you’re up against gamers who are playing on phones like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;Asus ROG Phone 5&lt;/a&gt; or others that feature ultrasonic sensors laid along their edge to mimic physical shoulder buttons. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346594/black-shark-4-pro-gaming-phone-shoulder-buttons-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Black Shark 4 lineup&lt;/a&gt; features actual mechanical shoulder buttons built into the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f8sP6Y"&gt;OnePlus’ option seems to be a solid, budget-friendly option for making your phone easier to game on, though there’s a downside if you value your phone’s expansive screen real estate: these clamps obscure parts of the screen. But if they’re as easy to clip on and remove as OnePlus’ photos indicate, I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395588/oneplus-gaming-triggers-ios-android-phone-mobile-controller"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395588/oneplus-gaming-triggers-ios-android-phone-mobile-controller</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s AirTags don’t have a built-in keychain loop, and we have some thoughts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fsh9JcBTVaabDsfJuV2nAvrMoWk=/77x0:904x551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162411/airtagaccessories.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CwaDy4"&gt;Apple’s new AirTag trackers are finally here after years of rumors. The $29 trackers work with Apple’s Find My network, utilizing both Bluetooth and UWB technology to help owners track anything from their keys to their bags. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzvFVZ"&gt;But the design of the new trackers is somewhat controversial: unlike most Bluetooth trackers, Apple’s iteration doesn’t include a built-in key ring loop. The subsequent debate has shattered the tranquility of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s newsroom over whether Apple’s somewhat Spartan design is brilliant or bogus. Well, at least between two of the most genteel &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers, Jon Porter and Chaim Gartenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/492kammhY61DFUGcSC-yVmeGOFs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458151/keychain.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist’s rendering of an AirTag design featuring a keychain hole punch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qh75iy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Porter, reporter&lt;/strong&gt;: Debate me, coward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KMiTJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim Gartenberg, news editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Gladly! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvGf9T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Let’s start with a point that we’ll definitely both agree on: it’s a relief to see the AirTags’ battery is user-replaceable. It sounds like such a basic point, but considering Apple’s track record with its AirPods, Magic Mouse, iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, MacBook line, Magic Keyboard — wait does anything else Apple makes have replaceable batteries? — it wasn’t a guarantee. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20901686/tile-tracker-mate-pro-slim-sticker-release-date-news-features"&gt;Tile’s keychain-focused Mate and Pro trackers&lt;/a&gt; have removable batteries, but its Sticker (which has a very similar form factor to the AirTag) doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HWw9NV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Brilliant or bogus?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DOebJ1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I will grant you that easily accessible, user-replaceable batteries are always a good thing. And on a whole, the overall aesthetics of the AirTags are nice, with a two-tone shiny white plastic / chrome back that’s vaguely reminiscent of the old iPods to me. But the overly sleek Apple design highlights the biggest issue I have here: there’s no built-in loop or hole to attach a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P8Ur5Y"&gt;The AirTag is a product that’s designed to track your keys, and yet it offers no way to actually attach itself to those keys out of the box, something that’s practically table stakes from Tile, Chipolo, and virtually every other Bluetooth tracker from the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TKNaTC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: I hear you, but I think Apple’s approach is better. It means it can sell just one version of the AirTag to track whatever item you want, rather than selling different devices whether you want to track your keys, or your bike, or your jacket. Just buy an AirTag and buy whatever accessory you need to attach it. And for what it’s worth, I really like the design of the little holder accessory they’re selling to attach the AirTag to a set of keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xhwlMC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: That little &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMHJ23ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-leather-key-ring%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;keychain accessory costs $35&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;em&gt;more than an entire AirTag&lt;/em&gt;. Even Apple’s cheapest AirTag case, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMK0W3ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-loop%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the $30 plastic loop&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t look like it’ll even be useful for attaching to keys. This is just Apple’s typical accessory tax, forced onto customers because of an intentional choice of aesthetic form over useful function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNKKxo"&gt;And don’t get me started on the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMX862AM%2FA%2Fairtag-herm%25C3%25A8s-bag-charm%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hermès accessories&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VOt7rznNzumaSTrrkX8AFrjBc6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458169/Screen_Shot_2021_04_20_at_5.57.30_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nmRXJl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Okay fine, I’m not going to argue that the $349 Hermès key ring isn’t incredibly stupid, and it would be nice if the leather key ring actually included an AirTag at that price. The setup is too expensive, period, and hopefully third-party accessory manufacturers will step in to fill the demand for cheap keychain holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="girWDS"&gt;But more importantly, I think separating the tech bit from the holder bit makes sense for an accessory that’s going to have to withstand so much abuse on a daily basis. Keys can be sharp, and they beat up anything that shares a pocket with them, so I’d prefer it if that thing that gets beaten up is a holder rather than the core piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t773Ho"&gt;Look at a Tile key fob tracker that’s been used for a couple of years, and it looks grimy as hell. I wouldn’t be surprised if some people end up replacing the whole device when the battery runs out, just so they can get a shiny new tracker. But when your AirTag keychain inevitably starts looking worse for wear, you just replace the holder rather than the tracker itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Co3luD8e5pkvGFCzcC1RfxhbWE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22457308/yJBAy1w.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hywvlC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: These are all valid points, but you’re ignoring the fact that &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Faccessories%2Fall%2Fairtag&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;these accessories and protective cases&lt;/a&gt; could all exist in &lt;em&gt;addition&lt;/em&gt; to including a cutout to directly attach a key ring. There’s already a similar cottage industry of accessories for Tile’s trackers for those who want them, and with the marketing power of Apple behind it, there’s no reason to think that AirTags wouldn’t have eclipsed that level of interest from accessory makers, even if it did have a cutout for a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NM8Yi5"&gt;It’s not that cases are bad — Apple’s leather option does look great and is almost definitely a more robust option than my hypothetical cutout. But it’d be nice to give customers the choice, instead of just forcing them into an option that requires spending more money right from the start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D24Qfh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are all the AirTag accessories we know about ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394331/apple-airtag-release-launch-accessory-roundup-nomad-belkin"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PwfbZF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: At a certain point, though, you’re running up against physical limitations, and Apple has to pick its battles. I’m already seeing some of our esteemed colleagues in Slack complaining about how thick these trackers are, which I’d wager is because Apple prioritized building in a removable battery. Adding a loop with enough space for a key chain to go through adds yet more bulk. You have to draw the line somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lSBjAD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: Fair enough. So, Jon, are you buying an AirTag tracker? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naEYZZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Honestly, I’m going to wait to see how the third-party accessories work out. If I can get a half-decent leather keychain holder for the equivalent of $20 or so, then I think it makes a lot of sense spending $50 all-in with the tracker itself. Yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pfzgre"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I might buy one to stick in my luggage at some point, but I generally don’t lose my keys enough to need to invest in a tracker for them (famous last words, potentially). Especially not at the $65 price tag that Apple is asking for a full key ring setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYatkG"&gt;Related:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2W0RfH"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirTags: the most Apple|101806" data-volume-uuid="791d9753f" data-volume-id="101806" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-782" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LMETVs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-20T15:49:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-20T15:49:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple quietly reveals that iOS 14.5 will arrive next week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TUSQo9wvznWlWZ9pyHG1BruKEuE=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69158860/findmy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iOS 14.5 will enable use of AirTag trackers to help locate tagged items using Apple’s Find My feature.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wYXsIE"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F04%2Fapple-introduces-airtag%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F20%2F22394200%2Fapple-ios-14-5-watch-os-7-4-mac-os-11-3-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; for Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/20844326/apple-airtags-bluetooth-tracker-keys-tile-features-price"&gt;new Tile-like AirTag tracker&lt;/a&gt;, the company has revealed that iOS 14.5 will officially arrive “starting next week” — as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JoannaStern"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s Joanna Stern&lt;/a&gt;. AirTags go on sale April 30th and will only work with devices running iOS 14.5 or higher. Likewise, watchOS 7.4 and macOS 11.3 will also launch next week, as they support new Apple Podcast feature updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwDeAc"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267230/apple-ios-14-5-watchos-7-4-public-beta-unlock-iphone-apple-watch-mask"&gt;first launched the 14.5 beta&lt;/a&gt; to the public earlier this year in February alongside watchOS 7.4 beta (no word on whether that’s arriving soon, too). Along with AirTag support, it will implement Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22253366/apple-app-tracking-transparency-opt-in-requirement-beta-launch"&gt;App Tracking Transparency&lt;/a&gt; requirement, which mandates that developers ask for permission to track users for ad targeting. The feature was announced last year and met with sharp resistance from Facebook in particular, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178068/facebook-apple-newspaper-ads-ios-privacy-changes"&gt;argues that the move&lt;/a&gt; will harm small businesses that benefit from ad tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ohaQHf"&gt;iOS 14.5 also introduces some welcome inclusivity features, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360502/apple-siri-female-voice-default-new-voices-ios-14-5"&gt;ability to change Siri’s voice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285963/apple-emoji-ios-14-5-smiley-faces-hearts-more-skin-tones"&gt;new skin tone options&lt;/a&gt; for some emoji. Another feature we’ve appreciated in our testing thus far is Siri’s ability to learn which audio-listening apps you prefer for certain activities. This stops short of letting you select a new default app, like picking Spotify for all of your streaming music requests, but it’s a helpful evolution in any case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jWsSBM"&gt;Of course, this feature may or may not make it to the final release, but we &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;know now when we can expect to find out which features made the final cut. Apple doesn’t say specifically which day we can expect 14.5, but when it does, iPhone users will be able to download the update in their phone’s settings as always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ycu2tJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394200/apple-ios-14-5-watch-os-7-4-mac-os-11-3-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394200/apple-ios-14-5-watch-os-7-4-mac-os-11-3-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-20T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-20T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Venmo is adding support for users to buy, store, and sell cryptocurrency</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a_BALD5_nFLqjGNAq2Oafvi0gUU=/1x0:1840x1226/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69154747/Crypto_on_Venmo_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Venmo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gfL0WM"&gt;Venmo is releasing a feature that will allow users the option to store, buy, and sell popular cryptocurrencies, PayPal announced on Tuesday. Similar to PayPal, Venmo will support four different cryptocurrencies: Bitcoin, Ethereum, Bitcoin Cash, and Litecoin. PayPal had said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527288/paypal-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-venmo-bitcoin"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; that Venmo would get support for cryptocurrencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AmttZG"&gt;You can get started with as little as $1, and transactions are managed from the app. Venmo said in a press release that it will begin rolling out the feature to some users today, and tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; it anticipates that “most customers” will have access to cryptocurrencies in the app by the end of May. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-KgL9q3m_iAUMs155lvTOQIiMGQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22455653/image001__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Venmo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All cryptocurrency transactions will be managed directly from the Venmo app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uuSgt4"&gt;Venmo’s support for cryptocurrencies could encourage more people to invest in them. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Fearnings%2Fcall-transcripts%2F2021%2F02%2F04%2Fpaypal-holdings-pypl-q4-2020-earnings-call-transcr%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F20%2F22392274%2Fvenmo-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-hold-bitcoin" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PayPal reported in its Q4 earnings reporter that Venmo had 70 million users&lt;/a&gt;; given the app operates like a social network, users may find cryptocurrency more approachable if they can see their friends buying and selling right inside Venmo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lyBbs2"&gt;Venmo is the latest payment app to offer support for cryptocurrency. PayPal allowed users to buy, hold, and sell cryptocurrency from the main PayPal app &lt;a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2020-10-21-PayPal-Launches-New-Service-Enabling-Users-to-Buy-Hold-and-Sell-Cryptocurrency?sf130849673=1"&gt;in November&lt;/a&gt; and added the ability for US users to make purchases with cryptocurrency &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357246/paypal-buy-with-bitcoin-litecoin-ethereum-crypto-checkout"&gt;in late March&lt;/a&gt;. And Venmo and PayPal competitor Square launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17689156/square-cash-expands-bitcoin-support-to-all-50-us-states"&gt;support for Bitcoin in its Cash App in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Z3HiUR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PayPal will let US users pay with Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Litecoin starting today","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357246/paypal-buy-with-bitcoin-litecoin-ethereum-crypto-checkout"},{"title":"PayPal will now let all users in the US buy and sell cryptocurrencies","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562771/paypal-cryptocurrency-buy-sell-bitcoin-ethereum-litecoin-us-users"},{"title":"PayPal and Venmo will offer and accept cryptocurrency for all online payments","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527288/paypal-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-venmo-bitcoin"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392274/venmo-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-hold-bitcoin"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392274/venmo-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-hold-bitcoin</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-20T01:52:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-20T01:52:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google adds Pac-Man, Hello Kitty, Gundam mechs, and more to AR search</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tSry71UehtkravCv4F8zsfnc5n4=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69154559/Screen_Shot_2021_04_20_at_14.42.54.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XhwWeH"&gt;Google has &lt;a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/japanese-characters-ar/"&gt;added&lt;/a&gt; a bunch of popular Japanese characters to its AR feature in mobile search, which has previously featured &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171601/google-adds-augmented-reality-ar-animals-search-3d"&gt;animals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21400577/google-arts-and-culture-augmented-reality-prehistoric-creatures-museum-exhibits"&gt;historical artifacts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308071/google-search-augmented-reality-animals-dinosaurs-tyrannosaurus-rex-velociraptor-triceratops"&gt;dinosaurs&lt;/a&gt;. The list of characters is taken from Japanese pop culture including anime, TV, and video games, with names like Pac-Man, Hello Kitty, mechs from Evangelion and Gundam, and more. The feature works on Google search on Android and the iOS Google app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZPAyI"&gt;When you enter the characters’ names, you’ll see an option to “see in your space” below the main search result, and that’ll let you drop a 3D model into your camera view. The models can appear at various degrees of scale, with an option to render at life size, though I’m not sure quite how accurate those measurements are. I was under the impression that Hello Kitty was five apples tall, for example, but she towered over my desk when I tried it out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YZWUeQCTnyOqYovKVVuZ75ZcySc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22456500/AR_Anime_EN.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rsGC8u"&gt;The full list of characters is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mFnxoh"&gt;Ultraman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wgSY13"&gt;Ultraman Zero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ekhymm"&gt;Ultraman Belial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="N2dwUs"&gt;Gomora&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cemAjs"&gt;Evangelion (EVA-01 Test Type)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Li0tRu"&gt;Gundam (Odysseus Gundam, Xi Gundam, Penelope)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R9NXaz"&gt;Cogimyun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8eVr2V"&gt;The drums from &lt;em&gt;Taiko no Tatsujin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1zvXYs"&gt;Pac-Man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6heNrj"&gt;Pompompurin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0S44KJ"&gt;Little Twin Stars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="mXYV1I"&gt;Google says that Pac-Man is by far the most searched-for character out of the list, with more than twice as many searches as for Hello Kitty at #2. Apparently, the top country for Pac-Man searches is Peru.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393349/google-ar-search-anime-video-game-japanese-characters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393349/google-ar-search-anime-video-game-japanese-characters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung wants to make sure nobody’s tracking you with its SmartTags</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZtbP4-MBz5379RsEJqeswdCxn2c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69154296/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jhUeDv"&gt;Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.samsungmobilepress.com/pressreleases/evolving-for-the-better-smartthings-ecosystem-gives-galaxy-users-better-control-over-their-connected-devices"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; that customers will soon be able to scan for unknown Galaxy SmartTags trackers using Samsung’s SmartThings Find service. The feature, called Unknown Tag Search, will be coming to the SmartThings app starting next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOZPGR"&gt;Users will be able to scan the nearby area for any SmartTags that don’t belong to them but that are moving along with them. This feature could be a big win for safety, providing an easy way to make sure that nobody’s tracking you with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227621/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-price-release-date-tile-locator"&gt;tiny SmartTag&lt;/a&gt; that they slipped in your backpack, purse, coat pocket, etc. It’s a nice feature if you’re concerned about the privacy or security implications of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227621/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-price-release-date-tile-locator"&gt;Tile-like tracking devices.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz0wkF"&gt;Samsung also announced that its assistant, Bixby, will gain the ability to find SmartTags. If you’ve placed a SmartTag on a certain item and named it, you’ll be able to use Bixby to find that tag. For example, if you’ve got a SmartTag on your keys, you could say “hi Bixby, where are my keys?” and it will set off the tag’s ringer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CG1j9Q"&gt;Apple currently has a feature similar to Unknown Tag Search &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313659/apple-find-my-app-item-safety-alerts-prevent-stalking"&gt;in the iOS 14.5 beta&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems like it would be a natural fit for the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427380/apple-airtags-tile-competitor-production"&gt;long-rumored AirTags&lt;/a&gt; item trackers. The company is hosting its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22385362/apple-event-ipad-airpods-pencil-tv-tags-rumors-spring-loaded"&gt;“Spring Loaded” event&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow, so perhaps we’ll see Apple officially unveil its rumored competitor to Samsung’s Galaxy SmartTags.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392924/samsung-smartags-tracker-bixby-privacy-smartthings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392924/samsung-smartags-tracker-bixby-privacy-smartthings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T16:03:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T16:03:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s latest foldable phone perk is free dessert</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4R5C2YZGCrWt_kyEZiJrMgt-NrI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151573/vpavic_200907_4181_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z8Zago"&gt;Samsung is giving owners of its foldable phones some free dessert. Specifically, an order of “Chef Daniel Boulud’s signature &lt;a href="https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/daniel-bouluds-madeleines"&gt;Madeleines&lt;/a&gt; and Canelé,” designed by the chef exclusively for &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-premier/benefits/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Premier program&lt;/a&gt;, which offers Galazy Z Fold and Flip owners free perks in exchange for having bought the luxury-styled phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1ppMS"&gt;The new perk is being offered in partnership with the Michelin Guide through Boulud’s restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.danielnyc.com/cuisine"&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; (which itself has two Michelin stars). Samsung’s announcement claims that the dessert in question is valued at $75, which seems like a lot for French pastries, but if you already own a Galaxy foldable, the price tag isn’t something you’ll need to worry about, given that it’s free. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IGpu-z0mcw0De16eOEqspIujx1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22455352/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_3.36.35_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fgGlFt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Who doesn’t like free French pastries?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QSDy62"&gt;The company has been offering additional perks for foldable owners through its Galaxy Z Premier program since it relaunched the service alongside last year’s Galaxy Z Fold 2. And Samsung has since been adding bonus offers for the owners of its most expensive phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ltk2TI"&gt;In addition to the free snacks (which will take three to four weeks for delivery), Samsung is offering a free year of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ffounderscard.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F19%2F22392343%2Fsamsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FoundersCard&lt;/a&gt; membership, letting owners join a “community of over 50,000 entrepreneurs and business executives who receive unprecedented benefits and networking opportunities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iB8A3H"&gt;The Galaxy Z Premier program already includes a free six-month trial of LinkedIn’s Premium Career service, a free round of golf through ClubLife, and six months of Obé Fitness. Samsung is also promising that it’ll have “new partners and benefits” to announce in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392343/samsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392343/samsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
