<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-03T23:00:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T23:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T23:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo announces ‘next-generation’ under-display selfie camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BVtbzeVdgX-gEZ2Tc2W38f8KvLQ=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675770/OPPO_USC_2021_Prototype___3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A prototype phone with Oppo’s latest under-screen camera tech. | Oppo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IQYZtA"&gt;Oppo has announced the latest iteration of its under-screen camera technology, claiming it allows for a selfie camera to be placed under the display “without compromising the integrity of the screen.” Unlike earlier approaches that reduce pixel density in the portion of the screen that covers the camera in order to let more light pass through, Oppo is using smaller pixels to maintain the same 400-ppi sharpness as the rest of the OLED panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvQ0np"&gt;The result, according to Oppo, is that users should notice “almost no visual difference between the [under-screen camera] area and the rest of the screen during everyday use, creating a much more immersive visual experience.” The company has shown off an image of a prototype phone running an e-reader app, which would be pretty much the worst-case scenario for earlier under-display cameras due to the white background and sharp text. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K3TP02N5rcWGkY2IS1v7OHz6xBw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22760057/OPPO_USC_E_book_Reading.JPG"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EEx8tP"&gt;As for the quality of the camera itself, here’s a sample image provided by Oppo:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KQ05q6C4pZWPQry7cZnrc1p2Hng=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22760056/OPPO_USC_Selfie_Sample_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UQ8tbD"&gt;It’s only one sample in good light, and there do seem to be some color artifacts in certain portions of the image. It does, however, look considerably better than what you’d get from the first under-display camera to hit the market, which was on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22191459/zte-axon-20-5g-under-display-camera-hands-on"&gt;ZTE’s Axon 20 5G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sx6BV"&gt;That said, ZTE has one up on Oppo by actually shipping a phone already, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597594/zte-axon-30-refresh-specs-availability-under-display-phone-camera"&gt;its latest Axon 30&lt;/a&gt; is meant to have improved the tech as well. ZTE is claiming the same 400-ppi density in the camera portion of the screen, plus better camera quality than the Axon 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="awZY8O"&gt;Oppo has been working on under-display cameras for a long time, showing off the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/26/18759380/under-display-selfie-camera-first-oppo-announcement"&gt;world’s first demo at MWC Shanghai in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but at some point it’s going to have to put one in an actual commercial device. For now, it’s hard to say too much about the tech improvements without even seeing a prototype for ourselves in person. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T19:51:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T19:51:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile confirms it will shut down Sprint’s LTE network next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="t-mobile and sprint logos" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s3IN2gvmTmq1MfpeKh-YCszm0W4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675116/acasatro_180430_1777_sprint_Tmobile_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile has wasted no time consolidating Sprint’s network and spectrum with its own.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nZkG92"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/t-mobile-to-shutter-sprints-lte-network-on-june-30-2022/d/d-id/771269"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Light Reading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; T-Mobile has committed to a June 30, 2022 shutdown date for Sprint’s LTE network. It’s an expected move as T-Mobile continues to absorb Sprint’s network and customers into its own base, and comes six months after its contentious planned January 1, 2022 shutdown of Sprint’s 3G CDMA network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mckReg"&gt;A third of Sprint customers have already been moved onto the T-Mobile network, &lt;a href="https://investor.t-mobile.com/news-and-events/t-mobile-us-press-releases/press-release-details/2021/T-Mobile-Raises-2021-Guidance-Across-the-Board-Again-and-Delivers-Record-Financial-Results-in-Q2/default.aspx"&gt;according to T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;. The company expects to be able to migrate the remaining two thirds by that mid-2022 deadline, &lt;a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/operators/t-mobile-running-fast-to-achieve-benefits-merger"&gt;according to CFO Peter Osvaldik’s remarks&lt;/a&gt; at an investor conference last month. Some of those customers will likely need new devices that are compatible with T-Mobile LTE and VoLTE, though the company has had no shortage of enticing &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Ft-mobile-revvl-v-plus-5g%3Ficid%3DMGPO_TMO_P_21REVVLOUS_1U0R1MHTP3PF5UOM25482&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;5G phone offers lately&lt;/a&gt;. T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fcoverage%2Ft-mobile-network-evolution&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;says it will reach out to all customers&lt;/a&gt; who will need a new SIM card or device to stay connected, but if you’re curious whether your device is compatible you can run an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fcoverage%2Ft-mobile-network%23tech&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;IMEI check on T-Mobile’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ujfewh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile hasn’t been shy about moving quickly to consolidate Sprint’s network assets with its own&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Vud9n"&gt;The Sprint LTE network shutdown doesn’t come as a shock — by Sprint’s own admission the network &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/28/17914230/sprint-lte-network-coverage-bad-tmobile-merger"&gt;wasn’t very good to begin with&lt;/a&gt;, and T-Mobile hasn’t been shy about moving quickly to consolidate Sprint’s network assets with its own. The company’s 3G shutdown timeline &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;has been the source of a lot of bad blood&lt;/a&gt; between T-Mobile and Dish Network, which acquired Sprint’s former prepaid business Boost Mobile as part of the merger deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2AlnAM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Dish ‘fix’ for the T-Mobile-Sprint merger seems more shortsighted than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22585761/dish-t-mobile-att-sprint-competition-editorial"},{"title":"Predictably, T-Mobile’s merger promises weren’t enough to make a carrier out of Dish","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587790/t-mobile-sprint-acquisition-dish-promises"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="MckEQj"&gt;The relationship has soured to the point of Dish announcing that it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583799/dish-network-att-mvno-t-mobile-5g-4g"&gt;take the majority of its MVNO business to AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; — which T-Mobile followed with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598163/t-mobile-metro-5g-prepaid-boost-cricket-switch-promotion"&gt;a promotional offer directed at Boost customers&lt;/a&gt;. Boost had no additional comments to share about the potential impacts of the LTE shutdown on its customers when contacted by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608265/t-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608265/t-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T19:46:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T19:46:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T has officially spun off DirecTV, which is now its own business</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="DirecTV" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L6HMv6H9Q7flUIXx9KDC-Cs6e7Q=/0x0:6390x4260/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675098/1174204846.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Thomas Trutschel/Photothek via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GXVhLG"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T announced earlier this year that it would spin its video properties DirecTV, AT&amp;amp;T TV, and U-verse into a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301840/att-tpg-directv-tv-uverse-new-company-announced"&gt;new company&lt;/a&gt; it would co-manage with private equity firm TPG Capital. That transaction is finally complete, and the services will now operate as a single company under the name DirecTV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m1XhQt"&gt;As outlined earlier this year when the company initially announced plans to off-load its struggling DirecTV business, AT&amp;amp;T will retain a 70 percent stake in the company, while TPG will take a 30 percent stake. The telecom giant said the deal for which it received $7.1 billion in cash would help pay off its &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/18/business/ATT-WarnerMedia-Discovery.html"&gt;massive debt&lt;/a&gt;, with the company projecting it can put a stop to the bleeding by the end of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlKQvY"&gt;Part of that debt is owed because of AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/18/5727276/att-acquires-directv"&gt;acquisition of the original DirecTV&lt;/a&gt; in 2015, at which time AT&amp;amp;T paid $48.5 billion ($67 billion accounting for debt) to acquire the business. To say that that business decision has failed to deliver is putting it mildly, as DirecTV &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/12/att-reportedly-struggling-to-sell-directv-at-anything-but-a-huge-loss/"&gt;bled customers for years&lt;/a&gt; prior to the TPG deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ywKqR9"&gt;At the time the TPG deal was announced in February, AT&amp;amp;T boss John Stankey said that the company planned to focus specifically on “connectivity and content,” including 5G wireless and fiber as well as its service HBO Max. More recently, however, AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451111/att-ceo-stankey-unleash-assets-warnermedia-discovery-hbo"&gt;revised strategy&lt;/a&gt; is to focus on its core business and as Stankey put it recently, “unleash the media assets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDePtL"&gt;The deal with TPG does not include any of WarnerMedia’s various assets, including its marquee streaming service HBO Max, because those are being offloaded to Discovery instead. (WarnerMedia and Discovery are currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22448140/warner-bros-discovery-warnermedia-new-name-merger-att"&gt;awaiting approval&lt;/a&gt; for the merger of their two companies.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1Ol8Z"&gt;But the deal &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/video.html"&gt;will include&lt;/a&gt; existing DirecTV content deals for things like NFL Sunday Ticket. AT&amp;amp;T added that DirecTV would “continue to offer HBO Max to subscribers along with any bundled wireless or broadband services and associated customer discounts.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608577/att-directv-tpg-deal-u-verse-att-tv-new-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608577/att-directv-tpg-deal-u-verse-att-tv-new-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp launches its ‘View Once’ disappearing photos and videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KSZLcAXWiRCxmmTDWpvTBWGCTZs=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69674643/EN__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: WhatsApp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ByfzID"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/view-once-photos-and-videos-on-whatsapp"&gt;WhatsApp is rolling out&lt;/a&gt; its “View Once” feature today, which deletes photos or videos from your chat after they’ve been opened by the recipient. When sending a photo or video, you can make it view once by tapping the “1” button to the left of the send button. After the recipient opens it, it’ll be deleted. The recipient will be able to see that it’s a disappearing photo, so it’s still the type of thing you’d only want to use for people you trust to not take a screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zkaq4I"&gt;In June, Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466425/whatsapp-multi-device-support-disappearing-mode-view-once-features-confirmed"&gt;confirmed that the feature would be coming&lt;/a&gt;, though details about when it would release were scarce. &lt;a href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-is-rolling-out-photos-and-videos-set-to-view-once/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;WaBetaInfo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the feature has been in beta for about a month. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7BP8SKBE5QH9dzr94PTwTZ_K8Wo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759545/comp_VIEW_ONCE_EN_16x9_v012_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: WhatsApp&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The recipient will be left with a bubble simply saying “opened.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uYH8tW"&gt;As an example of how the feature could be used, WhatsApp uses the example of sending a photo of sensitive information, like a Wi-Fi password. Of course, there are perhaps other less wholesome uses for this kind of feature. But either way, it’s useful to have an option between the &lt;a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/chats/about-disappearing-messages"&gt;app’s disappearing messages&lt;/a&gt;, which currently only go away after a week, and your chat’s permanent record.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608419/whatsapp-view-once-dissapearing-media-launch-testing-sensitive-info"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608419/whatsapp-view-once-dissapearing-media-launch-testing-sensitive-info</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T15:46:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T15:46:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>OtterBox’s latest gaming clip jumps aboard the MagSafe train</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Otterbox MagSafe gaming clip" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xYK6kH2AtpcOyPAWg1Br0zrEG4M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69673837/otterboxmagsafe.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OtterBox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aob8Dy"&gt;OtterBox’s latest gaming controller clip is MagSafe-compatible for iPhone 12 devices, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.otterbox.com/en-us/xbox-x%7Cs--xbox-one--xbox-elite-wireless-series-2-controllers/mobile-gaming-clip-for-magsafe/77-82969.html#tab5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and it costs $39.99&lt;/a&gt;. Compared to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338087/otterbox-mobile-gaming-clip-review-xbox-controller-cloud-price"&gt;previous $30 gaming clip&lt;/a&gt; that we reviewed earlier this year, it streamlines the process of connecting your phone to a controller clip by letting it snap on seamlessly with the help of magnets — in other words, MagSafe technology (TM). This solution is preferable to traditional controller clips that clamp around the edges of your phone’s display. I just wish that this one worked with other phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQis5B"&gt;Some MagSafe-compatible accessories can also charge iPhone 12-series models, but in this case, OtterBox’s MagSafe gaming clip seems to boil down to “it’s a circular magnetic surface.” There are no other special features listed on its product page, aside from being able to detach the magnetic arm from the controller to serve as a phone stand. Also, you don’t need to own an OtterBox MagSafe case, but the company says you’ll get the “best experience and protection” if you do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Otterbox MagSafe gaming clip" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3lTBjPZU0M3ISOevsg-UkFKQGBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759096/otterboxmagsafe2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OtterBox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The clip can detach from the controller to work in tabletop mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4psGIg"&gt;In terms of controller compatibility, OtterBox says on its site that this new clip will fit the newer Xbox Series X / S controller, the previous Xbox One wireless controller, or the Xbox Elite Series 2 controller. Oddly, it also provides the disclaimer that the clip was designed to “ensure zero interference” with controller functions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sa2TTX"&gt;It’s easy to read that and think, “Wait, can magnets interfere with Bluetooth?” If that were the case, Bluetooth speakers, among many other devices, wouldn’t operate properly. What I think it means is that your controller will work normally. Perhaps the company just needed another line to plug in that its product has MagSafe compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mDdod"&gt;The MagSafe gaming clip is available now for iPhone 12 owners who want the convenience of attaching their phone to their gaming clip with magnets and don’t mind paying the $10 premium. Otherwise, you can make do with OtterBox’s previous model that works as intended with practically any phone running a modern mobile OS.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608012/otterbox-magsafe-compatible-gaming-clip-xbox-controller-price-iphone-12-mini-pro-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608012/otterbox-magsafe-compatible-gaming-clip-xbox-controller-price-iphone-12-mini-pro-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T08:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T08:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Realme launches MagDart magnetic wireless charging devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_uLABIWNFvtb7IAxYfsNGoK0h4=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69671195/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.009___.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5RDuFl"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22595550/realme-flash-magdart-wireless-charging-magnetic-android-specs"&gt;reported last week&lt;/a&gt;, Realme is working on a magnetic wireless charging system for its Android phones, and today it’s revealed a full range of products that’ll use the new technology. Realme is calling the system MagDart, and it’s basically a high-powered take on Apple’s MagSafe system for the iPhone 12 range of phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r8jHox"&gt;The key product in the lineup is the 50W MagDart charger, which Realme says is the world’s fastest magnetic wireless charger. It has an inescapably bulky cuboid design that makes room for a cooling fan, but Realme is banking that users will make the tradeoff for faster charging speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oD8xGq"&gt;When plugged into the company’s 65W SuperDart wired charger, Realme claims that the MagDart charger will fill a 4,500mAh phone battery up to 100 percent in 54 minutes. That’s almost as fast as what you get from Realme’s 50W wired charger.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UMWayB2ya6IR8I5bD7B1J1qihsc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22757981/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.011___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RFObBC"&gt;If you don’t want to have to plug a charging brick into a charging brick, Realme is also working on a somewhat sleeker and more convenient 15W MagDart charger, which basically looks like Apple’s MagSafe puck — though Realme points out it’s 26.4 percent thinner and claims faster charging speeds. It’ll fill a 4,500mAh battery in 90 minutes, according to Realme, which would indeed be &lt;a href="https://www.cambrionix.com/magsafe-usb-c-charging-speed-tested"&gt;much faster&lt;/a&gt; than Apple’s own 15W option.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RA93AmxmWRjo782pjm_7h35o2XE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22757985/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.021___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="H9ZFQG"&gt;Wireless charging convenience aside, a major advantage of a magnetic design like MagDart and MagSafe is the potential for slick portless accessories, and Realme has a bunch of those as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="6mfuyn"&gt;The 2-in-1 MagDart Power Bank is similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini"&gt;Apple’s recently-released MagSafe Battery Pack,&lt;/a&gt; but it comes with a dock that lets you use the battery as a phone stand.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UVPrDZ-dVzmqXS8K8vO_CQ9Fbck=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22758014/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.001___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZKrtej"&gt;The MagDart Case is a carbon fiber-style case for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22534618/realme-gt-hands-on-europe-launch-price-specs"&gt;the new Realme GT flagship phone&lt;/a&gt; with a passthrough USB-C port and headphone jack as well as built-in MagDart connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TQa74990q8Wpfirf_vgZoOLEsUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22758017/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.043___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="mbW209"&gt;The MagDart Wallet is, you guessed it, a three-card sleeve similar to Apple’s MagSafe wallet. But this one has a kickstand.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8jKMiMMweJ5mfrbwMxdsjwDKU9M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22758020/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.040___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="qQDjyf"&gt;Perhaps best of all is the MagDart Beauty Light, a flip-up ring light for selfies that’s powered by reverse wireless charging. It has 60 mini LEDs and a dedicated control button that lets you adjust settings like brightness and color temperature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V5tmot1sqNpTLFLqUmEHiD6E5ks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22758023/MagDart_keynote_product_part_final_final.038___.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1wpXkD"&gt;Realme hasn’t said anything about a release date or pricing for any of these products, and the sole existing phone confirmed to work with any MagDart device is the Realme GT — and that’s only if you buy the dedicated case. Realme is demonstrating the ecosystem with a “concept phone” called the Realme Flash, which is pictured in the above images and does have MagDart directly built in, but there aren’t any plans to actually release it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhvDRX"&gt;That’s a pretty big catch for what’s ostensibly a launch for a major new ecosystem of products. But if Realme does integrate MagDart into its future phones, it could be a solid differentiator. Wireless charging is consistently one of the key omissions from Chinese phones that otherwise have impressive spec sheets — Oppo only recently adopted the tech, and Vivo is yet to get on board. And since Oppo’s VOOC fast-charging system made its way to OnePlus and Realme phones due to the companies’ shared ownership and supply chain, it’s plausible that the same could happen with MagDart.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607214/realme-magdart-announced-magnetic-wireless-charger-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607214/realme-magdart-announced-magnetic-wireless-charger-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-29T19:44:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T19:44:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon’s new hotspot plans are built for your #vanlife dreams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W4TuZei39F0XAwRboLP5ZsDXM78=/98x0:1133x690/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69653612/mobile_hotspot_1230x690.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verizon’s hotspot plans offer mobile data that can be shared with other devices in your luxury camper van, er, house.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Verizon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H6FUdT"&gt;Verizon has introduced &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/plans/devices/hotspots/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new mobile hotspot plans&lt;/a&gt;, with four options to choose from starting at 15GB for $20 per month up to 150GB for $80 per month. They offer standalone and unlimited plan add-on mobile hotspot data that’s ready to be taken on the road. Maybe in a Class B Winnebago Solis with a pop-up sleeping compartment, as featured on &lt;em&gt;Wheel of Fortune&lt;/em&gt;, south through the redwoods and along the coast and then on through the painted deserts of the Southwest. What? I said that out loud? I mean, hypothetically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yRuuTj"&gt;Anyway, the most basic plan, Essential, offers low-band Nationwide 5G and 4G LTE connectivity. The three more expensive plans — creatively named Plus, Pro, and Premium — include Ultra Wideband 5G, which encompasses the very fast, limited-range mmWave flavor of 5G as well as upcoming mid-band spectrum that should deliver broad coverage and fast performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="h6QtC8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;some of us (me) pay for unlimited data on Verizon that inexplicably can’t be used via mobile hotspot&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B1c2Yg"&gt;The plans promise certain monthly premium data allotments; if they’re exceeded, data will be slower for the remainder of the month. Essential and Plus are available to Verizon customers, while Pro and Premium can be either added to an unlimited plan or purchased as standalone products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Jk11h"&gt;This is all well and good, but while we’re on the subject of unlimited plans, let’s not forget that some of us (me) pay for unlimited data on Verizon that inexplicably can’t be used via mobile hotspot. Let’s say (hypothetically) you’re sitting around your freezing cold house in March during a power outage waiting for the heat and the Wi-Fi to come back on and you think you’d like to get a little work done by switching on your phone’s mobile hotspot feature. Nope! Because you picked the cheapest unlimited plan, you’re stuck working on offline Google Docs until the power comes back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gkKL9r"&gt;Well, now I (hypothetically) have a couple of options: pay up for a premium unlimited plan (which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425022/verizon-t-mobile-att-phone-promotion-magenta-max-5g-c-band"&gt;exactly what The Man wants us to do&lt;/a&gt;), or buy a mobile hotspot, load that baby up with Premium Unlimited hotspot data and take off on a dreamy #vanlife tour of the Pacific Coast in an imaginary Winnebago Solis. The white one, not the red one. Let’s not get carried away.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600581/verizon-mobile-hotspot-plans-vanlife"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600581/verizon-mobile-hotspot-plans-vanlife</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-29T13:58:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T13:58:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola debuts Edge 20 flagships globally with fast refresh screens and 108-megapixel cameras</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c6wqOigeWXYwlkB318-eVG-AgLc=/0x102:2000x1435/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69651710/Edge_family_2021_sm.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Motorola Edge 20 Pro, Edge 20, and Edge 20 Lite all support 5G and come with a 6.7-inch OLED.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Motorola&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BYOUQf"&gt;Motorola is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21229740/motorola-edge-plus-android-phone-display-features-camera-specs-hands-on"&gt;keeping its return to flagship devices running&lt;/a&gt; for the second year in a row with today’s global announcement of the Edge 20 Pro, Edge 20, and Edge 20 Lite. The top-end 20 Pro includes a periscope-style telephoto lens for the first time in a Motorola device and includes a Snapdragon 870 processor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8G23N3"&gt;All three devices support sub-6GHz 5G, offer 108-megapixel rear-facing cameras, and include 6.7-inch OLED screens with fast refresh rates. They’re due to arrive in August in Europe, Latin America, and Asia. While Motorola doesn’t offer specifics, it says that it plans to bring a 5G Edge device to North America this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f8gGM8Ni6wMaaQ40TnvV0kCJ6QE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22748778/Motorola_edge_20_pro_Indigo_Vegan_Leather_combo_sm.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Motorola&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Edge 20 Pro comes in a handsome indigo vegan leather option.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xxwhnE"&gt;Priced at €699 (about $830), Edge 20 Pro comes with many features common to the premium midrange class, including a Gorilla Glass 5 front panel, a 144Hz screen refresh rate, and 12GB of RAM with its capable 800-series chipset. Its main rear camera uses a 108-megapixel 1/1.52-inch sensor and f/1.9 aperture, specs that line up with last year’s Edge Plus camera. There’s also a new 8-megapixel 5x telephoto periscope-style camera with optical image stabilization. A 16-megapixel ultrawide does double duty as a macro camera, along with a 32-megapixel selfie camera around front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62mzj2"&gt;A couple of specs don’t quite measure up to the flagship class, though, which was something we noted about its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/30/21241919/motorola-edge-plus-review-android-phone-screen-camera-specs-price"&gt;“great but not quite good enough” Edge Plus predecessor&lt;/a&gt;. For starters, Motorola is committing to only two OS upgrades for the device, which ships with Android 11 — a policy that lags behind much of the field. The 4,500mAh battery can be charged via fast 30W wired charging but there’s no support for wireless charging. And its IP52 rating means it’s protected against splashes of water, but isn’t guaranteed to survive full submersion like the IP68-rated Samsung Galaxy S21. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J6vMmqTCTBBdwoes7UPsds_xjcE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22748783/Motorola_edge_20_Frosted_Onyx_hero_sm.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Motorola&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Edge 20 offers a 3x telephoto lens rather than the 5x periscope zoom on the 20 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="M2tWAB"&gt;The €499 (about $590) Edge 20 gets the same 6.7-inch OLED with 144Hz refresh rate (though just Gorilla Glass 3 on the front), but includes a stepped-down Snapdragon 778 processor. Rather than the periscope zoom, it offers a stabilized 8-megapixel 3x telephoto camera, but its main and ultrawide cameras match those on the 20 Pro. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TkhdvJprhyVHhDEIFM43iXokRS8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22748786/Motorola_edge_20_lite_Cyber_Teal_hero_sm.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Motorola&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Edge 20 Lite packs a bigger 5,000mAh battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JazrSK"&gt;The budget-friendliest Edge 20 Lite, priced at €349 (about $415), uses a MediaTek Dimensity 5G-B chipset, includes a 6.7-inch OLED with a slower-but-still-fast 90Hz refresh rate, skips the telephoto camera altogether, and includes a bigger 5,000mAh battery. It maintains the IP52 rating of the other two devices and still includes 30W fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvb9ut"&gt;We liked last year’s Edge phones, particularly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21347201/motorola-edge-review-android-phone-screen-camera-specs-price"&gt;the more attractively priced midrange Edge&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot of that was thanks to some strong camera capabilities. It’s promising to see Motorola leaning into that strength with a new telephoto lens, though the highest tier device still appears to lack a couple of key specs to compete well in its class. Maybe the midrange will be Motorola’s sweet spot again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OwESPa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction July 29th, 3:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;A previous version of this article stated that Motorola has only guaranteed one Android OS upgrade for the Edge 20 devices; it has committed to two. We regret the error.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22599860/motorola-edge-20-pro-lite-camera-5g-global-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22599860/motorola-edge-20-pro-lite-camera-5g-global-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-29T08:53:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T08:53:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s P50 announced with Snapdragon 888 and HarmonyOS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uhlp_KVEO3mqB6bLNXG4pspHF2o=/0x0:1350x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69649677/msedge_IURr7pZvgC.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Huawei P50 Pro.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Huawei&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9n20KE"&gt;Huawei has announced its latest flagship phones for the Chinese market, the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fcn%2Fphones%2Fp50%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F29%2F22598135%2Fhuawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;P50&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fcn%2Fphones%2Fp50-pro%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F29%2F22598135%2Fhuawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;P50 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. They’re the company’s first major phones to launch with HarmonyOS, the company’s own branded mobile operating system, which pairs with Huawei’s typically well-specced cameras and hardware that includes Qualcomm’s flagship Snapdragon 888 processor in some models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="enbexA"&gt;The launch of the P50 series has come a little later in the year than the P40 did in 2020, thanks to US sanctions which have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/9/21360598/huawei-chips-us-sanctions-trump-china-privacy-smartphone"&gt;seriously impacted&lt;/a&gt; Huawei’s ability to produce new phones and restricted its ability to buy chips and other components from companies using US tech. When he first teased the phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464776/huawei-p50-phone-camera-periscope-telephoto-leica-harmonyos"&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt;, Huawei’s consumer business CEO Richard Yu said that a launch date hadn’t been set at the time “for reasons you are all aware of.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YV6Wqz"&gt;These sanctions mean that like other recent Huawei phones, the P50 series won’t include Google’s apps and services if it ever releases outside of China. In fact, according to Huawei, the P50 doesn’t run Android at all, thanks to its own HarmonyOS software. The extent to which HarmonyOS is actually distinct from Android is a &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/06/huaweis-harmonyos-will-rollout-to-100-android-models-over-the-next-year/"&gt;point of some contention&lt;/a&gt;, however, following reports that it’s effectively a fork of Android’s open-source code.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8mnC0EjvmrUsSywQErEBjY2xk2c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22747894/msedge_cpBid3DGiv.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Huawei&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Huawei P50.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dOdWfF"&gt;US sanctions have meant that not every P50 uses Huawei’s own Kirin chips. The P50 and one version of the P50 Pro use Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 888 processor, according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fcn%2Fphones%2Fp50%2Fspecs%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F29%2F22598135%2Fhuawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spec&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fcn%2Fphones%2Fp50-pro%2Fspecs%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F29%2F22598135%2Fhuawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sheets&lt;/a&gt; on the company’s site. Qualcomm was granted permission to sell chips to Huawei &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/14/21565185/us-qualcomm-license-4g-chips-huawei-ban-china-phones"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also a version of the P50 Pro shown with Huawei’s own Kirin 9000 processor. The P50 Pro is available with either 8 or 12GB of RAM with up to 512GB of internal storage, while the P50 is available with 8GB of RAM and up to 256GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BcdRp2"&gt;What you won’t find on the spec sheet of either phone is any mention of 5G. Speaking onstage during the launch event, Huawei consumer business CEO Richard Yu said that US sanctions meant that “5G phones are beyond our reach, and we have to go with 4G by removing the 5G module from our chip design.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OawPTQ"&gt;The P50 Pro has a 6.6-inch 120Hz 1228p OLED display, while the P50 has a slightly smaller 6.5-inch 90Hz 1224p OLED display. The P50 Pro has a 4,360mAh battery, compared to a 4,100mAh battery in the P50. Both can be fast charged wired at 66W, and the P50 Pro can be wirelessly charged at 50W. There’s an IP68 rating for dust and water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JPtL2p"&gt;If Huawei’s recent flagships are anything to go by, it’s the P50 series’ cameras that’ll be their most interesting feature. Housed within two circular camera bumps, the P50 Pro has four rear cameras — a 50-megapixel main, 64-megapixel telephoto with a 3.5x optical zoom, a 40-megapixel monochrome, and a 13-megapixel ultra-wide. The P50 has a similar camera bump, but it has one fewer camera lens. It has a 50-megapixel main camera, a 12-megapixel telephoto with a 5x optical zoom, and a 13-megapixel ultrawide. Both have 13-megapixel selfie cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cb7QyT"&gt;The P50 Pro starts at 5,988 yuan (around $927) for a model with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage and will go on general sale in China on August 12th. Huawei says that the first models will ship with its Kirin 9000 processor, with Qualcomm models following at the end of the year. The P50 starts at 4,488 yuan (around $695), also with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, and will go on sale in September. It’s unclear if or when either phone will receive a release outside of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ASL3st"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 29th, 10:24AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated with Richard Yu’s comments about the phones’ lack of 5G support due to US sanctions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EVdUTJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T23:21:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T23:21:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung boosts profits and pledges to ‘mainstream’ foldables</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VN8GDHZN3lGUW8I88mgKXi112CY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69648657/vpavic_190731_z_flip_0247_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OdLFlF"&gt;Samsung Electronics has released its second-quarter earnings, reporting 20 percent higher revenue and 54 percent higher operating profit year-on-year despite its mobile division taking a hit due to component shortages. The company made an operating profit of 12.57 trillion won (~$10.97 billion) off 63.67 trillion won (~$55.56 billion) in revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z14TCM"&gt;Samsung says its mobile business suffered from the industry-wide component shortage as well as “production disruptions” in its Vietnam factories, some of which were closed after a COVID outbreak. Combined with weak seasonality resulting in less demand, revenue declined from the previous quarter, though it was still up year-on-year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hNF4wV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung confirms Z Fold 3 S Pen support as Note line is in limbo","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594685/samsung-z-fold-3-stylus-support-note-durability"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="42Li6o"&gt;The semiconductor business continues to be Samsung’s biggest financial driver, contributing more than a third of the company’s revenue and more than half of its profits for the quarter. Samsung says memory demand and price increases were higher than previously forecast, though mobile memory sales were impacted by the same issues as seen by the smartphone division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbOeNE"&gt;Looking forward to the rest of the year, Samsung says it will “solidify its leadership in the premium [smartphone] segment by mainstreaming the foldable category,” while the display division confirmed it’s working on under-screen camera technology. Samsung has an event set for August 11th where it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594685/samsung-z-fold-3-stylus-support-note-durability"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it’ll announce new phones in the Galaxy Z Fold and Z Flip lines.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22599306/samsung-q2-2021-earnings-component-shortage-foldables"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22599306/samsung-q2-2021-earnings-component-shortage-foldables</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
