<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-09T09:59:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T09:59:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T09:59:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vodafone latest UK carrier to reintroduce roaming charges in Europe after Brexit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Masked customers queue to enter Vodafone Mobile Phone Store..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xzuy64efwhZV1QK-OQVpuhOlVa8=/0x164:5000x3497/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69698853/1234410114.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael McNerney/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZNzbEa"&gt;Vodafone has announced it will &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vodafone.co.uk%2Froamingupdate22&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F9%2F22616543%2Fvodafone-europe-roaming-charges-price-tariff-brexit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reintroduce roaming charges&lt;/a&gt; in Europe for UK mobile customers from January next year. It’s the latest UK carrier to reintroduce the fees after the country’s departure from the European Union, and it follows a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548668/ee-uk-carrier-roaming-charges-european-union"&gt;similar U-turn from EE&lt;/a&gt; in June. All major carriers in the country &lt;a href="https://www.cityam.com/major-uk-mobile-networks-vow-not-reintroduce-roaming-charges/"&gt;previously said&lt;/a&gt; they had no plans to introduce roaming fees in Europe after the Brexit vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glGRZq"&gt;The fees will apply to any Vodafone customers who sign up to or change their contract from August 11th, 2021, with the fees applying from January 6th, 2022. Costs are dependent on the specific plan, but most customers will pay £2 ($2.77) a day to use their UK allowance of calls, texts, and data in Europe, or £1 a day if access is bought in eight- or 15-day bundles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ohPej"&gt;Customers signed up to Vodafone’s “Unlimited Data Xtra plan with 4 Xtra benefits” or “Limited Data Xtra plan with 4 Xtra benefits” will pay no extra fee to use their UK allowance in Europe. All UK Vodafone customers traveling to the Republic of Ireland, an EU member state, will not have to pay any roaming fees regardless of their contract. Full details of the new payment plans can be &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vodafone.co.uk%2Froamingupdate22&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F9%2F22616543%2Fvodafone-europe-roaming-charges-price-tariff-brexit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ti7lO"&gt;Roaming charges were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/25/15418776/eu-mobile-roaming-charges-date-june-15"&gt;abolished in the European Union&lt;/a&gt; on June 15th, 2017, but after the UK voted to leave the EU, it had to renegotiate its trade agreements with the bloc. These did not include free mobile roaming, allowing UK carriers to reintroduce fees if they wished. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tVuENU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616543/vodafone-europe-roaming-charges-price-tariff-brexit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616543/vodafone-europe-roaming-charges-price-tariff-brexit</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What to expect from Samsung’s August Unpacked event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5LSJypPHZrnZSp5JxQeLknnqQlo=/151x0:1050x599/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69698607/E7Ow9IyXsAAEUyS.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1419674682543034370" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WleRDN"&gt;The next Galaxy Unpacked event is fast approaching &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585256/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-flip-watch-unpacked-event-august"&gt;on August 11th at 10AM ET / 7AM PT&lt;/a&gt; — but you might’ve already seen what Samsung has lined up, thanks to a copious amount of leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNoWn8"&gt;Samsung is expected to announce new additions to its high-end line of folding Galaxy Z Fold and Z Flip phones. Based on leaks, both the Galaxy Z Fold 3 and Z Flip 3 seem more like refinements to Samsung’s existing designs with the newest specs. The new Fold and Flip should come with new color options and, in the case of the Flip, a reworked outside screen and camera housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9j18tO"&gt;Now that Samsung and Google have revealed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440483/samsung-smartwatch-google-wearos-tizen-watch"&gt;their smartwatch partnership with Wear OS 3&lt;/a&gt;, it seems like Samsung might also launch two of the first smartwatches to run it. Leaks seem to suggest Samsung will show off a new Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 Classic and Galaxy Watch Active 4. The company is also rumored to be updating its line of true wireless earbuds with the Galaxy Buds 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NFmZuZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; will be covering all of Samsung’s next foldable moves, but ahead of the event, here’s the breakdown of what we know so far.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qZULQKv1zeeuJKAzVV0v4dZAQrE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22679450/E4qkWBHXwAgIQ_W.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1408107239903223808?s=21" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (tweet now deleted)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Z Fold 3 with S Pen stylus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="tv9Bmy"&gt;The Galaxy Z Fold 3 is gaining a major Note feature: stylus support&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="r5IDMf"&gt;Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594685/samsung-z-fold-3-stylus-support-note-durability"&gt;has confirmed there won’t be a new Note in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems the Galaxy Z Fold 3 is the latest flagship phone to gain access to the Note’s formerly exclusive stylus features. &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-z-fold-3-s-pen-case-renders/"&gt;Leaked images from &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; suggest the Fold will get an optional case that holds Samsung’s S Pen stylus when you’re not using it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Leaked Galaxy Z Fold 3 case" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Df-Rb3lQUoCWfx8LGvHu7TVAxSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22741284/Samsung_Galaxy_Z_Fold3_Samsung_S_Pen_case_render_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-s-pen-case-renders-exclusive/" target="_blank"&gt;91mobiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leaked Galaxy Z Fold 3 case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4602QH"&gt;Bundled in its stylus reveal, Samsung also confirmed that the new Fold and Flip will feature improved durability, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594727/samsung-z-flip-3-fold-water-resistant-ipx8-pen-case"&gt;with rumors of IPX8 water resistance&lt;/a&gt; possibly supporting part of that claim. Otherwise, it seems like the new Fold will feel like a yet more refined version of the previous two models, offering three color options of green, black, and silver, and a Snapdragon 888 processor. The phone is also expected to have a 7.55-inch interior folding screen and a 6.23-inch external screen, with both rumored to be 120Hz high refresh rate displays, &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/samsung/galaxy-z-fold-3/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WihO95"&gt;For cameras, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1419674682543034370?s=20"&gt;prolific leaker Evan Blass suggests&lt;/a&gt; the Fold will feature three 12-megapixel rear cameras, one of which will be an ultrawide and the other telephoto, &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;XDA-Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The exterior selfie camera is expected to be 10 megapixels, while the inside selfie camera is rumored to only be 4 megapixels but possibly housed under the Fold’s inside panel. Samsung Display has teased its work with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230521/samsung-display-under-panel-camera-laptop-webcam-oled-bezels"&gt;under-panel cameras in the past for laptops&lt;/a&gt;, so it's possible the company could debut something similar with the Fold 3.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XUwp_n_ImCHiueUlb_cbu4yHlPc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22764805/E7zXe5GXEAAM7tj.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1422248674923589639?s=20" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A leaked render of the yellow Galaxy Z Flip 3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="1nyvu5"&gt;The Galaxy Z Flip 3 has a tweaked design and larger cover screen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="UKfSTW"&gt;The Galaxy Z Flip 3 is expected to feature a new exterior design with vertically stacked 12-megapixel rear cameras and a larger 1.9-inch cover display for notifications and selfie camera shots. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1422248661271162887?s=20"&gt;Leaked renders from Evan Blass&lt;/a&gt; show the device coming in at least four colors: light purple, light yellow, grayish-green, and black.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qrb8cxoGcRIF5FQz7wT2C9Iuweg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22770781/Screenshot_2021_08_08_10.17.53_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://winfuture.de/screenshots/Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-3-23535-1.html#sci1627690291,3240,2160,23535" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The redesigned front cover of the Galaxy Z Flip 3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S9nVyY"&gt;The interior screen of the Flip 3 is rumored to be &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/samsung/galaxy-z-flip-3/"&gt;the same 6.5-inch display size&lt;/a&gt; as the original Z Flip but with a new 120Hz high refresh rate display. The interior hole-punch selfie camera will reportedly sport a 10-megapixel sensor. This might not be a dramatic interior change from the first Galaxy Z Flip, but leaked renders suggest that Samsung may have also shrunk the bezels of the Flip 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wqpWTZ"&gt;Like Samsung’s other flagship phones, the Flip 3 will likely be powered by the Snapdragon 888 and, in the case of the Flip 3, the same 8GB of RAM as the first Flip, &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/samsung/galaxy-z-flip-3/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OuZNor39MpsFmXFgbdydFF_Y6iM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22764672/E70882aWUAYpaJ_.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1422360213236195329?s=20" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The rumored Galaxy Watch or Active 4.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="jHlNxl"&gt;The new Galaxy Watches might fit more wrists&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="qrL1Cc"&gt;Samsung is expected to introduce at least two new smartwatches at Wednesday’s event. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558761/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-classic-smartwatch-news-rumors-features"&gt;The Galaxy Watch 4 Classic&lt;/a&gt; will reportedly feature a more traditional watch shape, with a rotating bezel and 42mm, 44mm, and 46mm sizes, which should at least give people more size options to play with. The Galaxy Watch 4 Classic is rumored to come in two finishes, aluminum or stainless steel, both of which will be water-resistant in depths of up to 50 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IOVAOg"&gt;The more sleek and modern &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22546997/samsung-galaxy-watch-active-4-renders-leak-tizen-wear-os-smartwatch"&gt;Galaxy Watch 4&lt;/a&gt; (or Galaxy Watch 4 Active, it’s not entirely clear) will reportedly come with two side buttons and in either 40mm or 44mm sizes. &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/samsung/galaxy-watch-4/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt; suggests&lt;/a&gt; you’ll be able to choose from watches in either black, olive green, rose gold, or silver, with additional customizations for watch bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zbtmPH"&gt;Both watches are expected to run Samsung and Google’s new co-developed Wear OS 3. Not much is known about it, but leaks have definitely seemed to show it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/1/22604862/samsung-galaxy-watch-photos-images-leaked-classic-4-wear-smartwatch-os-google"&gt;running on both of Samsung’s new watches&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung also showed some of what its skinned One UI version of Wear OS 3 would look like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22550828/samsung-mwc-2021-one-ui-watch-smartwatch"&gt;at Mobile World Congress earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f3moMk3JWR22xBYUuwjT-1p-azQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22764741/E709wAtXsAMpqaV.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1422361025807101954?s=20" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Leaked renders of Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="FtxMJ0"&gt;New Galaxy Buds 2 with improved sound in a variety of colors&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="i9nhWr"&gt;Samsung’s next set of true wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/27/22552705/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-leaked-renders-four-colors"&gt;the Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt;, don’t seem wildly different from its original pair in terms of design. They are, however, expected to come in new colors and feature improved noise reduction abilities, possibly helped by silicone ear tips similar to the ones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Samsung included in the Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFe3Ro"&gt;The Galaxy Buds 2 are rumored to come in green (some renders look like the inside of a pistachio), pink, black, and white. The new case for the Buds 2 also seems to lift some of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465651/google-pixel-buds-a-series-earbuds-review-features-price"&gt;the design elements of the Pixel Buds A-series&lt;/a&gt;: uniform white exterior, with a colored interior that matches the buds themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldX4YS"&gt;It’s not clear what kind of battery life gains the new Galaxy Buds 2 could pack in, but Federal Communications Commission filings &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/galaxy-buds-2-fcc-leak/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;XDA-Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; show the device’s charging case has a 500mAh battery, and each earbud will have a 60mAh battery.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22608535/samsung-unpacked-event-date-time-galaxy-z-fold-flip-earbuds-watches"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22608535/samsung-unpacked-event-date-time-galaxy-z-fold-flip-earbuds-watches</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T14:35:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T14:35:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>The FCC finally made a new broadband map of the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wS0eUSzhJ-Rxjc9F9g3aolzq1ms=/184x0:1750x1044/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689876/Screen_Shot_2021_08_06_at_9.06.49_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: FCC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7eTcDY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-launches-new-mobile-broadband-map"&gt;The Federal Communications Commission has launched&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://fcc.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=6c1b2e73d9d749cdb7bc88a0d1bdd25b"&gt;new map&lt;/a&gt; designed to show consumers what kind of cellular coverage they can expect in a given area from AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, US Cellular, and Verizon. It’s been a long time coming, and it doesn’t address &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22418074/broadband-gap-america-map-county-microsoft-data"&gt;home internet availability&lt;/a&gt;, but it looks like an improvement over the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17882842/us-internet-broadband-map-isp-fcc-wireless-competition"&gt;woefully inadequate and inaccurate&lt;/a&gt; past attempts to show gaps in the nation’s broadband coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNVutI"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editor-in-chief Nilay Patel &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless/status/1423671191210954752?s=20"&gt;pointed out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, it shouldn’t have taken this long for this map to be available. The &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2020/3/bill-to-improve-broadband-data-maps-signed-into-law"&gt;law requiring that these maps be made&lt;/a&gt;, known as the Broadband Deployment Accuracy and Technological Availability (DATA) Act, was signed in March 2020, and the lack of details about broadband coverage has created confusion about the so-called digital divide for years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sL7XuU"&gt;It’s also worth noting that the map isn’t based on data that the FCC collected or crowdsourced. FCC acting chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel said in a news release that the data was provided by the carriers who don’t have a great reputation for having the most accurate picture &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;of where they do and don’t provide broadband&lt;/a&gt; (though the FCC is working on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22345533/fcc-broadband-data-collection-program-fix-the-internet"&gt;getting a better picture of home internet availability&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22574103/internet-bill-equity-verge-consumer-reports-partnership"&gt;working on examining how cost-effective broadband is&lt;/a&gt;). The map also doesn’t address the issue with home internet availability, which has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/10/6131759/i-live-in-the-us-and-i-cant-get-home-internet"&gt;a long-running concern&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Xj9r3k-UzIq5KRkXH20J0jatkc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766633/FCC_Map_Vs.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FCC’s map (left) versus T-Mobile (right, top), AT&amp;amp;T (right, middle), and Verizon’s (right, bottom).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w05RVM"&gt;The interactive map lets users select which carrier’s coverage map they want to see, and it provides information about LTE coverage, voice coverage, or both. The FCC says the map is the work of its Broadband Data Task Force. The map is fairly user-friendly; instead of having to flip between &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcoverage%2Fcoverage-map&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F6%2F22613096%2Ffcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/maps/wireless-coverage.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/coverage-map/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s&lt;/a&gt; coverage maps, users can see all of the data in one place, overlaid on top of each other. The map also provides a distinction between data availability and voice availability — which is useful, as being able to make a call and being able to get online are obviously two very different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ylnplN"&gt;One big thing the map is missing is data about 5G coverage, or really any indicator of what kind of speeds users can expect. &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/news-events/notes/2021/08/06/new-mobile-map-preview-whats-come"&gt;In a note about the map’s launch&lt;/a&gt;, Rosenworcel says the network has to provide at least 5Mbps down and 1Mbps up to qualify as 4G data coverage. If one carrier provided an area with 100Mbps speeds and another provided 10Mbps speeds, that could be difficult to distinguish on the map. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4ogxZB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Data for the map is provided by the carriers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="juNEm2"&gt;Rosenworcel also admits that this map is only a first step in the FCC’s work to improve the information available to consumers, but it’s an important one. It at least lets consumers know the minimum of what mobile coverage they should expect in a given area and gives them the tools to make more informed decisions about their cellular provider. Hopefully the FCC will be able to have a similar effort to map the availability of home internet connections in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1pnq8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 6th, 5:00PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clarified that this map doesn’t address home internet availability issues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613096/fcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613096/fcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T09:00:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T09:00:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best phone plans in 2021 (and how to pick one)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/scMaL7yhAqctduO7lUG16ZZ6KzM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69687901/awhite_200223_3916_0446.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Avery White for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Shopping for a phone plan doesn’t have to be painful&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="sWASXY"&gt;Some of us get excited about shopping for a new phone (New technology! Megapixels! Fancy screen!), but none of us enjoy shopping for a new phone plan. Spending any amount of time at a wireless retail store is not high on our list of things to do with our precious time on this planet. And yet we must. While we can’t promise to make it an enjoyable experience, we can help you do a little homework ahead of time to make it less painful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OQUpt4"&gt;If you prefer to cut right to the chase, we’ve got two recommendations from the major US carriers for you: &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone-plans%2Fessentials&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22606623%2Fbest-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile’s Essentials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking for unlimited, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/shared-data/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verizon’s 10GB Shared Data plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you’d rather have a set amount of data each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ObrwNh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10682646" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="EVX5wr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10682697" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YxiK3j"&gt;T-Mobile’s Essentials plan is your best bet for a cheap phone plan with unlimited data: at $60 per month for a single line, it’s the least expensive unlimited plan from a major carrier and includes some nice extras like wireless hotspot data (at slower 3G speeds, but better than none at all — which is what you’ll get on comparable plans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rGcWlt"&gt;Verizon’s 10GB Shared Data plan is $65 per month for a single line and should provide plenty of data for most people. Verizon lets you roll over unused data and includes mobile hotspot usage for no extra fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HZtrZO"&gt;We’ll go into more detail about these plans and some of our recommendations for the best cheap unlimited plan, best premium unlimited plan, and best cheap by-the-gig plan a bit later, but first, take a look at a few things to consider before you pick a plan. If you also happen to be shopping for a new device, we’ve got suggestions for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone"&gt;best phone you can buy right now&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"&gt;best phone under $500&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s_qJ3xeWXCnCBAPAWbr7rMnn2vM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13250625/akrales_181010_3013_0161.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nUzok3"&gt;Location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="fL0aST"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10686366"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kTOBax"&gt;This is an obvious — and important — first consideration in your mobile plan shopping process. On a high level, you’ll want to know which wireless carriers cover your area. If you’re in or near a major city, you’re pretty much guaranteed service from any of the major carriers. If you’re in a rural area, you may have fewer choices and a smaller, regional carrier might serve your needs better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5Jvjw"&gt;Carriers’ published coverage maps are a good starting point. They’re not reliable enough to gauge coverage in a particular neighborhood or on your street, but they can help identify carriers without a significant presence in your area. Check US Cellular’s coverage, too, since it tends to offer service where some of the major carriers don’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3O97am"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt; provides a thorough, balanced evaluation of the major carriers’ network performance across the country every year; &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/fastest-mobile-networks-2020"&gt;take a look at 2020’s results&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/opinions/which-us-5g-network-is-fastest-were-revving-up-to-find-out"&gt;keep an eye out for 2021 results soon&lt;/a&gt;. And it doesn’t hurt to poll your co-workers and neighbors about their wireless service for more data points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="FHTFCl"&gt;Budget basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xeRavP"&gt;When you start shopping around, you’ll see some very attractive prices on the major carriers’ unlimited plans, like $30 or $45 per month. Remember that those are prices &lt;em&gt;per line&lt;/em&gt; on your account, and the prices carriers like to show you are based on their best per line rate, which is usually available when you have four or five lines. If you’re shopping for a single line, expect to spend around $70 per month, plus taxes and fees in most cases. For four lines, expect around $140 for your total bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7LEeRV"&gt;The quoted prices on carriers’ websites also include a discount for signing up for autopay. If you’re not comfortable signing up for autopay, you’ll need to add a little more to your monthly bill — $10 per line per month in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="702rIO"&gt;Shared data versus unlimited&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="DnX0ZR"&gt;Plan costs add up fast, but there are ways to save a little bit if you’re okay with looking outside of the big carriers’ marquee plans. If you’re a lighter data user, a shared data plan with a set allotment of data per month can save you a bit of money. AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon both offer such plans starting around $50 per month for a single line. (All of T-Mobile’s plans offer some kind of “unlimited” data service.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aaXT4w"&gt;Shared data plans seem to be on their way out, and carriers will be much happier to steer you toward an unlimited plan. There are some downsides to shared data plans, too. They tend to be limited to 4G or low-band 5G, which isn’t a big deal now but could be in the next few years. But on the plus side, both Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T allow mobile hotspot use on their shared data plans, which isn’t an option on either carrier’s basic unlimited plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m0GJll"&gt;Which brings us to one of the great mysteries of carrier unlimited plans: they aren’t really unlimited. Even the most expensive unlimited plans include limitations on how much data you can use via mobile hotspot. Most plans also include monthly data thresholds that, once exceeded, leave you subject to temporary slowdowns in times when the network is busy. Before you pick an unlimited plan, it’s a good idea to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360228/unlimited-plan-verizon-att-t-mobile-premium-data-tethering-limits"&gt;read up on the fine print&lt;/a&gt; so you know just what you are (and aren’t) getting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ePTP7Pj9AsZJelzBrpC_kv5cKl0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11579471/akrales_180620_1777_0481.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wEQp9g"&gt;MVNOs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="Fwtn3f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10685640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CN3dzx"&gt;Signing up with a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO) can also help you save some money. These companies resell service on the major carriers’ networks, so with a couple of exceptions, you’re getting access to the same network for less money. These plans are better suited for those who don’t need the absolute best network speeds because they typically include lower prioritization thresholds than the major network plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a7hMrT"&gt;Many MVNOs are set up to operate without retail locations, too, which could be a positive or a negative depending on if you prefer to walk into a store to troubleshoot issues with your connectivity. They’re also more eagerly adopting eSIM, which many newer phones support and which removes the need to wait for a physical SIM card to pop into your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XQzs7e"&gt;Generally, you’ll find more plan options with set data limits per month than the few shared data options that remain with the big carriers. You’ll also find more prepaid options and fewer requirements like credit checks or contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2YDxaJ"&gt;Prepaid versus postpaid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="tFCoEl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10685643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oCKEFj"&gt;In addition to MVNO prepaid options, the big three carriers also offer their own prepaid plans. These plans don’t require credit checks, but you’re still getting your service and customer support directly from the network operator. There are data-capped and unlimited data options across the board, and if you’re willing to spend more, you can get premium features like HD streaming video and mobile hotspot data that not even all postpaid unlimited plans include.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zjDshy"&gt;Prepaid plans directly from the big carriers can also be nearly as expensive as postpaid. Depending on your situation, it may make sense to pay a little more per month for a postpaid plan or go with an MVNO for a better price. But they’re a decent option, especially if you’re looking for a single-line plan, have predictable data usage habits, and need to avoid the credit check on postpaid plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_eXRr4Xo7Emg-AFewkPhvPS7nUk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11596517/akrales_180620_1777_0259.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3gBzjR"&gt;Best phone plans in 2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SSIljM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our plan recommendations take into account cost, features, and restrictions imposed on the carrier plans we evaluated. They should be considered along with network performance in your area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="81QBe1"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best basic unlimited plan: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone-plans%2Fessentials&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22606623%2Fbest-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile Essentials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;$60 / month for one line (with autopay)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ei18fC"&gt;At $60 per month for a single line, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone-plans%2Fessentials&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22606623%2Fbest-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile’s Essentials&lt;/a&gt; is the least expensive of the major carriers. Assuming T-Mobile coverage in your area is sufficient, it offers the best value for someone who just wants to stay connected and not worry about data overages. Plus, it includes 3G hotspot data and access to all flavors of T-Mobile’s already-strong 5G network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mi9lYS"&gt;It’s always subject to data slowdowns when the network is busy, but so are the other carriers’ basic unlimited plans. T-Mobile may impose additional slowdowns for users who go over 50GB of data in a month, so if you’re a heavy data user, you may want to consider a more expensive unlimited plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lnoIck"&gt;T-Mobile offers a handy way to test-drive its network on your own phone without switching from your current provider. It’s only available with certain iPhones right now, and you should be aware that you might experience faster speeds than you’ll actually get with data prioritization on the Essentials plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BoeptR"&gt;
&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10682646"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="EncFUu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10682520"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5g314D"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ymV6yH"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best premium unlimited plan: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/unlimited/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verizon Play More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;$80 / month for a single line (with autopay)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dSigOl"&gt;The major carriers offer two pricier “step-up” plans with the exception of Verizon — it offers three, but the middle two are essentially the same except for the mix of included services. For very heavy data users and those who want the highest possible streaming video quality, the top tier plans make the most sense, but for most people, one of the middle-of-the-road options is likely a better fit. &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/unlimited/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s Play More Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; (and nearly identical Do More) plan isn’t the cheapest option, but it strikes the best balance of cost versus features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sj6Tfo"&gt;You’ll get 720p HD video streaming (though this needs to be enabled in your Verizon account) along with a healthy 15GB of mobile hotspot data and a 50GB threshold of premium data before slowdowns can be imposed. Crucially, it includes access to Verizon’s Ultra Wideband (UW) 5G, which will become important over the next few years as it brings new spectrum online. You get super-fast but hard to find mmWave 5G, too, which isn’t worth upgrading for, but it’s part of the UW bundle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GOY5Dj"&gt;Finally, the included services are worthwhile. Play More includes access to Disney Plus, Hulu, and ESPN Plus, which is shared across all lines on the account. If you’re not interested in those streaming services, Do More includes 600GB of Verizon Cloud storage as an alternative, though, honestly, that sounds like a lot less fun than having nine seasons of &lt;em&gt;Letterkenny&lt;/em&gt; included with your phone plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h8N4bl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685853"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="u7d2fg"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best family plan: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/unlimited/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verizon Play More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;$180 / month for four lines (with autopay)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="YNWBrA"&gt;Verizon’s Play More is also our top pick for families. Four standard lines will cost $45 each for a total of $180 per month, but parents with younger kids can mix and match the standard plan with &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/unlimited/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s Just Kids plans&lt;/a&gt;, which are cheaper and offer parental control features. Just Kids lines come with a limit of up to 20 contacts for talk and text, and speeds capped at 5Mbps — good for a younger kid whose phone use you want to keep closer tabs on but not well-suited for older kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZGmyt7"&gt;At least one unlimited plan line is required to add Just Kids lines, which are $35 each for an account with four lines, making a plan with two Play More lines and two Just Kids lines $160 per month. And Disney Plus included with the price of the plan doesn’t hurt, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Tn0aVJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10682526"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="GtZ2fZ"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="KrlGCb"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best postpaid shared data plan: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/shared-data/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verizon Shared Data Plan — 10GB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;$65 / month&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KapvP3"&gt;We think &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergePhonePlans08052021/https://www.verizon.com/plans/shared-data/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s $65 per month 10GB plan&lt;/a&gt; provides the best bang for your shared-data buck compared to its 5GB plan and AT&amp;amp;T’s 4GB plan (T-Mobile doesn’t offer postpaid shared data plans). However, if you buy a phone from Verizon on a two-year contract, that monthly price goes up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OFCXUf"&gt;The 10GB plan typically costs $40 per month for account access and an additional $25 per month per line (with autopay), adding up to $65 per month for a plan with a single line. If you’re on a two-year device contract, that $25 fee per line per month goes up to $40 — with or without autopay enabled — so you’ll pay $80 per month for a single line plus the cost of the phone itself, which varies depending on the model. If you prefer buying your phone through your carrier on a two-year plan, then an unlimited plan may make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wBAB6t"&gt;Otherwise, the 10GB plan is about the same price as the company’s basic unlimited plan but comes with the ability to stream video at 720p (once enabled for your account) and use your data via a mobile hotspot. You can also carry unused data over to the next billing cycle, and use your data on other non-phone connected devices like a tablet for an extra $10 per month per device; unlimited requires a separate device plan starting at $10 per month for a smartwatch or $20 for a tablet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="b8q5vP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685884"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Jgd2CY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10682529"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="oVlryv"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6KFJ2Z"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best cheap phone plan (by the gig): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/plans/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Fi Flexible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Starting at $30 / month for a single line&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="T7sKQo"&gt;Our pick for the best cheap data-capped phone plan is &lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/plans/"&gt;Google Fi Flexible&lt;/a&gt;, which costs between $30 and $80 per month. It isn’t the least expensive, and it’s certainly not the one with the easiest pricing structure to comprehend. But it does live up to its “Flexible” name and offers some inclusions that cost extra on other plans, like mobile hotspot data and additional SIMs for non-phone devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4jQDm"&gt;Here’s how it works: on the Flexible plan, you prepay a set access fee per line at the start of every month, depending on the number of lines on your account. (It’s $20 for one line.) At the end of that, you pay $10 for every 1GB of data used during the month, up to a set maximum amount determined by, again, the number of lines on your plan. That’s 6GB on a single-line plan, so your plan will cost at most $80 per month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9wbPA"&gt;You can keep using data beyond that limit, but you won’t be charged more, and you won’t experience drastic slowdowns until you reach 15GB. At that point, you’ll be dropped down to 2G speeds for the rest of the month unless you add more data at $10 / GB. Again — not the cheapest plan by any means — but if you can get by most months on 2 or 3GB of data, your $40 or $50 bill will look pretty good compared to most alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zugdMm"&gt;It’s a little bit more complicated than your typical phone plan, but it means you’re only paying for the data you use in a month — with a lot of flexibility built in if you need to use a little or a lot more data than usual in a typical billing cycle. And it includes a somewhat rare feature: the option to add data-only SIMs at no extra charge so you can use your plan across other devices like tablets and smartwatches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="U9Psqx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685910"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="GWgECJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10682574"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="jsQiQH"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Fhbd29"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Best cheap unlimited phone plan: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mintmobile.com%2Fproduct%2F12-month-unlimited-sim-card-plan%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22606623%2Fbest-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mint Mobile 12-month Unlimited Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;$30 / month (pre-pay $360)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="BXc1NS"&gt;Going by raw numbers alone, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mintmobile.com%2Fproduct%2F12-month-unlimited-sim-card-plan%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22606623%2Fbest-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Mobile’s $30-per-month unlimited plan&lt;/a&gt; stands out with easily the lowest monthly cost for unlimited data. However, to get that price you’ll need to prepay for 12 months of service for a sizable $360 upfront cost. New customers can try the service for three months at that $30 rate. But after that, you’ll need to renew for the full year or pay a little more for a six-month plan ($35 per month for an upfront cost of $210). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sh5oxm"&gt;If paying up front is doable for you, then you’ll get one of the best deals in wireless. The plan includes 5G, comes with 5GB of mobile hotspot data per month, and you won’t experience significant slowdowns unless you surpass 35GB of data in a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tlENcl"&gt;If paying for six or 12 months of service up front isn’t the best option for you, then we think &lt;a href="https://visible.pxf.io/c/482924/1068329/12909?subId1=VergePhonePlans08052021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.visible.com%2Fplan%2F"&gt;Visible’s $40 per month standard plan&lt;/a&gt; is the next best option. Visible runs on Verizon’s network (and is, in fact, owned by Verizon) and includes some perks you won’t even get on Verizon’s own basic unlimited plan. You’ll get UW 5G access — capped at 200Mbps, but still, probably at least as good as your home Wi-Fi. Mobile hotspot usage is also included, though it is capped at 5Mbps. That’s a bit slower than 4G, so you won’t want to rely on it as a primary connection for your laptop, but it’s good enough for basic internet browsing and email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OxZkPP"&gt;Of course, Visible customers are more likely to see their speeds slow down compared to Verizon’s own subscribers when the network gets busy, so there is some benefit to signing up directly with the network. But it’s a significant step up from $40 per month to the $70-per-month Verizon Start Unlimited plan in order to guarantee faster network speeds at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SpJLD3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685972"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="j797LN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10682576"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22606623/best-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22606623/best-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T19:09:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T19:09:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook streamlines the settings page on mobile</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WeaYdozU55jXG8f3rO9Z0346mqc=/10x0:1398x925/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69680466/Screen_Shot_2021_08_04_at_3.36.00_PM.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The old Facebook settings page compared to the new one on mobile.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g5pmmN"&gt;Facebook is streamlining the settings page on mobile in &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/08/facebook-settings-redesign/"&gt;a new redesign&lt;/a&gt; that’s rolling out starting Wednesday. Visually, the new layout looks much less cluttered, and individual settings don’t have descriptions, meaning you’ll see more on the page at a time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0ROKf"&gt;Facebook has also changed up the organization of the settings themselves. The company has reduced the number of categories for settings and renamed them, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/08/facebook-settings-redesign/"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, so now, you’ll see six categories of settings: Account, Preferences, Audience and Visibility, Permissions, Your Information, and Community Standards and Legal Policies. Some settings have also been relocated so that they’re by related ones, Facebook says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMPyON"&gt;You’ll be able to see the new look on Android, iOS, mobile web, and Facebook Lite. You might already have the redesign — I just checked the Facebook app on my iPhone 12 Mini and it loaded up. It was present on the mobile web for me, too.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610310/facebook-mobile-settings-page-redesign-layout-ios-android-web-lite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610310/facebook-mobile-settings-page-redesign-layout-ios-android-web-lite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T23:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T23:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo announces ‘next-generation’ under-display selfie camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BVtbzeVdgX-gEZ2Tc2W38f8KvLQ=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675770/OPPO_USC_2021_Prototype___3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Oppo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IQYZtA"&gt;Oppo has announced the latest iteration of its under-screen camera technology, claiming it allows for a selfie camera to be placed under the display “without compromising the integrity of the screen.” Unlike earlier approaches that reduce pixel density in the portion of the screen that covers the camera in order to let more light pass through, Oppo is using smaller pixels to maintain the same 400-ppi sharpness as the rest of the OLED panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvQ0np"&gt;The result, according to Oppo, is that users should notice “almost no visual difference between the [under-screen camera] area and the rest of the screen during everyday use, creating a much more immersive visual experience.” The company has shown off an image of a prototype phone running an e-reader app, which would be pretty much the worst-case scenario for earlier under-display cameras due to the white background and sharp text. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K3TP02N5rcWGkY2IS1v7OHz6xBw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22760057/OPPO_USC_E_book_Reading.JPG"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EEx8tP"&gt;As for the quality of the camera itself, here’s a sample image provided by Oppo:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KQ05q6C4pZWPQry7cZnrc1p2Hng=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22760056/OPPO_USC_Selfie_Sample_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UQ8tbD"&gt;It’s only one sample in good light, and there do seem to be some color artifacts in certain portions of the image. It does, however, look considerably better than what you’d get from the first under-display camera to hit the market, which was on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22191459/zte-axon-20-5g-under-display-camera-hands-on"&gt;ZTE’s Axon 20 5G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sx6BV"&gt;That said, ZTE has one up on Oppo by actually shipping a phone already, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597594/zte-axon-30-refresh-specs-availability-under-display-phone-camera"&gt;its latest Axon 30&lt;/a&gt; is meant to have improved the tech as well. ZTE is claiming the same 400-ppi density in the camera portion of the screen, plus better camera quality than the Axon 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="awZY8O"&gt;Oppo has been working on under-display cameras for a long time, showing off the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/26/18759380/under-display-selfie-camera-first-oppo-announcement"&gt;world’s first demo at MWC Shanghai in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but at some point it’s going to have to put one in an actual commercial device. For now, it’s hard to say too much about the tech improvements without even seeing a prototype for ourselves in person. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T19:51:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T19:51:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile confirms it will shut down Sprint’s LTE network next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="t-mobile and sprint logos" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s3IN2gvmTmq1MfpeKh-YCszm0W4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675116/acasatro_180430_1777_sprint_Tmobile_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile has wasted no time consolidating Sprint’s network and spectrum with its own.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nZkG92"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/t-mobile-to-shutter-sprints-lte-network-on-june-30-2022/d/d-id/771269"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Light Reading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; T-Mobile has committed to a June 30, 2022 shutdown date for Sprint’s LTE network. It’s an expected move as T-Mobile continues to absorb Sprint’s network and customers into its own base, and comes six months after its contentious planned January 1, 2022 shutdown of Sprint’s 3G CDMA network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mckReg"&gt;A third of Sprint customers have already been moved onto the T-Mobile network, &lt;a href="https://investor.t-mobile.com/news-and-events/t-mobile-us-press-releases/press-release-details/2021/T-Mobile-Raises-2021-Guidance-Across-the-Board-Again-and-Delivers-Record-Financial-Results-in-Q2/default.aspx"&gt;according to T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;. The company expects to be able to migrate the remaining two thirds by that mid-2022 deadline, &lt;a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/operators/t-mobile-running-fast-to-achieve-benefits-merger"&gt;according to CFO Peter Osvaldik’s remarks&lt;/a&gt; at an investor conference last month. Some of those customers will likely need new devices that are compatible with T-Mobile LTE and VoLTE, though the company has had no shortage of enticing &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Ft-mobile-revvl-v-plus-5g%3Ficid%3DMGPO_TMO_P_21REVVLOUS_1U0R1MHTP3PF5UOM25482&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;5G phone offers lately&lt;/a&gt;. T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fcoverage%2Ft-mobile-network-evolution&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;says it will reach out to all customers&lt;/a&gt; who will need a new SIM card or device to stay connected, but if you’re curious whether your device is compatible you can run an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fcoverage%2Ft-mobile-network%23tech&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F3%2F22608265%2Ft-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;IMEI check on T-Mobile’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ujfewh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile hasn’t been shy about moving quickly to consolidate Sprint’s network assets with its own&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Vud9n"&gt;The Sprint LTE network shutdown doesn’t come as a shock — by Sprint’s own admission the network &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/28/17914230/sprint-lte-network-coverage-bad-tmobile-merger"&gt;wasn’t very good to begin with&lt;/a&gt;, and T-Mobile hasn’t been shy about moving quickly to consolidate Sprint’s network assets with its own. The company’s 3G shutdown timeline &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;has been the source of a lot of bad blood&lt;/a&gt; between T-Mobile and Dish Network, which acquired Sprint’s former prepaid business Boost Mobile as part of the merger deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2AlnAM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Dish ‘fix’ for the T-Mobile-Sprint merger seems more shortsighted than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22585761/dish-t-mobile-att-sprint-competition-editorial"},{"title":"Predictably, T-Mobile’s merger promises weren’t enough to make a carrier out of Dish","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587790/t-mobile-sprint-acquisition-dish-promises"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="MckEQj"&gt;The relationship has soured to the point of Dish announcing that it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583799/dish-network-att-mvno-t-mobile-5g-4g"&gt;take the majority of its MVNO business to AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; — which T-Mobile followed with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598163/t-mobile-metro-5g-prepaid-boost-cricket-switch-promotion"&gt;a promotional offer directed at Boost customers&lt;/a&gt;. Boost had no additional comments to share about the potential impacts of the LTE shutdown on its customers when contacted by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608265/t-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608265/t-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T19:46:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T19:46:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T has officially spun off DirecTV, which is now its own business</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="DirecTV" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L6HMv6H9Q7flUIXx9KDC-Cs6e7Q=/0x0:6390x4260/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69675098/1174204846.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Thomas Trutschel/Photothek via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GXVhLG"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T announced earlier this year that it would spin its video properties DirecTV, AT&amp;amp;T TV, and U-verse into a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301840/att-tpg-directv-tv-uverse-new-company-announced"&gt;new company&lt;/a&gt; it would co-manage with private equity firm TPG Capital. That transaction is finally complete, and the services will now operate as a single company under the name DirecTV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m1XhQt"&gt;As outlined earlier this year when the company initially announced plans to off-load its struggling DirecTV business, AT&amp;amp;T will retain a 70 percent stake in the company, while TPG will take a 30 percent stake. The telecom giant said the deal for which it received $7.1 billion in cash would help pay off its &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/18/business/ATT-WarnerMedia-Discovery.html"&gt;massive debt&lt;/a&gt;, with the company projecting it can put a stop to the bleeding by the end of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlKQvY"&gt;Part of that debt is owed because of AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/18/5727276/att-acquires-directv"&gt;acquisition of the original DirecTV&lt;/a&gt; in 2015, at which time AT&amp;amp;T paid $48.5 billion ($67 billion accounting for debt) to acquire the business. To say that that business decision has failed to deliver is putting it mildly, as DirecTV &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/12/att-reportedly-struggling-to-sell-directv-at-anything-but-a-huge-loss/"&gt;bled customers for years&lt;/a&gt; prior to the TPG deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ywKqR9"&gt;At the time the TPG deal was announced in February, AT&amp;amp;T boss John Stankey said that the company planned to focus specifically on “connectivity and content,” including 5G wireless and fiber as well as its service HBO Max. More recently, however, AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451111/att-ceo-stankey-unleash-assets-warnermedia-discovery-hbo"&gt;revised strategy&lt;/a&gt; is to focus on its core business and as Stankey put it recently, “unleash the media assets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDePtL"&gt;The deal with TPG does not include any of WarnerMedia’s various assets, including its marquee streaming service HBO Max, because those are being offloaded to Discovery instead. (WarnerMedia and Discovery are currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22448140/warner-bros-discovery-warnermedia-new-name-merger-att"&gt;awaiting approval&lt;/a&gt; for the merger of their two companies.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1Ol8Z"&gt;But the deal &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/video.html"&gt;will include&lt;/a&gt; existing DirecTV content deals for things like NFL Sunday Ticket. AT&amp;amp;T added that DirecTV would “continue to offer HBO Max to subscribers along with any bundled wireless or broadband services and associated customer discounts.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608577/att-directv-tpg-deal-u-verse-att-tv-new-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608577/att-directv-tpg-deal-u-verse-att-tv-new-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp launches its ‘View Once’ disappearing photos and videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KSZLcAXWiRCxmmTDWpvTBWGCTZs=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69674643/EN__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: WhatsApp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ByfzID"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/view-once-photos-and-videos-on-whatsapp"&gt;WhatsApp is rolling out&lt;/a&gt; its “View Once” feature today, which deletes photos or videos from your chat after they’ve been opened by the recipient. When sending a photo or video, you can make it view once by tapping the “1” button to the left of the send button. After the recipient opens it, it’ll be deleted. The recipient will be able to see that it’s a disappearing photo, so it’s still the type of thing you’d only want to use for people you trust to not take a screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zkaq4I"&gt;In June, Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466425/whatsapp-multi-device-support-disappearing-mode-view-once-features-confirmed"&gt;confirmed that the feature would be coming&lt;/a&gt;, though details about when it would release were scarce. &lt;a href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-is-rolling-out-photos-and-videos-set-to-view-once/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;WaBetaInfo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the feature has been in beta for about a month. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7BP8SKBE5QH9dzr94PTwTZ_K8Wo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759545/comp_VIEW_ONCE_EN_16x9_v012_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: WhatsApp&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The recipient will be left with a bubble simply saying “opened.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uYH8tW"&gt;As an example of how the feature could be used, WhatsApp uses the example of sending a photo of sensitive information, like a Wi-Fi password. Of course, there are perhaps other less wholesome uses for this kind of feature. But either way, it’s useful to have an option between the &lt;a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/chats/about-disappearing-messages"&gt;app’s disappearing messages&lt;/a&gt;, which currently only go away after a week, and your chat’s permanent record.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608419/whatsapp-view-once-dissapearing-media-launch-testing-sensitive-info"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608419/whatsapp-view-once-dissapearing-media-launch-testing-sensitive-info</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-03T15:46:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-03T15:46:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>OtterBox’s latest gaming clip jumps aboard the MagSafe train</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Otterbox MagSafe gaming clip" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xYK6kH2AtpcOyPAWg1Br0zrEG4M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69673837/otterboxmagsafe.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OtterBox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aob8Dy"&gt;OtterBox’s latest gaming controller clip is MagSafe-compatible for iPhone 12 devices, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.otterbox.com/en-us/xbox-x%7Cs--xbox-one--xbox-elite-wireless-series-2-controllers/mobile-gaming-clip-for-magsafe/77-82969.html#tab5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and it costs $39.99&lt;/a&gt;. Compared to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338087/otterbox-mobile-gaming-clip-review-xbox-controller-cloud-price"&gt;previous $30 gaming clip&lt;/a&gt; that we reviewed earlier this year, it streamlines the process of connecting your phone to a controller clip by letting it snap on seamlessly with the help of magnets — in other words, MagSafe technology (TM). This solution is preferable to traditional controller clips that clamp around the edges of your phone’s display. I just wish that this one worked with other phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQis5B"&gt;Some MagSafe-compatible accessories can also charge iPhone 12-series models, but in this case, OtterBox’s MagSafe gaming clip seems to boil down to “it’s a circular magnetic surface.” There are no other special features listed on its product page, aside from being able to detach the magnetic arm from the controller to serve as a phone stand. Also, you don’t need to own an OtterBox MagSafe case, but the company says you’ll get the “best experience and protection” if you do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Otterbox MagSafe gaming clip" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3lTBjPZU0M3ISOevsg-UkFKQGBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759096/otterboxmagsafe2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OtterBox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The clip can detach from the controller to work in tabletop mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4psGIg"&gt;In terms of controller compatibility, OtterBox says on its site that this new clip will fit the newer Xbox Series X / S controller, the previous Xbox One wireless controller, or the Xbox Elite Series 2 controller. Oddly, it also provides the disclaimer that the clip was designed to “ensure zero interference” with controller functions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sa2TTX"&gt;It’s easy to read that and think, “Wait, can magnets interfere with Bluetooth?” If that were the case, Bluetooth speakers, among many other devices, wouldn’t operate properly. What I think it means is that your controller will work normally. Perhaps the company just needed another line to plug in that its product has MagSafe compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mDdod"&gt;The MagSafe gaming clip is available now for iPhone 12 owners who want the convenience of attaching their phone to their gaming clip with magnets and don’t mind paying the $10 premium. Otherwise, you can make do with OtterBox’s previous model that works as intended with practically any phone running a modern mobile OS.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608012/otterbox-magsafe-compatible-gaming-clip-xbox-controller-price-iphone-12-mini-pro-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608012/otterbox-magsafe-compatible-gaming-clip-xbox-controller-price-iphone-12-mini-pro-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
