<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-22T12:18:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T12:18:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T12:18:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile just brought back a true unlimited data plan with 5G and no throttling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lDgbCAqNAIeyRHBvOHBQ-5Kz3W4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855699/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SDBh15"&gt;T-Mobile has just announced a new monthly phone plan called Magenta Max that the company says is designed for the era of 5G. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fstories%2Fmagenta-max&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F22%2F22295466%2Ft-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to this press release&lt;/a&gt;, T-Mobile claims Magenta Max is “the first and only 5G consumer smartphone plan that can’t slow you down based on how much data you use.” That makes it sound like the carrier is doing away with what’s known as deprioritization, where your speeds are subject to slowdown after you exceed a certain amount of data in a billing cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kuw1DY"&gt;“T-Mobile has lit up the highest-capacity 5G network available — a network so powerful it can start unleashing the power of 5G to deliver unlimited premium data,” the company said.  Magenta Max promises “unlimited 4K UHD” video streaming compared to the DVD-quality (or 1080p at best) limit that comes with many unlimited plans. T-Mobile is also extending the company’s “Netflix on Us” promotion to single-line customers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R0-wI8Q_HvbP_ntwWv_Xf5KfwWw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320564/max.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="95rEr5"&gt;Magenta Max takes the place of the previous Magenta Plus plan and will be available starting on February 24th. It includes 40GB of high-speed tethering data, plus the usual T-Mobile perks like free in-flight Wi-Fi from Gogo, extensive international coverage, and Scam Shield protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KPA93Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VA4WAj"&gt;T-Mobile says pricing is “$57 per line per month for three lines with autopay and monthly taxes and fees included.” For a limited time, that’s dropped to $47 per line per month for three lines. Single-line customers will have to pay more at $85 per month with autopay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWVMpe"&gt;A lot of this has a “too good to be true” sound to it, so I’m also on the lookout for any asterisks or limits that T-Mobile isn’t talking about on the surface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fInXA9"&gt;Alongside Magenta Max, T-Mobile is also making changes to the core Magenta plan. It’s bumping up the monthly deprioritization ceiling to 100GB from the 50GB it’s at currently. Customers will also get more high-speed tethering data: it’s now 5GB compared to 3GB before.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:33:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:33:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ACCGYzU2wR3-6BaupyrR4XrSoRA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855298/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;In the US, 5G remains a work in progress, despite carriers waving “5G Mission Accomplished” banners for years | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The fourth industrial revolution will not be televised&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="2rF2Fy"&gt;After an introduction from Consumer Technology Association president Gary Shapiro, Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg takes the stage. He wears a simple black T-shirt with an unmistakable red check and begins delivering his keynote speech. The topic at hand is 5G, something Vestberg speaks about enthusiastically. The keynote covers the eight “currencies” of 5G, features a professional athlete, and highlights how 5G will transform the drone industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPtmvC"&gt;That was CES 2019. It was also CES 2021. Verizon hasn’t been alone in fueling the 5G hype machine; AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile have been talking up their 5G networks for years. Now, it’s showtime. With major flagship phones and a lot more budget devices supporting it, this is the year when a critical mass of phone buyers will finally see for themselves what all this talk is about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QaXFel"&gt;Here’s the bad news: if they’ve been listening to the hype, they’re going to be disappointed. We’ve been promised a fourth industrial revolution with fantastical things like remote surgery and driverless cars. Instead, what we have now is widespread 5G that’s more or less the same speed as (or even slower than) 4G and super-fast mmWave 5G in &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; parts of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; major cities with highly limited range. So where is this 5G future we’ve been promised? The truth is that it’s coming along, but it will materialize more slowly and in less obvious ways than what we’ve been led to believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uEFYKL"&gt;Spectrum wars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="dzciVm"&gt;To understand the complicated 5G situation in the US right now, you first need to know that there are low-, mid-, and high-band frequencies that carriers can use. Low-band is slower but offers widespread coverage. High-band, often called mmWave, is very fast but extremely limited in range. Mid-band sits in a sweet spot between the two, with good range and better-than-LTE speeds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXZ3ph"&gt;If you were building a 5G network from scratch, you’d probably want a bunch of mid-band spectrum, right? The trouble is, spectrum is a limited resource. &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/authors/sascha-segan"&gt;Sascha Segan&lt;/a&gt;, lead mobile analyst at &lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt; and a wealth of 5G knowledge, sums up part of the spectrum problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjjNjv"&gt;“Our government did not make the right channels available to the carriers,” he says. “Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T have basically just been using leftover odds and ends of their 4G spectrum... putting the 5G encoding on these leftover bits and bobs so they can pop a 5G icon on the screen. And the performance is meaningless.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="hRkK5K"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s kind of like having that super fast sports car and you’re stuck on the Santa Monica freeway.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xixtRf"&gt;The technology Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T are using to get nationwide 5G coverage is called Dynamic Spectrum Sharing (DSS), which allows 4G and 5G to coexist on the same spectrum. That helps carriers make the transition from one technology to the other, but it comes at a cost. Michael Thelander, president and founder of wireless industry research firm &lt;a href="https://signalsresearch.com/"&gt;Signals Research Group&lt;/a&gt;, sums it up this way: “It’s kind of like having that super fast sports car and you’re stuck on the Santa Monica freeway. You can’t experience the full capabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Sv52l"&gt;T-Mobile, on the other hand, doesn’t need to rely on spectrum sharing as much as the other two, thanks to its acquisition of Sprint and its mid-band spectrum. That has given it an edge in its 5G offerings thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WD5bmM"&gt;By early 2022, though, we will likely see Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T catching up. A swath of mid-band spectrum known as C-band went up for auction in late 2020. And while we don’t know which companies won which blocks of spectrum, we know those two carriers, in particular, spent big; bidding &lt;a href="https://auctiondata.fcc.gov/public/projects/auction107"&gt;topped out at over $80 billion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uw17dY"&gt;What happens next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="VsP8hz"&gt;The networks might not be firing on all cylinders yet, but more and more mobile devices are ready for them. In fact, by the end of the year, it may be harder to find a non-5G phone than one that supports the technology. Not only do Apple and Samsung’s flagship phones support 5G across their lineups, but it’s also making its way into more midrange and budget devices, thanks to new 5G-ready low-end processors like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22204586/qualcomm-snapdragon-480-5g-android-smartphone-price"&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 480&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiBmo5"&gt;More people than ever will buy a 5G phone this year — likely not because they really wanted 5G, but because the phone they were going to get anyway supports it. The good news is that there really isn’t a downside to buying a 5G phone now if it’s time to upgrade. The “5G tax” that put a higher price tag on 5G phones over the past couple of years seems to be disappearing, and we haven’t noticed any other drawbacks like excessive battery drain in our testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuP5JW4ilTFsD1GqJPcjnL_wagE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21973509/vpavic_4243_20201017_0144.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 series includes 5G connectivity across the lineup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sPWa6a"&gt;So what’s the reaction like so far from, say, someone who bought an iPhone 12 — not for 5G, but because it’s the new iPhone? “They’re frustrated and angry,” says Segan. “With both Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T, because of what I’ll call technical difficulties, their nationwide 5G is often slower than their 4G. So people are getting these iPhones and they’re finding that frequently they have worse performance than they had before 5G.” The “technical difficulties” he refers to include DSS in Verizon’s case and the limitations of the narrow 5MHz band that AT&amp;amp;T often uses for its 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p5fWGR"&gt;That’s not great. But a couple of factors will make a difference over the next year. First, that C-band spectrum will start coming online around the end of the year. If you’re one of the frustrated owners of an iPhone 12 or Galaxy S21, there’s good news: your phone is already approved to use C-band, so if you’re on Verizon or AT&amp;amp;T, you should see speed improvements when that happens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="u7PitC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They’re finding that frequently they have worse performance than they had before 5G”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MvPKH7"&gt;Not all 5G phones support C-band, though. Those that don’t will need a software update to use it, and there’s no guarantee that your phone’s manufacturer will offer one. Inexpensive 5G models, in particular, may not see a C-band update, even if they have the hardware to support it. Phone makers need to apply for Federal Communications Commission approval to enable it and may be less likely to bother with the cost of this step for phones with a shorter lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFIJxS"&gt;The other factor is something that will likely happen sooner than C-band becoming available: large gatherings. That’s when Segan thinks Verizon’s Ultra Wideband could really shine. “When we’re all vaccinated, I think people are going to be desperate... for all of these dense, crowded, communal experiences that we will have been missing for a year and a half. And so Verizon should be working on applications and experiences right now like the thing they did at the Super Bowl, or what they’ve talked about doing at Disney World, that you can only do on Ultra Wideband.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4L8b2T"&gt;Again, that will depend on your 5G phone supporting the right &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; of 5G — not every 5G phone supports mmWave. The aforementioned iPhone and Samsung flagships do, and other Verizon models that support are denoted as “UW.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oDOGa4"&gt;Where are our jetpacks?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ftsEj7"&gt;And what about the stuff of CES keynotes like remote surgery and self-driving cars? That’s on the way, too, but it’ll take longer. Thelander explains: “The first focus of 5G was really a feature called ‘enhanced mobile broadband’ and that’s just getting fast data speeds to the consumer on their smartphone. Things like factory automation and the functionality behind that, that was really developed afterwards, so it lags, from a standardization perspective.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="TCL 10 5G UW" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-45gdo6AJkDTvjeyQhEZkf3YK80=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21990050/cfaulkner_201023_4258_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first focus of 5G has been to boost mobile data speeds for consumers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uvow5O"&gt;Getting the technology piece sorted out is only half of the equation. “Once you’ve got a certain feature or functionality defined in a standard, now a vendor has to go out and build that functionality, then you have to test it, and then you have to have the industry adopt it,” Thelander says. “The technology may be there, the standard may be there, it may work fine, but it has to be implemented and rolled out. And you have to have the business case for it. How do you make money off of it? All those types of things… it just takes time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="SQZrz1"&gt;Despite networks constantly waving their “&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/mission-accomplished"&gt;5G Mission Accomplished&lt;/a&gt;” banners in TV commercials over the past year, 5G is very much still a work in progress. It’s going to get better, but how soon that happens for you depends on a lot of factors: which phone you have and what bands it supports, which network you’re on, where you are, and what you’re doing. It seems clear now that there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/23/18637213/5g-race-us-leadership-china-fcc-lte"&gt;never really was a “Race to 5G”&lt;/a&gt; — just technological progress as usual, which is often slow, confusing, and uneven. That’s a little bit harder to sell in a keynote or a commercial.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T09:28:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T09:28:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung launches EKG support for latest Galaxy Watch devices in 31 more countries</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JqgB59A0xwDD-a74CvLEbwmn9lA=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68854417/dseifert_200811_4139_0015.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vr5afU"&gt;Samsung has launched support for electrocardiogram (EKG) readings and blood pressure monitoring on its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20903452/samsung-galaxy-watch-active-2-review-fitness-tizen-apps-features-android-price"&gt;Galaxy Watch Active 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21368752/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Galaxy Watch 3&lt;/a&gt; devices, &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/ecg-support-for-galaxy-watch-2-galaxy-watch-3-rolling-out-to-31-markets/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The feature comes courtesy of the Samsung Health Monitor app, which is now available to download from the company’s app store in 31 additional countries. Prior to today, the features were restricted to owners of one of those two devices &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452541/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-active-2-ekg-ecg-electrocardiogram-update"&gt;in South Korea and the US only&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYgQdV"&gt;Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22251411/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-active-2-ekg-blood-pressure-health-monitor"&gt;first announced last month&lt;/a&gt; it would be adding the features to its latest Galaxy Watch devices through software updates, considering both smartwatches have the requisite sensors used for measuring heart rate and blood pressure and performing an EKG. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5IgP8dTfI_Iz4vIYnji5V5zCOPw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320177/Watch3_Three_UIs_ECG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fDLB4N"&gt;Now, users in 31 more countries — mostly in Europe — should have access after Samsung was given the CE marking clearance for its Samsung Health Monitor app in the EU. That regulatory approval signals the software meets the health and safety standards required for distribution in the region. &lt;em&gt;SamMobile &lt;/em&gt;notes you’ll need the app downloaded and updated to the latest version on both a compatible Galaxy Watch and Samsung phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TPFhQh"&gt;The full list of countries includes Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Chile, Croatia, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, the Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, the UAE, and the UK. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295074/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-ekg-blood-pressure-monitoring-eu-countries"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295074/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-ekg-blood-pressure-monitoring-eu-countries</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T07:12:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T07:12:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s Mate X2 foldable adopts Samsung’s dual-screen design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s1J-_p6smxsTD9tnRewI5aZrcjM=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68853932/image_178.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mate X2 has an 8-inch screen that folds inward.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Huawei&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dVrUeQ"&gt;Huawei has announced the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fen%2Fphones%2Fmate-x2%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F22%2F22294983%2Fhuawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mate X2&lt;/a&gt;, its first all-new foldable device &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/24/18238269/huawei-foldable-phone-mate-x-price-release-date-specs-mwc-2019"&gt;since 2019’s Mate X&lt;/a&gt;. The new phone has received a radical redesign compared to the original device, with a large screen that unfolds from the inside of the device rather than around the outside. For using the phone while folded, the Huawei Mate X2 has a second screen on its outside, similar to Samsung’s approach with the Galaxy Fold series. Images of the phone were leaked minutes ahead of its official announcement by &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/huawei-mate-x2-first-official-images-1613994247-1984855950"&gt;Evan Blass on &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tUTUPv"&gt;This being a Huawei device, the Mate X2 will launch without support for Google’s apps or services, which is likely to severely limit its appeal outside of China. According to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsumer.huawei.com%2Fen%2Fphones%2Fmate-x2%2Fspecs%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F22%2F22294983%2Fhuawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Huawei’s site&lt;/a&gt;, the phone will run on EMUI 11.0 based on Android 10. However, during its live stream, the company said it plans for the Mate X2 to be among the first phones to be updated to its own operating system, HarmonyOS, starting in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjKndz"&gt;The internal screen on the Mate X2 measures 8 inches with a resolution of 2480 x 2200, while the exterior screen is 6.45 inches with a 2700 x 1160 resolution. Both are OLED and have refresh rates of up to 90Hz. They’re also both slightly bigger than the 7.6-inch internal display and 6.2-inch external displays found on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 2&lt;/a&gt;. Internally, the phone is powered by the company’s flagship Kirin 9000 chip, the processor that debuted in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21529915/huawei-mate-40-pro-hands-on"&gt;Mate 40 Pro&lt;/a&gt; last year. This is paired with 8GB of RAM and a battery with a rated capacity of 4,400mAh that can be fast-charged at up to 55W. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5Yg-uODZq9hpnIhWL4-EpjdiE2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320067/msedge_6RvUDEI1g5.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Huawei&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mate X2 is available in four colors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GsHFfr"&gt;There are four cameras on the rear of the phone: a 50-megapixel wide-angle, a 16-megapixel ultrawide, a 12-megapixel telephoto with a 3x optical zoom, and an 8-megapixel “SuperZoom” camera with a 10x optical zoom. The selfie camera on the outside of the phone has a 16-megapixel resolution, and there doesn’t appear to be a selfie camera in or around the foldable inner screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMPOaj"&gt;The Mate X2 is technically the third phone in Huawei’s foldable lineup. Last year, it released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21145519/huawei-mate-xs-foldable-phone-news-features-quad-layer-screen-hinge-kirin-990-5g"&gt;Mate XS&lt;/a&gt;, an updated version of the original Mate X, which featured a more durable display and faster Kirin 990 processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gjsHSx"&gt;Huawei says the Mate X2 will be available in China with 256GB of internal storage for ¥17,999 (around $2,785) or for ¥18,999 (around $2,940) with 512GB of storage. Available colors include blue, pink, black, and white. It’ll be available to buy in China on February 25th, but it’s unclear when the phone could be released outside the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gvmaRt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DHJrbGquKWs?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22294983/huawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22294983/huawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-20T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Oatmeal’s creator says his new game is a way to ‘play the comic’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Comic-Con International 2014 - Day 2" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BrlV92tZLzkZlnYs9emVkFrDbxQ=/0x73:2000x1406/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68847517/452705690.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Daniel Knighton / WireImage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="00tbrs"&gt;The creator of &lt;em&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/em&gt;, Matthew Inman, released a new cat-themed mobile word game &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278773/kitty-letter-mobile-game-ios-android-the-oatmeal-exploding-kittens"&gt;called &lt;em&gt;Kitty Letter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week that feels like playing one of his silly comic strips. That feeling was intentional, Inman told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pwvZN4"&gt;“My comics have always been rhetorical,” he said. “You don’t interact with the comic, you have no say in it, you’re just experiencing it. So, with [&lt;em&gt;Kitty Letter&lt;/em&gt;], I got a chance to introduce some elements where people get to play the comic, and I thought that was a lot of fun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtO5ki"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kitty Letter&lt;/em&gt; has a structure that Inman described as “&lt;em&gt;Scrabble&lt;/em&gt; combined with &lt;em&gt;Clash Royale&lt;/em&gt;.” Your goal is to beat your opponent by spelling words from a combination of letters at the bottom of your phone’s screen. When you spell a word, you’ll send a small army of cats up an invisible “lane” toward your opponent. Meanwhile, your opponent is sending armies of cats to try and defeat you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UFbbBu"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dbI4NA6K63I?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H6K8fD"&gt;The game was actually going to be multiplayer-only at first, Inman told me. This might be surprising for those who’ve played the game, since it has a robust story mode spanning 13 chapters. But that story mode was born from creating the game’s tutorial, said Inman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQDdsc"&gt;“I started drawing this tutorial on how to play, and then the tutorial became that single-player mode, where you have this neighbor that moves in and tells the whole story about him,” Inman said. But then, he realized, “I got in too deep. I had written all this stuff, I was like, ‘I have to end this,’ and I ended up writing like 12 chapters. But it became my favorite part of the whole thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99w4WH"&gt;Inman also discussed the game’s free-to-play model, which is very generous. Unlike many free-to-play games, &lt;em&gt;Kitty Letter’s&lt;/em&gt; single-player story mode and multiplayer are completely free, with no restrictions. The decision to offer all of that came from what Inman disliked about other free games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="43BnPa"&gt;“I play free-to-play games, but I play them because I like the games,” Inman said. “The actual mechanics involved, like grinding and unlocking chests and getting gems and coins, I hate them. I fucking hate them. If [developers] were like, ‘pay us $20 and we’ll give you everything,’ I would do that. I much prefer that model.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxNC8R"&gt;The game does offer paid cosmetics for multiplayer, but they don’t provide any gameplay benefit and they’re buried in a menu. And Inman says that revenue from them has been “pretty much non-existent.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="EfuEXM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Kitty Letter is a new mobile word game from the creator of The Oatmeal, and it’s good","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278773/kitty-letter-mobile-game-ios-android-the-oatmeal-exploding-kittens"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="n0IOEg"&gt;Inman acknowledged that he can offer the game largely for free because of his other successful ventures, which include&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/28/7927121/exploding-kittens-most-backed-kickstarter-project-ever"&gt;hugely successful card game Exploding Kittens&lt;/a&gt;. “I’m not just some altruistic guy that doesn’t want to make a living from his work,” he said. “To be completely candid, we make a great living from our card games, and we make a great living from some of the other things that I do. With [&lt;em&gt;Kitty Letter&lt;/em&gt;], it felt like we could just get away with making it as enjoyable as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTJ8Vt"&gt;“This app more generates that currency of — and this is so fucking corny — currency of love and joy, like you have a joyful experience with the game,” he said. “So, in turn, you love Exploding Kittens more, and maybe one day, if you want to buy a card game from us, you can.” It’s a business model similar to that of &lt;em&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/em&gt;. Inman offers the comics for free online, but sells books and has offered merch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="utkPUl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It was cats from day one”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IBCcn6"&gt;Inman has a lot of ideas for what’s next for the game. He’d like to improve the arcade mode, add more single-player levels, and squash bugs. He’d also like to port the game to Steam and the Nintendo Switch, but those might be a little further away. “I would probably call it six months,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tz63Ig"&gt;And I had to ask: were cats always the focus of the game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUI9AQ"&gt;“It was cats from day one,” Inman said. “It was called &lt;em&gt;Cats Royale&lt;/em&gt;, originally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rPYzum"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ztD67Q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/20/22291686/the-oatmeal-creator-kitty-letter-matthew-inman-play-comic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/20/22291686/the-oatmeal-creator-kitty-letter-matthew-inman-play-comic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T14:53:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T14:53:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Australia’s ABC News shot to the top of the App Store charts following Facebook’s news ban</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yb82vmdANKzGW2j2LQPDDeuIAa4=/233x522:1793x1562/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68844399/Screen_Shot_2021_02_19_at_8.51.34_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: ABC News&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R6m0UT"&gt;The Australian Broadcasting Corporation’s ABC News app shot to the top of Apple’s App Store charts in Australia over the course of the last few days, not long after Facebook banned Australian news sources on its platform. As &lt;em&gt;Financial Times’ &lt;/em&gt;Uma Patel suggests &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/umabp/status/1362714384368361477?s=20"&gt;in a tweet thread&lt;/a&gt;, that’s possibly because ABC capitalized on Facebook’s news ban with an ad sending users to its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sj4g75"&gt;ABC News currently sits at No. 2 in the App Store’s overall app rankings in Australia, according to the analytics firm &lt;a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/"&gt;App Annie&lt;/a&gt;, and No. 1 in the news app charts. When Patel noticed the change, the app was also briefly No. 1 overall, ahead of Instagram, Facebook Messenger, and the Facebook app itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qFkBnJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;ABC has used facebook's ban to prompt visitors to download its app.. it became the most downloaded app in Australia.... although the next four are all owned by Facebook and the 6th is a company fb tried to buy &lt;a href="https://t.co/jGxeXYxv6x"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jGxeXYxv6x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Uma Patel (@umabp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/umabp/status/1362714384368361477?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MDiF39"&gt;Facebook’s ban was in response to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/19/21227263/australia-facebook-google-ad-revenue-media-coronavirus-economy"&gt;an expansive Australian regulatory measure&lt;/a&gt; that will force tech platforms to pay Australian media companies for the content users share (and that platforms earn ad revenue from). Facebook took issue with the change and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287776/facebook-block-news-australia-regulation-media-link-sharing"&gt;prohibited Australian news and media organizations&lt;/a&gt; from sharing news posts, and Australian users from seeing news from international sources as well. The ban also seemed to accidentally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288256/facebook-australia-news-ban-governmental-agency-accounts"&gt;wipe out the posts&lt;/a&gt; from government pages and some other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/StT4aNIHgZhgr9gzqM_12d_aBek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22315492/Screen_Shot_2021_02_19_at_8.51.34_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: ABC News&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;ABC News’ banner ad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YJubEU"&gt;Facebook’s ban dramatically shrunk the audience for some Australian news outlets, sending traffic down 93 percent the day after the ban was put in place, &lt;a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2021/02/in-australia-facebooks-ban-on-sharing-news-stories-has-sent-publishers-traffic-tumbling/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;NiemanLab&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;But ABC News responded by &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news"&gt;adding a banner&lt;/a&gt; to its home page. “Missing our news on Facebook?&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;—&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Get the latest news and live notifications with the ABC News app,” it reads. Since then, the app has risen from the high 400s to its current spot at No. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rV0MZe"&gt;Whatever the reason, readers heading directly to news sources over the social media sites that cannibalize them seems like a positive, and other news organizations could potentially take advantage of the ban in similar ways. It’s an unintended effect of Facebook’s hardline approach compared to its competitor Google, which struck a partnership deal with three of Australia’s largest media companies — &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/google-australia-news-technology-seven-west-media-2021-2#:~:text=Google%20signed%20up%20a%20major,force%20payments%20to%20media%20outlets."&gt;Seven West Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/feb/17/nine-agrees-to-join-google-news-showcase-in-australia-for-reported-30m-a-year#:~:text=Australia's%20biggest%20locally%2Downed%20media,laws%20being%20debated%20in%20parliament."&gt;Nine Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/feb/17/news-corp-agrees-deal-with-google-over-payments-for-journalism"&gt;NewsCorp&lt;/a&gt; — for its News Showcase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwnvJ1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVbLro"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Me65l"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291406/abc-news-app-top-charts-facebook-ban-australia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291406/abc-news-app-top-charts-facebook-ban-australia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T08:30:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T08:30:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo Find X3 Neo leaks, showing off third handset in upcoming X3 lineup  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IYPAfAMFk3RMlM4_Q-6O4iJlpfg=/0x0:1078x719/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841745/find_x3_neo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Neo.&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.nieuwemobiel.nl/022356/16021/Exclusief-Alle-persafbeeldingen-van-de-Oppo-Find-X3-Neo-5G.html" target="_blank"&gt;NieuweMobiel.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zoieCF"&gt;Images of the unannounced Oppo Find X3 Neo have leaked again, this time giving us our best look yet at the third phone in Oppo’s upcoming Find X3 phone lineup, &lt;a href="https://www.nieuwemobiel.nl/022356/16021/Exclusief-Alle-persafbeeldingen-van-de-Oppo-Find-X3-Neo-5G.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NieuweMobiel.nl&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. As tipster Evan Blass has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1362703973522751489"&gt;subsequently pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, the handset appears to be a rebranded version of Oppo’s Reno5 Pro Plus 5G. The phone is expected to be announced next month alongside the Find X3 Pro and Find X3 Lite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYnlF5"&gt;Since the Find X3 Neo is based on an existing phone, we already have a pretty good idea of what its specs might be. These include a Snapdragon 865 processor, 4,500mAh battery with 65W fast charging, and a 6.55-inch 90Hz OLED display. Around back there are four cameras: a 50-megapixel wide-angle camera, a 13-megapixel telephoto, a 16-megapixel ultrawide, and a 2-megapixel macro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dNZCj4JGf0QZIF5sOLHXEy2sSiU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314505/find_x3_pro.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4LVmcn_D8aqFgjAdAfOE-_eIeBA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314504/find_x3_pro_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MyuaG6"&gt;The Find X3 Pro, meanwhile, appears to be an all-new device. Blass detailed many of its features in a &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-fussi-detailed-1607361964-1"&gt;post on &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last December, noting that it’ll be powered by a Snapdragon 888 processor and will have a 6.7-inch 1440p display with a dynamic refresh rate that goes up to 120Hz. It also has a 4,500mAh battery with support for 65W fast charging, but it’ll also be able to wirelessly charge at up to 30W.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N91mR7"&gt;The Find X3 Pro’s cameras are particularly interesting. It’s reportedly got a pair of 50-megapixel sensors — one wide-angle and one ultrawide — as well as a 13-megapixel camera with a 2x optical zoom and a 3-megapixel macro camera. According to Blass, this macro camera could offer a 25x zoom, allowing it to work like a microscope. Check out more images of the upcoming phone &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832"&gt;over on &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zf5BhLI2sGUiGBCv0D6e-TH8mQI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314507/2a78e57b7f5cc9b6fc8073d395b216cfedd3bc70779c4acef193f98d73e40ba9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-lite-will-be-a-reno5-rebadge-1610105255-1817111864" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Lite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lwBc52"&gt;Finally there’s the Find X3 Lite, which &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-lite-will-be-a-reno5-rebadge-1610105255-1817111864"&gt;Blass notes&lt;/a&gt; appears to be a rebranded Oppo Reno5 5G. That means it’s likely to have a 6.43-inch 90Hz OLED display and four rear cameras: a 64-megapixel wide camera, an 8-megapixel ultrawide, a 2-megapixel macro, and a 2-megapixel depth camera. Internally, it’ll be powered by a Snapdragon 765G, and there’s a 4,300mAh battery that’s also capable of 65W fast charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91Z1yv"&gt;All three phones are expected to be announced soon, with a release in April.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290921/oppo-find-x3-neo-leaks-news-images-release-date-rumors-pro-lite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290921/oppo-find-x3-neo-leaks-news-images-release-date-rumors-pro-lite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T17:12:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T17:12:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Android 12 developer preview feature roundup: improved emergency calls, bigger notifications, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AI3Ezq7mZQa4ZStX2MPROKiSB2I=/0x0:800x533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68839346/VRG_1777_Android_12_006.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DM9Pmo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288084/android-12-developer-preview-available-google-pixel"&gt;The Android 12 developer preview is out&lt;/a&gt;, and the internet is busy poring over it to find any new features or hints at the OS’s future. So far, there have been a few interesting things discovered, such as an Emergency SOS feature, some redesigns, and other useful, if minor, finds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2qBspY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-you-can-now-enable-or-disable-specific-app-quick-settings-media-controls/"&gt;The ability to prevent specific apps from showing media controls in quick settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7RYQ6b"&gt;The ability to &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-wifi-passwords-nearby-share/"&gt;wirelessly share Wi-Fi passwords to people nearby with the tap of a button&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R2QfJU"&gt;An &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-markup-screenshots/"&gt;update to Markup that lets you put emoji (and text) on screenshots&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lp8afp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1362478110583775232"&gt;Bluetooth pairing options are now included in the media picker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="20Djz1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1362463236294135812?s=20"&gt;A reduce bright colors accessibility option&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4Rouxm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/gaming-with-a-controller-could-feel-a-lot-better-on-android-12/"&gt;Improved gamepad rumble support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tX9x3b"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/android-12s-new-toggle-design-is-big-and-bold-and-were-not-sure-what-to-think-of-it/"&gt;A toggle switch redesign&lt;/a&gt; (that looks really nice in my opinion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dbQGkK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/pixel-5s-hole-punch-can-be-hidden-on-android-12/"&gt;A developer option to hide the Pixel’s hole-punch camera cutout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CKGBLR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-pixel-launcher-4x5-grid/"&gt;The addition of a 4 x 5 grid option to the Pixel Launcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xQwE0S"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/android-12s-gestures-navigation-works-better-in-full-screen-and-immersive-views/"&gt;You can now gesture out of full-screen apps with a single swipe instead of two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="VSyb1A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/android-12-adds-emergency-sos-with-five-taps-of-the-power-button/"&gt;As pointed out by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Emergency SOS feature is also much easier to access now. Before, making an emergency call required you to hold the power button down, tap the emergency button, then tap twice on the Call 911 button. In Android 12, however, it can be activated by rapidly pressing the power button five times, which will trigger a countdown telling you that an emergency call is about to be placed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cl5aG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; notes that, by default, it calls 911. You can set it to call a different number, but if the number isn’t a government-run emergency line, your phone will have to be unlocked for the call to go through.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sAvyTViRefEUIrJCnL-ytVAwabk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22313226/android_11_emergency_call_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshots: Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The process for accessing the Emergency Call feature in Android 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rl0gcF3ID8VwV9yKK6p3OuH3UxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22313233/Screenshot_20210218_121043.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/18/android-12-adds-emergency-sos-with-five-taps-of-the-power-button/#ap-lightbox" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android 12 developer preview’s emergency call UI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oBs2NF"&gt;There have been a few minor redesigns of the &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-settings-app-gets-revamp-w-new-search-bar/"&gt;Settings app search bar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-lockscreen-and-notification-shade-media-player-gets-minor-ui-redesign/"&gt;the lock screen and notification media player&lt;/a&gt;, but Mishaal Rahman found a feature flag that “dramatically” changes the settings UI to be easier to use one-handed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zL3kvp"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;BIG change: If you enable the "Silky home" feature flag that I previously mentioned, you'll get a DRAMATICALLY changed Settings UI that's MUCH more one-handed friendly. Here are a few screenshots: &lt;a href="https://t.co/EcwqnU0LlB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/EcwqnU0LlB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mishaal Rahman (@MishaalRahman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1362462608826195976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sIbt8K"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-settings-app-gets-revamp-w-new-search-bar/"&gt;has also found that some screens in the settings app&lt;/a&gt; have blue-tinted backgrounds. It speculates that it could be part of a rumored theming system, but at the moment, it seems very unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r2s6V4j0taoI9ZQhK7Ddm-Wz7Tk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22313204/Screen_Shot_2021_02_18_at_12.43.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-settings-app-gets-revamp-w-new-search-bar/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5hJw8Y"&gt;Of course, notifications have also gotten a redesign, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-notifications-redesigned-w-bigger-icons-dedicated-snooze-button/"&gt;with &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; noting&lt;/a&gt; that there’s a dedicated snooze button now, and the icon bubbles are now much larger. This looks like it reduces the density of notifications, but it’s still very early days for Android 12, so it’s possible changes could be made or toggles could be added to control whether you want to see the larger app icon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KUErMwjizN3A6eaHU8juCNCrMJE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22313267/Screen_Shot_2021_02_18_at_1.07.22_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-notifications-redesigned-w-bigger-icons-dedicated-snooze-button/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The app icon bubbles are now larger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vQ2BNW"&gt;There are also a few features that are hinted at, or even have settings present, but currently don’t seem to work or aren’t enabled, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hpQbX6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-scrolling-screenshot/"&gt;Scrolling screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eyLggC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-dp1-pixel-double-tap-gesture-assistant-columbus/"&gt;A Pixel 5 double-tap feature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lJruiC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1362498569081618435"&gt;A one-handed mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sDPTlG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/18/android-12-privacy-toggles/"&gt;Privacy toggles to turn cameras and microphones off system-wide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="D98pvo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1362518136113815556?s=20"&gt;Pinch-to-resize picture-in-picture video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Go0CgL"&gt;Given the early state of the developer preview, it’s not really meant for day-to-day use on your main phone. And as with all betas, these features and designs are subject to change in new releases. Still, it’s a tantalizing glimpse at the future of Android and the features Google is adding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21285299/android-11-beta-features-notifications-bubbles-permissions-smart-home-video-google"&gt;to an already feature-packed mature OS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOuK9b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 18th, 8:25PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added some new features that have been found since this article was first posted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289976/android-12-developer-preview-roundup-notifications-redesign-tweaks-emergency-sos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289976/android-12-developer-preview-roundup-notifications-redesign-tweaks-emergency-sos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T16:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp is having another go at explaining its privacy policy to users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="WhatsApp stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W8F9yHgB-gRXv5FBQwFwWmGhkHs=/3x0:1017x676/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68838853/WhatsApp1_1020.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cGM3dT"&gt;WhatsApp has a new plan to explain its contentious privacy policy — the one that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226792/whatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;came under fire&lt;/a&gt; when users grew concerned the platform would share their messages with parent company Facebook. In an announcement on Thursday, the company explained how users can read through the new policy and learn how business and personal messages — which have different privacy standards — are handled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZaTmBM"&gt;The new privacy policy primarily concerns messaging businesses on WhatsApp and what parts of your data those businesses have access to. Most WhatsApp messages are end-to-end encrypted, meaning they can only be accessed by the people actually talking. But WhatsApp also lets users message businesses, and those messages aren’t extended the same protections. The data in business messages can be used for commercial purposes like ad targeting on Facebook, and some of them are also stored on Facebook’s servers. WhatsApp’s privacy policy was an attempt to explain that change, but many users interpreted it as WhatsApp comprising the privacy focus it was known for.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mk5JhiEgy3brAIplu44ieGNlXdI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22312921/image002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: WhatsApp&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;WhatsApp’s new banner and privacy policy explainer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="92FNL4"&gt;Ahead of the new May 15th launch (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233257/whatsapp-privacy-policy-update-delayed-three-months"&gt;moved from February 8th&lt;/a&gt;), WhatsApp plans to offer users the ability to review this new privacy policy inside its app. The company already tried to reassure users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/30/22257721/whatsapp-status-privacy-facebook-signal-telegram"&gt;through WhatsApp’s Status feature&lt;/a&gt;, but now WhatsApp will include a banner that can be tapped to pull up the explanation of the new policy. The company says it will eventually remind users to read the new policy and accept it to continue using the app as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="REd6tD"&gt;WhatsApp also notes that businesses pay for the right to use WhatsApp to reach customers, and that’s one of the ways WhatsApp is able to provide its app for free. The main features of WhatsApp remain as private as ever. Of course, it’s not as private as some users might think: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/25/12638698/whatsapp-to-start-sharing-user-data-with-facebook"&gt;WhatsApp started sharing some personal information&lt;/a&gt; like phone numbers and profile photos with Facebook in 2016 to improve friend recommendations and ads on the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R81gUH"&gt;WhatsApp’s tone in this redo of its policy change is somewhat apologetic. It didn’t explain what was changing well enough to users, and it’s owning up to that. But WhatsApp also managed to sneak in a dig at other companies that welcomed the exodus from WhatsApp prompted by the policy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="0irFGs"&gt;During this time, we understand some people may check out other apps to see what they have to offer. We’ve seen some of our competitors try to get away with claiming they can’t see people’s messages — if an app doesn’t offer end-to-end encryption by default that means they can read your messages. Other apps say they’re better because they know even less information than WhatsApp. We believe people are looking for apps to be both reliable and safe, even if that requires WhatsApp having some limited data. We strive to be thoughtful on the decisions we make and we’ll continue to develop new ways of meeting these responsibilities with less information, not more. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="gVSiP3"&gt;WhatsApp is obliquely referencing Telegram, an app that, along with Signal, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/telegram/status/1349014065931284480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1349014065931284480%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F12%2F22226792%2Fwhatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;seemed to benefit&lt;/a&gt; from the confusion over what was changing in WhatsApp. Telegram &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/why-you-should-stop-using-telegram-right-now-1782557415"&gt;has dealt with its own criticism&lt;/a&gt; over not enabling end-to-end encryption by default — and clearly, WhatsApp doesn’t want you to forget that. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289595/whatsapp-privacy-policy-app-banner-explanation-telegram"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289595/whatsapp-privacy-policy-app-banner-explanation-telegram</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T14:10:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T14:10:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to easily install the Android 12 developer preview</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9HBAEQVKp6e725lbGLfEysg0bU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66886289/jbareham_181010_2989_0074.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YlhtBR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 18th, 2:10PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Google released the first of its &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288084/android-12-developer-preview-available-google-pixel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android 12 developer previews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, so we’ve updated the info in this post to be relevant if you want to install it on your phone. The instructional photos might include a mention of Android 11, but we’ve ensured the steps are still accurate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MEa7Ku"&gt;You can try out the Android 12 developer preview software right now if you have a Pixel 3 or later, but it’s understandable if the idea of flashing your device to install the OS is intimidating. It can be a tricky process, and the steps differ slightly depending on what phone you have and what kind of computer you’re going to use to download the software. But Google itself makes this process much more streamlined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B6mztn"&gt;Google’s &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/about/versions/12/download"&gt;Android Flash Tool&lt;/a&gt; is a web application that handles most of the steps of flashing for you. There are a few steps that you’ll need to do yourself before the new software can be installed, which we’ll walk you through below, but Google’s tool basically eliminates most of the hassle and complexity that makes it easy to mess up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnBR1D"&gt;There are a few important notes to make up here at the top. First, once you flash your phone with the developer preview, your device will get all future developer preview and beta updates over the air. In other words, you won’t need to flash your phone again when new builds of Android 12 are released. Just head to your system settings and fetch an update. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="58Olby"&gt;The second note is just your standard disclaimer that you do this at your own risk. This is unfinished software, and installing it could lead to malfunctions with your device or to software that you usually use. And depending on settings that you adjust in the Android Flash Tool, you might have to wipe all of the data from your phone. So proceed with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nIGG-Z2OspcNqk1d8fR6JICl6vc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19303885/vpavic_191018_3725_0231.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SPg2X6"&gt;Is my phone compatible with Android 12?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JOSEp5"&gt;The Android 12 developer preview is compatible with the Pixel 3, Pixel 3 XL, Pixel 3A, Pixel 3A XL, Pixel 4, Pixel 4 XL, Pixel 4A, Pixel 4A 5G, and the Pixel 5. It’s possible that Google will broaden the list of devices supported by Android 12 in the upcoming beta, but for now, you’ll need one of those phones to get the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nWnG91"&gt;What browser do I need to use to flash my phone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="fwlb97"&gt;Google says that you can use any browser that supports the WebUSB API, which is supported by Chrome as well as Microsoft Edge version 79 and later. The Android Flash Tool works with all the major operating systems, including Linux, macOS, Chrome OS, and Windows 10, though browser compatibility may vary depending on your OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wxx6Rr"&gt;Step 1: Activate these three settings on your Android phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="BMI7cK"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Enable the Developer Options menu&lt;/strong&gt; in your phone. First, open the Settings app. For phones running Android 8 (Oreo), click System. Otherwise, if your phone has Android 7 (Nougat) or later, scroll down to About Phone, then find Build Number. Tap Build Number seven times to enable Developer Options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dO4knj"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Turn on USB debugging&lt;/strong&gt; (this lets your phone and computer communicate via USB) within the Developer Options menu. To do this, head to Settings &amp;gt; System &amp;gt; Advanced &amp;gt; Developer Options. You’ll find USB debugging with just a little scrolling down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ElHgpn"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Enable OEM unlocking&lt;/strong&gt;. This option is also part of the Developer Options menu, further up the page than where you found USB debugging. If that option isn’t available for you to enable, that might be because it’s already enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/csscsUs89Ir1CKE5Rd299XIo9bU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16213698/vpavic_190503_3404_0019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HzryhV"&gt;Step 2: Connect your phone to your computer and get started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OSeB6k"&gt;If you use Windows 10, &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/studio/run/win-usb"&gt;you’ll need to install this driver&lt;/a&gt; first for your phone to be recognized.  People using macOS or Linux don’t need a driver. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="weswdD"&gt;Connect your phone to your computer with a USB cable. Then &lt;a href="https://flash.android.com/preview/dp1"&gt;visit this page to proceed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NbuEfq"&gt;The Android Flash Tool will ask for permission to access ADB keys in a pop-up window, which is necessary to install software on your phone. You’ll need to tap “OK” to proceed with this process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android Flash Tool for Android 11" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R3SlZ5sAdLEg5Bm14ClFdb7XjIs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20014977/4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll need to hit OK to proceed with the installation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WpBss1"&gt;Click “Select device.” Your device should appear in a pop-up window on your computer, so go ahead and click it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0ljh0M"&gt;Once you do that, you should now see a request on your phone that says “Allow USB debugging?” You’ll also see a long string of numbers and letters that should match up with what your PC shows if you click the gear icon on the Android Flash Tool page. On your phone, check the box next to “Always allow from this computer,” then tap Allow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jHjb7D"&gt;After that, your device should show up on the Android Flash Tool as being connected. Click on the box with the name of your device to proceed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android flash tool" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oqEnVwEk_QE3UUVA0Z1kLBWYGvI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20014998/8.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once your device shows up as being connected, click into it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="sjTlzI"&gt;You’ll want to pay attention to what appears in the “Selected build” section of the Flash Tool (see below). It should say “Android 12 Developer Preview 1.” Before you hit the blue “Install” button at the bottom of the page, I recommend tapping the pencil icon next to “Selected build” and checking the “Lock Bootloader” box. This will lock the bootloader after this process is complete, leaving you with a more secure device than if it remained unlocked.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android flash tool" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n4ejoA2xy7n9DiZCVdq1AtGd6ko=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20014994/6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select the “Lock Bootloader” option, which will lock your bootloader after the software installation is complete.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="QyzbSn"&gt;The next window basically tells you to stop interacting with your phone during the rest of this process unless asked to do so and to not unplug your device. If you’re in a position to proceed, go ahead.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android flash tool" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XRc70KHCAQGodzC1Gat0h2vS2PM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20015001/1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make sure your data is backed up before you proceed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XlJyBQ"&gt;One more prompt before getting started: a license agreement. You need to agree to the terms of the Android Software Development Kit License Agreement, which you can find &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/studio/terms"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0FIfKs"&gt;After you hit “I accept,” your phone will reboot into its bootloader screen. If nothing happens for a few seconds, don’t worry. You may also see a window pop up on your computer that says “Reselect your device.” In that case, leave your phone alone and select “Reselect device” on the computer. According to Google, your phone might be renamed “Android,” though it might just be identified with the model name (e.g., Pixel 3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Zdpkzo"&gt;If you haven’t flashed software before, Google will probably need to unlock your bootloader to proceed with the installation. Keep in mind that doing this will trigger a factory reset on your phone. If you haven’t backed up your data, you’ll lose everything. Once you agree, you’ll need to allow the bootloader to unlock on your phone. To do this, use the volume keys to navigate to the option that says “Unlock the bootloader,” then hit the power button once to confirm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0LiOV5"&gt;After that, the Android Flash Tool will begin to download and install the software. You can continue to watch along, but don’t touch your phone at this point, even though it will restart several times. Just keep an eye on the progress using the Android Flash Tool page on your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android flash tool" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JAaw6d7-Vu3g4ted-MHrdzXS7bA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20015017/9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;At this point, you can just sit and wait for the Android Flash Tool to wrap things up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wQDNXV"&gt;Once you’re all done, the phone will reboot one last time, and over on your PC, you’ll be met with a celebratory screen. You’re all done! And thankfully, you won’t have to go through this process again for the next Android 12 update — easy as this was. You’ll automatically receive updates to the developer preview over the air.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android flash tool" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WegRO7aOJMtF7tnpQvdwsPwvMN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20015030/10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’re all done!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JwgANf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21278261/android-developer-preview-software-beta-flash-tool-install-how-to-google-pixelflash"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21278261/android-developer-preview-software-beta-flash-tool-install-how-to-google-pixelflash</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
