<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-19T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon 870 reheats the Snapdragon 865 for 2021 phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eX7yPnMfq5jFz2rX_XK0M0NPkjk=/149x0:1771x1081/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68688359/Snapdragon_870_5G_Mobile_Platform.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YZEDtY"&gt;Qualcomm has announced a new mobile phone processor: the Qualcomm Snapdragon 870, a successor to last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/12/4/20995562/qualcomm-snapdragon-865-5g-camera-gaming-artificial-intelligence-improvements"&gt;Snapdragon 865&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/8/21312035/qualcomm-new-snapdragon-865-plus-gaming-performance-faster-cpu-gpu-wifi"&gt;865 Plus&lt;/a&gt; models. To be clear, the 870 isn’t a new next-gen design — that title goes to the Snapdragon 888, which makes far more substantial improvements in performance and new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HCoHLD"&gt;The 870, on the other hand, is virtually identical to the 865 and 865 Plus, with the same design right down to the Kryo 585 CPU and Adreno 650 GPU cores. The 870 is clocked at 3.2GHz, however, making it about 10 percent faster than the original 865’s 2.84GHz and about 3 percent faster than the 865 Plus (which offered 3.1GHz speeds). Think of it almost like a Snapdragon 865 Plus-plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wotbFe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Think of it almost like a Snapdragon 865 Plus-plus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bmiTkY"&gt;Qualcomm says that the reason for the new chip is in response to manufacturer and market demands. The 870 is designed for companies that want to offer a top-tier processor but don’t need the absolute best features that the flagship Snapdragon 888 offers and the higher price tag that it demands. Instead, the company says that it expects that Snapdragon 870 phones should hit a sub-$800 price tag (although, confusingly, we’ve already seen Snapdragon 888 phones like the $799 Galaxy S21 start to bleed into that range).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Bk9nK"&gt;Presumably, there’s also a marketing aspect here: the Snapdragon 870’s new branding and modest (if still real) speed improvements over even the Snapdragon 865 Plus mean that companies using the chip in their phones get a “new” 2021 chip to boast about on spec sheets, without concerns of getting looked over by customers for having an “outdated” or “old” processor like the 865 or 865 Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r99Uf3"&gt;Qualcomm says that the first Snapdragon 870 phones should be available in Q1 of this year, with Motorola, OnePlus, Oppo, and Xiaomi among the list of manufacturers planning to use the new processor in their devices. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22233584/qualcomm-snapdragon-870-865-plus-refresh-processor-smartphones-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22233584/qualcomm-snapdragon-870-865-plus-refresh-processor-smartphones-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T17:13:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T17:13:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is reportedly prototyping foldable iPhone screens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HwkeUq48UTT1T633jq3bPiSLRco=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68675881/vpavic_4243_20201018_0154.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4esEx0"&gt;Apple has started work on a foldable phone, and it’s begun prototyping foldable screens internally, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-15/apple-considers-foldable-iphone-minor-changes-planned-for-2021-models"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A final device is likely still years away, the report says, and Apple is working on just the display for now — not the rest of the phone it would attach to&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrPm9a"&gt;The initial prototypes sound similar to the foldable screens we’ve seen used by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536546/motorola-razr-2020-review-5g-folding-flip"&gt;Motorola&lt;/a&gt;, and others. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; says Apple is looking at making foldable screens with a “mostly invisible hinge” that could unfold to around the size of the iPhone 12 Pro Max. The report says that several screen sizes are being discussed, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9z7JXa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Under-display Touch ID is reportedly still in testing for 2021&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HSC7fl"&gt;Apple hasn’t publicly indicated any interest in making a foldable phone, though the company rarely signals its interest before entering a new product category. Major competitors have a head start on foldable devices, with Samsung and Motorola already releasing multiple generations of folding phones. Samsung’s Galaxy Fold came out in April 2019 (albeit, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18498904/samsung-galaxy-fold-review-screen-broken-issue-durability-foldable-phone-video-performance-price"&gt;with some substantial issues&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q61LiJ"&gt;On a more immediate note, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;has some updates on Apple products coming in 2021. This year’s iPhone is expected to have “minor upgrades,” but one more substantial improvement is still a possibility: an in-screen fingerprint sensor. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;already said &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-05/apple-working-on-in-display-fingerprint-id-for-future-iphones"&gt;back in 2019&lt;/a&gt; that Apple was looking into the feature for as early as 2020, and it’d be an obvious addition in 2021 since the wide adoption of face masks has seriously hindered the ability to use Face ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PvPtBM"&gt;It’s not clear how likely in-display Touch ID is to ship in 2021 (Apple tends to have iPhone features locked well in advance of production), but &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;says Apple is “still testing” the tech for inclusion this year. On a worse note, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;also says that Apple has discussed removing the Lightning port in favor of wireless charging on “some” iPhone models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVN73K"&gt;Apple’s long-rumored Tile competitor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/20/20875341/apple-tags-location-rumor-roundup"&gt;AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, are finally planned to launch this year, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports, and the iPad Pro could be refreshed with a Mini LED display. A thinner entry-level iPad is reportedly in the works as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233644/foldable-iphone-apple-screens-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233644/foldable-iphone-apple-screens-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T14:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T14:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp to delay new privacy policy amid mass confusion about Facebook data sharing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H4Ou6zEiXz4l_m0CuKUCG1iVlvg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68674807/akrales_180215_2310_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0ItYbS"&gt;WhatsApp on Friday announced a three-month delay of a new privacy policy originally slated to go into effect on February 8th following widespread confusion over whether the new policy would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218989/signal-new-signups-whatsapp-facebook-privacy-controversy-elon-musk"&gt;mandate data sharing with Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2zqvq"&gt;The update does not in fact affect data sharing with Facebook with regard to user chats or other profile information; WhatsApp has repeatedly clarified that its update addresses business chats in the event a user converses with a company’s customer service platform through WhatsApp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nfZOsh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;WhatsApp is trying to clear up confusion about its privacy practices&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q26Fj9"&gt;“We’ve heard from so many people how much confusion there is around our recent update. There’s been a lot of misinformation causing concern and we want to help everyone understand our principles and the facts,” the company wrote in a &lt;a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/giving-more-time-for-our-recent-update"&gt;new blog post published today&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Kxcse"&gt;Since 2016, WhatsApp has shared certain information with Facebook, including your phone number, unless you were one of the select few users who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/26/12655518/how-to-stop-whatsapp-sharing-phone-number-facebook"&gt;chose to opt out of data sharing while the option was still available that year&lt;/a&gt;. WhatsApp does not, however, look at people’s chat messages or listen to their phone calls, and WhatsApp conversations are end-to-end encrypted to protect against those abuses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yb3iqi"&gt;Despite this, a pop-up informing users of the new change included mention of how WhatsApp partners with Facebook, and it also included an ultimatum instructing users to delete their account if they chose not to agree to the new terms. That gave people the idea they were being railroaded into new, more invasive terms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9falaM"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226792/whatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;released a separate blog post this week&lt;/a&gt; trying to clear up the confusion, and it included a chart that specifies what information is protected and not shared when someone uses WhatsApp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1Gos4A"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We want to address some rumors and be 100% clear we continue to protect your private messages with end-to-end encryption. &lt;a href="https://t.co/6qDnzQ98MP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6qDnzQ98MP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— WhatsApp (@WhatsApp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1348839600333049857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dQXH4t"&gt;But numerous media reports highlighting the addition of new, broad language in the privacy policy (language WhatsApp says has been misconstrued to imply mandated data sharing) and misinformation on social media have coalesced into a full-blown WhatsApp privacy backlash. The result has been a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226792/whatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;surge in sign-ups for messaging competitors&lt;/a&gt; like Signal and Telegram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWvOnh"&gt;Facebook executives, including Instagram chief Adam Mosseri and WhatsApp head Will Cathcart, used Twitter to try to clear up the confusion, it seems with little success. Facebook’s poor privacy track record, and the fact that WhatsApp has over time turned its sights on monetizing the platform for its large international user base, has eroded trust in the chat app, which, in turn, has had the effect of turning a relatively mundane update into a worldwide controversy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1ezUd"&gt;WhatsApp says it’s now going to use this three-month delay to better communicate both the changes in its new policy and its long-standing privacy practices around personal chats, location sharing, and other sensitive data. “We’re now moving back the date on which people will be asked to review and accept the terms,” the blog post reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="RfvTGW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This update does not expand our ability to share data with Facebook.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jbl556"&gt;WhatsApp says no one will be losing access to the app if they didn’t agree to the new terms of service agreement that communicated the changes earlier this month. “We’re also going to do a lot more to clear up the misinformation around how privacy and security works on WhatsApp. We’ll then go to people gradually to review the policy at their own pace before new business options are available on May 15,” the company says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbF9Ht"&gt;WhatsApp tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; the policy won’t be changing when it does come out. The intent of the update is communicating to users that messages with businesses on WhatsApp may be stored on Facebook servers, which necessitates data sharing between the two companies (that data, WhatsApp says, can be used for businesses for the purpose of advertising, but Facebook does not share it across its apps automatically). WhatsApp still intends to release the update on May 15th to coincide with new business chat features it &lt;a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/shopping-payments-and-customer-service-on-whatsapp"&gt;began previewing back in October&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GjSmTD"&gt;But the company hopes the extra time will help it get a handle on the controversy and better improve its messaging around what’s actually changing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Zz9V6"&gt;“The update includes new options people will have to message a business on WhatsApp, and provides further transparency about how we collect and use data. While not everyone shops with a business on WhatsApp today, we think that more people will choose to do so in the future and it’s important people are aware of these services,” the blog post reads. “This update does not expand our ability to share data with Facebook.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JzodJm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 15th, 3:26PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Clarified how WhatsApp’s new privacy policy will treat data collected during chats with businesses as part of the upcoming privacy policy change, now going into effect on May 15th. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233257/whatsapp-privacy-policy-update-delayed-three-months"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233257/whatsapp-privacy-policy-update-delayed-three-months</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T20:41:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T20:41:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung will gradually remove chargers and earbuds from future phones  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IdAoNgju0Ospakpat_qY_HC2yqU=/216x0:1271x703/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670789/galaxy_s21_5g_highlights_box.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IOacv4"&gt;Samsung’s future phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22225930/samsung-galaxy-s21-no-charger-brick-headphones-price"&gt;will also&lt;/a&gt; not come with charging bricks, the company &lt;a href="http://www.samsungmobilepress.com/featurestories/answers-to-your-questions-about-the-galaxy-s21-series-from-samsung-mobile-executives"&gt;has revealed&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s leaving itself some wiggle room. In a Q&amp;amp;A about why &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/14/22231102/samsung-apple-kill-charging-brick-obituary-eulogy"&gt;it’s no longer including headphones and a charging brick in the box&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung says it believes &lt;em&gt;gradually&lt;/em&gt; removing the accessories from its phones could help make them more sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WvvecV"&gt;This answer implies that, while the next generations of its phones may not come with the included accessories, some may. Samsung has other lines that it brands as Galaxy, from its folding phones to its more budget options, and it’s left itself room to keep including a charger in some of them for a little while longer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gxANF4"&gt;Maybe Samsung wants to keep the charger around &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220858/samsung-a02s-us-unlocked-verizon-att"&gt;in cheaper phones&lt;/a&gt; so people who aren’t tech enthusiasts will have a higher likelihood of buying them, or maybe it doesn’t want to upset the people who buy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21407750/samsungs-galaxy-z-fold-2-price-release-date-hinge-screen-durability"&gt;its $2,000 phones&lt;/a&gt;. It could do both, either, or neither, and it would still count as “gradually.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbGsMY"&gt;The company doesn’t appear, however, to be following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;Apple’s route of pulling the plugs from its lineup of existing phones&lt;/a&gt;. The listings for the Note 20 Ultra and Note 10 still show a charger coming in the box. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A “what’s in the box” image of the Note 20 Ultra, including a charging brick." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tC2N5qlU-eL6ocGQJh-WYOFKv9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236779/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_4.24.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Note 20 Ultra looks to still include a charger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8adKhW"&gt;While a company shipping older products with something that’s no longer included in its latest and greatest might seem odd, it means Samsung doesn’t have to re-make all the boxes for its old products, and that consumers won’t end up in the awkward situation where they watch an unboxing from a phone’s launch on YouTube and then have a decidedly different experience. Which approach is correct really depends what you’re optimizing for, but this seems to be the one Samsung has chosen: slow and steady wins the race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5lUFA"&gt;You can read the full answer down below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="gWPCmn"&gt;We discovered that more and more Galaxy users are reusing accessories they already have and making sustainable choices in their daily lives to promote better recycling habits. To support our Galaxy community in this journey, we are transitioning to removal of the charger plug and earphones in our latest line of Galaxy smartphones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mllep"&gt;We believe that the gradual removal of charger plugs and earphones from our in-box device packaging can help address sustainable consumption issues and remove any pressure that consumers may feel towards continually receiving unnecessary charger accessories with new phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1V567T"&gt;We’ve also been implementing standardized USB-C type charging ports since 2017, so older chargers can still be compatible with our newest Galaxy models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231954/samsung-to-gradually-remove-chargers-earbuds-from-future-phones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231954/samsung-to-gradually-remove-chargers-earbuds-from-future-phones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T19:00:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T19:00:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung says S Pen support is coming to ‘additional device categories’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dC2DzBJIDf-ClQQwc6RWGK8-DCE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670390/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fyaa1y"&gt;Samsung just revealed the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; would be its first Galaxy S phone to support the S Pen stylus, but the company is already saying that S Pen support will come to other devices in the future, according to a statement first given &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-confirmed-s-pen-more-galaxy-smartphones/"&gt;to &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkUdII"&gt;“We are committed to innovating new mobile experiences that flow seamlessly and continuously to make our consumers’ lives easier and better,” Samsung president of mobile TM Roh says in the statement, which the company shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’ve made the bold decision to expand the S Pen experience to Galaxy S21 Ultra, and plan to expand the S Pen experience across additional device categories in the future.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DlTXe"&gt;“Additional device categories” is vague on its own. But given that S Pen is already compatible with some of Samsung’s smartphones and its Tab tablets, the next logical device category that could use the S Pen, to me, would be Samsung’s foldables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZGaw8F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This isn’t Samsung’s first suggestion that S Pen support will come to other devices&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V8jik2"&gt;This isn’t Samsung’s first suggestion that S Pen support will come to other devices. Back in December, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175769/samsung-stylus-galaxy-phones-s21-foldable"&gt;Roh said that the company&lt;/a&gt; has been “paying attention to people’s favorite aspects of the Galaxy Note experience and are excited to add some of its most well-loved features to other devices in our lineup,” though didn’t specify further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BCsDOp"&gt;And Roh has even hinted toward the S Pen coming to foldables. In a Q&amp;amp;A during Samsung’s Galaxy Note 20 and Galaxy Z Fold 2 presentation from August, Roh left the door wide open to the idea that the S Pen would make its way to foldables in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECXOIM"&gt;“The S Pen has always been a well-loved feature of the Galaxy Note. And we are happy to hear that people want it so much, they even want it on the Fold,” Roh said. (You can hear his statement in &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/CmS5rlX9cDA?t=5079"&gt;context here&lt;/a&gt;.) Later, after reiterating the features of the Galaxy Z Fold 2, he added, “and we will certainly to continue to listen to our customers’ feedback. So please stay tuned for what the future will hold.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231677/samsung-s-pen-foldable-support-additional-device-categories"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231677/samsung-s-pen-foldable-support-additional-device-categories</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T15:03:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T15:03:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Galaxy S21 doesn’t support Samsung Pay’s most convenient feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8fInbBkh7rTQvF1eJKfLxl7v_zE=/0x45:1067x756/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68669092/SamsungPayMST.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hW6Fdv"&gt;Samsung has confirmed that the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"&gt;Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; no longer support the convenient Magnetic Secure Transmission (MST) feature of Samsung Pay. And based on &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/01/14/samsung-pay-is-losing-its-one-remaining-good-feature-on-the-galaxy-s21/"&gt;what the company told &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the same will be true for all phones that Samsung releases from here on out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sa4LC1"&gt;If you’re not familiar, &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/global/galaxy/what-is/mst/#:~:text=Magnetic%20Secure%20Transmission%2C%20or%20MST,that%20helps%20power%20Samsung%20Pay.&amp;amp;text=Accepted%20at%20nearly%20all%20payment,Pay%20also%20supports%20NFC%20payments." rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MST is a very cool trick&lt;/a&gt; that allows Samsung phones to send out a magnetic pulse that made payment terminals think that you’d swiped a regular credit card. The most beneficial thing about it is that MST can work in scenarios where NFC payments aren’t available. It can send that magnetic signal to pretty much any payment terminal with a traditional card swiper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YI6mpl"&gt;MST is by no means perfect: getting a payment to go through on the first try can sometimes be a challenge, and it’s worthless in situations where you have to stick your card all the way into a slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jTAnqH"&gt;But now it’s a goner, with Samsung believing that NFC adoption has reached a point where it can phase out the MST aspect of Samsung Pay. “Due to the rapid adoption of near field communication (NFC) technology by consumers and businesses, beginning with devices launched in 2021, Samsung Pay will focus its support on NFC transactions, across the Galaxy portfolio,” Samsung said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;Android Police.&lt;/em&gt; “While future devices will no longer include magnetic stripe technology (MST), customers with previous, compatible Galaxy devices will be able to continue using Samsung Pay, including MST.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7jR2kM"&gt;Samsung phones as recent as the Galaxy S20 FE still had MST capabilities built in, so you don’t have to go far back to find a compatible device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l67Tqb"&gt;This means with the Galaxy S21 family, Samsung has now gotten rid of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W98UH5"&gt;The charging brick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jfuZL1"&gt;microSD storage expansion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vZrE0Z"&gt;MST&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="3u7I9D"&gt;I get the sense that a lot of people won’t mind losing some (or all) of those things — especially with the lower starting prices on the S21 and S21 Plus — but there’s no denying that Samsung Pay just lost what was maybe its best standout trick. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231392/samsung-pay-mst-feature-discontinued-galaxy-s21"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231392/samsung-pay-mst-feature-discontinued-galaxy-s21</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T11:18:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T11:18:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy S21 event: the biggest announcements</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YV0RSC-rkbPJkorp0vY61wKO5E4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68667564/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8rmWgJ"&gt;Samsung just finished its first Unpacked event of 2021. The headline announcements were the three new phones in its S21 lineup, but the company also announced new true wireless headphones, an item tracker, and a few other things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TnCzZS"&gt;We’ve rounded up all of the biggest announcements from the event right here.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nW1DZw2s8CszwwLruPWVY8PPGyc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232924/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="T6OKVx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21991813"&gt;The Galaxy S21 and S21 Plus will launch on January 29th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Caz0kP"&gt;Samsung announced the $799 Galaxy S21 and $999 S21 Plus, which are available for preorder today ahead of availability on January 29th. They’re largely the same phones (except for their physical size), and their camera module takes up an entire corner of the phones, giving them a whole new look. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x1fJYPTkfuKz2n_hkJlD-KKe9uo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233315/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6QfS1q"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21991813"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy S21 Ultra is compatible with the S Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6iI9Bu"&gt;Samsung announced the $1,199 Galaxy S21 Ultra, its newest top-of-the-line flagship smartphone. It has a bigger screen and more cameras than the S21 and S21 Plus, and, in a first for Samsung’s S-line of smartphones, it has support for the S Pen stylus. It’s also available for preorder today and will launch on January 29th. Samsung is working on an S Pen Pro with Bluetooth, which is coming later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HfeF9PeMncaIVpZwABYhZsorqEA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22235236/galaxy_s21_5g_highlights_box.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Plus box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IulYwV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21989971"&gt;Samsung’s S21 lineup won’t include a charger in the box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4LZXZ"&gt;Samsung is following Apple in not including a charging brick in the box with its newest phones. The phones will come with a USB-C to USB-C cable, but you’ll need to own a compatible charging brick or buy a new one if you want to plug your brand-new phone into a wall. The S21 lineup also won’t include headphones in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n3CyMPp3keMhYFgIcFHra0jV7fU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233200/BudsPro.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F1Gy1N"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21992988"&gt;The Galaxy Buds Pro are Samsung’s most premium wireless earbuds yet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uBSCN7"&gt;Samsung’s new Galaxy Buds Pro true wireless earbuds have improved active noise cancellation, a refined ambient sound mode, an IPX7 rating for water resistance, and more. They cost $199, are available for preorder today, and you’ll be able to buy them in stores on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gKwRvaFw-fWFLQvkCbcQcv5SigE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232918/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qKuu8e"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21991662"&gt;Samsung announced the SmartTag and SmartTag Plus Tile-like item trackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4Xqze9"&gt;Samsung announced a Tile tracker competitor called the SmartTag. It’s a small Bluetooth Low Energy dongle that you can attach to things, and you can pair it with Samsung’s SmartThings app. The SmartTag only works with Galaxy devices, though. The SmartTag will be available on January 29th and it will cost $29.99. Samsung also announced the Galaxy SmartTag Plus, which uses ultra-wideband for more precise tracking. The SmartTag Plus is launching later this year, and you’ll be able to buy one for $39.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WKKtKX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra first look: polished design (and prices)","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"},{"title":"Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro review: the right balance","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Fn3ayE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227561/samsung-galaxy-s21-event-news-announcements-biggest-products-unpacked"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227561/samsung-galaxy-s21-event-news-announcements-biggest-products-unpacked</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s how Samsung’s S Pen works with the new Galaxy S21 Ultra</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0TPXpD8cjqgxASTxtfF6epuoFmo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68667023/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jkJS2j"&gt;Samsung’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21991813"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; supports the company’s S Pen stylus. Support for the accessory has been a staple of Samsung’s Galaxy Note smartphones for years, but this is the first time it’s been supported in the company’s Galaxy S-series. The new S Pen will be available as an optional $39.99 accessory, and Samsung says the S21 Ultra will also work with S Pens from other Galaxy Note or Galaxy Tab devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afNUJ4"&gt;As for what you can use the stylus to do on the S21 Ultra, Samsung has outlined a range of familiar use cases. These include drawing, note-taking, photo editing, and signing documents. Physically, the new S Pen stylus is a little bigger than previous Galaxy Note S Pens, but it retains the side button. Samsung is also releasing a bigger S Pen Pro later this year, which comes equipped with Bluetooth and support for air gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HYOCCVWTy8lcO03r4hsUFCm19mQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233313/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Ultra with its stylus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RdEXJg"&gt;Unlike Galaxy Note phones, the Galaxy S21 Ultra doesn’t have a built-in slot for storing the stylus. Instead, Samsung is selling cases with S Pen carrying slots, which cost $69.99 when bundled with the stylus. Having to use a case to carry the accessory doesn’t sound as convenient as being able to slot it in the phone directly, but it’s a compromise given there’ll be plenty of Galaxy S21 Ultra owners who won’t bother with the optional accessory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDp54E"&gt;In the new lineup, stylus support is exclusive to the Galaxy S21 Ultra. You won’t be able to use an S Pen with either the Galaxy S21 or S21 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEPyMe"&gt;Rumors of the Galaxy S21 Ultra’s stylus support have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754983/samsung-galaxy-note-21-2021-smartphone-discontinued-stylus-s21-foldable-rumor"&gt;around since last year&lt;/a&gt;, and the feature was essentially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22196897/s-pen-uwb-comfirm-galaxy-s21-ultra-fcc"&gt;confirmed in an FCC filing&lt;/a&gt; at the end of December. Now that the Galaxy S series is inheriting one of the Note series’s biggest features, there are rumors that the latter could be discontinued. However, this has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22177972/galaxy-note-21-still-happening-yonhap"&gt;reportedly been disputed&lt;/a&gt; by one Samsung official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FBtCqG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 14th, 11:02AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added details of Samsung’s S Pen Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YfVuyX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra review: the real deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22226594/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-s-pen-stylus-support-price-unpacked-event"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22226594/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-s-pen-stylus-support-price-unpacked-event</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra first look: polished design (and prices)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ohf7aS0VQJIX1JrQynhe9j-YDms=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68667033/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Starting at $799 and available on January 29th&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Bcr1Iv"&gt;Samsung’s latest flagships are here: the Galaxy S21, Galaxy S21 Plus, and the Galaxy S21 Ultra. The first two — which start at $799 and $999, respectively — mark some of the least expensive flagship phones that Samsung has made in years, while the $1,199 S21 Ultra aims to be not just the top-specced phone in Samsung’s lineup, but also the best phone, period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vasZep"&gt;I was able to briefly try out all three devices last week, and they all share a new design language that throws out a lot of what I’d come to expect from a Samsung smartphone. The internal changes are more incremental from last year’s S20 lineup, though, and in some cases, they’re an intentional step back. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729416028124288960" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;All three phones are available to preorder&lt;/a&gt; and will launch on January 29th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrknfq"&gt;The new devices can effectively be divided into two categories: the S21 and S21 Plus, which are aiming to achieve a more wallet-friendly flagship experience, and the S21 Ultra, the ultimate Samsung smartphone that cuts no corners and aims to offer the most premium phone possible — with a price tag to match. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z8zSO8"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Galaxy S21|100092" data-volume-uuid="242ec3170" data-volume-id="100092" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-83" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uUOavS"&gt;Galaxy S21 and S21 Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="wQ64gh"&gt;Unlike past years, the S21 and S21 Plus are almost identical devices this time around, barring the obvious differences in screen size, battery size, and one or two other minor details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1E3Mv"&gt;But the most important change with these two phones isn’t actually the hardware itself; it’s after years of creeping prices, Samsung has finally reversed course, with the S21 and S21 Plus actually starting at $799 and $999, respectively, this year. That’s a full $200 less than last year’s models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FCtUH9"&gt;In order to accomplish that, Samsung made a few compromises in order to reach those lower price points. The displays, while the same 6.2-inch (S21) and 6.7-inch (S21 Plus) sizes as last year’s models, have dropped the subtly curved edges that have been a Samsung hallmark for years. Those flat panel screens also feature a step down in resolution from the 3200 x 1440 panels on last year’s models to a more modest 2400 x 1080 resolution. Both phones still offer 120Hz refresh rates, although it’s dynamically adjusted now. Lastly, the RAM has also been dropped from 12GB to 8GB. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/186Qtt86WK6nB5BfKlTL1m8FVvw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232929/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Plus (left) and Galaxy S21 (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1zkIHr"&gt;The smaller Galaxy S21 makes additional trade-offs: the back panel is made of polycarbonate plastic, not glass, and it lacks an ultra-wideband radio (which the S21 Plus and Ultra offer for better integration with Samsung’s new Galaxy SmartTag.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtYrhs"&gt;Lastly, Samsung is following in Apple’s footsteps by no longer including a charging brick or headphones in the box, justifying it with similar environmental reasons (although Samsung will also likely save a few dollars by not bundling those parts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dh92Gr"&gt;The big question is: are those admittedly small changes worth the $200 price cuts? We’ll have to wait until we can put the new S21 and S21 Plus through their paces in our upcoming review. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hFe-VPqD3aWkiOZKXv6ArfBcTUA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232921/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dKXfsR"&gt;It’s not all downgrades, however: the processor is Qualcomm’s latest Snapdragon 888 chipset, which promises big improvements in overall performance. There’s comprehensive 5G integration on both devices, with support for mmWave and sub-6GHz networks. The fingerprint sensor has been upgraded to Qualcomm’s new 3D Sonic Sensor Gen 2, which should be faster and easier to use. And the batteries are still big: the S21 still offers a beefy 4,000mAh battery, and the S21 Plus has been upgraded to an even larger 4,800mAh one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSt4QD"&gt;But the biggest update this year is the new design, which ditches the glass-slab sandwich that Samsung’s been using for years for an updated look. And it’s easily my favorite thing about the new phones. After years of dealing with the protruding camera bumps that have been the de facto cost of offering bigger sensors and better lenses on our smartphones, the S21 and S21 Plus embrace the camera bump instead of trying to work around it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nW1DZw2s8CszwwLruPWVY8PPGyc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232924/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0009.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ya477yPE5nhznTuwoIoqHL25jbc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232931/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0013.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CMSm12v55xWzjOz-aJfp052Narg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232920/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Plus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s7ZVWo"&gt;The S21 and S21 Plus still have camera bumps, but they look good as seamless pieces of metal that flow out naturally from the matching sides of the phones, with smooth edges and spiffy two-tone designs that look really nice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GzyCMU"&gt;Largely unchanged from last year, though, is the camera system itself. Both the S21 and S21 Plus offer a 12-megapixel wide-angle camera, a 12-megapixel ultrawide camera, and a 64-megapixel telephoto lens, along with a 10-megapixel selfie camera. (The S21 Plus no longer has a depth sensor.) If those sound similar, it’s because the hardware is virtually identical to the cameras found on last year’s Galaxy S20 and S20 Plus phones. Samsung has made some improvements on the software side of things, including the 30x “Space Zoom” mode, a new “Director’s View” mode for video that makes it easy to swap between lenses while filming, and additions to Samsung’s “Single Take” mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YSpguD"&gt;Samsung has told us that it will no longer over-smooth faces by default, instead making it an option. It’s high time that happened.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HQ0IYBxvlbiKR_MsSYaoiVtoPgk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233312/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Ultra, with S Pen and case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XUq3vN"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dd9LV2"&gt;If the S21 and S21 Plus are more restrained steps back in smartphone design, the Galaxy S21 Ultra is a phone that imagines what it would look like if you never had to make any compromises. It’s a phone that promises the very best of what Samsung’s hardware and Android can offer — if you’re willing to pay for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2M8tJB"&gt;Starting at $1,199 (a price that doesn’t include any extras like an S Pen stylus or a case), the S21 Ultra is Samsung’s third superlatively named phone, the successor to last year’s S20 Ultra. And it has a lot in common with the original, including a massive screen, a 108-megapixel camera, and top-of-the-line specs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KKLqix"&gt;But the S21 Ultra is a more refined version of last year’s model, one that looks to smooth out some of the sharp edges for a better experience — literally, in some cases, thanks to Samsung’s new rounded design language (which is similar to the S21 and S21 Plus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QV-3wxNRI7HBzVVRk76GjemWaqw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233319/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PMPRS-gX4duxcdGclOLU06cKzNU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233310/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0001.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uZFJi11aO2QYYkS4ivp8fF5cVP8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233318/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0009.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uVjfvZ"&gt;Looking at the spec sheet, the S21 Ultra checks almost every box: a 6.8-inch 3200 x 1440 OLED display, with refresh rates up to 120Hz (a refresh rate the S21 Ultra can hit at full resolution, unlike last year). There’s 12GB of RAM, a 5,000mAh battery, up to 512GB of storage, and Qualcomm’s latest Snapdragon 888 processor. It’s hard to imagine Samsung cramming more in here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NGPnxT"&gt;Of course, just because Samsung can’t fit it into the phone doesn’t mean it’s done adding features. The S20 Ultra will be the first Galaxy S phone to support Samsung’s S Pen stylus, which does S Pen things. If you’ve used a Galaxy Note recently, you’ll have a good idea of what to expect. The only quibble: the stylus isn’t included in the box with your $1,199-plus phone: it’ll cost an extra $40, or $70 in a bundle that includes a case that can store both the phone and the stylus. And those cases are pretty bulky, adding extra width to an already pretty big phone. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x1fJYPTkfuKz2n_hkJlD-KKe9uo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233315/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ah66N0"&gt;And then there are the cameras. The S20 Ultra’s camera tried to shoot for the moon, with its 108-megapixel sensor and 100x zoom mode that promised photography that could live up to the “ultra” moniker of the rest of the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u27L7L"&gt;The technology was incredibly cool, but it had plenty of issues. The S21 Ultra promises to offer a more refined experience for the second time around: the camera has a new focal length for slightly wider shots, a new laser autofocus system (similar to the Note 20 Ultra) that should help with the focusing issues on last year’s model, support for 12-bit color depth, and a more refined demosaicing process. Samsung is also working to give users more control over things like its AI-based photo enhancements, allowing you to adjust the level of smoothing, for example. Whether that’s all enough to solve the issues of the original is something that will require further testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t6f9jF"&gt;The S21 Ultra isn’t just about that big 108-megapixel sensor, though. It also has an additional three rear cameras. There is a 12-megapixel ultrawide camera, of course. Then there is not one but &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; separate 10-megapixel telephoto cameras: one with a 3X zoom and one with 10X zoom, which Samsung says is designed to give users more flexibility in how they approach shots. The downside of all those added sensors is that it expands the camera array to almost twice as wide as the regular S21 and S21 Ultra models, which spoils the look a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sGrZtm1pLAsx2jJyW9c6328_C-E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232923/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0008.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Yv4rEt"&gt;The Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra are a more deliberate lineup than Samsung’s past offerings. It’s a balancing act: with one hand, the devices show that Samsung has started to internalize the idea that not every phone needs every aspect of its spec sheet ramped up to the absolute max; with the other, it offers the Galaxy S21 Ultra, a phone that does just that for the power users who truly want that kind of device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZEQIK"&gt;It’s a philosophy that we started to see last year with the $699 Galaxy S20 FE, an intentionally cheaper Samsung phone that aimed to offer a premium experience at a more affordable price. The $799 and $999 S21 and S21 Plus feel like extensions of that philosophy, expanded from a niche “fan edition” device to the most mainstream of Samsung’s hardware. Factor in the almost omnipresent Samsung sales, and the S21 could be the most affordable Galaxy S device in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LHMNCu"&gt;For years, Samsung has focused on making the best phones on paper that it could. The S21 lineup feels like an attempt to make the best phone for the different needs of different customers, rather than simply the most excessive phone it can muster. It might be the right strategy in the midst of a struggling economy, but it means that its smaller phones aren’t quite as impressive. With the S21, if you want the best thing Samsung has to offer, you are going to have to buy the biggest thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xwmGzr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy S21 Ultra starts at $1,199. This article incorrectly listed the price in one paragraph as $1,119. Additionally, the S21 Ultra and S21 Plus feature glass backs, not aluminum. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzbSvG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eE384a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra review: the real deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"},{"title":"Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro review: the right balance","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>With the Samsung Galaxy S21, it’s time for Bixby to put up or shut up</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FQ2xWZUtfBN8OSG41vsKCfp0NlQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68666219/vpavic_220317_1557_0163.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lkivyw"&gt;Today, Samsung will unveil the Galaxy S21, Galaxy S21 Plus, and Galaxy S21 Ultra (I’ll take the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227941/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-plus-brown-zune-unpacked-2021"&gt;Zune-inspired brown one&lt;/a&gt; thanks). It’s happening a couple months earlier than usual for the S line of phones, but otherwise the script will remain the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="StxdLf"&gt;Here’s the script. Samsung will be the first major Android maker out of the gate with Qualcomm’s newest chips, this time with the Snapdragon 888. Samsung will use its unseemingly immense marketing budget and longstanding carrier relationships to ensure it will be seen as the default option if you want a premium Android phone — &lt;em&gt;especially &lt;/em&gt;if you are making that purchase in a US carrier store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gpXxp6"&gt;Other parts of the script are not necessarily guaranteed but are safe bets. They will probably be excellent phones, well-balanced and capable. Samsung will make big camera claims that will require rigorous testing to verify. And of course the ever-swinging pendulum of Samsung’s OneUI software will continue its current arc towards being overloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="h9Nrsj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9028921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sLXQPb"&gt;That last part of the script has me thinking about one of the major recurring characters in it: Bixby. Samsung’s digital assistant launched in 2017 with the Galaxy S8. It was yet another digital assistant, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15094720/samsung-galaxy-s8-design-safety-vs-note-7-battery-explosion"&gt;as Dan Seifert wrote at the time&lt;/a&gt; it had a very clear and very good remit that helped to distinguish it from Alexa, Siri, and Google. Samsung wasn’t trying to turn Bixby into a general-purpose, know-and-do-everything assistant. It had &lt;em&gt;focus&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="NkAcum"&gt;Samsung knows it can’t compete with Google, Microsoft, Amazon, and others when it comes to raw machine learning power and putting vast amounts of information at your fingertips, so it’s using Bixby to solve a simpler task, one that those companies have largely ignored. Bixby isn’t going to try to be the everything-assistant. Instead, it will be that “bright sidekick” that complements those other services. It’s a new user interface, not a new way to ask how tall the Eiffel Tower is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="LJ1AqL"&gt;Bixby was to be an interface, not an assistant. Was that really a viable strategy? Who knows! Certainly not Samsung, which very quickly did what Samsung tends to do with software: give in to feature creep. Over the last few years, Bixby has turned into the thing it originally was designed &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to be: a worse version of the Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uZvqmB"&gt;Samsung tried to push Bixby. It created a dedicated button for it. It later dropped that button but assigned it to a long press of the power button. It built out Bixby routines (which was related to Bixby’s original purpose). But then it associated Bixby with a chum-feed of content that lived left-of-homescreen. And it announced independent smart Bixby speakers that never really shipped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2nXt6F"&gt;On The Vergecast we have a running joke that &lt;a href="https://bixbyshoes.tumblr.com/"&gt;Bixby is a dog that wears shoes and is also a butler&lt;/a&gt;. It’s well-meaning and eager to please, but ultimately stumbles around a lot and doesn’t do a very good job serving drinks or answering the door because &lt;a href="https://bixbyshoes.tumblr.com/post/171592540108"&gt;it is a dog, wearing shoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZUPu2j"&gt;
&lt;div class="tumblr-post" data-href="https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/3negucxstVdHs6YbOvHoDA/171592540108" data-did="da39a3ee5e6b4b0d3255bfef95601890afd80709"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bixbyshoes.tumblr.com/post/171592540108"&gt;https://bixbyshoes.tumblr.com/post/171592540108&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://assets.tumblr.com/post.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ncO1cS"&gt;Speaking of shoes, put yourself in Samsung’s. Why does it continue to develop Bixby? I can only think of two reasons, one good and one bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGopDR"&gt;The good reason: a hedge against Google and Android. It’s always possible Google might do something egregious and Samsung would want to bail and do without Google’s services (or even Android itself). It’s not a terrible idea to have your own digital assistant percolating just in case. If nothing else, it might serve as a signal to Google that Samsung is, in fact, willing to just walk away and do Tizen and Bixby in certain negotiations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXQj4X"&gt;That’s the good reason — or at least as close to a good reason as I can come up with — but I don’t know if it’s the real reason. I suspect the real reason is one and the same as the bad reason: Samsung is &lt;em&gt;still, &lt;/em&gt;after all these years and after all its successes, trying to be Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uJR5nc"&gt;Being Apple is shorthand for having an end-to-end ecosystem where your users live and breathe your services and are thereby locked into your products. If you’re going to have an holistic, all-encompassing ecosystem you need to cover all the bases, and so: Bixby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FlKK64"&gt;And also: your own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22215172/samsung-neo-qled-4k-8k-tv-announced-specs-ces-2021"&gt;fitness service&lt;/a&gt;. And your own health app and ecosystem of connections. Your own family of Bluetooth headphones. Your own tracker tag (before Apple even announces its tracker tag). Your own tablets. Your own music service. Your own news service. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="INAaIx"&gt;All of these are things that Samsung has either tried or is actively trying to do now. Some of them are really successful! Samsung’s Galaxy Buds line will today consist of three different variants of earbuds, each with its own clear reason for being and each quite good (presuming the new Galaxy Buds Pro don’t whiff). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FJW7R5"&gt;Samsung has always had aspirations to build up a whole world (or, er, Galaxy) for its users to live in, just like Apple. What’s frustrating is that Samsung is very good at so many things and if it would just lean a little more into those things, it could chart a more innovative and interesting path. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mmGeha"&gt;Take Samsung DeX, for just one example. It’s the thing that allows you to connect your phone to a bigger screen like a TV or a monitor and get a full desktop interface. It’s genuinely cool but, I suspect, more of a tech demo than an oft-used feature. But the Snapdragon 888 that will be in these S21 phones will in many ways be just as powerful as the chips that are going to be running Arm-based Windows laptops this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r8A0qP"&gt;There’s untapped potential with DeX that Apple couldn’t match for years if Samsung could figure it out. Instead, it’s putting effort into getting Tile-esque tracking tags out the door before Apple can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ONvSxX"&gt;If Samsung would focus a little more on where it’s already ahead and a little less on where it’s woefully behind, it would make much more exciting products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxuQXt"&gt;That’s why I’m calling it: I’ve had it with Bixby. If Samsung can’t either bring it up to snuff with Siri (a low bar!) or find a way to bring it back to its more focused roots, it’s time to send it to the farm. Or at least give users the option to remap the power button to the Google Assistant (without needing third-party hacks). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Urm3Xz"&gt;There is a tiny glimmer of hope. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8aD3a6gHZeQ?t=63"&gt;Jimmy is Promo’s leak&lt;/a&gt; of the new version of Samsung’s OneUI version of Android shows that users will be able to choose between the Google feed or Samsung Free feed on their home screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xUEQVH"&gt;Samsung’s user interface on top of Android has swung like a pendulum between two poles. It becomes overloaded with features and weird UI for a few years, then the pendulum hovers there at the end of its arc before swinging back to a cleaner, simpler UI. It’s time for the pendulum to swing back. And that means it’s time to let Bixby go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EIFHf5"&gt;The last of CES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1256224424"&gt;Are all of these technically CES announcements or are some of them merely CES-adjacent? When CES is all virtual is it an event where things happen or merely a mood, a state of mind? Am I using jokes about philosophical quandaries as a smoke screen to cover up my inability to determine whether or not these things technically are a part of CES or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7hLlPQ"&gt;Sometimes questions don’t have answers. All we can really know in this world is that laser projectors are still really cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAV2pM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/13/22229575/asus-latte-movie-projector-mobile"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus’ latte dispenses movies instead of coffee and milk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I have an Anker/Nebula version of one of these mini projector/speaker things and it’s one of the best things I throw in my suitcase when I travel (er, when I traveled). You really do need a dark room for it to be any good, but you’d be surprised how much more convenient it is to just plug an HDMI cable into the projector you’ve got than it is dealing with whatever TV might be at the hotel or Airbnb. I might be interested in switching to this, as the Nebula’s version of Android TV is old, buggy, and poorly supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CZhhJj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228488/lg-4k-laser-projector-airplay-2-price-release-date-specs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG’s latest 4K laser projector supports AirPlay 2 for $2,999&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256224595"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228861/lg-ultragear-gaming-monitors-4k-1440p-pc-xbox-series-x-ps5-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG’s new batch of gaming monitors includes 4K / 144Hz panel with HDMI 2.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Z5HpK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228859/asus-gaming-monitor-refresh-rate-hdmi-21-ces-2021-rog-strix-swift-4k"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But wait, Asus has even more gaming monitors equipped with HDMI 2.1 ports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JKJiz6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229159/asus-chromebook-cx9-br1100-price-release-date-specs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus’ new Chromebook CX9 offers military-grade durability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OkPURC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228946/asus-zenbook-duo-vivobook-laptops-preorder-date-ces"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus’ 2021 laptop line includes two new dual-screen ZenBooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; A new member joins the Keyboard In The Front club!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="D661uf"&gt;If you’re new to the ZenBook Duo line, the laptops have a primary screen (the regular one) as well as a secondary screen (the ScreenPad Plus) that’s built into the top half of the keyboard deck. It’s not really big enough to do anything on, but you can load your distractions (Twitter, Discord, etc.) onto it to keep them out of your main workspace. Some programs, including Adobe’s, also offer ScreenPad-specific interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="RkpnWt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228325/msi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MSI’s 2021 gaming laptops get Nvidia’s RTX 3000 series mobile graphics cards and Wi-Fi 6E support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Monica Chin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="YtsgbQ"&gt;MSI has introduced its early 2021 lineup of portable gaming laptops during CES on Wednesday. The big news is that all the new releases have been outfitted with Nvidia’s brand-new GeForce RTX 3000 series graphics cards. In addition to improved frame rates and ray tracing, these chips will deliver Nvidia’s latest features, including its resizable BAR technology. They’re also getting support for Wi-Fi 6E.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="uvbXcD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227846/msis-creator-15-nvidia-rtx-3000-price-specs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MSI’s new Creator 15 comes with RTX 3000 graphics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Monica Chin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="iMZBBp"&gt;The Creator 15 is just the latest of the dump of gaming- and creator-focused laptops to adopt Nvidia’s new RTX 3000 graphics, following their release at CES 2021. These laptops will use the third generation of Nvidia’s Max-Q design, which is engineered for thin gaming and content laptops. The new GPUs also include a new Dynamic Boost 2.0 technology that leverages AI to balance power between CPU, GPU, and GPU memory in real time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1256224724"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227970/msi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MSI’s new GE76 Raider Dragon Edition Tiamat is a tribute to an ancient goddess&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; 10-year-old me playing 1st Edition Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons would have lost it if he knew someday there’d be a Tiamat-themed gaming laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNPdhN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225459/best-tech-ces-2020-where-are-they-now-what-happened-next"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best tech of CES 2020: Where are they now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Jm66uM"&gt;More from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TS28en"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22217197/relaxation-drinks-recess-som-sleep-pepsi-branding"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chill imbibes: inside the booming business of relaxation drinks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Great feature from Liz Lopatto. I’ve been seeing ads for these drinks everywhere and wondering what the deal really was. Here’s the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256224760"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228580/apple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple’s first major racial equity investments include a Detroit developer center and HBCU tech hub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256224748"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228702/intel-ceo-bob-swan-pat-gelsinger-technical-financial"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel is replacing its CEO next month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RYGNmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225716/ring-end-to-end-encryption-video-launch"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ring adds end-to-end encryption to protect your video streams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMFVsJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228594/google-coronavirus-tracking-app-exposure-notifications-issues-problems"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google says a fix for Android coronavirus tracking delays is on the way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jXOfKf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nvidia and AMD address the great GPU shortage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxOHxU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230249/samsung-galaxy-s21-bixby"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230249/samsung-galaxy-s21-bixby</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
