<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-18T20:41:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T20:41:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T20:41:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Someone unboxed the Pixel 6 early and didn’t bother to turn it on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pixel 6 color choices" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-XfVzGdHxQQaqtli3WLbugSjLuk=/0x22:3170x2135/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011701/pixel_6_phones.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Pixel 6 color choices | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="auC0LN"&gt;Google’s upcoming phones have made early appearances in leaks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/14/20865699/pixel-4-xl-leaked-photos-camera-specs"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/3/17814936/google-pixel-3-xl-leak-found-in-lyft"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/5/3/18527905/pixel-3a-xl-best-buy-leak-6-inch-display-64gb-ram-specs-features"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/3/4691652/did-google-just-leak-the-nexus-5-kitkat-video"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/10/12/3493954/lg-nexus-4-full-review-leaked-ahead-of-announcement"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again, so it’s really no surprise that someone seems to have obtained a retail-boxed Pixel 6 unit ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;the fall launch event tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iG6u53"&gt;In a video posted initially to TikTok, then deleted but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469"&gt;still available on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a few hours, @CristianDimboiu took a literal approach to unboxing by removing the “Sorta Seafoam” green device from its carrier without going any further. We didn’t see the screen turn on or see the screen at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dxeipT"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Google Pixel 6 - World First Unboxing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GooglePixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GooglePixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Launch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6Launch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/0z6wttnVp7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0z6wttnVp7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris DB (@CristianDimboiu) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fd2ZyY"&gt;Fortunately, Google apparently ships its new phone upside down so that we could see the camera bar at the back with multiple lenses. It also appears that this phone ships with a cable and USB-C adapter but no charger, so hopefully, new owners will have one handy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t1JoRQ"&gt;Now the video has been removed from Twitter as well. However, it was so short that it’s hard to say you missed anything of note unless you really wanted to hear K Camp’s TikTok hit, Lottery, playing at maximum volume. Check back here on Tuesday at 1PM ET / 10AM PT for Google’s launch event to get a much more thorough look at both Pixel 6 devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qNmEWL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Google’s own preview&lt;/a&gt; revealed that the Pixel 6 Pro adds a telephoto lens to the mix, but more about the hardware performance, display characteristics, and software tweaks will have to wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cmdcuV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Pixel 6: what to expect from Google’s thoroughly pre-announced phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PFB3Oe"&gt;What we know so far about the Pixel 6 family, thanks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu"&gt;to retailer leaks over the weekend&lt;/a&gt;, is that pricing may have dropped compared to the Pixel 5. If information from Target is correct, then the 128GB Pixel 6 will go on sale for $599, while the 128GB Pixel 6 Pro costs $898.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66ECom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 18th, 8:40PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Noted that the video has been removed from Twitter and TikTok.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T10:40:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T10:40:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Pixel 6: what to expect from Google’s thoroughly pre-announced phone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 6" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3ANmSTGFUPwgXmctEALNH7XbPHU=/1142x0:7892x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70010304/Google_Pixel_6_Pro.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oOXIzj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;We’ve seen the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Google’s decision to announce and thoroughly tease its new high-end flagship was revealing and confusing but, given all the leaks that followed, ultimately not that consequential. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZL0jRM"&gt;The Pixel 6 and 6 Pro feature an all-new, in some cases, quite colorful design, with an in-display fingerprint sensor, Google’s new Tensor SoC, and the Titan M2 security chip. The standard Pixel 6 has a 90Hz 6.4-inch screen, while the Pro gets a 120Hz 6.7-inch, but the big difference might end up being the cameras. Both devices have new wide and ultrawide cameras, but the Pro comes with an additional 4x optical zoom periscope lens. You can see what they look like in the hands of real people in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129719782326274"&gt;this Twitter thread of leaked images&lt;/a&gt; from Evan Blass:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5INvVo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/xcfQ6ylGuD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xcfQ6ylGuD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— E (@evleaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129719782326274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TOH9Ng"&gt;But now that company is planning on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;launching its new phones on October 19th&lt;/a&gt;, you might be wondering: what could Google have left to share? If leaks are any indication, quite a few interesting things. We’ll be covering Google’s event live on Tuesday, but keep reading below for what to expect ahead of the Pixel 6 launch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google’s new Pixel 6 phones, regular and Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ckQnWc66L7bV9d2osK3PMYdxPE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22755089/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2tBUMk"&gt;Powerful new hardware, including upgraded cameras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rAJIdy"&gt;Google long held the crown for best smartphone camera on its Pixel line but slipped in the last few years in favor of what both Samsung and Apple brought to the table. A clear break from mid-range phones and mid-range specs to something decidedly on the high-end could be just the thing Google needs to retake its crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GffJx5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/9/22718007/google-pixel-6-leak-teases-magic-eraser-camera-five-years-android-security-updates"&gt;Rumors and leaked store pages from Carphone Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; (viewable on the Wayback Machine &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211009124417/https://www.carphonewarehouse.com/google/pixel6-river-content.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211009124928/https://www.carphonewarehouse.com/google/pixel6-pro-river-content.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) suggest Google is sparing no expense in updating &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;the cameras of the Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt;. Both versions of the Pixel 6 feature a 50MP main sensor — a big step up from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22674143/apple-iphone-13-pro-12-samsung-galaxy-pixel-android-comparison-specs"&gt;the iPhone 13 Pro’s 12MP camera&lt;/a&gt; — and a 12MP ultrawide. The Pixel 6 Pro also has an extra camera with 4x zoom with 48MP telephoto that can reach an even higher 20x zoom thanks to Google’s Super Res Zoom feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/15/17973484/google-pixel-3-xl-review-camera-features-screen-battery-price-photos"&gt;it first added with the Pixel 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ydITbR"&gt;On the front of the Pixel 6 Pro, the selfie camera can also be expected to feature a wide 94-degree field of view, not dissimilar from the wide-angle selfie camera on the Pixel 3. People love selfies, and the front camera is another clear place Google could shine since Apple decided to keep selfies the same on the iPhone 13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5A6jmW"&gt;Surprisingly affordable pricing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="veRS13"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here are the corroborated &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Pro?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6Pro&lt;/a&gt; prices in the Target inventory system in the US.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pixel 6: $599&lt;br&gt;Pixel 6 Pro: $898&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Google has to be subsidizing this phone like crazy. This is insanity. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/teampixel?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#teampixel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/OUBl8cXCBh"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OUBl8cXCBh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— M. Brandon Lee | THIS IS TECH TODAY (@thisistechtoday) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1449909532939804678?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tq0Apa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu"&gt;Pricing leaks snagged from Target shelf tags and its internal system have arrived&lt;/a&gt;, from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1449909532939804678"&gt;M. Brandon Lee&lt;/a&gt; and Evan Lei. They put the US starting price of 128GB Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro phones at $599 and $898, respectively. That’s cheaper than where the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; started last year ($699) and could help shake up the market for Android phones.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RylxEi0yU1z2JZlZhTPybKN9Dks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22925098/Screenshot_2021_10_13_3.29.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211009124417/https://www.carphonewarehouse.com/google/pixel6-river-content.html" target="_blank"&gt;Carphone Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1446843190892453889?s=20" target="_blank"&gt;@evleaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Pixel Stand, 30W charging brick, and clear Pixel 6 Case&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gvVvjU"&gt;Other tweaks are less visible. The battery in the Pixel 6 is expected to be improved and, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158452/google-pixel-december-feature-drop-features"&gt;with Extreme Battery Saver&lt;/a&gt; turned on, lasts for 48 hours on a single charge. The Pixel 6 Pro could also feature even faster charging, with the ability to hit 50 percent charge in 30 minutes, &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/massive-leak-just-confirmed-ton-new-pixel-6-features"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt; writes&lt;/a&gt;. Helping make all of that happen is a new 30W charging brick (which won’t be included in the box) and&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714141/google-pixel-6-pro-marketing-images-leak-evleaks-wireless-charger-face-unlock"&gt; a new 23W Pixel Stand with active cooling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zUOPIU"&gt;The same leaked Pixel 6 store pages also point to the use of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21335252/corning-gorilla-glass-victus-drop-scratch-resistant-apple-samsung"&gt;Corning’s Gorilla Glass Victus&lt;/a&gt; for the glass on the new phones and a new clear case that could be perfect for showing off the multicolored varieties of Pixel 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tdnanj"&gt;Long-awaited software tricks like the Magic Eraser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Wjhqyq"&gt;Google can pack as much high-tech hardware into its phones as it wants, but the real trick is all the extra performance its software squeezes out of it. The Pixel 6 and 6 Pro appear to have several software features that might do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5cnm2I"&gt;First is Magic Eraser, which promises to “remove strangers and unwanted objects” with just a few taps in Google Photos. This actually appears to be a photo feature Google’s been working on for at least four years. The company introduced a similar &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/17/15654476/google-photos-object-removal-feature-demo"&gt;obstruction-erasing feature in 2017&lt;/a&gt; by removing a fence from a photo of a baseball game. The fine print on the leaked store page is clear that Magic Eraser won’t work for every photo, but it certainly seems like it could be very impressive when it does.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kB-ygslMZlThvd8jZgUONPvXhC0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22925206/Screenshot_2021_10_13_4.16.48_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211009124417/https://www.carphonewarehouse.com/google/pixel6-river-content.html" target="_blank"&gt;Carphone Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1446843190892453889?s=21" target="_blank"&gt;@evleaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motion Mode on the new Pixel 6 and 6 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="epasHb"&gt;Google’s two other software features mentioned in the same leaked store pages are opposites. Face Unblur attempts to deblur faces captured in motion-heavy photos (Google’s example is children playing). While Motion Mode “adds more action to action shots.” It’s not super clear what that entails, but Google’s photo example shows a blurry, clearly in-motion Ferris wheel with two subjects in focus standing in front of it — almost like long exposure background with a traditional photo foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qQbbmU"&gt;Other software advancements include several varieties of on-device translation, thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676099/google-pixel-6-tensor-processor-rumor-arm-cortex-x1-core-mystery-strange"&gt;Google’s mysteriously structured Tensor chip&lt;/a&gt;. The text from the Carphone Warehouse leak specifically calls out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ap6A2s"&gt;Get your chats translated in real time, listen to podcasts with translated captions and even use your camera to read signs in up to 55 languages. No Internet needed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5vIJHc"&gt;Rumors point to fairly extensive software support for both versions of the Pixel 6, which means they could stay ahead of the pack as Google rolls out new features over time. So far, that looks like four major Android updates, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/10/13/pixel-6-android-updates/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and five years of security updates based on what &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; saw in those leaked store pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sVn4l7"&gt;The Google-y versions of an Apple One subscription&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wMCKbJ"&gt;What better to go with a bunch of new phone hardware and software than a nice all-in-one subscription package? &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21433205/apple-one-subscription-bundle-price-music-tv-plus-arcade-icloud"&gt;Apple One was Apple’s version of the subscription bundle&lt;/a&gt; tying in services like Apple TV Plus, Apple Music, and extra iCloud storage. Now, it seems like Google might have something similar in mind &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720374/google-pixel-pass-subscription-premium-services-bundle-extended-warranty"&gt;with a bundle called “Pixel Pass.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g49gvU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Pixel Pass: This appears to be a blend of the iPhone upgrade plan where you can get a new phone every year and the Apple One Subscription.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Contains YouTube Premium, Google One, Play Pass, extended warranty, and is associated with Google Fi.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#pixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/teampixel?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#teampixel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/iU7VTc16vS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iU7VTc16vS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— M. Brandon Lee | THIS IS TECH TODAY (@thisistechtoday) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1447248490321514500?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qlkSZt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1447248490321514500?s=20"&gt;A leaked document from Brandon Lee&lt;/a&gt; suggests Pixel Pass could combine up to four subscriptions: YouTube Premium or YouTube Music, Google One for extra storage and discounts, Play Pass for apps and games, and Google Fi. The bundle could also incorporate some kind of upgrade plan akin to Apple’s iPhone Upgrade program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6Mp7tu"&gt;A foldable Pixel &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jwYDcp"&gt;Last but not least, there’s a whole other Pixel device that Google could show off or at least tease at the launch of the Pixel 6 — a foldable codenamed “Passport.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="90DkF5"&gt;In 2019, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18535863/google-pixel-foldable-phone-prototype-samsung-galaxy-fold-io-2019"&gt;revealed it has prototyped foldable devices&lt;/a&gt; for years. The company has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18071720/google-android-foldables-fragmentation-displays"&gt;made modifications to Android&lt;/a&gt; over the years to better support devices like Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 3, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697950/android-12-1-foldable-features-report-split-screen-multi-tasking-taskbar"&gt;and it has even more planned&lt;/a&gt;. It follows that Google might at least try its hand at making some kind of device to straddle the phone and tablet markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZR16F5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21356760/foldable-google-pixel-q4-2021-leaked-internal-document-5-5a-4a-5g"&gt;An internal Google document leaked in 2020&lt;/a&gt; confirmed the company was targeting a 2021 release for the “Passport.” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"&gt;Further reporting from &lt;em&gt;The Elec&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;this June claimed that Samsung had begun production on folding OLED displays for use in new devices from Google, Vivo, and Xiaomi. That could line up with a late 2021 release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HbHhyI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 18th, 11:36AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added tweet thread from Evan Blass with pictures.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yp2bl3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T04:35:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T04:35:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Pixel 6 might start at a relatively affordable $599</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro lineup" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gvuijt355hlT98Haqc5CtsMGe3U=/448x0:7198x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70009616/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro lineup.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="s1StdY"&gt;The Pixel 6’s price could start at $599 with 128GB of storage, while the 128GB Pixel 6 Pro could start at $898, according to early US pricing at Target stores spotted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1449909532939804678"&gt;M. Brandon Lee&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EvanLei1/status/1449875442953949184"&gt;Evan Lei&lt;/a&gt;. Lei posted a photo of pricing already displayed on Target’s shelves, while Lee has images of the retailer’s inventory system showing the same prices. A “street date” for both phones (aka their release dates) is listed as October 28th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfvImM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ayOD9qDsSq0"&gt;Lee has previously reported&lt;/a&gt; that the European starting prices of the Pixel 6 and the Pixel 6 Pro will be €649 and €899 respectively, while &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rquandt/status/1449810859807608836?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1449810859807608836%7Ctwgr%5Ehb_2_7%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2F9to5google.com%2F2021%2F10%2F17%2Fpixel-6-us-price%2F"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;’s Roland Quandt&lt;/a&gt; has discovered Amazon UK listings that show the 128GB Pixel 6 Pro priced at £849, with a shipping date of November 1st. The Pixel 6 Pro with 256GB of storage could cost £100 more at £949.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xE8uCQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here are the corroborated &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Pro?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6Pro&lt;/a&gt; prices in the Target inventory system in the US.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pixel 6: $599&lt;br&gt;Pixel 6 Pro: $898&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Google has to be subsidizing this phone like crazy. This is insanity. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/teampixel?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#teampixel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/OUBl8cXCBh"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OUBl8cXCBh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— M. Brandon Lee | THIS IS TECH TODAY (@thisistechtoday) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thisistechtoday/status/1449909532939804678?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6h2Dhq"&gt;If accurate, these prices are much more affordable than what we expected after Google said it was making an “ultra high end” smartphone in August. Google’s hardware chief Rick Osterloh even said that the new phone would “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;certainly be a premium-priced product&lt;/a&gt;,” which suggested pricing of over $1,000. Instead, these starting prices are cheaper than the midrange &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; that debuted for $699 last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fqI3wS"&gt;Google is poised to announce its latest smartphones at an event &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;taking place on Tuesday at 1PM ET / 10AM PT&lt;/a&gt;. The two phones will be Google’s first to run its own Tensor processor, and could support face-unlock, up to 23W wireless fast charging via a new Pixel Stand, and come with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/9/22718007/google-pixel-6-leak-teases-magic-eraser-camera-five-years-android-security-updates"&gt;five years of Android security updates&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a closer look at the phones ahead of their official launch, plenty of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729135/google-pixel-6-pro-leaked-photos-images-renders-evan-blass"&gt;images of the handset have leaked&lt;/a&gt; showing every aspect of their design.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T11:09:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T11:09:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>ZmBIZI’s $550 Z2 phone pays you for your data usage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HzIRy1GZvCR0i5xnYHyUYlIdLa0=/0x0:2522x1681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999652/image__1___1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZmBIZI Z2 is a the $550 4G phone that pays you for the personal data you share on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HflYoT"&gt;We live so much of our lives on our smartphones these days that our mobile devices are just full of valuable data that we often unknowingly and freely give to all the major tech companies: our spending habits, our personal preferences, our locations, and much more. Since we can’t really live without our phones, and tech companies aren’t going to stop monetizing our data without a fight, we might as well get our cut of the data pie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ooKny"&gt;That’s the premise of ZmBIZI phones, the LA-based and minority-owned startup backed by the &lt;a href="https://streetcredcapital.com/portfolio-item/zmbizi/"&gt;fintech lender Street Cred Capital&lt;/a&gt; that is trying to make our phones work for us. Both its new phone, the Z2, and its proprietary software are designed to share the profit that your mobile data generate, back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUyqmx"&gt;I spoke with ZmBIZI co-founder &lt;a href="https://www.gq.co.za/culture/entertainment/alpesh-patel-the-african-connection-16554524"&gt;Alpesh Patel&lt;/a&gt;, the former director of sales at Motorola in Africa and founder of Mi-Fone in Africa, who explained ZmBIZI’s ambitions on both the hardware and software fronts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZoyxnN"&gt;ZmBIZI is putting its bets on its new $550 unlocked 4G phone, the Z2. It has a high-resolution, 6.67-inch Full HD+ LCD display (1080 x 2400 pixels; 20:9 aspect ratio), a MediaTek Helio P60 processor, 8GB RAM, and 128GB of storage. The version I saw through a Zoom video call has a glossy fuchsia back cover with transparent cut-outs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fdwasm"&gt;Like many phones these days, the Z2 has multiple cameras on the back. It has a 64-megapixel rear camera, a 16-megapixel wide-angle, 5-megapixel macro, and a 0.3-megapixel photosensitive one. The Z2 is powered by a 4,400mAh battery, has a dual-SIM slot, but has no 3.5mm audio jack. According to &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/this-startups-flagship-smartphone-pays-you"&gt;PCMag’s research, this phone is likely a rebrand of Cubot X50&lt;/a&gt; with some tweaks. PCMag also notes that it will work best on AT&amp;amp;T’s network, will have limited coverage on T-Mobile, and is unlikely to work at all on Verizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mk4JnC"&gt;Most importantly, the Z2 can accept contactless payments through NFC, which means it can be used as a point-of-sale terminal for someone running a food truck without additional hardware, for example. This is actually the first phone &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210616005325/en/Visa-Launches-its-First-U.S.-Tap-to-Phone-Pilot-in-Washington-D.C.-to-Support-Region%E2%80%99s-Black-Owned-Small-Businesses"&gt;Visa has partnered with to pilot its Tap to Phone&lt;/a&gt; program in America. This means customers can just tap their existing forms of payment (card or Apple or Google Pay) rather than download a third-party app like Venmo to pay or use a card swiping dongle from Square. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OnR7PacRrSulpTnWKQ_A0q-pKEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928858/ZmBIZI_Z2_back.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;ZmBIZI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZmBIZI Z2 has quad cameras on the back, with a 64-megapixel main camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S8fgQ4"&gt;The main selling point of this phone is that you can earn ZmBIZI Coins by using partnered apps or doing organic smartphone tasks on the Z2. It’s similar to using cash-back websites like Rakuten to shop, where you get money back by buying at their partnered retailers. Each ZmBIZI coin is equivalent to $0.01 USD, and when you’ve accumulated at least $20 USD, then you can move your coins onto a digital Visa debit card preloaded on the phone, which enables you to use that money in the real world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Us7qjW"&gt;The website and press materials claim you can make an average of $10 per month from the Z2, but that number feels very optimistic. Patel explained the payment scheme this way: when you buy something with your credit card on your phone, the retailer will share a fraction of the 3.5-percentage processing fee with ZmBIZI, and ZmBIZI will share 1/5 of that amount, evenly divided by the number of its users. This is the amount you can expect. Perhaps other things you do on the phone, such as viewing ads, will offer bigger payouts, but it’s hard to tell over a short Zoom call with limited app demonstrations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dww2f"&gt;Based on what I could see over Zoom and the company’s website, the Z2 homescreen has a circular launcher that ZmBIZI plans to serve custom ads to its users, so they can watch and get paid. This feature is more of a concept rather than a reality at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfnTlI"&gt;The Z2’s list of curated apps with rewards is long and often strange; you can see the complete list by hovering your mouse over different app icons on its &lt;a href="https://zmbizi.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. For example, you can get paid by doing something very simple, like using Yahoo Search rather than Google to search the web, because they have a paid partnership. There’s also an aptly named app called Earn Money, which gives you tasks like snap photos around your neighborhood and surveys to complete to earn your rewards. Perhaps you’d prefer the Smilecheck app, where “the more you smile, the more you get paid” — my guess is that you’d be feeding the AI valuable facial recognition information. It’s not clear whether each app will disclose how and where it will be using the information it collects about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbqIaS"&gt;Some of these coin-earning tasks are essentially asking you, the user, to allow yourself to become a data guinea pig, but I’m not sure the minimal reward will be worthwhile. I used to do &lt;a href="https://surveys.google.com/google-opinion-rewards/"&gt;Google’s Opinion Rewards surveys&lt;/a&gt; for fun until I got bored answering the same few questions, never redeemed my Google Play points, and have since lost track of my account. With the Z2, I guess even if you stop participating in the data collection, you’ll still be able to use the $550 Z2 as a fully functioning phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="21FqN5"&gt;Who knows if the company will be able to realize its vision of paying its users for their data usage or if the startup will just fold. Back in 2017, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/7/14841604/freedompop-free-mobile-plan-android-smartphone-v7"&gt;FreedomPop V7 phone in Europe&lt;/a&gt; had promised a “free mobile plan for life,” but it offered such low data limits (200 megabytes) that made the company pivot its strategy again. Or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635779/ceo-saygus-smartphone-company-fraud"&gt;Saygus company&lt;/a&gt; that raised money in 2006 for a new phone that was never made and ended up defrauding investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V0sYht"&gt;If you don’t mind taking a bet on ZmBIZI, you can pre-order the unlocked ZmBIZI Z2 directly from its &lt;a href="https://zmbizi.com/"&gt;website &lt;/a&gt;now (the phone should be available for sale by November 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XDpTh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0c52c"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22725407/zmbizis-z2-phone-data-pay-back-fintech-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22725407/zmbizis-z2-phone-data-pay-back-fintech-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T09:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T09:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>TCL’s budget 20S and 20SE phones beat expectations</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Big phones with small price tags&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="QTp9Ss"&gt;If the TCL 20S and 20SE phones were on &lt;em&gt;The Price Is Right&lt;/em&gt;, you would probably guess much higher prices than their retail ones. With the 20S retailing for $250 and the 20SE going for $190, these sub-$300 4G phones are the real deal. They check all the boxes for what you’d want in a smartphone: they have big and bright screens, large 5,000mAh batteries, 128GB of internal storage, and “good enough” cameras. You even get a free clear silicone case inside each box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sqCcrM"&gt;TCL certainly knows a thing or two about manufacturing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22616941/tcl-6-5-series-google-tv-price-specs"&gt;budget 4K Smart TVs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493125/tcl-alto-soundbar-9-plus-8i-6-plus-3-bluetooth-airplay-google-assistant-dolby-atmos-surround-sound"&gt;affordable soundbars&lt;/a&gt;, and many other gadgets. Heck, it was already quietly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/3/21120107/tcl-blackberry-ends-phone-global-rights-date-2020"&gt;producing phones for the likes of BlackBerry, Alcatel, and Palm&lt;/a&gt; before starting its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/6/21049747/tcl-10-pro-10l-5g-phones-brand-folding-prototype-ces-2020"&gt;eponymous line in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Now it’s taking those skills building other accessibly priced gadgets to its phone line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="da4rRU"&gt;Unlike &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22560849/tcl-20-pro-5g-review-screen-battery-price-specs"&gt;the fancier TCL 20 Pro 5G&lt;/a&gt;, neither the 20S nor the 20SE has the latest and greatest processor, nor do they support 5G networking — those aren’t unsurprising omissions at these price points. But given TCL’s history, it’s no wonder the real stars of the TCL 20S and 20SE are their brilliant displays — though they each use different panels. Both phones look and feel more luxurious than they are because of their solid build quality, as well as attention to the details users really actually care about: long-lasting battery life, strong performance, ample storage, as well as ingenious design. Who says good things can’t come in budget-friendly packages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="AjyYRY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10805445"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="wvub5R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10805028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8TsFX1"&gt;The $190 20SE has a 6.82-inch display, which, at 720 pixels wide, is too low-resolution for a screen this large (720 x 1640 pixels; aspect ratio 20.5:9). I tried watching the 4K Dune trailer on YouTube, and it looked too dim and fuzzy at 720p for me to enjoy the video. Nevertheless, this display offers vibrant colors even at 50 percent brightness, whether or not you turn on the NXTVISION display optimization software (I did not see much difference either way). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1qu6nF"&gt;The higher-priced 20S has a brighter yet slightly smaller 6.67-inch screen, with a higher-resolution FHD+ LCD display than the 20SE (1080 x 2400 pixels with 20:9 aspect ratio). When I watched the same Dune trailer at 1080p on the 20S, I could actually see sharper lines and more details this time around. Both displays look bright enough outdoors that I can read text if I boost the screen to 100 percent brightness. I also appreciate how unobtrusive the pinhole front camera is on the 20S compared to the 20SE’s tear-drop design, the latter of which actually cuts into the top of the display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I6H0ZSg1qQQL_QOlehzk-1_D9ow=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911279/gsin_190125_4797_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both the TCL 20S and 20SE have relatively bright displays with vibrant colors, thanks to TCL’s television know-how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ORMeyW"&gt;Of the two models, the 20S is slightly more manageable to use. But it’s still a big enough phone that I need two hands to use it safely. It can be a bit of a reach for my fingers to navigate different parts of the screen and hold it in the same hand, so I need my other hand to balance the device. At 0.23 inches (5.84mm) taller and 0.25oz (7.1g) heavier, the 20SE is physically bigger than the 20S, but its technical components are not in the same weight class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bhqb2d"&gt;With a price that is $60 less than the 20S, TCL had to find savings in the $190 20SE anywhere it could. For one thing, the 20SE uses the lower-tier Qualcomm Snapdragon 460 chipset, whose slower processing speed can’t make up ground with 4GB of RAM. The 20S, on the other hand, is powered by the faster Qualcomm Snapdragon 665 processor and is also supported by 4GB of RAM. The difference between the two isn’t very noticeable in basic texting and social media doomscrolling, but I would occasionally have to open an app or webpage twice on the 20SE because it wouldn’t load the first time around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y23HLKFT4D2eX5y-WPCxRJk6IUc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911281/gsin_190125_4797_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL 20SE’s 13-megapixel front camera and tear-drop design cuts into its display, but you don’t notice it after awhile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DaAVol"&gt;To see what these devices are capable of, I played a couple rounds of Pokemon Unite to see how they’d fare. Both TCL phones took about as long to load the game, whereas the OnePlus 9 Pro (with a Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 chip) loaded the same round in about half the time. Since the 20SE has a lesser quality display and processor, I was not surprised that my Pikachu moved with a bit of lag. It was only slightly more responsive on the 20S, however. The 20SE’s dual speakers are also louder and buzzier than the 20S speakers, which sounded quieter but produced a more nuanced sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pTbqi4"&gt;Despite their differences, both devices offer plenty of internal storage at 128GB and give you the option to expand that storage via microSD. The 20S’ microSD slot accepts up to a 1TB card, while the 20SE only supports up to a 256GB card. Both phones run Android 11 out of the box, with a TCL skin called TCL UI. Since the 20S will get one major OS update (TCL won’t commit to the same for the 20SE) and both phones will get two years of security updates, you’ll have ample room to install these upgrades and stash your content for the next few years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CTtJ7csyZMadmbrhuKLkxFMI55E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911285/gsin_190126_4797_0013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL 20S’ integrated fingerprint sensor in the power button was a delight to use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hbu5lC"&gt;The fingerprint sensors on the 20S and 20SE deserve a special mention as they’re quick to recognize my fingerprint and unlock the phones. I especially love the fingerprint sensor that is built into the 20S’ power button, located on the right side of the phone. With just one touch, you not only wake up your phone but also unlock it in an elegant and intuitive way. The 20SE has a more traditional round fingerprint sensor on the back of the device that works just as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B6Zl0Q"&gt;Facial recognition on the 20SE can be rather useless. It either doesn’t recognize my face or asks me to touch an icon on the lock screen so that I can unlock the phone with my face, which entirely defeats the purpose of using a hands-free method to unlock. (Thankfully, you can disable this “feature.”) Facial recognition simply worked more consistently on the 20S than on the 20SE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvglcj"&gt;Both phones include a 3.5mm audio jack on top, volume rocker on the right side, non-customizable Google Assistant button on the left, plus a USB-C port and a pair of bottom-firing dual speakers. The 20S has an understated back that looks curved from various angles, but the layer of “micron-sized prismatic crystals’’ actually makes the back cover really fingerprint-resistant. The 20SE’s back cover is the complete opposite: it’s a fingerprint disaster zone, thanks to its shiny, nano-photoetched back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KfWDPMO5nGAdmxi2MR5kDvnP_1w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911288/gsin_190126_4797_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both TCL 20S and 20SE include a free clear silicone case inside each box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U2FSO2"&gt;With a 5,000mAH battery inside both phones, it was a challenge to use up that much power on deadline without doing anything out of the ordinary. My normal phone diet includes: checking my two email accounts, texting on WhatsApp and Google Hangouts, tweeting on Twitter, visiting my usual slate of websites like Reddit, as well as listening to a podcast or two. Due to the pandemic, I was home during my testing but tried to use a mix of Wi-Fi and 4G service to mimic real-world use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="40nTeP"&gt;I actually got results that are close to TCL’s claims. I used the 20S for about 31 hours on one charge (TCL suggested 36 hours on 3G/4G) and took around 2.5 hours to fully charge the device, which is hardly a “fast charge” as claimed by TCL’s product sheet. Similarly, the 20SE lasted around 32 hours on one charge, compared to TCL’s estimate of 31 hours of use on 4G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a33xGW"&gt;Don’t get too excited about the cameras on the 20S or the 20SE, though: they can take great snaps in natural light, but I wouldn’t hang these photos on my wall. Both phones have a quad-camera setup, but each model uses different sensors. While the 20S has a 64-megapixel main and a 15-megapixel front camera, and the 20SE has a 48-megapixel main and 13-megapixel front camera, these numbers don’t really say anything about the quality of their photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZeUT9L"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10802883"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NDsaah"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample photos from the TCL 20S&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zTOxVs"&gt;I snapped a bunch of wide-angle and main camera shots (of the same area) using both phones. The ones from the 20S look more balanced with plenty of details, compared to the ones from the 20SE, where the water fountain area looks more over-exposed, especially at 4x cropped zoom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qVI7ry"&gt;There’s a noticeable difference in color between the photos captured with the main cameras and the ultrawide angle cameras on both phones (8-megapixel on the 20S; 5-megapixel on the 20SE). There is also a problem with the Super Macro mode on both phones’ 2-megapixel macro cameras. Photos of the fuchsia flower look pixelated and flat, while the colors from the indoor photos of the blue hydrangea look way over-saturated in the yellow channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5newt"&gt;Based on the price point of these phones, I was surprised when any of the night shots came out somewhat presentable (I know they’re in varying degrees of blurriness). To be fair, even the photos from my Pixel 5 weren’t perfect. Both the 20S and 20SE struggled to focus with so many different light sources in the dark, and each photo required many awkward seconds to process. The 20S produced the sharper photo, while the 20SE’s photos look much less detailed, especially if you look at the lights from the office towers in Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nn5y2T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10802941"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9fTXeF"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample photos from the TCL 20SE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gDTYKb"&gt;At first glance, both front-facing cameras captured decent selfies. But I have to give the edge to the 20S’ 16-megapixel camera for the more realistic colors and brighter photos. The selfie from the 20SE’s 13-megapixel front cam just looked more over-exposed: my sunglasses looked frosted, and my skin looked unnaturally pale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DzmjQQKUh-mGOy2MMqKXfwEeRWs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911280/gsin_190125_4797_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both TCL 20S and 20SE feel solid in-hand, with nice details like nano-photoetching and fingerprint-resistant crystal coating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TNF7iu"&gt;I can’t really think of a higher quality budget phone in the $250 range that can beat the TCL 20S. It’s got all the hallmarks of a more expensive device but with a more affordable price tag. Its vibrant 6.67-inch 1080p display doesn’t look out of place next to other flagship phones, and it feels luxurious with that fingerprint-proofed layer of “micron-sized prismatic crystals’’ on its back cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="z0mh1i"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You’ll be hard-pressed to find a better phone for $250 than the 20S&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YvGFC9"&gt;Sure, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;$250 Moto G Power (2021)&lt;/a&gt; has an equally large battery and a slightly newer processor. In exchange, you get a meager 64GB of internal storage, which is a far cry from the 128GB plus microSD card slot that is offered by the 20S. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;$269 OnePlus Nord 10&lt;/a&gt; (global GSM unlocked version) is also an option. It uses a newer Snapdragon chip that is 5G-compatible but still runs Android 10 when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708720/android-12-review-features-pixel-update-software"&gt;Android 12&lt;/a&gt; is ready to drop. If you don’t care about having a 5G-ready phone right now, then the TCL 20S makes more sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1gQL3S"&gt;If you’re looking for an unlocked phone that is compatible with Verizon and most 4G GSM networks like AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile, I don’t think you can go wrong with this unlocked TCL 20S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Us9CdG"&gt;If your budget is strictly sub-$200 and won’t be using Verizon as your carrier, then TCL 20SE is a smart choice. While the $180 OnePlus Nord N100 might save you $10, you’ll lose half the amount of internal storage for minimal savings (from 128GB on the TCL 20SE to 64GB on the N100) — that’s a terrible trade-off. You’ll be happier with a big bright screen, ample storage and battery life, as well as the ability to choose any GSM network (including AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile). If you don’t mind spending an extra $60, though, the 20S is worth the upgrade — your future self will thank you.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwJrYQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Gloria Sin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="jEENJY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10805623"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DqkawM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, October 14th, 2021 at 1:05pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version of this review incorrectly referred to the TCL 20 Pro 5G as TCL 20S Pro. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22717002/tcl-20s-and-20se-review-budget-affordable-unlocked-smartphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22717002/tcl-20s-and-20se-review-budget-affordable-unlocked-smartphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T13:06:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T13:06:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Visible confirms account breaches, blames ‘outside sources’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WCZPrRgPQ1Sq7t_GHPUEAtQEi8c=/0x25:1336x916/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69989709/Screen_Shot_2021_10_13_at_9.41.35_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Visible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CCertt"&gt;Cell service provider Visible has confirmed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales"&gt;customer reports&lt;/a&gt; of attackers accessing and changing user accounts, and it has said that the breaches were carried out using usernames and passwords from “outside sources.” In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; (which you can read in full below), the Verizon-owned carrier said that it’s worked to “mitigate the issue” since it became aware of it, though it doesn’t mention exactly what measures it’s put in place to protect customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lp7Iz8"&gt;Starting earlier this week, customers of Verizon’s lower-cost service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales"&gt;were reporting unauthorized charges&lt;/a&gt; from Visible on their PayPals or credit card statements, as well as emails telling them that their accounts’ passwords or addresses had been changed. Some customers have been frustrated with a lack of response from the company, as it hasn’t sent out emails or texts about the situation and was largely silent on social media until Wednesday, when it &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Visible/status/1448322446646554633?s=20"&gt;posted a Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5oHfGB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt; If you use your Visible username &amp;amp; password across multiple accounts, including your bank/financial accounts, we recommend updating your username/password with those services. Reminder: Visible will never call &amp;amp; ask for your password, secret questions or account PINs. &lt;/p&gt;— Visible (@Visible) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Visible/status/1448322446646554633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jXgEea"&gt;In both its statement and on Twitter, the company recommends resetting your password if it’s one you’ve used for other services. It’s good advice, but the company has turned off its password reset system — it wasn’t available yesterday, and as of Wednesday morning you’ll still get an error if you try to change your password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bVp1tn"&gt;Hackers getting into accounts using passwords found elsewhere is very common, that’s why everybody (including Visible) says to use unique passwords for each service and to change your passwords in the case of a breach. Security experts also recommend using two-factor authentication, which can help protect you even if your password fails (like in a situation where you’re not able to change it). Visible, however, doesn’t support two-factor authentication, which means that its customers are still potentially open to these kinds of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M2KJYg"&gt;Here’s Visible’s full statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="zaaqzD"&gt;Visible is aware of an issue in which some member accounts were accessed and/or charged without their authorization. As soon as we were made aware of the issue, we immediately initiated a review and started deploying tools to mitigate the issue and enable additional controls to further protect our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1lE5BM"&gt;Our investigation indicates that threat actors were able to access username/passwords from outside sources, and exploit that information to login to Visible accounts. If you use your Visible username and password across multiple accounts, including your bank or other financial accounts, we recommend updating your username/password with those services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mI9x16"&gt;Protecting customer information — including securing customer accounts — is critically important to our company and our customers. As a reminder, our company will never call and ask for your password, secret questions or account PINs. If you feel your account has been compromised, please reach out to us via chat at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fvisible.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F13%2F22724592%2Fvisible-account-breach-cell-purchases-outside-sources-passwords" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;visible.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724592/visible-account-breach-cell-purchases-outside-sources-passwords"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724592/visible-account-breach-cell-purchases-outside-sources-passwords</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T05:00:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T05:00:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Realme’s extremely green GT Neo 2 flagship has a Snapdragon 870 for $425</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8aMZvd8TZfj44M3gEcbFmurSixk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987706/IMG_0172.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9TPtp3"&gt;Realme has launched its latest flagship phone for India, the GT Neo 2. It’s similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22534618/realme-gt-hands-on-europe-launch-price-specs"&gt;the impressive Realme GT&lt;/a&gt; that came to Europe a few months ago — this one is better in some ways but worse in others. Depending on your taste, you’ll probably feel quite strongly about which bucket the neon green version pictured above falls into. (It also comes in black and blue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeSjvR"&gt;While the GT has a Snapdragon 888 processor, the GT Neo 2 is built around an 870. This is basically Qualcomm’s speed-bumped version of the 865 Plus, which was itself a faster version of last year’s flagship chip — the main core now runs at 3.2GHz. Realme says the GT Neo 2’s new vapor cooling system is 30 percent larger and 20 percent more efficient, making use of stainless steel as well as copper. The phone does include 5G connectivity, though 5G networks haven’t yet been switched on in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpIDHT"&gt;The display is a little bigger than the GT’s, measuring in at 6.62 inches. It’s a 1080p OLED panel with a 120Hz refresh rate. The battery is also bigger than the GT’s at 5,000mAh, up from 4,500mAh, and the GT Neo 2 still has Realme’s 65W SuperDart fast charging. Realme says it should take 36 minutes to fill from 0 to 100 percent. There’s still no wireless charging, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633722/realme-flash-magdart-magnetic-wireless-charging-time-test"&gt;the new magnetic MagDart system&lt;/a&gt; that is so far yet to be included on any commercial device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S-3WNa8ZoP38yeyR9-QOKV_Bvo0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22923288/IMG_0171.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="n7DWcE"&gt;Like the GT, the triple camera system includes a 64-megapixel main sensor, an 8-megapixel ultrawide camera, and a 2-megapixel macro lens. Realme is pushing the GT Neo 2’s Street Photography mode, which is supposed to boost shutter response and focus performance, as well as including some film simulation filters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QB7Ezh"&gt;The Realme GT Neo 2 will be available later this week in India. It costs Rs. 31,999 (~$425) for a model with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, or you can get a 12GB/256GB version for Rs. 35,999 (~$475).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723967/realme-gt-neo2-india-announced-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723967/realme-gt-neo2-india-announced-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T21:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some of Verizon’s Visible cell network customers say they’ve been hacked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JYy2soK3rXiuStajsstFeIuJ5qg=/331x0:1081x500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987158/1500x500.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Visible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8JPEpQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 13th, 1:10PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Visible has confirmed that some accounts were accessed without authorization. Read more in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724592/visible-account-breach-cell-purchases-outside-sources-passwords"&gt;&lt;em&gt;our follow-up article&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Our original story follows below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FQCSra"&gt;Some customers of Verizon’s Visible service are using social media to say that hackers have accessed their accounts, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q6y73u/im_seriously_disappointed_with_visible_today/"&gt;changed their information&lt;/a&gt; to lock them out, and in some cases &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q6o4q4/yes_i_was_hacked_as_well_im_making_this_as_public/"&gt;even ordered phones&lt;/a&gt; using their payment info (&lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/verizon-owned-visible-network-suffers-suspected-data-breach/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;XDA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). If you’re not familiar, Visible is a cell service &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/what-visible" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;owned and operated by Verizon&lt;/a&gt; that pitches itself as a less expensive, “all-digital” network, meaning there aren’t any physical stores like you’d get with a traditional carrier. Starting on Monday, customers on both Twitter and Reddit reported en masse that they’d been getting emails from the company about changed passwords and addresses, and that they’ve &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dao0815/status/1448026781332623360?s=20"&gt;had difficulties contacting the company’s chat support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KYw5nt"&gt;Visible’s customer service account on Twitter seemingly hasn’t addressed the issue, besides &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/visiblecare/status/1448040220318961665?s=20"&gt;directing upset customers to its DMs&lt;/a&gt;. A user marked as a Visible employee on the subreddit &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q65cdl/security_update/"&gt;posted a statement on Monday&lt;/a&gt; afternoon, saying that a “small number” of accounts were affected, but that the company didn’t believe its systems had been breached. The statement did recommend that users change their passwords, but as many commenters pointed out (and as I can confirm), the password reset system currently isn’t working. Verizon didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yX8ZQb"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="reddit-card" data-card-created='"2021-10-13T01:13:44.362093+00:00"'&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q65cdl/security_update/?ref_source=embed&amp;amp;ref=share"&gt;Security Update&lt;/a&gt; from
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/"&gt;Visible&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;script async="" src="https://embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D0Ho6e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I haven’t received any emails or texts from the company about the situation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9aXBLc"&gt;I’m a Visible customer myself (I switched from T-Mobile for reasons unrelated to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633853/tmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc"&gt;its recent massive data breach&lt;/a&gt;, but am &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; thrilled to possibly have been double-owned) and so far my account doesn’t seem to be compromised. I’m able to log in online and make sure my order history doesn’t have anything untoward, and opening the app is working like normal (though I received a few errors earlier in the day). I haven’t received any emails, texts, or other communications from the company regarding this situation. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sj6f0YP8i1FoTvugJ7E9tmVjifQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22922737/IMG_2881.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The error message I received earlier trying to log into the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ofVyAc"&gt;Without much official word from the company, it’s hard to say exactly how the reported breaches happened, and what any potential hackers have access to — though we’ll keep you updated if we hear back. With many security breaches, the advice is to change your password and make sure you have two-factor authentication turned on, but Visible &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q53nk9/lack_of_2fa_on_visisble/"&gt;currently doesn’t support 2FA&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully, incidents like this where some customers are seeing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Buttered_Pecans/status/1447413221057462275?s=20"&gt;$1,000-plus charges&lt;/a&gt; on their credit cards from Visible may make that feature a higher priority.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung announces Unpacked 2 event for Wednesday Oct 20th, right after Apple and Google</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KVR4JRpTmrHFcTSVE6s5D6S9qBk=/0x0:1013x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69986975/Samsung_Galaxy_Unpacked_Part2_Static_Samsung.com.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GKa0mn"&gt;Samsung has just sent out invitations for an event it is holding online on Wednesday, October 20th at 7AM PT / 10AM ET. It’s called “Galaxy Unpacked Part 2,” which is possibly an indication that rather than all new Galaxy phones, we may be seeing iterations on existing ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLUUSo"&gt;With Samsung’s announcement, we’ll now have an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;Apple event on Monday&lt;/a&gt; (where we are expecting new MacBook Pros), &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;Google’s Pixel 6 launch on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, and now Samsung’s apparently smaller event on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqhR10"&gt;In addition to the invite’s image, Samsung’s newsroom post announcing the event hints at some kind of personalization for Galaxy devices: “Our users are multifaceted and live life in so many colorful, interesting, and unique ways. As such, the technology they use every day should reflect their individuality. Join Galaxy Unpacked Part 2 on October 20 to see how Samsung is opening up new experiences for self-expression through technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="85GIiz"&gt;That could mean anything, but it does seem to hint at new colors of the Galaxy phones or maybe even a full-on customization option. I could imagine building a Z Flip 3 with my choice of colors on each side of the fold, for example, and the teaser image may hint at just that. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21407750/samsungs-galaxy-z-fold-2-price-release-date-hinge-screen-durability"&gt;With the Z Fold 2,&lt;/a&gt; Samsung offered customers the option to choose their own accent color for the hinge, though that option went away on the Z Fold 3 (thus far, anyway). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="H85ZA6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s going to be a very busy week&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FWsqIi"&gt;Of course, no customization program has come &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/5/4588922/moto-x-review"&gt;close to the original Moto X&lt;/a&gt;, which let people chose any number of different color options and even materials for their phone — including bamboo. It seems unlikely that Samsung will be willing to go that far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0UJLu"&gt;What seems even more unlikely is the Galaxy S21 FE, a lower-cost “fan edition” of the Galaxy S21 that’s been kicking around the rumor mill for a while now. It’s less likely mainly because the S21 FE is currently in a kind of limbo where it’s either been delayed or cancelled because of the chip shortage. &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s22-delayed-galaxy-s21-fe-quiet-launch-january/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sammobile&lt;/em&gt; reports that Samsung is still considering a January launch for the S21 FE&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="veyIZQ"&gt;Regardless of what Samsung announces on Wednesday the 20th, it will have a hard time getting attention after all the Sturm (Apple) and Drang (Google) the previous two days. Though perhaps picking Wednesday is Samsung’s strategic attempt to wrest some interest away from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/9/22718007/google-pixel-6-leak-teases-magic-eraser-camera-five-years-android-security-updates"&gt;the Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LnDwLD"&gt;Speaking of it being a busy week, we also have &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s 10 year event called &lt;a href="https://www.voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/Podcast"&gt;On The Verge&lt;/a&gt; on Friday and Saturday. If you’re in New York City, tickets are available at a &lt;a href="https://www.voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/Podcast"&gt;discount with code $99NOW right here&lt;/a&gt;. This leaves Thursday the 21st open for another tech company to announce something. Has anybody heard from OnePlus lately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLbaaV"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723435/samsung-announces-unpacked-2-event-galaxy-colors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723435/samsung-announces-unpacked-2-event-galaxy-colors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T09:01:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T09:01:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Meet Nokia G300, the $199 5G phone for Tracfone and Straight Talk customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/omd8QiOl4gfCJTEZBwjzk-LNN38=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983632/Nokia_G300_Lifestyle_Image__5_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G300 is a 5G-enabled phone with a 6.52-inch LCD and 4,470mAH battery.&lt;/em&gt; | HMD Global&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bFxqDG"&gt;Why should postpaid mobile customers have all the 5G fun? HMD Global, the manufacturer behind new Nokia phones, is announcing its most affordable 5G phone yet for Tracfone and Straight Talk Wireless’ prepaid customers — the Nokia G300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k0vG31"&gt;Like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557433/t-mobile-revvl-v-5g-price-screen-specs-availability"&gt;T-Mobile’s $199 REVVL V Plus 5G&lt;/a&gt;, the Nokia G300 doesn’t try to wow you with flagship-level specs but offers the bread-and-butter features you’ll care about at an affordable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFQXa5"&gt;One of the most useful features of the G300 is its fingerprint scanner. It is integrated with the power button so that you can inconspicuously unlock your phone while pressing the same button to wake it up. Of course, you can also use your face to unlock the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ceh2mc"&gt;It has a reasonably large 4,470mAh battery, which Nokia claims will last about two days before needing a charge. It also mixes in some old tech with the new: a 3.5mm audio jack for your wired headphones, radio antenna, NFC, and it runs Android 11 out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sh3NKs"&gt;The G300’s 16-megapixel rear camera has a relatively large aperture (f/1.8) that, coupled with its 2-megapixel depth sensor and 5-megapixel ultrawide camera (f/2.2), already sounds like a step up from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557433/t-mobile-revvl-v-5g-price-screen-specs-availability"&gt;REVVL V Plus 5G’s camera&lt;/a&gt;. Surprisingly, this phone can record 1080p videos at 60 frames per second, using electronic image stabilization (EIS) to help reduce your hand’s natural shakiness. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bRH3WfH1pu0l4CXBDn1-vbECPkE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920346/Nokia_G300_Product_Image__3_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: HMD Global&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Nokia G300 variant in charcoal, with 64GB of storage and 4GB RAM, will be available for sale on October 19th, 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TZJHup"&gt;Of course, the G300’s low price tag comes at a price. It has a 6.52-inch HD Plus LCD display that is quite low resolution for its size (720 x 1600 pixel, 20:9 aspect ratio). Like the similarly priced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547482/oneplus-nord-n200-5g-review-screen-price-specs"&gt;OnePlus Nord N200 5G&lt;/a&gt;, it only comes with 64GB of internal storage, which means you’ll need to invest in a microSD card to expand this phone’s storage capacity. The G300 is also powered by the same 5G-compatible Qualcomm Snapdragon 480 processor as the N200 and is supported by 4GB of RAM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8iuRP"&gt;While the Nokia G300 is 5G-ready, this variant is only capable of sub-6GHz speeds, which means it’s only compatible with T-Mobile’s 5G network, not AT&amp;amp;T or Verizon’s 5G technologies. Normally, when you bring your own device to these two mobile virtual network operators (MVNOs), you get to choose which carrier to use because they work with all the carriers, but not in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JZfilG"&gt;You can order the $199 Nokia G300 from Tracfone and Straight Talk Wireless on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;same day the new Pixel 6 phones will be announced&lt;/a&gt;. This configuration — in charcoal with 64GB storage and 4GB RAM — will be available for purchase directly from both companies on October 19th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lK6dB4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9hQNp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQFLRB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722036/nokia-g300-prepaid-5g-straight-talk-tracfone-price-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722036/nokia-g300-prepaid-5g-straight-talk-tracfone-price-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
