<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-04T17:23:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T17:23:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T17:23:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s Google partnership now includes an ‘exclusive’ cloud storage plan</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K3IOnO6iMCZa3k03V7fnxzghcqk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950406/ajohnson_210813_4713_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0u1gtV"&gt;T-Mobile and Google &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fun-carrier%2Ft-mobile-google-one&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F4%2F22709452%2Ft-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;have announced&lt;/a&gt; they’re offering an “exclusive” plan with 500GB of Google One cloud storage for T-Mobile customers starting October 12th. The plan will cost $5 per month, the latest addition in an ongoing partnership between the search giant and the mobile carrier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXle9c"&gt;Google offers Google One plans &lt;a href="https://one.google.com/about/plans"&gt;in a variety of sizes&lt;/a&gt; but, up until this point, didn’t have a 500GB tier, jumping from 200GB for $2.99 per month straight to 2TB for $9.99 per month. Anyone with a Google account gets 15GB for free, but T-Mobile’s offer could work as a nice middle ground if you’ve started to store more of your files in Google Drive and Google Photos. T-Mobile also says the plan can be shared with up to five other people, whether or not they have T-Mobile accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cvvIHL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile and Google started collaborating earlier this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IsXeoD"&gt;T-Mobile and Google first announced their partnership &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356918/t-mobile-google-android-services-rcs-youtube-tv-pixel-storage-backup"&gt;at the end of March this year&lt;/a&gt; for a set of still undisclosed financial terms. T-Mobile agreed to support Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/12/18137937/rcs-rich-communication-service-messaging-explainer-what-is-google-chat"&gt;messaging standard of choice, RCS&lt;/a&gt;, offer Google’s Android Messages as the default messaging app, and push YouTube TV and YouTube Premium through a variety of different deals. At the time, neither company included a deal to push Google One as T-Mobile’s official backup method for Android phones. But lo and behold, on October 12th, T-Mobile will now have an option for that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="btQTKt"&gt;Customers can sign up for the Google One deal through T-Mobile. The company says it’ll offer a 30-day free trial before it starts charging $5 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709452/t-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709452/t-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 9s get new look and features in OxygenOS 12 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 has a slightly smaller screen" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Igjpap2aW3dgzQiRZWP61guC9E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69949662/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0077_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PZspA1"&gt;Now that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538105/oneplus-oppo-merge-integration-ownership-bbk"&gt;OnePlus is a sub-brand of the Oppo family&lt;/a&gt;, the two companies not only merged their R&amp;amp;D departments in early 2021, but they are also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560765/oneplus-oxygenos-coloros-oppo-android-updates"&gt;consolidating code for their two Android-based operating systems&lt;/a&gt;. While OxygenOS 12 will be used on global OnePlus phones, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344054/oneplus-9-oppo-coloros-in-china-hydrogenos"&gt;ColorOS 12 will only be on China-only&lt;/a&gt; Oppo and OnePlus phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z2pODX"&gt;Alongside the release of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708992/android-12-aosp-available-download-install"&gt;Android 12 to AOSP today&lt;/a&gt;, OnePlus is releasing the first open beta of OxygenOS 12 to the OnePlus 9 and OnePlus 9 Pro now, while those with older models will have to wait for a later update. Once this version is deemed stable, it is likely a full version will be released within a month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;according to XDA Developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="p4SNh5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Android 12 review: it’s mostly about the looks","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708720/android-12-review-features-pixel-update-software"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="479hSr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Look&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i3mUnD"&gt;The new and improved OxygenOS 12 is colorful and minimalist like “&lt;a href="https://jamesturrell.com/"&gt;James Turrell’s&lt;/a&gt; Light and Space artwork,” as explained &lt;a href="https://forums.oneplus.com/threads/oxygenos-12-open-beta-1-for-oneplus-9-series.1502946/"&gt;in its forum post&lt;/a&gt; announcing this release. OxygenOS 12 shares some of the same design languages as ColorOS 12 and Android 12 by extension. All three OSes make liberal use of white space, as well as large sans-serif typography to “enhance readability and ease of use.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PoGgdw"&gt;OxygenOS 12 also follows the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;Material You aesthetic&lt;/a&gt;, where the new icons use simple lines, and new widgets use shapes to make information and actions more clear and accessible to a diverse group of users. Just like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679087/oppo-oneplus-coloros-12-update-announced-release-date"&gt;ColorOS 12&lt;/a&gt;, the OnePlus software is enhanced with more shadows and subtle gradients to give OxygenOS 12 a more premium look. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QM3BN5-sJCAvznQ-UQDo0IcSwac=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900111/darkmodes_3up.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;OnePlus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OxygenOS 12 offers three levels of Dark Mode to give you more control over your phone’s UI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="orGxgt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hviAhT"&gt;In addition to its new look, OxgyenOS 12 also learned some new tricks to improve your experience with OnePlus phones. If you’ve been playing with the developer preview of Android 12 on the OnePlus 9 series, you’ll be happy to know these features have made it into the open beta of OxygenOS 12:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="t5RKxn"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Private Safe&lt;/strong&gt;: This feature isolates sensitive files to a secured part of your phone, where you can safely store and protect specific photos, videos, audios, and documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yprYw6"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Updated OnePlus Shelf &amp;amp; OnePlus Scout&lt;/strong&gt;: The handy Shelf has been enhanced with even more widgets: from notes, step counting, weather, to the calculator, according to &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-dp-2-oneplus-9-pro-oxygenos/"&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/a&gt;. You can even search for anything on your phone using OnePlus Scout, which is now part of the Shelf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WDehnM"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Zen Mode &amp;amp; World Life Balance 2.0:&lt;/strong&gt; First popularized by OnePlus’ Indian users, both modes help you manage work-life balance by separating your personal and work accounts. You can set up different profiles with different Wi-Fi networks, with different app notifications and messages depending on the time of day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1EPmDl"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dark Mode:&lt;/strong&gt; This lets you choose between three levels of dark mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="t6WlFY"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note app: &lt;/strong&gt;This updated app now lets you doodle as well as type out your thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9dG93J"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Canvas AOD 2.0: &lt;/strong&gt;The app lets that you create a wireframe image on your lockscreen, based on your wallpaper, is back with more functionality. It now includes more brushes and lines for you to use, as well as more photos and effects available to support your artistic vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="dY7zR8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10789206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4nDAAI"&gt;It’s possible that this is the end of the road for OxygenOS, as the two companies could more fully integrate their software into one, rather than maintain two OSes. If that’s the case, OnePlus will hopefully be able to bring some of its most popular features like the Canvas AOD 2.0 and Work Life Balance 2.0 mode to future ColorOS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxTi9w"&gt;If you have a OnePlus 9 or 9 Pro and want to try out this open beta of OxygenOS 12, then head to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.in%2Fsupport%2Fsoftwareupgrade&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F4%2F22704578%2Foneplus-9-pro-oxygen-os-12-color-os-android-12-skin" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus’ Updates and Downloads page&lt;/a&gt; to download it onto your computer, and follow the instructions to install the software onto your OnePlus phone.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704578/oneplus-9-pro-oxygen-os-12-color-os-android-12-skin"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704578/oneplus-9-pro-oxygen-os-12-color-os-android-12-skin</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-01T16:47:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-01T16:47:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to switch languages using the Android Gboard keyboard</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hMP-VXXAwqGtVMo3s3cxKrQrupo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69939082/akrales_190903_3635_0219.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dp2uwu"&gt;Learning a new language on an Android device? If the language uses a different alphabet or employs accents that your primary language does not, you may need to add a new software keyboard to your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ssqMfc"&gt;Luckily, Google’s standard Gboard keyboard includes a plethora of language-related keyboards; at last count, it offered &lt;a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/gboard-500-languages-935836/"&gt;over 500 languages over 40 different writing systems&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve already installed Gboard in the US, you’re likely already set up with US English. But it’s not difficult to add one or more new keyboards and quickly switch from one language to another. Here’s how to install and use one or more of the many languages available. (Note: this was tried out using a Pixel 3 phone and Android 12; your interface may vary.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xf1duA"&gt;First, you need to get to the “Languages” page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LGBXTY"&gt;One way is to open an app such as email or chat and tap in an area where you can type in order to bring up the keyboard. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PSsHzl"&gt;Tap on the settings icon (the one that looks like a gear) just above the keyboard. If you don’t see it, click on the arrow on the left just above the keyboard to bring up the toolbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LP3vX2"&gt;Select “Languages.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Click on the gear icon above the keyboard." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qu9saZuI2orPNmInerzInO1hCK4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894517/Screenshot_20211001_155057.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click on the gear icon above the keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The languages you are using are listed on the “Languages page.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ovDpoVdI47-LJKfF2CHVqMsj6gI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894520/Screenshot_20210930_164122.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your languages are listed on the “Languages page.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rqnSFe"&gt;You can also get to the page from your Android device’s main settings menu. From the settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yW7sE8"&gt;Select “System.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GYny36"&gt;Select “Languages &amp;amp; input” &amp;gt; “On-screen keyboard” &amp;gt; “Gboard” &amp;gt; “Languages.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="wmVFz8"&gt;Once you’ve reached the “Languages” page, you can add a new language:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yC7lsy"&gt;Tap on “Add keyboard” at the bottom of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ww33gw"&gt;Scroll to the language that you want to add and tap it. (It’s a long list, so you might save some time by using the search icon on the top right of the screen.) If you’ve been using a language-learning or other language-related app recently, the one you want may already be on top under “Suggested languages.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The “Add keyboard” list is very, very long." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TEM3khB2V0MuK2HyvlQYfagklRM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894524/Screenshot_20210930_163837.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “Add keyboard” list is very, very long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You may have a choice of several types of keyboards." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cK8372CgjSIHQsJWQY05EQHUPhs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894525/Screenshot_20210930_163903.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You may have a choice of several types of keyboards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="rW5Whu"&gt;Depending on the language, you may be able to choose from a list of several types of keyboards on top of the screen. (For example, you may be able to opt for a QWERTY or Dvorak keyboard, or set handwriting options.) The most likely suggestion will be first, but you can swipe across to see others that are available. On the same page, under “Language settings,” the “Multilingual typing” option lets you choose to be given word suggestions from more than one language while you type. (Whether it’s available depends on which language you’re adding.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kvKuRC"&gt;When you’re finished, tap the “Done” button. You’ll be brought back to the “Languages” page where you’ll see the new language listed. Tap the left arrow at the top left corner to leave the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="JxQ4bk"&gt;You’ll now see the keyboard’s language named on the space bar. (If you enabled multilingual typing, you’ll see abbreviations of both language names.) In addition, there will now be a globe icon to the left of the keyboard instead of the emoji icon. (The emoji icon can now be accessed via a long press on the comma key.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SPywDn"&gt;To change keyboards, tap on the globe; your keyboard will switch to the next in line. You can also long press on the space bar and select the language you want from the pop-up menu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Multilingual typing will give you suggestions from both your languages." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MCAuFjv2LANZtoP6Q09KCWvRpig=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894539/Screenshot_20210930_164730.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multilingual typing will give you suggestions from both your languages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Long-press on the space bar to change language settings." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UNEv4XPFYkkRrRuYNWbCha7EwRw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894542/Screenshot_20210930_164746.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long press on the space bar to change language settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VzlAdz"&gt;If you’re no longer using one of your languages and you want to remove it from the list: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="AruZjo"&gt;Long press the space bar to get the “Change keyboard” menu. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Xm9Az0"&gt;Tap on “Language settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="FX7J8F"&gt;Find the language you no longer need, and swipe to the left to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8zQQlZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 1st, 2021, 4:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on January 3rd, 2020 and has been updated to allow for updates in the Android OS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22704840/gboard-keyboard-google-languages-android-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22704840/gboard-keyboard-google-languages-android-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T12:18:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T12:18:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>How Microsoft’s Surface Duo 2 compares with Samsung’s flagship foldable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dHCahZ1ArfRO8wI2MKOd-lbZK5o=/0x0:1361x907/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69931863/Microsoft_Surface_Duo_2_Lifestyle_Press_Image_White_Colorway.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Duo 2 works with Microsoft’s lineup of Surface Pens, including the Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/em&gt;. | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uvp11o"&gt;It’s official: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21428763/microsoft-surface-duo-review"&gt;troubled Surface Duo&lt;/a&gt; is now last-gen. Microsoft announced its successor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686707/microsoft-surface-duo-2-phone-design-specs-features-photos-hands-on"&gt;Surface Duo 2&lt;/a&gt;, during its recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684950/microsoft-surface-event-biggest-announcements-pro-8-duo-studio-laptop"&gt;fall Surface event&lt;/a&gt;, capping off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22593992/microsoft-surface-duo-2-triple-camera-leak-photos"&gt;months of rumors&lt;/a&gt; and introducing the device alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685923/microsoft-surface-pro-8-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686010/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt;, and a bevy of new devices designed to take advantage of &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/22557060/microsoft-windows-11-hands-on-preview"&gt;Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="84OsSx"&gt;The new Android-based smartphone &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684814/microsoft-surface-duo-2-price-specs-features-release-date"&gt;starts at $1,499.99&lt;/a&gt; — $100 less than the original — and launches on October 20th in multiple configurations. It retains the hinged design of its predecessor — only this time, it comes equipped with a more thought-out camera system, 5G support, and a modern processor that brings it more in line with flagships from Samsung, Xiaomi, and OnePlus. And while it’s not a foldable in the traditional sense — it’s outfitted with two screens, not one — it’s not in a class of its own, either. Blame the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22638257/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review"&gt;Galaxy Z Fold 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2upDAP"&gt;The Fold 3 recently set the bar for what foldable phones could achieve, bringing with it better multitasking, a water-resistant build, and a refined display that’s a notable step up from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18498904/samsung-galaxy-fold-review-screen-broken-issue-durability-foldable-phone-video-performance-price"&gt;original model&lt;/a&gt; released in 2019. But is Samsung’s premium foldable a match for the forthcoming Duo 2? After all, Samsung’s foldable is markedly different from Microsoft’s when it comes to design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nFo0sv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best phone to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone"},{"title":"The best smartphone you can buy under $500","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9wv8PG"&gt;The Fold 3 features a smaller, 6.2-inch display that covers the entire front of the device. It also contains a flexible, 7.6-inch OLED on the inside, which unfurls as you open the phone with the aid of an aluminum hinge. There’s still a small gap between the two sides when closed, however, which is visible on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22631125/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review"&gt;Galaxy Z Flip 3&lt;/a&gt; as well. The latter phone — an entirely different device from the Fold 3 we’re comparing here — also features a foldable display, only the device is smaller, folds vertically, and retails for $700 less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGVNFp"&gt;The Duo 2 doesn’t rely on a flexible display. Like its predecessor, it uses two separate, 5.8-inch OLED panels that amount to 8.3 inches when viewed together, with a large bezel running between them. The hinge connecting the two displays allows you to fold the phone in half with the displays on the outside so you can use the device one-handed, though the phone’s large camera bump means they’ll never close completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dktYqz"&gt;The screens — while the selling point — aren’t everything, however. Below, we’ve compared the Fold 3 and Duo 2 in more detail ahead of our full Duo 2 review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="f3yzsB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10768369"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tqSzKP"&gt;Spec-for-spec, in some ways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="leOvHG"&gt;To put it mildly: the original Surface 2 had its shortcomings. The camera was atrocious, the software buggy, and Microsoft was still charging a starting price of $1,399 for just the device, a staggering number when you consider the faults. And while it was seemingly released premature, it was innovative, so much so &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Dieter Bohn hoped — like me — that we’d see a second iteration of the smartphone down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fJoj2U"&gt;Well, here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Microsoft Surface Duo 2." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8nmPdR4lB6wNvS4fhfJT8IIlQ7g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22868426/bfarsace_210921_4770_0049.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Duo 2 features thinner bezels and the same processor found as the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xYD311"&gt;On paper, the Surface Duo 2 looks to address many of the aforementioned problems. It’s equipped with the same high-end Snapdragon 888 processor found in the Galaxy Z Fold 3, which is Qualcomm’s latest chipset and the brains behind almost every Android flagship released this year, from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;OnePlus 9&lt;/a&gt;. Like the Z Fold 3, the second-gen Duo will be available in both 128GB and 512GB storage configurations when it launches next month, as well as an additional 128GB variant. The Duo 2 only features 8GB of RAM, however, compared to the Fold 3’s 12GB. Software optimization will certainly play a role in how efficient the phone is at multitasking, but the Fold 3 has the upper hand spec-wise. Both phones also support 5G connectivity, Wi-Fi 6, and NFC for contactless payments — something the original Duo did not offer — along with either Bluetooth 5.0 or 5.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yrhOLY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10697006"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P0VneZ"&gt;Battery capacity tells a similar story. The Fold 3 packs in a 4,400mAh battery, which, in our testing, lasted a full day with roughly four hours of screen time. The Duo 2 features dual batteries that add up to a capacity of 4,449mAh, and Samsung claims they should provide 15.5 hours of local video playback and 28 hours of talk time. Both models also support fast charging and USB-C; however, the Fold 3 additionally supports wireless charging, whereas the Duo 2 does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wgjzwo"&gt;We’ll have a better sense of how far that battery capacity will get you once we’ve tested the device, but the increased capacity on this year’s Duo should help it compensate for the 90Hz display and added 5G support. The two batteries inside the original Duo only added up to a mere 3,577mAh, yet we routinely made it through a full day on a single charge. We’re hoping the same can be said of the Duo 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lzokQU"&gt;Displays on display&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hVp6H0sYuZFLx34hLpwM1Vyynb4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22801025/dbohn_210820_4722_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Z Fold 3 houses a vibrant, 7.6-inch OLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate on the inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xtppzUsJYDXp1-B7atPOX1httEg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869992/Surface_Duo_2_with_Pen_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The slight curviture of the Duo 2’s displays allows them to act as a notification panel when closed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XUe60X"&gt;Like all foldables, the defining characteristic of the Duo 2 and Fold 3 are the displays, which afford each smartphone more screen real estate and allow them to function a bit more akin to a tablet when opened. On the inside, the Fold 3 features a bright, 7.6-inch OLED screen with 2208 x 1768 resolution and a 120Hz refresh rate for smoother scrolling. It also sports a 6.2-inch display on the cover with 2268 x 832 resolution and, again, a 120Hz refresh rate. In our testing, we found both displays to be a vast improvement over earlier iterations, with the inner display showcasing an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619139/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-flip-screen-durability-waterproof-aluminum"&gt;added level of durability&lt;/a&gt; thanks to Samsung’s custom aluminum alloy. The exterior display on the Fold 3 also means you don’t need to open the device in order to use it, which renders it a little closer to a traditional phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jpyKGf"&gt;The Duo 2, however, takes a different approach. Inside, you’ll find two 5.8-inch OLED panels, each with 1344 x 1892 resolution and a 90Hz refresh rate. When opened, the dual panels create an 8.3-inch display with 2688 x 1892 resolution, with a bezel running between the two. The Duo 2 doesn’t offer an exterior cover like the Fold 3; however, the curved glass on the edges of the display does showcase the time and some notifications when the phone is closed, giving you some basic info at a glance. The 360-degree hinge also allows you to open the Duo 2 like a book or prop it up like a tent, providing an added level of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7An523"&gt;The outward design of both models is as varied as their approach to the display. The Fold 3 is relatively tall and narrow when closed, weighing in at 271 grams. The hinge-reliant Duo 2 is slightly shorter and heavier at 284 grams, though; it’s also thinner — so thin, in fact, that Microsoft claims the Duo 2 is the thinnest 5G device on the market (it’s only 11 millimeters thick when closed). It’s not as thin as the original Duo, which measures 9.9 millimeters at the hinge, but it’s close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQhJ4k"&gt;Additionally, both smartphones use Gorilla Glass Victus, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21335252/corning-gorilla-glass-victus-drop-scratch-resistant-apple-samsung"&gt;Corning claims can resist&lt;/a&gt; a six-foot drop while continuing to ward off scratches. The Fold 3, however, takes things further with IPX8 water resistance, meaning it can be fully submerged in up to half a meter of water for up to 30 minutes. We don’t anticipate most people will rush out to dunk their phones, but it’s nice to know it can handle an unforeseen spill or a little rain. The Duo 2 only offers an IPX1 rating, which, honestly, is effectively nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="o3WpTd"&gt;Android 11 all around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SXHsG4"&gt;Unsurprisingly, the Duo 2 and Z Fold 3 are also similar on the software front. Whereas the first-gen Duo launched with Android 10 has yet to receive Android 11 — Microsoft says it will arrive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690003/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11-update-release-date"&gt;before the end of the year&lt;/a&gt; — the Duo 2 ships with a customized version of the latter designed for better multitasking. The Fold 3 also runs on Android 11, albeit with some small visual and interface tweaks courtesy of Samsung’s custom One UI 3 skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The multitasking software on the Z Fold 3 is much more flexible than before." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S79WEKoUZ0TCUgJpSBFyqUC_56g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22801132/Screenshot_20210823_123216_Twitter.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Samsung’s One UI 3, multitasking on the Z Fold 3 is actually an enjoyable experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o8ot3Q"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21355777/samsung-android-os-update-promise-galaxy-phones-3-generations"&gt;Samsung said&lt;/a&gt; recent Galaxy devices will receive support for three generations of Android updates, and as such, the Fold 3 is set to receive routine Android OS updates alongside monthly security patches for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;next four years&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft has promised timely updates for the Duo 2, but it’s still unclear as to what that looks like. A year after its debut, the original Duo remains buggy, despite Microsoft having shipped a number of updates to address multitasking and gesture issues. Samsung has a better track record when it comes to issuing software updates in a timely manner, a likely boon for the Fold 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wc7Wyb"&gt;Both smartphones are designed for multitasking and productivity, however, and their software reflects that. The Duo 2 can run two apps side by side or one app that can expand across both displays. The Duo 2 also boasts compatibility with Microsoft’s lineup of Surface Pens, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt;, which can magnetically dock and charge wirelessly when paired with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690565/surface-duo-2-pen-cover-price-release-date-slim-pen"&gt;optional Surface Duo 2 Pen Cover&lt;/a&gt; ($65). The Fold 3 offers a similar set of functionality thanks to features like Flex mode and App Pair, as well as the Fold-specific S Pen, which is sold separately and also requires a special case for storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CHi0cu"&gt;Camera components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s1cDvT"&gt;Camera-wise, neither model is aimed at photography enthusiasts. Microsoft’s next foldable may be a massive step up from its first-gen counterpart and, on paper, a slight cut above the Fold 3, but it’s still more midrange than flagship. That said, both the Duo 2 and the Fold 3 feature a three-camera array on the rear, with 12-megapixel sensors for wide and telephoto. The Duo 2, however, also includes a higher-resolution ultrawide camera (16MP compared to the Fold 3’s 12MP sensor), as well as optical image stabilization on the wide and ultrawide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CGlDO6"&gt;Aperature, on the other hand, is nearly the same across both devices, with the wide-angle on the Duo 2 being slightly faster at f/1.7. We’ll have to wait until we can put the Duo 2 through its paces before we make a final judgment call, but if its three-camera array performs anything like that on the Fold 3, it’s still not going to compete with the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;Apple’s iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zdTA_zVVycc6UWK44TP4PXTJjG8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22880543/Surface_Duo_2_Photography_2.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The three-camera array on the Duo 2 looks to be a significant step up from the 11MP sensor on the original.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="77SP3x"&gt;On the front, the Duo 2 sports a 12MP shooter with an f/2.0 aperture. The Fold 3 sports a 10MP selfie camera with an f/2.2 on the cover, along with a 4MP under-display camera on the interior, which is equal parts terrible and distracting given the distinct moire effect the experimental feature creates at certain viewing angles. Both devices can also capture 1080p and 4K video footage at 30 and 60fps, as well as slow-motion video at up to 240fps. The Fold 3 goes a bit further with support for 720p, slow-motion video at 960fps, and 4K hyperlapse videos at 30fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0aFvlU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10763735"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="l8SCbz"&gt;Sky-high pricing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="di4uXg"&gt;Let’s face it: neither foldable is cheap — far from it. The 128GB base configuration of the Surface Duo 2 will &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeSurfaceDuo2092221&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-duo-2%2F9408kgxp4xjl%3Frtc%3D1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;run you $1,499.99&lt;/a&gt;, with the 256GB and 512GB models retailing for $1,599.99 and $1,799.99, respectively. Like the original model, Microsoft’s latest foldable will be available in glacier white, in addition to a new obsidian black colorway. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684018/microsoft-surface-duo-2-preorder-how-to-buy-price-release-date"&gt;Preorders are already underway&lt;/a&gt;, with shipments expected to go out before the phone’s launch on October 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kWLNiX"&gt;The Galaxy Fold 3 is even more expensive. The 256GB base model &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfGyXdxDbnR#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;retails for $1,799.99&lt;/a&gt; and is currently available in one of three colors: phantom green, phantom black, and phantom silver. The 512GB configuration runs $1,899.99; however, the larger model is only available in phantom black. Like the Duo 2, there are carrier deals, trade-in discounts, and payment plans available for the Fold 3; however, most kickbacks come in the form of credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hCNlhE"&gt;While not the focal point of this comparison, there’s also the Galaxy Flip 3 to consider. The device’s internal display might be smaller, but the phone still features a Snapdragon 888 processor, 8GB of RAM, and a water-resistant build. It also &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfGy2XM0TC2#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starts at $1,000&lt;/a&gt;, meaning it retails for around the same price as many high-end, non-folding phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZgrDZ5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how much that free iPhone really costs ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22684911/iphone-13-true-cost-of-free-phone-iphone-13-pro"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="uxDVDs"&gt;The bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dGDDHc"&gt;On paper, Microsoft’s Surface Duo 2 shows a lot of promise, particularly when compared to its predecessor. It has a modern, high-end processor and upgraded camera system, along with a bigger battery, larger displays, and 5G support. These are welcome upgrades, but we won’t have a concrete idea as to how well they perform until we can do an in-depth review. There’s also the question of longevity and support — will Microsoft truly update the Duo 2 in a timely fashion, or will it go the way of the Duo and only receive the occasional software patch and security update? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YhyK87"&gt;The Galaxy Z Fold 3, meanwhile, is the best foldable you can buy right now. The base configuration of the Fold 3 is $300 more than the starting price of the Duo 2, but it comes equipped with similar specs, along with a 120Hz display, wireless charging, and a waterproof, IPX8-rated design. The latter two features are now more of the norm than the exception, and it’s a shame Microsoft didn’t incorporate either with the Duo 2. Still, if you see no need for a display with a higher refresh rate or any of the aforementioned perks that come with the Fold 3, Microsoft’s second-gen foldable might be worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sDMXQJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22688370/microsoft-surface-duo-2-vs-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-comparison-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22688370/microsoft-surface-duo-2-vs-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-comparison-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T08:43:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T08:43:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Backbone releases free adapter and 3D-print files for iPhone 13 Pro camera bump issue</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BackBone One" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5pTzJYYDGcJV2im_LTmgwbvwrlc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913581/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hk174V"&gt;Backbone Labs has acknowledged the issue that hampers the use of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"&gt;excellent iPhone gaming controller&lt;/a&gt; with the new iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691301/iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-backbone-one-gaming-controller-accessory"&gt;As we noticed last week&lt;/a&gt;, the iPhone 13 Pro’s thicker camera bump means the phone doesn’t sit neatly in the Backbone One controller, either sticking out on one side or causing the bridge on the back to slightly buckle. It’s not unusable, but it’s not great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uV1mXY"&gt;“We spent a tremendous amount of time meticulously crafting every surface of Backbone One (both bits and atoms) and even designing universal support for the iPhones available when it was released,” a Backbone representative wrote in an &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Backbone/comments/pvhl98/backbone_one_iphone_13_pro_pro_max_adapter/"&gt;official post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, we’re disappointed in the situation at hand. Several folks on the team even upgraded to 13 Pro Max for a better gaming experience, and while the fit may be acceptable for some users, it’s not as good as we’d like it to be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WquSRF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Backbone One is a stunning controller that turns your iPhone into a more capable gaming device","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0nAvVr"&gt;To address this, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fplaybackbone.com%2Fadapter%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22695887%2Fbackbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Backbone has designed an adapter&lt;/a&gt; that is intended to improve the experience with the iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. Ordering one will require the latest version of the Backbone app. Once you boot into it, you should see a pop-up that will guide you through the process of ordering one. Otherwise, you can open the app, then go to Settings, find the Help button, then click “Request Adapter.” It’s free to order, but you’ll pay shipping fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZFzsm"&gt;Backbone has also released open-source 3D printable files for the adapter, if you’d prefer to go that route. &lt;a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4977709"&gt;The files are hosted on Thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;. It says on its site that “UPS offers printing services, there are tons of free local printers at libraries, and websites like Shapeways allow you to order prints to your doorstep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwUaUy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 30th, 8:42AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Backbone has added a support page that details the installation process for the iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max adapter. Additionally, it has steps for Backbone One owners, both current and new, to redeem a free adapter or 3D print it themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dish bets on 5G by making its own $279 5G phone for Boost Mobile</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2RfU8j1kHb_dlt0G11qeknp5YOw=/90x0:1710x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69930334/Celero_Option2_1800x1080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;DISH and Boost Mobile hope to bring in new 5G customers with their own phone, the Celero5G.&lt;/em&gt; | DISH/Boost Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="x0s0B3"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;acquiring Boost Mobile&lt;/a&gt; as part of the Sprint and T-Mobile merger in 2020 and snapping up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319621/dish-network-acquires-republic-wireless-5g-cell-carrier-mvno-t-mobile"&gt;Republic Wireless for its 5G network&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, Dish is finally ready to turn Boost Mobile into the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587790/t-mobile-sprint-acquisition-dish-promises"&gt;fourth wireless carrier that the FCC envisioned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zMGgqB"&gt;Its opening salvo? The satellite television provider is introducing an exclusive budget 5G phone for Boost Mobile’s prepaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="czzVHh"&gt;The Celero5G is a “custom-built phone” for Boost Mobile, according to its spokesperson. Just like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557433/t-mobile-revvl-v-5g-price-screen-specs-availability"&gt;T-Mobile’s Revvl&lt;/a&gt; or AT&amp;amp;T’s Radiant, it has unique branding that you won’t find anywhere else. For a carrier that is trying to expand its user base, this is certainly an unusual way to get there. After all, most other carriers try to dangle the latest flagship phones from Apple and Android to lure you to sign up for their expensive post-paid service plans, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22678111/iphone-13-carrier-promotions-new-signups"&gt;deluge of “free” iPhone 13 offers&lt;/a&gt; from the Big 3 carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOEGoM"&gt;“With LG leaving the mobile device market and creating seismic shifts in the supplier landscape, we saw an opportunity,” said a Boost Mobile spokesperson. “The departure of LG left a significant hole in the Boost lineup. Celero5G is the response to fill that hole.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jlQczK"&gt;Not much is known about this 5G phone at the moment besides the fact its name, Celero5G, is inspired by the “Latin word for speed.” According to the press release, the phone has a 6.52-inch display, four cameras, 36 hours of battery life, 4GB RAM, a microSD card slot, and 64GB of internal storage — all respectable specifications for a budget phone. Like the sub-$300 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;, this phone is probably powered by the same Qualcomm Snapdragon 690 5G chip that makes 5G connectivity possible at this price point. It also has a 4,000 mAh battery and 15W fast charger so you should be able to recharge your phone quickly when you run out of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oJFa6F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Celero5G fills a LG-sized hole in Boost Mobile’s lineup&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mcGsXb"&gt;Judging by the press materials that Boost Mobile provided, it looks like the Celero5G has an iPhone-like metallic trim around the phone, and a glass back, which are rather upscale touches for a phone of this class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OFINtE"&gt;The best part about this phone is the plan. If you pre-order the Celero5G by October 31, 2021, you will get 12 months of free unlimited talk, text, and data service from Boost Mobile. Of course, it’s not completely unlimited: you will be downgraded to 2G after burning through 35GB of data, but it’s still plenty to use comfortably. Dish and Boost Mobile will even give you a free case for your $279 Celero5G 5G phone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9pXwwQ"&gt;Signing up and keeping existing Boost Mobile customers with the Celero5G may be the easiest part of realizing Dish’s 5G dreams. Its biggest challenge will be to build out and provide national coverage to its 5G service — a  project that is much more expensive and challenging than releasing an exclusive 5G phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAeTZs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, September 30th, 2021, 12:24PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version of this article incorrectly said the Celero5G phone costs $280 rather than $279, and included a quote that was not in the final release. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, September 30th, 2021, 12:24pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added in extra details like the Celero5G’s battery size and charger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WFcG2u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22697318/dish-5g-game-279-boost-mobile-exclusive-5g-phone-prepaid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22697318/dish-5g-game-279-boost-mobile-exclusive-5g-phone-prepaid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T06:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T06:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fairphone’s latest sustainable smartphone comes with a five-year warranty</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TFSm8pgeN4YONzo30D4MpbSJmEs=/0x0:3969x2646/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69930128/Fairphone_02_grey_phone_in_hand_on_couch_Kera_0091_C1_RGB.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fairphone 4’s updated design makes it look like a modern smartphone.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Fairphone 4&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vr0H02"&gt;Fairphone, the manufacturer focused on making easy to repair smartphones made out of ethically sourced materials, just took the wraps off its fourth-generation handset. The Fairphone 4 uses a modular design that’s similar to the company’s previous phones, only now with more powerful internals, a five-year warranty, and a promise of two major Android updates and software support until the end of 2025. Prices start at €579 / £499 for the phone, which will ship on October 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fq3T8m"&gt;I’ve been using the Fairphone 4 for a couple of days as my primary phone, and while I’m not ready to give a final verdict just yet, it feels like a big step forward compared to the dated designs and low-power components found in the company’s previous phones. Stay tuned for my full review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1daxC7"&gt;Fairphone’s ambition is to produce a more ethical alternative to modern smartphones. That means making a device that’s ethically sourced using sustainable materials before providing the software support and warranty to make it useable for as long as possible. Although Fairphone is only guaranteeing software support until the end of 2025, it has ambitions to extend this as far as 2027. In an ideal world, Fairphone would also like to eventually release 2024’s Android 15 as an update to the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/up1_EG9tNOFkd0m4c_SfDHk3DUw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22887059/Fairphone_09_repairing_grey_phone_Keira_0069_C2_RGB.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fairphone&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like Fairphone’s previous devices, the Fairphone 4 is designed to be easy to disassemble.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="h3H3ln"&gt;Normally, the specs of Fairphone’s devices are secondary to its ethical considerations, but unlike its previous phones, the Fairphone 4 is competitive with other mid-range Android handsets. The 5G handset is powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 750G processor, and that’s paired with either 6 or 8GB of RAM and 128 or 256GB of internal storage, expandable via microSD. It’s powered by a 3,905mAh removable battery, and the display is a 6.3-inch 1080p LCD panel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lq6W69"&gt;There are two rear cameras — a 48-megapixel main camera and a 48-megapixel ultrawide — and a single 25-megapixel selfie camera. The main rear camera is equipped with optical image stabilization and can record at up to 4K / 30fps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rCGCMp"&gt;A notable downside compared to previous Fairphones is that the Fairphone 4 no longer includes a 3.5mm headphone jack, a choice that feels at odds with the company’s otherwise customer-first approach. Fairphone tells me it made this decision in order to be able to offer an official IP rating for dust and water resistance, which was missing from the company’s previous phones. It’s only IP54, which means it’s protected from light splashes rather than full submersion, but that’s impressive in light of its removable rear cover and modular design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2DwJSg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;No plans for a US release for now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3A5n1w"&gt;Regarding its modularity, Fairphone is selling eight repair modules for the phone, which include replacement displays, batteries, back covers, USB-C ports, loudspeakers, earpieces, rear cameras, and selfie cameras. All of these are easily removable using a standard Philips head screwdriver, which means customers should be able to carry out a lot of repairs themselves. But, if you need to turn to a professional, Fairphone says its spare parts are readily available for local repair shops to buy and use themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqG2V2"&gt;Fairphone’s previous two phones are the only devices to have received &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2Fsmartphone-repairability%3Fsort%3Dscore&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F30%2F22700014%2Ffairphone-4-release-date-news-features-warranty-price-sustainable" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;perfect repairability scores from iFixit&lt;/a&gt;, and the company tells me it believes the Fairphone 4 is even more repairable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NgUPR1"&gt;The hope is for these spare parts to be available until at least 2027. Fairphone has a good track record with previous devices, telling me it still has parts in stock for the six-year-old Fairphone 2, two years after the last handset was sold. But product manager Miquel Ballester concedes that the company has run out of certain parts for that model.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HkEF2FHwpum8W-kZquDJEBBkcQA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22887060/Fairphone_03_grey_phone_from_back_Kera_0114_C1_RGB.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fairphone&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the rear are two cameras and a TOF sensor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ogqpZC"&gt;So too does Fairphone have a solid record on the software side of providing major Android updates for its phones… eventually. Earlier this year, the company officially released its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22349953/fairphone-2-android-9-update-sustainable-long-term-support"&gt;Android 9 update for the Fairphone 2&lt;/a&gt;, a device that originally launched with Android 5. It may have come almost three years after Android 9’s original release, but it means that the phone continues to run an officially supported version of Google’s operating system. It bodes well for Fairphone’s support aspirations for the Fairphone 4, although it will have to contend with the fact that Qualcomm only officially supports its chipsets for three major OS updates and four years of security updates, &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/12/qualcomm-promises-three-years-of-android-updates-for-its-entire-soc-lineup/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h64dao"&gt;In terms of materials, the Fairphone 4 is made using Fairtrade-certified gold; responsibly sourced aluminum and tungsten; and recycled tin, rare earth minerals, and plastic (including its rear panel, which is 100 percent recycled polycarbonate). The company has various initiatives to improve the working conditions of miners and factory workers involved in the supply chains for its devices. Fairphone also claims that the Fairphone 4 is the “first electronic waste neutral handset” because it’ll recycle one phone or an equal amount of e-waste for each device sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icj5sw"&gt;The Fairphone 4 is available to preorder today in Europe and should ship starting October 25th. The model with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage costs €579 / £499, while the step-up model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage retails for €649 / ￡569. Unfortunately, there’s no sign of a US release: Fairphone says it’s interested but that it’s focusing on Europe for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22700014/fairphone-4-release-date-news-features-warranty-price-sustainable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22700014/fairphone-4-release-date-news-features-warranty-price-sustainable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T04:59:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T04:59:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android ‘12.1’ could be a big foldable-focused update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w8OdJ8SFn1epyOijRKkEriIgrxg=/1x0:1024x682/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69919029/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A redesigned lock screen could make better use of horizontal space.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-1-hands-on/" target="_blank"&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7yC0QO"&gt;Big foldable-focused improvements are on the way for Android, if leaked code &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-1-hands-on/"&gt;analyzed by &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to be believed. &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-v2-update/"&gt;Previous reports&lt;/a&gt; have suggested that this year’s Android 12 is going to be followed by a minor revision, which is expected to be called Android 12.1 based on previous naming conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QafWK8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA&lt;/em&gt;’s analysis suggests this update may deliver a host of improvements for how the operating system handles large foldable-sized screens, including offering a better split-screen UI, a lockscreen that makes better use of horizontal space, and a new taskbar that makes it easier to use multiple apps at once. They’re helpful additions that should reduce the need for manufacturers like Samsung to build their own foldable-focused UI improvements on top of Android for their own devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JbzYpIGNs8Nn9ZIr_ge74H-Qess=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884146/Android_12.1_dual_pane_notifications_1024x836.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-1-hands-on/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Viewing Android’s Quick Settings and notifications panel simultaneously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KwQpKQ"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;XDA’s&lt;/em&gt; analysis notes, most of the improvements relate to how the operating system makes better use of more horizontal screen real estate. For example, it allows the Quick Settings and notifications panels to be displayed simultaneously side-by-side (rather than one-at-a-time), while the lock screen can now be split to show the clock on one side and notifications on the other. When it comes time to enter a PIN or password, this can now be placed on the left or right of the display (rather than centered) to allow it to be entered with one hand on a foldable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ElMCrV"&gt;Android 12.1 is also designed to make it easier to use apps in split-screen. There’s a new shortcut in the recent apps menu to open an app in split-screen mode, rather than having to long press an app’s icon. Meanwhile, a new taskbar on the bottom of the screen can also be used to open recent apps in split-screen mode by dragging and dropping them onto either half of the screen. &lt;em&gt;XDA &lt;/em&gt;reports that it might eventually be possible to drag notifications to open their apps in split-screen mode. Finally, the Settings app also appears to be getting a new interface that allows top-level menu items to be displayed on the left, while its submenus open on the right half of the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9udA6aBjhBIGRYXMDS327gGtFj8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884143/Android_12.1_split_screen_UI_1024x836.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-1-hands-on/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A taskbar with access to recent apps on the bottom of the screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="78Z92c"&gt;Other non-foldable focused enhancements include being able to tweak the amount of time you have to hold the power button to activate the Google Assistant, and making it easier for manufacturers other than Google to match their system colors to Android 12’s lockscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rvt3jl"&gt;Google is yet to officially announce anything resembling Android 12.1, nor has it even released Android 12 to the general public. That means the features detailed by &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt; could change a lot before they’re released, if they’re ever released at all. But combined with the persistent rumors about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"&gt;Google releasing a foldable phone&lt;/a&gt; this year, it’s looking increasingly likely that we’ll see some of these features arrive sooner rather than later. Be sure to check out the full list of changes &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-12-1-hands-on/"&gt;over on &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhAAjQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mrkS1K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697950/android-12-1-foldable-features-report-split-screen-multi-tasking-taskbar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697950/android-12-1-foldable-features-report-split-screen-multi-tasking-taskbar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T10:35:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T10:35:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are our favorite MagSafe-compatible cases for the iPhone 13 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nV1BJrxb8kVbO4wD84DwBb2EHpI=/141x0:1640x999/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69914810/lcimg_d2e9ab3c_4dbb_4be2_8ce9_a0c53e9e1863.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A rainbow of Apple’s own MagSafe iPhone 13 caes.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xPF2ZE"&gt;Now that your brand-spanking-new iPhone 13 has arrived (or is on the way), it’s time to start thinking about protecting your baby. After all, it’s only a matter of time before your phone falls out of your pocket or makes contact with your keys, so it’s worth the extra investment now to prevent future damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CujTbM"&gt;Although MagSafe as an iPhone accessory standard is already a year old, Apple is off to a slow start building out its accessory ecosystem. Since its October 2020 launch event, Apple has only launched a dozen official MagSafe products: from the iconic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509659/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-charging-magnetic-charger-return"&gt;MagSafe Charger&lt;/a&gt; puck to the 2021 &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/974136/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMM0Q3ZM%2FA%2Fiphone-leather-wallet-with-magsafe-golden-brown" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MagSafe Leather Wallet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KebrqK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The iPhone 13 Mini still gets slower MagSafe charging speeds ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691602/iphone-13-mini-slower-magsafe-charging-speeds-12w"},{"title":"The Lightning port isn’t about convenience; it’s about control ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22690338/apple-iphone-lightning-ports-convenience-control-usb-c-eu-wireless-charging-mfi-magsafe"},{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="3z5diJ"&gt;Of course, third-party accessory makers are eager to make MagSafe products, too. Unfortunately, Apple is famously tight-fisted with its proprietary technology, even though its &lt;a href="https://mfi.apple.com/"&gt;MFi program&lt;/a&gt; is designed to license and control these very products. So third-party accessories like battery packs and chargers can only attach to the official MagSafe products and charge at 7.5W, rather than the 15W wireless charging standard that Apple-approved accessories can achieve. But third-party accessories tend to be cheaper in price and offer more selection than the official lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34HE13"&gt;In case you’re on the hunt for cases that will work with your official &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509659/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-charging-magnetic-charger-return"&gt;MagSafe Charger&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini"&gt;Battery Pack&lt;/a&gt;, here are the top 10 third-party iPhone 13 cases that caught my eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ku9TiG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772157"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="p5LwVN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771970"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="A8LVzW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772024"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="bU5xc5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772188"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="6aaiBV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772175"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="faf10L"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772213"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="zPDxwC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772104"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="CaGE3z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772073"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="K7ZAOQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772132"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ITb4EP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10772226"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z2tmTo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lhqWGG"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22671534/best-magsafe-iphone-13-cases-iphone-pro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22671534/best-magsafe-iphone-13-cases-iphone-pro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T16:17:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T16:17:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>It’s Friday, here’s the Galaxy S22 Ultra render that has the Android blogosphere abuzz</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tPAqt1bFg8PNssyPiGSlNCBun-M=/400x0:4720x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905230/GALAXY_S22_ULTRA_5K4.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Digit, OnLeaks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pA0XYz"&gt;It’s Friday, it’s fall, there’s a breeze in the air (hopefully), and there’s fresh, I’d argue ridiculous, renders of Samsung’s expected Galaxy S22 Ultra to show you. The renders come &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1441426057316368389?s=20"&gt;courtesy of @OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.digit.in/news/mobile-phones/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-exclusive-leaked-renders-specs-61203.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and they feature a new Samsung flagship with what looks like a Galaxy Note 20-inspired body and back that... well you should see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBQsVb"&gt;Since deciding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung"&gt;to skip the Galaxy Note in 2021&lt;/a&gt; — apparently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676054/t-mobile-cfo-peter-osvaldik-samsung-supply-no-note"&gt;much to the chagrin of T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;Samsung’s been seeding Note features across its popular phones. Both the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617206/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-features-specs-price-hands-on"&gt;Galaxy Z Fold 3&lt;/a&gt; offer stylus support. If these new renders are to be believed, the Galaxy S22 Ultra will go even further. According to OnLeaks and &lt;em&gt;Digit&lt;/em&gt;, the new phone will come with the hole-punch selfie camera and candy bar shape of last year’s Note, along with stylus support and what looks like an actual stylus slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fLZ8ro"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sooo... Here comes your very first and early look at the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Samsung?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Samsung&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GalaxyS22Ultra?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GalaxyS22Ultra&lt;/a&gt; and its quite "unique" rear camera housing design! (360° video + stunning 5K renders + dimensions)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On behalf of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/digitindia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@digitindia&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/vBGM3WJfru"&gt;https://t.co/vBGM3WJfru&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDqfFrVGLW"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YDqfFrVGLW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve H.McFly (@OnLeaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1441426057316368389?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NW5kU6"&gt;The render of the back of the device is where things get interesting, weird, or bad, depending on your taste. The Galaxy S22 Ultra appears to morph &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;the camera “plateau” of the S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; into an unmistakable letter P shape. Is the P for... photos? Pictures? Maybe periscope? There certainly seems to be plenty of room. For reference, the previous Ultra included a main 108-megapixel wide-angle sensor, two 10-megapixel telephoto sensors, and a 12-megapixel ultrawide sensor on the back of the device. Who knows what the new S22 Ultra will fit?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ATuyJXVgnfueUq6vLwNSV-oIdbY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875857/GALAXY_S22_ULTRA_07.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Digit, OnLeaks&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s hard to miss the P-shaped cameras, a little bit easier to miss the stylus slot at the bottom of the rumored device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sDJGdj"&gt;There’s some reason to believe this could be Samsung’s design, beyond it fitting with a general trend of camera bumps becoming big and increasingly... visible on devices like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;the iPhone 13 Pro&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;yet-to-be-released Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;. OnLeaks has a fairly good track record of leaking phones, pretty closely matching the looks of both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/21/21395173/leaked-google-pixel-5-renders-specs-october-launch"&gt;the Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"&gt;the Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of refinement to a camera housing also doesn’t seem out of the picture, in many ways it’s a reduction of the S21 Ultra’s cameras: a corner has been removed. That doesn’t mean it doesn’t look strange, though.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Galaxy S21 Ultra, in Phantom Black" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b1pRvJgZl0Ynhub4j7_nMUn0Zt0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22248961/vpavic_210119_4377_0170.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can imagine seeing a “P” on the Galaxy S21 Ultra if I really look at it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691985/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-render-p-camera-stylus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691985/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-render-p-camera-stylus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
