<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-14T16:55:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T16:55:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T16:55:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s critical Pixel 6 January update is here</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-kvqmfhip2vzuFHX3kE0wobOMMs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70391322/akrales_211020_4802_0471.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The January update promises to fix numerous bugs reported by Pixel 6 owners.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IRabhh"&gt;Google is in the process of releasing a much-anticipated update for Pixel 6 phones. Earlier today, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mishaalrahman/status/1482073557064638467"&gt;Android expert Mishaal Rahman noted&lt;/a&gt; that Google posted &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/android/ota"&gt;OTA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/android/images"&gt;factory images&lt;/a&gt; to its developer site for the January 2022 patch. That means anyone can sideload the update to their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"&gt;Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; now, and the official over-the-air update has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/1482098746779447305"&gt;already arrived on some devices&lt;/a&gt; (including some owned by &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Crc7jX"&gt;In an email, Google confirmed the rollout has begun, and that the software will automatically roll out over the next week, depending on your device and wireless carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBcYtF"&gt;Using the phones’ built-in checker may start the process now, and if it doesn’t, &lt;a href="https://flash.android.com/welcome"&gt;sideloading&lt;/a&gt; is still an option. However, waiting for the regular rollout instead of doing a manual install may be the best way to go, given the trouble caused by December’s update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26RgBb"&gt;This patch includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/13/22832212/google-pixel-6-pro-december-update-bug-fixes-fingerprint-sensor"&gt;numerous bug fixes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820593/google-pixel-december-feature-drop-quick-tap-to-snap-shortcut-ultra-wideband-nearby-share"&gt;a few new features&lt;/a&gt; that Pixel 6 owners have been anxiously awaiting. It’s supposed to tweak the fingerprint sensor, camera, and support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22788072/google-pixel-6-stand-wireless-charging-fast-23w-qi"&gt;23W wireless charging with the second-generation Pixel Stand&lt;/a&gt;. On the Pixel 6 Pro, you can use its ultra-wideband chip for digital car key access to compatible BMWs. This update also adds the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734993/pixel-6-snapchat-feature-tap-camera"&gt;Quick Tap to Snap&lt;/a&gt;” integration that Google and Snapchat touted during the devices’ launch event and new bass controls for the Pixel Buds A-Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXwjy1"&gt;Google originally intended to ship those features in the December update but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/30/22860191/pixel-6-pro-google-december-feature-update-paused"&gt;halted and ultimately removed the files&lt;/a&gt; from its site when users complained of connectivity troubles after installing the patch. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/143183382/december-2021-update-paused?hl=en"&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt; that the January update has fixes for those bugs, and includes &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/139017133/google-pixel-update-december-2021?hl=en"&gt;the December update’s fixes&lt;/a&gt; to address bugs that have driven &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/1481108783996751874?s=20"&gt;at least one well-known Pixel 6 user&lt;/a&gt; to ditch the phone entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0uUwIo"&gt;With the images public and &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2022/01/14/pixel-6-january-update-release-date/"&gt;one Canadian telecom company&lt;/a&gt; citing Monday, January 17th for the release, we thought the patch would arrive next week, but it’s already here. That’s none too soon for people who bought the Pixel 6 or 6 Pro expecting to get a premium device. While the hardware is truly flagship-level, the software experience &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update"&gt;hasn’t always been smooth&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SS9v0s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 14th, 4:30PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to reflect that the update is rolling out now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3HM1V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 14th, 4:55PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to note Google’s confirmation of the update, and that it includes both the December and January changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884219/google-january-2022-pixel-6-pro-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884219/google-january-2022-pixel-6-pro-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T21:14:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T21:14:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>PUBG’s developer is suing Apple, Google, and the developer of lucrative PUBG lookalike Free Fire</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pdM5PZpvs6i6DANsf5YzSeAubPM=/91x0:1077x657/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70386271/PUBG_CPP_2_1168x657.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG-maker Krafton filed a big lawsuit Monday.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Krafton&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N5FcXI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;-maker Krafton filed a &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21179291-krafton-lawsuit-against-sea-apple-and-google"&gt;big lawsuit Monday&lt;/a&gt;: it’s suing the developer of two mobile games that it accuses of copying &lt;em&gt;PUBG: Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;, the hit PC battle royale shooter, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it’s suing Apple and Google for distributing those games on their app stores. Krafton even accuses Google of hosting &lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt; videos with gameplay of the two games in question, as well as “numerous posts containing a feature-length Chinese film that is nothing more than a blatantly infringing live-action dramatization of &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZEIHWr"&gt;The games Krafton takes issue with are called &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt;, offered by developer Garena. On both the App Store and Google Play, they show up as &lt;em&gt;Garena Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Garena Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt;. Both are available for free with in-app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UvEfrw"&gt;According to Krafton:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="YztuSd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt; extensively copy numerous aspects of &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;, both individually and in combination, including &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds’&lt;/em&gt; copyrighted unique game opening “air drop” feature, the game structure and play, the combination and selection of weapons, armor, and unique objects, locations, and the overall choice of color schemes, materials, and textures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="83nhLy"&gt;Krafton alleges Garena has earned “hundreds of millions of dollars” from sales from the apps and that Apple and Google have “similarly earned a substantial amount of revenue from their distribution of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YsV-icHwtJtHnpDjWYzaIzWiN54=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167824/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.37.39_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Krafton&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the lawsuit, Krafton compiled comparisons like this to make its case against Garena.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GBI9HR"&gt;Krafton claims that on December 21st, it took a few actions: it asked Garena to “immediately stop its exploitation of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max,&lt;/em&gt;” which Garena apparently refused; it asked Apple and Google to stop distributing the games, which are both still available on both app stores; and it asked YouTube to remove videos featuring &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt; gameplay “that include elements that blatantly infringe &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt; and, separately, the infringing feature-length film,” which Krafton says YouTube hasn’t done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FMRuVD"&gt;In case you’re wondering about that film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JJlybn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update on the below:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1. The directors said it's not a PUBG movie, despite basically being a PUBG movie.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Krafton said they are considering suing given the similarities to the PUBG IP. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. You can watch it with English subs here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/lS1SfdTRhj"&gt;https://t.co/lS1SfdTRhj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/pBdcsqZttn"&gt;https://t.co/pBdcsqZttn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Daniel Ahmad (@ZhugeEX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZhugeEX/status/1427026510913880073?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="smoHXo"&gt;Krafton also notes that Garena sold a game in Singapore in 2017 that “copied” &lt;em&gt;PUBG: Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;. While claims regarding that were settled, there was no license agreement established, according to the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oP8pg9"&gt;I’ll admit that I hadn’t heard of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; before this lawsuit, but I’ve since learned that it’s quite lucrative. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; earned $1.1 billion in player spending in 2021, according to data that analytics firm Sensor Tower shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, an amount that was up 48 percent from 2020. While the total dollar amount is quite a bit less than the astonishing $2.9 billion that &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; earned in player spending last year, &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile’s&lt;/em&gt; figures were up only seven percent year-over-year, reports Sensor Tower. That could suggest &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile’s&lt;/em&gt; growth is slowing down just as &lt;em&gt;Free Fire’s&lt;/em&gt; is skyrocketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9ebCU"&gt;We also checked with another analytics firm, Appfigures, and while the data was different, it still suggested that &lt;em&gt;Free Fire &lt;/em&gt;is catching up. &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile Lite&lt;/em&gt;, and the China- and India-specific versions of &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; earned a combined $639 million in revenue last year, according to Appfigures, while &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; earned $414 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VFvCMO"&gt;Apple and Google didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment. Jason Golz, a spokesperson for &lt;a href="https://www.sea.com/home"&gt;Garena parent company Sea&lt;/a&gt;, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that “Krafton’s claims are groundless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CooJaG"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21179291-krafton-lawsuit-against-sea-apple-and-google/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Krafton lawsuit against Sea, Apple, and Google (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1IFBVN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzFu8X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882796/pubg-developer-krafton-suing-apple-google-garena-free-fire-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882796/pubg-developer-krafton-suing-apple-google-garena-free-fire-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T16:46:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T16:46:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>The FCC proposes new data breach rules for phone companies </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bXnEr5kcWkacDye7YHqmHrSEAS0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385426/acastro_170629_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4Jb3dz"&gt;Phone companies could have to follow new rules about how they notify customers and the government following a data breach if a proposal from the Federal Communication Commission’s chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel passes. The &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/chair-rosenworcel-circulates-new-data-breach-reporting-requirements"&gt;notice of proposed rulemaking&lt;/a&gt;, released on Wednesday, cites the “increasing frequency and severity of security breaches involving customer information” as a risk to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cC9s2f"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/47/64.2011"&gt;The current rules&lt;/a&gt; give telecommunication providers seven business days to notify the FBI and Secret Service of data breaches that leak customer proprietary network information, or CPNI. In most cases, the company cannot notify customers about the breach until seven business days after information has been relayed to federal law enforcement. The proposal suggests doing away with that mandatory waiting period and adds the FCC to the list of agencies that companies will have to notify in the case of a data breach. It also says that they would have to send out notifications even in the case of inadvertent breaches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RmtJqp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;News of a breach currently has to go to law enforcement before it can be sent to consumers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7ExrEv"&gt;CPNI is “some of the most sensitive personal information that carriers and providers have about their customers,” &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/general/customer-privacy"&gt;according to the FCC&lt;/a&gt;. It can include data like who a customer made calls to and when and where those calls were made. It can also include customers’ billing account name, phone and account number, and info about their plan. The proposed update would “better align the Commission’s rules” with the ones that have recently been put in place for other industries by federal and state governments, according to the notice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q8Fphs"&gt;This proposal isn’t being made in a vacuum. In late December, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/28/22857619/t-mobile-cyberattack-data-breach-december-2021-cpni-sim-swap"&gt;news broke&lt;/a&gt; that a data breach had exposed some T-Mobile customers’ CPNI. The carrier had also suffered a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/28/22646439/t-mobile-data-breach-ceo-security-mandiant-kpmg"&gt;much larger cybersecurity incident&lt;/a&gt; earlier in 2021, which affected over 50 million people and was already the carrier’s fifth breach in four years. While T-Mobile says it informed affected customers after the December breach, the FCC’s proposed rules would’ve placed stricter requirements on how and when those notifications went out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lysvz5"&gt;It may be a while before we see these requirements actually apply to phone companies — the FCC is currently in a political deadlock, with two Democrat members (including Rosenworcel) and two Republican members. The White House has nominated Gigi Sohn to fill the commission’s fifth seat, which would tip the scales, but there’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22876628/fcc-biden-ftc-gigi-sohn-alvaro-bedoya-rosenworcel-net-neutrality"&gt;currently a stalemate with the Senate&lt;/a&gt; on actually getting her confirmed. Even if the Senate manages to confirm Sohn despite &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787261/biden-fcc-net-neutrality-jessica-rosenworcel-gigi-sohn-broadband"&gt;some Republican senators’ vows to block her nomination&lt;/a&gt;, the proposal is just the beginning of the rule-changing process.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882281/fcc-telecom-data-breach-notification-rules-proposal-commission-seats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882281/fcc-telecom-data-breach-notification-rules-proposal-commission-seats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T15:23:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T15:23:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Android 12 update has been the rockiest in years</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Android 12" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gJdXwUYhlaEif8Ydo9DpPzXcSUM=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70384996/VRG_1777_Android_12_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From bugs to halted releases, Android 12 has seen an unusually troubled launch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;There are some unique complicating factors this year, but it’s the same old Android — the good and the bad&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="hLnFwe"&gt;Android 12 is one of the platform’s most ambitious updates in recent history, bringing a major design overhaul to every corner of the operating system. It has also been one of the rockiest Android OS launches in the past few years. Both Samsung and OnePlus paused the rollout of their stable Android 12-based updates amid reports of serious bugs. Google itself has addressed a laundry list of bug reports from Pixel 6 owners, just as it’s trying to convince them it’s finally figured out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22733159/sundar-pichai-rick-osterloh-google-pixel-6-interview-podcast"&gt;how to build a truly premium phone&lt;/a&gt;. What in the heck is going on? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTkjK4"&gt;The short answer is that there are some unique complicating factors at play this year but also that Android is inherently a little bit messy — that just comes with the territory when you’re designing a delightful public park compared to Apple’s walled garden.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Despite a refreshed look and some appealing new high-end handsets, Android is still Android — the good and the bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NFObXS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Android 12 review: it’s mostly about the looks","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708720/android-12-review-features-pixel-update-software"},{"title":"Sundar Pichai and Rick Osterloh think the Pixel 6 is Google’s breakout phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733159/sundar-pichai-rick-osterloh-google-pixel-6-interview-podcast"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zGyqPg"&gt;Android 12’s release started predictably enough with a formal announcement at Google I/O in May 2021. After that, the timeline looks a little different from previous years. A full stable release came a month later than usual, on October 4th, 2021. The Pixel 6 and 6 Pro launched later that month with Android 12 pre-loaded. A handful of bugs were to be expected, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/13/22832212/google-pixel-6-pro-december-update-bug-fixes-fingerprint-sensor"&gt;Google’s December Pixel update included dozens of fixes&lt;/a&gt; despite Google having that extra month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CKzuTq"&gt;Even worse, the December patch itself proved problematic as some Pixel 6 owners complained about network connection problems worsened by the update. Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/30/22860191/pixel-6-pro-google-december-feature-update-paused"&gt;halted the update&lt;/a&gt; and later &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/01/04/google-delists-december-2021-update-pixel-6-pro/"&gt;removed it from its archive&lt;/a&gt; to prevent manual downloads. When asked, the company didn’t offer an explanation for the problematic update but &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/143183382/december-2021-update-paused?hl=en"&gt;pointed to a statement&lt;/a&gt; that a fix is coming in late January that will include all of the bug fixes planned for the December patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D18tfaBTNzVe-giUTl3StbkE8bQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22957781/akrales_211022_4802_0822.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pixel 6 owners are still waiting for the bug fixes initially slated for the December update.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PUxGBh"&gt;Google’s not alone in having trouble with its new OS. Samsung users in South Korea &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-issues-after-android-12-update"&gt;reported serious problems&lt;/a&gt; with their Galaxy Fold 3 and Flip 3 devices after installing the One UI 4.0 (Android 12) stable release, including flickering displays and bricked phones. Samsung acknowledged the problem and &lt;a href="https://r1.community.samsung.com/t5/%ED%8C%81/4%EC%B0%A8-%EB%B2%A0%ED%83%80-%EC%86%8C%ED%94%84%ED%8A%B8%EC%9B%A8%EC%96%B4-%EC%97%85%EB%8D%B0%EC%9D%B4%ED%8A%B8-%EA%B3%B5%EC%A7%80-12-13/td-p/14321413"&gt;responded initially by releasing a fourth &lt;em&gt;beta&lt;/em&gt; version&lt;/a&gt; of the software to fix bugs introduced by the stable release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EK2MKt"&gt;OnePlus’ stable release wasn’t so stable, either: its Android 12 skin was so buggy that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22828553/oneplus-buggy-oxygenos-android-12-update-9-pro"&gt;the company paused its release&lt;/a&gt;, like Google, after it was widely criticized. In a brief statement, OnePlus explained that the fact this release marked the company’s attempt to integrate its OxygenOS and ColorOS codebases into the same build “led to the software experience not being smooth” and that its software team “collected the Community’s feedback and released a new build of OxygenOS 12 within a week to deliver a better user experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XpqlCV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“the biggest OS update to Android since Android 5.0 Lollipop, and that was many years ago”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r5oEEP"&gt;In each case, these “stable” releases were anything but, and none of these companies offered much detail about what went wrong. To try and figure out what the heck is going on, we talked to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman"&gt;Mishaal Rahman&lt;/a&gt;, former editor-in-chief of &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;, who’s well known for digging into Android codebases and discovering Google’s secrets. Speaking to the Pixel 6 bugs in particular, Rahman guesses that it has a lot to do with the unusually large size of the update. “Many people have called it, myself included, the biggest OS update to Android since Android 5.0 Lollipop, and that was many years ago. There are just so many massive changes to the interface and to the feature set.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kEJAy"&gt;He also suggests that Google’s commitment to issue a new Android update every year can make things worse when it’s trying to do so much, and the self-imposed one-year development cycle doesn’t leave much wiggle room in the timeline. “They started immediately after Android 11 was released to the public — and they have a hard cutoff date… After that, they just focus on fixing bugs.” Delay any longer, and they’d risk bumping into next year’s development cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5arqlH"&gt;It’s also possible that the attempt to bring timely Android updates to non-Google devices wound up backfiring. Android phone owners have been asking for faster updates for a long time — outside of Google’s Pixel phones and pricey flagships, many devices face long waits for OS updates. Sure enough, the updates have come faster this year. Case in point: Samsung users are accustomed to waiting about three months after an Android stable release to get their finished One UI update with the new version of the OS, but this year, One UI 4.0 arrived just one and a half months after Android 12. But the way things have gone this year, many users would likely have opted for a slower, stable update rather than a fast one riddled with bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="KpBnqN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;OnePlus, by its own admission, faced unique complications as it attempted to merge Oppo’s ColorOS and OxygenOS&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0oxxR5"&gt;OnePlus, by its own admission, faced unique complications as it attempted to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560765/oneplus-oxygenos-coloros-oppo-android-updates"&gt;merge Oppo’s ColorOS and OxygenOS&lt;/a&gt; at the same time it incorporated Android 12’s changes. That’s a recipe for bugs, Rahman explains. “Devices that are upgrading from Android 11 with OxygenOS 11 to OxygenOS 12 are having a lot of settings and features being migrated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V76dpX"&gt;To illustrate the problem, he describes a bug that some Realme device owners have encountered: users who restore settings from an old Android phone when setting up a Realme device would sometimes find the &lt;a href="https://forum.xda-developers.com/t/cant-disable-night-filter.4005543/"&gt;Night Light setting constantly enabled on their new phone&lt;/a&gt;. This happened because of a mismatch between Realme and Google’s open-source implementations of Night Light. OxygenOS 12, he suspects, suffered from similar issues. “It’s those kinds of bugs that are plaguing this update.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pTYtaG"&gt;While it’s still hard to understand how &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/oxygen-os12-oneplus-9-awful/"&gt;an update as buggy&lt;/a&gt; as OnePlus’ initial OxygenOS 12 release earned a “stable” designation, it makes a little more sense when you account for the huge challenge of merging two codebases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Hw5WUE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s no straight line from Android 12 to the Galaxy S21 or OnePlus 9&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eSzGYc"&gt;While all of these factors likely contributed to an unusually troubled release, the underlying problem is a familiar one. By its nature, Android is a fragmented ecosystem. There’s no straight line from Android 12 to the Galaxy S21 or OnePlus 9 — every major update sees handoffs between the manufacturer, carriers, and Google, all of which result in delays. Initiatives like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/12/15632552/android-o-faster-updates-project-treble-google"&gt;Project Treble&lt;/a&gt; seem to have helped speed up some parts of the process, but unless Google takes some drastic actions, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/4/20847758/google-android-update-problem-pie-q-treble-mainline"&gt;nobody can completely fix the problem&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rViwDT"&gt;While OEMs and Google push to get updates out faster, they’ve also made a push to produce more attention-grabbing, premium devices. OnePlus appears to be separating its “flagships, but cheaper” ethos into two different realms: “flagships” like the 9 Pro and separate “cheaper” phones a la the Nord series. Samsung is making a serious attempt to bring foldables into the mainstream. Google has positioned the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro as true flagships, with custom processors and a design language that’s more polished and less quirky than previous generations. This buggy OS rollout risks taking some of the shine off of the polished image these device makers are hoping to cultivate — in fact, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/1481108783996751874?s=20"&gt;damage may already be done&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FNT5vl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;My Pixel 6 Pro has slowly gotten so buggy since launch in October that I can no longer recommend it at $900. Combined with the latest botched  update it's just been a bad experience. My SIM is back in an S21 Ultra til the next review.&lt;/p&gt;— Marques Brownlee (@MKBHD) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/1481108783996751874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 12, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qBFeb9"&gt;It’s a shame because they’ve succeeded with the hardware. The Pixel 6 and 6 Pro are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"&gt;two of the best phones Google has ever made&lt;/a&gt;. OnePlus’ ambition to create a true flagship competitor has resulted in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"&gt;a refined product that’s the genuine article&lt;/a&gt;. And this time around, Samsung seems to have succeeded at making &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22631125/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review"&gt;a foldable phone&lt;/a&gt; that has captured the attention of more than just tech geeks. But behind the glossy hardware, the software experience can still be uneven at times. That’s easier to forgive on a midrange or budget phone, but it’s tough to stomach from a premium device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ru4JHg"&gt;It’s unlikely, though, that this unusually troubled release will sway significant numbers of people to bail on Android; as painful as some of these bugs have been, they’re probably not enough to push users over the hurdles of jumping ship to Apple. Rahman thinks that in most cases, the ecosystem lock-in is too strong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5k5rtS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;behind the glossy hardware, the software experience can still be uneven at times&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zaz9Vh"&gt;“You’d lose out on so many apps and services that you pay for. If you have other devices that interact with your smartphone, you’d lose access to that, or that access would be diminished in some way. I don’t see it as a significant factor convincing people to turn away from a particular device.” Those barriers exist on Apple’s side as well, of course. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute"&gt;Recently surfaced emails&lt;/a&gt; from Apple executives imply that iMessage remains exclusive to iPhones as a mechanism to keep Apple users with Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ONg9Or"&gt;Apple has also had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20872972/apple-ios-13-review-iphone-update-dark-mode-arcade-maps-photos-siri"&gt;its share of software stumbles&lt;/a&gt;, to be sure. But it’s generally a more predictable experience — if you’re willing to live within the boundaries of that walled garden. And there’s the flipside of Android’s fragmented existence: there’s no single entity dictating the hardware and software. In Apple’s ecosystem, you get what it deems to be the right features at the right time, and that’s that. Foldables? Maybe in a few years. A rainbow of customizable system colors? Forget it. Life is a little more interesting — if, at times, unpredictable and uneven — outside of the garden walls.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T22:41:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T22:41:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple and T-Mobile say iOS 15.2 didn’t switch off iCloud Private Relay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Mini" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P5mAZc705qkg0L06yKrgETfWWVw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70381863/vpavic_210916_4760_0323.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1qF06W"&gt;Apple has denied that last month’s iOS 15.2 update is behind the difficulty some iPhone owners have faced with using the iCloud Private Relay feature on cellular networks. Verizon, AT&amp;amp;T, and T-Mobile earlier this week said they weren’t blocking the VPN-like feature, but T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported"&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; to have identified that iOS 15.2 toggled it off by default. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F54OgM"&gt;Now Apple says that’s not the case. After releasing an updated beta of iOS 15.3 that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880835/apple-clarify-icloud-private-relay-error-messages-ios-15-3-cell-carriers"&gt;clarifies the language&lt;/a&gt; in iCloud settings, Apple &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/12/apple-reaffirms-icloud-private-relay-availability-refutes-t-mobiles-accusation-of-a-bug-ios-15-2/"&gt;issued a statement to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; saying that iOS 15.2 wasn’t the problem. “No changes were made to iCloud Private Relay in iOS 15.2 that would have toggled the feature off,” the statement reads. “Users are encouraged to check their Settings to see if Private Relay is enabled on their device or for a specific network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Lq8Yr2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iPhone 13 review: yep, bigger batteries are better","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jm2UUZ"&gt;T-Mobile has also followed up with &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; to say that that iOS 15.2 didn’t toggle the feature off after all. “Apple doesn’t change customers’ settings when they update to iOS 15.2,” the carrier says in a statement. “Customers may see an error message if they previously toggled iCloud Private Relay or Limit IP Address Tracking off in their Cellular Data Options Settings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6cTiEY"&gt;It’s still not entirely clear what caused all of this confusion, but the carriers do say they’re not blocking iCloud Private Relay (except for some T-Mobile plans that include content filtering services), so it’s worth double-checking your cellular settings to make sure everything’s the way it should be. Once the public version of iOS 15.3 is out, the language in settings won’t outright tell you that your cell plan doesn’t support the feature.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22881337/apple-t-mobile-icloud-private-relay-bug-ios-15-2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22881337/apple-t-mobile-icloud-private-relay-bug-ios-15-2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T09:51:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T09:51:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to mute a word or phrase on Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K9L9qO_CtfLAzWvVWNfupkuPkNE=/0x0:900x600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378592/twitter.0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tweet-user-name"&gt;In February 2020,  I found that that it was possible not only to mute conversations or other accounts on Twitter, but (courtesy of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nonprofWHIT/status/1229964006330380289?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1229964006330380289%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F2%2F19%2F21144097%2Ftwitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to-settings-phone-desktop"&gt;a tweet by @nonprofWHIT&lt;/a&gt; ) that you could also mute a specific &lt;em&gt;word&lt;/em&gt;. And you could do it straight from a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZRtti"&gt;Now, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1480958895287939072?s=20"&gt;Twitter has announced&lt;/a&gt; it is expanding this feature so that when you mute a word or phrase, it will not appear in your Explore tab or Event-based notifications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CalAyd"&gt;Here’s how you go about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cPBAYz"&gt;Mute words or phrases on an iPhone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="kiOUjU"&gt;If you’re using the Twitter app on an iPhone, it’s a quick and easy process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WDHN6T"&gt;Long-press on the word you want to mute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="olIheA"&gt;Choose “Mute” from the pop-up menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PEzRpO"&gt;You’ll be sent to a page where you can choose from where you want to mute the word (your timeline or notifications), from whom (anyone or people you don’t follow), and the duration (forever, 24 hours, seven days, or 30 days). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Long-press on the word you want to mute. " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ct4FjssBFbrPRlqSFHRIEaTYgSg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19731703/IMG_589D3687AA11_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long-press on the word you want to mute. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select where you want to mute it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dDH9hXswL9-N6bXW-V0tYJdiQvU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19731705/IMG_BB887E06D435_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select where you want to mute it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VevJJq"&gt;Mute words or phrases on an Android phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QEISnd"&gt;If you’ve got an Android phone, don’t despair. You can also mute words from the Android Twitter app (or, for that matter, from the iOS Twitter app) through the app’s settings. It’s not quite as fast as doing it directly from a tweet, but it’s just as effective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dioGVM"&gt;Select your icon on the upper left corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="86FxuH"&gt;Select “Settings and privacy” &amp;gt; “Privacy and safety” &amp;gt; “Mute and block.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aUmPGy"&gt;Tap “Muted words.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IWrdR2"&gt;Tap the plus sign and enter the word you want to mute. You then get the same choices as to where, from whom, and duration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In Android, you mute using settings." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nTl99kR7ncdZUAn443VgaOsHAHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161869/Screenshot_20220111_164607.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Android, you mute using settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Enter each word or phrase separately." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h4oiyYduCftQXYz_BYEYRnba7lA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161872/Screenshot_20220111_164831.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter each word or phrase separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="78Fb6s"&gt;If you no longer want to mute the word or you want to extend the mute time, return to the “Muted words” screen, tap on the word in question, and choose the corresponding option (“Delete word” or “Change mute time”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can always delete the muted word." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MJM9RKxdhhrJusCZm98IBsSy0b8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161887/Screenshot_20220111_164953.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can always delete the muted word.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Are you sure?" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0RO26hyhtA6H-OU6WSHsyeWV9GM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161886/Screenshot_20220111_165009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you sure?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yGqJr7"&gt;Mute words or phrases on your desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kIw7dK"&gt;And finally, if you’re tweeting directly from Twitter’s website, you can mute a word from there as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mUDyjq"&gt;On your desktop, from the left-hand menu, click on “More” &amp;gt; “Settings and privacy” &amp;gt; “Privacy and safety” &amp;gt; “Mute and block.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PlrwIF"&gt;In the right column, click on “Muted words.” Click on the plus sign in the upper right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0x5wni"&gt;Now you can enter the word or phrase you want to mute. As with the mobile Twitter apps, you can choose whether to mute from your timeline or notifications, from anyone or people you don’t follow, and for how long. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="On a desktop, you first find the “Mute and block” section." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sLiNAOQx6_OtIxogeghXdLHom1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161973/Screen_Shot_2022_01_11_at_4.59.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On a desktop, you first find the “Mute and block” section.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1BIzId"&gt;When you’ve made all your choices, click on “Save.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4rpSnz"&gt;If you want to unmute any words, go back to the “Muted words” column. Click on the red crossed-out volume symbol to the right of the word, and then click “Unmute” on the pop-up window that appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="It’s simple to go back and unmute a word or phrase." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R66EzpN58QfNo7ElEtgaP5xvr2Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161974/Screen_Shot_2022_01_11_at_5.01.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s simple to go back and unmute a word or phrase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7KYdrh"&gt;Some additional notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MIsPI2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/advanced-twitter-mute-options"&gt;Twitter has a number of ways&lt;/a&gt; you can mute different types of info in your timeline and notifications. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Tr9Tbt"&gt;You can also mute specific mentions of specific accounts (but not mute the account itself) by using the @ in front of the account name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hRELIu"&gt;If you mute a word, you will also mute that word’s hashtag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="znDiJJ"&gt;Muting is not case-sensitive (“spoilers” and “SPOILERS” will both work), and you can use a phrase with punctuation (“Hey, you!”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mdxx9i"&gt;Twitter is expanding the ability to mute words, phrases, etc. to areas other than timelines and notifications. Just yesterday, it announced that blocked or muted text would also no longer appear in Events-based areas:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="y91ggM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;First up, Events. Now across Android, iOS, and web, Events from accounts you’ve blocked or muted won’t appear in your Explore tab, “What’s happening” sidebar and emails, or Event-based notifications.&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1480958895287939072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 11, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="56qsSQ"&gt;If / when the ability to mute is extended even further, we’ll add it to this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W3o5ip"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 12th, 2022, 10:00AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on February 19th, 2020, and has been updated to allow for UI changes and new features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22878708/twitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22878708/twitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T19:23:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T19:23:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon, AT&amp;T, and T-Mobile say they’re not blocking Apple’s iCloud Private Relay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bVCnW6IcjHg1auWUvneXHpkTC_U=/128x0:1073x630/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70376980/og__ishslgdhhimq.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gsPVr9"&gt;T-Mobile, Verizon, and AT&amp;amp;T — the three biggest US cellular carriers — have all confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that they aren’t blocking Apple’s new iCloud Private Relay feature, following reports that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"&gt;some customers were having issues&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"&gt;with the VPN-like feature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kjO0fq"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon straight-up say they’re not blocking the feature from functioning. Verizon spokesperson George L. Koroneos confirms that Private Relay works on both cellular and Fios internet connections, and AT&amp;amp;T spokesperson Seth Bloom says the carrier’s policy is not to block Private Relay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9IG6Sn"&gt;T-Mobile’s situation is a little more complex: most customers shouldn’t have any issues with iCloud Private Relay. But those who use content filtering services (like the carrier’s Family Controls) won’t be able to use iCloud Private Relay, the carrier tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fa5X2u"&gt;“Customers who chose plans and features with content filtering (e.g. parent controls) do not have access to the iCloud Private Relay to allow these services to work as designed. All other customers have no restrictions,” T-Mobile spokesperson Bennet Ladyman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. That tracks with Apple’s messaging around the feature, which notes that “Networks that require the ability to audit traffic or perform network-based filtering will block access to Private Relay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uuaZLl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"T-Mobile identifies issue that prevented some iPhone users from using Private Relay","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="X5VL8i"&gt;T-Mobile’s spokesperson also told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the carrier &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; find an issue with Apple’s recent iOS 15.2 update that caused iCloud Private Relay to be toggled off following the update. “Overnight our team identified that in the 15.2 iOS release, some device settings default to the feature being toggled off. We have shared this with Apple. This is not specific to T-Mobile.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LnIzGG"&gt;If the problem really is on Apple’s end, it could also explain the issues that some Verizon or AT&amp;amp;T customers may have been experiencing in the wake of the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o68AKN"&gt;That said, it’s possible that carriers may sour on supporting Apple’s privacy feature in the future. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.telegraph.co.uk%2Fbusiness%2F2022%2F01%2F09%2Fapple-fire-iphone-encryption-tech%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22878885%2Fverizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Telegraph&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Vodafone, Telefonica, Orange, and T-Mobile have all signed a joint letter asking the European Commission to block Private Relay, arguing that the feature is “cutting off other networks and servers from accessing vital network data and metadata, including those operators in charge of the connectivity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZv0Sy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;iCloud Private Relay&lt;/a&gt; is similar in many ways to a VPN, working to automatically mask your internet traffic from both Apple, your ISP, and anyone else trying to snoop around what you’re doing online. The feature is still in beta but is currently available to anyone subscribing to a paid iCloud plan — although Apple doesn’t keep it toggled on by default, at least for now. There are other limitations, too: Private Relay won’t let you spoof your internet as coming from outside your rough geographic area (a popular use for VPNs to get around national or regional content limits), and it only works in Apple’s own Safari browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Apm9t5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T15:10:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T15:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile identifies issue that prevented some iPhone users from using Private Relay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a679SQQpMlD7hp-oo9jH_r4cJPA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70372164/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4lX89e"&gt;T-Mobile said Tuesday that it had not blocked iCloud Private relay, and that it had identified what was causing some iPhone users to appear blocked from using the feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OE9nGi"&gt;“Overnight our team identified that in the 15.2 iOS release, some device settings default to the feature being toggled off. We have shared this with Apple. This is not specific to T-Mobile. Again though, we have not broadly blocked iCloud Private,” the company &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1480987702363189248?s=20"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reporter Mark Gurman. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HhyPo0"&gt;iCloud Private Relay lets users hide the websites they visit from third parties, according to a report from &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/10/t-mobile-block-icloud-private-relay/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;VPN-like Private Relay&lt;/a&gt; hides your web activity from any outside sources — including Apple and your carrier — and prevents anyone from identifying you or the sites you access. It’s currently available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc"&gt;via a subscription to iCloud Plus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5ygsEB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TMobileHelp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TMobileHelp&lt;/a&gt; What the hey?  Why are you keeping us from using &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; ‘s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/icloud?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#icloud&lt;/a&gt; private relay? &lt;a href="https://t.co/EtdxkVSpWh"&gt;pic.twitter.com/EtdxkVSpWh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jon Guidry (@guidryjd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/guidryjd/status/1480599787577696260?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 10, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hwCA9M"&gt;Private Relay is still in beta in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, and it isn’t turned on by default. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;You have to go into your iPhone’s settings to switch it on&lt;/a&gt;, which is where some T-Mobile customers first noticed the message above appearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z095du"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/guidryjd/status/1480631410239094797?s=20"&gt;a reply to that tweet&lt;/a&gt;, the user shows what happens when you click the “Learn More” button below the initial message — there, Apple explains why T-Mobile might be blocking the feature. “Networks that require the ability to audit traffic or perform network-based filtering will block access to Private Relay,” it reads. “Your cellular provider may be providing network-based services, such as Parental Controls, requiring them to view the traffic on your network.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7oYDJF"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://tmo.report/2022/01/t-mobile-blocking-icloud-private-relay-for-some-but-its-not-what-you-think/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The T-Mo Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;iCloud Private Relay conflicts with a number of T-Mobile services, but that doesn’t appear to be the case here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j4ZROa"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/10/european-carriers-seek-to-block-iphone-private-relay-feature/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;iPhone users in Europe were the first to notice that access to the Private Relay feature wasn’t working. T-Mobile, Vodafone, and Telefonica added their names to an open letter published in &lt;a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2022/01/09/apple-fire-iphone-encryption-tech/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that criticizes the feature. Carriers argue that Private Relay “will impair others to innovate and compete in downstream digital markets and may negatively impact operators’ ability to efficiently manage telecommunication networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWnp0v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 11th, 4:48AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated with additional &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://tmo.report/2022/01/t-mobile-blocking-icloud-private-relay-for-some-but-its-not-what-you-think/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;reporting by The T-Mo Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k79kN0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 11th 3:00PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated throughout with comment from T-Mobile about the cause of the issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0rTF96"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T11:23:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T11:23:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony Xperia 5 III now shipping in the US, almost nine months after initial announcement</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YoS7oZk0NVKgSCFSQhWYKCyGe-U=/87x0:1022x623/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70374527/image.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e3KHRc"&gt;Sony’s Xperia 5 III, the compact counterpart to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22580552/sony-xperia-1-iii-review-price-specs-screen-camera"&gt;Xperia 1 III&lt;/a&gt;, is &lt;a href="https://pressroom.pixelshift.studio/sony-electronics-highly-anticipated-xperiar-5-iii-smartphone-now-shipping-in-the-united-states"&gt;now on sale in the US&lt;/a&gt;, almost nine months after the company initially announced the device &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382887/sony-announces-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii"&gt;in April 2021&lt;/a&gt;. The phone retails for $999.99 and will be available in black or green, with the latter exclusive to Sony’s own online store. The phone went on sale in the second half of last year in the UK and Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ktKLs8"&gt;The phone has seen some internal upgrades compared to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514064/sony-xperia-5-ii-review"&gt;Xperia 1 II&lt;/a&gt;, which bring it more into line with mainstream handsets from 2021. It’s powered by a Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 processor, runs Android 11 out of the box, and should also be able to benefit from at least some 5G connectivity in the US. Elsewhere, battery capacity has been upped to 4,500mAh, and Sony advertises that this larger battery can be charged to 50 percent in half an hour, like its predecessor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8e7JgyoV9gkitL48wARyEBuXEVk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23160681/auto.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A tall display paired with three rear cameras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gjED2g"&gt;Externally the Xperia 5 III has a similar design to the Xperia 5 II. Its 120Hz 6.1-inch display maintains Sony’s trademark 21:9 aspect ratio, and there are still three rear 12-megapixel cameras, which handle main, ultrawide, and telephoto duties, respectively. There’s support for taking photos at up to 20fps, with focus / exposure readings happening at 60fps, as well as support for recording 120fps 4K footage in HDR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rvspRt"&gt;It’s a decent set of specs, and if the Xperia 1 III is anything to go by, the phone should have decent camera performance and a stunning screen. But $999 seems like a high price when, very soon, we’re going to start seeing phones releasing with Qualcomm’s newer Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xr8tB8"&gt;The Xperia 5 III is shipping now, and Sony says that orders placed before February 27th will come with a pair of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/5/20682334/sony-wf-1000xm3-wireless-earbuds-hands-on-preview-features"&gt;WF-1000XM3&lt;/a&gt; earbuds and 43,200 &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; CP points for free. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878181/sony-xperia-5-iii-us-price-release-date-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878181/sony-xperia-5-iii-us-price-release-date-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Everything you need to know about 2022’s biggest chips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BA-qOvlIZpUM9jZivpdTDrd-cLY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70374177/acastro_210430_1777_semiCon_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Yd7xYj"&gt;It’s a new year, and like clockwork, 2022 has brought with it a plethora of new chips for laptops, desktops, phones, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEs5sx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22855915/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-chips-ces-2022-h-series-laptops-gaming-performance"&gt;Intel announced new CPUs&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866533/intel-12th-gen-cpu-alder-lake-mainstream-consumer-desktops-ces-2022"&gt;virtually every product it makes&lt;/a&gt;, AMD refreshed its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856150/amd-ryzen-6000-laptop-chips-gaming-battery-life-zen-3-plus-ces-2022"&gt;laptop processors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856150/amd-ryzen-6000-laptop-chips-gaming-battery-life-zen-3-plus-ces-2022"&gt;graphics cards&lt;/a&gt; for its whole lineup &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; started teasing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856151/amd-ryzen-7000-desktop-cpu-5nm-next-gen-zen-4-release-date-ces-2022"&gt;its next major desktop overhaul&lt;/a&gt;, and Nvidia came out swinging with the announcement of its most &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866454/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3090-ti-specifications-release-date-price-ces-2022"&gt;powerful GPU yet&lt;/a&gt;. If you weren’t keeping up (or even if you were) it was a &lt;em&gt;lot.&lt;/em&gt; And that was just CES: Qualcomm already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"&gt;announced &lt;em&gt;its&lt;/em&gt; next-gen chips&lt;/a&gt; for smartphones and laptops in December, and Samsung is teeing up a new Exynos processor, too. And that’s not even considering Apple, which tends to play its cards closer to its chest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWkn4I"&gt;But as the dust settles and products with that plethora of processors start to loom on the horizon, here’s a breakdown of 2022’s most important chips, and what they’ll mean when you’re looking for a new laptop, computer, or phone this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WBK3tc"&gt;Laptops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MZOC9y"&gt;2022 is shaping up to be a very interesting year for new laptops, thanks to AMD and Intel — both of which announced full slates of new laptop chips at CES 2022, which will likely power almost any major computer released this year that doesn’t have an Apple logo on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="392Zcv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Lots of new laptop hardware&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wWZNLm"&gt;Intel’s updates appear to be the more notable of the two companies, with the announcement of its Alder Lake family of chips for its entire laptop range (although only the most powerful H-series chips made their formal debut; the U-series and P-series lineups for lighter-weight laptops are set to arrive later in 2022). Like last year’s Alder Lake desktop chips, the new laptop chips are the first to feature Intel’s new (some might say Arm-esque) architecture with a mix of performance and efficiency cores.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rZoUXLvvbEWktQCn47-4fD92mQw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142901/12th_gen_mobile_chip_pose_06_4000px.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eSEIB2"&gt;The first wave of Alder Lake desktop processors were &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; impressive, a breakthrough product for an Intel that had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22597713/intel-7nm-delay-summer-2020-apple-arm-switch-roadmap-gelsinger-ceo"&gt;been caught in a yearslong slump of delays&lt;/a&gt; for its 10nm process (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594074/intel-acclerated-new-architecture-roadmap-naming-7nm-2025"&gt;since renamed Intel 7&lt;/a&gt;). If Intel can realize similar success on its laptop lineup, Alder Lake could be the edge the company needs to fend off an ascendant AMD and Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n8CJwX"&gt;Processors are only a piece of the puzzle, though, and Intel’s biggest product of 2022 was still largely missing from CES 2022: its upcoming lineup of discrete Arc GPUs, which will be rolling out later this year for desktop &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;laptop devices. The company has already started teasing that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865560/intel-arc-gpu-teaser-alchemist-ces-2022-oem"&gt;major partners like Dell, HP, and Samsung&lt;/a&gt; will be using its chips (in addition to adding the requirement that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856046/intel-evo-laptop-standard-foldable-laptops-h-series-project-athena-ces-2022"&gt;Intel Evo-branded laptops&lt;/a&gt; with discrete GPUs will need to be using Arc chips to get Intel’s seal of approval). And Intel is making big promises about the potential of combining its integrated graphics in conjunction with discrete Arc GPUs &lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/adaptix/deep-link.html"&gt;through its Deep Link technology&lt;/a&gt; for bigger gains. But for now, Arc is still one of the biggest question marks for 2022’s computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HaRkIf"&gt;On the other side of the aisle are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856150/amd-ryzen-6000-laptop-chips-gaming-battery-life-zen-3-plus-ces-2022"&gt;AMD’s new Ryzen 6000 chips&lt;/a&gt; for its laptops. This year’s chips still are using a slightly upgraded architecture from last year’s Ryzen 5000 (AMD calls its Zen 3 Plus and called out a few improvements like bumps to performance and battery life). That’s fine, given that last year’s Ryzen chips were already great —&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt; AMD’s 2021 laptops were its first truly premium designs in ages&lt;/a&gt;, with great battery life, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22548663/razer-blade-14-review-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen-9-5900hx-nvidia-rtx-3070"&gt;excellent performance&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465565/asus-rog-strix-g15-advantage-edition-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;powerful discrete GPUs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RG-699T4XpCmshx07FoajVAvCDU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23160565/Screen_Shot_2022_01_11_at_9.03.17_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LIzmAa"&gt;The integrated GPU side of things, though, is where this year’s biggest changes are for AMD, which is finally upgrading to its new RDNA 2 architecture here instead of continuing to use its old Vega GPU designs. RDNA 2 is the same architecture that the PS5 and Xbox Series X have, and while the integrated GPUs on 2022 AMD laptops won’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; approach the power of those consoles, they’re even closer (with the top Radeon RX 6850M XT GPU actually offering more compute units than the PS5 does). All told, AMD is promising some big boosts for gaming on laptops, which is an exciting prospect… if the chips actually hold up to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DDKUDN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;AMD has some big gaming updates&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9jtJYV"&gt;And for those who need more power, AMD also has a slate of new notebook GPUs, expanding its lower-end range for its 6000M series chips. It’s also introducing a new, more power-efficient line of Radeon 6000S chips for thinner and lighter laptops that — in theory — won’t have to compromise on gaming performance. Both of those lineups will be based on RDNA 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Nr1FZ"&gt;Lastly, there’s Nvidia, which announced a refreshed wave of powerful laptop GPUs that are coming soon: mobile versions of the RTX 3080 Ti and RTX 3070 Ti, which promise 1440p gaming at 100 and 120 frames per second and can integrate with a laptop’s CPU to balance power and temperature for maximum performance. Nvidia tells us they’re roughly 10-20 percent more powerful than their non-Ti laptop predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qmhmdp6umSn-6Sp_vSd5gNaW7vc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23144576/chrome_MtQmNzsoUF.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vpKkNV"&gt;All said, it’s an exciting time to be looking to buy a new laptop in the coming weeks or months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLbYKa"&gt;Of course, all that goes without acknowledging the elephant in the room: Apple, which has not so quietly been establishing itself as a silicon force to be reckoned with thanks to its excellent M1 series of processors. (They recently received high-powered upgrades in the company’s late 2021 MacBook Pros — resulting in some of the best performance and battery life on any computer &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has ever tested.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mmTDnB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Qualcomm will probably have to wait until next year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uTNRI3"&gt;Qualcomm is also trying again to make inroads with laptops, a market that the company (which thoroughly dominates mobile SoCs) has yet to really break into in any meaningful way. This year, the company has its new Snapdragon 8cx Gen 3 chipset, which the company says offers an 85 percent jump in CPU performance and a 60 percent faster GPU compared to Qualcomm’s previous laptop chip. That said, the new platform is off to a slow start: CES 2022 came and went without a single device announced using the 8cx Gen 3, and Qualcomm itself seems to be pinning its future not on its current flagship laptop chip, but a 2023 chip designed by the Nuvia team that will “set the performance benchmark for Windows PCs.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ovBXVa"&gt;While Apple didn’t make an appearance at CES 2022, the shadow of its chips were definitely felt: Intel defiantly rolled out slides of benchmarks claiming its new Alder Lake H-series chips were even more powerful than Cupertino’s best — something that we’ll have to test for ourselves when 2022’s new crop of laptops roll around. Battery life on Intel’s chips is also a big question mark, one that the company didn’t really address in its announcements. Nvidia also took a shot at Apple, arguing that its new RTX Studio-branded computers with its new GPUs can offer seven times the GPU performance as Apple’s M1 Max. But Apple itself is rumored to have its second-generation processors out later this year, which could throw 2022’s chip crown into contention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bB4Rcr"&gt;Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UHmEEY"&gt;The desktop side of things was a little calmer at CES 2022. Intel caught up the rest of its desktop lineup to Alder Lake, as well (last year’s launch was just a trio of high-powered gaming chips). The new lineup should bring Intel’s new architecture strategy (which has two types of processor cores) to the rest of its desktops, including more consumer-friendly desktop towers and all-in-one PCs. The company also rolled out new, cheaper motherboard designs to go with the broader release of chips (which were badly needed, given that until now there was just a single high-end chipset available). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wE3ADt"&gt;AMD (which hasn’t updated its desktop lineup since late 2020) only announced a single new chip coming in the first half of the year: Ryzen 7 5800X3D, which uses AMD’s 3D V-Cache stacking technology to squeak out an extra 15 percent of power compared to the Ryzen 5900X. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1hqEZvMf4RISZQ6DQob6ZI5lwBU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23144140/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_8.02.34_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bvFlJm"&gt;More exciting things are on the horizon for later in 2022, though, even if there’s going to be a bit of a wait to get them. AMD has started its next big processor refresh with the Ryzen 7000 line of chips, which will be powered by the company’s new Zen 4 architecture, jump to a 5nm process node, and add a new socket. The chips will switch to AMD’s new AM5 design, which puts pins on the motherboard instead of the CPUs. That means that for the first time in over five years, you’ll have to get a new motherboard to take advantage of AMD’s new CPUs. Those chips won’t arrive until the second half of the year, but they should make a pretty big splash when they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJoeCr"&gt;Nvidia also showed off its upcoming RTX 3090 Ti, which will take the crown as the company’s most powerful consumer graphics card when it arrives later this year (with a presumably sky-high price tag to match its performance).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d1NA3pSU803m-Z4iGtlydXb4VJI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23144510/rtx3090Ti.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fMlJhI"&gt;Similar to the laptop side of things, 2022’s most mysterious chip product is Intel’s upcoming Arc discrete GPUs. Codenamed “Alchemist,” Intel will finally look to take on AMD and Nvidia directly for the minds, hearts, and GPU slots of gamers and creatives alike when it launches its extremely hyped consumer graphics cards later in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zkYSih"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Arc is inbound&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="okM4gJ"&gt;Intel has already showed off some interesting demos, like its XeSS super-sampling for 4K scaling (similar to Nvidia’s DLSS or AMD’s FidelityFX Super Resolution). But the real test will come when the first GPUs actually ship. The current crop of rumors expect that Intel will be targeting the middle of the road for its first generation of GPUs (one leak from last fall &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/news/intel-arc-alchemist-gpu-could-be-a-game-changer-heres-everything-we-know"&gt;expects Intel’s best first-gen card&lt;/a&gt; to be competitive with about an RTX 3070), but we’ll have to wait for later this year when customers can see for themselves just how well Intel’s first major discrete GPUs in history really hold up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hnEdiD"&gt;Lastly, there’s Apple, which is rumored to be expanding its Arm-based chips to the rest of its desktop lineup in 2022, where some of its most intriguing products have yet to be updated, like its high-powered Mac Pro desktop. It’ll be interesting to see how Apple manages to scale up its chip designs to that level of power and performance — especially with the fierce competition from AMD and Intel’s refreshed lineups mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JyMcHD"&gt;Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jZrpY7"&gt;Things are a little simpler when it comes to mobile chips. If you’re buying an Android phone in the US, odds are it’ll have a Qualcomm chip powering it. If it’s a flagship device, it’ll be the recently announced Qualcomm 8 Gen 1, the company’s latest and greatest SoC that’s expected to start showing up in products like Samsung’s Galaxy S22 lineup in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cx9ECELaIfVlFXwfXgJGcLFNL0Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053632/Snapdragon_8_Gen_1_Mobile_Platform__Key_Visual__Angle_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Qualcomm&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="26x4vd"&gt;Apple will use whatever it names the next iteration of its A-series chips for the iPhone (the same money is on the A16), but it’ll be exclusively in Apple products. Samsung has its new Exynos 2200 processor, which will mix things up a bit with an AMD RDNA 2-powered GPU, but odds are it won’t ever make it to the US for a variety of licensing and modem issues (along with the simple fact that Qualcomm’s chips historically perform better than Samsung’s).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kpXs3W"&gt;Google is a company to watch, with its new Tensor SoC platform that it debuted on the Pixel 6 lineup last year; presumably, Google will be looking to follow that up with a second-generation version to power its 2022 smartphones. The company is rumored to be working on more powerful in-house chips for future Chromebooks, too — which could be extremely interesting in a world where Apple’s similarly custom-designed Arm-based laptops are some of the best computers around. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878059/chips-processors-cpu-gpu-2022-intel-amd-nvidia-qualcomm-apple-arm-x86"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878059/chips-processors-cpu-gpu-2022-intel-amd-nvidia-qualcomm-apple-arm-x86</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
