<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-06T07:12:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T07:12:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T07:12:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus Zenfone 8 Flip leak pairs flipping cameras with Snapdragon 888</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CCi4BG0vVvAlij763OVfUNK4bEs=/0x0:1296x864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69245135/asus_zenfone_8_flip_image_feat.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Zenfone 8 Flip.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/asus-zenfone-8-flip-specifications-renders-exclusive/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IDv02h"&gt;Asus’s successor to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21400709/asus-zenfone-7-flipping-triple-camera-zoom-ultrawide-battery-90hz-oled-display"&gt;last year’s Zenfone 7&lt;/a&gt; has leaked online, pointing to a return for the phones’ flipping camera array on May 12th. Specs and images of two upcoming devices — the Zenfone 8 and Zenfone 8 Flip — have been &lt;a href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/asus-zenfone-8-flip-specifications-renders-exclusive/"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, based on information provided by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ishanagarwal24/status/1389987244295950354"&gt;leaker Ishan Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;. As its name suggests, the 8 Flip has three cameras built into a mechanical flipping mechanism that rotates them over the top edge of the display to take selfies, while the 8 has two rear cameras in a more standard rectangular camera bump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MV8F8G"&gt;From the leaks, the Zenfone 8 Flip appears to be a comparatively minor spec bump compared to last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21408307/asus-zenfone-7-pro-review"&gt;Zenfone 7 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. It’s got a Snapdragon 888 processor rather than a Snapdragon 865 Plus, but the new model has the same massive 5,000mAH battery, 8GB of RAM, and 256GB of internal storage. The 1080p OLED display is still notchless thanks to the flipping cameras, still 6.67 inches in size, and still 90Hz, according to the leak. It also reportedly weighs the same at 230 grams, which could mean another heavy device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6Ffrdn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Full Specs &amp;amp; Renders of the ASUS Zenfone 8 &amp;amp; Zenfone 8 Flip, launching on May 12&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Zenfone 8 is a compact smartphone with 5.92" screen size while th 8 Flip has a 6.67" AMOLED Display.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Both feature Snapdragon 888 &amp;amp; 64MP Main Camera.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Please link &amp;amp; credit: &lt;a href="https://t.co/9ZO803tRlk"&gt;https://t.co/9ZO803tRlk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/MCc2p5ISaK"&gt;pic.twitter.com/MCc2p5ISaK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ishan Agarwal (@ishanagarwal24) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ishanagarwal24/status/1389987244295950354?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5rn2rP"&gt;The cameras also appear similar, with one key difference. While last year’s Zenfone 7 Pro had a 64 megapixel main camera paired with a 8 megapixel telephoto and 12 megapixel ultrawide, the new 8 Flip will apparently swap out the ultrawide for a 12 megapixel macro. We generally find ultrawide cameras much more useful than macro cameras on phones, making this an unfortunate change if accurate. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pocxci1AUQaLgnCeFnRDlvumiys=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22495517/asus_zenfone_8_render_01_1068x1066.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/asus-zenfone-8-flip-specifications-renders-exclusive/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Zenfone 8.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aOE2WZ"&gt;Meanwhile, the standard Zenfone 8 is a much more traditional device, according to the leak. It’ll apparently have a smaller 5.92-inch 1080p display, but internally there’s the same Snapdragon 888 processor, and 8GB of RAM, albeit with a smaller 4,000 mAh battery and 128GB of internal storage. It’ll also reportedly come with one less rear-facing camera since it lacks the telephoto of the 8 Flip. That said, it should have the same number of cameras overall thanks to its separate hole-punch selfie camera on the front. It’s also fitted with an increasingly rare headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzXUYu"&gt;No details were given on the phones’ pricing or release dates, but with a launch event reportedly coming next week, we won’t have long to wait for official information.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422561/zenfone-8-flip-leaks-specs-features-flipping-cameras-may-12-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422561/zenfone-8-flip-leaks-specs-features-flipping-cameras-may-12-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T19:43:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T19:43:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Boost Mobile’s Unlimited Plus plan now comes with talk, text, and telemedicine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4X_fGEwnFlZHAv7va5R3q9wr-xQ=/88x0:1242x769/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237815/Image_22.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Boost Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vnZy8n"&gt;In what looks to be a first in terms of subscriber perks, Boost Mobile &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.boostmobile.com%2Fadd-on-services%2Fhealth.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F4%2F22419961%2Fboost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; that its $60 per month Unlimited Plus cellphone plan will come with access to to 24/7 telemedicine through &lt;a href="https://khealth.com/primary-care/"&gt;K Health&lt;/a&gt; starting this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHkcNn"&gt;Specifically, Unlimited Plus subscribers will get all of the features of K Health’s usual $9-per-month offering. That includes the ability to text chat or hop on a video call with a doctor through the K Health app, which uses the app’s AI suggestions to identify symptoms and potential ailments, and receive actual treatment, including medications and other prescriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MC1ps4"&gt;The service is free and available for all Boost Unlimited Plus subscribers and offered at a discounted price of $7.99 per month for all of Boost Mobile’s other customers. You can sign up to get access to the service first &lt;a href="https://omniform1.com/signup/v1/5f8dbd4d4c7fa4332c668d65_607704924c7fa46eaf0721f2.html"&gt;on Boost Mobile’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BophuI"&gt;Because this is ultimately a phone plan, you’ll also get 35GB of 4G LTE data per month, after which you’ll get throttled to 2G speeds. That comes with “unlimited” talk and text, and a 30GB mobile hotspot as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGVVJh"&gt;Offering online healthcare to customers was not on the top of my list of things Boost Mobile would do &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;after getting absorbed by Dish Network&lt;/a&gt; (as part of T-Mobile’s merger with Sprint). But getting healthcare in the US is an often expensive proposition, and that’s before the bill comes after treatment. And, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;Boost has a large percentage of low-income customers&lt;/a&gt;, many of whom have likely been affected by the pandemic, so providing access to healthcare could be a real shot in the arm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEoifF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419961/boost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419961/boost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T18:38:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T18:38:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T violated labor law but can still ban workers from recording conversations, NLRB rules</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration the AT&amp;amp;amp;T logo is seen behind a..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vGaP4iyZJ5usl-36np8MwMpow54=/0x0:3888x2592/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237561/1231517624.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g8kGWp"&gt;An AT&amp;amp;T policy that bars employees from recording conversations with managers or colleagues is legal, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/case/05-CA-178637"&gt;ruling from the National Labor Relations Board Monday&lt;/a&gt;. The board found that while AT&amp;amp;T violated US labor law in how it had applied the policy, the recording ban itself was not illegal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DJMi09"&gt;According to AT&amp;amp;T’s rules, “employees may not record telephone or other conversations they have with their co-workers, managers or third parties unless such recordings are approved in advance by the Legal Department.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECrBeb"&gt;In its decision, the NLRB overturned part of an earlier ruling which said that the policy’s potential to infringe on workers’ rights outweighed AT&amp;amp;T’s need to keep customer data private. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Im8CHx"&gt;The case centers on a complaint filed by AT&amp;amp;T employee Marcus Davis in 2016. Davis served as the union steward for the Communications Workers of America Local 2336. In May 2016, he attended a meeting with an employee who was being fired and recorded the conversation. Davis’s manager found out, asked to meet with him, and deleted the recording off of his phone. He later told Davis not to encourage other employees to make in-store recordings since doing so violated AT&amp;amp;T’s rules, and noted he “did not want anyone held accountable for not following policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BP9jl"&gt;The NLRB found that Davis was engaged in protected union activity. The board said AT&amp;amp;T violated federal labor law by telling him not to encourage colleagues to make recordings and implying that there could be repercussions for those who did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WAwj6D"&gt;Yet the board also said that just because the policy was &lt;em&gt;applied&lt;/em&gt; illegally doesn’t mean it is inherently illegal. “A blanket prohibition on the continued maintenance of such rules, simply because of a single instance of unlawful application — even if that single instance is carried out by a misguided low- or mid-level supervisor whose action does not reflect corporate policy — fails to give proper weight to those legitimate interests,” the board wrote. “Indeed, it fails to give them any weight at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKF8HX"&gt;In her dissent, NLRB chairman Lauren McFerran said the rule was unlawfully over broad. “We all agree that some recordings by employees are protected by the National Labor Relations Act,”  she wrote. “By its terms, the rule does not differentiate between recordings protected by the National Labor Relations Act and those that are not...Indeed, as written, the rule applies even to conversations on nonwork time and in nonwork areas: an employee could not record a union meeting held in a breakroom at lunch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VaGYli"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T did not immediately respond to a request for comment from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419772/att-rule-barring-workers-recording-conversations-legal-federal-labor-law"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419772/att-rule-barring-workers-recording-conversations-legal-federal-labor-law</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T13:02:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T13:02:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>One of Samsung’s best phones ever is now officially retired</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S8 and Galaxy S8 Plus rear view" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8dDkt6Hi-KKqo3wFzuqknvwMqMc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69235494/jbareham_170414_1603_0044.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After four years of support, the S8 and S8 Plus will no longer receive security updates.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7CVLJg"&gt;Four years after its launch, the Samsung Galaxy S8 has received its last security update. The Galaxy S8 was a well-timed success story for Samsung, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15092590/samsung-galaxy-s8-plus-screen-size-aspect-ratio-edge"&gt;launching in the spring of 2017&lt;/a&gt; with a bold design that drew attention away from the well-documented &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/2/12767670/samsung-galaxy-note-7-recall-fire-risk"&gt;Galaxy Note 7 battery problems&lt;/a&gt; of the previous six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjJvyk"&gt;The S8 marked a design shift for Galaxy devices, with a wider-aspect edge-to-edge screen with minimal bezels that made it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15087530/samsung-galaxy-s8-announced-features-release-date-video-specifications"&gt;one of the best-looking phones&lt;/a&gt; we’d seen at that point. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/18/15328968/samsung-galaxy-s8-review-s8-plus"&gt;wasn’t just a good-looking device, either&lt;/a&gt;; it offered excellent hardware and a great camera, combined with a remarkably restrained software implementation. Best of all, the batteries did not catch fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DuyWyZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Samsung has one of the best support policies in the industry&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5X9xL1"&gt;Samsung recently introduced a formal policy of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;providing Galaxy devices with four years of security updates&lt;/a&gt;, including both S-series flagships and even budget-oriented A-series models. Premium devices tend to get monthly updates, at least for the first couple of years, with the cadence slowing down to quarterly or biannual updates toward end of life. It’s one of the best support policies in the industry — certainly for Android, and roughly on par with Apple’s typically lengthy device support schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EGe1su"&gt;While the S8 and S8 Plus have reached the end of that support period, the S8 Active is still &lt;a href="https://security.samsungmobile.com/workScope.smsb"&gt;on the schedule&lt;/a&gt; for quarterly updates and the S8 Lite is on the biannual schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419205/samsung-galaxy-s8-security-update-schedule"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419205/samsung-galaxy-s8-security-update-schedule</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T13:35:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T13:35:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dear wireless carriers: the 5G hype needs to stop</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kf0ie2OmFi9vJERCQ2Xnrr77vzc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69206320/VRG_ILLO_4037_5G_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4yHhZ4"&gt;Just stop. Stop telling us why your 5G network is the very best and fastest and most reliable. Stop running commercials about how life-changing your 5G network is. Definitely stop telling us why your 5G network is better than the other guy’s 5G network because can you &lt;em&gt;even imagine&lt;/em&gt; building a 5G network the way they have? Please stop with all of this, it’s been a very long year and we’re tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bsUxd7"&gt;It would be one thing to make all of these fantastical claims like you do if any of them reflected any real person’s experience. They don’t. Your 5G networks are just not that good yet. They’ll get better, and that’s nice! But please stop pretending like the 5G train has pulled into the station and all we have to do is get on board to be whisked away to the low-latency, Gigabit future when you’re still building the tracks. And the train station. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZrRbfP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;please stop pretending like the 5G train has pulled into the station&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9NUTGe"&gt;We’re tired of false starts. First there was 5G Evolution, which sounds exciting. It rhymes with revolution! But then it turned out to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18277484/att-fake-5g-e-network-lte-study"&gt;just another name for LTE&lt;/a&gt;, which was a bummer. Then there was mmWave, which you called Ultra Wideband because it sounds cooler. It will drive cars, do surgeries, fly drones, you said. You’ll experience download speeds on your phone so astoundingly fast that your sunglasses will fly off your face just being so close. And sure enough, the speed was impressive, that one time we were on the right street corner trying to download a whole movie. But then the crosswalk signal turned green and we kept walking, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326857/verizon-5g-ads-coverage-speeds-nationwide-misleading-nad-tv"&gt;we lost the signal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eNpLJv"&gt;Now we learn that Ultra Wideband suddenly means mmWave &lt;em&gt;and C-band&lt;/em&gt;, and that C-band will actually change everything and we’ll &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324345/verizon-c-band-5g-unlimited-plans"&gt;have to pay more if we want to use it&lt;/a&gt;. This is confusing, we’re tired, and now we have to go look for our sunglasses. So please let us know when you’ve settled on whatever frequencies will actually change our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="cDCA3F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Just build the network and we’ll see for ourselves if it really is great&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ngHBpI"&gt;We know you’re excited about how you’re building your 5G network, but please don’t explain to us in detail &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Fthe-current-state-of-5g&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F29%2F22409675%2Fverizon-att-tmobile-5g-mmwave-c-band" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;why your spectrum is the best spectrum&lt;/a&gt; and the other guy’s spectrum is garbage. You sound like a kid who wrote a PowerPoint presentation for her parents with a point-by-point argument for why she deserves a later bedtime. We, the general phone-using population, do not care to be dragged into these details. Just build the network and we’ll see for ourselves if it really is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="721s6X"&gt;You’ve spent a lot of time recently &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/verizon-reports-strong-start-2021-company-accelerates-5g-growth" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;breathlessly telling your shareholders&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Ft-mobile-further-solidifies-5g-leadership-position-with-successful-c-band-auction&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F29%2F22409675%2Fverizon-att-tmobile-5g-mmwave-c-band" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;why you won the C-band auction&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve been scraping the bottom of the barrel on live sports entertainment over the last year, but last time we checked, a federal spectrum auction is not the Super Bowl! Nobody’s keeping score! Unless you’re playing &lt;a href="https://calvinandhobbes.fandom.com/wiki/Calvinball"&gt;Calvinball&lt;/a&gt;, you can’t declare something to be a sport, run around the field, then put on a referee uniform and say that you won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="XR5TIx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We all just want our phone service to work when we need it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZSNlN9"&gt;This may come as a shock, but we don’t cheer for our wireless carriers as if they were baseball teams. We don’t trash-talk our friends about how our carrier’s 5G network is &lt;em&gt;absolutely crushing&lt;/em&gt; their carrier’s 5G network. We don’t ask them how they can live with themselves knowing that their carrier is building their 5G network the &lt;em&gt;wrong way&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2GP4x8"&gt;We all just want our phone service to work when we need it. We want to tweet our stupid tweets, share our dumb pet photos, follow our actual baseball teams, and do so with as little inconvenience as possible. Sure, we want faster service! But we don’t want to know how the sausage is made. Please stop for now and let us know when you’re ready to serve it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fUhMa5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aEAu9i"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409675/verizon-att-tmobile-5g-mmwave-c-band"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409675/verizon-att-tmobile-5g-mmwave-c-band</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T13:29:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T13:29:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dish chairman calls T-Mobile the ‘Grinch’ for going back on merger promises</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XcfFIuBT76j5-Jaypf0loEG6YDM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69206248/acastro_200804_1777_dish_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HgTetD"&gt;Today’s Dish Network Q1 earnings call took an unexpected turn into Whoville when chairman Charlie Ergen compared T-Mobile to the Grinch. The comparison came up when discussing the “Uncarrier’s” decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;go ahead with its CDMA shutdown&lt;/a&gt;, a move that will potentially see millions of Dish’s Boost Mobile customers losing service at the beginning of next year. Ergen made no secret what he thinks of the move: “They’ve become the Grinch.” He went on to add, “the Uncarrier’s become the uncaring carrier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1NEEk"&gt;Dish Network &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;acquired Boost as a condition of the Sprint / T-Mobile merger&lt;/a&gt; with the intention of positioning Dish to take Sprint’s place as the US’s fourth wireless carrier. A year later, the company faces a major setback following T-Mobile’s announcement that it plans to shut down the CDMA network many Boost customers use by the beginning of next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OD6CX1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Uncarrier’s become the uncaring carrier”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XKmjWh"&gt;Dish has issued statements warning that the consequences to its business would be dire, and &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/dish-california-regulators-t-mobile-inquiry-reopen-9d87c61c-8349-440c-97eb-8cde807ba9bf.html"&gt;recently asked&lt;/a&gt; the California Public Utilities Commission reopen its investigation of the merger. The company’s wireless business hasn’t been looking rosy even without considering the impending shutdown; it continued to lose subscribers with a net decrease of 161,000 last quarter, which is around half of the 363,000 it lost in the previous quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2kP87p"&gt;Ergen has previously voiced his disappointment in the timing of the shutdown, calling it anti-competitive, but he went a step further on this morning’s investor call with his Grinch metaphor, describing T-Mobile’s move as “heartless.” But he puts a hopeful spin on the metaphor, noting that the Grinch ended up giving back all of the toys he took from the Whos, and his heart grew three sizes that day. Ergen says the comparison was inspired by recently reading the book to his granddaughter, and that rather than the character’s trademark green color, he “kept seeing a magenta Grinch.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409800/dish-charlie-ergen-t-mobile-cdma-shutdown-grinch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409800/dish-charlie-ergen-t-mobile-cdma-shutdown-grinch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T18:49:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T18:49:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T is giving its top prepaid hotspot plan a big price cut and more data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F6nYNSjSefgz4FUmbf23KKjuw7g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69202232/acastro_180322_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers already enrolled in the prepaid plan will get a data boost and a lower price when their plan renews.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XCXn6a"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T says it will now offer a prepaid 5G data-only plan with up to 100GB of data for $55 per month — a big upgrade from its previous offering of 40GB for $75. The new pricing extends to Cricket Wireless customers as well as AT&amp;amp;T’s direct prepaid subscribers. These plans allow customers to buy data for their tablet or mobile hotspot separate from their voice plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DEnrf2"&gt;That 100GB is a lot of data at a lower price than the other major carriers are offering; currently, T-Mobile has a prepaid data-only plan of 50GB for $50 and Verizon has a 30GB plan for $65 per month. It may be no coincidence that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21497743/verizon-home-lte-service-rural-communities-48-states"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; are also eager to expand their own 5G and LTE-based fixed home wireless products, but AT&amp;amp;T may have a little more room to be aggressive with its mobile hotspot offerings while it remains committed to pushing its fiber home internet service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TWxMmR"&gt;The company says that current Cricket customers already enrolled in the 100GB data-only plan — previously $90 per month — will see the new price reflected on their next bill. Likewise, existing AT&amp;amp;T customers will get a data bump and a price decrease automatically. New customers can sign up for the plans starting today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oYtBqa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; A previous version of this article based on communication from an AT&amp;amp;T representative said that Cricket Wireless subscribers would not be able to use 5G hotspot data. That is not the case: both AT&amp;amp;T prepaid and Cricket customers can access the 5G network as part of the plan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408326/att-mobile-internet-hotspot-prepaid-plan-5g"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408326/att-mobile-internet-hotspot-prepaid-plan-5g</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T14:29:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T14:29:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon says problems with phone calls in Southern California are now fixed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b5uYohPrrW1XYNybYSJ5xRXQML0=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195325/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o4yCkB"&gt;Many Verizon customers in Southern California reported difficulties making calls on Tuesday afternoon, and the company confirmed to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; at the time that was a “network issue” affecting voice services in parts of the region. That issue was resolved overnight, a spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Wednesday morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y4u39G"&gt;During the outage, if you were having trouble making calls, the spokesperson recommended putting your device in airplane mode or restarting your phone, which they said should fix the issues. And in response to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VZWSupport/status/1387143438316064784"&gt;one person on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, Verizon’s support account recommended using Wi-Fi “if possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jrHKmG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We do apologize, Verizon is currently experiencing a wireless network issue in your area. Our technicians are aware of this issue and are working to resolve it quickly. It is best to use Wi-Fi if possible. Please also enable Data Roaming. *AOR&lt;/p&gt;— Verizon Wireless CS (@VZWSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VZWSupport/status/1387143438316064784?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qx0gQT"&gt;On Tuesday, I found &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/carlisleshelley/status/1387139550410010627"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeorgeGoff20/status/1387140510335205377"&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of people &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RickyJimenez/status/1387140515435466752"&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tscarrithers/status/1387140551258951681"&gt;problems&lt;/a&gt; making phone calls in Southern California, but it wasn’t clear exactly how far the outage extended or exactly which areas might have been affected. Downdetector’s &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/verizon/map/"&gt;map of user reports&lt;/a&gt; strongly indicated that the outage is affected Los Angeles, San Diego, and the surrounding areas. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CyZS7tN_0NfpXa4gKbvJbGVRV_E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22474098/Screen_Shot_2021_04_27_at_2.09.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Downdetector&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Downdetector’s map of reported issues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O4DHZM"&gt;As of 4:39PM ET on Tuseday, Downdetector counted &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/verizon/"&gt;nearly 8,000 reports of problems with Verizon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSbVCq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 28th, 2:29PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added confirmation from Verizon that the outage was fixed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406419/verizon-southern-california-outage-down-phone-calls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406419/verizon-southern-california-outage-down-phone-calls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T12:45:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T12:45:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Telegram’s group video calls will finally launch in May</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ixIbVRqXLhoVbk-Qj50vBt2inbc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69199888/acastro_180417_1777_telegram_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TCa1EK"&gt;Telegram CEO Pavel Durov &lt;a href="https://t.me/durov/160"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that the iOS version of Telegram will be updated to support group video calls in May (&lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/telegram-add-group-video-calls-125053371.html"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Yahoo Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The company originally planned to add the video call feature to its messaging service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/24/21234254/telegram-messaging-app-group-video-calling-security-usability"&gt;at some point in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, but the feature never materialized. Telegram did at least make it into the new year with one video call addition: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/15/21370420/telegram-video-calls-os-android"&gt;end-to-end encrypted one-on-one video calls&lt;/a&gt; were added in August 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXaM55"&gt;Durov’s announcement of the new launch date was shared — naturally — in his personal Telegram channel. He writes that group video calls will have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="jxGndK"&gt;Screen sharing, encryption, noise-cancelling, desktop and tablet support — everything you can expect from a modern video conferencing tool, but with Telegram-level UI, speed and encryption. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="qGq5qq"&gt;Telegram already offers end-to-end encryption on its one-on-one video calling, but the company hasn’t explicitly confirmed the feature here. We’ve reached out to confirm that it plans to offer the same on group video calls when they launch in May. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fc4J8B"&gt;Telegram has grown significantly over the pandemic, taking advantage of the shift to working from home and the general desire to stay connected securely. The company announced it reached &lt;a href="https://telegram.org/blog/400-million"&gt;400 million monthly active users&lt;/a&gt; in April 2020, up from &lt;a href="https://telegram.org/blog/200-million"&gt;200 million in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Some of that has to do with its competitor, WhatsApp, fumbling how it communicated its new privacy policy to customers, which inspired some users to leave the Facebook-owned app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226792/whatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;for Telegram and Signal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tihane"&gt;Despite seeming a bit less nimble, WhatsApp actually beat Telegram to offering end-to-end encrypted group video calls. The company&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/30/17632650/whatsapp-group-video-calling-feature-now-live"&gt; added group video and voice calling&lt;/a&gt; in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407752/telegram-group-video-calls-may-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407752/telegram-group-video-calls-may-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T12:27:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T12:27:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile launches LTE-based SyncUp Tracker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-W8JVbG76a6O-mdfEZJsOyqHfqI=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69199710/SyncUP_TRACKER_Black_Front_Left_Laynard_RGB_2020_10_01_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SyncUp uses LTE rather than Bluetooth or UWB so it doesn’t need to be within range of your phone (or someone else’s) to be located.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: T-Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mfl65d"&gt;It seems that 2021 is the year of the tracker, with new options from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227621/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-price-release-date-tile-locator"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/20844326/apple-airtags-bluetooth-tracker-keys-tile-features-price"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, and now T-Mobile in the form of its SyncUp Tracker. But unlike those other &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20901686/tile-tracker-mate-pro-slim-sticker-release-date-news-features"&gt;Tile-type&lt;/a&gt; tracking devices, SyncUp uses LTE rather than Bluetooth or Ultra Wideband for real-time location information, a la &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/10/17841570/samsung-smartthings-tracker-gps-lte-m"&gt;Samsung’s SmartThings&lt;/a&gt; tracker. That means it doesn’t rely on being within a certain range of your phone (or other phones) to tell you where it is — but it does come with a $5 per month data charge on your T-Mobile phone plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oAxx6S"&gt;The SyncUp offers some nice tracking features: you can make the device ring to help locate it when it’s out of sight, for example, and it offers geofencing to send you an alert when it leaves a predetermined area. It’s also IP67 dust and water resistant. More unusually, it offers a light sensor as an optional feature to detect if it’s been moved from somewhere dark, like the inside of a suitcase, to somewhere brighter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DzKIvKSkEiy0BEErMMBX5VLh1no=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22475640/T_Mobile_SyncUP_TRACKER_Lifestyle_Bike_21CM0084_030421_0918.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: T-Mobile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SyncUp’s rechargeable battery should last up to seven days on a charge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="urUnmC"&gt;Some trackers fit into the “set it and forget it” category with long-lasting batteries that only need to be replaced once a year or so. The SyncUp is not one of these devices. Its 900mAh battery needs to be recharged about once every seven days, so it’ll either be something you use occasionally as needed, or one more gadget in your life that you have to remember to charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cifbMS"&gt;Since the SyncUp operates on T-Mobile’s data network, you’ll need one of their data plans to use it: specifically, a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fplans&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F28%2F22407716%2Ft-mobile-syncup-tracker-lte-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;postpaid Magenta plan&lt;/a&gt;, though the company says it plans to make the tracker available for Sprint and prepaid customers in the future. With autopay, T-Mobile says prices start at $5 per month per connected device, and it’s compatible with both Android and iOS phones. It goes on sale next Friday, May 7th, for $60 outright or $2.50 per month with financing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407716/t-mobile-syncup-tracker-lte-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407716/t-mobile-syncup-tracker-lte-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
