<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Mobiles</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-27T14:43:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/mobile/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/mobile" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-27T14:43:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-27T14:43:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon Go Fest is back this July as a global event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KNf92PjhiT2Bf076B3GdZyXX_4Q=/128x0:896x512/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69194356/Ez_vg5sWEAQ5F9D.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A promotional image for Pokémon Go Fest 2021.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Niantic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y8aulW"&gt;The annual &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; Fest is back again this summer, scheduled for July 17th and 18th. Last year’s event was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/27/21272334/pokemon-go-fest-2020-online-niantic"&gt;held online&lt;/a&gt; due to the COVID-19 pandemic, instead of taking place in person in select cities around the globe. It sounds like this year’s fest will once again happen virtually; developer Niantic describes the event as a “global event.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F6Rc4S"&gt;Niantic didn’t share many other details, though it did tease that this year’s event could be particularly noteworthy. “2021 marks both the twenty-fifth anniversary of Pokémon and the fifth anniversary of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, so trust us when we say you won’t want to miss &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; Fest 2021!” &lt;a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/pokemongofest2021-save-the-date"&gt;Niantic said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qxExJA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Time to mark your calendars, Trainers!  ️ &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonGOFest2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#PokemonGOFest2021&lt;/a&gt; will be a two-day global event from July 17 to July 18!   We can’t wait to show you what’s in store. &lt;a href="https://t.co/L0fcETooMj"&gt;https://t.co/L0fcETooMj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/jljTUQBE1h"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jljTUQBE1h&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Pokémon GO (@PokemonGoApp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonGoApp/status/1387090560637456384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fF0EfE"&gt;Last year’s online-only &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; Fest was a huge success, with “a record number of millions of trainers” in 124 countries and regions catching nearly a billion pokémon in total, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/28/21344717/pokemon-go-fest-2020-stats-numbers-niantic"&gt;Niantic said&lt;/a&gt; after the 2020 fest. Niantic also said that players walked nearly 15 kilometers each on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1wspHO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Pokémon Go players caught nearly a billion pokémon at this year’s online-only fest","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/28/21344717/pokemon-go-fest-2020-stats-numbers-niantic"},{"title":"Pokémon Go Fest will be held online this year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/27/21272334/pokemon-go-fest-2020-online-niantic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406090/pokemon-go-fest-2021-dates-july"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406090/pokemon-go-fest-2021-dates-july</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-27T14:31:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-27T14:31:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>ZTE is selling a $200 phone with wireless charging through Visible and Yahoo Mobile</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sjp5VRooId_eTJ7urb12esvpm5Y=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69194294/Blade_11_Prime_Front_Left.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZTE Blade 11 Prime features a 6.5-inch display and also supports wired reverse charging.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: ZTE&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cR9ydL"&gt;ZTE is offering a feature rarely seen in the budget class of phones: wireless charging. The Blade 11 Prime is on sale now in the US for $192 through Visible and Yahoo Mobile, two MVNOs that use Verizon’s network. It’s an otherwise fairly unremarkable budget device, with a 6.5-inch 720p display shipping with Android 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdOn9x"&gt;In addition to wireless charging, the Blade 11 Prime supports reverse wired charging to provide some power to other devices in a pinch. However, the phone’s 4,000mAh battery is on the smaller side, so the feature is probably best reserved for emergencies. The 11 Prime uses a MediaTek 6762 chipset with 4GB of RAM and offers 64GB of built-in storage. It features 16-megapixel standard and 8-megapixel wide rear-facing cameras, plus an 8-megapixel selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t200QA9ZovjDyprLI6twl9ojvXY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22473490/Blade_11_Prime_Back.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: ZTE&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 11 Prime includes a 16-megapixel main camera in its rear triple-cam array.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DUlctz"&gt;There’s not a lot to get excited about here outside of wireless charging, but it is a nice feature to have available as an option in the budget class. More than a few phones around $200, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;Moto G Power&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22213714/oneplus-n10-5g-n100-nord-north-american-release"&gt;OnePlus Nord N100&lt;/a&gt;, offer huge battery capacity as a differentiating feature, but the option to use a wireless charger that’s likely compatible with other gadgets you already own is another handy proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405828/zte-blade-11-prime-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405828/zte-blade-11-prime-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-27T10:30:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-27T10:30:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Backbone One is a stunning controller that turns your iPhone into a more capable gaming device</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Complete with software features that make it easy to join parties, record, and share video clips&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="mbWWFf"&gt;As the high-profile disputes about what content you can play on your iPhone rage on between Apple, Epic Games, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357771/apple-cloud-gaming-microsoft-xcloud-google-stadia-ios-app-store-guidelines-violations"&gt;Google, and Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, a company called Backbone is focusing instead on making sure you get the most out of the games that are currently available. Like Razer did with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21431952/razer-kishi-controller-iphone-ios-review"&gt;Kishi controller for iOS&lt;/a&gt;, and as other companies have with snap-on controllers of their own, Backbone is introducing one for $100 that it calls the Backbone One. You can &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fplaybackbone.com%2Fproducts%2Fbackbone-one%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21525741%2Fbackbones-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy it from Backbone’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JltN1G"&gt;With the controller fully extended, it can fit any iPhone running iOS 13 or later, starting with the iPhone 6S and including the new iPhone 12 lineup. It’s great for Apple Arcade games that support controllers. &lt;em&gt;Sky: Children of the Light&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; play wonderfully with the One. And, for popular games like &lt;em&gt;COD: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; that don’t have controller support switched on from the start, Backbone curates visual tutorials that appear before it launches to walk you through the steps to turn it on in the game’s settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oj5Dex"&gt;Since the Backbone One launched, it now works with &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393793/microsoft-xbox-cloud-gaming-xcloud-iphone-ipad-hands-on"&gt;the xCloud iOS beta&lt;/a&gt; for Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22176273/google-stadia-ios-beta-live-now-mobile-safari-iphone-ipad-cloud-gaming"&gt;Google Stadia&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Even playing games like &lt;em&gt;Hades &lt;/em&gt;through the Steam Link app (with my PC connected via Wi-Fi) felt surprisingly natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h1n-iRgtg4cNfJG9iV9Qy9fsR30=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989942/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The analog stick is sized similarly to the ones built into the Joy-Con for Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwtkqN-w96Qpe_ZU3kc0i5S13g4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989940/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The triggers are also similar to those on the Joy-Con, yet these have a more satisfying travel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RBU5X5"&gt;Unlike most controller accessories made thus far, the Backbone One is a hybrid of tightly integrated hardware and software. If we’re looking at the hardware, it’s arguably the best of its kind yet. Both sides of this controller have rounded edges that fit naturally in my hand. I praised the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21285073/razer-kishi-review-game-controller-phone-price-nintendo-switch-stadia"&gt;design of the Razer Kishi&lt;/a&gt;, but this has a more subtle look that doesn’t cover up as much of your phone’s edges. Each button has a more responsive, tactile click, and the analog sticks feel roughly the same size as Nintendo’s Joy-Con for the Switch. Speaking of the Joy-Con, the One’s rear triggers actually feel &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="58jOQj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:9545130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dT19br"&gt;The Backbone One features passthrough Lightning charging, with support for Lightning headphones if you have a set. It also has a 3.5mm headphone jack, giving you another way to listen to audio — even if your iPhone doesn’t have the port itself. As for power consumption, Backbone says the One itself demands less power from your iPhone than many wired Lightning earbuds do. I didn’t notice more battery usage during gameplay with the controller attached than I normally would without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R4p9F_Zg3IM1_Vae-Y_dIeslxJI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989938/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0008.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miraculously, the One adds a 3.5mm port, so bust out those wired headphones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RfRkKTciPYMa4kacwguTUQNRdnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989939/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0007.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lightning port supports passthrough charging, as well as audio for Lightning EarPods.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l1gqUO"&gt;The hardware alone might make it worth the purchase, but the software is what really makes it unique. The One doesn’t require its companion app to work with any iOS game that supports a controller, but using the app turns your iPhone into a game console of sorts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jz4iFB"&gt;Pushing the controller’s orange Backbone button while the One is connected to your phone will open up the Backbone app, which looks like an operating system. There, you’ll find all of your installed games cleanly laid out in an almost tvOS-esque interface. The app also shows new games available for download in the App Store that support controllers. To add games to the Backbone interface, just tap the orange button when you first boot up each new game. This app takes advantage of the iPhone’s excellent haptics to buzz when you flip around the menu, and the company made its own satisfyingly subtle vibration effect that you’ll feel while quickly flying through a bunch of tiles in the interface with the L1 and R1 shoulder buttons. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-efuXwQzJPeyAGX1M8hsh_zbU_E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989937/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A full look at what you’ll see when you press the orange Backbone button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ru0rOB"&gt;Scroll down a little more in the app, and you’ll find photo and video clips you’ve saved and those from friends. This controller has a dedicated button to let you snap a screenshot in-game, or even record a video clip, which are features that should be familiar to anyone who’s used a modern gaming console. Notably here, though, is that you can press and hold that button for a moment to bookmark key moments on the fly. The Backbone button illuminates a red LED while you’re recording, so it’s easy to see at a glance when you’re live. Backbone handles recording and accessing clips much more elegantly than the Xbox One, PS4, PC, or Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zmj6IX"&gt;After a video clip is saved, you can then trim and share the clip in the Backbone app, as well as via iMessage or any social media apps you use. One special thing to note is that Backbone says it can record 1080p clips at 30 frames per second in the HEVC / H.265 codec (supported on the iPhone 7 and newer), so you’ll have higher-quality video without sacrificing as much storage space as other codecs require. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qDEF3SLBaPKkIkl_SrS9MuVoyhI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989936/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0011.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Backbone button pulses red to indicate when you’re recording the screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oSMZng"&gt;Yet another software feature you’ll get with the controller is the ability to create parties and voice chat with friends in the app. These parties operate independently of the game you’re each playing (you don’t even need to be playing a game), so it’s a good way to connect even if you aren’t all into &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, for example. If you’re into recording clips with your friends, the video recording feature will pick up your voice in the mix, along with everyone else’s in the party (indicated by the small orange light near the iPhone’s top bezel in iOS 14). Each participant can choose to mute their mic by double-pressing the left-most button that has three horizontal dots.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kgmECWkKc--QQXEotbQMAmPsNHI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989935/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0012.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can start or join a party to voice chat through the Backbone app with other users for free.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CHeiZ4"&gt;Snapshots, video recording, and organizing parties for voice chat are just a few ways in which Backbone takes the reins in iOS to create a more interesting experience than Apple itself offers to gamers. It also offers rich presence notifications, chiming in with a notification — whether you’re in the Backbone app or not — to tell you when a friend has logged on, or with an invite that you can click to join a party. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hxoO9S"&gt;On its face, the Backbone One is just a controller — and a very good one, at that. But with software enhancements that take advantage of iOS in some clever ways, Backbone makes the iPhone feel like a bona fide gaming platform that I want to remain a part of. When the hardware and software are all working together, with the ability to easily join up with friends and record clips, the One feels like a gaming experience that somehow beats Apple to the punch of fleshing out its own gaming ambitions. It is no longer just like a phone strapped into a few pieces of plastic but the start of something very special. And for $100, without monthly charges to use its software and party tools, it’s an appealing price if you do a lot of mobile gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="BackBone One" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IEqzM-niSipNq1wH_IfrUwzzutc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989945/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0001.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Backbone One controller supports all the way back to the iPhone 6S.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="bFdquo"&gt;As well as it works on iOS, the Backbone One seems perhaps better suited to launch on Android, given that &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; isn’t available on Apple’s App Store. Though, since the One launched, Google Stadia and Microsoft’s xCloud game streaming services have come to iOS, giving you more content to play than before. Backbone wouldn’t comment when I asked about an Android-specific version of the One. But this iOS controller is already worth the cost of admission if you’re an Apple Arcade subscriber or just enjoy a few one-off games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jIGiuB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHPQc6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 27th, 10:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Backbone confirmed that &lt;/em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;em&gt; is supported by the One. Also, I’ve updated this review to note that Google Stadia and xCloud are both accessible on iOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbones-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbones-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-27T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-27T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why Apple’s new privacy feature is such a big deal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_G4X8M_S6lSPjjJ01aHa2-DOPBw=/105x0:3255x2100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69192532/app_tracking_transparency.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YSB2td"&gt;Apple’s latest iPhone update, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403554/apple-ios-ipados-14-5-now-available-iphone-unlock-face-mask-app-tracking"&gt;iOS 14.5&lt;/a&gt;, brings a host of new features that customers will likely see and enjoy — better Face ID unlocking when wearing a mask (for Apple Watch users only), new emoji, support for PS5 and Xbox Series X controllers, and more. But the new update also adds a much more important and  controversial new feature: App Tracking Transparency. That’s Apple’s name for a privacy feature that’s shaping up to be the company’s next big fight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nivnR1"&gt;The change has been a contentious one. Apple originally announced the feature alongside the rest of iOS 14 last June &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/3/21420176/apple-ios-14-tracking-permission-rule-developers-delay"&gt;but has delayed the release until now&lt;/a&gt; to give developers more time to adapt to the changes. It’s finally live, though, setting the stage for what could be a massive fight between the Cupertino tech giant and competitors like Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="EygHYi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use iOS 14.5’s new app tracking blocker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22403523/ios-14-5-tracking-consent-app-transparency-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ddAD0r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did ad tracking work on iOS before?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mHQP3A"&gt;Before iOS 14.5, developers could use a host of tools to track user data from within an app. Advertisers could then use it in conjunction with similar data from around the rest of the web to broadly identify information about a user and use that profile to better target them with advertisements (and sell those advertisement opportunities to other companies and businesses that want to focus on their specific marketing segments). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GDglwp"&gt;The main tool that’s been available to developers until now has been an Apple-controlled system that’s been around for almost a decade, Identifier for Advertisers (IDFA), but developers could also use other third-party tools and methods to cobble together user data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i8konp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does App Tracking Transparency change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dFboTG"&gt;Technically, App Tracking Transparency alone doesn’t make any seismic changes to how iOS handles ad tracking. Users have been able to opt out of IDFA-based tracking before, but the new update puts the choice front and center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cA4LSg"&gt;It forces developers to give users a choice: once updated to iOS 14.5, every single company that wants to track users and their data across different apps and websites now have to ask permission first using a standardized prompt created by Apple, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rry80Qr7Mx3BYeP6skQNsVKCPmI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22472867/Untitled.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vMoguF"&gt;If users say that they’re cool with being tracked (by clicking the “Allow” button) everything works just like it did before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQSOr0"&gt;If they click “Ask app not to track,” though, then that developer can’t track customers using their data in that app, or sell that data to other companies. Not with Apple’s IDFA system, and not with their own systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZzoxT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any exceptions or alternatives? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NOPxXN"&gt;There are a few exceptions to Apple’s new app tracking rules. First, companies that own multiple apps can track users across those different apps — for example, Facebook can use data it gathers from Instagram to target ads in its main app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zz4j61"&gt;And Apple is offering new, in-house tools for developers to use instead. One tool, SKAdNetwork, can tell a company how many times its app was installed after an ad was seen. Another, Private Click Measurement, can tell them how many times users clicked on an ad for a product within an app. Apple says that both of those methods are designed to prevent companies from getting information about a specific user, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AkeMqz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are people annoyed about this? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ijBDL"&gt;App Tracking Transparency has been praised by groups like the Electronic Frontier Foundation, &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/facebooks-laughable-campaign-against-apple-really-against-users-and-small"&gt;which called the concept&lt;/a&gt; of making companies ask before they track users on the internet an “obvious baseline.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r0cwxe"&gt;But not everyone likes the system, and the strongest objections to App Tracking Transparency have been from Facebook. It says Apple’s new system will make it harder and more expensive for ad networks to easily target customers, which in turn will hurt small businesses that rely on highly targeted ad campaigns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v5HLD0"&gt;Facebook has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178068/facebook-apple-newspaper-ads-ios-privacy-changes"&gt;taken out full-page newspaper ads&lt;/a&gt; contesting the changes and argued that Apple’s changes could also hurt websites that rely on lucrative targeted ads to make ends meet, forcing them to subscription services or paywalls for content that used to be free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SqDODr"&gt;While Facebook’s main arguments appear altruistic, it’s also important to note that Facebook itself stands to lose out here. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theinformation.com%2Farticles%2Ffacebook-looks-to-take-its-fight-with-apple-to-court%3Firclickid%3D3NsQiH1XqxyLTgawUx0Mo38dUkB0YO0p3xAMRo0%26irgwc%3D1%26utm_source%3Daffiliate%26utm_medium%3Dcpa%26utm_campaign%3D10078-Skimbit%2BLtd.%26utm_term%3Dtheverge.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F27%2F22405474%2Fapple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; explains&lt;/a&gt;, the kinds of ads that Apple’s new rule impacts aren’t a huge part of Facebook’s business model — less than 5 percent of Facebook’s $84 billion annual ad revenue — but it’s still a noticeable chunk of change, especially considering that Facebook’s internal estimates reportedly expect around 80 percent of iOS users to opt out. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kwQxjzz2i6KUlQ00H5M-q9f8O4E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22472878/Untitled_1.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qabc7d"&gt;Apple is also giving companies a chance to make their case for allowing ad tracking. Developers will have control over &lt;em&gt;when &lt;/em&gt;to show Apple’s prompt, specifically to give apps like Facebook, NBC News, or BBC a chance to make their case to users about why they should allow tracking. And Facebook is doing just that, with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260274/facebook-prompt-apple-ios-ad-tracking-opt-in-permission-privacy-update"&gt;letter to users&lt;/a&gt; that tries to sell them on the idea of getting more relevant advertisements and supporting small businesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uCw19r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can companies just track me anyway?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mfLYzE"&gt;Apple’s prompt disables its own IFDA system on a system level, so if users turn down apps, developers can’t access it. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/"&gt;Apple says that companies&lt;/a&gt; are also “required to respect your choice beyond the advertising identifier” when it comes to other means of tracking user data, and companies that do try to sneak around the rules could be subject to the same consequences as any other developer violating App Store terms of service, up to and including having their app removed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVgODg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about Apple’s apps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DwQjMA"&gt;Apple says that its apps will abide by the new rules, too — as a matter of policy, the company claims that its first-party apps already don’t track users across other apps and websites, which is why you won’t see it appear on Apple’s apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsLNuh"&gt;That said, Apple &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; still have some tracking that it uses to serve personalized ads within the App Store, Stocks, and Apple News apps. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT205223"&gt;As detailed here&lt;/a&gt;, Apple uses information like location, keyboard language settings, device type, OS version, mobile carrier, and more to serve customers more relevant ads within its apps. It also uses account information and past purchases to lump customers into market segments to better target ads within those apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="svZ1Pm"&gt;The difference is that Apple only uses that information within its own apps, doesn’t link it to additional profiles from third-party sources, and doesn’t sell that data. Apple also has an &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074"&gt;additional toggle&lt;/a&gt;, located in “Settings &amp;gt; Privacy &amp;gt; Apple Advertising,” to disable that tracking. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Go to Settings &amp;amp;gt; Privacy &amp;amp;gt; Tracking to change the settings for specific or all apps." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w6w_zBXKYJsJ68-QaTDaA_HPCgU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22470579/Image_from_iOS__3_.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="l9VcBN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there antitrust concerns?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nnhA1Q"&gt;It’s a major tech story in 2021; of course there are antitrust concerns. A group of German advertisers have &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/0a48d9aa-244b-4945-b2a0-01c68683544a"&gt;already filed a complaint&lt;/a&gt; about the new system, and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-scores-legal-win-in-france-over-app-privacy-changes-11615971737"&gt;French regulators&lt;/a&gt; shot down an initial antitrust complaint in March, noting that the system “doesn’t appear to be abusive” on Apple’s part.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FjahJE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will I be spammed by these toggles forever? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AZX2mQ"&gt;Nope. Apps can only request once, when you first open them after the update. Developers who don’t want to track you don’t have to show the prompt at all. There’s also a global setting switch that lets users just opt out of all apps by default in Settings &amp;gt; Privacy &amp;gt; Tracking, and toggling off “Allow Apps to Request to Track.” That menu also allows users to grant (or revoke) permission from apps after the initial prompt has been shown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GsBf0X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TOuZV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-26T15:13:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-26T15:13:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola is once again announcing a low-cost phone with a 90Hz screen and a huge battery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PVlxPPCbd814-L4_xh2OWW_TEoY=/1x0:1396x930/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69188600/moto_g20.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Motorola Moto G20 features a large 5,000mAh battery and a faster-than-standard 90Hz 6.5-inch display.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: Motorola&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KnGKty"&gt;Motorola has announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350611/motorola-g100-g50-launch-price-specs"&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286048/motorola-moto-g30-moto-g10-90hz-screen-price-launch"&gt;low-cost devices&lt;/a&gt; with big batteries and fast-refreshing displays this year, and now it’s offering its least expensive model yet: the Moto G20. Launching in Europe this week for €149 (about $180), it includes a 6.5-inch 720p LCD with a 90Hz refresh rate and a 5,000mAh battery. It’s the latest in a series of budget devices from Motorola targeting slightly different price points in the budget range, and it would likely have a place in the US market if the company chose to offer it in the States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2d7kDh"&gt;The G20 features a 48-megapixel main camera, 8-megapixel ultrawide, 2-megapixel macro and depth-sensing cameras, and a 13-megapixel selfie camera. Unlike other Moto G-series phones launched this year, the G20 does not use a Snapdragon chipset, offering instead a Unisoc T700 processor with 4GB of RAM. The device’s built-in storage of 64GB or 128GB can be expanded via microSD, and it will ship with Android 11. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HpnZsKY4IFjbz2eAxNzW51i6lR0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22471191/156439_1200_auto.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Motorola&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto G20 includes a 48-megapixel main camera along with an ultrawide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="i5vYLX"&gt;There’s no indication whether the G20 will be sold in the US — the G100, G50, and G30 introduced earlier this year haven’t been offered stateside as of yet either. Motorola’s current US offerings are largely situated above the $200 mark, and there are &lt;a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/three-motorola-edge-flagships-coming-one-with-108mp-camera_id131722"&gt;rumblings&lt;/a&gt; that high-end Edge devices may be coming next. But with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375938/lg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola"&gt;the void LG is leaving&lt;/a&gt; at the budget end of the market, Motorola certainly has a full portfolio of devices it could offer if it wanted to try to fill the gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzEO9B"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403994/motorola-moto-g20-90hz-screen-battery-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403994/motorola-moto-g20-90hz-screen-battery-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-26T05:45:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-26T05:45:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pixel 5A camera sample leaks, hints at similar specs to the Pixel 5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LCACWXmndGxHJUKjB6Zv2lQ4b3o=/0x168:4032x2856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69185712/pixel_5a_ultrawide.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The since-removed photo, which appears to have been taken with the Pixel 5A.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ljHMMa"&gt;Google seems to have accidentally shared a photo sample from its upcoming Pixel 5A, giving us some hints about what to expect from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;barely announced&lt;/a&gt; device. The photo appeared in an album posted alongside a &lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2021/04/hdr-with-bracketing-on-pixel-phones.html?m=1"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about Google’s HDR+ Bracketing technology, which aims to reduce noise in HDR photos (via &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/04/23/our-first-potential-pixel-5a-camera-sample-looks-like-it-comes-from-a-very-familiar-sensor/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The EXIF data for most of the photos said they were captured by existing Pixel phones including the Pixel 5, Pixel 4A 5G, Pixel 4, and Pixel 4 XL, but in among them was one image apparently taken with a Pixel 5A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w2MvhN"&gt;Google recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;confirmed the existence of the Pixel 5A 5G&lt;/a&gt; in response to rumors that the device had been cancelled. However, beyond confirming that the device will be available later this year in the US and Japan, it didn’t offer any more details about the phone’s specs or cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pSjVsi"&gt;The image labeled as coming from a Pixel 5A has since been removed from &lt;a href="https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipPILk1LAjCRKAx7mfmgr_QNQmJ4U6zqhiFTwL88eTsXic8tSeS7dfTiswq1C-nEjw?key=eHJpUFgxOVBNaHVjSFZDMFE3OE5aZmlUZ0d5R1lR"&gt;the album&lt;/a&gt;, but offered several details about the camera performance of the upcoming device while it was up. First is that it appears to have been taken with an ultrawide camera, which corroborates &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/22/google-pixel-5a-renders-leak/"&gt;previous reports&lt;/a&gt; that the 5A will have two rear cameras — a main camera and an ultrawide. That’s similar to the Pixel 4A 5G, while the Pixel 4A had just the one rear camera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AqA5mi221HihuIROcaTN3Qg-ank=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22470037/image__6_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Google Photos&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of the photo’s EXIF data before it was removed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cFpbQk"&gt;Its resolution is also listed as 12.2 megapixels, which is similar to the photos we saw from the Pixel 5. Although the sensor in the Pixel 5’s ultrawide camera is technically 16 megapixels, it produces 12.2-megapixel shots by default. The 5A’s EXIF data also shows it has the same f/2.2 aperture as the 5. Given that the photo was attached to a blog post about HDR+ Bracketing, it seems likely that the 5A will also offer support for the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxe0qu"&gt;Combined with previous rumors, it looks like the Pixel 5A could be a very similar device to last year’s Pixel 5. Reports suggest it’ll use the &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/21/google-pixel-5a-5g-chip/"&gt;same Snapdragon 765G processor&lt;/a&gt;, and have &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/22/google-pixel-5a-renders-leak/"&gt;a similar design&lt;/a&gt; with a 6.2-inch OLED display with a hole-punch selfie camera. Like Google’s previous A-series devices, however, the rear panel is expected to be made of plastic rather than glass, and the phone will also reportedly feature a 3.5mm headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qtQvBG"&gt;According to the leaked photo’s EXIF data, the photo itself was taken last October just before the Pixel 5 was released. Without official confirmation from Google there’s no guarantee it’s representative of the 5A’s final camera hardware, but the fact that the photo has now been removed suggests it wasn’t a simple labeling mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403350/pixel-5a-leaked-camera-sample-ultrawide-12-2-megapixel-f-2-2-exif-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403350/pixel-5a-leaked-camera-sample-ultrawide-12-2-megapixel-f-2-2-exif-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-24T09:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-24T09:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung Galaxy A52 5G review: a midrange phone that will last</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not the cheapest budget phone, but it will go the distance&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="q8E5E4"&gt;If a $100 budget phone is the fast-food dollar menu and a $1,000 flagship is a steakhouse dinner, then the Samsung Galaxy A52 5G sits comfortably halfway between the two: the laid-back all-day cafe with surprisingly tasty food. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6762Rt"&gt;It’s good. More importantly, it’s good where it matters. Sure, you have to order your food at the counter and get your own water refills, but it’s worth it because brunch is fantastic and the prices are reasonable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="frUf4o"&gt;The A52 5G is the highest-specced of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370189/samsung-galaxy-a52-a42-a32-5g-a12-a02s-price-specs-price"&gt;budget A-series Galaxy phones&lt;/a&gt; we’ll see in the US this year, offering all of the basics for its $499 price tag along with a few good extras. Its 6.5-inch screen comes with a fast 120Hz refresh rate that’s scarce at this price point. Its main camera includes optical image stabilization, something I missed when I used the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;more expensive OnePlus 9&lt;/a&gt;. The A52 5G is rated IP67 waterproof for some extra peace of mind. And hey, there’s still a headphone jack! In this economy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CbrcLy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10462503"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r4ql9c"&gt;Still, this isn’t a flagship, and costs had to be cut somewhere. The device’s frame and back panel are plastic, and while I like the matte finish on the back, there’s a certain hollowness when you tap on it that’s not very reassuring. There’s also no telephoto to complement the wide and ultrawide cameras, just digital zoom plus a depth sensor and macro camera of dubious usefulness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nHb7bt"&gt;The important stuff is here, though. Samsung has the A52 5G on its list for monthly OS updates currently, and it says it will offer three years of major Android OS updates and at least some security support for four years. That will go a long way toward making the most out of your investment in this phone, and it will help you take advantage of its headline feature: 5G — Sub-6GHz, specifically, with hardware-level support for the C-band frequencies carriers will start using in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ags8Hc"&gt;It’s getting more common to see 5G offered in midrange and budget phones, but in this country, it’ll be a couple more years before our 5G networks are truly good. Healthy device support for the next few years makes it more likely that the A52 5G will actually last long enough to make it to that 5G promised land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N1lu981XZQQIMuwY7AbVUo_HWFU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465665/ajohnson_20210419_4541_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The A52 5G offers solid everyday performance with a Snapdragon 750G chipset and 6GB of RAM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vTC01h"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A52 5G performance and screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="xBcTmE"&gt;The A52 5G uses a Snapdragon 750G processor with 6GB of RAM, and the combination feels like a good fit here. You can certainly push it out of its comfort zone with heavier tasks like webpages with JavaScript, and I noticed it hesitating a moment too long when opening the camera app from the lock screen. But for day-to-day tasks and social media scrolling, it keeps up well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GHF1lS"&gt;As in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21251569/samsung-galaxy-a51-review-price-screen-camera-battery-life"&gt;last year’s model&lt;/a&gt;, the screen is where the A52 5G (and Samsung generally) really stand out. This is a 6.5-inch 1080p OLED panel that’s rich, bright, and generally lovely to look at. Plus, it offers all of the velvety smoothness that comes with its 120Hz refresh rate. Swiping between home screens, opening apps, scrolling through Twitter — it all just feels nicer with a fast refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="TlJgv3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One feature I continue to fight a losing battle with on the A52 5G is the in-display optical fingerprint sensor&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5WXx6D"&gt;Even considering the additional power needed for the 120Hz screen, the A52 5G’s 4,500mAh battery consistently lasted well into the next day in my use. I managed to get two full days out of it when I forgot to charge it overnight and decided to embrace chaos and just plow through on the remaining charge. This was with light to moderate use, and I was down to low double-digit battery percentage by the end of day two, but my gamble paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jvn5CE"&gt;One feature I continue to fight a losing battle with on the A52 5G is the in-display optical fingerprint sensor. I’ve been chastised by the phone many times for not leaving my finger on the sensor long enough, and I almost always need at least two tries to get it to register. That hit rate goes down significantly outside in bright light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gO7BU8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I see enough ads throughout my day as it is, and I do not appreciate seeing one more when I check the weather&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3s0y6"&gt;These problems aren’t unique to this device, and you can just opt to use (less secure) facial recognition or a plain old PIN to lock and unlock the phone. But there are nicer in-display fingerprint readers in pricier phones like the OnePlus 9 and Samsung’s own S21, so it’s a trade-off to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vk5IWZ"&gt;The Galaxy A52 5G ships with Android 11, which is great. The less good news is, as we saw in the S21 devices earlier this year, Samsung’s latest take on the OS stuffs a lot of unwanted apps, ads, and general clutter into the UI. I see enough ads throughout my day as it is, and I do not appreciate seeing one more when I check the weather on my phone’s own weather app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NPpfpU"&gt;If there’s a positive way to look at this situation, it’s that it feels more forgivable on a budget phone than on a $1,000-plus flagship. But I’d rather not have the ads at all. If you buy the similarly priced Pixel 4A 5G, you give up a lot of other features from the A52 5G, but you get an ad-free experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZhUR-qGtJB0ABj4ns-AbLqIMuEs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465664/ajohnson_20210419_4541_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Housed in the rear camera bump are a standard wide, ultrawide, macro, and depth sensor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HaqLe9"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A52 5G camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="TGVjuj"&gt;The A52 5G includes three rear cameras, plus a 5-megapixel depth sensor. You get a 64-megapixel standard wide with OIS, 12-megapixel ultrawide, and the seemingly obligatory 5-megapixel macro camera. There’s also a front-facing 32-megapixel selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1n9yk3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10462184"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LfMrMu"&gt;The 64-megapixel main camera produces 16-megapixel images in its standard photo mode that are bright with the very saturated colors you’d expect from a Samsung phone. Sometimes the look is pleasant, but more often than not, it’s a little much for my taste. The good news is that this sensor is capable of capturing lots of fine detail in good lighting, and it even does well in dim to very low-light conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VmGCNi"&gt;I put its night mode up against the Google Pixel 4A, which is still the low-light champ in the midrange class. There’s more noise visible in the A52 5G’s night mode shot, and details have a watercolory look, but while the 4A hangs on to its title, the A52 5G is quite close behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="muSVAD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10462353"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fL9uTL"&gt;The Pixel 4A is still the better camera in good lighting, too, but the differences are more subjective here. The 4A goes for more subdued color rendering, and the A52 5G’s images lack a little contrast in comparison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="b2waOI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10462360"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rEZCg3"&gt;So the A52 5G can’t beat the generation-old imaging tech in the 4A, but that might say more about the Pixel than anything else. Aside from that, the A52 5G turns in good all-around camera performance. Images from the ultrawide sometimes have a little cooler color cast but are generally good. The selfie camera offers two zoom settings: a slightly cropped-in standard wide view and an ever-so-slightly wider angle. The “focal length” difference between the two is almost laughably small. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4meBPd"&gt;At its default settings, the selfie camera does a fair amount of face smoothing and brightening. I don’t think it quite crosses the line into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21372109/samsung-galaxy-note-20-ultra-review-camera-price-photos-s-pen-notes"&gt;hamcam territory&lt;/a&gt;, but it certainly has that telltale “maybe it’s AI, maybe it’s Maybelline” smoothed look to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uhpTk3"&gt;If you want to go full hamcam, there’s a new mode just labeled “fun” in the camera app with AR face filters brought to you by Snapchat. There’s a different selection of them every day, and you don’t need a Snapchat account to use or share them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3rqpRt"&gt;I’m tempted to dismiss them as “for the youths,” but maybe this is really for the olds like me who would rather not join another social platform if I can possibly avoid it, thank you very much. At last, I can transform my face into a piece of broccoli and share it with the world without logging in to Snapchat — three years after the kids have all moved on to something else. Anyway, it’s there, it works, and you can indeed turn your face into broccoli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h1oKBK3JdgYUcwZh5b6fILyiLJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465662/ajohnson_20210419_4541_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good hardware and healthy software support make the A52 5G worth spending a little more on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="8blwo0"&gt;There’s a lot that the Galaxy A52 5G gets right. Maybe the most important feature is one that sounds much less exciting than cool headline specs: security updates for at least the next few years. At $500, this is the higher end of the budget market, but a few extra hundred dollars is likely easier to swallow if you know you’ll get a couple more years out of your investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QxfsaW"&gt;Samsung has invested in hardware in all the right places: the 120Hz screen makes for an elevated user experience, battery life is good, camera performance is strong, and a healthy processor / chipset combination handles daily tasks well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="pVgjzT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The A52 5G is a good midrange phone today — but just as importantly, it will be a good phone a few years from now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fXjffS"&gt;What I didn’t love — the cluttered software, fussy fingerprint sensor, a tendency toward oversaturated color in photos — feels more forgivable when the phone gets the nonnegotiable stuff right. The Pixel 4A 5G is probably this device’s closest competition, and it beats the A52 5G on camera quality and a cleaner UI, but it’s a smaller device without a fancy fast refresh rate screen. Depending on how you feel about either of those things, the 4A 5G might be the better pick for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="w7Ybue"&gt;In any case, the A52 5G is a good midrange phone today. But just as importantly, it will be a good phone a few years from now. With solid hardware and a software support system to back it up, this is a pricier budget phone that’s worth budgeting a little extra for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HofzVi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="JLn3Jw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10462523"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T13:45:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T13:45:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube makes it easier to save on data with new video resolution options</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HotfZ2qKIRCQeaaRGBrz9LWKI2M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69176603/acastro_180403_1777_youtube_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VbCxa0"&gt;The YouTube mobile app for iOS and Android now has new video settings that might make it a bit easier to save on data while watching video on the go (&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/23/youtube-adds-even-more-video-resolution-controls-and-options-on-mobile/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Along with specific resolutions in the video player, you can now toggle between three separate modes that either favor video quality, data use, or whatever works best for your current internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mBXfCp"&gt;You might already be familiar with “auto” mode as the default setting for most videos, which automatically adjusts video resolution depending on your current internet speed to give the best experience. YouTube’s new additions are the “higher picture quality” mode, which uses more data when not on Wi-Fi and defaults to 720p, and a “data saver” mode that maxes out at 480p.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bkG6Bx4FQtnsiKGWLwFjoM1myyk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465137/YouTube_resolutionsSettings.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTube’s new video settings include options for “higher picture quality” and “data saver.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CtqSNK"&gt;While these umbrella modes are good for quick scenario-specific adjustments to resolution, you can still dig in and get granular with specific resolutions. And any resolution adjustments can be set for the specific video you’re watching or system-wide for everything you watch, with specific behaviors for Wi-Fi and mobile networks. YouTube &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200309015249/https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/91449?hl=en"&gt;has had resolution settings&lt;/a&gt; and ways to keep the app &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2019/05/20/how-to-save-data-android/"&gt;from downloading / streaming HD videos&lt;/a&gt; for a while, but this automates the data-saving process and reframes it in a way that’s easier to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WUORpPGbGr2gBBgSsO8L-W2-5L8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465170/youTube_settings.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video settings can also be applied system-wide, with separate behavior for mobile and Wi-Fi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mIehp0"&gt;In an ideal world, none of this would matter and you could just watch high-resolution cooking videos (my preferred YouTube zone-out material of choice) to your heart’s content. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360228/unlimited-plan-verizon-att-t-mobile-premium-data-tethering-limits"&gt;But even on “unlimited” plans&lt;/a&gt;, most mobile carriers still cap video resolution at 480p. Videos watched at higher resolutions typically count against some kind of premium data allotment or other terrible carrier jargon and hit you where it hurts — in your monthly bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZl961"&gt;YouTube’s new video settings aren’t a magic bullet solution, but they make it easier to switch to a carrier-acceptable resolution without having to think about it. And when all my brain wants is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlJx9y9Toto"&gt;ASMR donut videos&lt;/a&gt;, that certainly helps.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399483/youtube-video-resolution-data-saver-mobile-carrier-caps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399483/youtube-video-resolution-data-saver-mobile-carrier-caps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T00:13:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T00:13:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple extends reprieve, won’t take a cut of online classes and events until next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q9YV-Fg0lbSGN7QOfXK9oShZhfg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173462/acastro_190322_1777_apple_streaming_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vl0knn"&gt;Apple announced on Wednesday that it’s &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=6qfoid1d&amp;amp;1619114022"&gt;once again extending the deadline&lt;/a&gt; for requiring in-app purchases for iOS apps that sell access to online classes and group events until December 31st, 2021, effectively meaning it won’t impose its 30 percent cut on businesses providing those services until next year. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21595040/apple-developer-in-app-purchase-deadline-online-classes-events"&gt;extended the deadline initially to June 30th, 2021&lt;/a&gt;, but now developers have another six months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TeBrI"&gt;Apple cites the ongoing pandemic as its main justification for the change, but we have to wonder if it might also have something to do with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396544/apple-app-store-google-play-monopoly-antitrust-bill-hearings"&gt;the Congressional antitrust hearings that have zeroed in on whether Apple and Google’s app stores are monopolies&lt;/a&gt;. Helping out small businesses by not taking its traditional 30 percent cut is an example Apple can now use to demonstrate how it encourages small businesses to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGWxmt"&gt;Wednesday’s &lt;a href="https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/meetings/antitrust-applied-examining-competition-in-app-stores"&gt;“Antitrust Applied: Examining Competition in App Stores”&lt;/a&gt; hearing featured complaints from lost item tracker company Tile, who Apple is now in direct competition with thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;Apple’s new AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, and Match Group, whose Tinder dating app uses Apple’s in-app purchases for subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4oDlVz"&gt;Not every company pays 30 percent. Apple doesn’t apply the same in-app purchases requirement to one-on-one classes like tutoring, so individuals can take other forms of payments and bypass Apple’s cut entirely. Apple’s also been criticized for quietly creating special deals for big companies like Amazon, where subscriptions sold on its Prime Video app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21348108/apple-amazon-prime-video-app-store-special-treatment-fee-subscriptions"&gt;are only subject to a 15 percent fee&lt;/a&gt;. (Generally, Apple doesn’t reduce its cut of subscription fees to 15 percent until users have been subscribed for a full year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGfuN5"&gt;After Amazon’s seeming sweetheart deal came to light, Apple launched a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;App Store Small Business Program&lt;/a&gt; in January 2021 where developers who earn less than $1 million in sales every year can apply to lower Apple’s commission to 15 percent on purchases — but only with Apple’s approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVIcV8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;Apple is now launching podcast subscriptions too&lt;/a&gt;, ones where podcasters can join by paying $19.99 a year plus 30 percent of each subscriber’s first year of revenue, then 15 percent after for subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="enJjh1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Can Apple get you to pay for podcasts?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396042/apple-podcast-subscriptions-launch-price"},{"title":"Apple’s $64 billion-a-year App Store isn’t catching the most egregious scams","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398338/apple-iap-classes-events-deadline-december-2021-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398338/apple-iap-classes-events-deadline-december-2021-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T14:54:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T14:54:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>The FCC wants your thoughts on improving the shorter National Suicide Prevention Lifeline number</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CfOzMoNMRHyN50Gx6z1f9burIoY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69170974/akrales_180620_1777_0600.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GQSbaz"&gt;The Federal Communications Commission &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FCC/status/1385250009092956161"&gt;has decided to look into&lt;/a&gt; letting people text the upcoming shortened National Suicide Prevention Lifeline number in a bid to increase accessibility and use of the service by those who need it most (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JohnHendel/status/1385243971044134920"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; reporter John Hendel&lt;/a&gt;). Last May, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/17/21328600/national-suicide-prevention-lifeline-number-dial-988-fcc"&gt;FCC approved the creation&lt;/a&gt; of a new short code, 988, that will act as an easier-to-remember phone number for the lifeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQGTdJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note that calling 988 will not connect you to the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline until July 16th, 2022.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OKURJ3"&gt;It’s worth noting that today’s approval is &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/general/rulemaking-fcc"&gt;just a first step&lt;/a&gt; and doesn’t mean that people will, for sure, be able to text the 988 number when it goes live in July 2022. However, it does mean that the FCC will be looking into making it a requirement for phone providers, and it will be accepting public comment on whether texting should be allowed. &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-lays-groundwork-text-988"&gt;According to its statement&lt;/a&gt;, the FCC would also like public comment on the implementation details before it starts drawing up actual rules, like what kinds of things people should be able to text the lifeline, what happens if a message bounces back, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="X1BwcY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:831613"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tAjrya"&gt;To provide a comment, you can go to &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/filings/express"&gt;the FCC’s express comment page&lt;/a&gt;. The proceeding is 18-336.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AgVB5v"&gt;While being able to contact the lifeline via phone or SMS with an easily memorable number is undoubtedly a good thing, it’s also worth noting that the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline also has a chat feature &lt;a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt;. The current hotline added the ability to accept text messages at 1-800-273-8255 in August 2020, but 988 is an easier number to remember, especially during times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1zYwg5"&gt;The proposal to add texting support to 988 wasn’t the only action the FCC took today to try to improve public safety. It also announced that it would be looking into increasing the reliability of the 911 emergency services network. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397823/fcc-considers-text-sms-support-988-suicide-prevention-lifeline"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397823/fcc-considers-text-sms-support-988-suicide-prevention-lifeline</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
