<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-06T07:02:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-06T07:02:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-06T07:02:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is fighting Russian regulator’s demands on alternative app payments</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SUUtKRbOpZjwnXWJ2gxbQ8gU0X4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70233966/acastro_180130_1777_0005_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IUbSSC"&gt;Apple is challenging antitrust action taken by Russia’s Federal Antimonopoly Service (FAS), which wants iOS developers to be able to tell customers about alternatives to Apple’s in-app payment option, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-starts-legal-action-against-russian-regulator-app-store-dispute-ria-2021-12-06/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Apple wants a judicial review of the regulator’s warning, &lt;a href="https://www.rt.com/business/542257-apple-takes-russia-court/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Russia Today&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, which was originally issued with a &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.ru/tekhnologii/438557-fas-predupredila-apple-iz-za-zapreta-soobsat-o-vozmoznosti-oplaty-vne-app-store"&gt;deadline of September 30th&lt;/a&gt; for the US tech giant to change its anti-steering policies. When Apple didn’t comply, FAS announced it was opening an antitrust case against the company &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/russia-opens-case-against-apple-over-app-store-payment-restrictions-2021-10-27/"&gt;at the end of October&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GgnoWb"&gt;The US tech giant’s policies on in-app payments are contentious, to say the very least. Apple requires iOS developers to use its own in-app payment system, which in many cases allows it to collect up to a lucrative 30 percent commission on any purchases. Not only does Apple ban developers from allowing third-party payment methods in their apps, it even limits their ability to tell customers when they accept alternative payment methods elsewhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zkRd5p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;FAS is accusing Apple of “abusing its dominant position”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="50iGGg"&gt;It’s this policy that FAS is specifically objecting to. In an announcement at the &lt;a href="http://en.fas.gov.ru/press-center/news/detail.html?id=55296"&gt;end of October&lt;/a&gt;, the regulator said Apple was “abusing its dominant position on the market for the distribution of apps through its App Store” by not allowing developers to tell “in-app users about the possibility [of paying] for their purchases outside the App Store.” Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PuC9iZ"&gt;In August, in response to a class-action lawsuit, Apple said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643807/apple-developer-class-action-lawsuit-collect-information-ios-apps-anti-steering"&gt;“clarifying” its policies&lt;/a&gt; about developers telling customers about alternative payment methods. It said that developers could use communications like emails to share information with customers about alternative payment methods. However, it stopped short of letting developers do this inside apps themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ntm1kO"&gt;Apple’s App Store policies are facing pushback around the world. In the US, the judge in Apple’s legal battle with Epic Games &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662320/epic-apple-ruling-injunction-judge-court-app-store"&gt;ordered the company to allow iOS apps&lt;/a&gt; to direct users to alternative payment options, and gave the company a deadline of December 9th to comply. Meanwhile &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22643800/apple-google-south-korea-app-store-payment-legislation-passes"&gt;lawmakers in South Korea passed a bill&lt;/a&gt; in late August banning platform holders like Google and Apple from limiting developers to using their first-party payment systems. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407376/apple-european-union-antitrust-charges-app-store-music-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager"&gt;European Commission has also issued antitrust charges&lt;/a&gt; over the practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlpKbz"&gt;Russia’s antitrust authority has already clashed with Apple this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407293/apple-russia-antitrust-monopoly-fine-kaspersky-parental-control-app"&gt;fining the tech giant $12 million&lt;/a&gt; over complaints it unfairly cracked down on third-party parental control apps. With its latest legal action, FAS is tapping into a far more contentious policy.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820078/apple-legal-action-russia-federal-antimonopoly-service-anti-steering-in-app-payment-options"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820078/apple-legal-action-russia-federal-antimonopoly-service-anti-steering-in-app-payment-options</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-04T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-04T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Buy two Nintendo Switch games and get one free at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R1nc4AQVlNYnmJd0H9GbpL8v5uY=/222x0:840x412/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70227915/Screenshot_2021_12_03_144418.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Buy two, get one free&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bLY7np"&gt;Best Buy is still hosting its mix-and-match sale featuring some excellent titles from the Nintendo Switch game library. Right now you can &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf77Eria2mK" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;get a third game of equal or lesser value for free if you buy two other select titles&lt;/a&gt;. This offer includes first-party titles like &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Mario Tennis: Aces&lt;/em&gt; that rarely see discounts. While this offer is limited to 11 titles, this is one of the best ways to stock up on games that are exclusive to the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TtZyEq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The next N64 game for Nintendo Switch Online is Paper Mario","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815382/n64-switch-paper-mario-release-date-announced"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XSyRF2"&gt;While not quite as enticing as Black Friday prices, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf77ITyjJM2" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy has discounted all models of the 11-inch iPad Pro that launched in 2020, with some versions receiving discounts of up to $200&lt;/a&gt;. This tablet is available with up to 1TB of built-in storage and comes with many of the same features you’ll find on the latest version, except the M1 processor. This includes USB-C charging, a 120Hz refresh rate display, and dual-lens rear cameras. However, if you’re in the market for something with a bit more screen real estate, Best Buy is offering similar discounts on 2020 model of the 12.9-inch iPad Pro. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NHuXli"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10692708" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KNsYYC"&gt;The Brydge Pro Plus is a quick and easy way to transform your iPad into a MacBook. Currently, Brydge is offering the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.brydge.com%2Fproducts%2Fbrydge-pro-plus-for-ipad-pro%3Fvariant%3D31717947441257&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F4%2F22816014%2Fnintendo-switch-games-asus-zephyrus-gaming-laptop-apple-ipad-pro-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11-inch version of this combination screen protector and keyboard for $120&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.brydge.com%2Fproducts%2Fbrydge-pro-plus-for-ipad-pro%3Fvariant%3D31717947408489&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F4%2F22816014%2Fnintendo-switch-games-asus-zephyrus-gaming-laptop-apple-ipad-pro-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;12.9-inch for $130&lt;/a&gt;, taking $30 and $40 off the regular prices, respectively. This case is designed to closely emulate the classic look and feel of the backlit keyboard on the MacBook Pro and even includes a trackpad in its list of features. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/3/21206568/brydge-pro-plus-review-ipad-pro-keyboard-trackpad" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Byford noted in his review&lt;/a&gt; that the Brydge Pro Plus transforms the iPad Pro into a convenient laptop form factor, even though some of the gestures you can use on the Apple magic keyboard aren’t available here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Czgpgd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10750005"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OvhcNP"&gt;Ponder having your own personal orb that you can talk to with this sweet discount on the latest Echo Dot. This version of the spherical speaker is currently available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XJ8C8F5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1749437417640247273" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $30, its lowest price ever. This omnidirectional speaker boasts all the functionality of previous Alexa-enabled speakers, just in a slightly more attractive form factor. It still features top-mounted touch controls, and is available in black, white, or blue. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Read our review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bt03pv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9607515" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pDW4hB"&gt;This &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf77LBUaeWf" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32-inch curved Asus TUF Gaming Monitor is currently discounted to just $290 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, taking $100 off the regular price. This monitor features a 165Hz refresh rate and  1440p resolution, as well as support for AMD FreeSync to help minimize screen tearing. This model features a pair of HDMI inputs as well as a DisplayPort jack, and a 3.5mm audio jack for headphones. The stand’s height, tilt, and swivel can be adjusted, but the monitor also supports VESA mount, if you’d prefer a wall-mounted or arm-based solution. This is one of the better prices we’ve seen for a monitor with these specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wISf2y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9739259"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R39XwA"&gt;The 15-inch Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 gaming laptop is still discounted to its Black Friday price. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf8e6fNlSML" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy is offering this capable laptop for $1,900&lt;/a&gt;, knocking $300 off the regular retail price. This laptop comes equipped with a a QHD display, an RTX 3080, an AMD Ryzen 7 CPU, 16GB of RAM, and a 1TB SSD for storage. Like virtually all of the gaming laptops available at Best Buy, the G15 also comes packaged with a free month of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, a perfect combo for playing &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; on launch day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E293gW"&gt;Monica Chin was thoroughly impressed with the Zephyrus G15 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/search?q=Asus+ROG+Zephyrus+G15" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in her review&lt;/a&gt; (though she tested the RTX 3070 model), and it even occupies the top spot for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our favorite gaming laptops&lt;/a&gt;. Unless you absolutely need a built-in webcam, which this model lacks, the Zephyrus G15 is otherwise an excellent choice for your next gaming laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zu235T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10385239"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZxPkWf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few more sweet deals for you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LyeRZ8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?node=21289088011" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is currently discounting a broad range of Otterbox products by as much as 50 percent&lt;/a&gt;. This includes cases for Samsung and Apple phones, as well as screen protectors and other accessories. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1eeoY5"&gt;The Ember Mug 2 is a smart mug that keeps your beverage hot for up to 80 minutes with its rechargeable battery. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf73MClgSYs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The blue version is discounted to $100 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YB1WeS"&gt;The Jabra Elite 85t is still one of the best alternatives to Apple’s AirPods and is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf77CTzsddd" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently available at Best Buy for $80 off the regular price&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it down to $150. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sD6KK1"&gt;Get the 2TB version of the WD_Black SN750 for less than half of its regular MSRP. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf77G5O9bJd" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This M.2 SSD has been discounted to just $250 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="8sJ2Yx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/4/22816014/nintendo-switch-games-asus-zephyrus-gaming-laptop-apple-ipad-pro-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/4/22816014/nintendo-switch-games-asus-zephyrus-gaming-laptop-apple-ipad-pro-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T01:42:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T01:42:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon Go now runs much smoother on iPhones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pokemon Go" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HxmZAAvywDy4fcTyRFgHsKMdl5c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70222795/jbareham_160711_1134_0119_02.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9BSXK3"&gt;A new update to &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; for iOS lets you run the game at higher frame rates. With version 1.191.0, the “advanced settings” section of the app now includes an option that reads “Unlock your device’s native refresh rate for higher FPS.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OBvPcj"&gt;I tried it out on my iPhone 13 Pro and it makes a huge difference. &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; isn’t the most visually complicated game, of course, but there’s a lot of scrolling and camera movement, and the smoother touch response feels a lot better when you’re lining up a pokéball throw with your finger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PEVyUa"&gt;Here’s how the feature appears in the game’s menu:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8nHW_89zKBQfybEMNL-btA64PvM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060153/IMG_1041.PNG"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LAgIfC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; was previously locked to 30fps on iOS devices. Many Android phones are already capable of running the game at a higher frame rate, though in my experience testing across several devices the support can be hit and miss. Still, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; generally ran better on Android until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tlPgzi"&gt;The new iOS feature isn’t limited to the 13 Pro and Pro Max, which are the only iPhones with 120Hz “ProMotion” displays. I also tried it on my old 8 Plus and it’s possible to unlock the frame rate there, too, though the aging A11 processor doesn’t always keep up a steady 60fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3P1tC"&gt;Niantic isn’t making a big deal out of the feature; it’s switched off by default and it isn’t mentioned in version 1.191.0’s release notes, beyond a vague mention of “various quality-of-life improvements.” It’s possible that enabling it for all users would cause complaints about battery life, considering that &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; is already a pretty heavy app in that regard. But if that’s not a concern for you, it’s worth giving the option a try.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815472/pokemon-go-frame-rate-ios-update-released"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815472/pokemon-go-frame-rate-ios-update-released</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T17:42:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T17:42:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLjcArAq4sGebo8JT2J9VP6QFsQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66976955/vpavic_200930_4216_0258.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Product Red edition of the Series 6 has often recieved the biggest discounts.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ozqXgk"&gt;Thinking about picking up a new Apple Watch? It might be tempting to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features"&gt;order one of the new Series 7 models&lt;/a&gt;, but new Apple hardware always comes at a premium. The latest version of the Apple wearable offers a slightly larger display and some improvements to durability but is largely the same Apple Watch we’re familiar with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxsAXI"&gt;Thankfully, each Apple Watch model offers ample functionality and has seen its fair share of discounts over the last year. So which ones should you consider if you’re in the market for Apple’s popular smartwatch while trying to shop smarter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtR5HF"&gt;There are currently four Apple Watch models to choose from, all of which support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;watchOS 8&lt;/a&gt;. The highest-end is the Apple Watch Series 7, which starts at $399. Last year's model, the Series 6, has received a modest discount at some retailers since its release but is still usually found starting at $399. If either of those models is a little too rich for your blood, however, you can save about $120 by opting for an Apple Watch SE, which will set you back $279.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44jktU"&gt;Finally, there’s the four-year-old &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Series 3&lt;/a&gt;, the most affordable Apple Watch to date. It has a starting retail price of $199, but it frequently goes on sale. However, if you want something more future-proof, you may want to consider Apple’s newer watches, as it’s not clear how much longer Apple will issue software updates to the Series 3 beyond watchOS 8 and the current update process for the Series 3 has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419569/apple-watch-series-3-software-update-reset-bad-experience"&gt;become a bit of a pain point&lt;/a&gt;. Regardless of which model you prefer, we’ve rounded up the best Apple Watch deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Yen8lP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="hdRa4b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10741666"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OlUIlK"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Apple Watch Series 3&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="c2iEiy"&gt;The regular price for the 38mm Series 3 is $199. It’s a good entry-level Apple Watch if you are looking for a smartwatch with reliable battery life and excellent build quality, especially if the SE, Series 6, and Series 7 seem out of your price range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4nwEyX"&gt;Right now, &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-38mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F706203065" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and Best Buy are both discounting the 38mm, GPS-enabled Series 3 by $30, bringing the price down to $169. If you prefer the bigger, 42mm configuration with GPS, it’s also on sale at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-42mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F742230355%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYU8dEI5wH" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $199 instead of $229. Both models are also available at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1187777/2092?subId1=VergeBestAppleWatchDeals111121&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-watch-series-3-gps-42mm-space-gray-aluminum-case-with-sport-band-black%2F-%2FA-54101062" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, though, not at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="N8sVLO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="zc5j8W"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10741240"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3G29qi"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GaARPa"&gt;Starting at $279 for a 40mm version or $309 for the 44mm, the Apple Watch SE is a good midrange wearable that shares some features found on the like-minded Series 6 and Series 7, including a built-in accelerometer and hand-washing detection. However, it doesn’t have the always-on display found on Apple’s latest flagships, nor does it feature blood oxygen monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="title"&gt;Right now, you can pick up the 40mm, GPS-equipped version with a silver aluminum case and an abyss blue sport band for $239 instead of $279 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B09G93BDQP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-40mm-Silver-Aluminum-Case-with-White-Sport-Band-Regular%2F305879066&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. Other configurations — as well as the larger, 44mm model with GPS — are currently only available at full price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k7Seuv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xtEsXh"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Gold-Aluminum-Case-with-Pink-Sand-Sport-Band-Regular%2F804932402%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; Watch Series 6&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oTrUCf"&gt;While &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22716438/apple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s no longer officially a part of Apple’s wearable lineup&lt;/a&gt;, you can still buy the Apple Watch Series 6 at several retailers. The Apple Watch comes in two sizes, 40mm and 44mm, which start at $399 and $429, respectively. The Series 6 features built-in sleep tracking, a great ecosystem of third-party complications, and more sensors than previous models, including one that allows the device to detect your body's blood oxygen levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PfLoQg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9432291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="60XJAV"&gt;Deals often come and go quickly on the Series 6. If you don’t mind a bit of vibrancy on your wrist, however, the 40mm, GPS-enabled blue configuration usually sees the biggest discounts with the most frequency. Right now, for instance, you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7KQg2qO7Z" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blue variant at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; right now for $299, one of the better prices we’ve seen on the Series 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8KuZ3"&gt;If the larger, 44mm model with GPS is your fancy, it’s available in white, pink, red, and black at &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-44mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-PRODUCT-RED-Sport-Band-Regular%2F847051571%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; for $329, its best-ever price. This discontinued model currently only has limited availability other retailers for full price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rn8JJi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10598305"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hZHCRf"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iK520N"&gt;With a slightly altered design and larger display, the new Series 7 comes in either a 41mm configuration starting at $399 or a 45mm configuration starting at $429. There are very few deals to speak of right now, however, you can pick up the 41mm, GPS-equipped model with a green Sport Band and green aluminum casing for $380 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HF1DC1J/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, a $20 discount, this same deal also applies to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HDYWTPV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the red variant, also available for $380&lt;/a&gt;. The 45mm model with GPS is also available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HFGSRJ7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; in red for $410.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4m59DD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860351"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="rwvKCC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860357"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="J2hTVr"&gt;A note on the more premium models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7aHrsm"&gt;While all of the Apple Watch models and colorways covered here are encased in aluminum, Apple does make a more premium range built out of stainless steel and titanium. These offerings have similar designs to their aluminum counterparts, with slightly refined colors and finishings — polished for the stainless steel, brushed for the titanium. However, they start at much steeper prices of $749 and above, and they are functionally the same, save for some exclusive digital watch faces Apple reserves for these premium models. Overall, the upmarket stainless, titanium, and Hermès edition Apple Watches don’t usually get the discounts and sales as the aluminum models, where the deals are often to be had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hjNY0P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T16:10:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T16:10:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to arrange for your digital legacy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="cemetery (SHUTTERSTOCK)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L21amYXQFewHblgYg9I43krU7Jo=/0x0:1000x667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70221033/shutterstock_13456018.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BiAC84"&gt;I’m about to introduce a topic that most of us would rather avoid: our digital legacy. In other words, what happens to all our digital stuff after we die? (And if your answer is “That’s not gonna happen,” you haven’t been paying a lot of attention lately, have you?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DOzpkg"&gt;If you’re reading this, odds are that you’ve got a lot of digital stuff, both on your own devices and floating around in the cloud: backups, photos, tweets, Facebook messages, texts, you name it. If you’re no longer around to pay attention, these can hang around for a very long time — and some of it may be important to your survivors. (For example, who else has the passwords to your bank accounts and credit cards?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AgTTqR"&gt;So let’s take a deep breath and discuss how to make things easier for your friends and relatives should something happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R7BP3Z"&gt;&lt;q&gt;What happens to all our digital stuff after we die? &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7dZmIj"&gt;To begin with, if you’re old enough (or wise enough) to have arranged for a will, then your executor (the person who is assigned to see that the terms of the will are carried out) will also have legal standing to access your digital assets: online accounts, websites, etc. This is specified by the &lt;a href="https://www.uniformlaws.org/committees/community-home?CommunityKey=f7237fc4-74c2-4728-81c6-b39a91ecdf22"&gt;revised Fiduciary Access to Digital Assets Act&lt;/a&gt;, which has been enacted by the majority of the states in the US. (As of this writing, it had not been passed by California, Oklahoma, or Louisiana; it has been introduced by not yet passed in Massachusetts.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ux7j0L"&gt;Since it doesn’t do your relatives or friends any good to have the right to take care of your data if they don’t have your passwords, you might want to think about entrusting at least one person with the passwords to your computer and / or your password manager — or think about putting that information in a secure place and let at least one person know where that place is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QoXb0c"&gt;However, the Act does not apply to social media sites — which could be a problem. You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; include whom you want to entrust with all your social media accounts in your will, which can make things somewhat easier for them — but will still involve a lot of back and forth as they prove their right to handle those accounts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y5jpXx"&gt;There are a few companies that have added features to let you plan ahead of time who is authorized to handle your cloud and / or social media accounts if you’re not able to. Listed here are how some of the major online services are (or are not) handling the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zbgz1o"&gt;Apple iCloud Digital Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="RbREc2"&gt;Until recently, getting access to the iCloud account of a deceased family member could be extremely difficult, especially if you didn’t have that person’s &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208072"&gt;recovery key&lt;/a&gt;. However, Apple has recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774873/apple-digital-legacy-program-comes-to-ios15-iphones-macs"&gt;added a Digital Legacy program&lt;/a&gt; to its iCloud accounts, which lets you name up to five Legacy Contacts who will have access to your account. The program is available starting with iOS 15.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fY6lU7"&gt;To set up your Legacy Contacts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="xE6VMc"&gt;Go to Settings and tap on your name at the top of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5thDh1"&gt;Select Password &amp;amp; Security &amp;gt; Legacy Contact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="65b3l2"&gt;This is where you can add the names of people who will be able to access and download your data after your death; it will also list anyone who has listed you as a Legacy Contact. Tap on Add Legacy Contact to add a name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A trusted friend or family member can access your iCloud account." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tbjCTrerbFBnHb9YNQnXw7m5YQM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058282/IMG_336C1C7F4E9D_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A trusted friend or family member can access your iCloud account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can add up to 10 Legacy Contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m8XlGcXACpJpGrq7p5FwWDOHNkc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058283/IMG_46BBD3E4A094_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can add up to 10 Legacy Contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XkyQ1i"&gt;The next page explains that you should choose someone you trust, and that the person will need to have your access key and a copy of your death certificate. Tap on the Add Legacy Contact button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="86OtX9"&gt;You will be presented with a list of your contacts. Choose one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BP5Cg5"&gt;Again, a page will explain what info the contact will have access to. Tap on Continue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Your access key can be shared via message or print / PDF." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fRH42kkkFepawmEQ89F6dthHzY4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058295/IMG_86EF6F6C0BD0_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your access key can be shared via message or print / PDF.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If your contact is an iOS user, they can be messaged the access key." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4fCQQEqvXgNaobHa4kVQoZUsXdg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058296/IMG_8DF1D0ECCD4F_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your contact is an iOS user, they can be messaged the access key.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="LmabEL"&gt;You can now choose how to share you access key (which is a very long string of numbers and letters). If you message your chosen legacy contact with the access key &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; if they accept it, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; if they have iOS 15.2, the key will be stored in their Apple settings. Otherwise, you can print out a copy for them in hard copy or as a PDF.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9r0gpE"&gt;Google Inactive Account Manager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TMOPg2"&gt;Google’s Inactive Account Manager is one of the more complete tools for taking care of your digital legacy — even if you’re just temporarily too ill to handle things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="exTeZc"&gt;Begin by going to the &lt;a href="https://myaccount.google.com/u/2/inactive"&gt;Inactive Account Manager&lt;/a&gt; and clicking on Start. You’re going to go through three setups: when the inactive account manager will kick in, who to notify, and whether everything should be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google’s Inactive Account Manager offers a variety of options for what to do with your data." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cdOdnUfXRKSvNvgpNbKwH-vLNJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058171/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_2.41.33_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s Inactive Account Manager offers a variety of options for what to do with your data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="HDcEf0"&gt;First, you decide whether the manager should activate if your account is inactive for three, six, 12, or 18 months. You’re also asked to verify a phone number and / or one or more email accounts where you can be contacted. If you haven’t gone into the account, Google will then use the phone number or email addresses to contact you a month before your set time is up to make sure that you’re really no longer around (and haven’t simply forgotten you had that account). &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can decide how long Google should wait before deciding you may no longer be around." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KmCnRs6gjS6UnAfH84h_trS2LWw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058235/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_2.46.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can choose how long Google should wait before deciding you may no longer be around.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="T8eU9O"&gt;The next page lets you list up to ten people who should be notified by Google that your account hasn’t been used. For each person, you can specify exactly which apps they should have access to, ranging from your calendar and contacts to your Google account and purchases. You can also simply let them have access to all your apps.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can specify what data can be shared with your legacy contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/87g9LZWwcbouJWBvk6yWUiYHfUI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058236/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_3.15.13_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can specify what data can be shared with your legacy contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6M83ad"&gt;If you want, you can add their phone number so that Google can use it to verify their identity (and, rather eerily, you can include a personal message to send them). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OqrVrT"&gt;You can also activate a Gmail message to anyone who emails you after the manager kicks in, telling them that the account is no longer active. You can have the message sent to everyone who emails you or only to people in your contact list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If you want, you can arrange to send a message in reply to emails." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Le5XrUDdvkkPpitbrQ05mF98TYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058237/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_3.37.53_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want, you can arrange to send a message in reply to emails.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="jT7MjM"&gt;Lastly, you can arrange for your entire account to be deleted three months after it is declared inactive. This will also include, according to Google, any shared public data such as YouTube videos. (If you’ve named someone who will have access to your account, this will give them three months before the account is pulled to save anything they want to.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If requested, Google will delete your entire account after three months." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lLPvWnHP3N7FswAng_iyl6yRdSc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058241/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_3.38.26_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If requested, Google will delete your entire account after three months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZgPOL0"&gt;Finally, you’ll be given the chance to look over your plan and confirm that this is what you want.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6GMZRa"&gt;Facebook Memorialization Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NRpASA"&gt;Facebook calls its digital legacy feature Memorialization Settings. It’s similar to Google’s and Apple’s — it gives a chosen person access to your account after your death. The only difference is that, because Facebook is often used to memorialize people who have died, there are some extra things of which to be aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="kdWY3s"&gt;To begin with, on the Facebook site, click on the downward arrow in the upper right corner, and go to Settings &amp;amp; Privacy &amp;gt; Settings. Make sure you’re in the General section (the first category in the left hand column) and select Memorialization Settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Facebook lets you choose a friend to manage your account posthumously." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yPYh1ZeMBhnSPL83JlCTAIY9KQ0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058172/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_3.46.24_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook lets you choose a friend to manage your account posthumously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="gCNkwr"&gt;The page will open up to explain that you can choose a legacy contact who will be able to manage tribute posts on your site, delete your site, accept new friends, and update your profile. The person you choose will be contacted by Facebook, so it’s probably a good idea to talk to them about it beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="abtQSz"&gt;You can also choose to have your account permanently deleted via a link at the bottom of that page. If you don’t choose that, then as soon as Facebook finds out you’re no longer alive, it will “memorialize” your account. That means that the word “Remembering” will be placed on your page, your content will remain, and friends can leave messages on the timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PXZYza"&gt;Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="yEkyHW"&gt;Twitter doesn’t provide any way to posthumously transfer your account to a family member or friend. Somebody who wants to close down the account of a deceased Twitter user will have to &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/contact-twitter-about-a-deceased-family-members-account"&gt;fill out a form&lt;/a&gt; and then send in a pile of paperwork, including their own ID and a death certificate. They will not be allowed access to the account.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Twitter will let a survivor delete your account assuming they have the right paperwork." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rdgO0tiShN0fogTSOkycuGwJ8A0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058247/Screen_Shot_2021_12_02_at_11.48.05_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter will let a survivor delete your account assuming they have the right paperwork.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NyOTvr"&gt;Instagram&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="19RHFA"&gt;Like Twitter, Instagram offers no way to plan ahead of time who will have access to your account or what they’ll do with it. Instead, &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/264154560391256/"&gt;the site will memorialize the account&lt;/a&gt; once it receives proof, such as a newspaper clipping or a death certificate. Family members can also request that an account be closed if they have &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/contact/1474899482730688"&gt;the proper proof&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Fill out this form to turn someone’s Instagram account into a memorial." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fGNpnlsWab57F7zAXn2YVg4sfT4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23058250/Screen_Shot_2021_12_02_at_11.49.55_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fill out this form to turn someone’s Instagram account into a memorial.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9qY3wa"&gt;As of this writing, there are no other social media sites that I know of that have any specific features for what happens when a user is no longer around. Instead, executors, family members, or others with legal standing will have to provide the paperwork needed to enable an account to be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WSaqgN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22812264/digital-legacy-death-estate-google-apple-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22812264/digital-legacy-death-estate-google-apple-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T12:52:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T12:52:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Luna Display’s latest update lets you use a Mac as a second PC display</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tHW-4QDGPEPP7WfRVz5Eqpcagag=/266x0:2234x1312/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70220047/5c_MattRonge_Astropad_r1_MSP29856_e1637257561528.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u7WibN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://astropad.com/luna-display-5-1/"&gt;Luna Display’s latest update&lt;/a&gt; adds a helpful new feature: allowing you to hook up a Windows PC to a Mac laptop or desktop (including Apple’s flash M1 iMacs) to use as a secondary display. The new update also enables 4K and 5K resolution options (assuming you’ve got a screen that supports it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mJiyw8"&gt;While Luna Display has offered Mac-to-Mac connectivity for a while, until now, users were only able to connect PCs to iPads using the company’s dongle and software setup. The new PC-to-Mac connection works both wirelessly and through an ethernet connection, just like the Mac-to-Mac option does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vnSmBm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Luna Display can now turn your iPad into a second screen for Windows devices","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724866/luna-display-windows-support-ipad-second-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jsAbyZ"&gt;Additionally, Luna Display’s update adds support for 5K and 4K monitors at full resolutions, although there are still some limitations there: PCs can only run 5K at 30Hz, while Macs can run it at up to 45Hz, assuming they’ve been updated to macOS Big Sur. On the other hand, 4K resolution will run at up to 60Hz on both platforms. Still, combined with the new PC support, Luna Display’s update makes it a nearly perfect solution for using an M1 iMac as a secondary display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a9FIlU"&gt;The new update comes hot on the heels of Luna Display &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724866/luna-display-windows-support-ipad-second-screen"&gt;adding support for PC-to-iPad&lt;/a&gt; setups earlier this year. Luna Display itself costs $129 for Mac or PC, with USB-C, HDMI, or Mini DisplayPort dongle options available depending on your platform of choice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5lh6u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/2/22813992/luna-display-update-pc-mac-second-display-4k-5k-imac-m1"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/2/22813992/luna-display-update-pc-mac-second-display-4k-5k-imac-m1</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s frontline employees are struggling to survive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TMakkNSkUDwmBNK1rWcmPwojpeM=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70219807/VRG_Illo_4894_Apple_Lede_Still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrations by Jesse Zhang&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DNHiPm"&gt;If you ask Jimmy Bailey what killed his best friend Mark Calivas, his answer is simple: “It was Apple.” How else could he explain how the Apple Store wellness champion — known for evangelizing therapy and mental health — would slide into a depression so profound he’d be forced to take medical leave and ultimately die by suicide? “It was nothing in his outside life that did this,” Bailey says. “It was work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IEf0VL"&gt;Calivas started at the Apple Southpoint store in Durham, North Carolina in March 2013. His colleagues laughed when he’d arrived in the morning with multiple changes of clothes (he went on a six-mile run up the American Tobacco Trail on his lunch break) and healthy snacks (he was on the keto diet and carried around two 64oz water bottles). “He always had so many bags,” Bailey remembers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FgrzDm"&gt;Calivas had his demons. His mother had died when he was young; he’d never really known his father. But his job at the Apple Store grounded him. It gave him a sense of dignity and purpose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dFP6sc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“To help dreamers become doers, to help passion expand human potential, to do the best work of our lives.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="B0tvm5"&gt;Then the store hired a new manager: a whip smart, data-driven woman. According to Bailey and another former colleague, if you were on her good side, you could get a good schedule, a special project, a promotion. But if you weren’t? “You’d be punished in the most strategic ways possible,” the former colleague says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="05UAOy"&gt;By all accounts, Mark Calivas was never on her good side. “She hated him, she told me,” the former colleague explains. “She just would constantly talk about how Mark wasn’t good enough, Mark wasn’t special, don’t give that opportunity to Mark because he hasn’t earned it, even though he had done everything to earn it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCaMbx"&gt;Over the years working under the manager, Calivas’ confidence started to wane. He felt trapped — intimidated and bullied by her behavior, according to his close friends. In 2021, he took medical leave to cope with his depression. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cp099m"&gt;&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="8ZE7X2"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-entry-sidebar"&gt;
  &lt;p id="ycdM7f"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you or anyone you know is considering suicide or is anxious, depressed, upset, or needs to talk, there are people who want to help:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctya36"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the US:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uQnmrF"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.crisistextline.org/" data-analytics-viewport="related-story" data-analytics-link="related-story"&gt;Crisis Text Line&lt;/a&gt;: Text START to 741741 from anywhere in the USA, at any time, about any type of crisis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tCSWwi"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/" data-analytics-viewport="related-story" data-analytics-link="related-story"&gt;The National Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt;: 1-800-273-8255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6KpLt1"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/" data-analytics-viewport="related-story" data-analytics-link="related-story"&gt;The Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt;: 1-866-488-7386&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wM5S3M"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside the US:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ia5gw0"&gt;The International Association for Suicide Prevention lists a number of suicide hotlines by country. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.iasp.info/resources/Crisis_Centres/" data-analytics-viewport="related-story" data-analytics-link="related-story"&gt;Click here to find them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YVqlTs"&gt;Befrienders Worldwide: &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.befrienders.org/need-to-talk" data-analytics-viewport="related-story" data-analytics-link="related-story"&gt;https://www.befrienders.org/need-to-talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fBYtjM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5M6EQx"&gt;Bailey and two former colleagues say there have been multiple HR complaints filed against the manager (Apple would not confirm the complaints). But nothing ever seemed to change. “I filed three, maybe four complaints myself,” one of the former colleagues says. “I participated in at least six investigations.” Eventually, employees lost hope that anyone at Apple’s corporate office would hold the woman accountable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wY5mhT"&gt;In response to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Apple spokesperson Nick Leahy said: “We are and have always been deeply committed to creating and maintaining a positive and inclusive workplace. We take all concerns seriously and we thoroughly investigate whenever a concern is raised and, out of respect for the privacy of any individuals involved, we do not discuss specific employee matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CasmPp"&gt;The story illustrates a potentially widespread problem for Apple’s frontline workers. When something goes wrong — a bad manager, a missed paycheck, an untenable onslaught of work — many say they have no one to turn to for help. “Corporate makes decisions based on what they think will work in the stores without talking to people who work in the stores,” a former colleague says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Zl4IJu"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eu7YEm"&gt;This struggle echoes a complaint made by some employees in Cupertino, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22700898/apple-company-culture-change-secrecy-employee-unrest"&gt;who’ve said that the employee relations team&lt;/a&gt; — Apple’s version of human resources — is more concerned with protecting the company than its workforce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xjANSH"&gt;But hourly workers at Apple may have it even worse. The employees who spoke to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;say that while the company is hyper concerned with customers, it treats its retail and customer service staff as an afterthought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3Zfdw"&gt;Over the past five months, Apple’s hourly workforce has been watching as corporate employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity"&gt;advocate for more pay transparency&lt;/a&gt;. Some have organized with employees in Cupertino &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638150/apple-appletoo-employee-harassment-discord"&gt;under the banner #AppleToo&lt;/a&gt;, to call for better working conditions. Others are just now beginning to speak out — realizing that the issues their well-compensated corporate colleagues are experiencing could be greatly exacerbated on the frontlines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MRCZOp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with 16 current and former employees on Apple’s retail, support, and sales teams who say their complaints about working conditions and pay have largely been ignored. Some say they are governed more by algorithms and systems than actual managers, making it difficult to get holistic help. All of them note that while they came into the job believing in Apple’s mission, they see a profound breakdown in how the company’s corporate values translate to the frontlines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZQAEDv"&gt;“They say our soul is our people but it really didn’t feel like that to me,” a former employee says.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mJPZZvn5ndQjxrwxIxtRC7BikAk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23049950/VRG_Illo_4894_Apple_Spot_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Illustrations by Jesse Zhang&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="kkef4x"&gt;Nearly every shift at an Apple Store starts the same way: an employee picks a line from the Apple credo and talks about how it applies to that day’s work: “We are here to enrich lives. To help dreamers become doers, to help passion expand human potential, to do the best work of our lives. At our best, we give more than we take.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VtfhTA"&gt;Workers say it’s easy to tell who wants to get promoted because they’ll pick the line “Turning dreamers into doers” and discuss how Apple’s devices can help customers do that. Not every retail worker buys into it, though. “People get emotional,” says a current retail employee in Pennsylvania. “You see people go really deep in that stuff when they want to get promoted. It’s all just pandering.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RFKkVX"&gt;Part of the issue is pay. Apple’s retail employees make on average between $19 and $25 an hour in the United States, &lt;a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/Hourly-Pay/Apple-Hourly-Pay-E1138.htm"&gt;according to Glassdoor&lt;/a&gt;. That’s good for the retail industry, but can be grating for employees who want to build a career at the tech giant. Some say that after staying at the company for six years, they’re making less than $21 an hour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2HZ7vQ"&gt;Then there’s the issue of how retail workers are evaluated. In the store, Apple uses something called a “net promoter score” to see how stores are performing. After a customer leaves, they’ll sometimes receive a survey asking them to evaluate the employee who helped them as well as the overall store experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="C4kFwa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Employees spent eight hours a day fielding inquiries from angry customers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ljeqNJ"&gt;Low scores can often be about factors outside the employees’ control — things like low inventory or wait time. But they still reflect poorly on staff. “There’s never positive intent assumed,” says a current employee in Pittsburgh. “It always feels like you’re a kid getting in trouble and you’re making an excuse.” The surveys are meant to give customers a consistent way to say whether the stores are meeting Apple’s standards — but they systematically place the customer over the employee, by design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qq4FU1"&gt;This can be particularly frustrating when the issue stems from Apple corporate. In 2017, Apple customers with older iPhones realized that if they replaced their phone batteries, the performance would significantly improve. This quickly became one of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/28/16827248/apple-iphone-battery-replacement-price-slow-down-apology"&gt;Apple’s largest customer experience scandals&lt;/a&gt;, as people realized the company had intentionally slowed down older iPhone models to (supposedly) preserve their battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zCeK0z"&gt;To quell public outrage, the company said it would replace phone batteries, free of charge, for a year. To meet rising customer demand, Apple told some retail workers to try to complete battery swaps in under 10 minutes, according to a former employee. The result was a disaster for workers, who say they didn’t have the supplies or resources necessary to meet the mandate. “You can’t replace a battery in 10 minutes,” a former retail manager says bluntly. “Nothing translates from corporate to the stores because they’re not in the stores.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwaHmR"&gt;Set against this backdrop, the Apple credo has become increasingly important. It’s meant to inspire employees to provide exemplary customer service — to elevate even mundane parts of the job to stratospheric levels of importance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJa16b"&gt;In the past, some employees assumed that it applied to how Apple treated its workforce. Wasn’t the company supposed to enrich the lives of its employees? To give more than it took?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9VQyvX"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FToUXM"&gt;That started to break down on March 14th, 2020, in the early days of the pandemic, when Apple announced it was temporarily closing all its stores, sending retail employees home. In Pennsylvania, one current worker was selected to be part of a new program to answer calls from customers who needed tech support over the phone. The employee was relieved — his wife was immunocompromised, and he himself suffered from asthma, making the pair particularly vulnerable to COVID-19. Being able to work from home seemed like a perfect solution to stay safe and continue earning money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ybNdj"&gt;From the start, the job was stressful. Employees spent eight hours a day fielding inquiries from angry customers. They were evaluated based on call time and customer satisfaction. As with many hourly roles at Apple, people with high scores knew they’d eventually get better schedules, promotions, and opportunities. People with low scores could be placed on action plans to try to improve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hiBQkL"&gt;The Pennsylvania employee says he didn’t hear much from his manager until July 2020, when he was told that his scores were good. So good, in fact, that he was going to start taking tier two calls. If a lower-level adviser couldn’t answer a customer’s questions, they could escalate the call to him. He asked if the job came with a pay bump and was told it did not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkD2aX"&gt;Apple tried to make up for the increased workload for hourly employees by sending employees in the work from home program a shirt as a gift for all their hard work. When it arrived, employees realized it had a large 14 on the back (for iOS 14) and 2020 printed on the sleeve. These were leftovers from WWDC 2020 — Apple’s live event that had been canceled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AGWyPI"&gt;The shirt felt like a slap in the face. Employees wanted a raise. Some had multiple roommates and worked two or three jobs to try to make ends meet. On top of that, they were dealing with the same existential angst as the rest of the population weathering a global pandemic — all while being yelled at on the phone by customers who barely treated them like people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tV4WZc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It starts to get into a game of fixing the numbers more than helping the customers.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wzI63A"&gt;The Pennsylvania employee said his mental health started to suffer. He was working in a poorly lit room, unable to leave the house because of the lockdown. When he tried to talk to his manager about how he was feeling, he was told to try opening a window or put a plant on his desk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xJI1Zm"&gt;One day, the employee was doing a screen share with a customer who was having issues with her display. The device wasn’t under warranty — he told her it would likely cost $500 to fix. The woman started to cry. “I’m a college student, can’t you make an exception?” she asked. He said he was sorry, but it wasn’t up to him. Then the woman opened Photo Booth on her computer screen — activating the webcam — and held a razor to her wrist. “This is what the stress you’re giving me is doing to me,” he says she told him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v97QKf"&gt;When the employee explained to his boss what had happened, the man asked if he needed half an hour to decompress. The employee responded that it didn’t feel like enough time. According to his recollection, his boss conceded: “Okay, take a breather, but try to keep it to 30 minutes because we need to keep our call time down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zpWZIg"&gt;In early 2021, Apple Stores started to reopen, and the employee asked to go back to in-person work. “I have asthma, my wife has a chronic illness, but we were forced to wager my mental health against my physical health to see if it was worth going back to the store,” he says. The decision wasn’t his anyway — he was told he needed to keep working from home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZJ8MoG"&gt;It wasn’t until he asked to go on medical leave that he was finally able to go back to the store. “They let me come back to the store to keep me off leave,” he alleges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8ABJz"&gt;In September, Apple announced that all retail and care employees who’d been with the company since March 31st would receive a $1,000 bonus. To some workers, it was a nice surprise; but after years of feeling mistreated, others believe the bonus had more sinister motivations. “I think it feels more like they don’t want to get sued for not offering hazard pay after making some of us work in public in the last year,” the Pennsylvania employee says.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ovKlXs7qk2IVFUFBF50Op8O4p2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23049949/VRG_Illo_4894_Apple_Spot_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Illustrations by Jesse Zhang&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="0xeMLe"&gt;The mental health strain that retail employees felt working from home during the pandemic gave them a glimpse into the lives of another organization at the tech giant: AppleCare. These employees are part of the company’s tech support team that answers customer questions in online chats and over the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Bv6pE"&gt;One employee, a gay man living in the South, said that when he landed a job at Apple after high school, he knew he’d stay with the company for years. “This big company that everyone talks about, I had a chance to be a part of,” he says. “I always describe it as my longest relationship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsK8Gu"&gt;At first, the idea of working from home for a tech giant seemed too good to be true. But over time, he says sitting at a computer for eight to 10 hours a day started to take a mental toll. In 2021, he decided to take medical leave to cope with the stress of responding to customers in under two minutes, a requirement for his position. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VPeSAC"&gt;As his medical bills started piling up, the employee says he and his partner ran out of money. “We had to start selling our belongings to pay bills,” he explains. “We downsized and spent most of the summer without electricity or air conditioning.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BAixJV"&gt;When his paycheck arrived in May 2021, he found it was just $23, due to health insurance deductions. He couldn’t afford to pay rent. When he contacted Apple’s corporate payroll team, he said the response was, “We’ll look into it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1fcM23"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bXxUn1"&gt;“I’ve given the best years of my life, all my 20s working for Apple, now I need help and they’re not there,” the employee says. “I don’t think the corporate people or payroll teams have any idea what it’s like to live on the edge financially,” the employee says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZ7H0H"&gt;While Apple’s corporate offices take a proactive, deliberate approach to product development, Apple’s customer support function operates in a reactive mania, using a vast array of processes and metrics to keep employees on task. If workers go to the bathroom or are away from their computers for more than five minutes, they’ll sometimes get a note from their manager asking why they aren’t working. They’re monitored based on their customer satisfaction score, as well as after call work time, which dictates how much time after a call or chat they spend writing up notes, and average handle time (AHT), which indicates how long it takes them to solve a customer issue. A good AHT is around 15 minutes for phone calls and about two minutes for chats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKkOyY"&gt;“It starts to get into a game of fixing the numbers more than helping the customers. They look at the numbers and assume that is helping the customer,” a former employee says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fd90iL"&gt;Employees who really want to help customers say they often have to sacrifice their personal metrics. “If I have an elderly person on the phone, am I going to be a little slower with them to the detriment of my personal metrics?” a current employee asks. “Yes, I can’t treat every person the same because they’re not all the same.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXfBC8"&gt;On chats, the ability to resolve issues can be even more difficult, as employees are expected to speak to three people simultaneously during busy parts of the year. “It’s impossible to do a good job multitasking with that many scenarios,” a current employee explains. “Especially because we have to respond in two minutes — from an Apple ID issue to an iCloud issue to an iOS [or] Mac install.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YhB1ke"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A month has passed and I still see him in that chair whether my eyes are closed or open.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="JaUc16"&gt;About four years ago, Apple started hiring vendors to manage some of the chats and calls. For tier two advisers — people who were tasked with taking calls that couldn’t be resolved by lower-level employees — this meant a sudden onslaught of angry customers. Vendors didn’t receive the same level of training as in-house Apple employees, according to multiple employees, meaning issues were constantly being escalated. By the time a tier two adviser got the call, customers were often irate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmFliU"&gt;In September 2019, an AppleCare employee wrote a letter to management laying out the team’s grievances. The letter said the company should “eradicate triple chats and reduce double chats” and noted “Apple should include a cost of living adjustment in addition to our raises, because it’s fair and just.” They included links to studies about how multitasking increases chronic stress. (The employee declined an interview request from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yWRzeH"&gt;Then, in February 2021, tier two chat advisers were told those jobs were being eliminated. One employee says they were told that it was because customer satisfaction ratings weren’t as high for the tier two chat team as they were for the tier two phone advisers. “It was a self-fulfilling prophecy,” the employee explains, noting that taking three chats at a time is notably different than answering one phone call after another. “We equated it to being able to do your job with one hand tied behind your back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eDEbs6"&gt;Employees felt like the promise of working at Apple — the idea that you could move up in the organization and eventually land a managerial role — was slowly being taken away. In the past, hardworking employees could be selected for a “team manager assistant” role — meaning they’d fill in for managers who were on vacation. The idea was that eventually they themselves would become the manager. In practice, however, it just meant that they took on managerial responsibilities, with the illusion of possible job progression, and received no extra pay. Now, even that thin reward felt elusive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZk8lv"&gt;Employees also saw a disparity in Apple’s financial success — reflected in the wealth of its executives — and their own financial pricarity. In 2015, Tim Cook announced that he planned to give away his $800 million fortune before he died. “When I saw Tim Cook was saying he’s worth nearly a billion dollars and he plans to give all of that away before he dies, I thought, ‘Well shit, he could start with us in AppleCare,’” a current employee says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="bqNaGO"&gt;
&lt;p id="ygS6iz"&gt;A few weeks before he died, Mark Calivas sent an email to an Apple human resources representative, according to a text conversation he later had with his friend Jimmy Bailey, excerpts of which have been viewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Over seven years, I too have been a victim of intimidation, public humiliation, bullying, slandering, retaliation, and on one occasion, lies,” he wrote. “I have held out a long time for change, but to date, no Store Leader or Senior Manager has been able to keep me safe from [the manager]. I want to return to work for Apple. I want to keep contributing to the company. However, for my mental health, I don’t feel like I can do so while working in the same environment as [the manager].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qL3l8C"&gt;Bailey says Calivas had lost hope that he’d be able to transfer to a different store. After all the investigations into the manager had gone nowhere, he felt — like some other employees at the store — that corporate just didn’t care. Unlike his three former colleagues, however, he was now too depressed to interview for another job and leave Apple altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lC2foe"&gt;The morning of September 7th, 2021, Bailey walked into Calivas’ room to find him slumped over a chair, his arms hanging limp in his lap. “A month has passed and I still see him in that chair whether my eyes are closed or open,” Bailey says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RVVRv0"&gt;“I want to end this speaking directly to Tim Cook,” Bailey says in a final interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Tim, I have emailed you about this issue. I explained the damage caused at Apple Southpoint. I spoke to an employee relations representative and expressed my concern. I told him that all they need to do is look into the records on hand to see the devastation that could have been prevented. What then, Tim, do you plan on doing? I still see Mark. I see him constantly. But even though I see him, he is gone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWiKEg"&gt;In a statement emailed to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, an Apple spokesperson said: “We were devastated by the death of our colleague and our thoughts are with his loved ones in their time of grief.”&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/c/22807871/apple-frontline-employees-retail-customer-service-pandemic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/c/22807871/apple-frontline-employees-retail-customer-service-pandemic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-02T09:05:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-02T09:05:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Govee’s immersive backlights are an affordable way to make your TV glow</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tQxpNE60vXxCMSU3ZwiyHIjNPIA=/0x171:4096x2902/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70219052/color_segmented_color.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both Govee’s newest and last-gen Immersion TV LED backlights are on sale today.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HEATvR"&gt;If you’re looking to step up your TV game and make watching movies and gaming more immersive, Govee offers a range of colorful lighting kits that also make for great holiday gifts. One of its most appealing products are the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22566408/govee-immersion-ambilight-tv-backlight-review"&gt;Immersion TV LED backlights&lt;/a&gt;, which sync to whatever you’re watching on your 55-inch or 65-inch screen, making it appear as if the TV colors are bleeding out of the frame and onto your walls. Responsive LED strips like these are typically expensive, but right now Govee’s 2020 backlighting kit costs just $61 once you clip the $10 off coupon at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Govee-Immersion-Backlights-Ambient-Assistant/dp/B08LVPWQQP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. That’s the kit’s best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SVGNj7"&gt;Prefer not to shop at Amazon? Govee is selling this product direct &lt;a href="https://us.govee.com/products/immersion-tv-backlights"&gt;for $63&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22725979/govee-tv-backlight-bars-review-specs-price"&gt;newer version&lt;/a&gt; of these lights, which farther extends the backlighting with Light Bars. Typically $150, you can &lt;a href="https://us.govee.com/products/govee-immersion-kit-wi-fi-tv-backlight-light-bars"&gt;buy this one for $130&lt;/a&gt; from Govee or for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Govee-Immersion-Backlights-Ambient-Assistant/dp/B09B7PY111?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$140 from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you clip the on-page coupon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Inb6v"&gt;If you intend to gift these to multiple people, Govee is additionally taking 5 percent off your purchase total when you buy two, 10 percent if you buy three, and 15 percent off if you buy five of them. Use the promo codes &lt;strong&gt;XMAS5&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; XMAS10&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; XMAS15&lt;/strong&gt; depending on the amount you’re purchasing. We found that both the 2020 model and this year’s version offer great value for the money, even before the discounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="megSUZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10681491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="XieHFJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10896909"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VeCscB"&gt;If you missed out on a smart display deal during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, you’re in luck: Walmart is now &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSmart-Clock-Gen-2-Grey-Color-Smart-Bulb%2F507060083&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDealRoundup1222021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offering a 60 percent off&lt;/a&gt; deal on the Lenovo Smart Clock 2 with a bundled Lenovo Smart Bulb, bringing the final sale price down to $25. The Lenovo Smart Clock 2 incorporates a touchscreen display into a form factor that would be right at home on your bedside table. It’s one of the smallest smart displays you can buy, yet it still offers full Google Assistant capabilities and comes with a handy night light feature. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22714538/lenovo-smart-clock-2-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PzrRNa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10869431"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ybzbpN"&gt;The latest AirPods sold out relatively quickly after receiving some of their first significant discounts during Black Friday and Cyber Monday. Thankfully, however, Amazon still is selling the third-generation AirPods for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQL3NWT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150&lt;/a&gt; at checkout — the lowest we saw them drop to during the recent shopping holiday. That’s a $30 discount on the latest AirPods model, which sport shorter stems, IPX4 water resistance, and improved sound over their last-gen counterpart. However, they lack active noise cancellation, which is found in the AirPods Pro. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ji1ZJE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10887582"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="leY0cM"&gt;If you don’t mind buying refurbished, Sonos is discounting several products right now. For those interested in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/27/17507796/sonos-beam-speaker-soundbar-alexa-review"&gt;Sonos Beam&lt;/a&gt;, the first generation is selling for &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-11556673?sid=VergeRoundup12221&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sonos.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fbeam-b-stock" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$319&lt;/a&gt; as opposed to $399, the full retail cost when purchased new. Although the soundbar lacks support for Dolby Atmos like the second-gen model, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701137/sonos-beam-gen-2-atmos-soundbar-review-specs"&gt;we found&lt;/a&gt; it’s still a competent smart speaker that shares many features in common with the newer version. Sonos is also discounting the third-gen Sonos Sub, selling it for &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-11556673?sid=VergeRoundUp212121&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sonos.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fsub-g3-b-stock" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$599&lt;/a&gt; refurbished. That is $150 less than if you were to purchase the wireless subwoofer new. The second-gen model, typically $699, is also selling for &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-11556673?sid=VergeRoundUp12121&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sonos.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fsub-g2-b-stock" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$549&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKhOhp"&gt;All of the products in this sale will arrive in a box with all original accessories and cables, and they’ve been certified directly from Sonos. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21530290/refurbished-tech-products-gadgets-where-to-buy-amazon-ebay"&gt;That means&lt;/a&gt; the company has tested and given each an internal and external cleaning and inspection. They also come with a one-year warranty and a 45-day money-back guarantee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="pyu4uR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sonos raises prices for majority of products amid supply chain crunch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667044/sonos-speaker-price-increases-announce-september-12"},{"title":"Sonos could soon announce a smaller, more affordable Sub Mini subwoofer","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808243/sonos-sub-mini-leaked-features-design"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="TLuKxY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603369"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="tqzyYp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603379"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lwMndD"&gt;If you missed out on a great TV deal during Black Friday, fret not, because Amazon still offering a significant discount on many sizes of one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"&gt;best TVs for gaming&lt;/a&gt;, the LG C1. The $1,500 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-OLED65C1PUB-Alexa-Built-Smart/dp/B08WFV7L3N/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=77&amp;amp;imprToken=8cbebbea-6135-8066-2bf&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/22800858%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch is still selling for $1,297&lt;/a&gt;, while the $2,500 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WG4HKKY/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=78&amp;amp;imprToken=8cbebbea-6135-8066-2bf&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/22800858%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch is going for $1,797&lt;/a&gt;. Regardless of which configuration you choose, however, all sport several features gamers will love, including a 120Hz refresh rate, Dolby Vision HDR compatibility, and support for HDMI 2.1. Best Buy is offering the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6NQzEaUul?u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%2F22800858%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;same discounts&lt;/a&gt; on the 55- and 65-inch models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kFuqM0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10897267"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="tw08Bz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10897277"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="cM7dw0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best streaming device to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21375098/best-streaming-device"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="xLa6UP"&gt;Other great deals happening now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ctZyQr"&gt;One of the best PlayStation 5 exclusives to date, &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;, is selling for just $50 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ratchet-Clank-Rift-Apart-PlayStation-5/dp/B095T8C99C/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; instead of $70. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523093/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-ps5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4ZpYKf"&gt;New subscribers can enjoy a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7mpFlBYRH" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;free six-month trial of Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7mp9tnVJz" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a free three-month trial of Apple TV Plus&lt;/a&gt; from Best Buy. You must create a Best Buy account to take advantage of either deal, however.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hWGNw0"&gt;Walmart is currently offering a &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1141873/1192598/9383?subId1=VergeDailyDealRoundup110221&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FOculus-Quest-2-Advanced-All-In-One-Virtual-Reality-Headset-64-GB-refurbished%2F612192172&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;refurbished, 64GB Oculus Quest 2 for $199&lt;/a&gt;, a rare $100 off the cost if you were to buy it new. The standalone virtual reality headset new also comes with a one-year warranty and a 30-day return policy. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="H3ffaN"&gt;The SteelBook launch edition of &lt;em&gt;Shin Megami Tensei V&lt;/em&gt; for the Nintendo Switch is $10 off at Amazon, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shin-Megami-Tensei-Steelbook-Launch-Nintendo/dp/B097PJX3Z9/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costing $50&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="p1si3E"&gt;Right now, Anker’s Amazon storefront is taking up to 35 percent off some of its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=anker+power+strip" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;power strips and surge protectors&lt;/a&gt;, with AC outlets like the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerExtend-Delivery-High-Speed-Charging/dp/B094V7D8CM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PowerExtend USB-C 3 Cube&lt;/a&gt; going for $26 instead of $40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wrn2eM"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7mRids2WY" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This blue Ember Smart Mug 2&lt;/a&gt; comes with a built-in battery that allows you to control the temperature, making for a great holiday gift. Right now, it’s down to $100 at Best Buy, $30 off the initial list price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3Ijz8w"&gt;Normally $35, you can buy the Blink Mini camera for just $20 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blink-Mini-plug-security-detection/dp/B07X6C9RMF/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=72&amp;amp;imprToken=8cbebbea-6135-8066-2bf&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/22800858%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, making it one of the cheapest indoor smart security cameras you can buy right now. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/28/21231112/blink-mini-smart-home-camera-security-cam-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SxazXT"&gt;Apple’s convenient MagSafe Battery Pack for iPhones with wireless charging has dropped to a new all-time low price on Amazon. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MJWY3AM-A-MagSafe-Battery/dp/B099BWY7WT?tag=theverge02-20#" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can pick one up for just $75&lt;/a&gt;, down from its usual $99. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="PD0FC2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wWW4MM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7feHv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G9bJZF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yeIiQf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3i844v"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y2whc7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrtpnr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysHeDE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/2/22811974/govee-light-kit-lenovo-smart-clock-2-airpods-3-sonos-lg-c1-oled-tv-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/2/22811974/govee-light-kit-lenovo-smart-clock-2-airpods-3-sonos-lg-c1-oled-tv-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T23:06:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T23:06:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple may have a problem with iPhone demand as well as supply</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Mini and iPhone 13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6Pt_bloSZ8pfkCa6qYK5dcV02U=/0x0:2002x1335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70218007/vpavic_210916_4760_0240.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4oAmLl"&gt;Apple is indicating to its iPhone 13 component suppliers that it may not order as many units as expected due to a drop in demand, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-02/apple-tells-suppliers-iphone-demand-has-slowed-as-holidays-near"&gt;report in Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCBnNe"&gt;While the company had already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723209/apple-iphone-13-chip-shortage-manufacturing-report"&gt;cut&lt;/a&gt; orders for the year to 80 million — down from a target of 90 million — it was reportedly planning to make up for much of the drop next year. Now, though, Apple is said to have told manufacturing partners that this may not happen and they might not see the expected boost in orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpdk2u"&gt;Like almost every other technology company, Apple has been dealing with supply issues brought on by the global semiconductor shortage. CEO Tim Cook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751418/apple-q4-2021-earnings-supply-constraints-chip-shortage"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the company’s last quarterly earnings took an estimated $6 billion hit due to the shortage as well as the impact of COVID-19 on manufacturing in Southeast Asia, and Apple was expecting an even bigger impact on this current holiday quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0UmohO"&gt;If Bloomberg’s report is accurate, though, it suggests that the iPhone 13 range might not meet Apple’s initial expectations even without the supply crunch. The original plan to assemble 90 million units for 2021 reflected a forecast of increased demand, as Apple usually orders around 75 million iPhones for the year of each launch. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22813347/apple-iphone-demand-suppliers-chip-shortage-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22813347/apple-iphone-demand-suppliers-chip-shortage-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T20:27:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T20:27:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are a go-to pick that’s often on sale&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HYaZ7v"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday may have come and gone, but that doesn’t mean there aren’t any AirPods deals to be had. In October, Apple finally launched its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third generation of AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, introducing a new AirPods lineup and dropping the starting price of the second-gen, entry-level AirPods from $159 to $129. Since then, we’ve seen many retailers starting to discount the second-gen AirPods as well as the more expensive AirPods Pro and Max, which offer noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard model. We’ve even seen some of the first discounts on the latest AirPods, despite how recently they launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the best deals available on each model, including the entry-level AirPods, the AirPods Pro, the third-gen AirPods, and the AirPods Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UJyTOI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on MacBooks right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"},{"title":"Which AirPods should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="VFDHZw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10742787"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ej2msf"&gt;The best entry-level &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt; (second-gen) deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eg29V6"&gt;Once $159, Apple recently lowered the list price of the second-gen AirPods — now the entry-level model — to $129. Moreover, it only sells the model with a wired charging case, which charges via a standard Lightning cable. What’s great, though, is that this version frequently gets discounted, so you can frequently find it for even less. During Black Friday, we saw this model drop to as low as $89. While the price has since increased, you can still find Apple’s most affordable pair of AirPods discounted down to $109 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;AirPods (third-gen)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="d2yjBK"&gt;As previously mentioned, the newest pair of wireless earbuds support Apple’s MagSafe technology. The short stems yield a more subtle design, while improved sound and features like sweat and water resistance, support for spatial audio with dynamic head tracking, and improved battery life render them a nice improvement over the last-gen model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QiPrKN"&gt;Deals were once hard to come by on the third-gen model given how recently they launched, but we finally started seeing some significant deals during Black Friday and Cyber Monday that are still available. Right now, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is selling the $179 earbuds for $150 at checkout, their lowest price yet. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FAirPods-3rd-generation%2F510546422&amp;amp;sharedid=VergeBestAirPodsdeals1222021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; is also discounting the third-gen model, but only by $10 or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q2OXRZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10744075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Iewbkw"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="S8o5q4"&gt;We think Apple’s premium true wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, are the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; that iPhone owners can buy, regardless of the price. They have better sound quality than the models above, offer active noise cancellation, and come with a wireless charging case. The earbuds also support Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; feature, which adds an immersive surround sound effect to select content, and comes with swappable silicone tips. In addition, they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713126/airpods-pro-conversation-boost-firmware-update"&gt;recently received a firmware&lt;/a&gt; update that added Conversation Boost, an accessibility feature for those who are hard of hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bM8uVd"&gt;Additionally, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"&gt;recently launched a new version&lt;/a&gt; of the AirPods Pro with a wireless charging case that supports Apple’s MagSafe technology, just like the third-gen AirPods. These start at $249, but you can buy them right now for $197 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQMJHXY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or $200 at &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/x9zDqO"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. That’s not quite as low as the $159 price we saw this model drop to during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, but it’s still roughly a $50 discount off the cost you’d pay through Apple directly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="THtgJp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x5NHYH"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ESUeUd"&gt;The AirPods Max aren’t the iconic in-ear style that has become synonymous with the AirPods name. They’re large and luxurious, comprised of aluminum, steel, and mesh fabric that remains comfortable during extended listening sessions. They also sport excellent noise cancellation, Apple’s spatial audio feature, and a wide, balanced sound, even if they lag behind some of their peers when it comes to bass response. They’re not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;best noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for most people — blame the $550 sticker price — but it’s hard to find a pair of Bluetooth headphones that sound better and feature more intuitive controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBAAwB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="irGZgJ"&gt;Although the AirPods Max were discounted to $429 at Amazon during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, prices have since increased. Still, the Max are currently available in various colorways at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-AirPods-Max-Space/dp/B08PZHYWJS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $429, or $479 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfThsYtSLBr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1610235-REG%2Fapple_mgyn3am_a_airpods_max_green.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Mpx47T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
