<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-13T18:05:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T18:05:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T18:05:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stop and update your iPhone to iOS 14.8 right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tD4CoZE3XDP5N7N3rFYqvkgwSSM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69854057/acastro_170731_1777_0003_v6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vNbyFA"&gt;Apple has released a suite of new updates for &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212807"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212804"&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212806"&gt;watchOS&lt;/a&gt; to fix a bug that &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild/"&gt;security researchers at Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt; say was very likely exploited to allow government agencies to install spyware into the phones of journalists, lawyers, and activists. The researchers say the bug allowed for a “zero-click” install (meaning the target didn’t have to do anything to be infected) of the Pegasus spyware, which is reportedly capable of stealing data, passwords, and activating a phone’s microphone or camera. You can read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;our explainer of Pegusus here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ghtgyJ"&gt;Given the severity of the exploit, you should update to iOS 14.8, macOS Big Sur 11.6, and watchOS 7.6.2 as soon as you can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gDzdFG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s update page says it’s “aware of a report that this issue may have been actively exploited.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11sjdQ"&gt;We heard about the exploit in August, &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/08/bahrain-hacks-activists-with-nso-group-zero-click-iphone-exploits/"&gt;when Citizen Lab reported&lt;/a&gt; that it had been successfully used against phones running iOS 14.6 (released in May). Citizen Lab also said the vulnerability, which it codenamed “ForcedEntry,” seemed to match the behavior of an exploit Amnesty International &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/research/2021/07/forensic-methodology-report-how-to-catch-nso-groups-pegasus/"&gt;wrote about in July&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, the security researchers wrote that it was made possible by a bug in Apple’s CoreGraphics system, and happened when the phone tried to use a function related to GIFs, after it received a text message containing a malicious file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GY3uHD"&gt;However, even with that info, it could be difficult to pin down exactly what was happening without access to the infected files themselves. &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild"&gt;According to Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt;, they discovered files while re-analyzing a backup from an activist’s hacked phone. The files appeared to be GIFs sent as SMS attachments, but were actually PSDs and PDFs. (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212807"&gt;Apple’s update notes&lt;/a&gt; say that the issue occurred when processing a maliciously crafted PDF.) Citizen Lab suspected they could’ve been related to Pegasus, so it sent the files to Apple on September 7th. Apple quickly released the software updates patching the bug on September 13th, and thanked Citizen Lab in a statement for “completing the very difficult work of obtaining a sample of this exploit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IweTQR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;iOS 14.8 is seemingly only focused on security&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TEuK8F"&gt;Some of Monday’s updates also fix a second security issue with WebKit for iOS and macOS Big Sur (it isn’t mentioned in the release notes for Catalina). While it’s unclear if it’s related to NSO’s exploits — its discovery is attributed to “an anonymous researcher” instead of Citizen Lab, and it’s in a different part of the system — Apple still says that it “may have been actively exploited.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWQTAy"&gt;Such an urgent security issue explains why we’re seeing a new update to iOS just a day before an Apple event, where it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"&gt;expected to announced new phones&lt;/a&gt; that will probably never run this version of the OS. Still, there have been rumors about an iOS 14.8 release &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/09/ios-14-8-release-date-information-rumor/"&gt;since early August&lt;/a&gt;, but given that Monday’s release seems to only deal with the security issues discovered in September, it’s possible we’ll see at least one more iOS 14 release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="55m3eu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Keep your devices up-to-date&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eLzesV"&gt;CoreGraphics’ PDF rendering seems to have been problematic recently when it comes to security. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212601"&gt;iOS 14.7 also included a fix&lt;/a&gt; for a seemingly separate issue with the system, which could also lead to arbitrary code execution. WebKit has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22251149/iphone-update-14-4-fixes-exploited-security-vulnerabilities"&gt;recently had&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22251149/iphone-update-14-4-fixes-exploited-security-vulnerabilities"&gt;few updates&lt;/a&gt; to fix security issues that Apple says “may have been actively exploited.” When news of the CoreGraphics exploit broke in August, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/"&gt;Apple told &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it was working on improving security for iOS 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IaocFK"&gt;All of this serves as a reminder about how important it is to keep all your devices up-to-date. While you hopefully never find yourself on the bad side of a government using advanced spyware, it’s still a good idea to make sure that your device isn’t vulnerable to widely-reported security exploits. Thankfully, Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-android-fragmentation-with-ios-15/"&gt;planning on letting&lt;/a&gt; users install security updates for iOS 14 without having to upgrade to iOS 15, which could be useful for any future fixes. For the time being, though, get all your devices updated as soon as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1LRoB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 13th, 7:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added quote from Apple’s statement thanking Citizen Lab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T17:45:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T17:45:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Air (late-2020).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YgkMYN"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including some equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the discounts that are currently available for the latest MacBook models, as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — which will be compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; upon its release in the fall — and we’ll highlight those when we find them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1022323/7613?sharedid=VergeBestDealsAppleMacbook042721&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15- to 20-percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. For now, however, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="15A2tS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;The best MacBook Air deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FJU3RG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance. It ticks all right boxes when it comes to performance and price, which is why it’s our number one pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best laptop of 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iF2kto"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and a 256GB SSD. It typically sells for $999, however, it’s currently available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $850 once you add it to your cart, where additional savings will automatically apply. This matches the all-time low for this popular entry-level laptop. The 512GB configuration is also on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LFLC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; in all three colorways for $1,100, a discount of $150 that automatically applies at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRJZQQ"&gt;Although retailers like &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747531561997035408#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604825-REG%2Fapple_mgn63ll_a_13_3_macbook_air_with.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; are selling the base 256GB MacBook Air and upgraded, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747532219045612135#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB&lt;/a&gt; model at regular price, we have seen them drop the pricing in the past to match Amazon’s discounts. These deals can come and go quickly, though, we expect more to come as the holiday shopping season draws near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;The best MacBook Pro deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The touch bar-equipped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; comes in more sizes and options than the Air, and it’s geared more toward demanding use cases. The base model is the 13-inch, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1-powered variant&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a brighter screen, longer battery life, and an internal fan designed to maintain performance under increased workloads. The M1 MacBook Pro 13 normally starts at $1,299, but the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is on sale for $150 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5N6RSS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738975458064148072#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; — bringing it down to $1,150.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afDps1"&gt;The upgraded version of the 13-inch M1 MacBook Pro with 8GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD is also $150 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LH3F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747532652589677821#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for a final sale price of $1,350.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjmE4B"&gt;While there have been rumors throughout the year of a r&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;edesigned MacBook Pro, one with an M1X processor and additional ports&lt;/a&gt;, we might not see it until further into the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ue6Q0U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="44XxWs"&gt;Of course, you can also buy some older MacBook Pro models, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21256520/apple-13-inch-macbook-pro-2020-review-keyboard-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch, mid-2020 model&lt;/a&gt;. The older device features four Thunderbolt ports, Windows bootcamp-ready Ice Lake processors, the current scissor-switch keyboard, increased RAM, and various storage configurations. Right now, the 13-inch model is available in two configurations at Amazon: one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-Pro-10th-Generation-Quad-Core/dp/B08DTPQ9XB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10th Gen i7 Intel processor and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; for $1,999, and one with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B08821TJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB of storage and a 2.0GHz 10th Gen Intel Core i5 processor&lt;/a&gt; for $1,600.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hij1MQ"&gt;If you want a bigger laptop with more horsepower, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2019 MacBook Pro 16&lt;/a&gt; is the top-of-the-line model. Compared to its predecessor, it has a better keyboard, newer processors, and improved speakers. Amazon is currently offering the space gray configuration with an Intel Core i7 CPU and 512GB of storage &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FZV45H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale for $2,285&lt;/a&gt;, a $114 discount. There are other configurations available with more storage and speedier processors — you can also get the 16-inch model with an Intel Core i9 CPU and 1TB of storage &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FTNGNC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $2,645 at Amaz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FV1Y57/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt;, for instance — but deals are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zjWXtS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10469149"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;The best Mac Mini deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. The outright best deal on the base Mac Mini is at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, where you can pick up the 256GB model for a historical low of $600 (discount applies at checkout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpqfyJ"&gt;As for the 512GB model, we have seen retailers such as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5P7TLW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604800-REG%2Fapple_mgnt3ll_a_mac_mini.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; offer it for $100 off its usual $899 price point, but there are currently no sizable discounts to be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T12:39:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T12:39:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple hasn’t decided whether to appeal the Epic v. Apple ruling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gd07Y2G1J0y_cyh8iC04BbcEFWk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69852281/acastro_210429_1777_epicApple_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hyYrSd"&gt;Apple is still weighing whether to appeal &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"&gt;last week’s &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple &lt;/em&gt;antitrust ruling&lt;/a&gt;, the company said today. In a call with reporters, a representative said Apple was still evaluating its legal options and had not made a decision about its next steps. The position contrasts sharply with Epic, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670269/epic-files-appeal-fortnite-legal-battle"&gt;announced yesterday&lt;/a&gt; that it intends to appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EpwrPk"&gt;Apple reiterated a position it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662320/epic-apple-ruling-injunction-judge-court-app-store"&gt;took last week&lt;/a&gt;, casting the ruling as a near-total victory. Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers dismissed nine of Epic’s 10 claims, including ones that would have required iOS to allow third-party app stores and payment processors. She ordered Epic to pay damages for breaching its developer contract. Apple also doesn’t have to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667069/fortnite-ios-return-apple-epic-ruling"&gt;return Epic’s hit game &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to the iOS App Store, and it can choose to terminate other Epic-affiliated developer accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m3O8ah"&gt;Apple hasn’t taken a position on whether it will ban any Epic-related apps beyond &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. Asked for comment, a representative said Apple is still looking at its options regarding Epic’s future on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qm8ccl"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/17/21372480/apple-epic-threat-developer-tools-agreement-unreal-engine-fortnite"&gt;Epic said Apple&lt;/a&gt; might cut off support for the widely used Unreal Engine on iOS — a nuclear option in the conflict between them. That seems theoretically possible now, but Apple has publicly taken a measured tone so far, saying it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667069/fortnite-ios-return-apple-epic-ruling"&gt;“welcome” &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; back into the App Store&lt;/a&gt; if it removed its non-Apple in-app purchase option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XsB9s"&gt;While Apple won most claims, it was found to be violating California’s Unfair Competition Law with its anti-steering rules. A court order will require it to let developers link to alternate payment options outside their apps, although they still need to use Apple’s in-app purchase system within them. That order will take effect in December if Apple doesn’t appeal and win a delay of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtwMqZ"&gt;For now Apple says it’s studying how it could change its rules to comply with the order, which it characterized as line-editing Apple’s terms of service. But unsurprisingly, it doesn’t have any answers to share.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671736/epic-apple-fortnite-antitrust-case-ruling-appeal-decision"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671736/epic-apple-fortnite-antitrust-case-ruling-appeal-decision</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What comes next for the App Store?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i46PCnuYdn54rk3JYSgtw-kZ6-0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69852010/acastro_190218_1777_apple_streaming_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8vxzkF"&gt;On September 10th, a verdict finally arrived in &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;, and it has left the App Store model in a precarious state. Epic wanted to do away with the system entirely, breaking Apple’s control over software distribution on iOS — but the ruling stopped well short of that. Instead, we got an ambiguously worded injunction that seems to open the door to developers skirting Apple’s commission system — or at least making it easier to use non-Apple payment methods outside their apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2bJ1Y"&gt;In the immediate aftermath of the ruling, Apple pushed to cast it as a victory — and Epic seemed sure it had lost. It’s understandable: until we see how Apple reacts and how the court looks on Epic’s recent appeal, it’s hard to know for sure what the injunction will actually mean. The ruling could be a significant leak in Apple’s carefully controlled ecosystem. But for that to happen, Epic and its allies will need a lot to break in their favor, both inside the courtroom and out. There are still lots of places for Apple to fight, and lots of ways to pare back developers’ small glimmer of a victory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLtFXm"&gt;Here are the four most important questions from those fights, the questions we’ll be watching particularly closely in the months to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LUEC9k"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much freedom does this ruling actually give developers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jos2mP"&gt;For all the complexities of the case, the actual order issued by the court is simple. It zeroes in on a single sentence in Apple’s App Store guidelines, which Apple is now forbidden from enforcing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kzfyla"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apps and their metadata may not include buttons, external links, or other calls to action that direct customers to purchasing mechanisms other than in-app purchase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QIjpkc"&gt;The one thing that’s clear is that developers have to be allowed some way to forward users to outside payment systems. But as my boss Nilay &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667161/app-store-epic-ruling-difference-button-external-link"&gt;points out here&lt;/a&gt;, the “buttons” clause is ambiguous and could let developers make those systems look a lot like Apple’s official option, even if they open Safari or another app for the actual payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ePca6"&gt;Enforcing that interpretation will take a lot of legal work from developers and a lot of developer-friendly rulings in court. From the other side, there will be lots of opportunities for Apple to chip away at the injunction’s force. It’s hard to say how interested courts will be in defending it. But if they aren’t, the App Store could still be a very risky place for developers using alternate payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OMkF8u"&gt;In particular, there’s a real threat that Apple will still be able to impose the so-called Apple tax on whatever new payment system is allowed. In theory, the App Store’s commissions are levied to support the entire store, not just the payment system, and in her ruling, the judge considers the idea of Apple allowing alternate payment methods but requiring the same 30 percent cut via audits or other systems. (My colleague Adi explores this in the seventh section of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"&gt;her deep dive on the ruling&lt;/a&gt;, under the heading “Apple could collect an ‘Apple Tax’ even without in-app payment charges.”) If that’s borne out in an actual legal order, the door would slam shut on alternate payment systems pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EDQ92r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will Apple change its App Store rules in response to this ruling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wlIOuT"&gt;The other half of the equation is Apple itself, which is almost certainly going to change its App Store rules if the order stands, if only to change the anti-steering clause. The specific rule about referring to outside payment systems is out, but Apple still has broad legal authority to write its own rules for the App Store. So what new rule will the company write to replace the old one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GU0qdE"&gt;In particular, there are lots of ways Apple could discourage outside payments without banning them entirely. There’s the commission rate idea we’ve already discussed, but Apple could also place restrictions on how outside payment links are presented. The company could require specific price differentials between Apple’s IAP system and any competitors, and it could require the systems to be presented side by side — whatever the company thinks will pass muster with the court and keep developers using the Apple system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1HcdZh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will external payments look like on the App Store?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vEXiBf"&gt;When the dust has settled on both those questions, developers will be left with some alternatives to Apple’s built-in payment system. It could be a simple button or a maze of links and forms — and a lot will be riding on where external payments land on that spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flmTxP"&gt;The specific numbers on this are important, since developers will be balancing the cost of friction against the extra money they get from sidestepping Apple. On the face of it, a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;-style app will get an extra 30 cents for every dollar of in-app purchases that don’t go through Apple’s system (minus whatever fees the cost of providing the alternative service eats up). But it also seems likely that leaving Apple’s walled garden will add friction to the process, which means there will be fewer overall dollars being spent through the alternate path. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McEMuJ"&gt;But how many fewer? If you lose four out of every ten customers by kicking to an outside payment system, then there’s no point putting it in place — but if it’s only two, you’ll still come out ahead. The specific UX details will make an enormous difference in determining that attrition rate: How large is the button? How many extra taps? Can Safari force you to enter in your credit card number each time you make a new purchase? Each extra step will nudge developers back toward IAP, and make Apple’s App Store profits that much safer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UoerZF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much of the App Store will move to external payments?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WrL9vF"&gt;Tim Sweeney’s dream in launching this lawsuit was to break Apple’s control over software on iOS. That didn’t happen, and as long as the ruling holds up on appeal, Apple’s control over iOS looks more solid than ever. Under the rules of the injunction, the only way Sweeney can hurt Apple is if developers vote with their feet and leave, taking their commissions with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NsbZED"&gt;Apple is particularly dependent on big developers like Epic, which have enough profits to pay 30 percent commission rates and generate the bulk of the App Store’s revenue. Crucially, the court’s injunction isn’t limited to games or in-app payments, so there’s no telling how much of the developer base will leave Apple’s payment system. If that happens, Apple could be forced to switch to give up the commission system for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m4h2Rx"&gt;So far, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667047/apple-epic-ruling-games-app-store-fortnite-revenue-purchases-business"&gt;doesn’t look like that’s happening&lt;/a&gt;. The response from most developers has been noncommittal, and some already seem to think it won’t make sense for them to pursue payments outside the Apple system. But with the actual changes still months away (and already under appeal), it makes sense for developers to wait and see whether the new system is worth pursuing. But after the many possibilities opened up on Friday, it seems hard to believe none of them will be interested in exploring their options.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671574/epic-apple-app-store-new-rules-meaning-ruling-decision"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671574/epic-apple-app-store-new-rules-meaning-ruling-decision</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What to expect from Apple’s iPhone 13 event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l2WnJedXB1sVhcLhp4xichPG_Tk=/166x0:1123x638/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69851117/Screenshot_2021_09_10_7.38.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IlLw7g"&gt;Apple’s first fall event is coming up on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22648593/apple-fall-event-2021-date-iphone-macbook-watch"&gt;Tuesday, September 14th, at 1PM ET / 10AM PT&lt;/a&gt;, right around the time when the company typically introduces its latest version of the iPhone. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21508028/apple-iphone-12-pro-max-homepod-mini-event-recap-biggest-announcements"&gt;Like last year’s iPhone event&lt;/a&gt;, Tuesday’s announcements will be entirely digital, in the slick, over-produced style that’s become Apple’s trademark during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Du1zo1"&gt;Rumors suggest a potentially less dramatic set of announcements compared to the iPhone 12’s radical flat-edged design. It does seem like the Apple Watch and AirPods could get some serious attention, though, even if the iPhone 13 looks more or less the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t0h080"&gt;Keep reading below for a roundup of everything we expect to see at the event, including some long-shot surprises Apple could have in store.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone 12 mini (left) and iPhone 12 (right)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8833rrFzFziADRLiBLUiwc7W2Ew=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22023082/vpavic_4279_20201107_0180.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ewr5Bs"&gt;An iPhone 13 with a familiar design and maybe a new nighttime camera trick&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HaEvbK"&gt;Rumors suggest that the iPhone 13 will look a lot like the iPhone 12 but with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307312/iphone-13-smaller-notch-high-refresh-rate-screen-hole-punch-foldable-se-5g"&gt;a possibly smaller notch and high refresh rate displays&lt;/a&gt; on all or most models. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576703/iphone-13-rumors-sizes-notch-camera-processor"&gt;Both &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; and analyst Ming-Chi Kuo&lt;/a&gt; seem to be in agreement that the new iPhone will receive iterative if helpful changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nUBVbq"&gt;Those could include an LTPO (low-temperature polycrystalline oxide) display like Apple uses to provide variable refresh rates on the Apple Watch. The new phone hardware may also include &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/04/rumors-iphone-13-to-feature-larger-wireless-charging-coil-alongside-stronger-magsafe-magnets/"&gt;stronger magnets, a larger charging coil for MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/02/14/iphone-13-always-on-display-matte-back/"&gt;always-on display&lt;/a&gt;, and possibly, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/09/iphone-13-fewer-storage-options-and-new-colors/"&gt;new colors and fewer storage options&lt;/a&gt;. A new A-series processor is naturally in the cards as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oXLloq"&gt;The star of Apple’s iPhones, the cameras, will likely also receive an upgrade with the iPhone 13. Improved performance for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21553255/apple-iphone-13-camera-2021-ming-chi-kuo-analyst-prediction"&gt;the ultrawide camera&lt;/a&gt;, better optical zoom for video recording, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-10/apple-readies-new-iphones-with-pro-focused-camera-video-updates"&gt;ProRes support, and a Portrait Mode for video&lt;/a&gt; have all been rumored. The other possible addition is &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/02/15/iphone-13-always-on-display-stronger-magesafe/"&gt;astrophotography capabilities&lt;/a&gt; to compete with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203782/google-removes-wide-angle-astrophotography-pixel-4a-5g-5"&gt;a similar feature&lt;/a&gt; Google has offered in the past. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1435272731746979840?s=20"&gt;An event announcement video&lt;/a&gt; tweeted by Apple’s senior vice president of worldwide marketing Greg Joswiak featuring a dramatic pan up to a starry night sky may have added more fuel to that specific fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZqhqLw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’re California Streaming on September 14th. See you real soon.   &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AppleEvent?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AppleEvent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/OjOvJFXlHd"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OjOvJFXlHd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Greg Joswiak (@gregjoz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1435272731746979840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k5WCNIbLNlpUf2UCoeBki_wnt90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21925375/vpavic_200929_4216_0121.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="g1aETW"&gt;A flat-edged Apple Watch Series 7 with a bigger screen and the same health features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MeuKUr"&gt;While the iPhone 13 is staying consistent, it seems the Apple Watch Series 7 might get a more involved redesign. The rounded body Apple’s used since the introduction of its smartwatch is rumored to be replaced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/29/22647766/apple-watch-series-7-rumors-screen-size-new-design-41mm-45mm"&gt;with flatter displays and edges&lt;/a&gt;, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;. The change sounds similar to the shift Apple made from the iPhone 11 to the iPhone 12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t4Grz5"&gt;Earlier this year, news broke that Apple was also possibly introducing an entirely separate, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22351979/apple-watch-rugged-extreme-sports-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;more rugged, extreme sports-friendly version of the Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;. Rumors have coalesced around the iPhone 12-inspired Series 7 since but not this sports version. We’ll have to wait and see if it arrives this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjio0g"&gt;Other improvements to the mainline Series 7 could include a faster processor and overall bigger watches at 41mm and 45mm (up from 40mm and 44mm), thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654621/apple-watch-series-7-new-watchfaces-bigger-screens"&gt;a combination of larger displays, smaller bezels, or both&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports. It’s not clear if that would impact the compatibility of the many watch bands Apple has sold over the years, but here’s hoping it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9yyugr"&gt;Those hardware changes will allow for new watchfaces, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman, but likely not new health features. Despite rumors of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532916/apple-watch-series-7-features-blood-glucose-body-temperature-extreme-sports-edition-se-2"&gt;body temperature and blood glucose tracking&lt;/a&gt;, now it seems Apple might leave those additions for future models. Complicating matters further, though, Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666305/apple-series-7-manufacturing-issues-resolved-september-mass-production"&gt;reportedly resolved production delays&lt;/a&gt; for the new Watch, some versions &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1436226530598817815?s=20"&gt;could arrive late or in smaller quantities&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uPyp1tAFu7ySzKQN1zzQF9Y5QPI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19336099/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F57Mhj"&gt;Third-generation AirPods with some AirPods Pro-inspired looks &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="imEUed"&gt;The entry-level third-generation AirPods are also rumored to be in line for a makeover. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534123/apple-airpods-3-pro-2-2021-chip-design-battery-life-true-wireless-earbuds-headphones-homepod"&gt;Early word in 2020&lt;/a&gt; pointed to a design that takes cues from the AirPods Pro, minus the earbuds’ swappable rubber tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GdxNzc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/apple-plans-redesigned-airpods-for-2021-new-airpods-pro-in-2022?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;Further corroboration in 2021&lt;/a&gt; suggests the same. It seems you can expect shorter stems, rounded earpieces, and a squatter wireless charging case that might have a 20 percent larger battery, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PineLeaks/status/1435302679014739970?s=20"&gt;according to Pine Leaks&lt;/a&gt;. In general, the new AirPods might finally look a bit less like headphones with the wires cut off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qCUCdYYVSJw438QnZ8SDpmQE4lU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22689246/cgartenberg_210629_4653_003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qwruU3"&gt;The launch of iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and macOS Monterey, with a few ingredients missing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1qfN18"&gt;Apple is expected to announce the launch dates for iOS 15, iPadOS 15, watchOS 8, and macOS Monterey, though the company has confirmed some features will arrive late or in beta form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W4DRGp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;iOS 15 and iPadOS 15&lt;/a&gt;, which finally brings proper, moveable widgets to the iPad for the first time along with other improvements, will likely arrive in late September with the iPhone 13. Notable upgrades include Focus Modes that create approved notification and app lists for specific settings like work or personal time, a dramatic redesign of Safari (that’s now settled into something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629183/ios-15-beta-safar-address-bar-fix-options-accessible-controls"&gt;a bit more familiar&lt;/a&gt;), new FaceTime layouts and audio improvements, a possible future source of controversy in digital IDs, and yet another tweak to multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWlynE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;watchOS 8 is also expected in the fall&lt;/a&gt; with more modest upgrades. Along with support for Focus Modes and new digital keys and IDs, watchOS 8 brings new watchfaces (including a nice photo one), new exercise types (pilates time to shine), and a mindfulness app to Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7omTiC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; could come later in the fall (perhaps timed to the launch of a new Mac computer). The new desktop OS continues to pick up features from Apple’s mobile OSes, like support for Shortcuts, AirPlay, and helpful changes to FaceTime and Messages. The most exciting new Monterey feature, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;Universal Control&lt;/a&gt;, allows for seamless control of an iPad with the mouse and keyboard already attached to your Mac. That includes easily dragging and dropping files from iPad to Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jNWBKl"&gt;Unfortunately, Universal Control might not be there at launch. The feature has yet to be included in a beta, and Apple has already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629165/apple-shareplay-ios-ipad-os-15-macos-delayed"&gt;announced delays for SharePlay&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s take on group watch plug-ins and Discord screen sharing that became all the rage early on in the pandemic. Luckily, other features &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596970/apple-macos-monterey-live-text-intel-processors"&gt;previously limited to Apple’s M1-based devices&lt;/a&gt; — like Live Text — are coming to older Intel machines. You win some, and you lose some, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9_f3z8bOTLHy8XPZWdaY6WFdmMY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15974614/akrales_190318_3298_0088.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eyTC3Z"&gt;Possibly a longer wait for new iPad Minis, iPads, and Macs of all stripes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ul7qvE"&gt;It really seems like updates to the entry-level iPad and the long-ignored iPad Mini are happening; the question is when. Apple could reserve the devices for a later event in October rather than hang with a new iPhone and Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FFHF0J"&gt;The new iPad Mini is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22573423/ipad-mini-2021-release-date-news-features-bezels"&gt;expected to receive the flat-edged design&lt;/a&gt; that’s apparently sweeping through Apple’s entire product line, along the usual processor improvements, a larger screen between 8.5 to 9 inches, no home button, and a Touch ID sensor built directly into the power button. The entry-level iPad changes are expected to be more minor — thinner bezels and body and the inclusion of an A13 Bionic chip, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/20/new-ipad-mini-exclusive-a15-processor-usb-c/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IeRsUa"&gt;Even less likely are new Macs, whether &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;a new Macbook Pro&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;Macbook Air&lt;/a&gt;. Apple will probably want to schedule some separate time to announce whatever it has planned for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637477/new-mac-mini-design-ports-m1x-release-date-gurman"&gt;next version of the M-series chips&lt;/a&gt; and the new designs that could come with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0Crt2"&gt;That’s a whole lot of possible announcements, not even taking into account a tease for longer-term Apple projects like the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654606/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-wireless-connection-stream-data"&gt;continued exploration of AR and VR&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; to hear about it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8FMjB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to sell or trade in your old iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T70nzkoDsN25RaoDxSoNkLFe0ws=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69851082/jbareham_170916_2000_0232.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r2qn1u"&gt;If you’re an iPhone owner, it’s very possible you’re considering trading up to the latest model, which (when this article was last updated) is likely to be the iPhone 13. However, if your current iPhone is still in good shape, you may be wondering about what to do with it. Should you sell it? Trade it in? Give it away?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DXGfsW"&gt;Well — any of the above. This guide will walk you through the process of preparing your old phone, and what your best alternatives are for disposing of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Y9FVIs"&gt;Are you transferring to a new iPhone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="DHovgw"&gt;If you’re transferring to a new iPhone — or even if you’re not — you probably want to back up your phone before you do anything else (see below). Backing up to iCloud is probably easiest — and it also gives you the option of transferring your data either directly from your old phone to your new phone, or transferring your data from iCloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3NF8gC"&gt;Once you’ve done that, then go ahead and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/20/20871131/data-transfer-new-iphone-11-pro-max-ios-how-to"&gt;copy all your data to your new phone&lt;/a&gt;. If you want, you can also try going to “Settings” &amp;gt; “General” &amp;gt; “Transfer or Reset iPhone.” Depending on the version of iOS you’re running, you may have access to a wizard called “Prepare for New iPhone,” which will run you through all the steps necessary to transfer your data to your new phone. (It will also let you check your phone’s trade-in Status.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="It doesn’t hurt to check that your iPhone is back up to iCloud." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8sugnJrj_qQoBajv2ry2xUaLYbs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22838046/IMG_D79739CF9DAE_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It doesn’t hurt to check that your iPhone is backed up to iCloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Under “Transfer or Reset Phone” you’ll find a wizard to walk you through the process." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LtRfDLKH_olAw2egNZ1dIhjsZ5Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22838053/IMG_D831063B05A8_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under “Transfer or Reset Phone” you’ll find a wizard to walk you through the process.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PMsgrZ"&gt;Back up your phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ffuR80"&gt;As mentioned above, it’s a good idea to have a current backup of all of your data saved on iCloud, your laptop, or any other local / cloud storage.  Backing up your phone on iCloud Backup is probably the easiest. If it’s been a while and you want to make sure backup is switched on in your phone’s iCloud settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ntzmom"&gt;Tap on “Settings” &amp;gt; [your name] top button &amp;gt; “iCloud” &amp;gt; “iCloud Backup.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEEtWS"&gt;If “iCloud Backup” is switched off, toggle it on. If it’s already toggled on, and you’re preparing to wipe your old iPhone, you may want to tap “Back Up Now” just in case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="nGLcQ1"&gt;You can also &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/iphone/back-up-iphone-iph3ecf67d29/ios"&gt;back up your iPhone to a computer&lt;/a&gt;: either to your Mac by using your Finder (if your Mac is using a macOS version before 10.15, you’ll use iTunes) or to a Windows PC (again, using iTunes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6qWjaR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge guide to the iPhone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/21/17828022/iphone-user-guide-how-to-ios-tips"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="3W7ILm"&gt;Wipe your phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BpfFOB"&gt;When you’re sure that all of your data is stored — and you’ve transferred all your data to your new phone — it’s time to wipe your old phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KJzHI1"&gt;First, you have to make sure you’ve gotten rid of a few identifiable features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="uUBuwb"&gt;Disable “Find My iPhone” by going to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Find My” &amp;gt; “Find My Phone” and toggling “Find My Phone” and “Find My Network” to off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DQ6OXX"&gt;Unpair any devices from your phone, including your Apple Watch. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SMREGp"&gt;Toggle iMessages off (just in case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="g1y20x"&gt;Then you need to sign out from your Apple ID:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="t9tT4x"&gt;	Select “Settings” &amp;gt; [your name] top button &amp;gt; “Sign Out” (at the bottom of the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LaxEWl"&gt;	Enter your Apple ID password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xmVLyK"&gt;	You’ll be asked if you want to keep a copy of your data on this iPhone. Assuming you’ve backed everything up and are about to wipe your phone, you don’t need to toggle anything on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xZdkhV"&gt;	Tap on “Sign Out” in the upper right corner, and then again on the “Are you sure?” pop-up window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="1ucZCq"&gt;Finally, get ready to erase it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="RHqjWX"&gt;Remove the SIM card from the phone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="72iH92"&gt;Go into “Settings” &amp;gt; “General” &amp;gt; “Transfer or Reset iPhone”  and select “Erase All Content and Settings.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If you’re wiping your phone, you don’t want to keep any data on it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/piUZnlaqfVeSDb64HBCoO6H3iqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22838056/IMG_C0157C8B9455_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re wiping your phone, you don’t want to keep any data on it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You’ll get one last chance to change your mind." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eMHILye-QLRmP11cto9ODExlSS0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22838059/IMG_BB1A5D632ACF_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll get one last chance to change your mind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XBA7Rz"&gt;Clean it up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sqdesG"&gt;Before you even think of selling your phone, you need to make sure it’s looking its best. Remove the case and / or any stickers, and assess the damage you can see, including scratches or dents, which you’ll have to mention when selling the phone. Then, clean your phone using a screen wipe or screen cleaner. (You might want to leave your screen protector on if it’s in good condition.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oZfhwf"&gt;It’s also a good idea to take photos of your phone. You’ll need them for the listing when selling the phone online; in addition, they’re useful in case the recipient reports further damage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cNdcWI"&gt;Sell your phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tUf4or"&gt;There are a variety of places where you can try to sell your used phone. A few of those are listed here, along with the estimates I got for an iPhone 11 in good condition with 256GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d0Rtla"&gt;The first thing you might think of is to trade your phone in to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Ftrade-in&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664451%2Fiphone-13-sell-trade-in-old-apple-how-to" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This may be especially useful if you haven’t bought your new iPhone yet, and you want to see if you can save a little on your new device. If you’ve already bought your new phone, then you can go to Apple’s trade-in page and see what your phone is worth. Note that in return you’ll be getting a gift card for future Apple purchases. The quote for the iPhone 11 was $390 in trade-in value at the time of publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofjsLE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.decluttr.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664451%2Fiphone-13-sell-trade-in-old-apple-how-to" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decluttr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; buys the phone from you and then resells it. The company gives you a price online; you then ship your phone to Decluttr within 28 days. The phone will be inspected; if there are issues, you will be offered a revised price which you will have 14 days to accept or decline. An iPhone 11 in good condition with 256GB received a quote for $401.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6JQzg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fservices%2Fbest-buy-trade-in%2Fpcmcat133600050011.c&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Buy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; lets you either mail in your phone or bring it to your nearest Best Buy retail store; either way, you can trade it in for an e-gift card. My iPhone 11 was given an estimated value of $360 (increased to $400 if traded in for specific tech products).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5F5SmE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flipsy.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flipsy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; deals with a variety of retail sites; it will let you know what vendors offer how much, and then you get 14 days to ship the device. The vendor pays for shipping. If the vendor doesn’t agree with your assessment, they will send a revised offer; since each vendor has its own return policies, it’s a good idea to check before you ship. The iPhone 11 got prices from two vendors; the highest was $455.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5YPx3L"&gt;With &lt;a href="https://swappa.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swappa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you create a listing along with a price; when your device is sold, you receive payment from Swappa and then ship the phone directly to the buyer. Swappa charges a fee from the buyer, depending on the price of the phone, but you are responsible for shipping costs. The average price that an iPhone 11 with 256GB could be sold for was quoted as $543.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3Gx6n"&gt;And of course, there’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fpages.ebay.com%2Fseller-center%2Findex.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664451%2Fiphone-13-sell-trade-in-old-apple-how-to" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eBay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Selling here can be a bit complicated, but basically you get up to 250 listings for free each month; once you sell your item, there is a 10.2 percent fee plus a $0.30 transaction fee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ktxNwU"&gt;Places where you can sell your phone free of charge (except, of course, for shipping fees) include &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/marketplace/selling/"&gt;Facebook Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://craigslist.org"&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt;, and the subreddits &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/phoneswap/"&gt;r/Phoneswap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/appleswap/"&gt;r/Appleswap&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/hardwareswap/"&gt;r/Hardwareswap&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3t6ZHP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you don’t want to sell or trade in your old phone, there are other things you can do with it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rx0YPR"&gt;Play it safe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="t0XZEr"&gt;Most of these transactions take place via mail. However, if you decide to do the transaction in person, it’s safest to meet in a public place — and these days, if you’re at all concerned about infection, to either do it outdoors in a park or other public space, or in a cafe or other indoor venue that follows current safety recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eicK6g"&gt;And if you decide you don’t want to sell or trade in your old phone, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21542079/phone-reuse-android-iphone-how-to"&gt;there are other things you can do with it&lt;/a&gt;, including using it as a webcam or letting it be your kids’ first grown-up phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhSxUq"&gt;Whatever you decide to do with your old phone, just make sure you’re happy with your new phone first. You don’t want to have to return that brand-new phone because of problems (or because you just don’t like it) and suddenly find yourself desperately scrounging around for a temporary substitute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A0PHLx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 10th, 2021, 2:00PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on January 14th, 2020 and has been updated to account for differences in iOS and in available services and websites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22664451/iphone-13-sell-trade-in-old-apple-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22664451/iphone-13-sell-trade-in-old-apple-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aliya Chaudhry</name>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-12T14:48:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-12T14:48:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic has appealed Friday’s ruling in the Epic v. Apple case</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OSH7yiCuSacSvN4rUhSdE0WOAjQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69848504/acstro_190902_apple_event_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qx655b"&gt;Epic Games has filed an appeal to a Friday’s ruling in its lawsuit against Apple, calling on a higher court to reexamine the case and overturn the judge’s ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29aZkr"&gt;“Notice is hereby given that Epic Games, Inc.... appeals to the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from the final Judgment entered on September 10, 2021,” &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21061142-epic-games-appeal"&gt;the document reads&lt;/a&gt;. Few details are given about the legal basis for Epic’s appeal, but it is likely to continue to press on the federal antitrust allegations dismissed by the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYIsOt"&gt;At trial, Epic argued Apple had a monopoly because of how it requires developers to use its payments system for in-game purchases. But Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers ruled Friday that Epic should pay damages to Apple for violating rules around its in-app purchasing system, while undoing Apple’s most restrictive rules on steering customers to alternate payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yG3pML"&gt;Most notably, the judge found that Epic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"&gt;failed to make the case&lt;/a&gt; for Apple as a monopoly in the mobile gaming marketplace, which she ultimately found was the relevant market for the company’s claims. “The evidence does suggest that Apple is near the precipice of substantial market power, or monopoly power, with its considerable market share,” Judge Rogers wrote — but said the antitrust claims failed in part “because [Epic] did not focus on this topic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ilf7Nz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A comprehensive breakdown of the Epic v. Apple ruling","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="K6YR6G"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21061142-epic-games-appeal/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="epic-games-appeal (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ntP38j"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670269/epic-files-appeal-fortnite-legal-battle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670269/epic-files-appeal-fortnite-legal-battle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-12T13:29:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-12T13:29:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>The first iPhone with 1TB of storage is reportedly coming Tuesday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xqd1kV2gcyc_EwTvq2d8SjY5pyA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69848264/vpavic_4243_20201017_0077.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Last year’s iPhone 12 | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IJGCgc"&gt;Days before Apple’s California Streaming event on September 14th, a new investor report from analyst Ming-Chi Kuo says he expects the iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro Max to each have a 1TB storage configuration (h/t &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/12/kuo-iphone-13-to-drop-64gb-storage-size-pro-models-to-offer-1tb-option/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Kuo also says the iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 mini will have storage configurations of 128GB, 256GB, and 512GB, but no 64GB option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybhuHK"&gt;Kuo also said he expects Apple to reveal AirPods 3 at Tuesday’s event, but that Apple will probably keep the AirPods 2 available. He cautions that the iPhone 13 could be affected by supply chain shortages, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650516/apple-watch-series-7-delayed-manufacturing-production-issues"&gt;has been previously reported&lt;/a&gt;, but expects there will be limited impact on iPhone 13 shipments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cTkCLy"&gt;Previous leaks and rumors have pointed to an iPhone 13 lineup that will include four models in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576703/iphone-13-rumors-sizes-notch-camera-processor"&gt;same sizes as last year’s models&lt;/a&gt;. The new phones are expected to have improved cameras that include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618070/apple-2021-iphone-13-camera-features-video-portrait-prores-ai-filters"&gt;video portrait mode and an astrophotography mode&lt;/a&gt;, an improved ultrawide lens and a better optical zoom for video recording. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eH8z5A"&gt;Other &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/29/22647766/apple-watch-series-7-rumors-screen-size-new-design-41mm-45mm"&gt;rumors around the Apple Watch 7&lt;/a&gt; are predicting a faster processor and a new hardware design, including larger screens and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654621/apple-watch-series-7-new-watchfaces-bigger-screens"&gt;new watchfaces&lt;/a&gt;. And the&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22573423/ipad-mini-2021-release-date-news-features-bezels"&gt; iPad Mini is expected&lt;/a&gt; to get a big redesign, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hehdwZ"&gt;The fall event gets underway at 1PM ET on September 14th, and will be a virtual event &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fapple-events%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F12%2F22670072%2Fapple-iphone-13-pro-models-1tb-storage-kuo" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;streaming from Apple Park&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVfIoX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670072/apple-iphone-13-pro-models-1tb-storage-kuo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670072/apple-iphone-13-pro-models-1tb-storage-kuo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-12T13:12:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-12T13:12:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>A short history of every time Apple CEO Tim Cook praised augmented reality</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tim Cook stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BFSuuOJCdScY2AnKMm3g_j2QVS4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69848232/tim-cook-apple-stock-0563.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Cook has been singing the praises of AR for five years&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ERzUQ0"&gt;Tim Cook has just marked &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22639629/tim-cook-apple-ten-years-decade-steve-jobs-legacy"&gt;10 years as Apple’s CEO&lt;/a&gt;, and while he’s grown Apple into the most valuable company in the world, it’s reasonable to argue he hasn’t yet introduced a signature, industry shaking product like Apple co-founder Steve Jobs did with the iPhone, iPad, Mac and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqO7Qo"&gt;But if you’ve been following Apple for a minute, you’ve probably heard Cook talk about the game-changing potential of augmented reality. While he once said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/5/28/4374482/tim-cook-apple-wearable-google-glass"&gt;hard to see the appeal of Google Glass&lt;/a&gt;, the AR wearable that proved unpopular with consumers, he’s held a consistently positive opinion on AR since at least 2016. While most of the industry was putting all its eggs in the VR basket, Cook repeatedly expressed support for what he views as the far superior AR. This would become a running theme: AR good, VR not so good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N3j429"&gt;It seems likely that AR may become the hallmark of Cook’s tenure, as long as Apple executes on a winning idea. While that’s not exactly guaranteed — Apple has yet to unveil an AR headset or glasses — Cook’s frequent comments about the tech keep the topic in the news and reassure investors and customers that Apple is working on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZIIDx"&gt;AR features are already available on the iPhone and iPad. And while hope is starting to fade that Apple will release a mixed reality device in 2022, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654606/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-wireless-connection-stream-data"&gt;latest rumors suggest&lt;/a&gt; the company is still forging ahead with some kind of AR/VR headset to be released in the not-distant future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5jIE1"&gt;Here’s a brief history of all the times Tim Cook said he was convinced AR was the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LR10VY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Cook says in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/7/26/12290920/apple-augmented-reality-ar-tim-cook"&gt;quarterly earnings call&lt;/a&gt; that “AR can be really great.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wX7rQO"&gt;“We have been and continue to invest a lot in this. We are high on AR for the long run, we think there’s great things for customers and a great commercial opportunity. The number one thing is to make sure our products work well with other developers’ kind of products like &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt;, that’s why you see so many iPhones in the wild chasing pokemons.” (Cook pronounces it “pokey-mans.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a3BaXv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2016: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Technology/exclusive-apple-ceo-tim-cook-prefers-augmented-reality/story?id=42064913"&gt;Cook tells &lt;em&gt;Good Morning America&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in an interview that he believes AR is a bigger deal than VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtE9kB"&gt;“There’s virtual reality and there’s augmented reality — both of these are incredibly interesting. But my own view is that augmented reality is the larger of the two, probably by far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HEwdho"&gt;AR “gives the capability for both of us to sit and be very present, talking to each other, but also have other things — visually — for both of us to see. Maybe it’s something we’re talking about, maybe it’s someone else here who’s not here present but who can be made to appear to be present.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WB8GUn"&gt;“There’s a lot of really cool things there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JqvA1V"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Cook makes a brief mention of AR in a &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sf/business/2016/08/13/tim-cook-the-interview-running-apple-is-sort-of-a-lonely-job/?utm_term=.71cfafb58188"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; profile&lt;/a&gt;: “I think AR [augmented reality] is extremely interesting and sort of a core technology. So, yes, it’s something we’re doing a lot of things on behind that curtain that we talked about.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LfFqeu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016: &lt;/strong&gt;In an appearance at Utah Tech Tour, Cook goes into detail about &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2016/10/02/tim-cook-talks-steve-jobs-need-for-encryption-at-utah-tech-tour-video/"&gt;how crucial AR may become&lt;/a&gt; and why he views it as superior to VR — while stressing that AR presents significant technology challenges before it can be adopted for mass consumerism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="s4U9pW"&gt;In terms of it becoming a mass adoption [phenomenon], so that, say, everyone in here would have an AR experience, the reality to do that, it has to be something that everyone in here views to be an “acceptable thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fE5O2T"&gt;And nobody in here, few people in here, think it’s acceptable to be tethered to a computer walking in here and sitting down, few people are going to view that it’s acceptable to be enclosed in something, because we’re all social people at heart. Even introverts are social people, we like people and we want to interact. It has to be that it’s likely that AR, of the two, is the one the largest number of people will engage with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uyxSDF"&gt;I do think that a significant portion of the population of developed countries, and eventually all countries, will have AR experiences every day, almost like eating three meals a day, it will become that much a part of you, a lot of us live on our smartphones, the iPhone, I hope, is very important for everyone, so AR will become really big. VR I think is not going to be that big, compared to AR. I’m not saying it’s not important, it is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mfq3v"&gt;I’m excited about VR from an education point of view, I think it can be really big for education, I think it can be very big for games. But I can’t imagine everyone in here getting in an enclosed VR experience while you’re sitting in here with me. But I could imagine everyone in here in an AR experience right now, if the technology was there, which it’s not today. How long will it take?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wx2VTE"&gt;AR is going to take a while, because there are some really hard technology challenges there. But it will happen, it will happen in a big way, and we will wonder when it does, how we ever lived without it. Like we wonder how we lived without our phone today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="o5nJLd"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZkV78RZ73Mw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="d6ivZT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Cook &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/johnpaczkowski/apple-ceo-tim-cook-on-virtual-reality-theres-no-substitute-f#.qel1aEjdb"&gt;tells &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that while “VR has some interesting applications,” AR is superior to VR because “there’s no substitute for human contact. And so you want the technology to encourage that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="LWV7WX"&gt;Augmented reality will take some time to get right, but I do think that it’s profound. We might ... have a more productive conversation, if both of us have an AR experience standing here, right? And so I think that things like these are better when they’re incorporated without becoming a barrier to our talking. ... You want the technology to amplify it, not to be a barrier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8zwWMG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2017: &lt;/strong&gt;Cook &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/features/apple-tim-cook-boss-brexit-uk-theresa-may-number-10-interview-ustwo-a7574086.html"&gt;expands his thoughts on AR’s potential&lt;/a&gt;, adding a new comparison: AR is a big idea, like the smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="qlZDkX"&gt;I’m excited about augmented reality because unlike virtual reality which closes the world out, AR allows individuals to be present in the world but hopefully allows an improvement on what’s happening presently. Most people don’t want to lock themselves out from the world for a long period of time and today you can’t do that because you get sick from it. With AR you can, not be engrossed in something, but have it be a part of your world, of your conversation. That has resonance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHlQnM"&gt;I regard it as a big idea like the smartphone. The smartphone is for everyone, we don’t have to think the iPhone is about a certain demographic, or country or vertical market: it’s for everyone. I think AR is that big, it’s huge. I get excited because of the things that could be done that could improve a lot of lives. And be entertaining. I view AR like I view the silicon here in my iPhone, it’s not a product per se, it’s a core technology. But there are things to discover before that technology is good enough for the mainstream. I do think there can be a lot of things that really help people out in daily life, real-life things, that’s why I get so excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ywuu2K"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; In a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-06-15/apple-s-tim-cook-on-donald-trump-the-homepod-and-the-legacy-of-steve-jobs"&gt;wide-ranging interview with &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Cook details his vision for AR at Apple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="b2MVpL"&gt;I think it is profound. I am so excited about it, I just want to yell out and scream. The first step in making it a mainstream kind of experience is to put it in the operating system. We’re building it into iOS 11, opening it to ­developers—and unleashing the creativity of millions of people. Even we can’t predict what’s going to come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b5fDe2"&gt;There’s some things that you can already get a vision of. We’ve talked to IKEA, and they have 3D images of their furniture line. You’re talking about changing the whole experience of how you shop for, in this case, furniture and other objects that you can place around the home. You can take that idea and begin to think this is something that stretches from enterprise to consumer. There’s not a lot of things that do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hboXPl"&gt;You’ll see things happening in enterprises where AR is ­fundamental to what they’re doing. You’re going to see some consumer things that are unbelievably cool. Can we do everything we want to do now? No. The technology’s not complete yet. But that’s the beauty to a certain degree. This has a runway. And it’s an incredible runway. It’s time to put the seat belt on and go. When people begin to see what’s possible, it’s going to get them very excited—like we are, like we’ve been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DIea6k"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; At an &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-41590323"&gt;event at Oxford&lt;/a&gt;, Cook responds to a student who asks what technology he would consider “transformative.” Cook says there are widespread uses for AR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gYUKHM"&gt;“I’m incredibly excited by AR because I can see uses for it everywhere. I can see uses for it in education, in consumers, in entertainment, in sports. I can see it in every business that I know anything about.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3JpVYm"&gt;“I also like the fact that it doesn’t isolate. I don’t like our products being used a lot. I like our products amplifying thoughts and I think AR can help amplify the human connection. I’ve never been a fan of VR like that because I think it does the opposite. There are clearly some cool niche things for VR but it’s not profound in my view. AR is profound.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lJlluP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; In an &lt;a href="https://www.vogue.co.uk/article/exclusive-apple-ceo-tim-cook-future-of-fashion-augmented-reality"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;Vogue UK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Cook says while Apple wasn’t looking to build a “giant database of clothes,” it would support companies in the AR space who were doing this work. “If you think about a runway show in the fashion world, that’s a great application of AR because some of these, you want to see the dress all the way around, you do not want to just see the front,” he tells &lt;em&gt;Vogue&lt;/em&gt;, noting how many runway shows are live-streamed and not just visible to an in-person audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBEvu6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; With the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/6/15742736/apple-arkit-augmented-reality-platform-wwdc-breakdown"&gt;introduction of its ARKit platform on iOS 11&lt;/a&gt;, Cook says in a quarterly earnings call that &lt;a href="https://www.patentlyapple.com/patently-apple/2017/11/the-transcript-of-todays-opening-statement-from-apples-ceo-on-fiscal-q4-2017-is-now-available.html"&gt;Apple has created&lt;/a&gt; the world’s largest augmented reality platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="GdJYqz"&gt;There already are over a thousand apps with powerful AR features in our App Store today with developers creating amazing new experiences in virtually every category of app aimed at consumers, students and business users alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RV7Y54"&gt;Put simply, we believe AR is going to change the way we use technology forever. We’re already seeing things that will transform the way you work, play, connect and learn. For example, there are AR apps that you interact with virtual models of everything you can imagine from the human body to the solar system. And of course you experience them like you’re really there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="je9Rb6"&gt;Instantly education becomes much more powerful when every subject comes to life in 3D. And imagine shopping when you can place an object in your living room before you make a purchase – or attending live sporting events when you can see the stats on the field. AR is going to change everything&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DM0tys"&gt;This is not quite what came to pass (more on that later). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJAyaa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; Post-ARKit launch, Cook admits he &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/features/apple-iphone-tim-cook-interview-features-new-augmented-reality-ar-arkit-a7993566.html"&gt;thinks AR technology&lt;/a&gt; for headsets or glasses isn’t yet up to par as far as Apple is concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ag0KHY"&gt;“I can tell you the technology itself doesn’t exist to do that in a quality way. The display technology required, as well as putting enough stuff around your face — there’s huge challenges with that. The field of view, the quality of the display itself, it’s not there yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MMoVt4"&gt;“We don’t give a rat’s about being first, we want to be the best, and give people a great experience. But now anything you would see on the market any time soon would not be something any of us would be satisfied with. Nor do I think the vast majority of people would be satisfied.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvKmAY"&gt;“Most technology challenges can be solved, but it’s a matter of how long.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WiQf8M"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2018: &lt;/strong&gt;During &lt;a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2018/02/01/apple-inc-appl-q1-2018-earnings-conference-call-tr.aspx"&gt;Apple’s Q1 earnings call&lt;/a&gt;, Cook describes “great excitement” around augmented reality among customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5QNWq"&gt;“Augmented reality is going to revolutionize many of the experiences we have with mobile devices, and with ARKit, we’re giving developers the most advanced tools on the market to create apps for the most advanced operating system running on the most advanced hardware. This is something only Apple can do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3yOGiC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2018: &lt;/strong&gt;Cook tells &lt;em&gt;NowThisNews&lt;/em&gt; during an interview about Apple’s Watch that AR is poised to become indispensable. “I think that one day we will wonder how we ever lived without it,” Cook says of AR. “We can have a much more enhanced conversation with the power of AR.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZOOfV"&gt;“The future is now,” he adds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EZs5TM"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vX9xBB_vBsc?rel=0&amp;amp;start=433" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VO88JU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2020: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.siliconrepublic.com/machines/tim-cook-ar-war-ducks-healthtech"&gt;Cook tells an audience in Dublin, Ireland&lt;/a&gt; that augmented reality “is the next big thing” and that it will “pervade our entire lives.” He gives an example of a company using AR and described its potential uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ImgYq0"&gt;Yesterday, I visited a development company called War Ducks … in Dublin – 15 people and they’re staffing up and using AR for games. You can imagine, for games it’s incredible but even for our discussion here. You and I might be talking about an article and using AR we can pull it up, and can both be looking at the same thing at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YDw6RA"&gt;I think it’s something that doesn’t isolate people. We can use it to enhance our discussion, not substitute it for human connection, which I’ve always deeply worried about in some of the other technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5lTJJO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: During an &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/05/opinion/apples-ceo-is-making-very-different-choices-from-mark-zuckerberg.html?showTranscript=1"&gt;interview with journalist Kara Swisher&lt;/a&gt; Cook agreed with her that augmented reality is “a critically important part of Apple’s future.” He imagines AR being used in health, education, retail, and gaming. “I’m already seeing AR take off in some of these areas with use of the phone. And I think the promise is even greater in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NExGsI"&gt;What’s Apple plan for AR?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MZhJMH"&gt;Clearly, Tim Cook has been bullish on AR for a long time. But so far, Apple’s biggest foray into AR remains the 2017 launch of ARKit — which use iPhones’ and iPads’ cameras and sensors to overlay images in 3D space when the device is pointed at a given area — for iOS 11. ARKit is available across Apple’s devices, which meant a lot of &lt;a href="https://github.com/olucurious/Awesome-ARKit"&gt;cool little projects&lt;/a&gt; by amateur AR enthusiasts. When ARKit launched, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/6/15742736/apple-arkit-augmented-reality-platform-wwdc-breakdown"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; wrote&lt;/a&gt; that the tech had the potential to allow Apple to catch rival Google in the AR space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dv9YB6"&gt;But despite the interesting early projects, ARKit hype fizzled after a few months. It’s not totally clear why, because it was released at the height of the &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; craze when AR finally had a popular mass-market application for a devoted fan base. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565654/pokemon-go-5-billion-fifth-anniversary-revenue-analytics"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go &lt;/em&gt;itself is still wildly profitable&lt;/a&gt;, raking in a billion dollars a year on average, but we haven’t seen a larger movement.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikGTfK"&gt;Since ARKit, Apple has made other, smaller steps forward with AR apps for the iPhone. In May 2019, it introduced its &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/05/14/statue-of-liberty-ar-ios-app/"&gt;Statue of Liberty AR app&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tim_cook/status/1128412203932049408"&gt;Cook tweeting&lt;/a&gt;, “The Statue of Liberty app is just the beginning of how AR will transform the way we connect with our world’s treasures.” In July 2019, it introduced augmented reality art sessions for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hh9exC"&gt;In addition to Tim Cook’s constant cheerleading of the technology, there are other signs that Apple is moving toward an AR future. Apple’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/natbro/status/1155849145350909954"&gt;hiring of people like Nat Brown&lt;/a&gt;, formerly of Microsoft; listing &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2019/08/01/apple-lists-ar-vr-jobs-reportedly-taps-executive-who-finalizes-products/"&gt;dozens of AR and VR job postings&lt;/a&gt;; acquisitions including &lt;a href="https://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2015/05/28/apple-buys-german-augmented-reality-firm-metaio/"&gt;Metaio in 2015&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/26/15877520/apple-sensomotoric-instruments-acquisition-ar-vr-eye-tracking"&gt;SensoMotoric in 2017&lt;/a&gt;; and patents on things like “&lt;a href="https://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?docid=09383582&amp;amp;SectionNum=1&amp;amp;IDKey=4E2221DF6AD9&amp;amp;HomeUrl=http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1%2526Sect2=HITOFF%2526d=PALL%2526p=1%2526u=%25252Fnetahtml%25252FPTO%25252Fsrchnum.htm%2526r=1%2526f=G%2526l=50%2526s1=9,383,582.PN.%2526OS=PN/9,383,582%2526RS=PN/9,383,582"&gt;head mounted display&lt;/a&gt;” devices all demonstrate its steady progress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="WuEKr7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s AR hardware is perennially two years away&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BbknTJ"&gt;Reports started &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/mobile/apple-is-working-on-an-ar-augmented-reality-vr-virtual-reality-headset-powered-by-a-wireless-wigig-hub/"&gt;trickling out in 2018&lt;/a&gt; that Apple had a timeline to launch both an AR headset and AR glasses. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-11-11/apple-s-ar-push-will-start-with-ipad-and-culminate-with-glasses"&gt;The company had 1,000 engineers&lt;/a&gt; working on its VR and AR initiative — &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-02-04/apple-augmented-reality-headset-executive-leaves-company"&gt;codenamed “T288”&lt;/a&gt; — which were expected to include a combined VR and AR headset to be released in 2021 or 2022, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;, with a pair of sleeker AR glasses predicted to launch in 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OqsIdJ"&gt;The latest reporting from &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apples-ar-vr-headset-will-need-connection-to-other-device-such-as-iphone"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;however, indicates that an Apple AR/VR headset may need to rely on the processor of another connected device like an iPhone (similar to the early Apple Watch models), and that Apple is working on a custom chip for the helmet-like headset that might take at least another year to arrive. Some aren’t as bullish on the more glasses-like variant either; &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; suggests Apple could still release that in 2023, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654606/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-wireless-connection-stream-data"&gt;analyst Ming-Chi Kuo thinks&lt;/a&gt; a 2025 release is more likely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2d0mj"&gt;It shouldn’t be all that surprising that Apple has taken its time making AR hardware; it is, after all, the company that introduced the AirPower wireless charging pad, showed it off to the world, then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/29/18287383/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-cancelled"&gt;canceled the product because it wasn’t up to company standards&lt;/a&gt; — and that was just an charging accessory, not a potentially new computing paradigm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vrJyTD"&gt;So it’s to be expected that Apple would take its time on an AR or VR headset. After hyping the potential for AR all this time, Cook surely doesn’t want Apple to repeat the failure of Google Glass by launching iGlasses too soon, and definitely not before the technology meets Apple’s very high bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NWAgj3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tim Cook’s Apple, ten years later","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22639629/tim-cook-apple-ten-years-decade-steve-jobs-legacy"},{"title":"The latest Oculus Quest update lets you easily invite others to play","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587352/oculus-quest-2-virtual-reality-headset-v31-software-invite-update-reactions-browser-password"},{"title":"Apple launches an augmented reality app to promote For All Mankind on Apple TV Plus","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278780/apple-augmented-reality-ar-app-for-all-mankind-tv-plus"},{"title":"Snap’s new Spectacles let you see the world in augmented reality","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445481/snap-spectacles-ar-augmented-reality-announced"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="DfDpvr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="87U4uc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21077484/apple-tim-cook-ar-augmented-reality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21077484/apple-tim-cook-ar-augmented-reality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-12T11:03:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-12T11:03:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>A comprehensive breakdown of the Epic v. Apple ruling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Craig Federighi addresses the court" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o0qIAOIkGnGPnBu-H50RRyeIfyA=/0x0:3840x2560/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69847808/IMG_2801.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image courtesy of Vicki Behringer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Whoever lost, we win&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="tZUq6R"&gt;On Friday, a California judge &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662320/epic-apple-ruling-injunction-judge-court-app-store"&gt;ruled on the influential &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667769/apple-epic-lost-lawsuit-verdict-ruling"&gt;both sides lost&lt;/a&gt;. Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers concluded that Apple wasn’t unfairly monopolizing the mobile app space with iOS or its in-app purchasing system, and she &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.814.0_2.pdf"&gt;ordered Epic to pay&lt;/a&gt; damages for violating its developer agreement with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. At the same time, she &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.813.0_3.pdf"&gt;ordered Apple to remove&lt;/a&gt; its anti-steering rules — policies banning developers from telling users about alternatives to Apple’s in-app purchase system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="UhUeEU"&gt;For readers outside those two companies, though, &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.812.0_3.pdf"&gt;Judge Gonzalez Rogers’ opinion&lt;/a&gt; has a lot to offer. Rogers clearly considers much of Epic and Apple’s behavior silly and many of both companies’ arguments bad. But she seriously examines all these arguments and lays out a blueprint for further legal arguments about mobile platforms, app monopolies, and modern antitrust law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="cgUMNJ"&gt;So we’re going to take a close look into the ruling’s biggest conclusions — and what they mean for both companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WozvDh"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="482" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3856497645&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1332xI"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; suit is about mobile game payments, not iOS apps or the bigger game market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="f0NWG6"&gt;During the trial, both sides argued over which market &lt;em&gt;Fortnite’s&lt;/em&gt; iOS app belonged to. Epic claimed Apple had abused a monopoly on the iOS app ecosystem; Apple claimed &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; was playing in the more competitive overall digital game market. (This is why the trial’s lawyers kept asking &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425774/epic-apple-roblox-fortnite-store-game-trial-day-5"&gt;whether &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is a game&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hUYi2"&gt;Judge Gonzalez Rogers says both these definitions are wrong, although Apple’s is somewhat less wrong. Instead, the question is whether Apple has an unlawful monopoly in “digital mobile gaming transactions.” Gonzalez Rogers notes that mobile games often have a different user base than PC or console games, and they rely hugely on the “freemium” model of in-game item sales, which are less important to both mobile apps and console or PC games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtzwYy"&gt;Epic made 10 claims against Apple. Most of them depended significantly on Apple having an unfair monopoly under either the federal Sherman Antitrust Act or California’s antitrust-focused Cartwright Act. And although the ruling is sympathetic toward several of Epic’s underlying arguments, nearly all its claims were dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J68sDL"&gt;Apple doesn’t have a monopoly in mobile gaming — yet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5wV9nV"&gt;Mobile games are a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; part of Apple’s App Store revenue — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667047/apple-epic-ruling-games-app-store-fortnite-revenue-purchases-business"&gt;approximately 70 percent&lt;/a&gt;, according to the ruling — and Apple has outsized power in mobile gaming. Gonzalez Rogers concludes iOS and Android hold a near-duopoly, although she considers the Nintendo Switch and cloud gaming services potential near-future competitors. The ruling estimates that Apple has a share of around 55 percent in the mobile game transactions market, alongside “extraordinarily high profit margins,” which can be a sign of monopoly power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Pdl6sN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Success is not illegal”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RrGKLl"&gt;But despite Apple’s “considerable” power and profit margins, “these factors alone do not show antitrust conduct. Success is not illegal,” Gonzalez Rogers concludes. While Epic argued that iMessage and other factors deliberately lock users into iOS, Gonzalez Rogers wasn’t convinced by this line of reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mMPX5K"&gt;The ruling leaves the door open for future antitrust complaints. “The evidence does suggest that Apple is near the precipice of substantial market power, or monopoly power, with its considerable market share,” Gonzalez Rogers writes. “Apple is only saved by the fact that its share is not higher, that competitors from related submarkets are making inroads into the mobile gaming submarket, and, perhaps, because [Epic] did not focus on this topic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zSh0zM"&gt;For now, though, this judgment undercut Epic’s allegation that Apple maintained a monopoly or unlawfully restrained trade under the Sherman Act, helping taking down four of its claims against Apple. The ruling says that by extension, it means Apple didn’t violate California’s Cartwright Act, taking down two more of the claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d9TwG9"&gt;A seventh claim said iOS was an “essential facility” that Apple had unfairly denied access to. But Epic didn’t seriously argue this claim, and for mobile app developers, Gonzalez Rogers says web apps and other digital platforms provide a reasonable (if not ideal) distribution alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Jxi0sJ"&gt;The App Store has a troubling lack of competition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="EE2yh1"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; ruling has some harsh words for the App Store. At one point, Gonzalez Rogers notes that “nothing other than legal action seems to motivate Apple to reconsider pricing and reduce rates.” At other points, she says Apple “does a poor job of mediating disputes between a developer and its customer,” and it’s been “slow either to adopt automated tools that could improve speed and accuracy or to hire more reviewers” for its app review process. “Apple’s slow innovation stems in part from its low investment in the App Store,” the ruling elaborates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b2QuZ5"&gt;Meanwhile, although Gonzalez Rogers takes a dim view of Epic’s economic analysis, she accepts that “Apple’s operating margins tied to the App Store are extraordinarily high.” And she specifically calls out a lack of competition as an issue. “The point is not that ... Apple provides bad services. It does not,” she writes. “The point is that a third-party app store could put pressure on Apple to innovate by providing features that Apple has neglected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6bCBIN"&gt;Apple has valid security fears about opening up iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZIXRgv"&gt;Apple’s trial witnesses promoted iOS as an unusually safe and secure ecosystem because of its walled-garden model, saying no other option would be appropriate for the sensitive data on people’s phones. Epic called that claim a pretext for shutting down competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BiHVZW"&gt;The ruling deflates some of Apple’s protestations. Judge Gonzalez Rogers is particularly dubious of Apple software engineering VP Craig Federighi, who delivered a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667256/apple-vs-epic-trail-judge-craig-federighi-macos-security-arguments-iphone-ios-response"&gt;dramatic but suspiciously new denunciation&lt;/a&gt; of macOS malware. She’s generally receptive to Epic’s suggestion that Apple could review and notarize iOS apps for security but allow distribution through other sources, similar to macOS. “Even though unrestricted app distribution likely decreases security, alternative models are readily achievable to attain the same ends even if not currently employed,” she concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJbOvQ"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers doesn’t think that makes Apple’s claims pretextual, though. She agrees with Apple that comprehensive human review — which isn’t part of macOS notarization — can offer a “safe and trusted user experience” that’s actually pro-consumer. By contrast, she says Epic’s proposed solutions “principally appear to eliminate app review.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SesPrv"&gt;The ruling dashes Epic’s hope that Apple would legally have to allow sideloaded apps and third-party app stores on iOS — which was Apple’s worst-case scenario going into the trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ypc4OO"&gt;Apple has a right to require its in-app payment options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QA0G2F"&gt;As you might remember if you’ve been following &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;, this whole dispute started with in-app purchase (or IAP) payment processing. Epic tweaked &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on iOS so that players could buy in-game V-Bucks via two methods: the Apple App Store or an “Epic direct payment” with a 20 percent discount.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshot of Epic’s “Direct Pay” option on Fortnite for iOS" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3eqtNf3_1u_dHbT4SK8io5ZnyvM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22842905/epic_direct_pay_apple_app_store_2045x979_730033169.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Epic’s “Direct Pay” option on Fortnite for iOS, August 2020&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AAQide"&gt;Epic described Apple’s IAP system as a glorified payment processor with outsized fees, and it argued that Apple was illegally tying IAP to the overall App Store. In Epic’s view, developers should be able to offer multiple payment processing options or reject Apple’s payment system altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QEQffk"&gt;This is a big point of dissatisfaction among major app developers, and Friday’s ruling isn’t terribly promising for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4jACtu"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers is skeptical of some Apple arguments for its current locked-down system and the attendant 30 percent — for big companies like Epic — commission. (Dunking on both sides’ expert witness analysis is a running theme in her ruling.) She also notes there’s “no evidence that IAP provides developers with any unique features” compared to standard payment processing. But she’s fairly straightforwardly opposed to making Apple unbundle the system, calling Epic’s request for it “deficient.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpZxdf"&gt;Throughout the trial, Apple has said that it’s not simply charging for payment processing on IAP. It’s using it to collect a commission — the 15 or 30 percent so-called “Apple Tax” — on the larger value of the App Store. Epic disputed that Apple meaningfully earned that commission, saying that although the App Store connects (in its words, “matches”) users with developers, Apple doesn’t deserve a cut of every transaction that happens after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="sjKF7R"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple and Epic argued over how much the in-app purchase system actually benefits developers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qhhmZ0"&gt;The ruling says the matching description is “partially true,” but that Apple has “never argued that it levies a commission merely because it matches the developers with the customers.” Instead, “IAP is the method by which Apple collects its licensing fee from developers for the use of Apple’s intellectual property.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="28REhZ"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers admittedly finds “no basis” for the specific 30 percent rate, despite Apple hiring a consultant to testify about the value of its patents. (As mentioned previously, the ruling is &lt;em&gt;full&lt;/em&gt; of dunks on the expert witnesses.) But she says Apple is still entitled to license that intellectual property for a fee of some sort, and requiring developers to use Apple’s payment system “accomplishes this goal in the easiest and most direct manner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ty0mzd"&gt;Epic’s unbundling alternative, meanwhile, would “severely undermine” the system, says the ruling. “Indeed, to the extent Epic Games suggests that Apple receive nothing from in-app purchases made on its platform, such a remedy is inconsistent with prevailing intellectual property law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXFczv"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers’ conclusion is another reason Epic didn’t prevail on the monopoly maintenance or restraint of trade claims discussed above, since two of them specifically dealt with IAP. She also says IAP isn’t a standalone product, so Apple isn’t illegally tying it to the App Store, which nixes two more Sherman and Cartwright Act claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5F17md"&gt;For those keeping score, that’s nine claims down for Epic. But there’s one final claim that makes this ruling a significant thorn in Apple’s side. Let’s talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Drmlt4"&gt;iOS developers have a right to talk about alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2LfpMU"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers concludes that Apple doesn’t monopolize mobile gaming. But the company &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; violate California’s Unfair Competition Law (UCL) through its anti-steering rules: policies that restrict developers from telling users they can buy digital goods outside Apple’s ecosystem. The ruling focuses on this portion of Apple’s developer agreement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="teWznP"&gt;“Apps and their metadata may not include buttons, external links, or other calls to action that direct customers to purchasing mechanisms other than in-app purchase.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="9HEtdf"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers has almost unreserved scorn for this policy. “By employing anti-steering provisions, consumers do not know what developers may be offering on their websites, including lower prices,” she writes. Developers are allowed to email customers to advertise, but only through addresses they’ve collected outside the iOS signup process, which consumers also don’t necessarily know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8HVpQx"&gt;Users don’t necessarily even know about the cut Apple is taking — that “if they subscribe to their favorite newspaper on the web,” for instance, “all the proceeds go to the newspaper, rather than the reduced amount by subscribing on the iOS device.” Some people appreciate that Apple offers a unified place to manage subscriptions. But others might not, and “Apple actively denies them the choice” to find alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="E34gtC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple created a new and innovative platform which was also a black box”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fhcWQH"&gt;“Apple created a new and innovative platform which was also a black box. It enforced silence to control information and actively impede users from obtaining the knowledge to obtain digital goods on other platforms,” Gonzalez Rogers concludes. “Apple has used this lack of knowledge to exploit its position.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zi337e"&gt;The ruling says Apple’s situation is “distinctly different” from another case that let American Express use anti-steering rules for brick-and-mortar merchants, because even in that scenario, merchants can still say they also accept Visa and MasterCard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xWLp8B"&gt;Accordingly, a new injunction will soon prevent Apple from banning “buttons, external links, or other calls to action” that direct users to other payment mechanisms. That’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667047/apple-epic-ruling-games-app-store-fortnite-revenue-purchases-business"&gt;potentially a big deal for Apple&lt;/a&gt;... although it’s not yet clear just &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; big a deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WDuR25"&gt;Apple could collect an ‘Apple Tax’ even without in-app payment charges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="o2ZXJn"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667161/app-store-epic-ruling-difference-button-external-link"&gt;my colleague Nilay Patel discusses&lt;/a&gt;, Judge Gonzalez Rogers’ injunction leaves some weird ambiguity about what developers can do. In theory, a developer could add a button that directs users to Safari or another app for payment, but looks indistinguishable from the option to pay with Apple’s system. (It’s worth noting the injunction &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; say Apple has to let developers build complete alternate payment methods into their apps, and based on the statements quoted earlier, Gonzalez Rogers seems fairly down on that prospect.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mQsMYF"&gt;But developers like Epic don’t just care about controlling payment methods out of principle — although it offers some unique benefits like getting to handle refunds. They care about ditching Apple’s 30 percent commission. And Gonzalez Rogers says bluntly that it’s not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9kscF"&gt;Even if developers could entirely stop using the IAP system, “Apple could still charge a commission on developers. It would simply be more difficult for Apple to collect that commission,” Gonzalez Rogers writes. The ruling elaborates on this scenario — in which Apple is outright banned from making developers use its payment option — in a footnote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="XuuLne"&gt;“In such a hypothetical world, developers could potentially avoid the commission while benefitting from Apple’s innovation and intellectual property free of charge. The Court presumes that in such circumstances that Apple may rely on imposing and utilizing a contractual right to audit developers annual accounting to ensure compliance with its commissions, among other methods. Of course, any alternatives to IAP (including the foregoing) would seemingly impose both increased monetary and time costs to both Apple and the developers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="TXWvCV"&gt;The law now says that Apple can’t stop developers from offering cheaper prices outside their iOS apps and telling users about it. But if big developers successfully route a lot of money away from the App Store this way, Gonzalez Rogers seemingly leaves the door open to collecting the “Apple Tax” some other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LidZbJ"&gt;Epic and Apple’s contract was valid, and Epic knowingly broke it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="a0bs43"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; ruling declares that part of Apple’s developer agreement (called the DPLA) is unlawful... but Epic still has to pay for breaking it with the &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; payment system change. By the same token, Apple doesn’t have to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667069/fortnite-ios-return-apple-epic-ruling"&gt;restore &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or keep Epic’s other apps on iOS if it doesn’t agree to follow Apple’s rules. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AuAAIW"&gt;The first reason is basically that Apple’s agreement didn’t break the law &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt;. Epic claimed the contract was “illegal and unenforceable” because it violated the Sherman Act, the Cartwright Act, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the UCL. Gonzalez Rogers concludes that the single UCL offense wasn’t sufficiently related or severe to justify Epic’s rulebreaking. She also dismisses the claim that Apple’s contract was “unconscionable” — in other words, one-sided enough to “shock the conscience.” (“These are billion and trillion dollar companies with a business dispute,” the ruling notes dryly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lXqm5t"&gt;The second reason is that Epic broke another rule in the process. It hid the alternate payment system inside a remote “hotfix” when Apple’s policies said it couldn’t “provide, unlock, or enable additional features or functionality through distribution mechanisms other than the App Store.” That specific provision wasn’t related to antitrust claims, and the ruling concludes Epic “never showed why it had to breach its agreements” to challenge Apple’s alleged anti-competitive actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CzJay8"&gt;We still don’t know what a game is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ahoIyG"&gt;Sure, all the questions above are &lt;em&gt;legally relevant&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;important for consumers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;set a detailed precedent for future antitrust legislation and lawsuits&lt;/em&gt;. But let’s end with the fun part: after all the time witnesses spent arguing about what a video game is, does the ruling give us a definition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lYo3N1"&gt;The short answer is no, because it doesn’t have to. “The court need not reach a conclusive definition of a video game or game because by all accounts, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; itself is both externally and internally considered a video game.” &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; markets itself as a game, and even if CEO Tim Sweeney &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;considers it the basis for a larger metaverse&lt;/a&gt; (in case you were wondering, “the court generally finds Mr. Sweeney’s personal beliefs about the future of the metaverse are sincerely held”), the metaverse as a product “remains in its infancy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdPQ4P"&gt;As for the definitions introduced by witnesses, “unfortunately, no one agrees and neither side introduced evidence of any commonly accepted industry definition.” That includes Sweeney’s claim that a game “involves some sort of win or loss or a score progression,” as well as Apple app review head Trystan Kosmynka’s claim that “games have a beginning, [and] an end,” and “there’s challenges in place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jX5BQC"&gt;Gonzalez Rogers does, however, spend a surprising amount of time breaking down the core elements of a video game. Here’s a brief definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="WlDnB1"&gt;“The court concludes that video games include a diverse and eclectic genre of games, that are tied together at minimum through varying degrees of interactivity and involvement from a game player.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="JZEU5f"&gt;There’s also a more elaborate one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6OmG0k"&gt;“At a bare minimum, video games appear to require some level of interactivity or involvement between the player and the medium. In other words, a game requires that a player be able to input some level of a command or choice which is then reflected in the game itself. This gaming definition contrasts to other forms of entertainment, which are often passive forms enjoyed by consumers (e.g., films, television, music). Video games are also generally graphically rendered or animated, as opposed to being recorded live or via motion capture as in films and television.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="eidJop"&gt;You could certainly quibble with elements of this, and Gonzalez Rogers admits she’s not clarifying the “outer boundaries of the definition of video games.” She declines to say whether specific non-Epic titles, like &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt; and Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/em&gt;, are games. She also says she can’t conclude whether &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425759/epic-apple-trial-app-store-itch-io-offensive-sexualized-unspeakable-games-day-5"&gt;certain games on the &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://Itch.io"&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425759/epic-apple-trial-app-store-itch-io-offensive-sexualized-unspeakable-games-day-5"&gt; storefront&lt;/a&gt; were sexually explicit or problematic, given that “the corresponding materials ... were not submitted to the court” — although she does offer a ruling on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666922/apple-epic-peely-naked-banana-judgement"&gt;naked banana man decorum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Ff4CL1"&gt;Ultimately, “the court leaves the thornier further questions of what is properly included and excluded in the definition of a video game to the academics and commentators,” Gonzalez Rogers determines. And fortunately plenty of both seem ready to take up the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
