<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-11T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Belkin’s second MagSafe dock drops the Apple Watch charger and the price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EazKyFOGOUrWVsR6XKEG2a6VMAU=/240x0:1440x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68650761/2in1_MagSafe_lifestyle2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mapDzk"&gt;Since Apple’s reveal of its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509659/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-charging-magnetic-charger-return"&gt;MagSafe charging standard&lt;/a&gt;, officially approved wireless chargers that use the standard have been few and far between. But Belkin is boosting those numbers with its new BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 2-in-1 Wireless Charger, which also brings a more palatable $99.95 price tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfEv2n"&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/14/21516404/belkin-magsafe-boostcharge-pro-charger-car-mount-iphone-12-accessories"&gt;BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 3-in-1 Wireless Charger&lt;/a&gt;, the BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 2-in-1 Wireless Charger — as you might be able to already guess — can charge two products instead of three. Now, the futuristic charging tree will offer just a MagSafe pad and a regular Qi charger for your AirPods (or any other device that fits), dropping the Apple Watch charger found on the 3-in-1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="aRpqEr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Belkin’s first MagSafe products are a wild-looking 3-in-1 charger and a car mount","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/14/21516404/belkin-magsafe-boostcharge-pro-charger-car-mount-iphone-12-accessories"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NhmgKk"&gt;And like the 3-in-1, the new BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 2-in-1 is an official, MFi-approved MagSafe device, meaning that it’s one of the few options out there for taking advantage of MagSafe’s faster 15W wireless charger. And the one-third reduction in functionality comes with a similar reduction in price: the BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 2-in-1 costs $99.95, compared to the $149.95 that Belkin charges for its larger counterpart. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7-ir9R3QUca94OebYXITs2Was38=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223074/2in1_MagSafe_poduct1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FSJGEm"&gt;The BoostCharge Pro MagSafe 2-in-1 Wireless Charger is set to release later this year in March or April, when it’ll be available from both Apple’s and Belkin’s websites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bu5QuD"&gt;Along with the new wireless charger, Belkin also announced its second set of wireless earbuds, the Soundform Freedom True Wireless Earbuds. Where the original Soundform True Wireless Earbuds were a budget option at $59.99 (with features to match), Belkin is aiming higher with the Soundform Freedom buds. The new buds feature better battery life (up to eight hours, with an additional 20 hours in the case), USB-C charging, and improved isolation of background noise (although there’s no active noise cancellation). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b4ImBC"&gt;Notably, the Soundform Freedom earbuds will also be one of the first third-party products to work with Apple’s Find My network (something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21299712/apple-find-my-iphone-network-third-party-devices-support-location-tracking"&gt;Apple announced&lt;/a&gt; it would be offering as an option last year). That means that — similar to Apple’s own AirPods — you’ll be able to use the Find My app on iPhone and Mac devices to locate your missing headphones, using the same crowdsourced network of Apple products that the company’s own first-party devices can use. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RUSrMG9eWnhkTtTj2kQEj2wfpHE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223076/SoundForm_Freedom_white1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o8kwuy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TbeTlx"&gt;The Soundform Freedom earbuds also offer both Qi and USB-C charging, swappable ear tips, and are rated IPX5 for sweat and splash resistance. Belkin has yet to announce pricing, but they’ll be available to purchase sometime in March or April. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219529/belkin-magsafe-dock-charging-wireless-ces-2021-earbuds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219529/belkin-magsafe-dock-charging-wireless-ces-2021-earbuds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:32:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:32:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Grab a two-pack of the latest Echo Dot for $50 at Amazon today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RKYqCATZvDr2IuOfaK6WZ1jto4g=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68650511/dseifert_201025_4263_00011.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The fourth-gen Amazon Echo Dot looks more like a ball and less like a dot. | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="a4eq7M"&gt;The new ball-shaped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker#:~:text=It%20provides%20excellent%20sound%20quality,is%20easy%20to%20stick%20in"&gt;fourth-gen Amazon Echo&lt;/a&gt;, which was released last year, was frequently discounted over the holiday season. If you missed those deals and are looking to grab two Echo Dots, Amazon is currently running a promotion that allows you to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Staging-Product-Not-Retail-Sale/dp/B084J4MZK8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=a703bc6b8141b27e290f322ffa1dd1f6&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy two for $50&lt;/a&gt; (before tax) when you enter the code &lt;strong&gt;DOT2PACK&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GoR9Eq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9607515"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pS6v38"&gt;If you are looking to pick up Apple’s flagship earbuds, there are a few deals currently available. Right now, if you want the lowest price for these wireless earbuds and don’t mind buying refurbished, they are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729136281790037757" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$190 at Best Buy (Geek Squad Certified)&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a new pair, they are &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=1cb418f86cbc3130d86f2c11133013ba&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$219 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, or you can shell out an extra dollar and get them at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-airpods-pro-headphones%2F%3Fadobe_mc%3DMCMID%253D55131310889127428182344810019896154467%257CMCORGID%253D843F02BE53271A1A0A490D4C%252540AdobeOrg%257CTS%253D1610382226%26mboxSession%3D65afb81e970d4d718f6541d9e5064d3e#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon and choose in-store pickup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wv5evx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8q4HQ4"&gt;At Best Buy, you can buy a pair of Beats Solo Pro headphones &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729136008423635134" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in light blue for $170&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729136078803064284" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729135573227190787" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;navy blue for just $180&lt;/a&gt;. Normally $300, the Beats Solo Pro are great if you are looking for a pair of wireless headphones because of their effective noise cancellation and increased sweat resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HcONUw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2qcJqt"&gt;Preorders for the OnePlus Nord N100 phone began last Friday. If you pre-purchase the phone through &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1611766-REG%2Foneplus_5011101344_oneplus_nord_n100_64gb.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo, you will also receive a $30 gift card&lt;/a&gt; for the retailer at no additional cost. Or if you want to preorder through the &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Foneplus-n100&amp;amp;xcust=verge#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus’ website&lt;/a&gt;, the company will throw in a pair of black OnePlus Bullets Wireless Z earbuds for free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FYB9mD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10273236"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/11/22224715/amazon-echo-dot-airpods-pro-beats-solo-pro-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/11/22224715/amazon-echo-dot-airpods-pro-beats-solo-pro-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T03:13:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T03:13:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Parler is gone for now as Amazon terminates hosting</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-IT-LIFESTYLE-MEDIA-POLITICS-PARLER" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3i_F4Eg6ZlMTQaAXK1I89g16EjQ=/6x0:3995x2659/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68648550/1225872885.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parler has been taken offline&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by OLIVIER DOULIERY/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HH3EVI"&gt;After Parler was banned on both the Apple and Google app stores for failing to curb violent and threatening content on its platform, the social media site is now completely offline as a result of Amazon terminating Parler’s web hosting services. The official Parler website now returns a 403 error, while its app is showing networking errors and can’t load content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oij1R5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22222637/amazon-workers-aws-stop-hosting-services-parler-capitol-violence"&gt;Amazon told Parler of its decision&lt;/a&gt; late Saturday, in a letter to chief policy officer Amy Peikoff. Its Amazon Web Service (AWS) “cannot provide services to a customer that is unable to effectively identify and remove content that encourages or incites violence against others,” &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/johnpaczkowski/amazon-parler-aws"&gt;the letter to Peikoff states&lt;/a&gt;, adding that Parler “poses a very real risk to public safety.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/idJlPKDKDtg5Y6-ZthZ4Tw5JyY8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227121/File.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Parler&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parler’s iOS app, which now can’t load content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ApEuFA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Cbluedreams/status/1347405890505252864?"&gt;Posts on Parler that encouraged violence&lt;/a&gt; leading up to the Wednesday attack on the Capitol that left five people dead were circulated on other platforms in the wake of the riot. An example:  “take zip ties with you, sneak up on them like ninjas and zip tie their hands and feet,” to which another poster replied: “around their neck, can’t get it off in time, they die.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="81ruz0"&gt;According to the AWS &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/aup/?tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21986678%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;acceptable use policy&lt;/a&gt; customers may not use its services “for any illegal, harmful, fraudulent, infringing or offensive use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgLpkL"&gt;Parler launched in 2018 presenting itself as a free-speech haven and an alternative to other social media sites. The site &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21557219/parler-conservative-app-download-new-users-moderation-bias"&gt;saw its user numbers spike&lt;/a&gt; in recent months, as Twitter and Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552763/election-2020-tech-social-platforms-facebook-twitter-youtube-misinformation"&gt;tightened their moderation policies&lt;/a&gt;, especially around election and coronavirus information. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552752/facebook-stopthesteal-ban-twitter-parler-discord-trump"&gt;“Stop the Steal” campaign&lt;/a&gt; challenging President Trump’s loss gained momentum among Parler users, as did other conspiracy theories around the election. Parler’s less-strict moderation policies were part of its appeal for many users, but the lack of content moderation is a big part of why companies suspended their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mW8lXP"&gt;When it pulled Parler from the Play Store, Google said while reasonable debate about content policy was possible, and it can be hard for apps to remove violative content immediately, “for us to distribute an app through Google Play, we do require that apps implement robust moderation for egregious content.” Apple told the company that “the processes Parler has put in place to moderate or prevent the spread of dangerous and illegal content have proved insufficient. Specifically, we have continued to find direct threats of violence and calls to incite lawless action.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XKD0V"&gt;Even with the app removed from the Play Store users could still install Parler on their Android devices by downloading it directly from Parler’s website and sideloading it. However, with its AWS services now disabled, the website and apps no longer work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ytelNk"&gt;Parler CEO John Matze — who, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Fjmatze%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F11%2F22223335%2Fparler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to his LinkedIn page&lt;/a&gt; worked for AWS for three months in 2017 — wrote in a post on Parler late Saturday that he believes Amazon, Google, and Apple “worked together to try and ensure they don’t have competition,” adding “They will NOT win! We are the worlds [sic] last hope for free speech and free information.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pSELOn"&gt;Matze said in &lt;a href="https://parler.com/post/009ba435b68c46d4955e1cd7737fa27c"&gt;a separate post&lt;/a&gt; that the Parler could be offline for up to a week “as we rebuild from scratch.” Matze added, “You can expect the war on competition and free speech to continue, but don’t count us out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YyhCUf"&gt;Perhaps the best-known recent instance of a site being deplatformed for violent content was social network Gab. After a gunman killed &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/31/us/pittsburgh-funerals-synagogue-shooting.html"&gt;eleven people in a Pittsburgh synagogue&lt;/a&gt; in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/27/18032930/paypal-banned-gab-following-pittsburgh-shooting"&gt;PayPal banned Gab&lt;/a&gt; from its platform, when it was revealed that suspect Robert Bowers had posted anti-Semitic threats on Gab ahead of the shooting. &lt;a href="https://www.inc.com/salvador-rodriguez/gab-apple-inauguration.html"&gt;Apple rejected&lt;/a&gt; Gab’s application to appear in its App Store in 2016, and Twitter removed Gab’s access to its API. Google booted Gab app from its Play store in 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/18/16166240/gab-google-play-removed-hate-speech"&gt;for violating its hate speech policy&lt;/a&gt;, and AWS &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/far-right-haven-gabcom-had-its-fundraising-site-shut-down"&gt;cut ties with Gab&lt;/a&gt; in 2019, for violating its policy against hateful content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SZjE3X"&gt;Parler has not responded to multiple requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223335/parler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223335/parler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-10T15:58:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-10T15:58:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: Locked Down, Supernova, Losing Alice and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B9x2PLzyePPgRp-fp7_M55YKCMI=/249x0:1559x873/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68646979/lockd_donwn.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Chiwetel Ejiofor and Anne Hathaway star in Locked Down | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mepeWor5JPk&amp;amp;ab_channel=HBOMax" target="_blank"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9nKl7i"&gt;So with all the chaos of the past week, you may have missed that Friday was the final episode of Jeopardy! with Alex Trebek as host. Trebek, who died in November at age 80 after a battle with cancer, hosted the answer-and-question game show for 37 years. The show posted a best-of highlight reel of Trebek’s performances over the years (remember the brouhaha when he shaved his mustache?!) and it may make you tear up a bit. My favorite appreciation of Trebek was from &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/08/arts/television/alex-trebek-jeopardy.html"&gt;James Poniewozik in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; which concludes: “He was our trusted man with the answers, even in times when reality came to us in the form of a question.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nCCKAb"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/arsStQAhHVA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SMqPc8"&gt;Out new trailers this week range from dark and creepy to quirky to unsettling (which, to be totally honest, I prefer all of the above to syrupy holiday movies). Let’s go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bT4tGS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="siXO2q"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2zfSw7G1A-0?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nPRlag"&gt;Losing Alice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="B6zDpi"&gt;A movie director fretting about her age meets a mysterious screenwriter on a train, and the two are drawn into a weird relationship. Love a good noir movie. Losing Alice was written and directed by Sigal Avin. Ayelet Zurer and Lihi Kornowski star in the eight-episode streaming series which premieres on Apple TV Plus January 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8SO7io"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mepeWor5JPk?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0UP4au"&gt;Locked Down&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Ve2uUN"&gt;Look I just love Anne Hathaway so I’m willing to give anything she’s in at least a chance. A couple quarantining together during the pandemic just after they decide to break up, meh, OK. But &lt;em&gt;plot twist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;they also plan a jewelry heist at Harrod’s department store to steal a bazillion-dollar diamond. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; I’m on board. Chiwetel Ejiofor (another fave) also stars in&lt;em&gt; Locked Down&lt;/em&gt;, which hits HBO Max January 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EwnqT0"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_62BeXxd_jo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jIFZHK"&gt;Derek DelGaudio’s In &amp;amp; Of Itself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="DttZwT"&gt;What is this weirdness about? Put simply, it’s a one-man show by Derek DelGuadio, who describes himself as a “storyteller and conceptual magician.” &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2020/03/in-of-itself-review-derek-delgaudio-frank-oz-sxsw-1202217981/"&gt;IndieWire’s review&lt;/a&gt; says it’s a blend of “stage trickery and alluring autobiographical asides,” that’s also a “meditation on existential yearning.” Hey I’m down for whatever. Directed by Frank Oz and executive-produced by Stephen Colbert (yep and yep!), &lt;em&gt;In &amp;amp; of Itself&lt;/em&gt; hits Hulu January 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KgvaOq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bRz2hY6ykGE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Cowg3v"&gt;Supernova&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="QbpC9g"&gt;Stanley Tucci and Colin Firth star as a partners of 20 years traveling across England to visit family and friends. It’s not just a beautiful road trip movie, though; Tucci’s character Tusker has dementia and is slowly losing his memory, so the pair are acutely aware of the value of the time they have left together. &lt;em&gt;Supernova&lt;/em&gt; is slated to hit theaters January 29th, with a “digital release” February 16th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/10/22223591/new-trailers-locked-down-supernova-losing-alice-hulu-hbo-max-apple-alex-trebek-jeopardy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/10/22223591/new-trailers-locked-down-supernova-losing-alice-hulu-hbo-max-apple-alex-trebek-jeopardy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-09T19:47:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-09T19:47:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple removes Parler from the App Store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s1zEUh9OTr-kmE8w5ICh-zXLQLA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68644631/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jYBDmZ"&gt;Apple has removed Parler from the App Store, following accusations that the social media app was fostering calls to violence ahead of, and following, the raid on the US Capitol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sczRDR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;We have always supported diverse points of view being represented on the App Store, but there is no place on our platform for threats of violence and illegal activity. Parler has not taken adequate measures to address the proliferation of these threats to people’s safety. We have suspended Parler from the App Store until they resolve these issues,” reads a statement from the company on Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TMGX2M"&gt;Apple issued an ultimatum to Parler on Friday demanding that it remove content in violation with its policies and provide a plan on how it would moderate content moving forward, which was &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/apple-threatens-ban-parler?bftwnews&amp;amp;utm_term=4ldqpgc#4ldqpgc"&gt;first reported by &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Apple said Parler had 24 hours to make the changes or else it would be removed from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gFq69X"&gt;Apparently, Parler did propose some changes, but Apple decided they weren’t sufficient, according to a statement Apple sent to Parler alongside its final decision to remove the app. It states that “the processes Parler has put in place to moderate or prevent the spread of dangerous and illegal content have proved insufficient,” and that Parler will not return to the App Store until it has “demonstrated your ability to effectively moderate and filter the dangerous and harmful content on your service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbl08K"&gt;Here’s the full statement as provided by Apple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fbXilX"&gt;To the developers of the Parler app,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yubcZL"&gt;Thank you for your response regarding dangerous and harmful content on Parler. We have determined that the measures you describe are inadequate to address the proliferation of dangerous and objectionable content on your app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YasLJX"&gt;Parler has not upheld its commitment to moderate and remove harmful or dangerous content encouraging violence and illegal activity, and is not in compliance with the App Store Review Guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9VKNj"&gt;In your response, you referenced that Parler has been taking this content “very seriously for weeks.” However, the processes Parler has put in place to moderate or prevent the spread of dangerous and illegal content have proved insufficient. Specifically, we have continued to find direct threats of violence and calls to incite lawless action in violation of Guideline 1.1 - Safety - Objectionable Content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NfOJuv"&gt;Your response also references a moderation plan “for the time being,” which does not meet the ongoing requirements in Guideline 1.2 - Safety - User Generated content. While there is no perfect system to prevent all dangerous or hateful user content, apps are required to have robust content moderation plans in place to proactively and effectively address these issues. A temporary “task force” is not a sufficient response given the widespread proliferation of harmful content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwSxC1"&gt;For these reasons, your app will be removed from the App Store until we receive an update that is compliant with the App Store Review Guidelines and you have demonstrated your ability to effectively moderate and filter the dangerous and harmful content on your service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ySL7W"&gt;Regards, App Review Board&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="3Vis3k"&gt;The app was briefly still available on Apple’s store after we received the statement, but it disappeared from the store a number of minutes after we published this post. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/09/parler-jumps-to-no-1-on-app-store-after-facebook-and-twitter-bans/"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; reported earlier today&lt;/a&gt;, the app jumped up to #1 on the App Store and may have gained hundreds of thousands of users between the time Apple issued its 24-hour ultimatum and when the company pulled it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f16mNP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22221648/google-suspends-bans-parler-play-store"&gt;Google pulled Parler&lt;/a&gt; Friday evening. “We’re aware of continued posting in the Parler app that seeks to incite ongoing violence in the US,” Google said in a statement. “We recognize that there can be reasonable debate about content policies and that it can be difficult for apps to immediately remove all violative content, but for us to distribute an app through Google Play, we do require that apps implement robust moderation for egregious content. In light of this ongoing and urgent public safety threat, we are suspending the app’s listings from the Play Store until it addresses these issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74XGOB"&gt;Both Apple and Google faced pressure &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220366/apple-google-parler-pressure-deplatform-violence-capitol"&gt;on Friday&lt;/a&gt; to deplatform Parler, which is known for being conservative-friendly and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21557219/parler-conservative-app-download-new-users-moderation-bias"&gt;having less stringent moderation&lt;/a&gt; than other social media platforms. The removal of both apps comes after a mob attack Wednesday on the US Capitol by pro-Trump rioters. On Friday, Amy Piekoff, head of policy at Parler, &lt;a href="https://video.foxnews.com/v/6221435493001#sp=show-clips"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Fox News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a ban from the App Store would be “huge,” adding that if it Apple removed Parler “we’re toast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="daAZBG"&gt;Parler did not immediately respond to a request for comment Saturday. CEO John Matze &lt;a href="https://parler.com/post/7a9ba1df6d0949f2996dd7d5f13b1b49"&gt;posted a statement on Parler&lt;/a&gt; accusing Apple of applying a “horrible double standard” in its decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="URthnz"&gt;“Apple, Google and the rest of the anti-competitive pack of big tech tyrants coordinate their moves and work together to stifle competition in the marketplace,” he wrote. Matze added more details would be coming soon about Parler’s plans “as we have many options.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hjzs5v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 9th, 8:58PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added statement from Parler CEO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WaBW2Y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QbyNph"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BPWAQQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-09T12:57:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-09T12:57:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Social media and telco companies urged to preserve evidence from Capitol attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uYx6LN5QqKIZvEdN5raw-DLZWmA=/25x0:2016x1327/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68643477/GettyImages_1230453521.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Rioters breached security at the Capitol on Wednesday January 6th | Photo by Olivier Douliery / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7aoZXg"&gt;Sen. Mark Warner (D-Virginia), incoming chair of the Senate Intelligence Committee, is asking mobile carriers and social media platforms to preserve “content and associated metadata” that may be  connected to the attack on the US Capitol. Warner said in a statement Saturday that he contacted the CEOs of AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, Verizon, Apple, Facebook, Gab, Google, Parler, Signal, Telegram, and Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4VTOB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“The United States Capitol is now a crime scene,” Warner &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22224462/capitol_attack_twitter.pdf"&gt;wrote in his letters&lt;/a&gt;. “The FBI and other law enforcement agencies are currently investigating the events of that day, and trying to piece together what happened and the perpetrators involved. The prospect of litigation on behalf of the victims of the mayhem also is highly likely. Messaging data to and from your subscribers that may have participated in, or assisted, those engaged in this insurrection – and associated subscriber information – are critical evidence in helping to bring these rioters to justice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1yemBp"&gt;Warner noted that many of those participating in the January 6th attack that left five people dead posted images to social media, or shared them via text and mobile messaging platforms while the riot was underway and afterward, “to celebrate their disdain for our democratic process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTUI64"&gt;All the named companies routinely comply with &lt;a href="https://cyber.harvard.edu/digitaldiscovery/library/preservation/preservationanalysis.html"&gt;court-issued preservation orders&lt;/a&gt;, issued during criminal investigations. But Warner’s letter is an informal request, without the legal force of a criminal preservation order, and it is unclear how the companies will respond. Court-issued preservation orders are often issued under seal so it is also possible that one of the many agencies investigating the Capitol raid has already issued such an order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVn9sb"&gt;We’ve reached out to the companies to ask how and if they plan to comply with Warner’s request and will update if we hear back from them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhFLv8"&gt;A Facebook spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company was “continuing our ongoing, proactive outreach to law enforcement and have worked to quickly provide responses to valid legal requests. We are removing content, disabling accounts, and working with law enforcement to protect against direct threats to public safety.” T-Mobile acknowledged it had received Warner’s letter. “As always, we will fully cooperate with requests from law enforcement,” a spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2HhUjv"&gt;To reiterate, however, Warner’s request doesn’t carry quite the same legal weight as a subpoena or other formal request from a law enforcement agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8fHkL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/01/08/capitol-riot-democrats-social-media-456325"&gt;Warner told &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that following Wednesday’s attack, Congress would “come back with a vengeance” against social media platforms that were unable to rein in violent content and threats on their platforms. “This is going to come back and bite ‘em,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cJb7nH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 9th 1:15PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds comment from Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mY9cWX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 9th 3:43PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds comment from T-Mobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22222200/social-media-telco-urged-preserve-evidence-capitol-attack-twitter-facebook-google-verizon-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22222200/social-media-telco-urged-preserve-evidence-capitol-attack-twitter-facebook-google-verizon-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T14:40:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T14:40:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s App Store made an estimated $64 billion in 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1KGftnuRi0M1JL9oBjZ7X5Pizck=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68639783/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KcvAtL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/08/apples-app-store-had-gross-sales-around-64-billion-in-2020.html"&gt;According to CNBC’s analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s App Store made $64 billion in revenue in 2020, which is a 28 percent increase from the estimated $50 billion it made in 2019. This represents a good amount of growth for the App Store since the estimated increase between 2018 and 2019 was only 3.1 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gnEwX"&gt;It’s hard to tell the exact reason for the spike in growth, but it likely had something to do with the COVID-19 pandemic. I can say from personal experience that I bought quite a few more games in 2020 than I have in years past, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020-roundup/22206745/2020-home-exercise-tech-games-apps-vr-apple-watch-covid-quarantine-pandemic-shelter-in-place"&gt;as well as subscriptions to fitness&lt;/a&gt; and productivity apps to try to regain some control of my life during quarantine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwJfxj"&gt;When Apple reports on its financials, it lumps the money it makes from the App Store in with its services revenue, &lt;a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/04/apple-to-release-financial-results-amid-global-crisis/"&gt;which is by far its fastest-growing category&lt;/a&gt;. The company takes a 30 percent cut of most of the money coming in to the App Store, which, while there are caveats and exceptions, represents billions of dollars of revenue. Apple typically guards its take carefully, despite recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21298552/apple-hey-email-app-approval-rules-basecamp-launch"&gt;pushback from developers like Hey.com&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know"&gt;legal challenges from Epic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVKrKD"&gt;Its grip has recently loosened just a little, though, as Apple now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;only takes a 15 percent cut from developers who make under $1 million a year&lt;/a&gt; from the App Store. That isn’t likely to have a huge change on the revenue estimates, as analysts have approximated that &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/18/technology/apple-app-store-fee.html"&gt;the top 2 percent of App Store developers generate 95 percent of the revenue&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lu63PU"&gt;Every year, Apple reports how much money it has paid out to developers since 2008. CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;used that to calculate the App Store revenue number by subtracting last year’s number from this year’s, then it accounts for Apple’s 30 percent cut. While the numbers may be a little rough, Apple doesn’t self-report them, so all we can do is get close. Regardless, there are two things that are hard to argue: the App Store’s revenue grew by quite a bit this year, and it brought in a lot of money for both developers and for Apple. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220873/apple-2020-app-store-revenue-60-billion-dollars"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220873/apple-2020-app-store-revenue-60-billion-dollars</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T07:18:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T07:18:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok debuts first augmented reality filter that uses iPhone 12 Pro’s LIDAR camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DygVw3ARrSiEzfSckTBv7MAI6U8=/0x61:1140x821/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68631739/Screen_Shot_2021_01_06_at_4.48.53_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uhmZUR"&gt;TikTok has released its first augmented reality filter that can utilize the iPhone 12 Pro’s LIDAR sensor for an enhanced confetti effect that realistically settles on people or objects in your room. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2G3MoC"&gt;The effect itself is just a somewhat belated 2021 ball drop (which feels like it would have been a lot more useful a few days ago.) But the ball drop filter is just the start, with TikTok promising to “develop more innovative effects in 2021.” And the fact that one of the most popular video platforms in the world is jumping onboard with support for one of the marquee features on Apple’s more pricey and premium smartphones is certainly notable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2M5naX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;To ring in 2021 we released our first AR effect on the new iPhone 12 Pro, using LiDAR technology which allows us to create effects that interact with your environment - visually bridging the digital and physical worlds. We're excited to develop more innovative effects in 2021! &lt;a href="https://t.co/6yFD2FfHta"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6yFD2FfHta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— TikTokComms (@tiktok_comms) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tiktok_comms/status/1346828242506969089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tAnqPi"&gt;TikTok isn’t the only major company with eyes on Apple’s LIDAR tech. Snapchat, one of the other major players when it comes to augmented reality filters, already added support for Apple’s LIDAR sensor &lt;a href="https://lensstudio.snapchat.com/news/create-lidar-powered-lenses-for-the-new-iphone-12-pro/"&gt;back in October&lt;/a&gt;, allowing creators to build their own enhanced AR filters for the app. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217465/tiktok-augmented-reality-filter-iphone-12-pros-lidar-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217465/tiktok-augmented-reality-filter-iphone-12-pros-lidar-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T03:47:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T03:47:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple celebrates the Year of the Ox with limited AirPods Pro in Asia</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SZAYDEQaWLHOnr3Xhm3MR9sUB6Q=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68631509/app.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="reHh0q"&gt;February 12th marks the first day of Lunar New Year, with 2021 ushering in the Year of the Ox and saying farewell to the Year of the Rat. To celebrate, Apple is releasing limited edition AirPods Pro in certain Asian countries, with a case branded with a new version of the cow emoji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WXbijB"&gt;Apple has also given an ox-themed makeover to its logo on some regional versions of its website:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pOcnU-kbNPaBIotVqc7JfIuWLA8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219378/Screen_Shot_2021_01_07_at_17.17.28.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="V4eMsW"&gt;The special edition AirPods Pro sell for the same price as the regular AirPods Pro, which is just as well considering you can order those with any text or emoji you want engraved on the case for free. They’re 1,999 yuan ($310) &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com.cn/shop/product/MJ533CH/A"&gt;in mainland China&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and they’re also for sale in Hong Kong, Taiwan, Singapore, and Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tLV6w4"&gt;Apple is limiting orders to two per customer, and the AirPods Pro will only be available at retail Apple Stores as well as Apple’s local websites in each region. The Year of the Ox only comes around once every 12 years, though, so if you do buy these you may end up wanting to swap them out for a tiger-themed model in a year’s time — assuming Apple decides to release one. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218360/apple-lunar-new-year-ox-airpods-pro-asia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218360/apple-lunar-new-year-ox-airpods-pro-asia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T20:44:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T20:44:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Today I learned your Apple Watch can double as a vlogging viewfinder </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uJ2R2SUUeFS4mE0jZx5JI8_l2w0=/0x0:2200x1467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68625472/20210105_mitchell_clark_Verge_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UgD7vJ"&gt;The Apple Watch’s ability to act as a camera remote for your phone &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/9/6125873/apple-watch-smartwatch-announced"&gt;got a mention in its announcement keynote&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s been around a while, but I’ve only ever used it once or twice to take group pictures. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeterSciretta/status/1346526439068160002?s=20"&gt;Twitter user @PeterSciretta&lt;/a&gt;, however, has pointed out that you can also use it as a vlogging aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b6TueN"&gt;Doing this is simple: On your watch, go to the Camera Remote app. This will open the camera app on your iPhone, and you can switch it to video mode, set it up, and record. You don’t even have to strap your watch to your phone like he does in the tweet; the remote camera will totally work while your watch is on your wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="B1HhEr"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is the best self-recording hack ever and even works with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FiLMiCPro?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@FiLMiCPro&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeterSciretta?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@PeterSciretta&lt;/a&gt; for this tip.   &lt;a href="https://t.co/LGKS3S2pCh"&gt;pic.twitter.com/LGKS3S2pCh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Roy   ☕️     (@pulpjedi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pulpjedi/status/1346523889736695808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C3hAgW"&gt;I’ve shot videos on my phone before, and it was often an exercise in frustration trying to get the framing right. There was a lot of running back and forth, recording short clips to make sure the focus and framing were correct. I could’ve definitely saved myself the hassle if I had remembered that my watch could do this, though I guess I would’ve gotten fewer steps in. It’s a sacrifice I’ll just have to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1VTzHl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Using your Apple Watch as an iPhone viewfinder: surprisingly latency-free and useful &lt;a href="https://t.co/PyoxK6TxND"&gt;pic.twitter.com/PyoxK6TxND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mitchell (@strawberrywell) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/strawberrywell/status/1346618135604908032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p3jPJX"&gt;Android users don’t need to feel left out either, as Wear OS devices &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/23/18014640/google-pixel-wear-os-smartwatch-camera-viewfinder"&gt;can also act as a camera viewfinder&lt;/a&gt; when connected to Pixel phones. The Apple Watch trick will also work with the popular video camera app FiLMiC Pro, as Jeff mentions in his tweet. That way, you can get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/28/7925023/sundance-film-festival-2015-tangerine-iphone-5s"&gt;all the benefits the third-party app offers&lt;/a&gt;, plus the remote viewing on your watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8sAwSS"&gt;Of course, if you’re setting out to create a new vlogging setup, this is probably not the best way to go, especially if you don’t already have an Apple Watch. For less than the price of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2019/3/11/18259791/apple-watch-series-3-lte-best-buy-price-sale"&gt;Apple’s least expensive Watch (the Series 3)&lt;/a&gt;, you could instead get Apple’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMD826AM%2FA%2Flightning-digital-av-adapter&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F1%2F5%2F22216064%2Fiphone-vlogging-video-apple-watch-viewfinder#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lightning to HDMI adapter&lt;/a&gt; (which would also let you power your phone so it doesn’t run out of battery), and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Neewer-1280x800-Mirrorless-Panasonic-Included/dp/B077FTPT46/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=camera+monitor&amp;amp;qid=1609895598&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;tag=duckduckgo-osx-b-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a small camera monitor&lt;/a&gt;. Or, you could just position your phone in front of a mirror. But if you already have an Apple Watch, and want to film yourself using your iPhone, this tip may just make that easier.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/5/22216064/iphone-vlogging-video-apple-watch-viewfinder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/5/22216064/iphone-vlogging-video-apple-watch-viewfinder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
