<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-27T15:51:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-27T15:51:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-27T15:51:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>New trailers: The Harder They Fall, Ted Lasso, The Suicide Squad, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FwBR07XF1meccu6ml0OlduyE8yE=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69510942/king_and_elba.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Regina King and Idris Elba in &lt;em&gt;The Harder They Fall&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pKz5kZr8mrg&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5eTIke"&gt;Since it was one of the top picks on Netflix and everyone’s talking about it, I started watching Manifest and got five episodes in before I realized it was basically a version of Lost with a few wacky twists and I am not falling for THAT again. But the deeply weird and wonderful &lt;em&gt;The Good Fight&lt;/em&gt; is back, and the pilot had Christine Baranski and Audra McDonald at their best, so I can’t wait to see what happens this season (although we said goodbye to two of the show’s best characters, boo). Also can we talk about &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;? We probably can’t without giving away spoilers but episode three gave us a LOT, most of which I suspect were attempts at misdirection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQN1sH"&gt;I got so engrossed in writing last Sunday’s trailers post that I totally missed the new &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; trailer that dropped that day. Derp. Don’t worry, I’ve included it here (in case you haven’t already watched it 1,000 times like I have).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OPphFJ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pKz5kZr8mrg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AUbM7U"&gt;The Harder They Fall &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="iPeNzE"&gt;This trailer (sorry, it’s the official &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teaser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) for a Western about rival outlaw gangs opens with a train heist where Regina King and Lakeith Stanfield free Idris Elba from captivity— with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0zWRjgathjA&amp;amp;ab_channel=gd73"&gt;“Let’s Start”&lt;/a&gt; by Fela Kuti playing — and then proceed to shoot their way out in slow-motion. It’s almost too much cool to take in all at once. Our plot: Outlaw Nat Love (Jonathan Majors) and his gang Stagecoach Mary (Zazie Beetz), Bill Pickett (Edi Gathegi), and Jim Beckwourth (RJ Cyler) are rivals of the newly-released Rufus Buck (Elba) and his crew, Treacherous Judy Smith (King), and Cherokee Bill (Stanfield). Delroy Lindo and Damon Wayans Jr., also star in &lt;em&gt;The Harder They Fall&lt;/em&gt;, (what a cast!) which is directed by Jeymes Samuel and is coming to Netflix soon (hurry up pls!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yRcGXN"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/reP1gVGpFKo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="R4dHfK"&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="RXhhjk"&gt;Ted unleashes his alter ego Led Tasso to be tough and mean to the floundering Richmond football club and it’s so goofy and ridiculous but so very &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; (lol he calls them “turd birds” what?). Jason Sudeikis and the rest of the crew are back in the second season, and we have less than a month to wait for new episodes, you guys (side note: you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22543775/apple-tv-ted-lasso-merch-kit-jersey-trailer-season-2"&gt;buy Richmond jerseys&lt;/a&gt; at the Ted Lasso merch store). Season 2 of &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; premieres July 23rd on Apple TV Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3khcqb"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eg5ciqQzmK0?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="B9yc13"&gt;The Suicide Squad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="V7HVWx"&gt;Is Idris Elba in every movie coming out this summer? (for the record I am very OK with this). James Gunn’s take on the band of supervillains led by Elba as Bloodsport (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JamesGunn/status/1407730256283193351"&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; at last!) has them taking on even badder bad guys on a remote jungle island. Margot Robbie, Viola Davis, Joel Kinnaman, Michael Rooker, Pete Davidson, Nathan Fillion, and John Cena also star in&lt;em&gt; The Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to theaters and HBO Max on August 6th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PKpjTu"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8YjFbMbfXaQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="QJyLPV"&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HCs08s"&gt;We saw a&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teaser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for this movie back in April, but this is the official &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trailer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (and again, I don’t think there’s really much difference between teasers and trailers anymore, but I digress). Simu Liu plays Shang-Chi, trained as an assassin as a child, who is trying to escape to have a normal life. This latest movie in the Marvel cinematic universe has an almost entirely Asian cast, including its title character. And yes, the giant monster Shang-Chi is shown fighting in a cage match &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MCU_Direct/status/1408233747082878988?"&gt;looks to be Abomination&lt;/a&gt;. Tony Leung, Michelle Yeoh, and Awkwafina also star in &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings,&lt;/em&gt; coming to theaters September 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="e7PAyF"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yKG0RodrzVo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="EPVmei"&gt;Schmigadoon! &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hCQ1aL"&gt;Keegan Michael Key and Cecily Strong play a couple trapped in a musical until they find true love. OK, sure, why not. This six-episode series has an all-star cast of musical talent, including Kristin Chenoweth, Alan Cummings, Fred Armisen, Jane Krakowski, and Martin Short. This feels like one of those flicks that is either going to be super funny or super cringe (although I did laugh at Strong’s character realizing that musicals kill people off all the time, so that’s a good sign). &lt;em&gt;Schmigadoon! &lt;/em&gt;(I’ll let them have the exclamation point) comes to Apple TV Plus on July 16th, with new episodes every Friday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I00scW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/27/22550467/new-trailers-harder-they-fall-ted-lasso-suicide-squad-shang-chi-netflix-hbo-apple-marvel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/27/22550467/new-trailers-harder-they-fall-ted-lasso-suicide-squad-shang-chi-netflix-hbo-apple-marvel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T21:37:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T21:37:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly sends warning letter to Chinese leaker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IjOarRV2oNTOUTQIzC-b_KTdAOw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69506761/vpavic_042020_3980_0055.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bH10md"&gt;Despite Apple’s efforts to keep anyone from finding out what it’s working on, leaks have continued to give the world early previews of new iPhones, Macs and more. Its campaign to plug the holes is apparently extending to threats of legal action, as the leaker known as “Kang” &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/1694917363/KlE4Ozlsd?from=page_1005051694917363_profile&amp;amp;wvr=6&amp;amp;mod=weibotime&amp;amp;ssl_rnd=1624542267.3793&amp;amp;type=comment"&gt;posted to Weibo&lt;/a&gt; this week about a notice he received from the company (via &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/24/reliable-leaker-kang-hit-with-warning/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gEq4Ok"&gt;Kang currently holds the &lt;a href="https://appletrack.com/kang/"&gt;number one spot on the AppleTrack leaderboard&lt;/a&gt;, which attempts to compare the reliability of the information various leakers share, and &lt;a href="https://appletrack.com/apple-targets-leakers-and-collaborators-in-new-offensive-to-stop-rumors/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ReviveOldPost"&gt;AppleTrack indicates&lt;/a&gt; that other leakers have received similar messages. Prior to the iPhone 12 launch, Kang posted about all four models that Apple had prepared, revealing their prices, colors and planned release dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WelwFO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iPhone 12: everything we think we know about Apple’s 2020 5G iPhones, which could be announced on October 13th ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21423811/apple-iphone-12-max-pro-leaks-rumors-specs-design-2020"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="FLVL0Q"&gt;According to Kang, the letter from a law firm claimed that his actions could share information with Apple’s competitors, or mislead consumers about devices that aren’t coming. It also included screenshots of his Weibo page, showing posts beyond the leaks, like ones where he talked about problems he’s had with Apple products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GKPO8n"&gt;For his part, Kang claims to have never signed an NDA, published undisclosed pictures or profited from his information. Still, the tracker shows his information has revealed details about everything from the iPhone SE to the HomePod mini. Content creator Ben Geskin &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BenGeskin/status/1408121541150269446"&gt;mentioned receiving&lt;/a&gt; a similar notice last year, while fellow leaker L0vetodream (number five on the source ranking list) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/L0vetodream/status/1408018049102356484"&gt;said they had not received anything&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnVfPT"&gt;Apple did not respond to a request for comment about the letters or how many were sent. As for Kang, the post indicates he won’t post “riddles” or “dreams” about upcoming devices, so while the weight of the threat is unclear, it may have had Apple’s intended effect.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22551182/kang-letter-apple-leak-warning-iphone-12"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22551182/kang-letter-apple-leak-warning-iphone-12</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hybrid work is coming to big tech. Its contractors might not be so lucky</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FRANCE-ECONOMY-HEALTH-VIRUS" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nJeccnQcyc1wYovV-Wtr19gpbMM=/0x0:5453x3635/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69503849/1229318293.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by CHRISTOPHE ARCHAMBAULT/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pRoNjf"&gt;In fits and starts, the US is reopening — in many cases to the chagrin of office workers who have settled into work-from-wherever setups they’ve had the past 16-ish months to perfect. And given the willingness of many of those same workers to quit rather than go back to full-time cubicle life, many companies have offered some form of “hybrid” arrangement as a compromise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rrj36O"&gt;It seems that benefit isn’t being extended to all workers, though. Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, and Microsoft were short on concrete answers as to which contingent workers — which comprise sizable, sometimes majority portions of their workforce, and perform functions from hospitality and security to content moderation and coding — if any would be allowed to work remotely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="CCIz44"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10619076"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sbMzdw"&gt;Each of these tech giants appear to be instituting some version of partial remote work for corporate employees, with some minor variations. &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/workplace/amazon-updates-return-to-office-guidance"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/inside-google/life-at-google/hybrid-approach-work"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2021/03/22/the-philosophy-and-practice-of-our-hybrid-workplace/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; each announced these changes publicly on their corporate blogs, while internal memos to the same effect within Facebook and Apple were reported on by the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-lets-more-employees-choose-full-time-remote-work-or-return-to-the-office-11623258049"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, respectively. All instituted a future of what Microsoft hazily described as “working from home part of the time (less than 50%) as standard for most roles,” and its competitors as some variation of requiring three days per week in the office. Apple took the extra step of mandating which three days — Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WerBel"&gt;There are of course, caveats in both directions. Some roles were flagged by Facebook and Amazon as not being remote work-applicable: jobs like hardware engineers and data center workers. On the other hand, nearly all of these companies noted that eligible employees could remain fully remote if they were granted that permission by their manager. Google even &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/google-rolls-out-tool-to-show-its-employees-compensation-changes-for-transferring-offices/"&gt;developed a tool&lt;/a&gt; that will show remote workers how much it plans to shave off their salaries if they go the remote option and move somewhere with a lower cost of living. (Thanks?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nA3t6B"&gt;Missing from any of these memos or announcements, though, was any mention of whether remote work options were available to the legions of contractors that help these companies function. Spokespeople for most of these companies sidestepped the question. “When it comes down to our contractors and partners, I wouldn’t be able to speak on their behalf or how they would implement our policy,” an Amazon spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; Facebook provided a similar answer. Facebook’s spokesperson did not respond to a request for a list of which agencies they used for contract labor so that we could ask each company about its remote work policies, while Amazon declined to provide one citing “confidentiality reasons.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8YErj"&gt;A spokesperson with Google stated that temporary staff would likely be required to come in the same days as the teams of employees that oversee them, while the companies that employ its contingent “vendors” had already determined which jobs could or could not perform their work remotely. The same spokesperson was not able to provide an approximate percentage for how many of these vendors would have that benefit extended to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Hzmjz"&gt;Through an external communications agency, a spokesperson for Microsoft wrote that aforementioned corporate blog was “all the company has to share.” Apple did not respond to multiple requests for information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9qnZ98"&gt;It’s logical to defer to these external agencies, but it also belies how much leverage tech companies have in these relationships. Microsoft has previously &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/076474aa0b1b47b6b4790dbf98ed6108"&gt;required&lt;/a&gt; firms it works with provide paid childcare leave for its contractors; Google too has &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-require-suppliers-give-benefits-workers/"&gt;mandated&lt;/a&gt; contractors receive at least $15 per hour, healthcare, and parental leave. Facebook has also &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2019/05/compensating-and-supporting-contractors/"&gt;instituted&lt;/a&gt; “well-being and resiliency training” for its contractor moderators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IBDFO2"&gt;It’s also a bit hard to believe — especially in instances where these workers would be reporting to these companies’ facilities — that these companies lack any direct oversight over who is coming into their offices at a time when indoor capacity limits are not only a matter of corporate policy, but often a matter of state mandate too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KgpBMi"&gt;The issues of remote work for contractors is also not a new one — and much earlier in the pandemic it caused quite a bit of bad PR for several of these companies. Facebook took heat from having some of those same content moderators working from the office back in November, a month where the US was seeing around 100,000 new cases of covid daily — and from awarding monetary bonuses to employees &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/03/17/facebook-coronavirus-bonus-contractors/"&gt;but not to contractors&lt;/a&gt;. Google was requiring some contractors to report to work in person in March of 2020, sparking internal &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184495/google-employees-memo-contract-workers-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;backlash from its own employees&lt;/a&gt;; it also rescinded job offers to around 2,000 contractors — citing the economic downturn — while apportioning $1,000 each for employees to purchase desks and other items for their from-home workspaces. Around the same time, hundreds of contractor jobs with Apple were reportedly suspended without pay — only to be restored after a contingent of unionized janitors and the Wall Street Journal began &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-commits-to-paying-contractors-after-some-were-told-theyd-lose-work-11585667276"&gt;asking questions&lt;/a&gt;. Most of this &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7j7mb/amazon-delivery-drivers-are-overwhelmed-and-overworked-by-covid-19-surge"&gt;barely holds a candle&lt;/a&gt; to what Amazon’s considerably more frontline delivery contractors experienced, as a whole country, trapped inside, dramatically increased its online purchasing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iqZlJx"&gt;This is all relevant insofar as it illustrates that the two-tiered system of employment within these companies is alive and well, but also that these very big, very wealthy companies, supposedly staffed by the best and brightest, had many, many months to consider a return to office plan that would be transparent and comprehensible. Contractors themselves, and a news media willing to report on them, has been asking how tech companies will handle this disparity in benefits &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/03/09/tech-contractors-coronavirus/"&gt;essentially since the pandemic began&lt;/a&gt;. A year and a half later, there’s still no clear answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kDduGv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22545717/big-tech-hybrid-work-remote-contractors-google-apple-amazon-facebook-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22545717/big-tech-hybrid-work-remote-contractors-google-apple-amazon-facebook-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-24T04:34:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-24T04:34:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Listen to Spotify on this nostalgic iPod-style web music player</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uDmQ2dBlwx_rwed9iaXCBEqlecE=/0x0:1301x867/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69497486/msedge_a3fZpfyz0z.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A classic iPod interface for your Spotify or Apple Music library.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: tannerv.com/ipod&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E1SnOd"&gt;In an era before multitouch displays, the iPod’s click wheel was the king of music playback control. Now, a new project from frontend software developer Tanner Villarete has attempted to emulate its classic controls &lt;a href="https://tannerv.com/ipod/"&gt;as a web app&lt;/a&gt;, complete with support for your Spotify and Apple Music library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XrKaLi"&gt;It’s fantastically simple, using your mouse or finger on a touchscreen to emulate the classic controls. You’ll need to sign in using an Apple Music or Spotify Account, and then it’s a simple case of using the virtual click wheel to select and listen to a selection of your most listened-to artists. It even supports the iPod’s classic “Cover Flow” interface, letting you to flip through album covers like a jukebox. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hP_hg_8nKMgRMrqrUd8Flpzsp80=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22678584/msedge_qAYmQ76Ggy.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: tannerv.com/ipod&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And yes, it totally has a built-in Brick Breaker clone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BPYGOk"&gt;Now, obviously there’s a reason why modern apps don’t use click wheel interfaces. Using the touch-sensitive wheel via a phone’s web browser feels ok, but on desktop having to drag a mouse around a virtual circle feels &lt;em&gt;inefficient&lt;/em&gt; at best. It’s at its worst when loading up the virtual iPod’s built-in Brick Breaker game clone (which, sidenote, also rips). But as a nostalgic trip down memory lane? Perfection. The project is &lt;a href="https://github.com/tvillarete/ipod-classic-js"&gt;on GitHub here&lt;/a&gt; if you want to have a poke around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pp7NO"&gt;Apple killed off the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/9/4715274/ipod-classic-discontinued-a-visual-history"&gt;classic iPod design in 2014&lt;/a&gt;. It now sells just one iPod branded device, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/7/18656480/apple-ipod-touch-7th-generation-2019-update-review"&gt;iPod Touch&lt;/a&gt;, which in terms of hardware is effectively a dated iPhone with no cellular connectivity, biometric authentication, or other modern features. We’d love to see the classic design return, but according to Apple CEO Tim Cook, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/28/7082095/tim-cook-says-apple-killed-the-ipod-classic-because-it-couldnt-get"&gt;simply couldn’t get the parts anymore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RZCPJd"&gt;Let’s just hope Apple doesn’t kill the project &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/16/21024729/apple-rewound-app-iphone-ipod-click-wheel-web-android-not-available"&gt;like it did Rewound&lt;/a&gt;, the music player app that &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; attempted to bring back the iPod’s classic control scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548356/ipod-web-player-spotify-apple-music"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548356/ipod-web-player-spotify-apple-music</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-24T02:23:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-24T02:23:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lenovo made a wireless charger for your laptop</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sew8VjSvFkcnV0hCLzVP0e8_0LE=/0x0:2100x1400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69497384/Screenshot_2021_06_24_at_15.18.45.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bg2Y7S"&gt;Lenovo has announced a new product called the Go Wireless Charging Kit, which lets you retrofit wireless charging functionality to a wide variety of laptops. It makes use of “Power by Contact” technology from Energy Square, rather than the more common Qi standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tzneP1"&gt;The kit consists of a 3.2mm-thick brushed metal charging mat that you plug into the wall and leave at your desk, as well as a long wireless charging receiver that attaches to the base of your laptop and connects over USB-C. Once set up, Lenovo says it should charge most 13-inch to 14-inch “non-touch notebooks of up to 65W” with efficiency of 93 percent, and it’ll work with both Windows and macOS devices. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i30wzLO4H8xfFUsRUHss8S0dojQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22678555/02_Lenovo_Go_USB_C_Wireless_Charging_Kit_Mat_Dongle_Hero_Front.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="x6zjKJ"&gt;Wireless charging on laptops is pretty rare. Dell released what it called the world’s first wirelessly charging 2-in-1, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/11/15955350/dell-latitude-7000-price-availability-wireless-charging"&gt;the Latitude 7285&lt;/a&gt;, in 2017, although it was more of a tablet that could be charged through a keyboard base. Intel also made efforts to integrate the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/20/5430310/a4wp-wireless-ultrabook-charging-dell-joins"&gt;Rezence&lt;/a&gt; magnetic resonance charging standard into its laptop specifications, but nothing was ever released commercially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vx2meT"&gt;Lenovo will release the Go Wireless Charging Kit in October for $139.99. It’s part of a new range of Go-branded mobile accessories including a Qi-equipped power bank, wireless mice, headphones, and keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548300/lenovo-go-wireless-charging-kit-laptop-charger-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548300/lenovo-go-wireless-charging-kit-laptop-charger-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T20:24:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T20:24:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple may be looking to make a less expensive big phone in 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-5IOh_hyZLO3rP-d4_rJF-ixICw=/498x0:2802x1536/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69496618/Screen_Shot_2021_06_23_at_3.53.24_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aVq5eH"&gt;According to noted analyst Ming-Chi Kuo, Apple will sell an iPhone with a 6.7-inch screen for less than $900 in 2022 (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/23/kuo-2022-iphones-could-feature-under-display-touch-id-lowest-price-ever-for-6-7-inch-iphone/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). If this turns out to be the case, iPhone 14 buyers will have a less expensive way to get a screen size that Apple currently only sells on the 12 Pro Max, which starts at $1,099. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKs7gA"&gt;Kuo predicts that Apple’s 2022 non-pro iPhone lineup includes phones with 6.1 and 6.7-inch screens (the same sizes as the current iPhone 12 Pro and 12 Pro Max, respectively). Absent is the iPhone Mini with its 5.4-inch screen. Analysts, including Kuo, have said that the Mini will be going away in 2022 due to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322843/iphone-12-mini-apple-low-production-numbers-decrease"&gt;reportedly low sales&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YOFORJ"&gt;While some may mourn the loss of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21222642/iphone-se-2-size-comparison-small-phone-trend-galaxy-oneplus"&gt;an actually small phone option&lt;/a&gt;, from Apple’s perspective, going big with its line of mainstream phones makes sense. We know from documents unearthed in the Epic v. Apple trial that Apple commissioned a report on the smartphone purchasing habits of consumers late last year. The report showed both that many customers were buying phones that had screens larger than six inches and that more people were turning to Samsung than Apple for their big phone needs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cp_Grsgbx--DQMHTv8awM5dW7L4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22678069/apple_charts.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charts from the report showing the screen size breakdown for phones sold and average price points.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cb9O4E"&gt;Both companies face &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166399/iphone-android-apple-samsung-smartphone-sales-peak"&gt;a market that is slowing down&lt;/a&gt;, and one that is having to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/18/18263584/why-phones-are-so-expensive-price-apple-samsung-google"&gt;grapple with rising costs&lt;/a&gt;. If Apple has made the decision to make a lower-end big phone, it’s done so after seeing the research that many consumers want phones that are both bigger, and cheaper. While Apple has somewhat been working toward that goal (the iPhone 12, 11, and XR have all had 6.1-inch screens), it’s generally kept the really big phones at the high-end — next year could be its time to court users who want something bigger than 6.1-inches, but don’t want to spend over $1,000 to get it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fxKBtV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s generally kept the really big phones at the high-end&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ncmGUf"&gt;In addition to his prediction about the lower-end 6.7-inch iPhone, &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; also reports that Kuo said the 2022 iPhones will have under-display fingerprint readers, and that there will be a new &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/23/kuo-new-iphone-se-with-5g-and-new-processor-still-on-track-for-first-half-of-2022/"&gt;iPhone SE with 5G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYDTyc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: We previously stated the iPhone 12 mini had a 5.7-inch screen, but it has a 5.4-inch screen. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547615/apple-big-screen-iphone-14-2022-less-expensive-rumor-kuo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547615/apple-big-screen-iphone-14-2022-less-expensive-rumor-kuo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T19:32:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T19:32:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Logitech’s improved Combo Touch keyboard will be available for the fourth-gen iPad Air in July</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fxqS1UL0ZIZ3XuVGNFE20_03YFo=/0x201:1080x921/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69496407/Combo_Touch_for_iPad_Air_Oxford_Grey_Beautiful_Design_Enviro_1080x1080.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Combo Touch case.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Logitech&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iE98Y1"&gt;Logitech is releasing a version of its Combo Touch keyboard case, which has a Microsoft Surface-style kickstand and a detachable keyboard with an integrated trackpad, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.logitech.com%2F2021%2F06%2F23%2Flogitech-announces-combo-touch-for-ipad-air-and-new-color%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F23%2F22547938%2Flogitech-combo-touch-ipad-air-fourth-generation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for the fourth-generation iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;. The case will cost $199.99, making it $100 cheaper than Apple’s Magic Keyboard that fits the iPad Air, and it will be available in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y92CD4"&gt;The Combo Touch’s keyboard is powered by the iPad’s Smart Connector, meaning that you won’t need to charge up the keyboard on its own, and it offers backlit keys and iPadOS shortcut keys. The case also a handy open spot at the top where you can store a second-gen Apple Pencil, which attaches magnetically to the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpBqDE"&gt;This case’s design might feel familiar — it looks nearly identical to the Combo Touch cases that were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395219/logitech-combo-touch-keyboard-new-ipad-pro"&gt;recently released for the 2021 iPad Pros&lt;/a&gt;. It also seems like it will be an upgrade from the version of the Combo Touch that fits the third-generation iPad Air — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231088/logitech-combo-touch-ipad-keyboard-trackpad-case-review-price-specs-features"&gt;and my colleague Phil Esposito already liked that case a lot&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p7DC8y"&gt;Speaking of the Combo Touch for the iPad Pros, Logitech is also introducing a new “sand” color (I’d describe it as &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitech.com%2Fen-us%2Fproducts%2Fipad-keyboards%2Fcombo-touch-ipad.html%3Fcrid%3D1762%23buy-combo-touch-ipad&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F23%2F22547938%2Flogitech-combo-touch-ipad-air-fourth-generation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a light gray&lt;/a&gt;) that will also be available in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gpRtC7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Logitech announces cheaper Magic Keyboard alternative for new iPad Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395219/logitech-combo-touch-keyboard-new-ipad-pro"},{"title":"Logitech’s Combo Touch is the Magic Keyboard for everyone else","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231088/logitech-combo-touch-ipad-keyboard-trackpad-case-review-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547938/logitech-combo-touch-ipad-air-fourth-generation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547938/logitech-combo-touch-ipad-air-fourth-generation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T12:55:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T12:55:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Foundation will debut on Apple TV Plus in September</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qnd6z3ry89CES0r4LRh6KS9H5VA=/256x0:1792x1024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69493817/apple_foundation.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RZcT9s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; — Apple’s big-budget adaptation of the classic Isaac Asimov books — finally has a release date: it’ll debut on Apple TV Plus sometime this September, according to an email to subscribers &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/23/apple-tv-foundation-series-release-date/"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. An exact release date has yet to be announced, although, presumably, Apple will provide details on that in the coming weeks as the marketing blitz for the show picks up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhBl2L"&gt;The series has been a long time coming. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/11/17223728/apple-foundation-trilogy-isaac-asimov-tv-show-david-goyer-josh-friedman"&gt;first announced &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; back in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, as one of the marque series for the streaming service, and it debuted a trailer for it during its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21295512/apple-tv-plus-foundation-show-trailer-isaac-asimov-wwdc-2020"&gt;WWDC keynote presentation last year&lt;/a&gt;. But due to delays from the COVID-19 pandemic, the show was delayed to late 2021, and Apple hasn’t really shown off any more footage or information since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="O0VuAz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Can ‘Foundation’ bring in viewers to TV Plus?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ou0MW2"&gt;Set to star Jared Harris as Hari Seldon, Lee Pace the Emperor of the Galaxy, and Lou Llobell as Gaal Dornick, the series appears to be starting at the same place Asimov’s series does: with the Galactic Empire still at its height, but with Seldon’s “psychohistory” predicting its downfall, necessitating the creation of the titular Foundation to house mankind’s knowledge during a new dark age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhHrNi"&gt;Since launching in late 2019, Apple’s streaming service has been searching for its must-watch flagship series, a &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones, The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; of a show that gets viewers to pay the service’s monthly cost. And while the service has seen some success from shows like &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show &lt;/em&gt;— two of its earliest debuts — neither series has turned into the kind of massive hit that can drive an entire streaming service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AUN185"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"You may have to actually pay for Apple TV Plus to watch Ted Lasso’s second season","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="50j53b"&gt;So far, the biggest impact of TV Plus has been in the unlikely hero of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;Jason Sudeikis’ sports comedy &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — so much so, in fact, that Apple appears to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"&gt;timing the end of its extended promotional free trial&lt;/a&gt; for day-one TV Plus subscribers just ahead of the show’s upcoming second season. Apple is betting that the show will be the draw to get viewers to start subscribing in earnest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8FIVj"&gt;Apple TV Plus is currently available for $4.99 a month or as part of the company’s Apple One service bundles, which also include iCloud storage, Apple Music, Apple Arcade, and on the highest tier, Apple News Plus and Apple Fitness Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQG4ok"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W899zL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547252/foundation-release-date-apple-tv-plus-september"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547252/foundation-release-date-apple-tv-plus-september</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T10:32:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best iPad deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The 2020 iPad Air has the same design and shape as the 11-inch iPad Pro" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OqDG5sf2dQljUBF65yxBXRiy6oE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66899976/vpavic_4244_20201020_0013.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1L3M8j"&gt;Deals on Apple’s iPad are more common than you might think. Whether you’re after the affordable iPad, the high-end iPad Pro, or something in between like the iPad Air or iPad Mini, there’s usually some sort of price cut happening somewhere. Of course, it’s difficult to know exactly where you can find those deals unless you’re looking around at all of the major retailers. But that’s what we’re doing each day when we hunt for deals, so let us help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzVhpS"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each of the current iPads available for purchase. Most of the time, there’s some sort of discount happening on a new or refurbished model. When there is a deal we think worth telling you about, we’ll let you know, along with any info you need to keep it in context. If there isn’t a current deal, we’ll tell you how much the most recent sale price was for, so you’ll know when to take the plunge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhF14P"&gt;Just to let you know up top, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fus-hed%2Fshop%2Fback-to-school&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21280354%2Fbest-ipad-deals-apple" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s back-to-school promotion has already kicked off&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you can snag a free set of AirPods with the purchase of either an iPad Air or iPad Pro. Granted, you have to be a student who’s eligible to check out at Apple’s educational storefront. If you prefer the AirPods Pro, you can also upgrade for an additional $90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DMtl0v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on MacBooks right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="hb2n3u"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="q5ZrvP"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;2020 iPad&lt;/a&gt; is Apple’s most affordable tablet, usually costing $329 for the model with 32GB of storage or $429 for the model with 128GB of storage. Each has a 10.2-inch display and features the A12 Bionic processor, a Touch ID fingerprint sensor, and a Smart Connector for connecting a Smart Keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hDQ0n6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508346"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5m6ZrK"&gt;Currently, you can purchase the base iPad with 32GB of storage for $299 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-2-inch-iPad-8th-Gen-Wi-Fi-32GB-Space-Gray%2F989344107%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=VergeiPadDeals3292021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J65DST5/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=ipad+2020&amp;amp;qid=1621350979&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzSkVCMDZaTjVCV0VFJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwMDM2OTM2RjNHV0xNUDNHUDk1JmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTAyMjg1ODkyMVFXT0lITjVaR0hZJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. Both retailers also offer the 128GB configuration in multiple colors for $395 (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J61NFNR/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=ipad%2B2020&amp;amp;qid=1621350979&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzSkVCMDZaTjVCV0VFJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwMDM2OTM2RjNHV0xNUDNHUDk1JmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTAyMjg1ODkyMVFXT0lITjVaR0hZJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-2-inch-iPad-8th-Gen-Wi-Fi-128GB-Silver%2F252643318%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=VergeiPadDeals032921" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fmPtFu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad mini (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MgBOt3"&gt;Apple released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;latest iPad mini&lt;/a&gt; in early 2019, equipped with the same 7.9-inch display and design as previous iterations, but with refreshed internal specs. It has the A12 Bionic processor found in the base iPad, along with Wi-Fi support. Apple sells 64GB and 256GB models of the iPad mini, with prices set at $400 and $500 respectively. If you want LTE connectivity, the starting price is $530.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rG7i7T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515887"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QD0sMe"&gt;Sales on the basic Wi-Fi model are rare, but if you want to buy the 64GB iPad mini right now, it is available for its usual $329 at Walmart. There is also a sale on the 256GB, which is available for $490 in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PQ8XKZC?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rose gold&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07NHN9W4J?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="66nPkj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Air (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5sW0N"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;2020 iPad Air&lt;/a&gt; has a slightly larger 10.9-inch display compared to the prior model’s 10.5-inch screen and features thinner bezels around it. It has relocated the Touch ID fingerprint sensor to the power button, located on the top of the device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VGT87b"&gt;The fourth-gen iPad Air model comes in 64GB or 256GB storage configurations. The Wi-Fi models start at $599 and $749, respectively, making the starting price slightly more than last year’s models. The model that supports LTE starts at $729. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JhHVno"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7PfM3l"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Pro (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9tR4OQ"&gt;The fifth-gen, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;M1-equipped iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; is currently available, which means there are plenty of deals to be had on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;2020 iteration of the iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The fourth-gen iPad Pro looks a lot like the 2018 model, aside from its dual-lens rear camera array. Unlike the less expensive iPad models, the 2020 iPad Pro ditches the headphone jack and uses a USB-C port instead of a Lightning port. It also features a high refresh display and Face ID to help you unlock the tablet instead of relying on the Touch ID fingerprint sensor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dnrxd6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Zobp6q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="vdWMel"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="iuddo9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T08:38:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T08:38:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple argues against sideloading iPhone apps as regulatory pressure mounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YKJG7cTmNKROtjO3RMvsT2dflkE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69492130/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QRE13b"&gt;In a new 16-page report, Apple has laid out its arguments against allowing sideloading iPhone apps, claiming the practice would make its phones less secure and trustworthy for users. &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/privacy/docs/Building_a_Trusted_Ecosystem_for_Millions_of_Apps.pdf"&gt;The report&lt;/a&gt;, which is titled “Building a Trusted Ecosystem for Millions of Apps,” outlines Apple’s existing security processes and how it believes these could change if it were forced by regulators to allow sideloading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9B99a"&gt;The report is part of Apple’s pushback against lawmakers and other critics, who have argued that it should be forced to allow apps to be sideloaded onto its iPhones, bypassing its centralized App Store. In the US, the House Judiciary Committee is expected today to debate &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529857/democrats-antitrust-big-tech-facebook-amazon-google-apple-competition-package-bills"&gt;a series of bills&lt;/a&gt; aimed at addressing tech monopolies, including Apple’s App Store policies. One such bill sponsored by Rep. David Cicilline (D-RI), chairman of the antitrust subcommittee, could force Apple to allow third-party app stores on its platform, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-23/apple-says-third-party-app-stores-would-open-iphones-to-scammers?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sPr0gs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Allowing sideloading would degrade the security of the iOS platform”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3cUmqE"&gt;Elsewhere, the EU’s proposed Digital Markets Act (DMA) could compel Apple to allow sideloading of apps. “The current DMA language that is being discussed, would force sideloading on the iPhone,” Apple’s CEO Tim Cook previously said, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/23/apple-warns-of-perils-installing-rogue-apps-ahead-of-antitrust-debate.html"&gt;according to CNBC&lt;/a&gt;. This “alternate way of getting apps onto the iPhone” would “destroy” its security, the CEO argued. Epic also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22452035/epic-apple-antitrust-trial-final-arguments"&gt;argued for Apple to allow sideloading&lt;/a&gt; in its recent high-profile trial with the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hx3Kqb"&gt;Apple already allows sideloading on its Mac computers, but it argues that this model doesn’t work for iPhones because they carry more sensitive and personal information. Apple’s senior vice president of software engineering Craig Federighi recently argued &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22444353/mac-malware-not-acceptable-craig-federighi-apple-epic"&gt;during the company’s trial with Epic Games&lt;/a&gt; that the Mac’s model means that it has a level of malware that “we don’t find acceptable and is much worse than iOS.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ViF7QT"&gt;“Allowing sideloading would degrade the security of the iOS platform and expose users to serious security risks not only on third-party app stores, but also on the App Store,” Apple’s new report says. Apps that don’t go through its App Store review process could contain malware that Apple’s reviewers would otherwise catch, the company argues, citing research that suggests third-party app stores on Android (which does allow sideloading) are more likely to contain malicious code. Non-App Store apps may also not use Apple’s security and privacy features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWgKac"&gt;However, critics have pushed back against Apple’s claims about the security of apps on its store. Despite Apple’s assurances that it has a 500-plus strong team reviewing around 100,000 new apps and updates every week, there have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;numerous examples of scam apps&lt;/a&gt; slipping through its checks, including some that hide &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22386533/ios-app-scam-jungle-runner-magical-forest-apple-kosta"&gt;casinos in kids apps&lt;/a&gt; or others that charge extortionately high subscription fees. And forcing developers to use the App Store to distribute apps means many have to pay Apple a 30 percent commission on app sales and in-app purchases for digital goods, a commission that Cicilline has previously called “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21295778/apple-app-store-hey-email-fees-policies-antitrust-wwdc-2020"&gt;highway robbery&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XH22xG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ios-app-store-antitrust-174909862.html"&gt;Some experts have also argued&lt;/a&gt; that the iPhone’s security has more to do with the security features of iOS, including the way apps run in a so-called “sandbox,” rather than the App Store’s review process. But Apple’s report claims that “the best defense relies on a combination of all layers,” combining App Store review with built-in platform protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ywVi16"&gt;Apple says allowing sideloading on iPhones would affect all of its billion-plus users, regardless of whether they actually want to download apps that aren’t available on the App Store. Users might need to download a non-App Store app because they need it for work or school, or they might be unknowingly tricked into it. More broadly, Apple claims that sideloading would give malicious actors more versatility for how they attack iPhones. In other words, this isn’t simply a matter of user choice, Apple says, because it would affect all iPhone users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iENdSf"&gt;Finally, developers could also suffer if sideloading is allowed, according to Apple. The company claims users are more likely to try out new apps from smaller developers if they come from a trusted source, and that allowing users to get apps from anywhere could harm this trust and cause them to spend less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVWvkL"&gt;Alongside its report, Apple is also lobbying lawmakers directly. Yesterday, the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/22/technology/amazon-apple-google-facebook-antitrust-bills.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22546286/apple-tim-cook-nancy-pelosi-google-amazon-facebook-antitrust-lobbying"&gt;Tim Cook called Speaker Nancy Pelosi&lt;/a&gt; to express his concerns about the antitrust bills. Today, Cook is scheduled to have a virtual meeting with the EU’s competition head Margrethe Vestager, according to her &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/commissioners/2019-2024/calendar_en?field_editorial_section_multiple_tid=462&amp;amp;date_filter_min%5Bvalue%5D%5Bdate%5D=22/06/2021"&gt;official schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R8ZEbG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="onyKCM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22546771/apple-side-loading-security-risk-report-regulatory-pressure"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22546771/apple-side-loading-security-risk-report-regulatory-pressure</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
