<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-15T18:31:29-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T18:31:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T18:31:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is blocking Apple Silicon Mac users from sideloading iPhone apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A screenshot with an error message saying “Unable to install ‘PS App’ Please try again later”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J-lRiTcoTbR5HI1lAsiVDeaN5Bs=/0x0:803x535/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68676278/Screen_Shot_2021_01_15_at_2.19.03_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The error message in macOS 11.1.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: Jay Peters&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dCRz7v"&gt;Apple has turned off users’ ability to unofficially install iOS apps onto their M1 Macs (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/01/15/apple-blocks-m1-mac-iphone-app-side-loading/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). While iOS apps are still available in the Mac App Store, many apps, such as Dark Sky and Netflix, don’t have their developer’s approval to be run on macOS. Up until now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21574207/how-to-install-run-any-iphone-ipad-app-m1-mac"&gt;there was a workaround&lt;/a&gt; that allowed the use of third-party software to install the apps without having to use the Mac App Store, but it seems like Apple has remotely disabled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bqtcld"&gt;When we tried to install an unsupported app on an M1 Mac running macOS 11.1, we got an error message saying that we couldn’t install it and should “try again later”. You can see a screenshot at the top of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xrOykf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Mac users have been used to having more freedom in what programs they’re able to run&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tnodcf"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;, the message on the most recent macOS 11.2 beta is more specific: “the application cannot be installed because the developer did not intend for it to run on this platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dPy6vy"&gt;Apple moving to block the unauthorized app installs isn’t necessarily surprising. &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/01/13/macos-beta-code-suggests-apple-will-block-users-from-sideloading-unsupported-ios-apps-on-m1-macs/"&gt;Code was found in the beta&lt;/a&gt; indicating a ban would be coming, and Apple has given developers power to block their apps from running on the Mac — a power that is undermined by sideloading. It is, however, sad to see the feature go, as Mac users have been used to having &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167964/cydia-sues-apple-monopoly-anticompetitive-iphone"&gt;more freedom in what programs they’re able to run&lt;/a&gt; than they do on iOS (though Apple’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.intego.com%2Fmac-security-blog%2Fwhat-are-all-those-macos-catalina-security-alerts%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F15%2F22233754%2Fapple-blocking-m1-iphone-app-sideloading#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;control on the Mac has been tightening over the years&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhcXOw"&gt;We were able to run an app that we had already installed, but Apple is clearly cracking down on this behavior, so there's no guarantees that our already-sideloaded apps will work in the future either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="QTkYc6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple MacBook Air with M1 review: new chip, no problem","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"},{"title":"11 great apps ready for your new 2020 M1 Mac","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22188814/apple-apps-m1-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-lightroom-office-2020"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233754/apple-blocking-m1-iphone-app-sideloading"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233754/apple-blocking-m1-iphone-app-sideloading</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T17:13:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T17:13:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is reportedly prototyping foldable iPhone screens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HwkeUq48UTT1T633jq3bPiSLRco=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68675881/vpavic_4243_20201018_0154.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4esEx0"&gt;Apple has started work on a foldable phone, and it’s begun prototyping foldable screens internally, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-15/apple-considers-foldable-iphone-minor-changes-planned-for-2021-models"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A final device is likely still years away, the report says, and Apple is working on just the display for now — not the rest of the phone it would attach to&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrPm9a"&gt;The initial prototypes sound similar to the foldable screens we’ve seen used by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536546/motorola-razr-2020-review-5g-folding-flip"&gt;Motorola&lt;/a&gt;, and others. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; says Apple is looking at making foldable screens with a “mostly invisible hinge” that could unfold to around the size of the iPhone 12 Pro Max. The report says that several screen sizes are being discussed, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9z7JXa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Under-display Touch ID is reportedly still in testing for 2021&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HSC7fl"&gt;Apple hasn’t publicly indicated any interest in making a foldable phone, though the company rarely signals its interest before entering a new product category. Major competitors have a head start on foldable devices, with Samsung and Motorola already releasing multiple generations of folding phones. Samsung’s Galaxy Fold came out in April 2019 (albeit, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18498904/samsung-galaxy-fold-review-screen-broken-issue-durability-foldable-phone-video-performance-price"&gt;with some substantial issues&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q61LiJ"&gt;On a more immediate note, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;has some updates on Apple products coming in 2021. This year’s iPhone is expected to have “minor upgrades,” but one more substantial improvement is still a possibility: an in-screen fingerprint sensor. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;already said &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-09-05/apple-working-on-in-display-fingerprint-id-for-future-iphones"&gt;back in 2019&lt;/a&gt; that Apple was looking into the feature for as early as 2020, and it’d be an obvious addition in 2021 since the wide adoption of face masks has seriously hindered the ability to use Face ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PvPtBM"&gt;It’s not clear how likely in-display Touch ID is to ship in 2021 (Apple tends to have iPhone features locked well in advance of production), but &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;says Apple is “still testing” the tech for inclusion this year. On a worse note, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;also says that Apple has discussed removing the Lightning port in favor of wireless charging on “some” iPhone models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVN73K"&gt;Apple’s long-rumored Tile competitor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/20/20875341/apple-tags-location-rumor-roundup"&gt;AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, are finally planned to launch this year, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports, and the iPad Pro could be refreshed with a Mini LED display. A thinner entry-level iPad is reportedly in the works as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233644/foldable-iphone-apple-screens-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233644/foldable-iphone-apple-screens-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T15:47:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T15:47:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple doesn’t make a MagSafe car charger — here are your options</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2YypLOutr2SHxGrv2FW75FTcd5Y=/337x0:1537x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68675287/belkin_wic002_magnetic_vent_cable_management_product_page_v01_r01_1680x600_us.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Belkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XkfDkH"&gt;Getting a MagSafe car charger for your iPhone seems like a simple process, but the current landscape is one of trade-offs: there are no all-in-one solutions that will wirelessly hold and charge your phone &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; are MagSafe certified to provide up to 15W of power. However, manufactures have been finding workarounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="agS2QL"&gt;First, there’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fp%2FP-WIC002%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F15%2F22231718%2Fmagsafe-car-chargers-apple-iphone-certification-process#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Belkin’s Car Vent Mount Pro&lt;/a&gt;, which is the only MagSafe Certified car mount, and it sells for $39.99. Being certified doesn’t mean it provides power, though. You’ll have to plug your phone in with a Lightning cable (which you’d have to do anyway for wired CarPlay compatibility). This does technically let you charge your phone faster than regular wireless charging, but it leaves you messing around with a cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8tH9D"&gt;Then there’s &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/01/14/scosche-magsafe-magicmount-series-brings-magsafe-charging-to-your-car"&gt;the Scosche MagicMount&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a 20W car adapter but nothing to plug into it. You have to provide your own MagSafe puck, which adds $39 to the MagicMount’s $29.99 to $39.99 price tag (which varies by model). While it does technically get you MagSafe-certified mounting and charging, that’s only because you’re using Apple’s own puck. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1A3jkGPVnNX0cQqFQinjlAXv-6c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22238391/Screen_Shot_2021_01_15_at_10.16.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re fine with just using an official MagSafe puck, you will be spoiled for choice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CfxoE7"&gt;Just providing the plastic to put around Apple’s charger is a common approach. Amazon is full of the BYOP (bring your own puck) car mounts, and we’ve &lt;a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/3300477/elago-w3-macintosh-apple-watch-charging-stand-sale-on-amazon.html"&gt;also seen it with Apple Watch charger accessories&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a quick and easy way to get users the fully certified experience without having to wait for certification (and without Apple’s Made For iPhone program fees). The downside is that users have to buy two different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Eh2PCV"&gt;Finally, there’s &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/20/12/26/review-esr-halolock-is-everything-a-magsafe-car-charger-should-be"&gt;the ESR HaloLock&lt;/a&gt;, which seems to have it all. It’s one piece, magnetically holds your iPhone, and provides wireless charging. The only thing missing is MagSafe certification, meaning Apple will only let your phone charge at 7.5W. You’ll again see a lot of similar products on Amazon, where the manufacturer has copied MagSafe’s magnets but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215639/anker-magsafe-qi-charger-apple-alternative-giant-usb-c-plug-explained"&gt;used a standard Qi charger for power&lt;/a&gt;. Like the puck holders, you’ll get most of the functionality without actually having to be certified, and the product will be fine for people who aren’t worried about fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cV4d0"&gt;This isn’t to say that third-party, fully certified MagSafe car mounts won’t show up at some point, just that it may take a little while. And given the other routes get you pretty close to the real deal, you can expect to see a lot of those in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7YyJJx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Peak Design takes on MagSafe with its own compatible magnetic mounts","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/19/21522620/peak-design-mobile-phone-case-bike-car-mount-tripod-hands-on-kickstarter"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231718/magsafe-car-chargers-apple-iphone-certification-process"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231718/magsafe-car-chargers-apple-iphone-certification-process</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T14:50:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T14:50:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is again extending TV Plus trials to July</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/me2uysfcLPyuog6TRPxQGfc2-eM=/128x0:1505x918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68674914/Apple_introduces_apple_tv_plus_03252019_big.jpg.large_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oOgrkB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/01/15/apple-again-extends-apple-tv-free-trials-subscribers-now-get-free-access-until-july-2021/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Apple will be extending its free year-long trials of its TV Plus service to customers until July 2021. The trials were originally included with the purchase of any Apple device (e.g., an iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple TV) and were initially set to last until November 1st, 2020. This is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21508148/apple-tv-plus-free-period-extended-february-2021-streaming"&gt;the second extension&lt;/a&gt;, with the first extending from November 2020 to February 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWCt0Q"&gt;Subscribers who had free subscriptions that were set to expire any time from February 2021 to June 2021 will also get an extension until July. The extension comes in the wake of production delays. Only one of the shows the service launched with (&lt;em&gt;Dickinson&lt;/em&gt;) has had its second season premiere, while others — like &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;See&lt;/em&gt; — are still waiting for their second seasons to come out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zB2ZgV"&gt;Show productions being delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic is no surprise, and extending the trial is a nice gesture. Viewers probably would like to start watching the second seasons of their favorite shows before they decide whether the service is worth $4.99 a month, and the extension is giving them the ability to do so. After all, there’s not a ton of use in a TV subscription service if some shows only have 12 episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233276/apple-free-tv-plus-service-trials-extended"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233276/apple-free-tv-plus-service-trials-extended</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T13:47:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T13:47:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly planning big iMac redesign and half-sized Mac Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The 2020 27-inch iMac" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4NLbopL1lUnciLfhthZSqzZUmWg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68674516/DSC01539.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZlSMVl"&gt;In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;revamped MacBook Pros that ditch the Touch Bar and resurrect MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;, Apple is also said to be planning to announce its long-awaited iMac redesign this year — and a pair of Mac Pro refreshes are on the roadmap, too. This is all according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-15/apple-plans-redesigned-imac-new-mac-pro-smaller-mac-pro-cheaper-monitor?sref=9hGJlFio"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’s&lt;/em&gt; Mark Gurman&lt;/a&gt;, who says the iMac will undergo its most significant overhaul since 2012: Apple will reportedly ditch the chin beneath the screen, cut down on display bezels, and move to a flat-back design. The overall appearance will likely resemble the Pro Display XDR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rT5Uv7"&gt;The new iMac will replace the Intel-powered 27-inch and 21.5-inch versions currently available and move the all-in-one desktop to Apple silicon. It’ll be one of the most significant visual makeovers of any Apple product this year, according to the report. The existing iMac packs top-tier specs and a beautiful screen into a design that has felt particularly outdated these last couple of years, so this change will be welcome. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356416/apple-imac-27-2020-review-price-specs-features"&gt;The last revision&lt;/a&gt; focused on increased speed, an improved webcam, and also added an option for a matte / nano-texture display coating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hFnZ6"&gt;As for the Mac Pro, Apple seems to have a two-prong plan: it’ll refresh the current upgradeable tower design — Gurman says the company is considering sticking with Intel processors for this machine. But that doesn’t mean Apple is stalling on a Mac Pro that runs on its own chips. The company is also apparently at work on a completely new form factor that Gurman says is less than half the total size of the current Mac Pro. “The design will feature a mostly aluminum exterior and could invoke nostalgia for the Power Mac G4 Cube,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqzZRq"&gt;All of these will feature the next generation of Apple’s own Mac processors, which first debuted in last year’s M1 MacBook Air, MacBook Pro, and Mac mini. Last, Apple is reportedly planning to release a new external monitor that gives up some of the professional-grade display specifications of the Pro Display XDR to reach a wider audience of customers. The Pro Display XDR starts at $5,000, and Apple currently sells third-party monitors from LG as a  more affordable step-down option. But it sounds like a spiritual successor to the Thunderbolt Display could be on the way in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233191/apple-silicon-redesigned-imac-mac-pro-rumor-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233191/apple-silicon-redesigned-imac-mac-pro-rumor-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to cancel your account at Netflix, Amazon Prime, and others</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple TV Hulu Plus" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0LAoTontXny1CbzxU3RJXUwAY0Y=/0x0:1020x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68672182/IMG_9379.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jcHElm"&gt;Let’s face it: some of us are so busy these days — what with pandemics and presidential elections and attempted overthrows of the government — that we don’t pay enough attention to what we are subscribed to (and paying for). Especially now, when there are more and more streaming services vying for our attention, it’s easy to go for a trial subscription, or to decide that you’re going to subscribe “just for a couple of months,” and then completely forget about it. Meanwhile, your charge card is being pinged every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YsPHRR"&gt;For example, Matthew Inman, the artist who creates the comics site &lt;a href="https://theoatmeal.com/"&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/a&gt;, recently reported (to his apparent chagrin), that he had been paying for Netflix’s DVD subscription for the last 13 years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="luVyPd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today Netflix was kind enough to let me know that  I've accidentally been paying for a DVD subscription for THIRTEEN FUCKING YEARS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I have been renting imaginary DVDs since &lt;br&gt;George Bush was president.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The lesson here: keep an eye on your subscriptions. And vote Obama 2008. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iNtpuKzkdD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iNtpuKzkdD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— The Oatmeal (@Oatmeal) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Oatmeal/status/1349076285880819714?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rmTfhs"&gt;(For our younger readers: yes, Netflix started out as a DVD rental service and then segued to the streaming service it is today.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T255hD"&gt;So it may be a good idea, especially if your income is a little tight, to check your current streaming subscriptions and drop the ones that you haven’t used for several months. (After all, unless you’re grandfathered into an especially good deal — and that’s happening less and less these days — you can always re-up again if there’s something on the service you want to watch.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCmqvI"&gt;One thing to be aware of: during the process of canceling a streaming service, you may need to go through several pages or pop-ups urging you to not cancel or to at least settle for a less expensive (and usually less feature-filled) version of the service. In fact, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55637140"&gt;according to the BBC&lt;/a&gt;, several lawsuits by such organizations as The Norwegian Consumer Council and Public Citizen in the US are claiming that Amazon Prime’s canceling process &lt;a href="https://fil.forbrukerradet.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2021-01-14-you-can-log-out-but-you-can-never-leave-final.pdf"&gt;manipulates consumers into keeping their subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;. So be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VoLr9T"&gt;Here’s where you can go to cancel some of the more popular streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lwjUqE"&gt;Netflix&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Netflix logo" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5hbwCRavkGxvN1FD3H8EZ1AvimA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets/755523/netflix-logo-705px.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sx7uOC"&gt;You can find your current subscription status at Netflix by clicking on your personal icon on the top-right corner and &lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com/YourAccount"&gt;choosing “Account.”&lt;/a&gt; The second section down should be “Plan Details,” and you’ll not only be able to change your plan, but you’ll immediately see if you have a live DVD plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="53wLvq"&gt;If you want to leave the service completely, there is a “Cancel Membership” button to the left in the “Membership &amp;amp; Billing” section.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9dZwQI"&gt;Amazon Prime&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7oUIfS7zhlNKY0wsyu1-yML49P0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233388/Prime_0.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XuoS2n"&gt;If you’re a month-to-month member of Amazon Prime and decide you want to cancel, you can go to this page and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_left_v4_sib?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;nodeId=201910380&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;click on the “End Membership” button&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ohwkqg"&gt;If, on the other hand, you’ve paid for an annual membership, you can only cancel within three days of signing up. You can also cancel that paid annual membership if you’ve just converted from a free trial or “if you and your account did not make any eligible purchases or take advantage of Prime benefits since your latest Prime membership charge” (in other words, if you’ve never used any of your Prime benefits since you paid for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAg6OG"&gt;If you want to completely close your Amazon account &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; delete all of your data, you can go &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/privacy/data-deletion?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GBa63i"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BmuPy5Z2FZqt75qJPQ422GM_OPg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233417/HBO_Max_Press_On_White_Horiz_300dpi_0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: HBO&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="W1o4c8"&gt;HBO Max can be subscribed to either by itself, or through a number of different providers, such as the Apple App Store, Google Play, Roku, and a bunch of others. The best way to find out how to drop the service is to go to HBO’s &lt;a href="https://help.hbomax.com/Answer/Detail/2334"&gt;help page on canceling your subscription or trial&lt;/a&gt; and clicking on the appropriate link for directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="twhHFa"&gt;According to HBO, you should try to cancel one or two days before your billing cycle renews, and if you cancel mid-month, you will still have access to HBO Max until the month is up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5GdnwM"&gt;Apple TV Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GsdiTYeTe2jHpMVh0DlhWOaRtDY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15985971/Apple_introduces_apple_tv_plus_03252019_big.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mufJxC"&gt;As with HBO Max, your Apple TV Plus subscription will be useable until the end of the billing cycle, even after you cancel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3o7IZ"&gt;Instructions for canceling your Apple subscriptions &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202039"&gt;can be found here&lt;/a&gt;. In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="95HoHH"&gt;To cancel on your Mac, go to the App Store, click your name (at the bottom of the page) and then “View Information” (at the top). Go to “Subscriptions” &amp;gt; “Manage.” Click on “Edit” next to the subscription you want to cancel and select “Cancel Subscription.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PWkYfG"&gt;On an iPhone or iPad, go to “Settings,” select your name, then “Subscriptions.” Select the subscription you want to leave, and Tap on Cancel Subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JfdY9N"&gt;Hulu&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TQaMvXMCCjH7-ridKyC3od2ac2g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233427/Screen_Shot_2021_01_13_at_2.52.19_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hulu&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1ypKXj"&gt;Like Apple TV Plus and HBO Max, your canceled subscription will last until the end of your billing cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a2cKxA"&gt;Hulu offers &lt;a href="https://help.hulu.com/s/article/cancel-hulu-subscription?language=en_US"&gt;instructions on how to cancel here&lt;/a&gt;. Since, like HBO Max, there’s a good chance you’ve signed up through a third party such as Amazon, Verizon, or Sprint, there are several links on the page where you can get specific instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OqzcDf"&gt;YouTube TV&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/COfUCxET7zyumttSE81Rhqm55h8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233437/yt_tv_full_rgb_black_copy.max_2800x2800.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: YouTube&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zpNbg7"&gt;Interestingly, you can either cancel or pause your YouTube TV subscription (&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtubetv/answer/7129668"&gt;links for either process are on the same page&lt;/a&gt;). Pausing is a good option if for some reason (a vacation, a work project, temporary financial difficulties) you don’t want to use the subscription for anywhere from four weeks to six months. You won’t be able to use the service during that time to watch or record, but your already-recorded content will be saved. Once the pause is over (either via a pre-selected date or if you manually end the pause period), your billing will recommence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RtTO6J"&gt;If you want to leave YouTube TV entirely, select “Cancel Now” on that same page. You will still have service until the end of your payment period; after that, you’ll have another 21 days to view the recorded programs in your library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CmT6VJ"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="disney+" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mXvQjzF9LVi8uyKQpglhwA7KFZ8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13412121/disneyplus.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2tFAqP"&gt;To cancel your Disney Plus subscription on the website, go to your profile icon in the upper-right corner, and then click on “Account.” Find your subscription level under the subhead “Subscription,” click on that, and then scroll down to where it says “Cancel Subscription.” As with most other services, you will still have access to Disney Plus until the end of your billing cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oVf6oh"&gt;Note that canceling Disney Plus TV does not cancel your general Disney account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vrUI9Z"&gt;ESPN Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w1-ZlWtg6ANQSl4BI5OPkfCSS90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233680/ESPN_PLUS_FC_NEG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: ESPN Plus&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KSWxJH"&gt;ESPN Plus is another one of those services that is available via a number of third-party sources, such as Roku, Amazon, Apple Pay, and iTunes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h9OSuP"&gt;If you subscribed directly via the web and want to cancel your subscription, log in, select “Manage” &amp;gt; “Cancel Subscription.” Otherwise, if you subscribed through one of the services mentioned above, your best bet is to &lt;a href="https://help.espnplus.com/espnplus_hc?id=espnplus_article_content&amp;amp;sys_kb_id=f6dcac54dbb79498534deadc139619c5"&gt;go to this page&lt;/a&gt;, which links to all of the ways it’s possible to cancel, depending on how you originally subscribed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3KWm0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ze7SrE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22227476/cancel-netflix-apple-plus-amazon-prime-hbo-max-how-to-streaming-subscriptions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22227476/cancel-netflix-apple-plus-amazon-prime-hbo-max-how-to-streaming-subscriptions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T07:59:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T07:59:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Intel has to be better than ‘lifestyle company’ Apple at making CPUs, says new CEO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BEgGbV08ddIMYpC4zYwvsn8dlPY=/57x0:1992x1290/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68672176/intellogo.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="znkclz"&gt;Intel’s new CEO, Pat Gelsinger, doesn’t start his new role until February, but he’s already prepping the company to take on Apple’s M1 chips. &lt;em&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/em&gt;, a local newspaper in Oregon where Intel maintains a large presence, &lt;a href="https://www.oregonlive.com/silicon-forest/2021/01/intel-will-wait-for-new-ceo-to-make-critical-decisions-on-manufacturing-crisis.html"&gt;reports that the chip maker&lt;/a&gt; held an all-hands company meeting yesterday, and Gelsinger attended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avnQA2"&gt;“We have to deliver better products to the PC ecosystem than any possible thing that a lifestyle company in Cupertino” makes, Gelsinger reportedly told Intel employees. “We have to be that good, in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3XtsIn"&gt;Intel has been facing increased competition from both Apple and AMD recently. Apple announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21295475/apple-mac-processors-arm-silicon-chips-wwdc-2020"&gt;transition to its own silicon&lt;/a&gt; back in June, calling it a “historic day for the Mac.” The transition has gone well, with M1-based Macs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;providing impressive performance and battery life&lt;/a&gt; compared to existing Intel-based Macs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2vw39M"&gt;While Apple will still use Intel chips for some Macs in the future, the move away from reliance on Intel is significant. It comes just as AMD has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21552336/amd-zen-3-ryzen-review-roundup-5950x-intel-comparison"&gt;taken the performance crown&lt;/a&gt; from Intel in gaming, and pressures its laptop dominance with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225474/amd-ryzen-5000-series-mobile-processors-ces-2021"&gt;new Ryzen 5000 mobile chips&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jkaWTr"&gt;Intel announced earlier this week that current &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228702/intel-ceo-bob-swan-pat-gelsinger-technical-financial"&gt;CEO Bob Swan is stepping down&lt;/a&gt; from the position on February 15th, set to be replaced by VMware CEO Pat Gelsinger. This marks a return to Intel for Gelsinger, who previously worked at the chip maker for 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z8Pxaz-BEMp1KC5irsrV-gT0ABM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22237510/intel.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Intel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Intel manufacturing facility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="I5psXn"&gt;Gelsinger now faces the reality of competing with Apple, AMD, and others after Intel has struggled to transition to a 10nm manufacturing process for years. Intel has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/23/21336356/intel-7nm-chips-next-gen-delay-q2-2020-earnings-amd-10nm-tiger-lake-desktop-laptop-cpu"&gt;delayed its 7nm chips&lt;/a&gt; until at least 2022, and the company now faces a tough decision whether to outsource chip fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCtzuO"&gt;That’s a decision that Intel had scheduled to make next week, but &lt;em&gt;The Oregonian &lt;/em&gt;reports it could be delayed to give Gelsinger time to weigh in on the choice. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-08/intel-talks-with-tsmc-samsung-to-outsource-some-chip-production"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt; recently reported&lt;/a&gt; that Intel has been in talks with both TSMC and Samsung to outsource some chip production. Market research firm &lt;a href="https://www.trendforce.com/presscenter/news/20210113-10651.html"&gt;TrendForce claims&lt;/a&gt; around 20 percent of Intel’s non-CPU chips will now be outsourced to both TSMC and UMC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKYbE0"&gt;Analysts argue that outsourcing its own CPU production would allow Intel to be more flexible and focus on its designs to recover from the 10nm issues it has experienced. Apple, AMD, Qualcomm, MediaTek, and other Intel competitors are already using TSMC for chip production.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232554/intel-ceo-apple-lifestyle-company-cpus-comment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232554/intel-ceo-apple-lifestyle-company-cpus-comment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-15T01:43:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T01:43:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>2021 MacBook Pro will ditch the Touch Bar and bring back MagSafe, say reports</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/578LDvIoamqsoVtOTsZuIoUSoFc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68671647/akramer_201113_4290_0007.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alexander Kramer for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="43m1v7"&gt;Apple is planning a major MacBook Pro redesign for the third quarter of 2021, according to a research note written by TF International Securities analyst Ming-chi Kuo and reported on by &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/01/15/new-macbook-pro-models-magsafe-ports/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/01/14/kuo-details-2021-macbook-pro-new-design-with-squared-off-sides-magsafe-connector-and-io-return-touch-bar-removed/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/01/15/kuo-two-redesigned-macbook-pro-models-with-magsafe-no-touch-bar-coming-in-q3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kuo calls it the first major redesign of the MacBook Pro since the introduction of the current generation in 2016. Bloomberg’s Mark Gurman has followed up with a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-15/apple-macbook-pros-with-magsafe-return-in-the-works"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; corroborating many of the same details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qyoot7"&gt;The new MacBook Pro is said to have squared-off sides like the iPad Pro and the iPhone 12; the current laptop already has sharp edges, but it sounds like the top and bottom panels are going to be flatter than before as well. The new model will reportedly come in 14-inch and 16-inch sizes both featuring Apple-designed Arm processors, with no Intel options. Kuo says the laptops will use a similar heat pipe system to the current 16-inch MacBook Pro, giving more thermal headroom and enabling higher performance. Bloomberg reports that the new models will have “brighter, higher contrast” displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z8rkiH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;New story: For new high-end 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros, Apple indeed plans return of MagSafe, the end of the Touch Bar (finally), brighter screens, minor design changes, next-gen M-series chips and more. Launch around mid-2021. &lt;a href="https://t.co/eL3r06oexW"&gt;https://t.co/eL3r06oexW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mark Gurman (@markgurman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1349973715623178241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qi5ZQg"&gt;Perhaps most notably, Kuo believes the new Pro laptops will backtrack on some of the controversial changes Apple made with the current generation. The OLED Touch Bar, for example, is said to have been replaced altogether by physical function keys. Kuo also says that there’ll be a wider range of ports reducing the need for dongles, though he doesn’t get specific. And a MagSafe magnetic charging connector is also set to return. (It’s not clear whether it’ll have anything in common with the new MagSafe accessory system for the iPhone 12.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K8jpjj"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;new 13-inch MacBook Pro with Apple’s M1 processor&lt;/a&gt; was just released in November, but that model otherwise had near-identical hardware to the existing Intel version. If Kuo is to be believed — and his track record suggests that he is — the next models could be a huge improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TbPjpx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, Jan 15th, 2.45PM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added mention of Bloomberg’s subsequent report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T07:26:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T07:26:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>BMW’s Digital Key Plus will let iPhones unlock the iX from a pocket or bag</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aK_LSvSPVvGtpA6JaqPXSSuCvEI=/291x0:4071x2520/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68666289/P90411221_highRes.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMW’s all-electric iX will be first to support the Digital Key Plus feature.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: BMW&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZYx0y1"&gt;BMW has announced an upgraded version of its mobile car key technology dubbed &lt;a href="https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0324128EN/bmw-announces-bmw-digital-key-plus-with-ultra-wideband-technology-coming-to-the-bmw-ix"&gt;Digital Key Plus&lt;/a&gt;. It promises to allow iPhone owners to unlock select BMW cars without having to take out their phones. The feature relies on ultra wideband (UWB) which has been included in Apple’s flagship iPhones since the iPhone 11 thanks to the U1 chip. Digital Key Plus will debut on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21558833/bmw-ix-inext-electric-suv-range-price-specs"&gt;all-electric BMW iX&lt;/a&gt; which launches later this year in Europe and next year in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3xYGGm"&gt;The big benefit of Digital Key Plus, according to BMW, is that it uses UWB so it works with an iPhone that’s still in your pocket or bag. In contrast, the current Digital Key system used by Apple and BMW is NFC based, so you have to hold an iPhone (or Apple Watch) near the car’s tag to unlock it. BMW also emphasizes the security of its new UWB approach, noting that it’s resistant to relay attacks that might try and jam or intercept its signal and offers “the greatest possible security.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OXUmYC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;BMW claims ultra wideband offers “the greatest possible security”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YTWZPC"&gt;At present, only a limited number of iPhones include the U1 chip that offers UWB support. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/10/20859550/apple-iphone-11-pro-airdrop-u1-locator-chip-tag-tile-bluetooth-tracking"&gt;debuted in the iPhone 11&lt;/a&gt; and was later included in the iPhone 12, but was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21222731/apple-iphone-se-u1-locator-chip-wifi-6-express-cards"&gt;missing from the budget iPhone SE 2020&lt;/a&gt; that released early last year. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/9/15/21438497/apple-watch-series-6-u1-locator-ultra-wideband-location"&gt;U1 chip was also included&lt;/a&gt; on the Apple Watch Series 6, released last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fFrQ8D"&gt;Apple built support for digital car keys into iOS with &lt;a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/apple_releases_ios_136_with_digital_car_keys_and_new_health_features-news-44287.php"&gt;version 13.6 last year&lt;/a&gt;, following its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21299182/apple-carkey-ios-14-13-digital-key-unlock-car-iphone-wwdc-2020"&gt;announcement at WWDC 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/01/13/bmw-digital-key-plus-ultra-wideband/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that BMW is currently the only car manufacturer to use the technology, though &lt;a href="http://www.businesskorea.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=58446"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Korea&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Hyundai has plans to adopt the feature later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwcCBT"&gt;There’s a push to make UWB a standard for digital keys. When it announced support for digital car keys in June last year, Apple said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21299182/apple-carkey-ios-14-13-digital-key-unlock-car-iphone-wwdc-2020#dfYYdo:~:text=Apple%20says%20it%E2%80%99s%20working%20on%20an,instead%20of%20relying%20solely%20on%20NFC."&gt;working on an industry-wide standard&lt;/a&gt; that would use its U1 chip. In today’s announcement, BMW says it’s working with Apple and the Car Connectivity Consortium to build UWB support into version 3.0 of the Digital Key specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C7WBK0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgrCUA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230569/bmw-digital-key-plus-iphone-unlock-u1-chip-ultra-wideband"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230569/bmw-digital-key-plus-iphone-unlock-u1-chip-ultra-wideband</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:28:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:28:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm just bought a two-year-old startup founded by former Apple engineers for $1.4 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ByI-VZRgXa3MpWsXI_iXNs_238k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663783/acastro_180529_1777_qualcomm_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iMaorN"&gt;Qualcomm has just made a &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2021/01/13/qualcomm-acquire-nuvia?mkt_tok=eyJpIjoiWm1RMk1qazFOV0ZqT1dWaCIsInQiOiJpdWM0WjJIUitvMlgxOHNvS1Y2WWY3VXBBQ2xZY0lSd1I1eXNRdVpIRVJNcXlEd2d1QlZKcUljMHl4WnhDYmgrRWhcL3Irc3VFTEo3M3lLUDVQUHQzZUdaS3BtTUZlTitXMTB5bEFhdXZoRWlieGZ4d3QwM2lVS1FoNDVyYWVSOU8ifQ%3D%3D"&gt;splashy acquisition&lt;/a&gt; in the chip market that’s sure to shake up the semiconductor industry in substantial fashion. The company Qualcomm is purchasing, Nuvia, was formed in 2019 by three former engineers and chip specialists, all of whom &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/15/three-of-apple-and-googles-former-star-chip-designers-launch-nuvia-with-53m-in-series-a-funding/"&gt;worked at Apple on the A-series chip line that powers the iPhone and iPad&lt;/a&gt;. And now, Qualcomm is paying an eye-popping $1.4 billion for the firm, placing a huge bet on the team’s talent and its focus on building next-generation CPUs for use in data centers, mobile, and other devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdD4RT"&gt;Qualcomm is specifically calling out the growth of 5G as one of the reasons it’s paying such a handsome sum for a company of just a couple hundred employees founded only two years ago. “5G is further accelerating the convergence of mobility and computing. The acquisition of Nuvia builds on Qualcomm Technologies’ Snapdragon technology leadership, delivering step-function improvements in CPU performance and power efficiency to meet the demands of next-generation 5G computing,” Qualcomm said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IMpB2x"&gt;All three of the company’s co-founders — Gerard Williams, Manu Gulati, and John Bruno — will be joining Qualcomm, which expects to integrate the company’s chips “across Qualcomm Technologies’ broad portfolio of products,” including the components that make their way into data centers, smartphones, laptops, vehicles, and other devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p7npXr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nuvia is just two years old, but Qualcomm is paying $1.4 billion to acquire its technology&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M5vI10"&gt;“CPU performance leadership will be critical in defining and delivering on the next era of computing innovation,” Nuvia CEO Gerard Williams, formerly chief CPU architect at Apple, said in a statement. “The combination of Nuvia and Qualcomm will bring the industry’s best engineering talent, technology and resources together to create a new class of high-performance computing platforms that set the bar for our industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="twDKSg"&gt;Qualcomm is collecting tech and talent and taking aim at the data center industry at a time of significant change in the chip market. Many companies that once used to rely on big-name chipmakers like AMD, Intel, and Qualcomm have spent much of the last decade building out their own internal chip design teams to lessen their reliance on third-party companies and to better integrate their hardware and software. This is true not just of Apple, at which Nuvia’s co-founders gained their expertise, but also Amazon, Google, Facebook, and others, too. (Nuvia’s other two co-founders worked on chip design at Google, too.) All of these companies are building their own chips for use in everything from data centers to smart speakers and everything in between, often licensing the Arm architecture to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZcE2Q"&gt;That’s put Qualcomm at odds with companies it used to consider core partners. Apple and Qualcomm, in fact, engaged in a bitter multiyear patent infringement legal battle the two companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/16/18410985/apple-qualcomm-settle-royalty-dispute-patent-licensing-terms-high-fees"&gt;settled in 2019,&lt;/a&gt; but the message was clear: Apple was tired of paying other companies to license their tech and would rather go it alone using Arm-based designs. That was only further cemented by Apple’s landmark decision to drop Intel in the CPU field for Apple’s own custom-designed line of M1 processors, which arrived on the scene last fall powering the first of many new Apple computers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;critical acclaim thanks to their huge performance gains&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lWPZV7"&gt;While Apple and Qualcomm cut a deal for the iPhone maker to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18525962/qualcomm-apple-settlement-4-5-billion-dollars-patent"&gt;continue using Qualcomm’s modems&lt;/a&gt;, including its 5G ones that enable the network capabilities on the latest iPhones, Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168779/apple-leak-cellular-modem-johny-srouji-town-hall"&gt;reportedly hard at work on building its own cellular modems&lt;/a&gt; to further extricate itself from Qualcomm in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="auSOKt"&gt;And that’s where a company like Nuvia comes in. While many companies are building their own Arm-based CPUs to compete with AMD and Intel in the data center — like &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/15578/cloud-clash-amazon-graviton2-arm-against-intel-and-amd"&gt;Amazon’s Graviton chip&lt;/a&gt; — Nuvia is &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/09/24/nuvia-raises-240-million-to-design-arm-based-cpus-for-datacenters/"&gt;reportedly building a more flexible custom chip core&lt;/a&gt; (also based on Arm) called Phoenix. That chip core could result in a variety of different CPUs down the line, not just those designed to act as data center processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWkUEz"&gt;“We’re designing our own core from the ground up,” Williams &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/09/24/nuvia-raises-240-million-to-design-arm-based-cpus-for-datacenters/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;VentureBeat &lt;/em&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, when the company raised $240 million in a Series B funding round. “Our secret sauce is really physical design capabilities and microarchitecture. And that’s where you see the differentiation coming into play for almost anybody that builds a processor.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAsNbS"&gt;Williams said at the time that the speed and efficiency of its chip core was “very much like a mobile core in terms of size and power,” but with with “substantially higher” performance, a prescient statement to make considering Qualcomm’s plans to use Nuvia technology in its mobile Snapdragon system-on-a-chip line. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229497/qualcomm-apple-nuvia-acquisition-cpu-chip-design-data-center"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229497/qualcomm-apple-nuvia-acquisition-cpu-chip-design-data-center</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
