<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-09T16:01:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T16:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T16:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple may have accidentally confirmed the existence of an M1X MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TQZIHF05TX0m46MhjejfbxYvORg=/0x1:1020x681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69429868/retina-macbook-pro-15-stock_1020.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not the new MacBook Pro, but it does have ports that are tipped to return!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GWELYT"&gt;Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference keynote came and went this year without a new MacBook Pro — but it looks like that wasn’t the original intent! Intriguingly, Apple quietly included the phrases “M1X MacBook Pro” and “M1X” as tags &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TD96VTf0Xs"&gt;on its YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; of the live keynote, as spotted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maxbalzer_/status/1402626084265500679"&gt;by Max Balzer&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/09/m1x-macbook-pro-referenced-in-metadata-for-apples-wwdc-youtube-video/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cl9C5u"&gt;Not only does that sound like tacit confirmation of at least one new Arm-powered MacBook Pro, it also corroborates the rumors that it’ll include a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;M1 chip&lt;/a&gt;, and that Apple will likely market it as an enhanced “X” variant, like it used to do with its high-end iPads, rather than going straight to M2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtQeP6"&gt;Three weeks ago, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/apple-readies-macbook-pro-macbook-air-revamps-with-faster-chips?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman reported&lt;/a&gt; that we’d see redesigned 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros “as early as this summer,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;ones that would&lt;/a&gt; bring back the SD card slot, HDMI port, and some form of the beloved trip-friendly MagSafe charging connector; offer twice as many high-performance CPU and GPU cores; and support up to 64GB of RAM. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;I really thought&lt;/a&gt; announcing them at WWDC would be the perfect way to distract from recent developer turmoil — you know, by announcing a MacBook Pro that’s actually for pros? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IqEEJD"&gt;Perhaps that was the original idea, but we got an absolutely jam-packed keynote filled with rapid-fire software announcements instead. Check out our supercut below for the condensed video version, or read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;our list of the 15 biggest WWDC 2021 announcements&lt;/a&gt; if you only want the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6ptwKW"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="WWDC 2021|102453" data-volume-uuid="7c6d9d097" data-volume-id="102453" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-419" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hcpC2U"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEXRxX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T15:40:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T15:40:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The MacBook Air is the most impressive laptop I’ve used in years" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Air (late-2020).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p1z5Ah"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including some equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;We’ll run through discounts currently available for the latest MacBook models as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — all of which will be compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; upon its release in the fall — and we’ll also highlight those when we find them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1022323/7613?sharedid=VergeBestDealsAppleMacbook042721&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15- to 20-percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which is currently lining up deals ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prime Day&lt;/a&gt;, which takes place on June 21st and 22nd. However, for now, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aqfkV0"&gt;The MacBook Air is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FJU3RG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base configuration of MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and 256GB of SSD and typically sells for $999. Right now, you can get it for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$949 ($50 off) at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. The retail giant also has the 512GB configuration on sale in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5M9XBS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold for $1,149&lt;/a&gt; ($100 off), as does &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RDkNac"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The MacBook Pro comes in more sizes and options than the Air, and it’s more geared toward demanding use cases. The base model is the 13-inch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1-powered variant&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a brighter screen and longer battery life compared to the M1 Air. The M1 MacBook Pro 13 normally starts at $1,299, but the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is on sale for $100 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5N6RSS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738975458064148072#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afDps1"&gt;The upgraded, silver version of the M1-touting MacBook Pro with 8GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LH3F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. The space gray variant, which typically retails for $1,499 alongside the silver model, is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LM1K3/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1742946215000206869#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it to $1,399. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44XxWs"&gt;Of course, you can also buy some older MacBook Pro models, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21256520/apple-13-inch-macbook-pro-2020-review-keyboard-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch mid-2020 model&lt;/a&gt;. The older device features four Thunderbolt ports, Ice Lake processors, a new keyboard, increased RAM, and various storage configurations. Right now, you can save $200 on the 13-inch model at Amazon, which is available in two configurations: a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B0881Z844Y?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10th Gen i7 Intel processor and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; for $1,600 at Amazon, or you can buy one with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B08821TJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB of storage and a 2.0GHz 10th Gen Intel Core i5&lt;/a&gt; processor for $1,800 at Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J3a3Uu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hij1MQ"&gt;If you want a bigger laptop with more horsepower, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro 16&lt;/a&gt; is the top-of-the-line model. Compared to its predecessor, it has a better keyboard, newer processors, and improved speakers. B&amp;amp;H Photo currently has an Intel Core i7 CPU and 512GB of storage configuration in both &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1520434-REG%2Fapple_mvvj2ll_a_16_macbook_pro_late.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1520436-REG%2Fapple_mvvl2ll_a_16_macbook_pro_late.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt; on sale for $2,199 ($200 off). There are other configurations available with more storage and quicker processors, however, not at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zjWXtS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10469149"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the Mac Mini is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. We’ve seen the base model drop to as low as $600, which is its current price at &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/mac-mini-%e2%80%93-apple-m1-chip-8-core-cpu%2c-8-core-gpu-%e2%80%93-8gb-memory-%e2%80%93-256gb-ssd-%e2%80%93%E2%80%94silver.product.100694159.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; right now (coupon applied at checkout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The creator economy is running into the Apple Tax — this startup is fighting back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The name “Fanhouse” on a tie-dye background. The H is shaped like a house." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3b6H9XwVqaUOTS2WG2nxLnA3Sqw=/0x342:2048x1707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69429382/EvRNO57WYAEsngW.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The logo for Fanhouse, a platform that lets creators charge for access to a private social feed. | Image: Fanhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VxoadZ"&gt;Apple is clashing with the platform &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/"&gt;Fanhouse&lt;/a&gt; over whether it gets to take a cut of in-app payments to creators. The incident underscores just how little Apple understands about the creator economy, with the likely outcome being less money in creators’ pockets — and more money for one of the world’s most profitable corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQfXy8"&gt;Founders of Fanhouse — which is basically OnlyFans without the nudity — say the platform will be kicked out of the App Store in August if it doesn’t start forking over 30 percent of the fees people pay creators when purchases are made through the iPhone app. One of Fanhouse’s creators, the streamer &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/breadwitchery/fanwall"&gt;Breadwitchery&lt;/a&gt;, says that cut would mean losing two months of rent from her earnings to date. The company doesn’t have a lot of options to push back, but it’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasminericegirl/status/1402691047940100100"&gt;launching a campaign today&lt;/a&gt; to pressure Apple into easing its rules around payments to creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D37kCi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I use this to pay the bills for my family.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aMflPk"&gt;Fanhouse is only the latest company to clash with Apple over App Store terms that are increasingly viewed as steep and domineering. Sure, it’s a small app, and its disappearance won’t necessarily cause problems for Apple, but the situation speaks to the challenges creator-focused apps face in the App Store. As the creator economy continues to grow, the rules mean Apple will be taking more money from not just businesses, but individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oVCxDY"&gt;“People are using this platform to survive, starting with me, our very first creator,” Jasmine Rice, &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/jasminericegirl/fanwall"&gt;a Fanhouse creator&lt;/a&gt; and one of the platform’s co-founders, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; “I use this to pay the bills for my family. I use this to pay my mom’s medical expenses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3EtD4I"&gt;Fanhouse, which launched in 2020, initially slipped past the App Store bouncers and offered payments on the web without issue. Now that Apple has spotted the potential for profit, it’s given Fanhouse the same ultimatum it gives (almost) everyone else: Fanhouse either needs to pay up or get booted from the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="vVpFM6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple often takes a larger cut than the actual platforms&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bc2LQV"&gt;The app only takes a 10 percent cut on its own, so the platform’s creators could soon be earning a whole lot less. Rice says she would be okay with handing Apple a 30 percent cut of Fanhouse’s own profits. But once that 30 percent has to cut into creators’ profits, it starts to hurt &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;, not just the platform. “This money really means a second job for some people, that they have a place to live, that they can afford tuition,” Rice says. “And we tried to explain this to Apple.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsCEqe"&gt;Fanhouse allows creators to charge a subscription for access to a private social media feed where they can post updates about their life or publish photos and videos. Creators can also earn money from tips, or they can post “locked” updates that fans need to pay to view. Each account also has a public feed that can be viewed without a subscription, which may be why the app was able to slip through the App Store unnoticed until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fojC0h"&gt;Apple told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it’s working with Fanhouse to bring the app into compliance with its rules. The company referred to &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/#in-app-purchase"&gt;its in-app purchase guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and said Fanhouse was rejected previously because of a similar violation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ue8vgJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/fuckapple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#fuckapple&lt;/a&gt;, a thread&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I cofounded &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fanhouseapp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@fanhouseapp&lt;/a&gt; 8 months ago to empower creators to monetize their content. We pay creators 90% of earnings. Now, Apple is threatening to remove Fanhouse from the app store unless we give them 30% of creator earnings. This is theft and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;— jasmine   (@jasminericegirl) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasminericegirl/status/1402691047940100100?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ciuIBg"&gt;Apple requires a 30 percent cut from in-app purchases of “digital” goods, such as &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; skins or Netflix subscriptions, though it has a number of exceptions. The figure is reduced to 15 percent for multiyear subscriptions and apps that earn under $1 million. (Fanhouse has more than $1 million in revenue, but it pays nearly all of it out to creators.) And it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21293813/apple-app-store-policies-hey-30-percent-developers-the-trial-by-franz-kafka"&gt;up to Apple to decide&lt;/a&gt; what qualifies as a “digital” good and what doesn’t. For instance, Apple allows Patreon to offer third-party payment solutions for creators rather than use in-app purchases, avoiding the fee. Other apps aren’t afforded that privilege. Apple and Patreon did not respond to a request for comment on the arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="QkpcIF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think it speaks to a creator illiteracy.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wAnZPt"&gt;Apple’s App Store rules didn’t even acknowledge creators &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523332/apple-app-store-guidelines-change-wwdc-2021-fraud-scam-creators-marijuana-law-roblox"&gt;until this week&lt;/a&gt;. On Monday, they were updated with a new section saying that creator-made content and experiences are allowed in apps — so long as they’re properly moderated and monetized for Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JOP5P3"&gt;The problem is likely to become more acute as platforms offer more ways for creators to get paid. Twitter plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447328/twitter-ticketed-spaces-monetization-stripe-approval"&gt;take a 20 percent cut&lt;/a&gt; from ticketed audio rooms later this year, from which Apple will take another 30 percent if fans pay on their iPhones. Facebook is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522706/facebook-creators-apple-google-fees-payment-interface-events"&gt;waiving its cut&lt;/a&gt; for the next year on fan subscriptions and other sources of creator revenue, but Apple will still be taking 30 percent when purchases are made through its store. Twitch already hands Apple a 30 percent cut of subscriptions and tips made through iOS, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/18/20921448/twitch-subscription-ios-app-store-price"&gt;it hikes prices there&lt;/a&gt; so that viewers have to cover the added costs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZzZqi"&gt;Other creator-focused services simply aren’t offered on iOS because of Apple’s rules: Spotify doesn’t let listeners &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404273/spotify-podcast-subscriptions-monetize-subscriber-shows"&gt;pay for podcast subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, despite offering them, and OnlyFans isn’t available on the platform at all because of Apple’s ban on “overtly sexual or pornographic material.” The newsletter &lt;em&gt;Means of Creation&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://every.to/means-of-creation/apple-is-holding-back-the-creator-economy"&gt;criticized these policies last month&lt;/a&gt;, writing that “Apple is now one of the main barriers to independent creators thriving on the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uDAm7R"&gt;Apple is currently caught in a legal battle with Epic, the maker of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite,&lt;/em&gt; over its App Store fees. Apple is happy with its cut: it brought in $64 billion in revenue last year, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/08/apples-app-store-had-gross-sales-around-64-billion-in-2020.html"&gt;according to a CNBC analysis&lt;/a&gt;. During the trial, Apple CEO Tim Cook said that allowing other payment options “would in essence give up our total return on our IP.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32RExv"&gt;“I think it speaks to a creator illiteracy,” says Breadwitchery, a narrative games streamer who works part time as a community manager for Fanhouse. “Those corporations like Apple, do you not think that if you invest in creators and treat them well, they’re going to be motivated to make more content and make more money?”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525904/fanhouse-apple-tax-app-store-creator-fees"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525904/fanhouse-apple-tax-app-store-creator-fees</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T13:06:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T13:06:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some of macOS Monterey’s best features aren’t coming to Intel Macs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YvzQ-RzNNfKs73oC9dJaR5FRs-M=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69428805/Apple_macos_monterey_maps_06072021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You won’t be able to see Apple Maps’ new globe view on an Intel-based Mac.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4gynH7"&gt;Apple’s next big macOS update, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt;, adds a bunch of good-looking new features, but some of the more interesting ones won’t be coming to Intel-based Macs, according to the fine print on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmacos%2Fmonterey-preview%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22526224%2Fmacos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s macOS Monterey website&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/09/macos-monterey-features-for-m1-macs-only/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="96ARyd"&gt;If you don’t have an M1-based Mac — and many people probably don’t, given that the first Macs with M1 chips were just released in November — here are the new features that you won’t be able to use in macOS Monterey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WAM4Ol"&gt;FaceTime’s Portrait mode, which blurs the background behind you while you’re on a video call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="peoeQY"&gt;Live Text, which lets you interact with text in photos and images (such as being able to copy and paste an address on a sign)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RaCNJH"&gt;Apple Maps’ new globe view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2sEh84"&gt;Apple Maps’ more detailed maps in cities including San Francisco, Los Angeles, New York, and London&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mjxEfy"&gt;Neural text-to-speech voices in Swedish, Danish, Norwegian, and Finnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uc1ozd"&gt;Offline, on-device dictation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YiEuuY"&gt;On-device dictation without a time limit (previously, dictation was limited to 60 seconds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="62eMVY"&gt;If you’re still using an Intel-based Mac that you’re happy with and aren’t planning to upgrade anytime soon, it might be disappointing to hear that you won’t be able to use some of the new features in macOS Monterey. These M1-exclusive updates in Monterey also suggest that Apple could make features on future macOS releases only work on computers with its own chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAtgj7"&gt;Last June, when Apple first announced the transition to its custom-designed processors, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2020%2F06%2Fapple-announces-mac-transition-to-apple-silicon%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22526224%2Fmacos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company did promise&lt;/a&gt; that it would “continue to support and release new versions of macOS for Intel-based Macs for years to come.” But apparently, that support also means that some new features won’t be coming to Intel-based Macs. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T12:55:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T12:55:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Podcasts says it’ll launch in-app subscriptions globally on June 15th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hB1oWJ8BHUxYyRIB0LSpudZZhEc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69428704/acastro_210429_1777_epicApple_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JMmkd8"&gt;After some major hiccups and a delay, Apple Podcasts says it’s launching in-app subscriptions next week. The global launch of subscriptions and channels, which are groups of shows, will happen on June 15th, the company said today in an email to podcasters, which &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has viewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ceJe91"&gt;Apple first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;debuted in-app subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; in April with a launch planned for May. It then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459129/apple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june"&gt;emailed creators&lt;/a&gt; to tell them the feature launch would be pushed to June to “ensure we are delivering the best experience for creators and listeners,” likely because of issues the company introduced with a recent backend update. Through the feature, listeners can subscribe to certain shows or networks for early access and ad-free content, among other perks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNwBmt"&gt;Beyond this rollout being delayed, podcasters have complained that Apple’s latest Podcasts update, made in preparation for the subscription offerings, completely bonked the system. &lt;a href="https://podnews.net/article/apple-podcasts-lemon-bugs?utm_source=podnews.net&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=podnews.net:2021-05-28"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Podnews&lt;/em&gt; wrote&lt;/a&gt; two weeks ago that multiple creators experienced a range of issues, including their episodes being delayed, their analytics breaking, and artwork going missing. Hopefully Apple will have all that sorted prior to this rollout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxiQLL"&gt;Meanwhile, Spotify &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404273/spotify-podcast-subscriptions-monetize-subscriber-shows"&gt;announced and launched&lt;/a&gt; its plan for subscription podcasts in the time since Apple debuted its product and delayed the release. Spotify’s solution doesn’t allow people to subscribe in-app, thereby allowing the creators and the company to skirt around Apple’s App Store fees. Instead, listeners have to navigate to an external Anchor webpage. Though that also puts a big hurdle between creators and potential subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ItxBMa"&gt;Apple’s big idea is that putting a subscribe button in the podcast app could draw more premium listeners to various services, like Luminary and Wondery Plus. Those groups have had to get over the hurdle of making people subscribe in an app separate from their usual listening platform. Starting this month, we’ll finally see how powerful a subscribe button might be. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526186/apple-podcasts-in-app-subscription-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526186/apple-podcasts-in-app-subscription-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T11:15:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T11:15:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>New iPhone Health app feature gives doctors easier access to data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ARrzlgjEHswkBGmAjj2X9sdU65g=/0x33:1629x1119/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69428056/image__4_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone users will be able to share their Health app data directly with doctors.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3fpuBY"&gt;People with smartphones and wearable devices regularly show up to the doctor’s office with readouts from apps detailing everything from their heart rate to sleep patterns. Now, with the new iOS 15 update this fall, some iPhone users will be able to send data directly from their Health app to their doctors’ electronic medical records systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dPKuGC"&gt;That type of integration could make it easier for patients to share information with their doctors, said Libo Wang, a cardiology fellow at the University of Utah School of Medicine who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463322/wearables-afib-apple-fitbit-doctor-visit"&gt;studies wearables&lt;/a&gt;. “The current workflow is mildly laborious, and requires the patient to email the pdf, and a clinician manually uploading that file to create a permanent record in the official electronic medical record,” he said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="joIhNj"&gt;Users could already pull in data from the other direction: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/29/17176740/apple-health-records-app-ios-update"&gt;since 2018&lt;/a&gt;, Apple has allowed people to add records from &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208647"&gt;dozens&lt;/a&gt; of clinics and hospitals to their Health app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qf5K9k"&gt;The new integration will work with six electronic medical records companies in the United States. That includes Cerner, which controls around &lt;a href="https://www.ehrinpractice.com/largest-ehr-vendors.html"&gt;a quarter&lt;/a&gt; of the market, and five smaller groups. Apple says it could continue to add more. Doctors who use the records from those companies would be able to open any shared data within a patient’s health record. The dashboard opens as a web view directly inside the record; it doesn’t take providers to another outside app. The design is similar within the records for each of the six companies, Apple says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hUX3Js"&gt;The Health app data isn’t directly transferred into the electronic health record. Doctors can see a window with the data, but the information isn’t permanently added to the record. If an iPhone user decides to stop sharing their health data, none remains within the health record. The system is built using a framework called &lt;a href="https://smarthealthit.org/"&gt;SMART on FHIR&lt;/a&gt;, an open interface for third-party applications that can work within electronic health records. Any group can create an app using the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfcajx"&gt;For physicians — and particularly cardiologists — direct access to iPhone data within health records could help them make more meaningful use of the information, Wang said. One &lt;a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.044126?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub%20%200pubmed"&gt;2020 study&lt;/a&gt; found that when physicians directly reviewed the strip generated by the Apple Watch that visually shows a user’s heart rate, they were able to flag more cases of abnormal heart rhythms than the Watch’s algorithm flagged. If the rhythm strips are shared directly to someone’s doctor, the doctor might be able to identify any concerning patterns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UF1Tvv"&gt;The downside, though, is the potential for information overload, Wang said. More data isn’t necessarily better, particularly if doctors don’t trust its accuracy. While the data collected by wearables and smartphones may seem helpful to patients, it’s still not entirely clear if it actually helps people feel better or gives them better care, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIn4Hz"&gt;Cerner, one of the electronic health record companies participating in the initial rollout, was able to test the new Apple feature at its onsite clinic for employees. “Having secure ways to view and share this information in a clinical context has been helpful,” said Sam Lambson, vice president of interoperability at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beMShQ"&gt;It’s more and more common for patients to bring health data from their personal devices to health visits, and Lambson said Cerner is focused on efforts to incorporate that into its systems even outside of the new Apple program. One advantage of the Apple system is that it’s easy for doctors to use, said Jessica Oveys, director of product management at Cerner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3ovFu"&gt;“I think the key to it is certainly empowering and making the patient feel at the center and secure, and making it easy for them to share. But also, it’s really presenting the data in a way that’s actionable and relevant to the clinician,” she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UDhmVq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB0FTa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526024/apple-health-app-data-medical-record-iphone-doctor-access"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526024/apple-health-app-data-medical-record-iphone-doctor-access</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T11:00:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T11:00:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music’s spatial audio is sometimes amazing but mostly inconsistent</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1gYZtMLk1bB46AsGjCUQv1egAwY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69427941/acastro_180130_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;At launch, it’s a very hit or miss experience&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="AQSssp"&gt;Late on Monday night, Apple flipped the switch on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;two new features for its Apple Music subscription service&lt;/a&gt;: immersive Dolby Atmos spatial audio and lossless-quality streaming. It feels like the company is really only excited about one of them, though, and it’s not the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N07Cwb"&gt;Eddy Cue is Apple’s senior vice president of services and the person who oversees Apple Music. He &lt;a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/business/streaming/9583947/apple-music-eddy-cue-spatial-audio-lossless-future-of-music/"&gt;didn’t mince words when he told &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the sudden proliferation of lossless audio isn’t going to significantly evolve or change how we listen to music. “There’s no question it’s not going to be lossless,” he said when asked what technologies will bring about the “next-gen” of music streaming. Cue firmly stands on the side of the crowd that argues most people can’t hear any difference between CD-quality or hi-res tracks and the AAC or MP3 files that’ve been filling their ears for so long now. He did acknowledge that the higher-bit rate tracks might matter to music lovers with particularly sharp hearing or premium audio equipment, but he was also direct about how niche that group is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jKCf33"&gt;“The reality of lossless is: if you take 100 people and you take a stereo song in lossless and you take a song that’s been in Apple Music that’s compressed, I don’t know if it’s 99 or 98 can’t tell the difference.” Cue revealed that he has regularly done blind tests with the Apple Music team, and they confirm how rare it is for anyone to be able to consistently recognize lossless audio. “You can tell somebody, ‘Oh, you’re listening to a lossless [song],’ and they tell you, ‘Oh, wow. That sounds incredible.’ They’re just saying it because you told them it’s lossless and it sounds like the right thing to say, but you just can’t tell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fKbQBn"&gt;If you go by the message that Cue and Apple are pushing, the Dolby Atmos-powered spatial audio feature is where the true breakthrough is. “When I look at Dolby Atmos, I think it’s going to do for music what HD did for television,” Cue said in the &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; interview. And then he &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; went in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="UAmSeJ"&gt;“I think this is going to take over everything. It’s the way I want to listen to music when I’m in my car. It’s going to be the way I listen to music immediately with my AirPods. It’s going to be the way I listen to music in my house. In a way, it won’t feel very good when I’m listening to something that’s not Dolby Atmos because it’s so good. It’s like when I’m watching HD, it’s hard to go back.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="eqX3h9"&gt;“This requires somebody who’s a sound engineer, and the artist to sit back and listen, and really make the right calls and what the right things to do are,” Cue told &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; about mixing for spatial audio. “It’s a process that takes time, but it’s worth it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J5rpOU"&gt;Problem is, with much of the Dolby Atmos content on Apple Music I’ve sampled so far, it doesn’t seem like everyone is making those right calls. It’s a hit-or-miss game of exploration, and songs that truly showcase the immersive potential of Atmos are more often the exception than the rule. In many cases, spatial audio tracks have an artificial wideness to them, unfamiliar placement of vocals and instrumentation, and just sound… &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt;. Distant? Too reverb-y? Pick your preferred interpretation. Yet, Apple is so confident in Apple Music’s spatial audio that essentially overnight it became the default for millions of customers listening with AirPods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nue23S"&gt;But let’s back up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xXic1j"&gt;What is spatial audio supposed to do for music?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="11yuxN"&gt;In a word, it’s all about immersion. Here’s how Cue hyped it: “it makes you feel like you’re onstage, standing right next to the singer, it makes you feel like you might be to the left of the drummer, to the right of the guitarist.” On its website, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fapple-music%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple says&lt;/a&gt; “music created in Dolby Atmos is freed from channels, allowing artists to place individual sounds all around you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jfUQw4"&gt;Whoa there. Like all of Apple’s senior executives, Eddy Cue knows how to pitch something. But if you slap on your AirPods and expect to feel like an invisible person standing in the middle of a recording session, you’ll probably be underwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RCDpv"&gt;When it’s done well, spatial audio does indeed give music a unique feeling of breadth. And it’s in a different way than a high-end pair of headphones might bring the most out of a stereo track’s soundstage. In particular, vocals often have a very distinct placement in the mix and cut through better than on traditional stereo tracks. That’s the most consistent advantage I’ve noticed with spatial audio music. But because of the different mix, you’ll very likely also pick up on details or sounds that ordinarily don’t stand out in the regular version of a song. And on the best Atmos tracks, everything has a lot more room to breathe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rw13aL"&gt;But when engineers don’t put much care into an Atmos mix, it really shows. Sometimes giving everything so much space can take the impact or crunch out of guitars. Or other aspects of a track fall flat. I’ve included just a few samples below where the spatial audio version of a song is an obvious downgrade from the original. But there are many, and when you hit a few in a row where the vocals sound weird or something’s amiss, it can detract from the listening experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="B3ZRod"&gt;How many songs are available in Dolby Atmos spatial audio?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WmlWUp"&gt;Apple currently isn’t providing a hard number, and is instead only saying that “thousands” of tracks are available with spatial audio at launch, with many more on the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uBiKGJ"&gt;How do I know when I’m hearing spatial audio on Apple Music?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="23SBGz"&gt;You’ll see either a Dolby Atmos or Dolby Audio logo appear on the Now Playing screen beneath the album artwork. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="o4yEjZ"&gt;A few random, good examples of Apple Music spatial audio:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QZsfzd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: if the below tracks don’t initially play as Dolby Atmos, try browsing to them from Apple’s new playlists like &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fmade-for-spatial-audio%2Fpl.154af9931b214278a64274c410046e69&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;made for spatial audio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fhits-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.ba2404fbc4464b8ba2d60399189cf24e&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;hits in spatial audio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, plus genre-specific playlists for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fpop-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.cc74a5aec23942da9cf083c6c4344aee&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;pop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Frock-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.a82d7ac0ee854d8b8a95708c76210023&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;rock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fhip-hop-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.a0c765aa555e457c9666b2a201de5506&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;hip-hop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fcountry-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.924f9f9df2294b9c97f5e40d8862f7e7&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and others.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z57G7e"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fdont-know-why%2F728317060%3Fi%3D728317110&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Don’t Know Why” by Norah Jones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— This is one where I nearly buy into Cue’s description. Close your eyes, and you could almost transport yourself to a small club where the spread of this mix feels like a live version of Jones’ career-making hit. Stereo doesn’t take you to the same place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sPvVgB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fpaparazzi%2F1440818588%3Fi%3D1440818663&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Paparazzi” by Lady Gaga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — With a very surround sound-esque mix (skip to the second verse at 1:23 for the best examples), this is a great example of an old pop hit with an excellent spatial audio treatment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3pUlD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fboom%2F1445039970%3Fi%3D1445039972&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Boom” by Tiësto and Sevenn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — A fun, lively track that does give off a nice surround sound effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2NlV7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fblack-skinhead%2F1440873068%3Fi%3D1440873230&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Black Skinhead” by Kanye West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — This one is another good example of the “beyond two-channel” openness that spatial audio can provide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gj4mdV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A whole lot of &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fjazz-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.efbd24628ff04ff3b5e416a6e237d753&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jazz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Fplaylist%2Fclassical-in-spatial-audio%2Fpl.ffea4bbea2d141cbb0ec67e32059b278&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;classical&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — If there are two genres that naturally lend themselves to spatial audio and Dolby Atmos, it’s jazz and classical. Orchestras can sound truly massive, and it’s a captivating way to listen to jazz ensembles where it’s easy to hear even the quietest notes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x9Wd0G"&gt;Other examples where it just sounds wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LRYDOh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fbuddy-holly%2F1440878798%3Fi%3D1440879325&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Buddy Holly” by Weezer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — The guitars basically lose all life in this mix and vocals dominate the entire thing in a way that just sounds strange and bad. And yet this song is on Apple’s own playlist meant to showcase Atmos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zd7B49"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Ffollow-your-arrow%2F1440858493%3Fi%3D1440858612&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Follow Your Arrow” by Kacey Musgraves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— Apple mentioned Musgraves as an artist to check out with Atmos. And while her most recent album &lt;em&gt;Golden Hour&lt;/em&gt; sounds… fine… her breakthrough &lt;em&gt;Same Trailer Different Park&lt;/em&gt; is pretty rough in spatial audio format. “Follow Your Arrow” seems to lose most of its background vocals, and even the main guitar melody is way quieter here than in the regular mix. It almost comes off like a demo recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJDOwx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Fwhats-my-age-again%2F1440839912%3Fi%3D1440840493&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What’s My Age Again?” by Blink 182&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — This is another song that Apple seems to think makes spatial audio sound good, but I’d strongly argue it does the opposite. Mark Hoppus’ muffled vocals legitimately sound like they were recorded through a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zkCdc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Fus%2Falbum%2Falex-chilton%2F698654479%3Fi%3D698654487&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Alex Chilton” by The Replacements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Is that enough cowbell for you during the chorus? It overpowers everything else and makes me feel like I’m in the old Christopher Walken &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; skit, only with a different band. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2qTZ2"&gt;I’m curious to hear some of your examples that sound great, and others you’ve found that are a disappointment with Atmos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NQHaSb"&gt;Do I need AirPods or Beats headphones for Apple Music spatial audio?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="i47rdV"&gt;No. Apple Music’s spatial audio works on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oCk9sW"&gt;All headphones and earbuds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ICjX4a"&gt;The loudspeakers on supported iPhones, iPads, and Macs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2KknA7"&gt;Apple TV 4K&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="qc9Feh"&gt;If you set Dolby Atmos to “always on” in settings for the Music app, you’ll see a pop-up advising that it probably won’t sound right on all speakers, but Apple Music will still play the spatial audio mix if that’s your preference. In fact, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212182"&gt;Apple clearly states&lt;/a&gt; that you can “listen on any headphones” to Apple Music’s spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="V229ep"&gt;How do I turn off Apple Music spatial audio if I don’t like it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5x0IvE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iOS and iPadOS:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to Settings &amp;gt; Music &amp;gt; Dolby Atmos (under “audio”), and there you can pick between automatic, always on, and off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PekaN7"&gt;If you’d prefer to leave Atmos on by default but want to quickly switch to a regular stereo version of any song that’s playing, just pull down Control Center, press and hold on the volume slider, and toggle off spatial audio. Apple Music will switch over to stereo. If you turn spatial audio back on, you’ll return to the Atmos track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Houvwm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS: &lt;/strong&gt;In the Music app, open preferences and select the “playback” tab. Halfway down you’ll see an “audio quality” section and Atmos is in there. You get the same three automatic / always on / off choices as on Apple’s mobile devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZeqbWk"&gt;Head tracking is coming to Apple Music spatial audio this fall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CGvFcb"&gt;Apple Music’s spatial audio is currently much different than the spatial audio experience you get when watching movies and TV shows on an iPhone or iPad. For videos, Apple includes a head-tracking feature that adjusts the sound placement as you turn your head to keep it anchored to the source device. This trick is exclusive to the AirPods lineup, but it’s a very impressive effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wONQz3"&gt;Apple has said it plans to bring this sound-changes-as-you-turn-your-head feature to Apple Music in the fall — likely with iOS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="83be3G"&gt;Is this just a gimmick?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JqTPw8"&gt;That’s really the question that remains to be answered. But Apple isn’t alone in hyping multidimensional music (nor is it the first to do so). Amazon, Tidal, and others are also increasingly pushing the experience. I recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22360437/sony-srs-ra5000-speaker-review-360-audio-features"&gt;reviewed an extravagant Sony speaker&lt;/a&gt; that positions 360-degree audio as its main selling point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIKRc0"&gt;Are people like Eddy Cue and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F06%2Fapple-musics-zane-lowe-explains-how-spatial-audio-will-transform-music%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22525028%2Fapple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zane Lowe&lt;/a&gt; right in their insistence that spatial audio will revolutionize how we consume music in the same way that stereo did? Or is this a gimmick like 3D TVs that will fizzle out and be forgotten within a few years? If it’s going to be the former, it’ll take a lot of work and creativity from artists, producers, and mixers to make this format shine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="92rz3E"&gt;Because right now, for every Atmos spatial audio track that’s a standout on Apple Music, there are a dozen others that are quite meh — or worse than in stereo. We’re still in the early days, and now that Atmos is officially part of Apple Music, hopefully the consistency will improve. When you do find those mixes where they totally nail it, it’s something special. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tKT9hC"&gt;Apple should make it easier to switch between Atmos and stereo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jV8qIF"&gt;But in the meantime, and to avoid turning people &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; from Atmos when they land on a lackluster mix, Apple Music should make it easier to go back and forth between spatial audio and regular stereo tracks on a per-song basis. One solution could be displaying a choice when you tap on the Dolby icon, similar to the “go to artist / album” options that appear when tapping on an artist’s name. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T08:48:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T08:48:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the developer beta of iOS 15</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zGHU86pLQ0nPVQUSouD_cYsx_uE=/76x0:1885x1206/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69427177/apple_live_text.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gCRRF5"&gt;In its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;much-anticipated WWDC session&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, June 7th, Apple introduced a load of new features for its upcoming update of its iOS mobile operating system: iOS 15. The developer’s beta is now available for anyone who’d like to download it — and who is a registered developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oXuH7Q"&gt;First, the obligatory warning: this version of iOS 15 is going to be very new and very beta. If you’re a developer, you know all this, but it’s worth repeating: it’s best to install this on a phone that isn’t the one that you rely on. In addition, remember that Backups Are Your Friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="81kWuD"&gt;You can find the developers beta of iOS 15 on &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/ios/"&gt;Apple’s Developers Website&lt;/a&gt;. You will, of course, have to sign in (we’re assuming you’ve paid your $99 for a developer’s account). You may be asked to register your device if it isn’t registered already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NiJBjy"&gt;Find the iOS 15 profile by choosing Downloads (either from the button on the upper right corner, or by using the two-line drop-down menu on the upper left).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rxypZu"&gt;Look for the iOS profile, and allow the download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1Uk9rC"&gt;Once the profile is downloaded, go to the Settings on your device, find “Profile Downloaded,” and follow the instructions. You will eventually be told to reboot, and then should be able to install the update that is available in Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Software Update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="MmG9Dh"&gt;If you’re not enrolled as an Apple developer, don’t be downhearted — there will be a public beta available for download sometime in July. When it’s available, we’ll let you know where to find it and how to install it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSkEdx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Em7HR0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mSRbsl"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dAVqQV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22524845/ios-15-how-to-install"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22524845/ios-15-how-to-install</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T03:49:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T03:49:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max update fixes the worst of its Apple TV woes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ShSffe4iCzq3nBcS3gixmzmCj4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69426541/wjoel_200527_1777_hbomax_0001.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uHisVp"&gt;HBO Max has updated its Apple TV app as it attempts to fix the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525177/hbo-max-apple-tv-broken-button-controls"&gt;myriad issues&lt;/a&gt; that have been plaguing the software since last week. The update &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HBOMAX/comments/nvl4yq/fixed/"&gt;fixes significant problems&lt;/a&gt; with basic features like fast-forwarding and rewinding, which had been introduced after the software switched away from using the native tvOS video player. The software update brings the native player back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="boCiIG"&gt;“We just released an update to our Apple TV app, restoring the native tvOS video playback experience you know and love, with more improvements to come,” HBO Max &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HBOMaxHelp/status/1402484711423975426"&gt;said in a tweet&lt;/a&gt;. “Ensuring HBO Max viewers have a quality experience is our top priority and we missed the mark here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gEKmLc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We just released an update to our Apple TV app, restoring the native tvOS video playback experience you know and love, with more improvements to come. Ensuring HBO Max viewers have a quality experience is our top priority and we missed the mark here. Thank you for your patience.&lt;/p&gt;— HBOMaxHelp (@HBOMaxHelp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HBOMaxHelp/status/1402484711423975426?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uA2VlS"&gt;Although the worst of the issues appear to have been fixed, users on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HBOMAX/comments/nvl4yq/fixed/"&gt;HBOMax subreddit&lt;/a&gt; are reporting that some bugs remain after the new update. One user reports that they’re finding their subtitles keep &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HBOMAX/comments/nvl4yq/fixed/h14cg1l?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;reverting back to Spanish&lt;/a&gt;, for example. Thankfully, as another user has pointed out, the new update makes it easier to switch subtitles back, a process which the previous update had made &lt;a href="https://www.screentimes.net/article/hbo-max-tvos-update-breaks-several-key-features-degrading-experience-significantly#:~:text=turning%20on%2Foff%20subtitles%20requires%20pressing%20pause%2C%20swiping%20down%20then%20across%20to%20subtitles%2C%20pressing%20again%20then%20scrolling%20to%20your%20desired%20option%2C%20pressing%20yet%20again%20then%20resuming%20playback.%20before%2C%20you%20could%20swipe%20down%2C%20select%20your%20choice%2C%20then%20swipe%20up%20again%20-%20the%20standard%20tvos%20way."&gt;significantly more difficult&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GXzQuQ"&gt;Questions remain about how such broken software was able to be released to users in the first place. Responding to a tweet from &lt;em&gt;The Verge’s&lt;/em&gt; editor in chief Nilay Patel, HBO Max’s EVP and general manager Andy Forssell admitted that this was “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aforssell/status/1401955206233923595"&gt;the zillion dollar question&lt;/a&gt;” and that the company would be investigating the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S7Reh2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4TdiB1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525635/hbo-max-apple-tv-app-update-native-tvos-player-fixed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525635/hbo-max-apple-tv-app-update-native-tvos-player-fixed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T20:44:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T20:44:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max has been busted for days </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The HBO Max logo against a dark background with white circles around it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IMhD-qZm5Fgljs7YY1kaw_O9nPY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69425659/acastro_200602_1777_HBOMax_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T0tRNJ"&gt;If you’ve attempted to stream something on HBO Max from an Apple TV sometime during the last several days, you may have noticed that its player controls are unusable. It’s not just you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MqDmgf"&gt;Ongoing issues seem to be related to an &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hbo-max-stream-tv-movies/id971265422"&gt;app update&lt;/a&gt; that supposedly addressed “a few bugs lurking around” on June 5th. Since that update released, users &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1401730242775961600"&gt;have reported&lt;/a&gt; that basic playback functionality — such as fast-forwarding, rewinding, and pausing — is borked completely when you try to use the service on an Apple TV box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="POJuAO"&gt;How an update this riddled with bugs rolled out to consumers remains unclear. Unfortunately, it’s also unclear when exactly they’re going to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="l3P1rU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;There’s legitimately no way to pause, rewind or fast forward on the HBO Max app no matter if you use the apple remote or the remote mobile app. Idk how anyone is watching anything on there&lt;/p&gt;— Taylor Lorenz (@TaylorLorenz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1401730242775961600?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PgIQWY"&gt;Asked for comment on Tuesday, a spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company was working to fix the issue “as quickly as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b8wi12"&gt;When &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s editor in chief Nilay Patel tweeted about the issue, HBO Max’s EVP and general manager &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aforssell/status/1401771759641055244"&gt;Andy Forssell replied&lt;/a&gt; that the company was undertaking “one whale of an effort to address this with app updates as soon as humanly possible.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8iuUh"&gt;“You’ll hear no excuses from us,” Forssell added, “fixes coming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZP1rz"&gt;But &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless/status/1401883622089674752"&gt;when asked&lt;/a&gt; by Patel how it was possible that the update shipped to users with broken playback controls, the HBO Max head said that was “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aforssell/status/1401955206233923595"&gt;the zillion dollar question&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="60k69f"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@reckless&lt;/a&gt; That's the zillion dollar question. First priority is to deliver for users in addressing the issues, but in parallel we will also dive deep into that question. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;— Andy Forssell (@aforssell) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aforssell/status/1401955206233923595?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ro2i5x"&gt;On Twitter, the HBO Max help account is replying directly to frustrated users. “We’re aware that our recent &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HBOMax?src=hashtag_click"&gt;#HBOMax&lt;/a&gt; app update for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppleTV"&gt;@AppleTV&lt;/a&gt; led to a number of issues for our viewers,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HBOMaxHelp/status/1402409361461460993"&gt;the account said in one tweet&lt;/a&gt;. “Our team is working quickly to restore the experience you’re used to. We appreciate your patience and will provide updates as they become available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8gX9MN"&gt;Separately, on Friday,&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; contacted the service about reported issues affecting the new Siri Remote’s scrubbing feature — though that issue was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22519340/siri-remote-scrubbing-feature-disney-plus"&gt;not limited to just HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, a spokesperson said that it was aware of player control issues as well as “a few isolated reports” of HDR playback problems. But the spokesperson also added that the company did not believe the HDR issues were related to an update, as the most recent update at the time did not include changes to the video player itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eE5Z0L"&gt;Given the problems with the app right now, if you were hoping to stream the &lt;em&gt;Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt; finale on your Apple TV box without issue, you may want to hold off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0XsQAR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 9th, 3:52AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; HBO Max has &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525635/hbo-max-apple-tv-app-update-native-tvos-player-fixed"&gt;&lt;em&gt;released an update&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; for its Apple TV app which users are reporting fixes many of the issues detailed above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525177/hbo-max-apple-tv-broken-button-controls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525177/hbo-max-apple-tv-broken-button-controls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
