<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-28T15:48:06-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T15:48:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T15:48:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dropbox clarifies that a native Apple Silicon app is coming in 2022 after forum outrage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5FJSImoVKSscJ0gK7033q8W0Nkk=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70058892/dropbox_logo_2x.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9Pdh3z"&gt;Dropbox will finally be updating its Mac app to natively support Apple Silicon sometime in the first half of 2022, the company confirmed today. A previous forum thread saw Dropbox staffers claim that a native app would require “a bit more support before we share your suggestion with our team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9MAXIF"&gt;The months-old thread was resurfaced in a post by developer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mitchellh/status/1453394500848537605?s=20"&gt;Mitchell Hashimoto&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/28/dropbox-no-plans-to-support-apple-silicon/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), sparking complaints from Dropbox users who were disappointed by the impression that the company would only develop the app if enough customers asked for it. While Dropbox technically does work with Apple Silicon hardware thanks to Apple’s Rosetta 2 software translation layer, it’s not as power or memory efficient as it could be if it ran natively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27WhBd"&gt;In response to the confusion, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drewhouston/status/1453762478479843332"&gt;Dropbox’s CEO Drew Houston&lt;/a&gt; clarified that the service is “certainly supporting Apple Silicon” and that it’s been “working for a while on a native M1 build which we aim to release in H1 2022.” Houston also apologized for the support thread responses, which he called “not ideal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1zbF00"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We're certainly supporting Apple Silicon, sorry for the confusion. We've been working for a while on a native M1 build which we aim to release in H1 2022. (And agree the responses in the support thread were not ideal)&lt;/p&gt;— Drew Houston (@drewhouston) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drewhouston/status/1453762478479843332?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bodyDisplay_9"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.dropboxforum.com/t5/Dropbox-ideas/Apple-Silicon-M1-Desktop-Sync-Compatibility/idc-p/553669/highlight/true#M64135"&gt;support thread&lt;/a&gt; has also since been resolved with a similar update clarifying the current development of a native M1 app and apologizing for the confusion. “While we regularly ask for customer feedback and input on new products or features, this should not have been one of those instances.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751178/dropbox-native-apple-silicon-app-m1-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751178/dropbox-native-apple-silicon-app-m1-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T10:08:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T10:08:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Comcast will bring Apple TV to X1 boxes and the new XClass smart TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Brendan Hunt, Cristo Fernández and Jason Sudeikis in “Ted Lasso”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iTfRXVjz4FRNKZs672Qh3EvIWA4=/0x0:1800x1200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70056848/Ted_Lasso_Photo_020106.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Brendan Hunt, Cristo Fernández and Jason Sudeikis in “Ted Lasso” | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RHCSff"&gt;Comcast’s X1 platform has slowly added apps to its library over the years, and &lt;a href="https://www.cmcsa.com/events/event-details/q3-2021-comcast-corporation-earnings-conference-call"&gt;this morning on the company’s earnings call&lt;/a&gt;, CEO Brian Roberts announced that the Apple TV app would join the roster soon, while Comcast’s Xfinity Stream app will launch on Apple TV devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zg5NjK"&gt;Comcast’s tech platform, which already has apps for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/1/16593310/netflix-4k-comcast-xfinity-x1-users-stranger-things-house-cards"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/2/17645152/comcast-amazon-prime-video-xfinity-x1-box"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, YouTube, and Disney+ in the US, isn’t just on its cable boxes anymore. It underpins the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18276040/comcast-flex-streaming-announced-features-pricing"&gt;Xfinity Flex&lt;/a&gt; streaming platform, the XiOne streaming set-top box, and new &lt;a href="https://corporate.comcast.com/press/releases/comcast-launches-xclass-tv-powered-by-global-entertainment-platforms"&gt;XClass 4K TVs&lt;/a&gt; that recently launched from Hisense. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="XClass 4K TV" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dK9B-cvClKWfgrY-QnxrxCX-qLw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22962772/corporate_xclass_tv_inline_yellowstone_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Comcast&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;XClass 4K TV&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vkkY59"&gt;Two models of the TV are available, in 43- and 50-inch sizes, for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHisense-43-inch-XClass-4K-UHD-A6-Series-Smart-TV-43A6GX%2F357811284&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$298&lt;/a&gt; and $348, respectively. Like other smart TVs in their price range — and other devices on Comcast’s platform — they have streaming apps, Dolby Vision HDR, and voice search remotes. They also include a one-year subscription to Comcast’s Peacock Premium streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9vNHK0"&gt;As Comcast tries to sell its tech on devices worldwide (in the UK and other European markets, it’s pushing a &lt;a href="https://corporate.comcast.com/press/releases/introducing-sky-glass-streaming-tv-from-sky"&gt;Sky Glass TV&lt;/a&gt; with the same basic platform), then including access to Apple TV Plus is simply a requirement to compete. Getting its app on Apple TV is a bonus as cord-cutting proceeds to shrink its base of customers with cable TV service.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750469/apple-tv-plus-comcast-x1-flex-xclass-streaming-box-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750469/apple-tv-plus-comcast-x1-flex-xclass-streaming-box-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T08:45:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T08:45:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Save hundreds on one of the best TVs for gaming today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/430IObsd1R9Mr9miC61Z9z_xDBw=/5x0:1460x970/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70056365/Screen_Shot_2021_10_27_at_2.37.12_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can save up to $700 on LG’s brilliant C1 OLED today at multiple retailers.&lt;/em&gt; | LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Chp932"&gt;You can save up to $700 on one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"&gt;best TVs for gaming&lt;/a&gt; today, the LG C1. Right now, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F313720184065%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals102821%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F28%2F22748849%2Fapple-airpods-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-lg-c1-oled-roku-streaming-stick-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BuyDig’s digital storefront on eBay&lt;/a&gt; is selling the 55-inch model for $1,297 instead of $1,500, while adding $120 of eBay credit and a four-year extended warranty. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/lg-65%2522-class---c1-series---4k-uhd-oled-tv---allstate-3-year-protection-plan-bundle-included-for-5-years-of-total-coverage*.product.100761679.html"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WG4HKKY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; have the 65-inch versions for $1,800 and $1,797, respectively, though you’ll need to be a Costco member to take advantage of its discount. If you are a Costco member, however, the OLED TV comes with an Allstate Protection Plan —  an extended three-year warranty for your TV — and a $100 streaming credit toward Google Play, Paramount Plus, Showtime, or several other services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5d3TKA"&gt;No matter which C1 model you buy, however, all sport several features gamers in particular will love, including a 120Hz refresh rate and Dolby Vision HDR compatibility. All of the configurations also offer support for VRR (variable refresh rate), along with FreeSync and G-Sync adaptive sync technologies, meaning you can enjoy high frame rates without screen tearing. Their HDMI 2.1 support means all of these specs will work well with next-gen consoles, including the Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5, while the “Game Optimizer” dashboard makes it possible to quickly apply your ideal settings for specific game genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EBsIBl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10618444"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="OhS6mS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10782874"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6gdwhB"&gt;It’s only been a week since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"&gt;Apple quietly announced them&lt;/a&gt;, yet Amazon is already offering a discount on the latest &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MLWK3AM-A-New-AirPods/dp/B09JQMJHXY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro, which come with Apple’s new MagSafe charging case&lt;/a&gt;. Typically $249, you can currently buy the latest version of one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best pairs of wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; for $220. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k5amXM"&gt;As the name suggests, the updated charging case for the AirPods Pro is compatible with Apple’s MagSafe charging system. Despite this, it still works with Qi chargers and Lightning cables, and provides for up to 24 hours of playback. The earbuds boast deep integration with iOS and excellent noise cancellation, too, the latter of which silences background noise so you can concentrate more easily on what you’re listening to. They also support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;Apple’s spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;, which can make for a more immersive listening experience. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dTxNYR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10826178"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="uO3HIC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Which AirPods model should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"},{"title":"Apple AirPods (third-gen) review: new design, same appeal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sIzbeu"&gt;Android users, we also have a great earbuds deal for you. Right now, Amazon is selling the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08MWY75DH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt; at their lowest price to date. Regularly $200, the wireless earbuds are just $141 in the phantom violet style and slightly more in different colorways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zDo9su"&gt;As noted in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, we found the Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro had the best sound quality yet of any of the company’s earbuds. Like the AirPods Pro, Samsung’s earbuds also support active noise cancellation and 3D audio, which is essentially Samsung’s version of Apple’s spatial audio feature. However, the Galaxy Buds Pro are rated IPX7 for water and sweat resistance — beating the AirPods Pro’s IPX4. They also allow you to automatically switch between your Galaxy smartphone and tablet, though this feature doesn’t apply to laptops. In addition, their Qi-enabled charging case also allows for 28 hours of playback without noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lfXmFG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="viLELE"&gt;Samsung’s 43-inch M7 Smart Monitor is selling at its lowest price ever on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B096MY3BN8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; right now, going for $520 instead of $600. The smart 4K monitor, which is also selling for the same price at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfSvKg0ylwZ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, acts as a TV for your PC that you can even mount to your wall or a monitor arm using Vesa mounts. It can stream HDR10 content from a host of popular apps without additional hardware, too, and supports Apple’s AirPlay 2, meaning you can easily cast content from a host of Apple devices. The monitor also comes with a solar-powered remote control and support for Google Assistant and Amazon’s Alexa, as well as USB-C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V5VbmD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10745870"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3KtZxA"&gt;If you have an iPhone 12-series or iPhone 13-series phone, perhaps picking up Apple’s MagSafe Battery Pack has come across your mind before. It’s the company’s battery that magnetically snaps onto the back of those phones and begins charging. You can also charge devices like the AirPods Pro with it. Now is officially the best time to buy, since the battery pack is cheaper than ever at Amazon. Regularly $99, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MJWY3AM-A-MagSafe-Battery/dp/B099BWY7WT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s just $80&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jlfMWw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10782055"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l6wWl5"&gt;The latest Roku Streaming Stick 4K just launched last month, yet Amazon is already selling the 2021 model at a record low. Normally $50, the retailer is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09BKCDXZC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently offering the streaming device for $35&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s not dramatically different from its predecessor, Roku’s latest streaming stick is faster, comes with improved Wi-Fi performance, and supports Dolby Vision and HDR10 Plus. Roku’s players also now support AirPlay 2, so you can also use your iPhone, iPad, or Mac to easily cast content to the device. And, of course, the stick continues to offer access to popular streaming services, including Netflix, Hulu, Disney Plus, Vudu, Prime Video, HBO Max, Apple TV Plus, and Sling TV. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22727963/roku-streaming-stick-4k-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8tlEnn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10828277"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="nVyQld"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h1 id="3FgBnJ"&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/28/22748849/apple-airpods-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-lg-c1-oled-roku-streaming-stick-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/28/22748849/apple-airpods-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-lg-c1-oled-roku-streaming-stick-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T04:51:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T04:51:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s notch ‘fix’ brings fat bezels back to the MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wiu7VIMuMSoYQiWrrLF65mrNB_E=/0x0:2672x1781/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70055755/Screen_Shot_2021_10_28_at_1.13.50_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter user @Jatodaro demonstrates how to use the new ‘Scale to fit below built-in camera’ feature.&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/Jatodaro/status/1453382287328874497" target="_blank"&gt;@Jatodaro&lt;/a&gt; via Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sQKkP1"&gt;A new &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212842"&gt;support document&lt;/a&gt; released yesterday details a “&lt;em&gt;Scale to fit below built-in camera”&lt;/em&gt; option in macOS that will forcibly scale apps to only use the display below the notch. It’s a temporary workaround for apps that don’t currently play nice with the notch on Apple’s new MacBook Pros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FC8ZmZ"&gt;The camera notch cutout on Apple’s latest laptops was meant to enable a more expansive edge-to-edge screen. But as we saw yesterday, owners of the new MacBook Pro models have seen both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748371/apple-macbook-pro-notch-issues-inconsistencies-apps"&gt;apps and the OS misbehave&lt;/a&gt;, whereby app menus and status bar items can get hidden under the camera cutout. The scale-to-fit workaround fixes this, but results in the type of large bezels the notch was meant to negate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="98Uor4"&gt;The scaling feature was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Jatodaro/status/1453382287328874497"&gt;demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; by artist @Jatodaro on Twitter, showing how checking the box for &lt;em&gt;‘Scale to fit below built-in camera’&lt;/em&gt; in an app’s &lt;em&gt;Get Info&lt;/em&gt; window will shrink the display for all apps. The full-sized display (with notch) will only return if either the app is closed or if the box is unchecked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZuSL5X"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Good news for notch haters! If you've got an app (or apps) with menus that collide with the notch, just Get Info on the app, and enable "Scale to fit below built-in camera". &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the app is running (even in the bg), your display is scaled.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/M1Pro?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#M1Pro&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/M1Max?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#M1Max&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MacBookPro2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#MacBookPro2021&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/nlGqkFkXAH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/nlGqkFkXAH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Joseph from Sketch (@Jatodaro) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Jatodaro/status/1453382287328874497?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X7Qhs5"&gt;Apple also mentions in the support document that this scaling feature will disappear once developers update their apps to deal with the notch correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750236/apple-macbook-pro-hide-notch-fix-scale-to-fit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750236/apple-macbook-pro-hide-notch-fix-scale-to-fit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T16:39:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T16:39:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use SharePlay to share your FaceTime screen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vVae-cS6Azvyc1ojvyhJoeTGAOg=/151x0:1708x1038/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70054096/Screen_Shot_2021_10_27_at_3.39.30_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1rVwYI"&gt;One of the new features that iOS 15 has promised to offer is the ability to share your iPhone and iPad screen during FaceTime sessions so that you can enjoy films, music, and other media along with friends and family. While this new feature, called SharePlay, did not ship with the first version of iOS 15, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22732647/apple-ios-15-1-download-release-available-now"&gt;it has been included in iOS 15.1&lt;/a&gt; and can now be enjoyed — to a limited extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xoTigL"&gt;Currently, you can share content from Apple TV and Apple Music — assuming both of you are subscribers — and a few other apps. I had no problem sharing a YouTube video, for example; other apps that are supported include HBO Max, Hulu, and Disney Plus (but not Netflix). It can be presumed that the list of shareable apps will continue to expand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B82Gs8"&gt;It’s quite easy to use the new SharePlay feature, once you’ve installed iOS 15.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6YTBHh"&gt;Start a FaceTime session. Make sure whoever else is on the session also has iOS 15.1 installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gnLi6x"&gt;You should see a new icon on the upper right side of the screen that resembles a small figure in front of a screen. Tap on that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ApbjOw"&gt;You’ll see a drop-down button that says “Share My Screen.” Tap on that and you’ll be sharing your screen with your friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on “Share My Screen” to start using SharePlay." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uVCThijIWn6KU7YrpNwga9zSr58=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960467/IMG_DD5C33FA0874_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on “Share My Screen” to start using SharePlay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="SharePlay lets you both watch the same YouTube video." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Njh9Kxf8AiYyMVmvf0mlfAzZptA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960468/IMG_60BC16B3DB0E_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePlay lets you both watch the same YouTube video.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gOH64r"&gt;Now you can show off your homescreen to your FaceTime friend, play a YouTube video, or listen to the same Apple Music track. If you want to switch to the other person’s screen, all they have to do is tap on their SharePlay icon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkI9Sr"&gt;Another way to share an app is to simply go to that app during a FaceTime session and start it up. If SharePlay is possible, you will get a pop-up menu asking if you want to use SharePlay, or if you want to play the video or music only for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ox15m"&gt;And at any time, you can go back to your FaceTime app, tap on the SharePlay icon, and select End SharePlay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can see your friend’s home screen in miniature, or tap on it to maximize it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oIJXzKVleBy8TbXilrjRe4y9D28=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960470/IMG_B56CC427212E_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can see your friend’s homescreen in miniature, or tap on it to maximize it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Unfortunately, some apps are not yet supported." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YmKZe1FqMkh6pCpIlWooRMI5wDw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960475/IMG_B3896698408C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately, some apps are not yet supported.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XHryBS"&gt;The new SharePlay feature in iOS 15.1 is probably going to be very popular. It will allow friends and family to chat together while watching videos or listening to music; let business associates discuss a spreadsheet while out and about; or make it easier to share and comment on your latest group photos. And as Apple adds more apps that can make use of SharePlay, it should just get better.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22749161/iphone-ios-15-facetime-share-play"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22749161/iphone-ios-15-facetime-share-play</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T16:31:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T16:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s system to tell on creepy apps just arrived in beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JTD-U2p-SrpiBi62HoKVK65tcPk=/223x0:2416x1462/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70054031/Screen_Shot_2021_10_27_at_12.46.16.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q1L2lT"&gt;Apple’s App Privacy Report, announced at WWDC 2021, has &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=n5jlz7ox&amp;amp;1635379062"&gt;made its way onto iPhones&lt;/a&gt; with the first release of the iOS 15.2 beta, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/27/everything-new-ios-15-2/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The new screen in Settings gives users an overview of what information their apps have access to and what they’re sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HY1At2"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/0TD96VTf0Xs?t=3053"&gt;Apple’s WWDC announcement&lt;/a&gt;, the feature will show you what permissions apps have and how often they accessed them over the past week (for example, it could show that your weather app accesses your location every hour). The report will also show you which other web domains the app contacted and let you compare that with the sites you visited directly in the app to give you a better idea of who could be seeing your data. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ajuZM4lbuJsxSChLwSIK-RBGslA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960619/Screen_Shot_2021_10_27_at_12.32.28.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s Safari Privacy Report, which shows similar data but for the websites you visit instead of the apps you use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NXYzhT"&gt;Some of Apple’s other privacy initiatives haven’t sat well with all developers. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22296309/google-gmail-ios-app-privacy-labels"&gt;took Google almost two months&lt;/a&gt; to adopt iOS App Store privacy labels, and both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22745381/facebook-reality-labs-10-billion-metaverse"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738940/snap-q3-2021-earnings-ios-ad-tracking"&gt;Snap&lt;/a&gt; partially blamed the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;iPhone’s Ad Tracking Transparency feature&lt;/a&gt; (which lets users easily opt out of certain forms of ad tracking) for missed revenue goals. It’s possible that we’ll see more complaints from developers if the App Privacy Report paints them in a negative light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYgl6K"&gt;As always with betas, it’s not a sure-fire thing that this feature will make it into the final 15.2 release. However, Apple’s SharePlay feature, which showed up in the 15.1 beta (after being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629165/apple-shareplay-ios-ipad-os-15-macos-delayed"&gt;taken out from an earlier beta&lt;/a&gt; release), &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22732647/apple-ios-15-1-download-release-available-now"&gt;did end up shipping with the final version&lt;/a&gt;, so there’s a good chance we could see the privacy report soon. Whether we like what shows may be another story entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l5JoGh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LS8GMH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749352/apple-app-privacy-report-ios-15-2-beta-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749352/apple-app-privacy-report-ios-15-2-beta-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T11:50:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T11:50:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chinese students sue Apple for not including a charger with the iPhone 12</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OHfvlwkzpoAbgcEOjTGzpSEO4Pk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052302/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="poI4Sh"&gt;Five Chinese students are suing Apple for not providing a charger with the iPhone 12, first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7vqmb/apple-sued-china-iphone-chargers"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;stopped including EarPods and wall chargers with iPhones&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, opting only to include a USB-C to Lightning cable in its packaging. &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/10/apple-introduces-iphone-12-pro-and-iphone-12-pro-max-with-5g/"&gt;According to Apple&lt;/a&gt;, ditching the charger and EarPods is supposed to reduce carbon emissions and preserve raw materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qf2nzM"&gt;There’s some skepticism as to whether Apple really did this to cut costs, rather than save the environment, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519466/apple-iphone-12-chargers-airpods-greenhouse-gas-emissions-e-waste"&gt;the transition to 5G could make iPhones more expensive to make&lt;/a&gt;. Skipping out on chargers and EarPods could be a way for Apple to save a buck, and forcing customers to purchase accessories separately may help increase profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXtIhD"&gt;The students’ argument in court, which is a part of the Xiaocheng Cup Public Welfare Litigation Competition, cruxes on this premise. A report by the &lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/z4w89z7vhGdeTY2algqlYw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes the case in detail, noting that one of the students, named Xiaofang, was frustrated that her purchase of the iPhone 12 Pro Max didn’t come with a charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66GsW9"&gt;Xiaofang points out that since the cable included with the device is a USB-C to Lightning, it’s not compatible with the wall chargers that were previously included with Apple devices (via &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;). This means that customers will have to purchase a USB-C-compatible charger or a MagSafe charger if they don’t have one already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kxHSQY"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;, Xiaofang claims that Apple is leaving out wall chargers to promote its MagSafe chargers, a line of magnetic chargers that powers your phone wirelessly. She alleges that Apple’s decision not to include a charger is motivated by profit, and that Apple is merely operating under the guise of saving the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6aYMwb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="j5Bc3i"&gt;Xiaofang and her colleagues took Apple to the Beijing Internet Court, asking for Apple to provide a wall charger, as well as pay 100 yuan ($16) for breach of contract and for litigation fees (via &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;). As mentioned in the report by the &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;, a representative for Apple argued that it’s common for companies to sell phones without a charger and noted that the iPhone 12’s packaging makes it clear that no charger is included. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mFFHw1"&gt;The case is reportedly still in progress and has since gone viral on Chinese social media site Weibo, where the students have seen an outpouring of support (via &lt;a href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202110/1237420.shtml"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Suing Apple for such a small sum may seem odd, but it’s the statement that matters. According to the report by &lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt;, a Chinese student sued the Shanghai Disney Resort in 2019 for just 50 yuan ($7) for not letting customers bring food into the park — Disney later conceded and agreed to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uc0fCf"&gt;This isn’t the first time Apple has faced legal issues for not providing chargers. Earlier this year, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22342051/brazil-regulator-fines-apple-2-million-chargers-iphone-12"&gt;Brazilian regulator fined Apple $2 million&lt;/a&gt; for failing to include chargers with the iPhone 12, alleging that Apple is misleading the customer by selling it without one.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748474/chinese-students-sue-apple-including-charger-iphone-12"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748474/chinese-students-sue-apple-including-charger-iphone-12</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T11:13:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T11:13:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music officially launches on the PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nQuU-7Cr-UMxNhdtSzswTipThzM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052084/acastro_180927_1777_apple_music_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uOoQoN"&gt;Apple Music is coming to a gaming console, and it’s &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/10/27/apple-music-launches-on-ps5-today/"&gt;the PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt;. The new app lets Apple Music subscribers stream music on Sony’s latest console, similar to what was already available with Spotify. Audio can play in the background while you’re gaming or just play on its own. Instructions on how to set up Apple Music for your PS5 are available &lt;a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/subscriptions/set-up-apple-music/"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple Music running on the PlayStation 5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oiom00ANabhzFV9dcfx3zw2ePHA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22959764/FCtqOYEWYAkJdCy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple Music running on the PlayStation 5&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LN1ATV"&gt;This is the PS5’s second major integration with an Apple service; both Sony and Microsoft’s next-gen gaming platforms &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528372/ps5-streaming-apps-support-day-one-netflix-disney-plus-twitch"&gt;launched with the Apple TV Plus app last year&lt;/a&gt;. Sony extended the partnership to offer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588577/ps5-sony-apple-tv-plus-six-month-trial-subscription"&gt;six months of free Apple TV Plus membership&lt;/a&gt; to PS5 owners earlier this year. Having Apple Music on a console is a nice addition if you’re looking to simplify your TV setup and avoid having to switch too much between dedicated streaming boxes and built-in apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0VmYJa"&gt;News of the PS5’s Apple Music app emerged after a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AppleMusic/comments/q68jxg/since_when_was_this_a_thing_i_made_a_new_account/?ref=share&amp;amp;ref_source=link"&gt;Reddit user spotted&lt;/a&gt; the streaming service in the console’s music menu, and &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-10-14-it-looks-like-apple-music-may-be-coming-to-playstation-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; was subsequently able&lt;/a&gt; to get the icon to appear by creating a new account. Apple Music is also available on Android, Amazon Echo, Chrome OS, Sonos, the web, and of course, Apple’s own range of hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22727865/sony-ps5-apple-music-app-streaming-game-console"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22727865/sony-ps5-apple-music-app-streaming-game-console</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s new TVs will soon support Apple AirPlay 2 and HomeKit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6nn16Ht5TdjOu74_4qjvsD-Ztnw=/183x0:2430x1498/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70051650/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_7.38.51_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2RuB2k"&gt;Amazon is now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22662673/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-price-features"&gt;making its own TVs&lt;/a&gt;, and today marks the release of the company’s Omni and 4-Series Fire TVs. As the 4K HDR sets start making their way to customers, Amazon is making one more last-minute announcement: it plans to add support for Apple’s AirPlay 2 and HomeKit features “soon.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iAFoJJ"&gt;AirPlay 2 makes it easy to play content on the TV screen from an iPhone, iPad, or Mac. And HomeKit integration will allow the Omni and 4-Series TVs to be controlled by Siri or the Home app; it also makes it easy to include them in smart home routines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGUV78"&gt;Amazon has already rolled out AirPlay 2 and HomeKit to &lt;a href="https://amazonfiretv.blog/apple-airplay-2-and-homekit-now-available-on-toshiba-and-insignia-4k-uhd-smart-fire-tv-2020-models-89188a0b0fb3"&gt;some of its “Fire TV Edition” TVs from Toshiba and Insignia&lt;/a&gt;. Curiously, these features have yet to come to the company’s standalone Fire TV streaming devices — including the just-released Fire TV Stick 4K Max. I’m not sure if that’s an intentional choice, but it’s a bit odd that Amazon is ready to announce support on day one for its brand-new TVs with nothing to share about AirPlay 2 coming to its cheaper devices. (Roku supports AirPlay 2 on both its players and Roku TVs.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XpXQrx"&gt;The Fire TV Omni series TVs offer the better picture quality of the two lines and come with built-in far-field microphones for hands-free Alexa voice commands. The 65-inch and 75-inch models support Dolby Vision HDR, though there are also smaller 43-, 50-, and 55-inch sizes available with HDR10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K0D51s"&gt;Stay tuned for our impressions of Amazon’s first self-branded 4K TVs in the days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="15I9Eu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747811/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-apple-airplay-2-homekit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747811/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-apple-airplay-2-homekit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T09:30:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T09:30:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple AirPods (third-gen) review: new design, same appeal</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The new regular AirPods get a lot right even before the gimmicky spatial audio part&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mYTlYX"&gt;For the first time since their introduction in 2016, Apple’s AirPods have a completely new design. The third-generation AirPods, priced at $179, bear a much closer resemblance to the AirPods Pro than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/20/14016568/apple-airpods-wireless-earpods-earbuds-review"&gt;long-stemmed original&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;second-gen pairs&lt;/a&gt;. Apple has upgraded their sound, added new features like spatial audio head tracking, made them more durable with IPX4 water resistance, and lengthened their battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFDLaT"&gt;What remains unchanged about the AirPods is their ease of use and deep integration with Apple’s ecosystem of devices including the iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple TV, and Apple Watch. If you’re living in Apple’s world, you still get exclusive features like the intuitive, just-hold-them-near-your-iPhone setup, audio sharing, automatic device switching, and other software tricks that have helped the AirPods stay atop the true wireless earbuds market by a wide margin. The third-generation AirPods also gain more extensive Find My support to help you locate them if they go missing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iup0oN"&gt;The AirPods Pro and AirPods Max didn’t even exist the last time Apple refreshed its standard AirPods. So the third-gen earbuds also establish more feature parity across the entire lineup. There are definitely still reasons to pick those products instead — active noise cancellation, namely — but anyone who’s ready to upgrade their original AirPods will find a lot to like with the new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LWOCkg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10826364"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="444ptP"&gt;These AirPods basically look like the AirPods Pro with their ear tips chopped off. They share similar contours, especially now that Apple has shortened the stems by 33 percent. There are also grilled black speakers, mics, and vents around each earbud. These hardware elements have become so prominent that I’m surprised Apple isn’t offering the new AirPods in black to help camouflage them. But nope: they still only come in white. Since their design is now so similar, Apple carried over the “force sensor” controls from the AirPods Pro, with an indent on each stem that designates where to press. The tap gestures from the old AirPods are gone. Apple’s non-remappable controls handle media playback, and you can summon Siri with a long press. But you’ve also got hands-free “Hey Siri” voice commands at your disposal for adjusting volume or changing up the playlist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfbDUX"&gt;Unlike the Pros, there are no silicone ear tips for a customizable fit: as with its previous standard AirPods, Apple sticks with a one-size-fits-most hard plastic design. They’re open-style earbuds that rest in your ears instead of extending deep into the ear canal. A lot of people love the barely there comfort of the AirPods. The main side effect of their open design is that they let in a ton of outside noise. For me, that’s always been a significant turnoff. But again, others value having the added awareness — be it for personal safety reasons or otherwise — and view this as an upside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GOF4UNksPfsgjJRt-H2qZmI9HNc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953794/IMG_0048_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The third-gen AirPods (below) are clearly cut from the same cloth as the AirPods Pro (above).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="die3Jr"&gt;Unfortunately, fit is where the old AirPods have always let me down. They just weren’t a good match for my large-ish ears and would come loose and fall out way too easily. All ears are different, and I know a ton of people who had no such issues. But I was expecting another round of disappointment when I put the third-gen AirPods into my ears for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nBcM1"&gt;Fortunately, the new shape fits my ears much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFVPQU"&gt;Apple says it conducted a ton of user research when designing the third-generation AirPods, involving thousands of ear scans, heat maps, and so on. And at least in my case, something about the new shape definitely works better. They’re staying put so well that I no longer feel the same anxiety about them tumbling onto the ground and down a sewer grate. That worry was always present with the older AirPods. The healthy dose of ambient sound remains, and I’m just someone who prefers earbuds that offer some quiet from the outside world. But I can finally say that Apple’s regular AirPods fit me, and that was never true previously. If you had issues with the original design, it’s worth giving these a try.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/woYRg7Y4GOzAoeIkIMHF92IN-90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953799/IMG_0047.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new AirPods have much shorter stems than before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YBojuP"&gt;The charging case now opens in landscape — just like the case for the AirPods Pro — but it’s noticeably smaller than that one. It’s closer in overall size to the original AirPods case, though a smidge thicker. The case still has a Lightning port for wired charging, and it also supports Qi-compatible wireless chargers. Apple says the new AirPods case is designed to work with the company’s MagSafe chargers. And sure enough, it grabs onto the circular MagSafe charging pad with the same perfect alignment as an iPhone 12 or 13. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nISprs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If the old AirPods never fit your ears, these might do the trick&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8V0LTd"&gt;But don’t expect to charge your earbuds by placing them on the back of Apple’s MagSafe-ready iPhones: there’s no reverse wireless charging. And to drive that point home, Apple told me it intentionally designed the AirPods case so that it doesn’t magnetically latch onto the back of those phones. You’ll feel some pull when sliding the case around the back of the phone, but it’s nowhere near enough force to keep the two attached. As for the actual battery life, Apple says the third-gen AirPods can hit six hours of continuous playback and a total of 30 hours counting case recharges. That’s a modest improvement over the five hours and “over 24 hours” estimates from the previous model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wiGbOD"&gt;Both the AirPods and their case are now rated IPX4 for water and sweat resistance. Plenty of people used the older generations for workouts, but the official certification gives added peace of mind if you’ll frequently be using these AirPods as a gym companion. There’s also a new “skin detection sensor” on each earbud that replaces the old IR sensor. It still tells the AirPods to pause when removed from your ears (or resume when placed back in), but Apple says this sensor can tell the difference between your ears or tight spaces like a pants pocket that might’ve fooled the previous AirPods into resuming playback if you put them in there without the case. It’s not difficult to envision future evolutions of this sensor tying into Apple’s health and fitness efforts. But for now it’s just there to make auto-pause more reliable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFY7Ex"&gt;Apple has completely redesigned the acoustic driver and amplifier in the third-gen AirPods. The company told me it aimed to give them a sound profile similar to the AirPods Pro. There’s only so much you can do with open-style earbuds to improve bass performance; these will never pack the same low-end punch as many upscale in-ear buds. But the new AirPods do sound noticeably fuller and more dynamic than their predecessors — and yes, very similar to the Pros. In the right ways, they still sound like AirPods, and they’re tuned to work equally well for music, watching videos, podcasts, games, and so on. But Apple says music is still far and away the leading thing people use their AirPods for, so it’s trying to deliver the best audio quality possible in this form factor. I’ve found that the open design often leads to a more spacious soundstage. The AirPods are still handily outperformed by top-tier earbuds like Sony’s WF-1000XM4 or the Bose QuietComfort Earbuds, but among other buds with an open design, they’re up there with the best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WK-mSuFuVOg5iUNkHQdRI1SwPYA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953803/IMG_0044.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The third-gen AirPods have redesigned drivers and support spatial audio with head tracking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lfClhR"&gt;To further enhance their sound, the new AirPods use the same adaptive EQ feature as the Pros and Max. There’s an inward-facing mic on each earbud that analyzes what you’re hearing and, so Apple claims, adjusts the output in real time to what’s best for your unique ear shape. But the thing about adaptive EQ is that it’s impossible to ever really know when it’s doing something — or what that something is. It’s invisible to the listener at all times, so there’s not much to say about it. There’s no telling whether the improved sound is due to the redesigned drivers, the inclusion of adaptive EQ, or a combination of both. The third-gen AirPods do a better job of steering audio into your ears, which also helps achieve that full-bodied sound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPpQJ6"&gt;But that brings us to the big trick Apple is advertising with the new AirPods: spatial audio with head tracking. Like the AirPods Pro and Max, the third-gen pair can dynamically adjust the sound in each earbud as you turn your head from side to side, keeping the sound source anchored to the iPhone, iPad, Mac, or Apple TV you’re watching. When you’re watching movies in Netflix, HBO Max, Disney Plus, Amazon Prime Video, or other popular apps, this head tracking can be an immersive, fun experience and mimics surround sound better than a regular stereo mix would. It really does add to the satisfaction of watching movies on my iPad Pro. And for those times when someone’s asleep at home and you can’t take advantage of your soundbar or surround system on the Apple TV, you can listen in private with AirPods and spatial audio head tracking. Apple has also thought of other use cases: on group FaceTime calls, spatial audio creates a sound field that places the voices where they’re positioned on your device’s screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="HUXc0F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We’re still in the early days of spatial audio — and you can tell&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="683JZk"&gt;But when it comes to music, it all feels far more gimmicky. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;I’ve written about Apple Music’s Dolby Atmos-powered spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; before, and everything there applies here. The feature works with all headphones, but only the third-gen AirPods, Pros, and Max add head tracking to the equation. That doesn’t really change where I stand on it. Spatial audio mixes can often sound objectively worse than their stereo counterparts. It takes a lot of work from engineers and producers to get the most from Atmos, and it remains obvious that a lot of albums available in spatial audio on Apple Music haven’t gotten that level of attention. Instruments and effects can sound out of place, vocals can get drowned out in the mix, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x1oiF2"&gt;The situation is improving as newer records are mixed for Atmos from the get-go. (And Atmos mixes do generally sound a lot better on actual Atmos home theater systems.) The recent Giles Martin remix of &lt;em&gt;Let It Be&lt;/em&gt; by The Beatles takes advantage of spatial audio well without trying to do too much. It has that feeling of being in the room with the band. But other examples, like Kacey Musgraves’ &lt;em&gt;Star-Crossed&lt;/em&gt;, don’t do anything for me that I don’t already get from the stereo version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BrGfV"&gt;In short, spatial audio can wow when it comes to video, but we’re still in the very early stages of the music side — and it’s not a reason to buy these earbuds yet. Apple makes it easy to switch back and forth between spatial audio and regular sound in Control Center. And iOS 15 actually lets you “spatialize” sound from apps like Spotify that don’t otherwise offer the feature. I guess that’s nice to have if you really find yourself loving this new way of listening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W73EEHXIiB114uTu-QbiD6XBZUY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953861/IMG_0049_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like all AirPods before them, the third-gen earbuds are positioned as the perfect iPhone accessory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ajGJmS"&gt;The AirPods have long been the champion of voice calls, and with the third-gen set, Apple is trying to improve the fidelity of FaceTime calls by using a new AAC-ELD codec for clearer voice reproduction. There’s also acoustic mesh on the outward-facing side of each AirPod that’s meant to reduce wind noise. Despite the shorter stems, overall microphone performance remains excellent and the new AirPods remain easy to recommend if you want earbuds that guarantee you’ll come through clearly on calls. Stay tuned for our video review for the full mic test — with Becca, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="1Vctld"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10826383"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W1Oafy"&gt;Apple has also given the new AirPods a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22711557/apple-lost-airpods-pro-max-find-my-network-now-available"&gt;deeper level of integration with its Find My app&lt;/a&gt;. You could always play a sound to find a missing (nearby) earbud or see the location where they were last connected to your phone. But now the third-gen AirPods get the same “find nearby” feature as the AirPods Pro and Max. This is an AirTags-like interface for pinpointing where the AirPods are if you’re in close proximity to them. It’s not as accurate as an AirTag, but the UI will tell you when the AirPods are “nearby” and then show “here” when you’re right near them. If they’re really nowhere to be found, you can also now enable lost mode and be alerted if your missing AirPods come within range of millions of other iOS devices. My favorite of the new Find My features are the separation alerts that automatically pop up if you leave your AirPods behind somewhere. That alone should prevent a lot of heartbreak and lost earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4aimgs"&gt;The new AirPods are the first big redesign of Apple’s massively popular true wireless earbuds. From a fit and comfort standpoint, I think Apple succeeded: these are still wonderfully lightweight earbuds, and they actually stay in my ears now. The sound quality has seen some refinement, and the third-gen AirPods are a better gym buddy than their predecessors. Plus you’ve got longer battery life and nice-to-have features like spatial audio head tracking — even if Apple is overselling it a bit. I’ll personally be sticking with the AirPods Pro and other earbuds that offer noise cancellation or at least some isolation. But if you prefer the open-style AirPods and have an older pair that can’t hold a charge anymore, these are a worthwhile upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Y3dZlM"&gt;But before you go getting locked deeper into Apple’s ecosystem, it’s worth exploring your options. The game has changed a lot since the second-gen AirPods were released, and it’s possible to find better sound quality among competitors like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637548/oneplus-buds-pro-review-specs-price-features"&gt;OnePlus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22323748/anker-liberty-air-2-pro-review-wireless-headphone-price"&gt;Anker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and others. If you can do without the frills, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;spend much less and still be happy&lt;/a&gt;. Still, if you’ve got an iPhone, none of those can deliver the same seamless experience as the AirPods. They’re still designed to perfectly complement Apple’s smartphone, and in that regard they don’t disappoint. Perhaps more than any other Apple product today, AirPods still just work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VQxXLI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
