<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-12T17:39:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T17:39:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T17:39:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple will clarify iCloud Private Relay error messages in iOS 15.3 to not blame cell carriers as much</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3DF4-0WNQ2LGPIXLaHWqCZAcq8o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70380977/cgartenberg_210917_4762_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CoeElR"&gt;Apple is updating the wording for iCloud Private Relay issues in the latest iOS 15.3 beta, clarifying that problems with the service may be an inadvertently switched-off setting and not issues with a customer’s specific cell carrier, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/12/icloud-private-relay-clarification-ios-15-3/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=webfeeds"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tUZct6"&gt;The old message put the blame for iCloud Private Relay not working squarely on the shoulders of cell carriers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ULsaTL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Relay is turned off for your cellular plan&lt;/strong&gt;. Your cellular plan doesn’t support ‌iCloud‌ Private Relay. With ‌iCloud‌ Private Relay turned off, this network can monitor your internet activity, and your IP address is not hidden from known trackers or websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="cQVN1J"&gt;Unsurprisingly, that wording &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported"&gt;led to confusion earlier this week&lt;/a&gt; when customers couldn’t get iCloud Private Relay to work on cellular connections. The issue, at least according to T-Mobile, was actually on Apple’s end: it seems that the company’s recent iOS 15.2 update toggled off Private Relay for cellular data by accident, not that T-Mobile, AT&amp;amp;T, and Verizon had suddenly disabled the feature from working on their networks. The new wording makes things a little clearer that the issue might be an accidentally toggled setting elsewhere in iOS and not a cell company problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ZAeNGD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Relay is turned off for your cellular plan&lt;/strong&gt;. Private Relay is either not supported by your cellular plan or has been turned off in Cellular Settings. With Private Relay turned off, this network can monitor your internet activity, and your IP address is not hidden from known trackers or websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ImUhRW"&gt;Apple has also updated its &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212614"&gt;iCloud Private Relay support document&lt;/a&gt; today to make it clearer that customers might not be able to use the feature if they’ve turned off the “Limit IP Address Tracking” toggle for specific Wi-Fi or cellular networks, along with how to fix that problem on their devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fh2k9M"&gt;Hopefully, the new support document, clarified language from Apple, and the confirmations from all three major US carriers will be enough to put this week’s iCloud Private Relay confusion behind everyone. Given that the service is still technically in beta, though, it’s probably a good thing that Apple is sorting out the bugs now before it turns the service on by default. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880835/apple-clarify-icloud-private-relay-error-messages-ios-15-3-cell-carriers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880835/apple-clarify-icloud-private-relay-error-messages-ios-15-3-cell-carriers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T14:30:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T14:30:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple patches HomeKit denial-of-service bug with new iOS update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DKIfW9xo6YGfBxgtaUb4cDK08us=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70380017/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9h7iO0"&gt;On Wednesday, Apple released the 15.2.1 version of iOS, a minor update to the mobile operating system that fixes bugs, including a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22865145/apple-ios-vulnerability-homekit-devices-bug-crash"&gt;denial-of-service vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; previously reported by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gvcEXU"&gt;The 15.2.1 patch addresses a vulnerability triggered through HomeKit, the software API for connecting smart home devices to iOS applications. If the vulnerability was exploited, HomeKit devices labeled with a very long name would cause iPhones and iPads to endlessly freeze, crash, and reboot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTLX5z"&gt;Since HomeKit device names are backed up to iCloud, signing in to the same iCloud account with a restored device would trigger the crash again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pec8D"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213043"&gt;security notification&lt;/a&gt; for the 15.2.1 update lists only one change, a fix for the HomeKit vulnerability. Details of the fix state that a “resource exhaustion issue was addressed with improved input validation,” presumably to prevent long HomeKit device names from being read into memory by iOS devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SQUHsu"&gt;Besides security updates, the patch also fixed a bug that impacted performance of third-party CarPlay apps and another that prevented the Messages app from loading certain photos sent via iCloud. Users can update iOS by opening the Settings app on a device and tapping “General,” then selecting “Software Update.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RE9TA"&gt;The HomeKit bug was discovered by security researcher Trevor Spiniolas, who &lt;a href="https://trevorspiniolas.com/doorlock/doorlock.html"&gt;published details on his blog&lt;/a&gt; on January 1st. At the time, Spiniolas accused Apple of being slow to respond to his initial disclosure, which was made in August 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FTr7iW"&gt;According to Spiniolas’ blog, the bug affects iOS versions at least as far back as 14.7 and likely before, meaning these devices are still vulnerable. Owners of iPhones or iPads should update their devices as soon as possible to benefit from the new update.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880493/apple-15-2-1-patch-ios-homekit-denial-of-service-vulnerability-fix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880493/apple-15-2-1-patch-ios-homekit-denial-of-service-vulnerability-fix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:45:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:45:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s largest iPad Pro with the M1 processor is $100 off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPad Pro with the Liquid Retina XDR display" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3c1n-CLOaIRAs0MA4nf51TOTOH8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378854/vpavic_210512_4592_0192.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The larger 12.9-inch iPad sports a Mini LED screen and more real estate for use with Apple’s Pencil.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mpzFb6"&gt;There is no better screen in the world of tablets (yet) than the Mini LED panel on the 12.9-inch iPad Pro of 2021. While Mini LED is not super common yet — though we did see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22871890/computer-monitors-ces-2022-lg-samsung-asus-alienware-oled-qd-mini-led-ark"&gt;more of it announced at CES 2022&lt;/a&gt; — it’s appealing as it achieves deeper black levels, a high contrast ratio, and high brightness. It’s also more expensive than a traditional LCD panel, so any dollar saved can be a worthwhile one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kcfaiz"&gt;If you want that Mini LED-equipped iPad Pro, we have a solid discount to share. Apple’s Wi-Fi-equipped base 128GB storage configuration is $100 off. This model usually runs for $1,099, but &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0932BKSLP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is selling it in the silver colorway for $999. The 2021 iPad Pro also packs Apple’s stellar M1 processor, ensuring its performance can not only push all those pixels but do so with speed and with the promise of enough performance headroom to likely stay that way for years to come. If you prefer more storage, you can get the 256GB configuration for $1,099 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-12-9-inch-iPad-Pro-2021-Wi-Fi-256GB-Space-Gray%2F385211636&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailydeals011222" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (also $100 off). &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VjMeBq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aYPmhE"&gt;The PowerA Fusion Pro wireless controller for Switch is an intriguing alternative to Nintendo’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/2/24/14699044/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-hands-on-preview"&gt;Switch Pro controller&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08XXTW41G?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has the Fusion Pro in its slick white-and-black colorway for $65.99, a savings of $34 off its usual price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zjE22"&gt;The PowerA Fusion Pro may be worth considering if you want to try something that’s as close as you can get to a Switch-equivalent to the Xbox Elite controller. It has customizable analog sticks and optional rear paddle buttons. When it’s wired to your Switch dock, its 3.5mm headphone jack can pipe game audio to your headphones. It also lacks some things found in the Switch Pro controller, like rumble and Amiibo support. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22608203/powera-fusion-pro-customizable-analog-sticks-paddles-nintendo-switch-controller-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lt5ZZK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10973226"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qrvxhl"&gt;From a cute white controller to a cute white camera, the Wyze Cam v3 is an inexpensive home camera that supports 1080p recording with weather resistance for outdoor use. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B095NWYQBC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has it with kitted out with a spotlight LED for just $36.60, saving about $16 and making it an excellent option for monitoring a front door, like a mini flood light for a much cheaper price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cq87FF"&gt;The Wyze Cam v3 also supports both color and black-and-white night vision, so its ability to see in the dark is quite good even when the spotlight is not in use. These little cameras are some of the most affordable ones around, offering solid video quality with motion detection, two-way audio, and support for both Alexa and Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mnpk7X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Wyze’s security camera pay-what-you-want subscription accepts $0","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879759/wyze-cam-plus-lite-pay-what-you-want-subscription-person-detection-cloud-recordings-12-seconds"},{"title":"Wyze’s cameras can now be a monitored home security system","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750594/wyze-cams-monitored-security-smart-switches-price-release-date-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="hVbINL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10973234"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tAKO0S"&gt;While the recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22870203/ces-2022-best-of-gadgets-concepts-tech"&gt;CES 2022&lt;/a&gt; announcements featured new innovations &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865220/sony-a95k-qd-oled-qdoled-4k-tv-announced-features-explainer"&gt;coming to OLED TVs&lt;/a&gt;, the promise of even better tech will ultimately bring us even more expensive OLEDs. As for the here and now, the 48-inch LG A1 OLED is $846.99 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-Built-Refresh-AI-Powered-OLED48A1PUA/dp/B092LZNZB7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, saving $353 off MSRP. The A1 may not be the top tier in LG’s lineup, but if you don’t need a giant TV you can’t go wrong saving money on this affordable panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XiTCRr"&gt;OLEDs are a great choice in general for deeper black levels and excellent contrast, but you don’t have to break the bank. We have featured the popular LG C1 OLED TVs numerous times, though today’s deal on its entry-level A1 counterpart gets us below $1,000 — not something you see every day for OLED. Unlike the C1, which features a 120Hz refresh rate and HDMI 2.1 ports, the A1 tops out at 60Hz and doesn’t support 4K at 120Hz. Still, it seems like a solid TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LyFvW0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10959416"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tj92BW"&gt;More deals to deal with:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="L6SAZv"&gt;The Razer Nari Essential gaming headset is a bit long in the tooth, but if you don’t mind Micro-USB charging it seems like a fine wireless headset for just $41.99 ($58 off MSRP) at &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836602-13527013?sid=vergedailydeals011222&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcomputers.woot.com%2Foffers%2Frazer-nari-essential-gaming-headset-27" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a new all-time low, though it’s also available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Nari-Essential-Wireless-Auto-Adjusting/dp/B07HZ5N8QT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $49.99.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="msGnnF"&gt;GoPro’s latest Hero10 Black action camera is still $429.99 ($70 off) at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1658382-REG%2Fgopro_chdhx_101_hero10_black.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F12%2F22878428%2Fapple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/GoPro-HERO10-Black-Waterproof-Stabilization/dp/B09CS9X5F5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, the lowest price available on this cam launched in the late summer of 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22675560/gopro-hero10-action-camera-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oxbzCp"&gt;If you’re looking to use video games to get in shape for a New Year’s resolution, not only is &lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ring-Fit-Adventure-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B07XV4NHHN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;still on sale for $54.99&lt;/a&gt; ($25 off) but now &lt;em&gt;Fitness Boxing 2: Rhythm &amp;amp; Exercise&lt;/em&gt; is also on sale for $34.99 ($15 off) from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitness-Boxing-Exercise-Standard-Digital/dp/B08JZN6T9M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; as a Nintendo Switch digital download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6ahcA9"&gt;Lenovo’s Smart Clock 2 with wireless charging dock is just $69.99 ($20 off) at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgo6mfTa46d" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and makes for a handy companion to sit beside your bedside table. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22714538/lenovo-smart-clock-2-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="Wepfnf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7s3iGw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 1:50PM ET, January 12th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Amazon price of the 48-inch LG A1 OLED TV increased from $796.99 to $846.99, and has been updated in the copy and product card.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/12/22878428/apple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/12/22878428/apple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T09:51:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T09:51:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to mute a word or phrase on Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K9L9qO_CtfLAzWvVWNfupkuPkNE=/0x0:900x600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378592/twitter.0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tweet-user-name"&gt;In February 2020,  I found that that it was possible not only to mute conversations or other accounts on Twitter, but (courtesy of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nonprofWHIT/status/1229964006330380289?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1229964006330380289%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F2%2F19%2F21144097%2Ftwitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to-settings-phone-desktop"&gt;a tweet by @nonprofWHIT&lt;/a&gt; ) that you could also mute a specific &lt;em&gt;word&lt;/em&gt;. And you could do it straight from a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZRtti"&gt;Now, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1480958895287939072?s=20"&gt;Twitter has announced&lt;/a&gt; it is expanding this feature so that when you mute a word or phrase, it will not appear in your Explore tab or Event-based notifications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CalAyd"&gt;Here’s how you go about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cPBAYz"&gt;Mute words or phrases on an iPhone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="kiOUjU"&gt;If you’re using the Twitter app on an iPhone, it’s a quick and easy process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WDHN6T"&gt;Long-press on the word you want to mute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="olIheA"&gt;Choose “Mute” from the pop-up menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PEzRpO"&gt;You’ll be sent to a page where you can choose from where you want to mute the word (your timeline or notifications), from whom (anyone or people you don’t follow), and the duration (forever, 24 hours, seven days, or 30 days). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Long-press on the word you want to mute. " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ct4FjssBFbrPRlqSFHRIEaTYgSg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19731703/IMG_589D3687AA11_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long-press on the word you want to mute. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select where you want to mute it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dDH9hXswL9-N6bXW-V0tYJdiQvU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19731705/IMG_BB887E06D435_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select where you want to mute it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VevJJq"&gt;Mute words or phrases on an Android phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QEISnd"&gt;If you’ve got an Android phone, don’t despair. You can also mute words from the Android Twitter app (or, for that matter, from the iOS Twitter app) through the app’s settings. It’s not quite as fast as doing it directly from a tweet, but it’s just as effective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dioGVM"&gt;Select your icon on the upper left corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="86FxuH"&gt;Select “Settings and privacy” &amp;gt; “Privacy and safety” &amp;gt; “Mute and block.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aUmPGy"&gt;Tap “Muted words.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IWrdR2"&gt;Tap the plus sign and enter the word you want to mute. You then get the same choices as to where, from whom, and duration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In Android, you mute using settings." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nTl99kR7ncdZUAn443VgaOsHAHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161869/Screenshot_20220111_164607.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Android, you mute using settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Enter each word or phrase separately." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h4oiyYduCftQXYz_BYEYRnba7lA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161872/Screenshot_20220111_164831.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter each word or phrase separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="78Fb6s"&gt;If you no longer want to mute the word or you want to extend the mute time, return to the “Muted words” screen, tap on the word in question, and choose the corresponding option (“Delete word” or “Change mute time”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can always delete the muted word." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MJM9RKxdhhrJusCZm98IBsSy0b8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161887/Screenshot_20220111_164953.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can always delete the muted word.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Are you sure?" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0RO26hyhtA6H-OU6WSHsyeWV9GM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161886/Screenshot_20220111_165009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you sure?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yGqJr7"&gt;Mute words or phrases on your desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kIw7dK"&gt;And finally, if you’re tweeting directly from Twitter’s website, you can mute a word from there as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mUDyjq"&gt;On your desktop, from the left-hand menu, click on “More” &amp;gt; “Settings and privacy” &amp;gt; “Privacy and safety” &amp;gt; “Mute and block.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PlrwIF"&gt;In the right column, click on “Muted words.” Click on the plus sign in the upper right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0x5wni"&gt;Now you can enter the word or phrase you want to mute. As with the mobile Twitter apps, you can choose whether to mute from your timeline or notifications, from anyone or people you don’t follow, and for how long. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="On a desktop, you first find the “Mute and block” section." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sLiNAOQx6_OtIxogeghXdLHom1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161973/Screen_Shot_2022_01_11_at_4.59.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On a desktop, you first find the “Mute and block” section.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1BIzId"&gt;When you’ve made all your choices, click on “Save.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4rpSnz"&gt;If you want to unmute any words, go back to the “Muted words” column. Click on the red crossed-out volume symbol to the right of the word, and then click “Unmute” on the pop-up window that appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="It’s simple to go back and unmute a word or phrase." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R66EzpN58QfNo7ElEtgaP5xvr2Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161974/Screen_Shot_2022_01_11_at_5.01.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s simple to go back and unmute a word or phrase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7KYdrh"&gt;Some additional notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MIsPI2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/advanced-twitter-mute-options"&gt;Twitter has a number of ways&lt;/a&gt; you can mute different types of info in your timeline and notifications. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Tr9Tbt"&gt;You can also mute specific mentions of specific accounts (but not mute the account itself) by using the @ in front of the account name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hRELIu"&gt;If you mute a word, you will also mute that word’s hashtag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="znDiJJ"&gt;Muting is not case-sensitive (“spoilers” and “SPOILERS” will both work), and you can use a phrase with punctuation (“Hey, you!”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mdxx9i"&gt;Twitter is expanding the ability to mute words, phrases, etc. to areas other than timelines and notifications. Just yesterday, it announced that blocked or muted text would also no longer appear in Events-based areas:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="y91ggM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;First up, Events. Now across Android, iOS, and web, Events from accounts you’ve blocked or muted won’t appear in your Explore tab, “What’s happening” sidebar and emails, or Event-based notifications.&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1480958895287939072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 11, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="56qsSQ"&gt;If / when the ability to mute is extended even further, we’ll add it to this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W3o5ip"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 12th, 2022, 10:00AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on February 19th, 2020, and has been updated to allow for UI changes and new features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22878708/twitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22878708/twitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T20:31:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T20:31:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Wordle clones have disappeared from the App Store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2zZmq0Lstg1m_wcC2YCTG26fErM=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70377148/VRG_ILLO_4536_001_7.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier today, the App Store was overflowing with games ripping off a viral web app. &lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QLIZAP"&gt;Has Apple taken action against apps that cloned the popular web game Wordle? They have now disappeared from the App Store, after &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/11/psa-wordle-clone-with-annual-subscription-is-the-latest-rip-off-to-hit-the-app-store/"&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/wordle-copycat-app-store-twitter"&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase"&gt;including &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) called out a flood of copycats so blatant as to be named “Wordle” and that featured the same gameplay and UI, each taking advantage of the fact that developer Josh Wardle didn’t create an Apple app of his own. While we’re still seeing a few clones on the App Store, they don’t use the Wordle name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMeMb6"&gt;The clone apps had a spotlight shone on them today, when one developer &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/tech-dude-rips-off-wordle-angers-internet-1848341422"&gt;started bragging about how many downloads his version of Wordle was getting&lt;/a&gt;. Following some intense backlash from the community, he set his account to private, but people had already started finding many other apps like it on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eXFsor"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The App Store clones are here to profit off Wordle’s success","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yYQOJeNtNEEZB_72WBwboMnXZj4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23162051/IMG_3661.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The search results for Wordle at 5PM ET today, showing two clones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cBxGL0BzrKpXmt9N2ro0h_yUC18=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23162334/IMG_3666.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The search results for Wordle at 8:08PM ET — the first results are now an app from five years ago, and a story about Words With Friends 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fdr2q4"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately respond to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s request for confirmation that it was the one that took action against the Wordle-alikes, but it seems vanishingly unlikely that each developer decided to take down their app in the space of about an hour. If Apple really is initiating a crackdown on the apps, it’s tipping the scales significantly to protect the original game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KGNEZ"&gt;While there have been similar high-profile situations in the past — &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/bulletins/wordle-clone-ios-mobile-gaming"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/11/5401552/the-weird-world-of-flappy-bird-clones"&gt;Flappy Bird&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/3/28/5556760/threes-developer-releases-emails-showing-work-in-reply-to-clones"&gt;Threes vs 2048&lt;/a&gt; come to mind — it’s hard to think of a recent example where Apple stepped in as heavily as it seems to have done today. Apple &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/#copycats"&gt;does have language about copycats in its developer guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s notably vague: “Come up with your own ideas,” section 4.1 reads. “Don’t simply copy the latest popular app on the App Store, or make some minor changes to another app’s name or UI and pass it off as your own.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ooG9T"&gt;There have been &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/21/apple-goes-after-clones-and-spam-on-the-app-store/"&gt;questions about how Apple would deal with blatant clones&lt;/a&gt;, as it’s seemingly let things slide in some instances. With disappearance of the Wordle-alikes from the App Store, we may have gotten a precedent for how similar is too similar. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22879295/wordle-clones-app-store-removal-online-backlash-copycats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22879295/wordle-clones-app-store-removal-online-backlash-copycats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T19:23:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T19:23:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon, AT&amp;T, and T-Mobile say they’re not blocking Apple’s iCloud Private Relay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bVCnW6IcjHg1auWUvneXHpkTC_U=/128x0:1073x630/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70376980/og__ishslgdhhimq.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gsPVr9"&gt;T-Mobile, Verizon, and AT&amp;amp;T — the three biggest US cellular carriers — have all confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that they aren’t blocking Apple’s new iCloud Private Relay feature, following reports that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"&gt;some customers were having issues&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"&gt;with the VPN-like feature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kjO0fq"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon straight-up say they’re not blocking the feature from functioning. Verizon spokesperson George L. Koroneos confirms that Private Relay works on both cellular and Fios internet connections, and AT&amp;amp;T spokesperson Seth Bloom says the carrier’s policy is not to block Private Relay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9IG6Sn"&gt;T-Mobile’s situation is a little more complex: most customers shouldn’t have any issues with iCloud Private Relay. But those who use content filtering services (like the carrier’s Family Controls) won’t be able to use iCloud Private Relay, the carrier tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fa5X2u"&gt;“Customers who chose plans and features with content filtering (e.g. parent controls) do not have access to the iCloud Private Relay to allow these services to work as designed. All other customers have no restrictions,” T-Mobile spokesperson Bennet Ladyman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. That tracks with Apple’s messaging around the feature, which notes that “Networks that require the ability to audit traffic or perform network-based filtering will block access to Private Relay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uuaZLl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"T-Mobile identifies issue that prevented some iPhone users from using Private Relay","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="X5VL8i"&gt;T-Mobile’s spokesperson also told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the carrier &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; find an issue with Apple’s recent iOS 15.2 update that caused iCloud Private Relay to be toggled off following the update. “Overnight our team identified that in the 15.2 iOS release, some device settings default to the feature being toggled off. We have shared this with Apple. This is not specific to T-Mobile.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LnIzGG"&gt;If the problem really is on Apple’s end, it could also explain the issues that some Verizon or AT&amp;amp;T customers may have been experiencing in the wake of the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o68AKN"&gt;That said, it’s possible that carriers may sour on supporting Apple’s privacy feature in the future. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.telegraph.co.uk%2Fbusiness%2F2022%2F01%2F09%2Fapple-fire-iphone-encryption-tech%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22878885%2Fverizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Telegraph&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Vodafone, Telefonica, Orange, and T-Mobile have all signed a joint letter asking the European Commission to block Private Relay, arguing that the feature is “cutting off other networks and servers from accessing vital network data and metadata, including those operators in charge of the connectivity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZv0Sy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;iCloud Private Relay&lt;/a&gt; is similar in many ways to a VPN, working to automatically mask your internet traffic from both Apple, your ISP, and anyone else trying to snoop around what you’re doing online. The feature is still in beta but is currently available to anyone subscribing to a paid iCloud plan — although Apple doesn’t keep it toggled on by default, at least for now. There are other limitations, too: Private Relay won’t let you spoof your internet as coming from outside your rough geographic area (a popular use for VPNs to get around national or regional content limits), and it only works in Apple’s own Safari browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Apm9t5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22878885/verizon-att-t-mobile-apple-icloud-private-relay-feature-supported</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T18:57:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T18:57:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>The App Store clones are here to profit off Wordle’s success</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lw21bUEW8l0kQjcVdBZ7XBEnmGI=/16x0:1110x729/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70376898/IMG_3664.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copies of the popular web app have made it past App Review.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Oddcq1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.powerlanguage.co.uk/wordle/"&gt;Wordle&lt;/a&gt;, the word-guessing puzzle game that’s &lt;a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2022/01/09/lifestyle/what-is-wordle-why-is-everyone-twitter-playing-it/"&gt;taken over our Twitter timelines&lt;/a&gt;, doesn’t currently have an official app. That may come as a surprise to anyone who’s searched for it on the App Store, though — earlier today, doing so would show you several blatant unofficial copies, each of which use the same name and mechanics as the original, which &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2022/jan/11/wordle-creator-overwhelmed-by-global-success-of-hit-puzzle"&gt;was made by Josh Wardle&lt;/a&gt; and distributed on the web for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iobEAS"&gt;Most people who’ve been online recently will have had at least some exposure to Wordle if they haven’t been playing it themselves (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2022/jan/11/wordle-creator-overwhelmed-by-global-success-of-hit-puzzle"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; it has 2 million daily players). It’s a simple concept but done well: each day, you go to the Wordle website, where you’re given six chances to guess a five-letter word. The game gives you feedback about what letters you’ve put in the right place, what letters are in the word, but not in the order you’ve picked and what letters aren’t in the correct answer. Certain parts of Twitter have been taken over by black, green, and yellow square emojis, which players use to show off their gameplay without spoiling the word of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="io8n5e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As with many good viral ideas, Wordle has spawned waves of parodies and memes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sVgm5Z"&gt;As happens to most good ideas (especially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/11/5401552/the-weird-world-of-flappy-bird-clones"&gt;the ones that go viral&lt;/a&gt;), there have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2022/1/11/22877996/wordle-spoofs-alternatives-letterle-sweardle-queerdle"&gt;several clever parodies of Wordle&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Fobwashed/status/1480975713620541440"&gt;waves of jokes&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter using the emoji block format that players use to share their scores. But while many of the parody versions point users back to the original, this doesn’t seem to be the case for the versions on the App Store. Instead, they try their best to look like the web version without mentioning that they’re actually a spin-off. Trying out five versions of the game from the App Store, only one seemed to acknowledge Wardle’s version — ironically, it was one of the few that didn’t actually call itself Wordle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GOchjE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10973311"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="7978Mo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data="{&amp;quot;stories&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The weird world of 'Flappy Bird' clones&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/11/5401552/the-weird-world-of-flappy-bird-clones&amp;quot;}]}"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9wtMf3"&gt;The situation is a little embarrassing for Apple, which has often cited its high standards and App Review process as a reason it should be allowed to keep control over which apps run on iPhones and iPads. The review process has been called into question by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454468/ios-app-scam-review-3-star-force-review-process-apple"&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;scams&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;controversies&lt;/a&gt;, but these feel especially blatant — they’re using the same name and have an extremely similar interface to the original. It’s easy to see many people being tricked into thinking that they’re playing an official version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bEfdJN"&gt;Even worse is that the apps are copying a website, months after Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417725/apple-vs-epic-full-trial-slideshows-opening-arguments"&gt;championed&lt;/a&gt; progressive web apps in court as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22421912/iphone-web-app-pwa-cloud-gaming-epic-v-apple-safari"&gt;an option for developers during its legal battle with Epic Games&lt;/a&gt;. That argument may fall flat with developers targeting mobile audiences. As Owen Williams, a UX manager, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ow/status/1480984480538005504?s=20"&gt;points out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, they won’t even get a seat at the table when someone searches for their creation on the App Store (which is something a lot of people might do if they, say, see a flurry of tweets with the name of a Cool New Thing everyone’s playing with).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tyno2K"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If Apple and Google were *actually* allowing proper competition, you’d be able to register a PWA/web app in their stores if you choose that route instead of a native app. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But uh, that doesn’t help build their walled gardens so we get…this&lt;/p&gt;— Owen Williams ⚡ (@ow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ow/status/1480984480538005504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 11, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vqJ57J"&gt;To add insult to injury, it appears that Wordle clones aren’t nearly as rampant on Google’s Play Store. Only one of the first two dozen search results for “wordle” appeared to be a clone, and it was buried deep behind a “show more” button. Google Play reports the app has “500+ downloads” — the developer behind one of the Wordle clones on iOS claimed to be getting 5,400 downloads an hour on Twitter, and their version wasn’t even in the top three search results. (The same developer tweeted a screenshot of a notification saying that their app was waiting for review, with the caption “let’s see what Apple thinks” prior to the app going live.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LibNuw"&gt;Wardle hasn’t monetized his version of Wordle with ads, subscriptions, one-time payments, or a tip jar. It’s totally free. According to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/03/technology/wordle-word-game-creator.html"&gt;a profile in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he made the game for his partner, who enjoyed crossword puzzles. “I think people kind of appreciate that there’s this thing online that’s just fun,” Wardle said of Wordle’s success. “It’s not trying to do anything shady with your data or your eyeballs. It’s just a game that’s fun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="3yUEzd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re going to the fucking moon”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hkZLp8"&gt;The Wordle apps I tried haven’t copied the original’s lack of a monetization scheme. Some showed a plethora of ads, often with the option of paying to remove them, and one even had a $30-a-year in-app purchase to unlock the “Pro” version. (That particular app’s developer said on their now-private Twitter account that the app was “going to the fucking moon” and that one of their goals for 2022 was to “make tons of fucking money.”) Paying would let you choose how many letters you wanted in the words and would allow multiple games a day. As &lt;a href="https://slate.com/culture/2022/01/wordle-game-online-free-explained.html"&gt;many have noted&lt;/a&gt;, the real Wordle’s once-a-day play is another one of the things that makes it so appealing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ugXCOB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Added a share button to Wordle that generates a spoiler-free emoji grid for you. Shoutout to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/irihapeta?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@irihapeta&lt;/a&gt; for inventing such a cool way to share your results each day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;⬛⬛⬛⬛⬛&lt;br&gt; ⬛  ⬛&lt;br&gt;     &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wordle 180 3/6&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Try it out: &lt;a href="https://t.co/pZTmeT1p7E"&gt;https://t.co/pZTmeT1p7E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Josh Wardle (@powerlanguish) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/powerlanguish/status/1471493886031773707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OYMB2N"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wordle’s developer explaining the game’s share function.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I3SU7O"&gt;Most of the apps I tried didn’t have any obvious copies of the original’s share feature, which lets you easily copy a series of spoiler-free blocks to share with friends or on social media. The one that offered the $30 subscription, however, did — adding a few extra words and saying “The Wordle App” in place of Wordle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tqv7X7"&gt;Keeping blatant copies off the App Store might not be an easy moderation task if Apple wanted to do it — for example, there are a few games on the App Store that share the “Wordle” name but not gameplay. However, they’re pretty obviously not trying to capitalize on a trend by copying a popular app — many of them haven’t been updated in years (and are therefore not likely requiring any judgment calls from App Review). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4VdUXQ"&gt;It appears that Apple has decided to try, though. Roughly an hour after we published this post, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1481063416630583300"&gt;we heard&lt;/a&gt; that the clones had started disappearing from the App Store. All the ones we saw that used the word “Wordle” in their title are now gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdiT6Q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to both Apple and one of the developers behind a Wordle clone. Neither responded to our request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hw18VC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 7:50PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added that Wordle clones are now disappearing from the App Store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pQigNf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, January 12th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The original version of this article stated that you get five tries to guess the Wordle word, when you actually get six. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T15:10:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T15:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile identifies issue that prevented some iPhone users from using Private Relay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a679SQQpMlD7hp-oo9jH_r4cJPA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70372164/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4lX89e"&gt;T-Mobile said Tuesday that it had not blocked iCloud Private relay, and that it had identified what was causing some iPhone users to appear blocked from using the feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OE9nGi"&gt;“Overnight our team identified that in the 15.2 iOS release, some device settings default to the feature being toggled off. We have shared this with Apple. This is not specific to T-Mobile. Again though, we have not broadly blocked iCloud Private,” the company &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1480987702363189248?s=20"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reporter Mark Gurman. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HhyPo0"&gt;iCloud Private Relay lets users hide the websites they visit from third parties, according to a report from &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/10/t-mobile-block-icloud-private-relay/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;VPN-like Private Relay&lt;/a&gt; hides your web activity from any outside sources — including Apple and your carrier — and prevents anyone from identifying you or the sites you access. It’s currently available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc"&gt;via a subscription to iCloud Plus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5ygsEB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TMobileHelp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TMobileHelp&lt;/a&gt; What the hey?  Why are you keeping us from using &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; ‘s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/icloud?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#icloud&lt;/a&gt; private relay? &lt;a href="https://t.co/EtdxkVSpWh"&gt;pic.twitter.com/EtdxkVSpWh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jon Guidry (@guidryjd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/guidryjd/status/1480599787577696260?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 10, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hwCA9M"&gt;Private Relay is still in beta in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, and it isn’t turned on by default. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573519/apple-private-relay-icloud-plus-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-how-to"&gt;You have to go into your iPhone’s settings to switch it on&lt;/a&gt;, which is where some T-Mobile customers first noticed the message above appearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z095du"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/guidryjd/status/1480631410239094797?s=20"&gt;a reply to that tweet&lt;/a&gt;, the user shows what happens when you click the “Learn More” button below the initial message — there, Apple explains why T-Mobile might be blocking the feature. “Networks that require the ability to audit traffic or perform network-based filtering will block access to Private Relay,” it reads. “Your cellular provider may be providing network-based services, such as Parental Controls, requiring them to view the traffic on your network.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7oYDJF"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://tmo.report/2022/01/t-mobile-blocking-icloud-private-relay-for-some-but-its-not-what-you-think/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The T-Mo Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;iCloud Private Relay conflicts with a number of T-Mobile services, but that doesn’t appear to be the case here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j4ZROa"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/10/european-carriers-seek-to-block-iphone-private-relay-feature/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;iPhone users in Europe were the first to notice that access to the Private Relay feature wasn’t working. T-Mobile, Vodafone, and Telefonica added their names to an open letter published in &lt;a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2022/01/09/apple-fire-iphone-encryption-tech/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that criticizes the feature. Carriers argue that Private Relay “will impair others to innovate and compete in downstream digital markets and may negatively impact operators’ ability to efficiently manage telecommunication networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWnp0v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 11th, 4:48AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated with additional &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://tmo.report/2022/01/t-mobile-blocking-icloud-private-relay-for-some-but-its-not-what-you-think/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;reporting by The T-Mo Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k79kN0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 11th 3:00PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated throughout with comment from T-Mobile about the cause of the issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0rTF96"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877211/t-mobile-iphone-private-relay-block</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T14:43:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T14:43:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s $19 polishing cloth is back in stock online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3BFtKsVDD9wBdeVm05pluPcOn08=/0x167:1000x834/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70375574/MM6F3_AV2.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can buy the cloth once again.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PGwWdl"&gt;Apple’s $19 polishing cloth is back in stock &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1235321/7613?subId1=Verge%252C%2520Apple%2520Polishing%2520Cloth%2520News%2520Post%252C%25201%252F11%252F22&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMM6F3AM%2FA%2Fpolishing-cloth" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;at the company’s online store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/11/the-nightmare-is-over-the-apple-polishing-cloth-is-back-in-stock-and-ready-to-ship/"&gt;as spotted by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The very expensive piece of cloth was first introduced following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices"&gt;Apple’s October event&lt;/a&gt;, but it was quickly backordered — &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/11/apple-polishing-cloth-in-stock/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it was “impossible” to get one before the holidays — so if you’ve been waiting to get one, now’s your chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SIrJTx"&gt;“Made with soft, nonabrasive material, the Polishing Cloth cleans any Apple display, including nano-texture glass, safely and effectively,” reads Apple’s description of the cloth on its product page. Sounds perfect if you need to clean a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"&gt;Pro Display XDR&lt;/a&gt; with the nano-texture glass screen. That already costs $5,999 — the nano-texture glass is a $1,000 upgrade from the &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1235321/7613?subId1=Verge%252C%2520Apple%2520Polishing%2520Cloth%2520News%2520Post%252C%25201%252F11%252F22&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fpro-display-xdr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;standard model&lt;/a&gt; — and if you want Apple’s official stand for the display, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/6/3/18651001/apples-mac-pro-xdr-display-monitor-stand-expensive-dongle-not-included-wwdc-2019"&gt;you’ll have to drop an additional grand&lt;/a&gt;, so what’s another $19 for the company’s polishing cloth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="StcXNF"&gt;It appears that the cloth isn’t in stock at the company’s retail stores; it isn’t available for in-store pickup at any of the stores near me. If you order one as I write this, though, Apple says it will be delivered by Friday. While you’re waiting for your order to arrive, don’t miss &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FNews%2F54122%2Fmacbook-pro-2021-teardown%23cloth&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F11%2F22878673%2Fapple-polishing-cloth-in-stock-online" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iFixit’s actual teardown of the cloth&lt;/a&gt; — which is actually &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753184/ifixit-apple-polishing-cloth-19-repair-backorder"&gt;more interesting than you might expect&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878673/apple-polishing-cloth-in-stock-online"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878673/apple-polishing-cloth-in-stock-online</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-11T14:22:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T14:22:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>The excellent Beats Fit Pro earbuds are coming to many more countries on January 28th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7ayG7Wf6Tozvi1zlC44rD7MSdLg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70375456/DSCF6033_Edited.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fIDPIb"&gt;Beats’ best earbuds yet, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple"&gt;Beats Fit Pro&lt;/a&gt;, were only available in the United States immediately upon their release a few months ago. Apple then launched the earbuds in China, but now they’re set to become much more widely available on January 28th. That’s when the Beats Fit Pro will launch across Canada, Europe, and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OV04z1"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beatsbydre/status/1480947737118101506"&gt;a tweet from the Apple-owned brand&lt;/a&gt;, preorders for the “worldwide” release will begin on January 24th before the buds hit shelves on the 28th. The Beats Fit Pro include flexible wingtips that help them (comfortably) stay anchored in your ears without coming loose — even during exercise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oaoI5x"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/beats-fit-pro-canada-europe-japan-release-date-161335850.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in Europe the Beats Fit Pro will be priced at £200 / €230; in Canada they’ll cost $250 CAD; and in Japan you’ll be able to get them for 24,800 yen. As in the US, the Fit Pro earbuds will be offered in black, white, gray, and purple. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ptNyqVVjvt3IM3On3kkY-q2tLvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973260/DSCF6027_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Beats Fit Pro earbuds are basically a sportier version of the AirPods Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OYFwzG"&gt;They feature the same active noise cancellation system as the AirPods Pro, IPX4 water resistance, and also support head tracking when listening to spatial audio. Battery life is rated at up to six hours on a charge, with the case good for another 21 hours. They don’t check off all the bells and whistles: there’s no wireless charging, for example, and AirPods still perform better on voice calls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tG3gc5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Beats Fit Pro review: sporty AirPods Pros with better sound","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="gLqzYG"&gt;But they maintain most of Apple’s ecosystem tricks while delivering arguably better, more powerful sound in a fit that offers superior stability. They’re our top pick for workout earbuds, but I find myself using them just as regularly for everyday listening.  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878599/apple-beats-fit-pro-earbuds-global-release-date-january-28"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878599/apple-beats-fit-pro-earbuds-global-release-date-january-28</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
