<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-02T18:46:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T18:46:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T18:46:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple asks staff to return to office three days a week starting in early September </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lLQ2WHLpEs-9flnsbZB5C7U9Hn8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69380177/acastro_190322_1777_apple_streaming_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q0JJHI"&gt;Apple employees are being asked to return to the office three days a week starting in early September. Tim Cook sent out an email Wednesday informing staff of the change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PODrP"&gt;“For all that we’ve been able to achieve while many of us have been separated, the truth is that there has been something essential missing from this past year: each other,” he said. “Video conference calling has narrowed the distance between us, to be sure, but there are things it simply cannot replicate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sgrpkz"&gt;Cook said that most employees will be asked to come in to the office on Mondays, Tuesdays, and Thursdays, with the option of working remotely on Wednesdays and Fridays. Teams that need to work in-person will return four to five days a week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mnaG3Q"&gt;Employees also have the chance to work remotely for up to two weeks a year, “to be closer to family and loved ones, find a change of scenery, manage unexpected travel, or a different reason all your own,” according to the letter. Managers need to approve remote work requests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aLkk8F"&gt;The change is not entirely unexpected for Apple staff. While employees have worked remotely during the coronavirus pandemic, the company famously discouraged working from home prior to 2020. In December, Tim Cook told employees they could be asked to come back to the office as early as June, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-29/apple-encourages-staff-to-get-vaccinated-offers-paid-time-off?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xbt1dK"&gt;Apple’s stance on remote work, while getting more relaxed, is still conservative compared to the other tech giants. In May, Google announced that &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/05/google-relaxes-remote-work-plan-will-let-20percent-of-employees-telecommute.html"&gt;20 percent of its workforce would be able to work from home permanently&lt;/a&gt;. Mark Zuckerberg has said that remote work “is the future,” and told Facebook employees they can all work from home forever, so long as they get their manager’s approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYLBVR"&gt;In the letter Wednesday, Cook also encouraged all employees to get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZawd9"&gt;“For now, let me simply say that I look forward to seeing your faces,” he said in closing. “I know I’m not alone in missing the hum of activity, the energy, creativity and collaboration of our in-person meetings and the sense of community we’ve all built.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1Ly2l"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T16:34:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T16:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Apple Card outage has been resolved after five hours</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q4n0npO9Hc_laGzjqgNIRTMSivI=/201x0:2349x1432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69377427/Screen_Shot_2019_03_26_at_1.49.46_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QPBOUA"&gt;The Apple Card experienced an outage on Wednesday that reportedly affected users’ ability to make payments, manage their cards, and see recent transactions, according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fsupport%2Fsystemstatus%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F2%2F22465000%2Fapple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s status page&lt;/a&gt;. Interruption in service appears to have started at 6:17AM PT today and lasted for a little over five hours, ending at 12:19PM PT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2J5kgD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019"&gt;Apple’s credit card solution&lt;/a&gt; is managed almost entirely through the built-in Wallet app in iOS, where users can pay off their credit card bill, see recent transactions, and make payments through Apple Pay. Apple said that all users were affected by today’s outage, but it wasn’t clear if every user experienced all of the possible issues the company reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jd8AY4"&gt;My colleague Mitchell Clark was able to pay off a portion of their bill and see the transaction show up in the Wallet app during the outage, so it’s possible the issues were slowly fixed over time, or never as widespread as Apple warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCZcu2"&gt;Apple never provided comment on the actual size or scope of the problem, but the status page says the issues is resolved, and you should be able to use your card like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w1n6ui"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 2nd, 2:25PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information about Apple Card usage and updated the duration of the outage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB8vd6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 2nd, 4:34PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added that the outage has ended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465000/apple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465000/apple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T06:56:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T06:56:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Judge dismisses charges against Apple chief accused of bribing police officers with iPads </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2B6pA47_2BHq9No4prWTG12iMs8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376086/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q4CY76"&gt;A Californian court has dismissed bribery charges against Apple’s Chief Security Officer Thomas Moyer, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/judge-dismisses-charges-against-apple-security-chief-gun-permit-probe-2021-06-01/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, who was accused of offering iPads as bribes to obtain concealed-weapons permits for Apple employees. Judge Eric S. Geffon dismissed arguments of corrupt intent as “pure speculation” that were “not supported by the evidence presented to the grand jury.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bViO1M"&gt;Moyer was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21611525/apple-ipads-bribes-concealed-gun-permits-security-head-accused-santa-clara"&gt;accused last November&lt;/a&gt; of trying to bribe Santa Clara County officials by offering to donate 200 iPads to two officers in the sheriff’s office following a meeting in 2019. Moyer had indeed made the offer, but evidence suggests he believed the permits were already approved at this time, Judge Geffon wrote. This, combined with the fact that Moyer followed Apple’s rules about donations and was donating the iPads to the Sheriff’s Office rather than the officers themselves, was seen as further evidence against him acting with corrupt intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YFUwyq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple dropped its plans to donate the computers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OjCdg8"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/local/article/Bribery-charge-against-Apple-executive-who-16218024.php"&gt;&lt;em&gt;San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Apple halted plans to donate the computers to the Sheriff’s Office following media reports about the incident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3qWX9t"&gt;In a statement reported by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, Moyer thanked the court for its decision. “I also want to thank Apple, my friends and family for their unwavering support,” he added. Last November, Apple &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/11/apple-security-chief-maintains-innocence-after-bribery-charges/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that an internal investigation had found no wrongdoing. Moyer has reportedly been at Apple for around 15 years, and has served as its global security head since November 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZjjyWL"&gt;Despite the bribery charges being dismissed, Santa Clara District Attorney Jeff Rosen said prosecutors believed Moyer had been “correctly indicted... for bribery.” Rosen said they “stand by the grand jury’s decision and are evaluating our options.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464580/apple-security-chief-bribery-charges-dropped-evidence"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464580/apple-security-chief-bribery-charges-dropped-evidence</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T11:11:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T11:11:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>What’s on your desk, Brandon Widder? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cxqaVYEE4fsxe0IbKH_ZhXy-FsE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69371542/bwidder_20210524_4602_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Some great tech, along with a mood light and a bobcat skull&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="myZQWm"&gt;As we slowly emerge from the pandemic, many companies are figuratively shaking themselves off, taking stock, and hiring for new types of positions. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is no different; it has recently hired Brandon Widder to be its senior commerce editor, a brand-new title for our next chapter. We asked Brandon if we could take a look at his home workspace, and this is what he showed (and told) us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gUN2DR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about yourself. What is your background, and what do you do at &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cCcGks"&gt;Great question! I recently started at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; as its first senior commerce editor. As of right now, I’m fixated on improving our deals, buying guides, gift guides, and any other type of content with commerce potential. If it’s an article with a product recommendation — laptop, headset, what have you — there’s a good chance I’ll be looking at it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CS9BuS"&gt;Before starting at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, I worked a number of years helming similar types of evergreen content for &lt;em&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/em&gt;, another consumer tech site. I also used to routinely freelance for an alt-weekly in Portland, Oregon, where I currently live with my partner and our two cats. I mostly wrote about local and touring bands, with some outdoorsy stuff sprinkled in here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Louise Desk Chair came with the territory" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WquN_swIvQSkYuN3uQquY-gs1WM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545811/bwidder_20210525_4602_0031.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Louise Desk Chair came with the territory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5Yq9qo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you decide where and how to set up your workspace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Go5A3e"&gt;Well, “decide” is a strong word. My partner and I were forced to work from home as a result of the pandemic. We feel extremely fortunate that we were able to do so, but we didn’t have a dedicated space for us both to work in the beginning. Fortunately, when the unexpected desk shortage of 2020 subsided, I was able to set one up in the corner of our guest room, directly next to the window where I could watch the rain. It’s small and probably doesn’t have much in the way of feng shui, but, honestly, I enjoy how cozy it is. Space is overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB8lZ4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about the desk itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vueHiE"&gt;The desk is the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13720150?sid=VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wayfair.com%2Ffurniture%2Fpdp%2Fcorrigan-studio-munguia-desk-w005270388.html%3Fpiid%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Munguia Desk&lt;/a&gt; from Wayfair. I actually didn’t pick it out... let’s just say I inherited it when my partner and I traded work spaces at home. As much as it pains me to admit it, I do like it, namely because it’s relatively sturdy and affords me just the right amount of cubby space. It’s not particularly wide, but it also has a single drawer where I can stash my &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; and all the cables I probably should have thrown away a decade ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="fAuQVY"&gt;
&lt;div id="6YIjzq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523553"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XN9dnD"&gt;
&lt;p id="3JgJqR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how about your desk chair?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hSp14"&gt;Like my desk, the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13720150?sid=VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wayfair.com%2Ffurniture%2Fpdp%2Fkelly-clarkson-home-louise-task-chair-w003318245.html%3Fpiid%3D6833205" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Louise Desk Chair&lt;/a&gt; came with the territory when I took over the office. We were looking for something to match the brass guest bed shoved into the corner of the room, and despite it being a little too glam for my taste, it’s extremely comfortable and meshes well with the rest of the decor. Apparently, it’s “hand-curated by Kelly Clarkson,” which is something I just figured out while looking at the product listing. I just wish it could tilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3joQN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a rather simple setup compared to some of your Verge compatriots. Could you tell us a bit about your tech?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qu8ixG"&gt;Clutter can really get to me, so I try to keep things clean. For work, I use the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=macbook%2Bair&amp;amp;qid=1622050268&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyM080VVhUVVMzOVI4JmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNzg5NDQ0MVpLT0syNVFOSUVLTiZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwMzg4MDE1MkREMVpISEc0MjdXTSZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1 MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, but you wouldn’t know it given that it’s housed in the cubby beneath my desk. It’s a great machine, one that Dieter and the team &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;have already gushed over&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q5n9JV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523564"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="helivd"&gt;On the peripheral front, I recently sprung for the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821/https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-ultrasharp-27-4k-usb-c-monitor-u2720q/apd/210-avjv/monitors-monitor-accessories" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell UltraSharp U2720Q&lt;/a&gt;, a fantastic 4K display that affords me a bit more screen real estate than the Air and simultaneously charges my laptop via USB-C. I also have Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Keyboard-Wireless-Rechargable-English/dp/B016QO64FI/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=magic+keyboard&amp;amp;qid=1622050179&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyS0U3TVVLV0ZLRVU4JmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNzIzNTUxMUdaMVIzTkFMQ0JUWSZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwODExNjA2MU5OSjIzVEtLSlRVOCZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU%3D&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Magic-Trackpad-Wireless-Rechargable/dp/B07BRF3ZQD/ref=sr_1_3?crid=2B9L8DKHKSWGV&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=magic%2Btrackpad%2B2&amp;amp;qid=1622050188&amp;amp;sprefix=magic%2Btrack%2Caps%2C240&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Trackpad 2&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve never been a huge fan of desktop mice, so when I picked up an external monitor, the trackpad just made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XtLJmN"&gt;Elsewhere on my desk, I have one of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0756Z8X82/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s wireless Qi charging pads&lt;/a&gt; for my iPhone X and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sonos-One-Gen-Controlled-Built/dp/B07NJPXRBC?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos One&lt;/a&gt;. I listen to everything from political post-punk to the gorgeous instrumental work of Icelandic composer Ólafur Arnalds, but everything in the Sonos lineup really shines regardless of the genre. I’m a sucker for the entire ecosystem, especially given its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t1pfow"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523576"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pGNfZ8"&gt;
&lt;p id="DMjQoQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us about the interesting wood piece that you have on your desk. And the — jawbone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dw7rIz"&gt;When I’m not working, I tend to spend a lot of time outside. I love hiking and backpacking, and I’m really involved with Pacific Northwest Search and Rescue, one of our local SAR outfits. The driftwood is from the shores of the San Juan Islands; the rock from a small peak in Sun Valley, Idaho. My fascination with the natural world extends to bones — morbid, I know — which is why I have a bobcat skull sitting on my desk. It’s a bit in shambles at this point, though, having succumbed to my cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A bobcat skull, a little worse for wear" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtF_Fjf0Ie_S2hO50K4qPa9vW6A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545809/bwidder_20210524_4602_0026.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bobcat skull, a little worse for wear.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Driftwood from the shores of the San Juan Islands" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CpKRnx1-G5ohKGZtpHnXKjvASMA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545803/bwidder_20210524_4602_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Driftwood from the shores of the San Juan Islands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Mood lighting for the home office" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3qqAoK2cCTNt1CPoY1Scmr_cgFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545802/bwidder_20210524_4602_0015_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mood lighting for the home office.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WNfnpc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m fascinated by the old-fashioned lightbulb you have next to the plant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gsotu5"&gt;That would be my so-called mood lighting. There’s a small-ish company out of Portland called &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgrovemade.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22458437%2Fhome-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Grovemade&lt;/a&gt;, which manufactures an assortment of desk accessories out of wood and leather. Most of them run on the pricey side, but the quality is great. I picked up the now-discontinued walnut lamp a few years back and, more recently, the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgrovemade.com%2Fproduct%2Fleather-desk-pad%2F%3Finitial%3D547&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22458437%2Fhome-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;leather pad&lt;/a&gt; on which my keyboard and trackpad rest. It’s basically me trying to bring more natural elements into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujGaCb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you have a notebook and pen by your keyboard.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtFMpO"&gt;Yes! Like most people at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, I probably have more spreadsheets and Google Docs than I care to admit. The notebook allows me to jot down quick notes and keep them close at hand. It also just feels really good to physically write every once in a while, which is something I think a lot of us can appreciate. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07V5SQ6Q2/ref=redir_mobile_desktop?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;aaxitk=85a771eb1a014108995c19f32725f01c&amp;amp;hsa_cr_id=2895318650401&amp;amp;pd_rd_plhdr=t&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=2921f872-3cff-4acd-bcce-35efdaaf6aef&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=Mpdtv&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=kYtdu&amp;amp;ref_=sbx_be_s_sparkle_mcd_asin_2_img&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt; are great because they come in all shapes and sizes, some of which are waterproof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S5zY00"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else about your work space that we haven’t covered?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErgenS"&gt;Not really! The only other thing worth noting is my backlighting, which, if you live in an area that gets as much rain as I do, is crucial during the wetter months. For me, I’ve found the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07QV9XB87/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Philips Hue color lightbulbs&lt;/a&gt; to work best, partly because I’m tapped into the Hue network. If I want bright lights for a Zoom call or something more moody for after-hours work, all I have to do is say the word to Alexa. It’s super convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="EEcMoD"&gt;Also, go read &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/0399184767/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=carrie+brownstein&amp;amp;qid=1622050875&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Carrie Brownstein’s autobiography&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Black-Leopard-Wolf-Dark-Trilogy-ebook/dp/B07DP5W1LT/ref=sr_1_1?crid=LCC3B8H6JIMM&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=black+leopard+red+wolf&amp;amp;qid=1622050899&amp;amp;sprefix=black+leap%2Caps%2C244&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Leopard, Red Wolf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;by Marlon James, both of which are sitting on my desk at the moment. You won’t be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGHj9F"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBEhEE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22458437/home-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22458437/home-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple TV app comes to Nvidia Shield</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BrmdMSUmEmfe5XeeI4AfSn-_QU8=/130x0:1150x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69371440/Apple_TV_on_SHIELD.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Apple TV app on Shield. | Image: Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JTbS6V"&gt;Apple’s streaming TV app is coming to another platform today: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20935215/nvidia-shield-tv-2019-review-streaming-stick-dolby-vision-4k-price-specs-features"&gt;Nvidia’s Shield&lt;/a&gt;. Shield owners will &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/06/01/shield-apple-TV/"&gt;now be able to access&lt;/a&gt; Apple TV Plus, rent movies through Apple’s store, and access subscriptions to premium channels like Showtime and Starz that were set up through Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TC3WbI"&gt;The biggest hook is finally getting access to Apple TV Plus. Apple needs the streaming service to be accessible in as many places as possible in order to expand viewership. And viewers need to be able to access the service on whatever device is hooked up to their TV, if Apple wants to make sure people use it and stay signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJxtSG"&gt;Apple TV Plus is already available through &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fapple-tv-app%2Fdevices%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F1%2F22462960%2Fapple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;many of the most popular&lt;/a&gt; streaming devices. It’s offered through Roku and Fire TV streaming devices, available on recent PlayStations and Xboxes, and supported on many Vizio, Sony, Samsung, and LG TVs. The app came to Google’s latest Chromecast in February, and it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287905/apple-tv-app-now-available-chromecast-google-tv"&gt;supposed to expand to other Android TV devices&lt;/a&gt; — like the Shield — sometime after that. The service will support Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos on Shield devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N8OVrH"&gt;The timing is good for Apple. Free trials for Apple TV &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"&gt;are about to lapse&lt;/a&gt; for the service’s earliest users. And the second season of the service’s biggest (and pretty much only) hit, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;debuts July 23rd&lt;/a&gt;. The more places Apple TV Plus can be accessed, the better odds Apple has of getting some actual paying subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88NcKJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462960/apple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462960/apple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T18:19:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T18:19:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple delays Podcasts subscriptions to June</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4N2LqGV-Go2B5YClyIs2R8yGGgs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69359138/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n0NyLH"&gt;Apple is delaying the launch of its upcoming Podcasts subscriptions until June, the company announced in an email sent to creators Friday (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/05/28/apple-delaying-podcasts-subscriptions-launch-until-june-promises-improvements-to-podcasts-app/amp/?__twitter_impression=true"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The service was previously set to launch this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjbNaY"&gt;Apple’s Podcasts subscriptions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;will allow people&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to participating podcasts to get extra perks like ad-free listening or early access to episodes. In April, Apple said the subscriptions would launch in 170 countries, and that initial partners include Pushkin Industries and NPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bq5QCY"&gt;The shifted launch comes as some creators using Apple Podcasts &lt;a href="https://podnews.net/article/apple-podcasts-lemon-bugs?utm_source=podnews.net&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=podnews.net:2021-05-28"&gt;have recently run into some issues&lt;/a&gt;, such as being unable to log in to Apple’s Podcast Connect portal or seeing a delay in the availability of new episodes. In its email sent Friday, Apple said it has fixed the “disruptions” that presented problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7UXzb"&gt;You can read Apple’s full email to creators below, which the company shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ka4avf"&gt;We’re writing to provide an update on the availability of Apple Podcasts Subscriptions and channels. We’ve been delighted by the response to last month’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F04%2Fapple-leads-the-next-chapter-of-podcasting-with-apple-podcasts-subscriptions%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F28%2F22459129%2Fapple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; and it’s exciting to see the hundreds of new subscriptions and channels submitted from creators across the globe every day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hvdhoL"&gt;To ensure we are delivering the best experience for creators and listeners, Apple Podcasts Subscriptions and channels will now launch in June. We will communicate further updates on availability, and best practices to help you prepare your subscriptions and channels, through this newsletter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nna6d5"&gt;Over the last few weeks, some creators have experienced delays in the availability of their content and access to Apple Podcasts Connect. We’ve addressed these disruptions and encourage creators experiencing any issues to &lt;a href="https://podcastsconnect.apple.com/contactus"&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LY27Uc"&gt;We’ve also heard from listeners and made adjustments based on their feedback with iOS 14.6, which was released on Monday. We will introduce additional enhancements to Library in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NCvcwF"&gt;Thank you for your understanding. We can’t wait to see your new subscriptions and channels and we are looking forward to launching them to listeners around the world soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459129/apple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459129/apple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T09:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T09:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The AirPods Pro’s force sensor is a more comfortable way to control audio</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lwoxfJvKR8bfojMWh8jqAzd5gvE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69356058/vpavic_4603_20210525_0018_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WjhY2z"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; cleverly solve one of the trickiest parts of earbud design with a unique button — even if it’s not technically a button at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sKi4jL"&gt;Officially referred to as the “force sensor” (a title that makes the button sound far more interesting than it actually is), it’s technically nothing more than an indented portion of the AirPods Pro’s stems, with some fancy hardware that measures not just capacitive touch but also pressure. But the faux-buttons solve one of the most annoying things about earbuds: how to control them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SSF7c8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A smart solution for a more recent problem&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wF9nN8"&gt;The issue of controlling truly wireless earbuds is a relatively new one. Older in-ear headphones often included a row of buttons on their wires, which allowed for volume and playback controls to be placed in a spot that’s easy to reach and find. But in-ear wireless earbuds don’t leave a lot of space for buttons, joysticks, or control wheels to manipulate playback, forcing manufacturers to come up with alternate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ry-XASBpDsHpD2CY_IGMMPv1QD0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22539213/vpavic_4603_20210525_0020_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hQSlsa"&gt;Touch controls, employed by headphones like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Galaxy Buds&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;regular AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, have emerged as the most common answer. Tap, double tap, or triple tap your earbuds, and you’ll be able to play, pause, and skip around your tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAjnnr"&gt;The problem, though, is that in-ear headphones — as the name suggests — are already nestled pretty firmly into your ear. And tap controls mean that you’re either shoving those earbuds further into your ear (painfully so, sometimes) or dislodging them entirely, at which point you’re risking loss or damage when your expensive buds plummet to the ground. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uv9w0A"&gt;Apple avoids both of those problems with the force sensor. Instead of putting pressure on your ear, Apple has users squeeze the stem of the AirPod. It’s a far gentler movement that doesn’t move the earbud as much, reducing both the risk of discomfort and dislodging. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CyBe0o_QmVvM29cY0XkZl66-nVo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22539210/vpavic_4603_20210525_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EOET2D"&gt;Its controls are pretty similar to the other methods of headphone control: one squeeze to toggle play / pause, two to skip forward a track, and three to skip back. There’s also a fourth long press, which toggles the various noise cancellation modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0W4DZ"&gt;The whole design guides you through how to use them, too. The indented pad makes it clear where to press to activate the “button,” while the requirement for some slight force makes it hard to trigger unintentionally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iD1kZh"&gt;And while there’s no &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; haptic feedback from the force sensor, Apple does some masterful work in tricking your brain that there is, through clever clicking sound effects relayed through the earbuds to make it feel like you’re pressing a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ga9LqW"&gt;The controls &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458155/new-airpods-pro-2022-fitness-release-dates-report-design-features"&gt;might not be long for this world&lt;/a&gt; — Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/apple-plans-redesigned-airpods-for-2021-new-airpods-pro-in-2022"&gt;rumored to be testing a new version&lt;/a&gt; of the AirPods Pro that would remove the stem (and the force sensor) entirely. It’d be a disappointing change, given that the force sensor isn’t just a great control method; the AirPod stems are one of the more recognizable parts of the product, so much so that it’s the main thing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/13/21435637/us-cbp-counterfeit-airpods-oneplus-buds-mixup"&gt;copycat designs&lt;/a&gt; tend to replicate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhNoli"&gt;Is it a lot of engineering work for a relatively simple function? Undoubtedly. But it makes a crucial part of operating the AirPods a seamless, aesthetically pleasing, and comfortable process. And what more can you ask than that?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22457468/airpods-pro-force-sensor-control-audio-button"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22457468/airpods-pro-force-sensor-control-audio-button</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T08:22:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T08:22:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>New AirPods Pro could launch in 2022 with a focus on fitness tracking</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tKzjXr_CyP-rN9bA4oYiY2DE1X0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69355728/akrales_191030_3763_0471.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The current AirPods Pro from 2019.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Utbha7"&gt;Apple’s second-generation AirPods Pro will launch next year, following the release of an updated pair of standard AirPods this year, according to a new &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/apple-plans-redesigned-airpods-for-2021-new-airpods-pro-in-2022?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The new AirPods Pro will reportedly feature upgraded motion sensors to allow for fitness tracking, while the entry-level AirPods will have an updated design similar to the Pro models along with a shorter stem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8Kark"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534123/apple-airpods-3-pro-2-2021-chip-design-battery-life-true-wireless-earbuds-headphones-homepod"&gt;previous report from last year&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; said that the upcoming AirPods Pro could ditch the stem entirely in favor of a more compact design similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21147654/samsung-galaxy-buds-plus-review-wireless-earbuds-sound-quality-battery-life"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Plus&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21400695/google-pixel-buds-2-2020-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;Google’s Pixel Buds&lt;/a&gt;. However, at the time &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; noted that design challenges meant these plans could change. Its latest report says Apple has “tested” this design, which sounds like it’s not guaranteed to appear in the final model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4zETRX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Following the launch of the AirPods Max&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZaxHpL"&gt;Alongside the two new AirPods models, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379470/apple-tv-homepod-speaker-camera-video-call-soundbar-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;Apple is reported to be developing&lt;/a&gt; a HomePod equipped with a screen, as well as a separate Apple TV-like device that could include a speaker and camera for video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zQ6nt6"&gt;The new AirPods would be the first updates to Apple’s true wireless lineup in over a year. Apple first release its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro in late 2019&lt;/a&gt;, while its entry-level AirPods haven’t been updated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;since March 2019&lt;/a&gt;. It released its first AirPods-branded over-ear headphones, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt;, in December.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458155/new-airpods-pro-2022-fitness-release-dates-report-design-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458155/new-airpods-pro-2022-fitness-release-dates-report-design-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-27T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-27T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nine things we learned from the Epic v. Apple trial</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Epic-Apple Trial Hangs Over Some 50,000 Games On App Store" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QvWjpsyzhn-QaXVWIPxFHZ2LJao=/1x0:4000x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69350409/1233086757.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ThdAUl"&gt;It’s been just over three weeks since the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; proceedings kicked off, and the news has been relentless. So as we wait for a verdict to roll in, we’re taking a quick turn through all the biggest takeaways from the trial. A lot of the juiciest points didn’t speak directly to the verdict — like the profit structure of the Xbox or the troubled history of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; crossplay — but that’s part of the fun of a massive trans-corporate dustup like this. Once you start digging through CEO Tim Cook’s inbox, all sorts of interesting stuff comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1BNyLu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1] Apple keeps iMessage closed in order to sell more iPhones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="WI4baB"&gt;We’ve known for a while that Apple isn’t going to make iMessage available outside of iOS devices, but this trial showed exactly how thoroughly Apple has considered expanding iMessage into other operating systems — and exactly why the company doesn’t want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J0FX3w"&gt;Internal emails show Eddy Cue pushing to expand iMessage into a WhatsApp-style messaging platform &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406303/imessage-android-eddy-cue-emails-apple-epic-deposition"&gt;as early as 2013&lt;/a&gt; — and the issue reemerging in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute"&gt;an email to Phil Schiller in 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was rejected for the same reason both times: opening up iMessage would just mean one less reason to buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YKMGWs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sony saw ‘Fortnite’ crossplay as a business liability&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5EXf53"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2] PlayStation’s &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortnite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; crossplay deal is even sketchier than we realized&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wrxQdG"&gt;Sony took its time enabling crossplay between different console versions of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, eventually relenting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/26/17905146/sony-fortnite-ps4-cross-play-support"&gt;late in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417560/sony-ps4-cross-play-confidential-documents-epic-games-agreements"&gt;a handful of new emails with Epic Games&lt;/a&gt; showed the deal was even knottier than was publicly known. Apparently, Sony saw crossplay as a business liability for its business and was only willing to adopt it after Epic agreed to a complicated cross-platform revenue sharing agreement. It’s a unique arrangement — but since we also learned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407939/fortnite-biggest-platform-revenue-playstation-not-ios-iphone"&gt;PlayStation is the top revenue driver for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Epic seems to have been willing to make concessions for the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sjPoT0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3] Apple pulled out all the stops to keep Netflix selling subscriptions on the iPhone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Vjt96K"&gt;Apple insists it treats all App Store developers equally, but it’s clear big players like Amazon have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/3/21206400/apple-tax-amazon-tv-prime-30-percent-developers"&gt;gotten special treatment&lt;/a&gt; because of their sheer number of users. This trial turned up another instance, with emails that showed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421734/apple-epic-netflix-in-app-purchase-removal-emails"&gt;Apple employees scrambling behind the scenes&lt;/a&gt; to keep Netflix from removing in-app purchases from its iPhone app in 2018. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s3gsZx"&gt;For Netflix, the logic was hard to avoid: Apple’s 30 percent cut was costing it money any time someone signed up through the iOS app instead of through a web browser. But for a while, Apple was willing to do just about anything to keep Netflix from giving in to the obvious economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="3OCcP0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple says it doesn’t know how much money the App Store makes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0baW1c"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4] The App Store is wildly profitable, but Apple won’t admit it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lVNJHf"&gt;One of the running jokes of the trial was Apple’s insistence that it had no idea how much money the App Store makes in profit. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thedextriarchy/status/1394710317033312257"&gt;Phil Schiller said outright&lt;/a&gt; that he had no idea if the App Store had brought in more money than it spent since 2009 “because that’s not how I look at the business.” (For context, the App Store brought in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220873/apple-2020-app-store-revenue-60-billion-dollars"&gt;more than $60 billion in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, which would be quite a lot to burn through without realizing.) Tim Cook was a little bit more reserved, saying he &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thedextriarchy/status/1395773390632464384"&gt;believed it was profitable&lt;/a&gt; but hadn’t calculated by how much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ENvdpj"&gt;The firmest number came from an expert witness hired by the Epic side, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/1/22414402/epic-expert-apple-app-store-fortnite-court-profit"&gt;pegged the profit margin as high as 78 percent&lt;/a&gt;. That would leave Apple with more than $45 billion in profit from the App Store alone — but don’t expect them to admit it out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="H5FEcb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5] The economics of the Xbox is kind of weird&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HXfXr6"&gt;Microsoft was a kind of unofficial sidekick to Epic for the trial, providing executives to testify in court and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/1/22411686/microsoft-windows-store-game-fees-change-apple-app-store-epic-games-eu"&gt;abruptly lowering its Windows Store fees&lt;/a&gt; to put extra pressure on Apple. But the most exciting turn came when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421570/epic-apple-trial-iphone-xbox-console-specific-general-purpose-pc-testimony-day-3"&gt;Xbox boss Lori Wright took the stand&lt;/a&gt;, testifying that Microsoft doesn’t make money from Xbox hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrBtuz"&gt;For lawyers on the Epic side, the goal was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421570/epic-apple-trial-iphone-xbox-console-specific-general-purpose-pc-testimony-day-3"&gt;to distinguish the Xbox from the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;: Microsoft sells Xbox hardware at a loss (or a near-loss), so the company’s approach is different from Apple, which makes money off every iPhone it sells. But any new information about the Xbox business was interesting far beyond Epic and Apple, so things started to spiral almost immediately. Microsoft’s official PR was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422691/microsoft-xbox-consoles-profit-software-services-revenue-apple-epic-games-trial"&gt;quick to walk back the claim&lt;/a&gt;, making sure everyone knew that the overall Xbox business is profitable in spite of the hardware subsidy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J1wVhe"&gt;Apple pressed the issue even further, trying to force Microsoft to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424668/epic-apple-antitrust-lawsuit-microsoft-xbox-profitability-lori-wright"&gt;release its profit-and-loss statements for the Xbox business&lt;/a&gt; if it wanted to keep Wright’s testimony in the record. It was a chance to see serious jousting between some of the biggest companies in the world — and a reminder of how knotty these businesses are once you look under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0PF2az"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Epic has spent hundreds of millions of dollars on its PC gaming storefront&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="J7EJUA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6] The economics of the Epic Games Store is even weirder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lNvyLF"&gt;In the lead-up to the trial, &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; case filings showed Epic has spent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22380895/epic-games-store-afford-give-away-17-5-billion-free-games"&gt;hundreds of millions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; on its PC gaming storefront. Much of that went toward pricey deals to attract developers and consumers, including a free games program that earned Epic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22418782/epic-games-store-free-games-cost-apple-trial-arkham-subnautica-mutant-year-zero"&gt;millions of new users&lt;/a&gt; while offering developers a flat fee for participation. Epic also tried to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22424596/epic-games-store-sony-playstation-pc-games-steam-competition"&gt;get Sony and Microsoft’s first-party games&lt;/a&gt; on the Epic Games Store, although it apparently never reached a deal over them. Tim Sweeney said in testimony that he expects the store to turn a profit around 2024 — although Epic has apparently planned out &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-05-04-epic-expects-epic-games-store-to-be-profitable-by-2024"&gt;several possible scenarios&lt;/a&gt; for its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l1nXkR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7] Apple gains a lot by slow-walking progressive web apps on the iPhone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6Kwnxt"&gt;In theory, there’s a way to get software onto iPhones that doesn’t include the App Store. iPhones include web browsers, after all, and there’s a whole range of technologies (usually bundled under the name Progressive Web Apps or PWAs) that are intended &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22421912/iphone-web-app-pwa-cloud-gaming-epic-v-apple-safari"&gt;to make the functionality of an app available through a browser&lt;/a&gt;. Google has been pushing this hard with some support from Microsoft and Twitter — but so far, mobile Safari has been slow to roll out support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gXM4gs"&gt;We didn’t get any new documents saying exactly why that is, but we did get a whole lot of Apple executives saying how important it was for Apple to be able to protect iPhone users from bad apps. In short, Apple sees its stranglehold on iOS software as an important security feature — and progressive web apps threaten that stranglehold. As long as that stays true, it’s hard to imagine mobile Safari catching up in PWA support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xcTgVI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8] Apple is still worried about malware downloads on the Mac&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="h5TMVg"&gt;One of Epic’s big challenges to Apple is why the company can’t run the iPhone the same way it runs the Mac: with a central app store but lots of other ways to get software outside of it. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22444353/mac-malware-not-acceptable-craig-federighi-apple-epic"&gt;On the stand&lt;/a&gt;, Craig Federighi had a simple answer: we don’t actually like how it works on the Mac. Federighi said the level of malware on the Mac was “unacceptable” and that iOS would get “run over” by malware attacks if it adopted the same model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ny71ka"&gt;The whole point of the trial is to maintain App Store exclusivity, so it’s no surprise that Federighi wanted to shut the door — but the sheer anxiety he showed about Mac malware came as a bit of a surprise. It’s particularly notable since &lt;a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2019/04/22/the-true-and-false-security-benefits-of-mac-app-notarization/"&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gruber/status/1153814930832777222?s=20"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; are worried that macOS is inching toward the iOS model, making it a little more difficult to install unauthorized software with each new version. If you were already anxious about the Mac ecosystem closing off entirely, Federighi’s testimony gave you plenty more to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="adApDl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9] Tim Sweeney has been bugging Tim Cook about this for years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Y95iVl"&gt;Arguably the funniest part of the trial has been the sheer determination of Tim Sweeney to unwind Apple’s app store policies. The fight became public when &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; went nuclear last year, but new emails from Sweeney show he’s been trying to charm, cajole, and annoy Apple into allowing alternate app stores for years now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RsQDff"&gt;That effort peaked with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419618/tim-sweeney-email-tim-cook-wwdc-2015-ios-open-platform-antitrust"&gt;a 2015 email directly to Cook&lt;/a&gt;, laying out the case for an open iOS over the course of four paragraphs. (Cook responded to Schiller and Cue: “Is this the guy that was at one of our rehearsals?”) Three years later, Sweeney was &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20697673-px-2421"&gt;still trying&lt;/a&gt;, pressing the case through the various developer-relations channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXAerr"&gt;Of course, Tim Cook is not going to change Apple’s business model just because some guy emailed him saying it would be a good idea — but there’s no harm in trying, right?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22454959/epic-apple-trial-recap-video-tim-cook-xbox-playstation-business"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22454959/epic-apple-trial-recap-video-tim-cook-xbox-playstation-business</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T20:41:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T20:41:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>LeBron James may have just proved the unannounced Beats Studio Buds are real</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f_8v8cL4aa1hJ14i-4Xt45GtYoI=/0x2:780x522/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69348543/191152746_211492840634582_216780930635838230_n.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeBron James wearing what appear to be Beats Studio Buds.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/" target="_blank"&gt;LeBron James on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qz926I"&gt;Earlier this month, an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440700/beats-studio-buds-leak-ios-tvos-design"&gt;unannounced pair of Beats wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, apparently called the Beats Studio Buds, showed up in beta releases of iOS and tvOS. While those betas were a good start, a flood of new leaks — including actual photos of mystery earbuds from superstar athlete LeBron James — suggest that they could be available very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pGPjqk"&gt;Here’s what we already knew: on May 17th, people digging into the iOS and tvOS 14.6 betas found evidence of the new headphones, with perhaps the clearest look at them coming from animations in the OS shared by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; contributor Steve Moser (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveMoser/status/1394361761571254272"&gt;he has a whole thread of them here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rmle67"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Beats Studio Buds ‘charged’ &lt;a href="https://t.co/xTqj1vo8Mq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xTqj1vo8Mq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve Moser (@SteveMoser) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveMoser/status/1394361883457724417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kQVHxT"&gt;This week, the Beats Studio Buds appeared under that name in &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513"&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2512"&gt;filings&lt;/a&gt;, a sign that the product has been cleared for sale in the US. Diagrams in &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250626"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2512/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250503"&gt;filings&lt;/a&gt; also give us a clear look at the shape of the buds from one specific angle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8-NOHOSoySTqmkx9jH255WMG1WM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542107/Screen_Shot_2021_05_26_at_3.46.30_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250626" target="_blank"&gt;fccid.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diagrams of the Beats Studio Buds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="h2KMfh"&gt;Photos &lt;a href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/apple-beats-studio-buds-live-images-leaked-design-revealed/"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this week show devices that have a very similar design to those FCC diagrams — though it looks like these new photos are just of the plastic casing for the earbuds. While &lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt; said it “could not independently verify the authenticity of these images,” the design seems to match other leaks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z76_kCoB_ZbwwUNH3t8BeUiMUTY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542113/Apple_Beats_Studio_Buds.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/apple-beats-studio-buds-live-images-leaked-design-revealed/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This looks pretty similar to the design in the FCC filings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5E3RE0"&gt;Now, on Wednesday evening, we may have gotten our first look at the earbuds in the wild in the ears of LeBron James, who posted &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/"&gt;new photos on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; where he is seemingly wearing the buds (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1397676604512407560"&gt;via &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/05/26/lebron-james-beats-studio-buds/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). At first glance, it’s hard to tell exactly what headphones he’s wearing, but if you look &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; closely, you can see a squared off ridge on the outside of the headphones that looks an awful lot like the headphones shown in the animation shared by Moser. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/amTKEe5QxV5NdIs9CyMIQt15Xt4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542250/lebron_james.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/" target="_blank"&gt;LeBron James on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;That earbud sure looks like a Beats Studio Bud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S0Hwdy"&gt;LeBron surely knows what he’s doing. At this point, it seems like the Beats Studio Buds are the real deal and they could arrive at any moment. Now we just need Apple to announce them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455747/beats-studio-buds-apple-lebron-james-instagram-photos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455747/beats-studio-buds-apple-lebron-james-instagram-photos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
