<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-23T13:00:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T13:00:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T13:00:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $129 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or for $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D1003525%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AFyzAp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. You can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bM8uVd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. The lowest you can grab a pair right now is for $197 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_XyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3DXyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3Dverge%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $278&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Weird Apple design: ‘Spring Loaded’ edition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l545-m0sx8cwjt0bJs9_bsClobA=/231x0:2637x1604/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69176346/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_9.33.43_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iMac’s big chin.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UyKg81"&gt;Apple’s product design is usually very good, setting industry standards for how many of the gadgets and computers we use every day look and feel. But the company’s many hits make the less obvious design decisions stand out that much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rtX65y"&gt;Thanks to the huge amount of new stuff Apple introduced at its “Spring Loaded” event on Tuesday, we have a lot of new Apple designs to scrutinize. While the company generally did pretty well with this round of updates, there are still a few things that made us raise our eyebrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8n6Tlw"&gt;The iMac still has a big chin&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/twrBv0Hp1a2Gbkio5xPerUdAiLY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465084/apple_new_imac_spring21_pf_blue_04202021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iMac and its large chin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hMoHaK"&gt;I think Apple’s new iMacs look &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good — except for that darn chin, which, once again, proudly protrudes from the bottom of the computer’s screen like Johnny Bravo’s impressive jawline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nlzqib"&gt;To be fair, Apple did what it could to make the chin look nice. The pastel colors are really fun, and I’m happy Apple removed the giant logo that graced the chin of previous iMac generations. (Remove the “MacBook Air” text from my laptop’s bezel next, Apple.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iqVNyt"&gt;And I get that the chin is necessary to allow iMac to be as ridiculously thin as it is. Instead of putting the computer’s internals behind the screen, Apple has stuffed them into the chin. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zTSll4M3e0UferpP1mpfN9_rAxw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461554/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_9.29.41_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iMac’s logic board and cooling system, stuffed into the chin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nFskwN"&gt;Someday, though, I’d like to see Apple release an iMac with no chin at all — just a screen that’s a computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kUMifA"&gt;The iMac has white bezels&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TplkHXkzNIO-1EvVBPr0BTiFU3M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461521/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_9.02.06_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The white bezels on the new iMac.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vow78N"&gt;Perhaps the most surprising thing to me about the new iMac was its white bezels. Most of Apple’s recent computers have had black bezels, which typically do a better job of hiding the edges of the display and make it less obvious where the screen ends and the bezel begins. (The non-Retina MacBook Air, with its silver bezels, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/9/20687417/apple-discontinues-12-inch-macbook"&gt;hung around until 2019&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ypnoiw"&gt;But again, I have to give Apple some credit for its choice here. Black bezels paired with the bright new iMac colors would be quite jarring — the white looks great with the new iMac colors. And these white bezels are &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; smaller than the giant black bezels on the Intel-based iMacs that are still on sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u1wyXQ"&gt;The new iMacs join Apple’s base iPad, the iPad mini, and the iPod touch in the white bezel club. It remains to be seen if the new iMac joining it is foreshadowing others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="luxA65"&gt;The curved corner keys on the iMac’s Magic Keyboard don’t look good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="USJjPE"&gt;The new Magic Keyboard has some nice upgrades, including a Touch ID sensor (which comes with more expensive models), new function keys, and color-matched aluminum. But the look of just four of the keys on the keyboard makes it much worse than the previous model, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wrTIvh"&gt;Check out the keys on the four corners of the new Magic Keyboard. Notice how they each have one corner with a much wider curve than the rest?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aruhuy301-SGWzFmr40ygZ_o4ho=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22463676/apple_new_imac_spring21_magic_keyboard_with_numeric_keypad_yellow_04202021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new Magic Keyboard, with the weirdly rounded corner keys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CZsxxs"&gt;I just think they don’t look very good. I get that they better match the wider curves of the keyboard itself, but I think they look odd when all of the other keys have four corners with exactly the same curvature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KNtCBI"&gt;Here’s an image slider comparing the old keyboard to the new. The uniform corners on the old model look a lot better, in my opinion. Look at that bad right arrow key on the new one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oj5FsC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10459575"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zulWkv"&gt;And by the way, it looks like the Magic Trackpad that comes with the new iMac has the same wider corners as the new keyboard, too, based on a picture from Apple’s website. So if you want your keyboard and trackpad to have matched corners, you’re going to have to pay extra to get the new trackpad. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NqsP6iX7NdItMBo00JarMHxtBf4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22464798/Screen_Shot_2021_04_23_at_8.05.46_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new Magic Keyboard and Trackpad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oDWNW5"&gt;The new iMac does not have a touchscreen, despite looking an awful lot like another Apple device with a touchscreen&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PK1hbfo64f_Ttk3X62ceNRe7QCM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22463711/Screen_Shot_2021_04_22_at_5.00.09_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hmm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xywJHp"&gt;The iPad Pro’s front camera is still in portrait instead of landscape &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8D7zOTtph2Rx7r36uibXLbUHcjc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461630/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_10.06.27_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iPad Pro’s portrait front camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7ZFsDj"&gt;Apple, once again, has released a new iPad Pro with a front camera that’s placed on top of the device in portrait mode instead of on top in landscape mode. That means if you use any keyboard case that requires the tablet to be in landscape and you want to take a video call (which is something a lot of people are doing right now), the camera is awkwardly off to the side instead of right above the middle of your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i6bLbU"&gt;To try to get around this, Apple upgraded the iPad Pro’s new front camera to make it an ultrawide, and the company debuted a new technology that can automatically keep you in frame during video calls. But we won’t know for sure if that will keep you better-centered until we can test it for ourselves. And it won’t solve the problem of forcing you to look to the side if you want to look directly into the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5HEigT"&gt;The new 12.9-inch iPad Pro isn’t compatible with the original Magic Keyboard case&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tn1jiUHUdYBgvGh-7YNN1N45UPg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19911773/vpavic_042018_3979_0072.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kkm8wv"&gt;Apple’s new 12.9-inch iPad Pro &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399095/apple-12-9-inch-ipad-pro-2020-models-magic-keyboard-incompatible"&gt;isn’t compatible&lt;/a&gt; with the original Magic Keyboard case, which fits the 2018 and 2020 models of the tablet. It’s not exactly clear why, but it could be because the new iPad Pro is 0.5mm thicker than the 2020 12.9-inch iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4JSu4"&gt;Regardless of what the reason is, though, if you’re planning to buy the new 12.9-inch iPad Pro and want to use a Magic Keyboard along with it, you’re also going to have to pony up $349 to buy the new version of the Magic Keyboard case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xOcIoh"&gt;AirTags don’t have a built-in keychain loop &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iuDV4kEAC6aBIbowdTFix0Yz13g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461541/Apple_airtag_front_and_back_emoji_2up_042021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirTag tracker doesn’t have a keychain loop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LbHWqz"&gt;Apple’s new AirTag item trackers sure seem like they should have an easy way to directly attach to something, but Apple decided not to include a small hole for, say, a keychain or a string. (Yes, I side with my colleague Chaim Gartenberg in his great &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"&gt;AirTags keychain loop debate&lt;/a&gt; with Jon Porter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SV6BzT"&gt;The Magic Mouse’s charging port is still on the bottom, five and a half years later&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JY7mfNejfVDbX486GvNIzYAolMo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9833361/Apple_Magic_Mouse_Bad_Design_2.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is still how you charge the Magic Mouse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="K2aplw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394552/apple-new-magic-mouse-charging-port-bottom-lightning"&gt;I already wrote about this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Kr2fYZ"&gt;There is some hope: it looks like Apple fixed its TV remote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="khCLGC"&gt;Apple’s new Siri remote, with its iPod-like scroll wheel, a five-way click pad, and smaller touchpad, looks like it will address complaints about the previous Apple TV remote’s annoyingly oversensitive touch controls. And the new aluminum design with black buttons should make it easier to see the buttons on the remote compared to the mostly black design of the previous model.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vARJrX6IqEqGeZfJ0dONZWIz6bU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461483/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_8.40.52_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s seemingly fixed TV remote.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xIAA6P"&gt;The new remote looks great. Apple can change! &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22396936/weird-apple-design-spring-loaded-edition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22396936/weird-apple-design-spring-loaded-edition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T12:25:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T12:25:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new 12.9-inch iPad Pro won’t work with the original $349 Magic Keyboard</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1j8ntN2FIvbvCJtwgIuxpUeXV-Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69176079/vpavic_042018_3979_0072.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y1jUjU"&gt;Apple’s new 12.9-inch iPad Pro has a big catch: it turns out that the new 2021 model is incompatible with the old Magic Keyboard folio case for the 2018 and 2020 models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Caamg9"&gt;The news, first reported by French site &lt;a href="https://www.igen.fr/accessoires/2021/04/lipad-pro-129-de-2021-besoin-dun-nouveau-magic-keyboard-selon-apple-122043"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iGeneration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and confirmed via sources familiar with the matter to &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;means that if you’re looking to upgrade from a 2018 or 2020 12.9-inch iPad Pro to the refreshed model (with its Mini LED display, faster M1 processor, and upgraded camera), you’ll also have to shell out an extra $349 for a new Magic Keyboard case, even if you already bought the prior version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1cohH8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Bad news for 2020 iPad Pro owners&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="08S7i0"&gt;The 2021 12.9-inch iPad Pro is slightly thicker than the 2020 version: the new model measures in at 6.4mm thick, or 0.5mm thicker than the 5.9mm 2020 model, an increase that’s speculated to be due to the more complex Mini LED screen technology. The updated 11-inch iPad Pro, on the other hand, will still be compatible with the older Magic Keyboard case (it doesn’t have an upgraded screen and its dimensions haven’t changed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hG6aB1"&gt;The good news is that the new 2021 Magic Keyboard case is backwards compatible with the previous 2018 and 2020 iterations of the iPad Pro, so if you end up shelling out for the new model, you’ll be able to use it with older iPads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OVREGv"&gt;But it’s certainly frustrating for anyone who already owns a 12.9-inch iPad Pro and Magic Keyboard to see that upgrading won’t just mean spending at least $1,099 to get the benefits of the new model — they’ll also have to spend the extra $349 for a new Magic Keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399095/apple-12-9-inch-ipad-pro-2020-models-magic-keyboard-incompatible"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399095/apple-12-9-inch-ipad-pro-2020-models-magic-keyboard-incompatible</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T12:17:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T12:17:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Thank you for the memories, Siri Remote</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rT4fXeZaUdJ_leb-zSgmxY9I6Vs=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69176015/VRG_ILLO_4545_Siri_Remote.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4Wc76v"&gt;The Apple TV remote is gone and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;new remote&lt;/a&gt; — with the exact same name, considerably more buttons, and a two-tone color scheme straight out of 2010 — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394196/apple-tv-4k-new-siri-remote-sold-separately-price-buttons"&gt;has replaced it&lt;/a&gt;. The majority of people have rejoiced this move, but I am here to mourn a remote that had no business being as captivating for my thumb as it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g07aNG"&gt;Technically called the Siri Remote, the super-slim minimalist remote launched in 2015 alongside the fourth-gen Apple TV (now known as the Apple TV HD). It was the third remote designed by Apple to control your TV and the first one to include a touchpad or microphones. The Siri Remote was named for the big Siri button below the touchpad and was meant to make the digital assistant a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/9/10948544/apple-tv-is-finally-getting-voice-dictation"&gt;more natural part of the way&lt;/a&gt; you interacted with your television. It didn’t do that for me, personally, but I may be an outlier on all things Apple remote. I just used it as a remote to control my TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bjjh1s"&gt;I loved the Lightning port it used for charging. It was too thin to use the tiny coin cell batteries the previous Apple remotes used (and that I never had lying around my house). I could let it go months between charges, and then I just had to plug it in with the same cord I used to charge my phone. It was a nice little convenience I appreciated, and far more expensive and capable remotes, like Logitech’s recently discontinued line of Harmony remotes, felt old-fashioned next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAWrUr"&gt;The Siri Remote was also one of the first set-top box remotes I used that let me put away my TV remote. The fourth-generation Apple TV was the first with volume control over HDMI CEC. What that meant was you could use the included Siri remote to control your TV. While it didn’t have a dedicated power button like the new remote does, it was easy for me to turn on my TV by pressing any button on the remote. I could even control my Sonos soundbar with the volume buttons. Turning the TV off did require an adventure to the Settings menu on the Apple TV if you were like me and didn’t know there was a shortcut for sleeping all devices.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Being able to control everything with one tiny remote was a welcome change of pace from juggling multiple remotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EodowT"&gt;But I didn’t just love the Siri Remote because it gave me limited control of my TV or had a Lightning port. It was also because of the touchpad, which made skimming through content on Netflix or Plex or fast-forwarding through a show on Hulu an absolute breeze. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="THBRLK"&gt;At least I think so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xrna5"&gt;While some (again maybe it was just me!) have praised the Siri Remote’s touchpad, the majority of people — including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/22268724/apple-tv-remote-game-boy-color-mod"&gt;bulk&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/9/9/9297131/new-apple-tv-update-remote-2015-hands-on-video-photos"&gt;staff&lt;/a&gt; here at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300891/apple-tv-siri-remote-touchpad-button-design-form-function"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, every Apple TV user on Reddit, and my mother — absolutely hated it.  Many complained about the sensitivity of the touchpad, which let you fly across the screen with a swipe but required a far gentler touch if you just wanted to pop over a row. They also complained about how easy it was to accidentally select something or lose the remote due to its size. My mother even complained because she somehow managed to shatter her remote with an accidental drop onto her tile floor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An image of a broken Apple Remote. Followed by the text: Oops fell off chair. Put some tape on it. Should I get a new one? Still works ...." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oQl0BSdgj56WFzsGDWr3wTJuVwM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22463422/Capto_Capture_2021_04_22_05_43_11_PM.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Alex Cranz / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It has not been fine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bccDQY"&gt;I loved it precisely because it was so sensitive. I run my trackpad and mouse at similarly high sensitivity levels and like the ability to yeet across a screen with a flick. With the Siri Remote, I could flit from place to place or rewind back exactly 10 seconds with a very careful swipe of the remote. The tvOS user interface worked perfectly with the touchpad and every app icon’s appearance shifted slightly as you dragged your finger back and forth across the remote. More than once I returned to the home screen when someone called, and I used the remote and the app icons up on my TV as a digital fidget toy while I chatted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TnNBeB"&gt;The sensitivity of the touchpad also resolved naysayers’ other major problem with the remote: its size. I loved how it could fit in my extremely small hands and make me feel like the rest of you feel when you hold a normal-size remote. Many people complained about how it could slip in between cushions on the couch or disappear under an entertainment center or chair. But I’ve lost it exactly once, and that was because I stuck it in a jacket pocket and then tossed the jacket in the laundry. I never lost it when it slipped between or beneath cushions. It took just the barest of pressure on the couch to depress the touchpad’s button. Simply sitting down would reveal the remote’s location whether I wanted to find it or not. Finding it under furniture was easy, too. I just squatted down and blindly reached. If things changed on the TV I knew I’d come in contact with some part of the touchpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaXRzQ"&gt;I can only hope the touchpad built into the directional pad of the new remote is as sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2Hhx0"&gt;And it’s really everything about the new remote that has me missing the old one (which technically survives even now in a basket of remotes by my couch). The new remote looks so drastically different and is such a major improvement on others’ complaints that I feel sort of how that dad who never amounted to much after high school must feel when he sees his large son dominate in the popular sport of their hometown. “Oh,” I think, “this is what it was supposed to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22394083/siri-remote-apple-tv-goodbye"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22394083/siri-remote-apple-tv-goodbye</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T10:53:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T10:53:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: the two Apple events from this week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12 and an AirTag" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aUcRPCQrksqNZ5vErcFW0gEowKU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69175456/vpavic_4547_20210421_0119.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HiSohv"&gt;You may have heard of the new Apple products announced at the company’s “Spring Loaded” event this week — including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;the redesigned colorful iMac&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;location-tracking AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, and the boosted specs on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;the next iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. But there was another big event focused on Apple this week: on Capitol Hill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wBOZAJ"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/0Wmd05zs48HYLqPq2AkWK3" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X9H9lt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1HLZF"&gt;This week on &lt;em&gt;The Verge’&lt;/em&gt;s flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, co-&lt;/em&gt;hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22384756/apple-spring-loaded-event-recap-biggest-announcements-airtag-ipad-pro-imac"&gt;Tuesday hardware event&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; news editor Chaim Gartenberg as well as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396544/apple-app-store-google-play-monopoly-antitrust-bill-hearings"&gt;Wednesday’s congressional hearing&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to antitrust in the App Store with &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; politics reporter Makena Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXqqlO"&gt;The show bridges the gap between Apple announcing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215381/tile-ultra-wide-band-tracker-apple-airtags-samsung-smartthings"&gt;Tile competitor&lt;/a&gt; and Tile speaking in front of Congress the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RnCLZQ"&gt;Listen here or in your preferred podcast player to hear the full discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rcVTDa"&gt;Further reading: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="KqOP27"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395551/covid-vaccine-breakthrough-infection-rare-cdc"&gt;What we’re learning from the rare cases of COVID-19 in vaccinated people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IxXjty"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393624/alexa-covid-vaccine-amazon-site-location-call"&gt;Alexa can now tell you where to find a COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MDe2ed"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391587/long-covid-brain-cognitive-treatment-video-game-akili"&gt;Doctors are testing a prescription video game for COVID-19 ‘brain fog’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UHdNep"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393679/wisconsin-foxconn-contract-amendment-shrink"&gt;Wisconsin amends Foxconn’s contract to reflect radically smaller project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IvyuQ3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22384756/apple-spring-loaded-event-recap-biggest-announcements-airtag-ipad-pro-imac"&gt;Apple’s Spring Loaded event: the 8 biggest announcements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2FMiwu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;Apple Podcasts launches in-app subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="j8sD7A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396042/apple-podcast-subscriptions-launch-price"&gt;Can Apple get you to pay for podcasts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dqQn8c"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;Apple AirTag hands-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aobUwS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"&gt;Apple’s AirTags don’t have a built-in keychain loop, and we have some thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="favjas"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"&gt;Apple announces new Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ohvPT9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;Apple unveils an improved remote for its Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z8DidL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397231/apple-tv-4k-hd-iphone-color-calibration-sensor"&gt;Yes, older Apple TVs can also be calibrated with your iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6Bk4tu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Apple announces thinner iMac with M1 chip and bright colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cYNXkJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397196/magic-keyboard-touch-id-m1-mac-macbook-intel"&gt;New Touch ID Magic Keyboards work with all M1 Macs, not just the iMac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1HNqDS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;Apple launches new iPad Pro with M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EL9VX1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22394384/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-comparison"&gt;How the M1-powered iPad Pro compares to other iPad models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dB7Uzo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams"&gt;Any video conferencing app can use the iPad Pro’s fancy zoom and pan camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BNVRW0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395449/apple-ipad-pro-2021-liquid-retina-xdr-mini-led-explainer"&gt;Big iPad, Mini LED: why Apple’s new iPad Pro display is better and brighter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dzPBWT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396449/apple-ipad-pro-macbook-air-macos-2021"&gt;Put macOS on the iPad, you cowards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RUDFRj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396544/apple-app-store-google-play-monopoly-antitrust-bill-hearings"&gt;Congress is diving into the App Store fight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A8Viwz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/5/18212213/amazons-facebook-break-up-antitrust-paradox-lina-kahn-vergecast"&gt;Lina Kahn on Amazon’s antitrust paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lTNdT4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;Apple’s $64 billion-a-year app store isn’t catching the most egregious scams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A6EdQC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22392050/senator-tammy-duckworth-racism-anti-asian-hate"&gt;Sen. Tammy Duckworth on hate crimes, racism, and environmental justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Tk65G5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393622/asian-hate-crime-reporting-community-group-statistics"&gt;Asian Activists are tracking the surge in hate crimes as police reporting falls short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WHAGWd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22393952/glass-fiber-internet-cable-wifi-speed-5g-explainer-video"&gt;Inside the glass fibers connecting our wireless world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="0VkjM8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399276/vergecast-podcast-449-apple-spring-loaded-event-app-store-antitrust-hearing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399276/vergecast-podcast-449-apple-spring-loaded-event-app-store-antitrust-hearing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T09:27:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T09:27:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple AirTags and purple iPhone 12 are now available for preorder</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A bunch of AirTags" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C2ExKA4SOxeFX2-JGM0PFUhsF8s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69174776/vpavic_4547_20210421_0131.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new AirTag tracking devices&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q1LYDo"&gt;Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;Tile-like AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, long-rumored and finally announced at this week’s Spring Loaded event, are now available for preorder on Apple’s website. The small circular trackers work with Apple’s “Find My” app on iOS and have a built-in speaker, accelerometer, Bluetooth LE, and a replaceable battery. They cost &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-airtag%2Fairtag&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;$29 for one set&lt;/a&gt; or $99 for a four-pack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ni2m3L"&gt;Apple says the AirTags’ battery should be good for a year. They should start delivering between May 3rd and May 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Qp0xO"&gt;The existence of AirTags first became known nearly two years ago, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/30/20841204/ios13-code-apple-tile-location-tracking-tag-find-my-app"&gt;copies of the iOS 13 beta&lt;/a&gt;. Apple accidentally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21205994/apple-airtags-name-confirmed-tile-tracker-rumor-leak"&gt;confirmed the AirTags name&lt;/a&gt; in a support video last year that has since been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DIeNW8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"AirTag location trackers are smart, capable, and very Apple","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fi1d3g"&gt;Also revealed at Spring Loaded was the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22396502/purple-iphone-12-color-photos-shade-hue-lilac-lavender"&gt;new purple iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;. It’s identical to the other colors of the iPhone 12; it’s very fast, has a very nice screen, 5G, and great cameras, according to our review. It’s also available for &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-iphone%2Fiphone-12&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;preorder today on Apple’s website&lt;/a&gt; and will be widely available starting April 30th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yytOgK"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;2021 iMac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"&gt;new Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;new iPad Pro models&lt;/a&gt; Apple showed off at the Spring Loaded event will be available for preorder starting April 30th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gkdlzi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399157/apple-airtags-purple-iphone-12-preorder-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399157/apple-airtags-purple-iphone-12-preorder-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What’s on your desk, Dan Seifert? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A long look at the workspace of one of The Verge’s leading tech enthusiasts." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y870UlgZ0Oia76xZnZlNb5QlxkI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69174303/dseifert_20210415_4535_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A long look at the workspace of one of &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s leading tech enthusiasts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Visit the office of a Verge gearhead&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="sNynCU"&gt;If you’ve read a review, a gift guide, or a how-to on &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, then you’ve read something that’s been assigned by, edited by, or written by Dan Seifert. A longtime presence here, Dan’s knowledge of tech is vast and impressive — and is reflected by the number and quality of the devices you can see here in his home office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AqVuZd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about yourself. What is your background, and what do you do at &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TTQcpJ"&gt;I’ve been at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for nearly nine years and have held many hats and done many jobs over that time. But I’ve always had an involvement in the product reviews program, because I’m a complete gearhead who loves playing with new gadgets and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fOyWjy"&gt;Currently, I’m a deputy editor who helps run &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; machine every day. I oversee our entire product reviews and service journalism program, including reviews, gift guides, buying guides, how-to articles, deals articles, and yes, the “What’s on your desk?” series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jt7mtp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you decide where and how to set up your workspace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ytapus"&gt;I’ve been working from home a few days per week for a long time, so when we bought our current house a few years ago, one of the requirements was that it would have a dedicated office space that I could work from. That’s proven immensely helpful over the past year as we transitioned to a fully remote working environment during the pandemic. I cannot put enough emphasis on how valuable a separate workspace, complete with a door you can close, is when you work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wF4Lwy"&gt;That hasn’t stopped me from spending far too much time in here, though, as I also use this space for personal hobbies like tinkering with keyboards or playing the occasional PC game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dan’s desk is large enough to have space for multiple devices at the same time." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SmztO5AbQ4OLsqSQ2o6nBI5KrdY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461580/dseifert_20210415_4535_0018.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dan’s desk is large enough to have space for multiple devices at the same time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zPhTSh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about the desk itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50C7bG"&gt;The desk is one that is probably familiar to &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers, as it’s shown up in a few “What’s on your desk?” articles already. It’s a &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Fcatalog%2Fproduct%2Fview%2Fid%2F233%2Fs%2Fjarvis-adjustable-height-desk-bamboo%2Fcategory%2F3%2F%3Futm_source%3DNYMag%26utm_medium%3Drakuten%26ranMID%3D44880%26ranEAID%3DOHlcvPYhHQM%26ranSiteID%3DOHlcvPYhHQM-I22_PHu1Y9zpq1rraujdUw&amp;amp;xcust=VergeWOYDDanSeifert04212021"&gt;Fully Jarvis adjustable standing desk&lt;/a&gt; that I purchased about five years ago, back before the company rebranded from Ergo Depot to Fully. Believe it or not, I actually use the standing feature quite a bit and switch between standing and sitting modes multiple times per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cOOD7c"&gt;Mine is big — one of the things I wanted from it was the space to have multiple devices on the desk at the same time, since I’m constantly having to test new things. It’s 60 inches wide, has a bamboo top, and has the “ergo cut” in the front that makes it a little easier to pull my chair up close to it. Mounted underneath and out of site is a swiveling pencil tray that I keep odds and ends in, an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Delivery-Anker-PowerStrip-Outlets-Control/dp/B07DFFX34P?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=ad7cde89cb7f54d6cfe0c7619be64272&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Anker power adapter&lt;/a&gt; that has two three-prong power outlets, two USB-A ports, a USB-C port for easy device charging, and cable trays for all of the power strips that I need to run everything on my desk. Those plug in to a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/CyberPower-CP1500AVRLCD-Intelligent-Outlets-Mini-Tower/dp/B000FBK3QK?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=77ab0d3b5730457eb060aeb644d94dcf&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;CyberPower UPS&lt;/a&gt; down on the floor, which I bought when we started having some issues with power flickering in our house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="IEiK01"&gt;
&lt;div id="MP84Ae"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10458129"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0ZG3eN"&gt;
&lt;p id="3oeQ17"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how about your desk chair?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7UQzF"&gt;My chair is a relatively recent addition — the one I had for years worked fine for a couple of days per week working from home, but when I transferred to full-time remote, it just wasn’t cutting it. So I jumped last year when Amazon had a sale on the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Steelcase-442A40-5S25-Gesture-Graphite/dp/B016OIF2JU?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=9d31b2bf1192b3922f7ffdd8d3d731ef&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Steelcase Gesture&lt;/a&gt;, which was admittedly way more expensive than a chair should be (even on sale!), but it’s comfortable and endlessly adjustable, so I’ve been happy with it so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkQM8M"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a LOT of tech — more than we usually get to talk about. Why don’t we start with your main working setup? (That’s quite a monitor, by the way — and an interesting keyboard.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ruPwvO"&gt;I did warn you — I love gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RACHbc"&gt;The monitor is a 34-inch LG 34UM94-P ultrawide that I’ve had for about five years now. It’s great — I’ve plugged countless laptops, desktops, and other devices into it and it just gives me so much room for digital activities. It’s not the best for gaming, since it only goes up to 60Hz refresh rates, but its 3440 x 1440 resolution is ideal for productivity and photo editing. It’s mounted on an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/AmazonBasics-Premium-Single-Monitor-Stand/dp/B00MIBN16O?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=fbe892d1a6c334c8fadd6fe81d23d056&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Amazon Basics monitor arm&lt;/a&gt;, which keeps it at eye level for me and frees up more space on my desk. That weird little white puck in the middle of the stand post is a SmartThings motion and temperature sensor, which controls the smart lights and fans in my office. It’s in that spot because that’s where it can reliably see my fingers moving on the keyboard or mouse, which prevents the lights from shutting off in the middle of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u0qW4n"&gt;The keyboard is something I’ve spent a ton of time (and way too much money) tinkering on, and I’m constantly changing parts of it to try different things. The board itself is an &lt;a href="https://epomaker.com/collections/mini-64/products/epomaker-gk68xs?variant=31743346737225"&gt;Epomaker / Skyloong GK68XS aluminum&lt;/a&gt;, which has a compact 65 percent layout, hot swappable switches, and built-in Bluetooth support. I bought it completely assembled, but before I even plugged it in, I pulled all the keycaps and switches out of it and replaced them with ones of my own choosing. The caps are currently the &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdrop.com%2F%3Forigin%3D%252Fbuy%252Fdrop-matt3o-mt3-susuwatari-custom-keycap-set&amp;amp;xcust=VergeWOYDDanSeifert04222021"&gt;Matt3o MT3 Susuwatari set from Drop&lt;/a&gt; and the switches are &lt;a href="https://mkultra.click/gazzew-boba-silent-tactile-u4-switches"&gt;Gazzew Boba U4 silent tactiles&lt;/a&gt;, which I have dismantled and put 55g springs inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UF5Xnm"&gt;
&lt;div id="BrtNY3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10458140"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Xpp4Bs"&gt;
&lt;p id="7l56kz"&gt;I recently rewatched &lt;em&gt;Halt and Catch Fire&lt;/em&gt; and was enamored with the vintage PC keyboards they used in the show, so I built this one with that aesthetic in mind. As mentioned, it’s a wireless board, but I couldn’t resist getting one of those &lt;a href="https://mechcables.com/collections/pre-made/products/stealth-gray-coiled-aviator-cable"&gt;fancy coiled cables&lt;/a&gt; for it, so I typically use it plugged in most of the time. I don’t like noisy keyboards at all, but this setup is surprisingly quiet — even quieter than the keyboard on my MacBook Air. I have no issue using it during Zoom calls and will probably bring it to the office with me when we return to work there since it won’t disturb others. That will free up space on my desk for another keyboard, giving me a whole new thing to tinker with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="This Epomaker aluminum keyboard has had all its keycaps and switches replaced." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l1Tg9vn8I9GFAwMihnl0aorX_No=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461569/dseifert_20210415_4535_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Epomaker aluminum keyboard has had all its keycaps and switches replaced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A SmartThings motion / temperature sensor hangs next to a CalDigit TS3 Plus Thunderbolt 3 dock." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZmK7DNyXsbA8vd8MpUbOE2u6C6M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461574/dseifert_20210415_4535_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A SmartThings motion / temperature sensor hangs next to a CalDigit TS3 Plus Thunderbolt 3 dock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A set of Microsoft Surface Headphones 2 next to a long-discontinued speaker from Audyssey." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LbV9GkSC-82jMFNvIvPyRqr9RsA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461576/dseifert_20210415_4535_0014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A set of Microsoft Surface Headphones 2 next to a long-discontinued speaker from Audyssey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vnWAtn"&gt;Next to it is a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Vertical-Wireless-Mouse-Rechargeable/dp/B07FNJB8TT?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=98868343bc48c0c2d331becc3cea68a5&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Logitech MX Vertical mouse&lt;/a&gt;, which I got when I started having some pain in my right shoulder after using a mouse all day. It seems to have relieved it, but if you can avoid getting old, I recommend that instead — it’s no fun. The other piece of ergonomic equipment I have is the wrist rest in front of the keyboard, which I can’t type without. I’ve tried soft wrist rests before, but I really like the support this &lt;a href="https://www.nizkeyboard.com/collections/ornaments/products/walnut-wood-keyboard-handle-60-81-84-87-108-size-customization?variant=31000131829831"&gt;walnut one from NIZ Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; provides. It also looks nice, which I can’t always say for soft types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5lJ1H1"&gt;Every device on my desk — monitor, keyboard, speakers, microphone, external storage drives, laptop, camera, Ethernet — is plugged into a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/CalDigit-TS3-Plus-Thunderbolt-Dock/dp/B07CZPV8DF?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=44e010434d44d85df190150cf59f5f6f&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;CalDigit TS3 Plus&lt;/a&gt; Thunderbolt 3 dock. I love this thing because it lets me easily swap between computers with just one cable, keeps my laptop charged up, and gives me all the ports I need. It even has a high-speed SD card slot on the front which I use all the time when dumping images from my camera. My only gripe is the obvious cable management mess you can see behind it — I’ve given up trying to make it any better than it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="X67m9v"&gt;
&lt;div id="1NVm1L"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10199988"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="6vcgEs"&gt;
&lt;p id="B0JrpB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a more complete assortment of devices for online meetings than most, with a camera, microphone, headphones…  And I see you use a “regular” camera for your video.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmtCxf"&gt;Yeah, it’s… a lot. The headphones are a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/NEW-Microsoft-Surface-Headphones-Light/dp/B086Q9YGD3?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=d3a04f9c332ba2e81dc27685ed0aa4d2&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Microsoft Surface Headphones 2&lt;/a&gt; that I put on an old Twelve South Fermata stand, which has a built-in cable to charge them up when I’m done. I use these wirelessly the vast majority of the time and for every video call meeting I take, so even though they have relatively good battery life, I still have to charge them every other day or so. A lot of times, I just have them on with nothing playing because the noise cancellation blocks out the sounds of my kids playing just outside the office door. I’ve also got a set of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=12835663ef7b1640a2b324d53871b825&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mophie-Wireless-Charge-Pad-Charging/dp/B07XPWD4WW?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=ed53412036c3100213a44762a5f822b5&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Mophie 3-in-1 wireless charger&lt;/a&gt; that I use if I forget to charge the Surface Headphones or just need a break from something sitting on my head. Also on my desk and plugged into the Thunderbolt dock is a set of &lt;a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_from=R40&amp;amp;_trksid=p2546172.m570.l1313&amp;amp;_nkw=lower+east+side+speakers&amp;amp;_sacat=0&amp;amp;mkcid=1&amp;amp;mkrid=711-53200-19255-0&amp;amp;siteid=0&amp;amp;campid=5338794975&amp;amp;customid=VergeWOYDanSeifert04222021&amp;amp;toolid=10001&amp;amp;mkevt=1#donotlink"&gt;long-discontinued Audyssey Lower East Side speakers&lt;/a&gt;, which have enough punch on their own that I don’t need a subwoofer for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q8jzsD"&gt;When I need to record better audio for a podcast, I use the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blue-Yeti-USB-Microphone-Blackout/dp/B00N1YPXW2?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=7d3b63ea07e45c2f39167a4364e3ce95&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Blue Yeti mic&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07DHLSTLV?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=af2adee52e919fd7d8f7cac2cb215183&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;swiveling boom arm&lt;/a&gt; that I can just push out of the way when I don’t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ARkpx"&gt;The camera is a Fujifilm X-H1 mounted on an adjustable rig I &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1015864-REG%2Fimpact_3_section_double_articulated.html&amp;amp;xcust=VergeWOYDDanSeifert04212021"&gt;cobbled&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/824360-REG/impact_cc_106r_super_clamp_with_ratchet.html"&gt;together&lt;/a&gt; and is plugged into an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07Y7BFXVM?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=5e10fc3b8f0697b5ee4b6b4014cdbdcd&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;HDMI capture card&lt;/a&gt; that’s mounted out of sight behind the monitor. Its video quality is a lot better than any webcam you can purchase, even if it’s decidedly overkill for the Zoom calls that I do all day long. Hooking it all up is surprisingly easy to do if you have a camera lying around — I &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21244380/webcam-camera-how-to-dslr-mirrorless-capture-card-usb-hdmi"&gt;wrote about how to do it for the site&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXR5e6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next to the window, you have a tablet and — what looks like a small pile of tech?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3UjaLd"&gt;Ah yes, the overflow pile. Over there is where I have a pencil cup, some notebooks, and random headphones. There’s also an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Show-8/dp/B07PF1Y28C?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=886f2bf0e5b8c636c150ddc51968b7f6&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"&gt;Amazon Echo Show 8&lt;/a&gt; that alerts me when someone has rung the doorbell and also lets me tap into the baby camera so I can keep an eye on her when she’s napping. There are a couple other smart home sensors there, too, which help my HVAC system know when I’m in the office and adjust itself accordingly. Mounted on the wall is a bulletin board where I’ve got some pictures of my kids and artwork they’ve made for me. And, oh yeah, there’s a lightsaber.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The overflow pile includes review devices, sensors, and an Echo Show 8." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9lLVA8NbCTJSVKnshft3fk0122U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22461579/dseifert_20210415_4535_0017.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The overflow pile includes review devices, sensors, and an Echo Show 8.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3O7mO4"&gt;My daily work computer is an &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1041045/7613?sharedid=VergeWOYDDanSeifert04222021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-air"&gt;M1 MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, which works great for nearly everything. But if I want to play games, I need a Windows machine, so over on the other side of the desk is my gaming laptop (an &lt;a href="https://www.eluktronics.com/MAG-15-1P16R"&gt;Eluktronics MAG-15&lt;/a&gt; with an RTX 2070), plus a 12.9-inch 2018 iPad Pro that I used to use a lot more when I commuted. It has built-in LTE, which is a lifesaver on the train but not especially useful when I’m home on Wi-Fi all the time. This pile is also where the rotating cast of review devices tend to live when I’m testing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hJ4lKP"&gt;
&lt;div id="O0ar7I"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9573987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="x58Rfn"&gt;
&lt;p id="6rbGVI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All in all, you seem pretty organized — you even have a box for your really small items.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSILu5"&gt;If there’s one complaint I have with my desk, it’s that there’s no under-desk storage, so I basically have to keep everything on top of it or in other organizing systems elsewhere in my office. So in addition to the hidden pencil tray mounted underneath the desk, I have some &lt;a href="https://www.muji.us/store/furniture-interior/storage-organizers.html"&gt;small stackable Muji makeup trays&lt;/a&gt; to keep random things like SIM card tools, batteries, microfiber cloths, SD cards, USB cables, etc. somewhat organized. There’s often a lot of spill over, though, and since this desk is so big, it’s easy for me to ignore the mess and let it pile up. It’s possible I may have cheated a little and cleaned up before taking these pictures, but I won’t tell if you don’t. &lt;em&gt;[Editor’s note: it’s too late — we’ve all seen your desk at the office...]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3fcH8A"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And with all that tech, you still have an old-fashioned notebook and pen by your keyboard.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aqm5Ur"&gt;I’ve spent so many years trying to make a digital note-taking system work for me, but I just can’t get along with writing on a screen. I keep a Moleskine notebook open next to me at all times so I can quickly jot down things I need to remember or notes when I’m in a call or meeting. I find I can pay attention to meetings better when I’m handwriting notes compared to typing them out, even if I struggle to actually read my handwriting afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f8GgIZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else about your workspace that we haven’t covered?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="JTQIQH"&gt;Being forced to tally all of this stuff up makes me realize just how much is involved with my work setup. It could probably use a bit of pruning and simplification. But since I spend so much time here, investing in the space has been worth it, even if it seems like a lot when it’s all added up. Between the comfort and efficiency my workspace gives me, I don’t totally dread spending most of my day in this spot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0u0R6Q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2BXYT5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22395531/remote-work-desk-setup-from-home-office-tech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22395531/remote-work-desk-setup-from-home-office-tech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T07:22:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T07:22:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft releases Office 2021 for Mac preview</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HU0XifkQndRgA4G7dtf1vQyddk0=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69174157/officeicons.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B3VY3V"&gt;Microsoft is releasing a preview version of Office 2021 for Mac and Office LTSC this week. While Office LTSC (Long-Term Servicing Channel) is &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/commercial-preview-of-microsoft-office-long-term-servicing/ba-p/2260013"&gt;designed for commercial customers&lt;/a&gt;, both versions are perpetual versions of Office that don’t rely on subscriptions or the cloud. Microsoft announced its plans for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288959/microsoft-office-2021-windows-mac-features-release-date-price"&gt;Office 2021 back in February&lt;/a&gt;, and a Windows version — which won’t be available in preview — will also be released later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFjn18"&gt;Office 2021 for Mac will support both Apple Silicon and Intel-based Macs, and require at least 4GB of RAM and 10GB of storage space. It’s designed to be a static release of Office, but during the preview there will be monthly updates that could include new features. Once Office 2021 for Mac is final and released, no new features will be added. Current &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/deployoffice/office2021/overview-mac-preview"&gt;improvements include&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kykYrT"&gt;Line Focus, this feature removes distractions to let Word users move through a document line by line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iNW3AM"&gt;XLOOKUP, an Excel feature that lets you find things in a table or range by row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1Pddsg"&gt;Dynamic array support in Excel, which has new functions for dynamic arrays in spreadsheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nFdtpj"&gt;Record a slide show with narration in PowerPoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="MV6Iiw"&gt;Microsoft’s Office LTSC variant will also include things like dark mode support, accessibility improvements, and the same Dynamic Arrays and XLOOKUP features found in Excel 2021 for Mac. Office 2021 for Windows will include similar features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NqNCk3"&gt;If you’re interested in trying out Office 2021 for Mac, you’ll need to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgo.microsoft.com%2Ffwlink%2Fp%2F%3Flinkid%3D2159127&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F23%2F22399042%2Fmicrosoft-office-2021-for-mac-preview-download" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;download the installer from Microsoft’s site&lt;/a&gt; and a special &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgo.microsoft.com%2Ffwlink%2Fp%2F%3Flinkid%3D2147058&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F23%2F22399042%2Fmicrosoft-office-2021-for-mac-preview-download" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Volume License Serializer&lt;/a&gt; to activate the preview.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399042/microsoft-office-2021-for-mac-preview-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399042/microsoft-office-2021-for-mac-preview-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T07:00:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T07:00:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple lawsuit over ‘buy’ and ‘rent’ labels for digital content can continue, rules federal judge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fq0LmCW3roSsZeMH42Rdq4LXNcA=/42x0:1590x1032/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69174133/apple_previews_macos_catalina_apple_music_screen_06032019.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZAqtTC"&gt;A federal judge has rejected a motion by Apple to dismiss a putative class action lawsuit over the company’s use of the labels “buy” and “rent” when selling digital content. As first covered by &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr-esq/apple-must-face-lawsuit-for-telling-consumers-they-can-buy-movies-tv-shows"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the suit can now continue, though could yet be settled before ever reaching trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnmeP6"&gt;The lead plaintiff in the case, David Andino, argues that Apple is misleading consumers when it tells them it can “buy” digital versions of albums, TV shows, and films from its stores. Why? Because the iPhone-maker retains the power to terminate customers’ access to this content whenever it likes. This can happen, for example, when the company loses distribution rights to content that users haven’t secured by downloading to their device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HAO8ke"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Just like Best Buy cannot come into a person’s home to repossess [your] DVD”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M0ptNB"&gt;“Just like Best Buy cannot come into a person’s home to repossess the movie DVD that such person purchased from it, defendant should not be able to remove, or permit the removal by others of, digital content from its customers,” says Andino’s &lt;a href="http://casefilingsalert.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Apple-Video-Content.pdf"&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;. “Though some consumers may get lucky and never lose access to any of their paid for media, others may one day find that their digital content is now gone forever.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i7Oc68"&gt;Apple attempted to have the case dismissed, but a ruling this week by US District Court Judge John Mendez shows that the company’s arguments weren’t entirely convincing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WA5YOC"&gt;“Apple contends that ‘[n]o reasonable consumer would believe’ that purchased content would remain on the iTunes platform indefinitely,” wrote Mendez in an &lt;a href="https://cases.justia.com/federal/district-courts/california/caedce/2:2020cv01628/377618/22/0.pdf?ts=1618990542"&gt;order&lt;/a&gt; filed with the Eastern District of California. “But in common usage, the term ‘buy’ means to acquire possession over something. It seems plausible, at least at the motion to dismiss stage, that reasonable consumers would expect their access couldn’t be revoked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="XIvBgO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;To quote Webster’s definition of “buy”...&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O69b21"&gt;To emphasize his point, Mendez pointed to the definition of the word “buy” in the &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/buy"&gt;Mirriam-Webster dictionary&lt;/a&gt; (meaning “to acquire possession, ownership, or rights to the use or services of by payment especially of money”) — a timeless move that is, apparently, as welcome in federal legal proceedings as in hastily-written wedding speeches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27Kz4t"&gt;Apple tried to argue that Andino’s “injury” was purely speculative, as he has not actually lost access to any content. But, as Mendez summarizes, the injury being presented is not the threat of losing future access, but the deception involved in Apple’s use of the word “buy.” This misleads consumers about the exact nature of ownership, meaning Andino “paid either too much for the product or spent money he would not have but for the misrepresentation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwygkI"&gt;Apple did have some success, though, and one element of the lawsuit was dismissed: Andino’s claims to “unjust enrichment,” which would affect how any potential damages would be calculated. Mendez did, though, leave open the possibility of future “injunctive relief” — that is, material changes to how Apple sells content in future. All these questions, though, will have to be settled in future proceedings. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399008/apple-lawsuit-over-buy-and-rent-labels-for-digital-content-can-continue-rules-federal-judge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399008/apple-lawsuit-over-buy-and-rent-labels-for-digital-content-can-continue-rules-federal-judge</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T04:20:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T04:20:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Siri Remote waves goodbye to Apple TV games that require motion control</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EVlOdKQnByZasU0uBk2tT9_NSXs=/121x0:1414x862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173835/WcGeQVXeT3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SFX6wg"&gt;Apple’s new Siri Remote doesn’t come equipped with an accelerometer or gyroscope, which means it won’t work as a motion controller in certain Apple TV games. The omission was initially &lt;a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/new-siri-remote-59-dollars/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and can be seen on the remotes’ product pages. The &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:ir5H-fryxNwJ:https://www.apple.com/uk/shop/product/MQGD2ZM/A/siri-remote+&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=uk"&gt;old&lt;/a&gt; Siri Remote listed an “Accelerometer” and “Three-axis gyro” in the tech specs, but they’re missing from the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fuk%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMJFM3ZM%2FA%2Fsiri-remote&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F23%2F22398974%2Fapple-tv-siri-remote-motion-controls-accelerometer-three-axis-gyro" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new listing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7asiI"&gt;The change means that the new Siri Remote won’t work with certain Apple TV games that rely on motion controls. According to code in tvOS 14.5 &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/04/22/new-siri-remote-lacks-accelerometer-gyroscope/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=webfeeds"&gt;seen by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, trying to play an incompatible game will lead to the following error message: “To play this game on your Apple TV, you need to connect the Apple TV Remote (1st generation) or a compatible PlayStation, Xbox or MFi controller.” If you’ve got one, you might want to keep an old Siri Remote around for occasions like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQhZTH"&gt;The lack of motion controls might sound surprising given the new Apple TV box was expected to have a bigger gaming focus, and arrives as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370217/apple-arcade-fantasian-nba2k-wonderbox-classics-netflix"&gt;Apple Arcade is maturing&lt;/a&gt; into a pretty compelling games subscription service. But in recent years Apple has shifted its attention towards more traditional gaming controllers, away from motion controls. It dropped its requirement for games to support the Siri Remote’s motion controls &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/6/14/11930760/apple-tv-games-controller-remote-requirement"&gt;in June 2016&lt;/a&gt; just months after the remote launched alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/28/9630952/new-apple-tv-4-review"&gt;2015 Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;. Then, in June 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18650683/apple-tv-xbox-one-ps4-controller-support-wwdc-2019"&gt;it announced&lt;/a&gt; Apple TV support for Xbox One and PS4 controllers. Support for PS5 and Xbox Series X and S controllers is &lt;a href="https://www.flatpanelshd.com/news.php?subaction=showfull&amp;amp;id=1612241720"&gt;expected to arrive with tvOS 14.5&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dTdow6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJqfkY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398974/apple-tv-siri-remote-motion-controls-accelerometer-three-axis-gyro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398974/apple-tv-siri-remote-motion-controls-accelerometer-three-axis-gyro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
