<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-13T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-13T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-13T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to customize your iPhone’s app icons</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OOdBcTTheQdzuU1CVztawE8DbsE=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69446002/bfarsace_201106_4269_030.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CT8iXi"&gt;Have you ever wanted to make your iPhone your own, with your individualized style and flair? Sure, you can change your home screen wallpaper. But if you really want to personalize your phone, why not create your own app icons? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D4hFLk"&gt;It’s doable, using Apple’s built-in Shortcuts app. You actually won’t be replacing the icons that the apps came with — rather, you’ll be creating separate Shortcuts that lead to the app.   It’s a tedious and time-consuming process, but in the end, you can have a fully customized iPhone home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JTqHfS"&gt;Here’s how you do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4opbvA"&gt;First, find and tap on the Shortcuts app. It’s pre-installed; if you can’t see it immediately on your home screen, swipe left until you’re at the App Library and start typing “Shortcuts” into the top search bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dA4Adi"&gt;Once you’re in the app, tap on the “plus” sign in the upper-right corner, and then on “Add Action”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Shortcut can help you create new bookmarks for your apps" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DmTDxfYPnlWBvy5ksFZwCCeVnMA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653452/IMG_9007135DEFEF_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shortcuts can help you create new bookmarks for your apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The plus sign in the opening screen will lead to the New Shortcut page" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/36aWAUpH5b8ORalmRTApv3FwoP8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653453/IMG_8B871FA6861F_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The plus sign in the opening screen will lead to the New Shortcut page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Rl4v05"&gt;There are a lot of interesting things to try out in Shortcuts. But right now, what we want to do is switch app icons. Type “Open app” in the search bar and then tap on the “Open App” link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XCKRrg"&gt;Tap on the word “Choose.” You’ll see a list of your apps; pick the one you want to customize and you’ll be taken back to the New Shortcut page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Type “Open app” in the search bar" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cl_fKOn61f18IdH-awincjKiD9g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653455/IMG_37022E4783D2_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Type “Open app” in the search bar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on “Choose” to select which icon to replace" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X-I9_LAmRnwQlRO5sEvmwinCkg4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653457/IMG_1A089FF8B14A_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on “Choose” to select which icon to replace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="HzgHOz"&gt;Select the three dots in the upper-right corner. You’re now in the Details page. Give your shortcut a name and tap “Add to Home Screen.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uuIAM1"&gt;You’ll now see a preview of the icon (which will be a standard, uninteresting icon that Shortcuts automatically adds). Don’t worry, we’re going to make it better. Select Add in the top-right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Name your shortcut and tap on “Add to Home Screen”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DvxzULfAgJv8c2t7cL15UgDni-I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653471/IMG_C0782AA4336E_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name your shortcut and tap on “Add to Home Screen.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select “Add”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rpqlPJlBKnT0wSSeVIn8cNh2Rcw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653474/IMG_5A5AAD54523D_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select “Add.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4A9Oyt"&gt;Now it’s time to find your substitute icon. There are a bunch of icon sources online (&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.flaticon.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22529978%2Fapple-iphone-ios-apps-icon-change" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Flaticon&lt;/a&gt;, for example), or if you’re artistic and / or ambitious, you can create your own. Whether you use someone else’s or your own, save the image to Photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2SImSe"&gt;Now go back to the Shortcuts preview area. (You can find it again by going to the Details section and tapping on “Add to Home Screen.”) Tap on the icon under “Home Screen Name and Icon.” You’ll have the choice of either taking a photo, choosing a photo, or choosing a file. Assuming you’ve already saved an image in Photo, tap on “Choose Photo” and select the photo you want to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="udyrhq"&gt;On the next screen, a highlighted area will indicate what part of the photo will appear as an icon; you can move the photo around until you’re happy with the section indicated. Tap “Choose” in the lower-right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can create an icon from a new photo, a saved photo, or a file" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tVDuCP2oNtlJkjaJJkSN8j_CM7s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653487/IMG_8F28F1423B8D_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can create an icon from a new photo, a saved photo, or a file.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You’ll have to crop your photo to the right dimensions" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/02fQSnoF4bW2iUtHgdeN-rswHUo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653493/IMG_2A665EFE27F3_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll have to crop your photo to the right dimensions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lCKV5y"&gt;Now, you’ll see your new icon. Tap Add.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vzDhp6"&gt;You should see your new customized icon on your home screen. Congrats!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SBacWP"&gt;There’s the possibility you may see two new icons on your home screen: one with the first boring icon, and one with your wonderful new icon. If that’s the case, just press and hold the icon that you don’t want, and then select “Delete bookmark.” Remember, this (and the other you created) is a bookmark / shortcut — not the original.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Voila! Your new icon is ready" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IqDtwhDt2TrnFN05duszNvUc69w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653500/IMG_0D46D384E161_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voila! Your new icon is ready.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can hide the original icon if you want" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2wcXApwlRvi8PzqoYVUXlCHp7iw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653502/IMG_141812774F53_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can hide the original icon if you want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="uMQx0K"&gt;You can also hide the original app icon so you’ll just have the new one visible. (You don’t want to delete it completely, of course; that would delete the app.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4q02gy"&gt;Long-press on the original app icon and select “Edit Home Screen” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8Ppj8h"&gt;Tap on the minus sign. On the pop-up menu, tap “Remove from Home Screen.” The original icon won’t be deleted, just hidden; you can always find it in the App Library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="vs46q8"&gt;One note: when you use your new icon to go to the app, you will occasionally get a small drop-down notice that tells you what the original app is called and to remind you of the fact that it is a shortcut. But the drop-down will only last for a second or two, so it shouldn’t be much of a bother.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22529978/apple-iphone-ios-apps-icon-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22529978/apple-iphone-ios-apps-icon-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T14:15:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T14:15:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>New iPad Pro ad features classic song from The Little Mermaid</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Bikg-WGXHKryB29DkniiLYC7cA=/58x0:1248x793/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444467/Screen_Shot_2021_06_12_at_10.35.24_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cmtkPo"&gt;Apple’s YouTube page currently has an unlisted video for a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=awTP7IUY3uo"&gt;very clever iPad Pro ad&lt;/a&gt; featuring the song “Part of Your World” from Disney’s iconic animated film &lt;em&gt;The Little Mermaid &lt;/em&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/12/ipad-pro-ad-little-mermaid/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WLmP44"&gt;In the ad, PC users sing the lyrics to the classic song while looking upon their (of course) ugly-looking computer setups that are filled with peripherals and wires. (One woman’s leg is literally tied to her chair by a cord.) Often, they forlornly look outside, where people are happily using their iPad Pros to video chat, play games, and do work, seemingly free from the horrible confines of desktop computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UBvotj"&gt;The lyrics, admittedly, do apply well for an ad where Apple is trying to prove that an iPad Pro can do everything that a “normal” computer can do without things like a dedicated monitor or a constant power supply. I should note, though, that many of the iPad Pro users in the ad have additional accessories paired with their device such as an Apple Pencil or a Magic Keyboard case. Even in Apple’s own marketing, an iPad Pro on its own sometimes isn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n8juw8"&gt;Here are all of the lyrics used in the ad, if you want to follow along while you watch. (For the Disney purists, or those that grew up seeing &lt;em&gt;The Little Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; approximately one thousand times, like I did, you should know that Apple skips chunks of the full song to make the lyrics work better for the ad.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0WqhjX"&gt;Look at this stuff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XB7xOv"&gt;Isn’t it neat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Whjop"&gt;Wouldn’t you think my collection’s complete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojdzA8"&gt;Wouldn’t think I’m the girl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jYQeXR"&gt;The girl who has everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bC71b6"&gt;Got gadgets and gizmos a-plenty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nh9cCH"&gt;Got whositz and whatzits galore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="69xheR"&gt;You want thingamobs? I’ve got 20!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFv1wG"&gt;But who cares, no big deal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ou1Zb4"&gt;I want more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTKSRY"&gt;Up where they walk, up where they run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWBaxF"&gt;Up where they stay all day in the sun &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5o7W2R"&gt;Wandering free, wish I could be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e09Fer"&gt;Part of that world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="uYcOqH"&gt;The ad’s appearance follows the release of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;new iPad Pros in May&lt;/a&gt; that have Apple’s custom-designed M1 processor onboard and, for the 12.9-inch model, a brand new Mini LED display.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530965/apple-ipad-pro-ad-the-little-mermaid-song-part-of-your-world"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530965/apple-ipad-pro-ad-the-little-mermaid-song-part-of-your-world</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T20:18:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T20:18:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple rubberstamped Trump’s request to secretly scoop up data on two members of Congress</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wxb5CmJPhMnhWOoqpeb-NdvtPNk=/0x336:4032x3024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69442683/B2E53F34_14F4_4895_AECA_E72D86070E7C.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Steve Jobs Theater at Apple’s Apple Park headquarters.&lt;/em&gt; | Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FBbcJ8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/11/technology/apple-google-leak-investigation-data-requests.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;is reporting&lt;/a&gt; on a new wrinkle in the story of how the Trump administration’s Department of Justice used Big Tech &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data"&gt;to spy on two members of the House Intelligence Committee&lt;/a&gt; in an attempt to track down leaks to the press — namely, that Apple didn’t fight it, perhaps never had a chance to fight it, because the company rubberstamped the request. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rGvdjG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Trump administration forced Apple to secretly reveal at least two Democrats’ data","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="13T3Uy"&gt;Apple didn’t even know it was handing over the records of Congressman Adam Schiff (D-CA), then the ranking member of the House Intelligence Committee, it told the publication. In a statement, Apple said it didn’t know what the investigation was about, and couldn’t have known unless it dug through user accounts itself. So it was handled like the vast majority of the 250 requests the company received from the government each week: approved. “An Apple paralegal complied and provided the information,” reports the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nWJTaa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Apple did not realize that data on two Democratic lawmakers was part of a request by the Trump Justice Department. It was handled by a paralegal like a routine request.&lt;a href="https://t.co/kS51EUmnCp"&gt;https://t.co/kS51EUmnCp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jack Nicas (@jacknicas) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jacknicas/status/1403471132435623936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="myl4ao"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;More details: The grand jury subpoena sought metadata for 109 identifiers, specifically 73 phone numbers and 36 email addresses. Apple said it assumes ISPs and other tech companies were also sent similar requests. Apple now limits identifiers to 25 or less.&lt;/p&gt;— Zack Whittaker (@zackwhittaker) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zackwhittaker/status/1403476908789178375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9KULPB"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Times’ &lt;/em&gt;piece paints a picture of a US government whose requests have been increasing in volume, and perhaps a general willingness by Big Tech to comply (not that these companies often have a choice). Apple challenged only 4 percent of this sort of request in the first six months of 2020, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;. And while Google fought a gag order when the Trump administration seized the phone records of &lt;em&gt;NYT &lt;/em&gt;reporters, the story suggests it was easier to challenge because Google counted the NYT as a corporate customer, not an individual user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLMN3L"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/transparency/us.html"&gt;Both Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/user-data/overview?hl=en&amp;amp;user_requests_report_period=series:requests,accounts;authority:US;time:&amp;amp;lu=user_requests_report_period"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; have transparency report pages where you can see how many government requests they received, and how often they comply. Apple didn’t reply to our request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="If2jF8"&gt;Microsoft was also swept up in Trump’s leak hunt. It told the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; that it, too, only learned that it had provided information to the government about a congressional staff member after a gag order expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hzJtqP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RPiZb9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkxpTv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530359/trump-leak-hunt-apple-google-microsoft-subpoena"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530359/trump-leak-hunt-apple-google-microsoft-subpoena</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T15:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T15:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple added beautiful 3D details to Maps, but it still can’t get me out of this forest</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nl0o8e27XqvpcvCsZpQNU99YuG4=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69441470/image.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is impressive, but it won’t help me get around town.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wShuUH"&gt;During the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22456874/apple-ios-15-features-notifications-facetime-wwdc-2021"&gt;iOS portion of Apple’s WWDC keynote&lt;/a&gt;, it showed some amazing demos of 3D cities and AR transit directions, but amid all the beautiful features there were a few things missing from the stage and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fios%2Fios-15-preview%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F11%2F22528793%2Fapple-maps-missing-features-ios-15-aesthetics-functionality" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s iOS 15 feature list&lt;/a&gt;. Namely, some basic navigation tools that would let me get around easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ex1Ol4"&gt;Since Apple seems to be focusing a lot on Maps (it got stage time &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/GEZhD3J89ZE?t=1190"&gt;at last year’s keynote, too&lt;/a&gt;), perhaps they’re also taking requests? Here’s my wishlist. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ppj4Zoa2G1SbtyIMxLl4cY242jI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653069/IMG_1751.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t forget, you’re here forever.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="Sv4BJw"&gt;Offline Maps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="CJGdyY"&gt;Without a cellular signal or Wi-Fi, Apple Maps turns into a brick — you can’t search for locations, find routes, or do anything useful. This is, to put it lightly, a bit of a problem for a navigation app that’s been around for eight years. Imagine you used Apple Maps to navigate to somewhere that doesn’t have reliable cell service (like, say, many national parks), then want to go home. Apple Maps can get you through a dead zone, but if you’ll be staying a while, you won’t be able to use Apple Maps to get back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DUwfl5"&gt;While leaving civilization and never coming back may appeal to some people (hello), it’s not the experience most are looking for. There are various ways to solve this — Apple could create a system where Maps caches the places you’ve recently traveled through, making at least basic routing available without an internet connection, or it could go full Google Maps and let you arbitrarily download massive parts of the map that will be available offline. There just needs to be some way to navigate your way out of a cellular dead zone should you find yourself in one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zddpp0"&gt;Since Apple Maps will work offline if you’ve got navigation going, maybe there’s a workaround? Could you create a route that brings you to a place, but then also takes you back home? That’s very clever, but no, because Apple Maps doesn’t have... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="zMSdQm"&gt;The ability to create multi-stop routes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="cIIMfP"&gt;The ability to create routes with more than one destination is, admittedly, more useful while you’re planning a trip than while you’re actually traveling, but it can still save you the hassle of having to choose a new destination every time you arrive somewhere. Apple Maps, however, doesn’t have this ability — you can do point-to-point travel, and that’s it. As far as I (and people on &lt;a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/8502456"&gt;Apple’s forums&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/ck4wcg/why_doesnt_apple_maps_support_multiple/"&gt;and Reddit&lt;/a&gt;) can tell, you can’t even do multiple stops in the desktop Apple Maps, which would at least help with planning. Meanwhile, in Google Maps land...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E4srLdrdUKbUmWaH6pv7VEhLgIo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652964/IMG_1746.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JkM6vN"&gt;But wait, isn’t there an Add Stop button in Apple Maps? Indeed, there is, but I regret to tell you that it’s not for creating multi-stop routes — it’s for adding a brief detour. And, to add insult to injury, it’s almost useless for what it’s actually designed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-riJ2fVYEGKgJ_bzJ3eVcGpwaLk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652951/IMG_1747.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Add Stop button brings nothing but frustration. In my two years using Apple Maps, I’ve never successfully used it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id="SlimF6"&gt;The ability to actually choose a stop along your route&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="JyOBYk"&gt;The Add Stop button lets you find a temporary pit stop along your route, so you can take a break from driving to get food, gas, or whatever. The problem is that it’s extremely limited in this capability — it only lets you choose from a few predetermined categories and will only show you a few from each one. It does provide a quick and easy interface for use while driving, but if you want to do something specific, you’ll be in for a rough time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ntFXkTLnQeJ5oUz7PLoGLuXrZgk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653067/IMG_1752.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tapping on Restaurants (currently labeled “Breakfast” because it’s morning) will give you a list of 10 places that are nearby.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="c6KcFm"&gt;If you want to stop at a specific restaurant, you can’t search for it using the Add Stop menu. As an example, say I was traveling to Seattle but wanted to stop at a McDonald’s along the way. I’d have to stop my navigation to Seattle and set it to McDonald’s instead. Then, after I was done there, I’d have to set my navigation to Seattle again. With Google Maps, I’d just be able to search along my route, add McDonald’s, and be good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B4XBxf"&gt;Google Maps’ search along route feature is great for another reason — if I want to stop in, say, 60 miles instead of right now, I could set Google Maps&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to a gas station that’s a ways up the road. Apple Maps can only show what’s around you, not further on along the route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="HI06lC"&gt;More obvious bike and footpaths&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="nCayN9"&gt;This one is small, but if you’re trying to visually plan out a route where you’ll be walking or biking, you’ll really have to hunt for paths in Apple Maps. Look at this comparison between a local paved trail in Apple Maps versus what it looks like in Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ls1HNY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10602509"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yFbuKk"&gt;It’s safe to say that the one in Google Maps is just a tad easier to notice and trace. Apple did mention improving details like this in iOS 15, but those improvements seemed to be in the cities that were getting the upgraded 3D maps, not everywhere (though I’d love for that to not be the case). Either way, Apple obviously knows my trail exists, so it’d be great if it could highlight it in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="yq5TwW"&gt;Satellite view in CarPlay&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="GeqW0N"&gt;This is, again, a small one — Apple talked about Maps helping people navigate better while driving, but for the areas that won’t get 3D mapped anytime soon, actually being able to see a satellite view while driving could help improve their navigation experience. Satellite view may not be for everyone all the time, but if you’re navigating a tricky intersection, or a dense area where landmarks may be key, being able to see a top-down picture instead of just an abstracted map could help you avoid missing a turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ImK6nR"&gt;
&lt;p id="CxcoPJ"&gt;Of course, there are navigation apps available that have these features — I’ve directly compared Apple Maps with Google Maps several times, and Google also makes Waze. However, while Google Maps and Waze do have CarPlay integration, they’re generally not as well-integrated as Apple Maps is (for obvious reasons). There’s also the matter of privacy — some people, myself included, would rather not give Google all the location data that comes with using their mapping service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJbSe5"&gt;Whatever reason people decide to stick with Apple Maps, they deserve to have a useful navigation experience, and it’d be nice to see Apple getting the basics done before adding an (admittedly lovely looking) moonlight aesthetic to Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528793/apple-maps-missing-features-ios-15-aesthetics-functionality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528793/apple-maps-missing-features-ios-15-aesthetics-functionality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T14:34:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T14:34:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>House lawmakers introduce five bipartisan bills to unwind tech monopolies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qFoUOaPpANoVE-soa2qL07Bow5s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69441138/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NMGfr4"&gt;On Friday, House Democrats introduced five new bills meant to chip away at the power of big tech companies, targeting a variety of practices that antitrust advocates say are stifling competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZVRWK"&gt;These measures are the House Judiciary Committee’s historic, 16-month long investigation into the business tactics of companies like Apple, Amazon, Facebook, and Google. With this new slate of bills, Congress is getting ready to legislate based on the concerns raised by that investigation — and the move could reshape the tech industry as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bYQVBr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Right now, unregulated tech monopolies have too much power over our economy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zbQdoB"&gt;“Right now, unregulated tech monopolies have too much power over our economy. They are in a unique position to pick winners and losers, destroy small businesses, raise prices on consumers, and put folks out of work,” Rep. David Cicilline (D-RI) said in a statement Friday. “Our agenda will level the playing field and ensure the wealthiest, most powerful tech monopolies play by the same rules as the rest of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpFpvp"&gt;The package unveiled Friday includes five measures targeting the different ways in which tech companies maintain market dominance. One bill would empower the Justice Department or the Federal Trade Commission to break up tech firms by forcing them to sell off parts of their business that could create a conflict of interest — potentially forcing Amazon to carve off house brands like Amazon Basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tenz8K"&gt;Another bill would bar companies from giving their own services preference over their rivals, like Google boosting its own products in search results over competitors. Yet another bill would block companies like Facebook from buying up nascent competitors like in the 2012 acquisition of Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lNP5ao"&gt;The last two bills are less controversial. Last week, the Senate already passed a measure put out by Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) that would boost merger filing fees for large companies, giving antitrust enforcers more money to take on cases. A bill mirroring that legislation was introduced Wednesday. The last bill would force platforms to make the data they collect interoperable in order to make it easier for users to jump from one service to another. Both Republicans and Democrats seem eager to move forward on data portability legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yNGQif"&gt;The House’s tech investigation was a bipartisan endeavor, and while both parties agree on many of the probe’s findings, they disagree on some of the solutions. The probe culminated into an over 400-page report from Democratic staff detailing its findings. Rep. Ken Buck (CO), the committee’s top Republican, issued his own report focusing on the ways large platforms allegedly censor conservative speech and encouraging other Republicans to support competition reform as a means of addressing the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XaBR2c"&gt;It’s unclear how lawmakers plan to move forward on the legislation, but the multi-pronged approach could make it easier to enact some changes over the coming Term. More measured approaches like Klobuchar’s to boost regulatory funding could find broad support in the House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNhFrU"&gt;At least one Republican and one Democrat signed on to each of Friday’s measures. Still it’s unclear if all members support each bill. On Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/murdoch-pushes-republicans-support-antitrust-bills-471e7868-4dd3-4b3b-a8af-62cf25582fe7.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Axios &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that lobbyists for Rupert Murdoch’s media companies, like Fox Corp. and News Corp., were urging House Republicans to support the measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hk3sNM"&gt;“These companies have maintained monopoly power in the online marketplace by using a variety of anticompetitive behaviors to stifle competition,” Buck said in a statement Friday. “Doing nothing is not an option, we must act now.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529857/democrats-antitrust-big-tech-facebook-amazon-google-apple-competition-package-bills"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529857/democrats-antitrust-big-tech-facebook-amazon-google-apple-competition-package-bills</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple admits why its own Files app was ranked first when users searched for competitor Dropbox</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GS-K3T8YZ5YQPqrOFrucrnVG1Xk=/0x0:1947x1298/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69440655/apple_app_store_wwdc_2021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qdrjqi"&gt;In 2019, facing down extensive investigations &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-dominates-app-store-search-results-thwarting-competitors-11563897221?shareToken=st44e68b42ce5f45f5bd573dae5f8f0f5c"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/09/09/technology/apple-app-store-competition.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that showed Apple’s App Store clearly and consistently ranking its own apps ahead of competitors, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/23/20707323/apple-app-store-apps-favor-own-competitors-search-results-deny"&gt;claimed it had done nothing wrong&lt;/a&gt; — a secret algorithm containing 42 different variables was working as intended, top executives told the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, insisting that Apple doesn’t manually alter search results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0Q5kC"&gt;Why do I bring this up? An intriguing email chain has surfaced during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22454959/epic-apple-trial-recap-video-tim-cook-xbox-playstation-business"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial&lt;/a&gt; where it sure looks like Apple did the exact opposite — seemingly admitting it manually boosted the ranking of its own Files app ahead of the competition for 11 entire months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Z1mj2y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Who green lit putting the Files app above Dropbox in organic search results?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XUC3pE"&gt;“We are removing the manual boost and the search results should be more relevant now,” wrote Apple app search lead Debankur Naskar, after the company was confronted by Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney over Apple’s Files app showing up first when searching for Dropbox. “Dropbox wasn’t even visible on the first page [of search results],” Sweeney wrote. You can read the whole email chain embedded a little ways below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0x5c0n"&gt;As you’ll see, Naskar suggested that Files had been &lt;em&gt;intentionally&lt;/em&gt; boosted for that exact search result during the “last WWDC.” That would have been WWDC 2017, nearly a year earlier, when the Files apps first debuted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUbFBh"&gt;The email chain actually reflects fairly well on Apple overall. Apple’s Matt Fischer (VP of the App Store) clearly objects to the idea at first. “[W]ho green lit putting the Files app above Dropbox in organic search results? I didn’t know we did that, and I don’t think we should,” he says. But he does end the conversation with “In the future, I want any similar requests to come to me for review/approval,” suggesting that he’s not entirely ruling out manual overrides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5WMd4u"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/20805886-epic-v-apple-internal-email-chain-re-tim-sweeney-and-app-store-search/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Epic v. Apple internal email chain re: Tim Sweeney and App Store search (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="990" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b9z2fE"&gt;But Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that what we think we’re seeing in these emails isn’t quite accurate. While Apple didn’t challenge the idea that Files was unfairly ranked over Dropbox, the company says the reality was a simple mistake: the Files app had a Dropbox integration, so Apple put “Dropbox” into the app’s metadata, and it was automatically ranked higher for “Dropbox” searches as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BE236b"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Apple manually boosts its first-party apps in search results? Funny, I feel like somebody testified under oath that that never happens &lt;a href="https://t.co/mTgnw8d8CK"&gt;https://t.co/mTgnw8d8CK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve Troughton-Smith (@stroughtonsmith) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stroughtonsmith/status/1401905981085343749?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CLrqtE"&gt;I’m slightly skeptical of that explanation — partially because it doesn’t line up with what Naskar suggests in the email, partially because Apple &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; told me it immediately fixed the error (despite it apparently continuing to exist for 11 months, hardly immediate), and partially because the company repeatedly ignored my questions about whether this has ever happened with other apps before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJqqIF"&gt;The most Apple would tell me is that it didn’t &lt;em&gt;manually&lt;/em&gt; boost Files over competitors, and that “we do not advantage our apps over those of any developer or competitor” as a general rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="220iuT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Best case, Apple didn’t notice it was giving itself an unfair advantage until another CEO pointed it out&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CbOYWR"&gt;But honestly, it may not matter whether Apple &lt;em&gt;manually&lt;/em&gt; boosted its own apps or not. What matters is the result: for 11 months, Apple’s new Files app owned exact searches for its competitor Dropbox, a company &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/steve-jobs-once-vowed-to-kill-dropbox-now-its-worth-2013-11"&gt;Steve Jobs reportedly swore he would kill off&lt;/a&gt;, and it took the CEO of a prominent Apple partner emailing the company before Apple did something about it. And based on &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s investigation, Apple may not have done much: the Files app still ranked #1 in the App Store for cloud storage in June 2018, a month after this email chain was resolved, according to an infographic that accompanied &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-dominates-app-store-search-results-thwarting-competitors-11563897221?shareToken=st44e68b42ce5f45f5bd573dae5f8f0f5c"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kJYQuX"&gt;Besides, the distinction between a “manual” boost and any other kind of boost may be purely academic. Algorithms are written by people, after all. If Apple can build a 42-factor algorithm that gives its own apps favorable results, why would it need to override that algorithm and risk its emails getting caught up in a lawsuit years from now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pqVtQu"&gt;It could just tweak that algorithm at will — which is exactly what it did to resolve the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; NYT&lt;/em&gt;’s scrutiny two years ago. It only took a single engineer to change the algorithm in July 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/09/09/technology/apple-app-store-competition.html"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Apple’s own apps immediately fell in App Store rankings. But that time, executives said the previous formula wasn’t a mistake. Apple simply wanted to make it look less like its own apps were getting special treatment. So it “improved” the algorithm to achieve the new result it wanted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHf6Te"&gt;Apple provided this statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Vr2d2K"&gt;We created the App Store to be a safe and trusted place for customers to discover and download apps, and a great business opportunity for all developers. App Store Search has only one goal — to get customers what they are looking for. We do that in a way that is fair to all developers and we do not advantage our apps over those of any developer or competitor. Today, developers have many options for distributing their apps and that’s why we work hard to make it easy, fair and a great opportunity for them to develop apps for our customers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;aside id="KvTb1f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple went into WWDC 2021 under more scrutiny than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/6/22520378/apple-wwdc-2021-developer-insult-macbook-pro"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="aNmgly"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Epic v. Apple trial was much bigger than Fortnite|102313" data-volume-uuid="2e5d0ec67" data-volume-id="102313" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-488" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528701/apple-rank-own-app-over-competitor-files-dropbox-wwdc-2017"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528701/apple-rank-own-app-over-competitor-files-dropbox-wwdc-2017</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T12:01:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T12:01:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is trying to dominate watch parties, but it needs more help</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ft-o9a0LPyS-oG4BM2_sWZNV3ZQ=/0x59:941x686/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69440167/download.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePlay displayed on an iPhone.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3QfG3e"&gt;Apple is bringing one of streaming’s trendiest features to iPhone users with the debut of SharePlay in iOS 15 later this year, allowing FaceTime users to stream music, online videos, and movies together with friends. The move positions FaceTime to compete more directly with platforms like Facebook Messenger, Instagram, and Houseparty, which all offer ways to video chat while watching things as a group.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It offers Apple a chance to hook a new generation of users on FaceTime — but the service is still missing some key integrations to make that happen, particularly for the teens most likely to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AR91ld"&gt;SharePlay, announced earlier this week and likely arriving in the fall, will allow FaceTime users to share and stream media in real time from an iPhone, iPad, Mac, or Apple TV. It’s a neat tool for the pandemic era, and it takes inspiration from the watch party modes that &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/hidden-code-on-the-disney-site-suggests-a-watch-party-1844906374"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21307519/amazon-watch-party-prime-video-virtual-parties-streaming-netflix-disney-hbo-scener-twitch"&gt;major&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22092452/hulu-watch-party-now-available-all-subscribers"&gt;streaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452744/sling-tv-watch-party-live-tv-beta-chrome-available-now"&gt;platforms&lt;/a&gt; — including Disney Plus, Hulu, and Prime Video, among others — added themselves in the last year. For services where it’s not supported, like Netflix, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21307583/watch-videos-movies-online-friends-streaming-netflix-hulu-amazon-scener-extensions"&gt;there are popular extensions&lt;/a&gt; that enable simultaneous streaming and chatting as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1WHxU0"&gt;The goal isn’t to compete with those native platforms, though. After all, you’re still watching Hulu, just in a different space. Instead, the update puts FaceTime square against services like Facebook Messenger that dominate messaging and have already been trying to build out co-watching experiences, but without as robust of a service list as Apple has the ability to line up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3uFYit"&gt;&lt;q&gt;SharePlay makes sense for teen streamers, but the feature needs wider app support if it’s going to work&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HvQexT"&gt;SharePlay particularly makes sense for the next generation of iPhone users, as teens are more &lt;a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/young-americans-watching-online-videos-spike-to-the-highest-rate-ever-2019-10-29"&gt;inclined to watch videos&lt;/a&gt; on their phones. Video-based social media apps like Instagram and TikTok are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/31/17382058/youtube-teens-preferred-platform"&gt;immensely popular&lt;/a&gt; among teens, and an &lt;a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/sites/default/files/uploads/research/2019-census-8-to-18-key-findings-updated.pdf"&gt;overwhelming majority&lt;/a&gt; of teens have access to these apps on their own personal smartphones. Video chatting is hugely popular, too, with a &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2015/08/06/teens-technology-and-friendships/"&gt;2015 survey&lt;/a&gt; from Pew Research finding that 59 percent of US teens video chatted with their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DrWEL"&gt;The introduction of SharePlay also jibes with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-22/apple-plans-notifications-ipad-home-screen-upgrades-for-ios-15?sref=i3mD6rA5"&gt;reported plans&lt;/a&gt; to make iMessage compete more directly with Facebook-owned WhatsApp by becoming more of a social network. It makes a lot of sense that the company would similarly invest in developments for its video-calling product as well, which is just a couple of taps away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KCdLPN"&gt;But if Apple wants SharePlay to be a success among the demographic of consumers most likely to use it, it’ll need to expand the number of apps that support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jDU2mj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Fewer than a dozen services were included on Apple’s SharePlay slide at WWDC&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fnpZzZ"&gt;Apple said that at launch, Disney Plus, ESPN Plus, HBO Max, Hulu, MasterClass, Paramount Plus, Pluto TV, TikTok, and Twitch will be supported on SharePlay, which is a somewhat limited grab bag of streaming options. Granted, there’s plenty of time for that list to get longer before iOS 15 officially rolls out to users in the fall. And Apple told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that SharePlay will be available to any streaming app that wants to support it, so we’re likely to see wider adoption down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2z7kOl"&gt;Some of the best applications of this feature failed to make their way into Apple’s initial slide of supported services, though. Netflix is perhaps the most obvious of these simply on the basis that virtually everyone has a Netflix login, whether they’re actually paying for it or not (at least until the inevitable &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-netflix-password-sharing-crackdown-has-begun-1846460641"&gt;password crackdown&lt;/a&gt;). But YouTube was not mentioned either, and neither company had comment to share about potential support down the line when contacted by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; this week. A spokesperson for Peacock, however, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that SharePlay support was on its “roadmap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U7TPW8"&gt;YouTube, in particular, seems like a huge miss for Apple, especially &lt;a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/young-americans-watching-online-videos-spike-to-the-highest-rate-ever-2019-10-29"&gt;where teens are concerned&lt;/a&gt;. YouTube hosts just about every digital media format imaginable — music, movies, news, personalities, tutorials, live feeds, etc. — but most importantly, it’s free. As video callers &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2010/10/13/video-calling-and-video-chat/"&gt;tend to skew younger&lt;/a&gt; already, apps with highly shareable content like livestreams seem like the best use case for SharePlay outside of live sporting events. That’s particularly true given that for paid services, each participant in a SharePlay streaming session will need a login for the app. After all, if the tool didn’t require credentials and allowed just anyone to drop in a FaceTime stream of content from a paid service, SharePlay would be a piracy nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="M0YGcs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Are users prepared to pay up just to stream a title with friends?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XiHmsQ"&gt;But that’s part of what makes the practical application of SharePlay a bit of a puzzler. Streaming the game or a movie premiere could get expensive fast. If your friends are watching NFL coverage on Sling TV, you’ll need a $35 subscription to join in (assuming the content is included in one of the service’s base plans). If you wanted to watch a Premier Access release like &lt;em&gt;Cruella&lt;/em&gt; on Disney Plus, you’d need to pay the $8 monthly subscription cost &lt;em&gt;on top of&lt;/em&gt; an additional $30 early access ticket fee. (A spokesperson for Disney Plus confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that SharePlay users still need to pay for access to watch.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GfmiOk"&gt;It’s hard to imagine that most users would pay for a service just to be able to FaceTime while they’re watching a title. Then again, based on recent media consumption trends among teens, maybe SharePlay is part of the future of how entertainment is consumed, at least for the younger subset of Apple users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kWNNec"&gt;It makes sense that a company investing heavily in its services offerings would jump on the watch party trend, if not a little late, and it does feel like a natural way for Apple to not only stay relevant but also sell subscriptions and hardware — even if right now, SharePlay alone seems unlikely to balloon numbers for streaming services. Free, social-leaning services and streaming titans are most likely to see success with this feature, and livestreaming apps seem likely to perform best. But they’ll actually have to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; SharePlay for that to work. As it currently stands, many are not.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T10:43:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T10:43:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast WWDC: iOS 15, spatial audio, macOS Monterey, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0CZPPYcGGb8SnSoYqpY7tlH26Co=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69439620/lcimg_71a6f738_86b9_4aed_a194_067e8224a6d4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PxqLol"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wzToI2"&gt;This week, Nilay and Dieter bring in &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editors Alex Cranz and Chris Welch to discuss all of the announcements from Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference that took place this week — from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22456874/apple-ios-15-features-notifications-facetime-wwdc-2021"&gt;a preview of iOS 15&lt;/a&gt; to the introduction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;spatial audio on Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; to a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523322/apple-wwdc-impressive-drag-and-drop-universal-control-demo"&gt;drag-and-drop feature between the Mac and the iPad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Yxsjjc"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP9710704064&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MJc8SN"&gt;You can listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjaRLZ"&gt;Links from this week’s episode: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0ukoJi"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22518570/covid-hospitalization-icu-teenagers-vaccines-cdc"&gt;COVID-19 hospitalization rates in adolescents went up during March and April&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UTASnM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22516823/covid-vaccine-microchip-conspiracy-theory-explained-reddit"&gt;Where did the COVID microchip conspiracy theory come from anyway?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KYVnk7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525027/pandemic-e-waste-digital-divide"&gt;The pandemic might cut down e-waste but widen the digital divide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lqW9KW"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;Apple WWDC 2021: the 15 biggest announcements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kAeZ1m"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22456874/apple-ios-15-features-notifications-facetime-wwdc-2021"&gt;Apple previews iOS 15 at WWDC 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qGG6pG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22526451/iphone-ipad-mac-apple-watch-wwdc-best-features-ios-monterey"&gt;The best features of iOS, iPadOS, and macOS that Apple didn’t announce onstage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cMNZ91"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc"&gt;Apple’s Siri will finally work without an internet connection with on-device speech recognition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LWW3oX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523438/apple-iphone-siri-on-device-processing-ios-15-wwdc-privacy"&gt;Watch Apple’s Siri blaze through requests with on-device processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LK8Gd7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;You’ll soon be able to use your iPhone as ID at the airport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="97aJEZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22502877/apple-app-privacy-report-ip-hiding-safari-mail-wwdc"&gt;Apple adds welcome privacy features to Mail, Safari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MWEL84"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc"&gt;Apple’s iCloud Plus bundles a VPN, private email, and HomeKit camera storage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PBc36n"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22526881/apple-icloud-plus-privacy-subscription-services-revenue-wwdc-2021"&gt;With iCloud Plus, Apple’s privacy promise is paired with an upsell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2zZCvb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523871/china-private-relay-regulatory-reasons-not-launching-great-firewall-internet-censorship"&gt;Apple’s privacy-focused Private Relay feature isn’t coming to China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hjeoJ3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;Apple Music’s spatial audio is sometimes amazing but mostly inconsistent &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RDlrRk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523914/macos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max"&gt;macOS and tvOS are getting spatial audio support with the AirPods Pro and Max&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QvXxWu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;Apple Music begins rolling out lossless streaming and Dolby Atmos spatial audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2Gengp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;Apple introduces Siri for third-party devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="THi3U9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;macOS Monterey lets you run Shortcuts and share files between Macs and iPads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FMWudE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523322/apple-wwdc-impressive-drag-and-drop-universal-control-demo"&gt;Apple may have done the coolest drag and drop demo ever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YOIYwo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;How Universal Control on macOS Monterey works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4Q0t4x"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522889/apple-facetime-android-windows-web-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;FaceTime is coming to Android and Windows via the web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C0TkMI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522904/apple-shareplay-facetime-music-hulu-videos-tiktok-wwdc"&gt;Apple is building video and music sharing into FaceTime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ARm8ZT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;Apple announces watchOS 8 with new health features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wcwdat"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527707/apple-health-data-eldery-falls-walking-privacy"&gt;Apple’s new health features bring new focus to elder care technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n86XtV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522872/health-app-family-mobility-fall-risk-wwdc-2021"&gt;Apple lets users see family members’ Health data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f79UYc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463812/apple-ipados-15-features-productivity-release-date"&gt;Apple announces iPadOS 15 with homescreen and multitasking improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BSfYrs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527420/microsoft-xbox-tv-app-streaming-stick-xcloud"&gt;Microsoft announces Xbox TV app and its own xCloud streaming stick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IKU3jZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526266/facebook-smartwatch-two-cameras-heart-rate-monitor"&gt;Facebook plans first smartwatch for next summer with two cameras, heart rate monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JjRtNX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM4 earbuds announced / review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="a8UNTd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"&gt;Google’s first folding Pixel is apparently still on track for a 2021 reveal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wUB1sP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22519705/clubhouse-social-audio-accessibility"&gt;Clubhouse and its clones have an accessibility problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wW5vGA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525953/biden-tiktok-wechat-trump-bans-revoked-alipay"&gt;Biden revokes Trump bans on TikTok and WeChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="eEx3sc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529488/vergecast-podcast-454-wwdc-2021-ios15-macos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529488/vergecast-podcast-454-wwdc-2021-ios15-macos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T10:16:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T10:16:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple finally supports Windows Precision Touchpad gestures in new Boot Camp update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gO-zeq-e1F3DMbq3XMdaOqXkZJU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69439491/vpavic_191118_3800_0122.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verg&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wOOYiW"&gt;Apple is finally adding support for Windows Precision Touchpad drivers in its latest Boot Camp update. The new 6.1.15 update includes support for Windows Precision Touchpad, including single tap to click, lower-right corner to right-click, down motion to scroll up, and three or four finger gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fo8U2R"&gt;Various &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MacOS/comments/nx558h/apple_finally_adds_support_for_windows_precision/"&gt;Reddit users noticed&lt;/a&gt; the surprise update went live yesterday, and it apparently works better than third-party solutions like Trackpad++ and mac-precision-touchpad that people have had to use for years. “Works way better than both of them with better palm and thumb detection too,” &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bootcamp/comments/nwva18/boot_camp_6115_released_adds_support_for_windows/"&gt;says one Reddit user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3nRyEZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft started supporting Precision Touchpads more than seven years ago&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YbbGDR"&gt;Microsoft first started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/7/3/4489692/windows-8-1-precision-touchpad-support-intel-synaptics"&gt;introducing Windows Precision Touchpad&lt;/a&gt; with Intel in 2013, in an effort to fix what were notorious PC trackpad issues at the time. It has taken Apple a long time to enable Windows Precision Touchpad in Boot Camp, but not every MacBook is supported. An &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/bootcamp-control-panel/bcmpa82153f3/mac"&gt;Apple support document&lt;/a&gt; notes that only Mac computers with a T2 chip will be able to access Windows Precision Touchpad, which is most MacBook Air and MacBook Pro models from 2018 onward (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208862"&gt;full list here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eeo71j"&gt;The timing of such a significant update to Boot Camp is also surprising and could hint that Intel-based Macs will coexist with Apple’s M1-based Macs for a while yet. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21559003/apple-mac-macbook-air-pro-mini-m1-intel-processor-cpu"&gt;discontinued Intel-based MacBook Airs&lt;/a&gt; last year, but you can still buy a 13-inch MacBook Pro with an Intel CPU for now. Apple has said that its “transition to Apple silicon will take about two years to complete.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529493/apple-windows-precision-touchpad-support-boot-camp-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529493/apple-windows-precision-touchpad-support-boot-camp-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T08:03:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T08:03:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to stop your emails from being tracked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of a letter envelope with a target over it with pixels floating around both." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Pi8r0uc4i8-kswTyRNU-H0pTaQ=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841883/VRG_4614_3_EmailTracking.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Maria Chimishkyan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wmDbQw"&gt;All of those obnoxious marketing emails that crowd your inbox aren’t just pushing a product. They’re also tracking whether you’ve opened the email, when you opened it, and where you were at the time by using software like Mailchimp to embed tracking software into the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1f75NZ"&gt;How does it work? A single tracking pixel is embedded in the email, usually (but not always) hidden within an image or a link. When the email is opened, code within the pixel sends the info back to the company’s server. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYBZIp"&gt;There have been some attempts to restrict the amount of information that can be transmitted this way. For example, since 2014, &lt;a href="https://gmail.googleblog.com/2013/12/images-now-showing.html"&gt;Google has served all images in Gmail through its own proxy servers&lt;/a&gt;, which could hide your location from at least some tracking applications. And extensions such as &lt;a href="https://uglyemail.com/"&gt;Ugly Email&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/pixelblock/jmpmfcjnflbcoidlgapblgpgbilinlem"&gt;PixelBlock&lt;/a&gt; have been developed to block trackers on Chrome and Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6EFgJ"&gt;There is also a simple, basic step you can take to avoid trackers: stop your email from automatically loading images, since images are where the majority of these pixels hide. You won’t be able to avoid all of the trackers that can hide in your email this way, but you will stop many of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qjXsAd"&gt;Here’s how to disable image autoloading in the major desktop and mobile email apps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="91Fgwl"&gt;Gmail on the web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="zbqpz9"&gt;Click on the gear icon in the upper-right corner to access your settings, and then click on “See all settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZEfys0"&gt;In the “General” tab (the first one), scroll down to “Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z0QTtq"&gt;Select “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VeQHzw"&gt;Scroll down to the bottom of the page and click on “Save Changes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="yRek5v"&gt;Note that this will also turn off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282636/amp-gmail-shopping-rsvp-forms-inbox-google-beta"&gt;Gmail’s dynamic email feature&lt;/a&gt;, which makes emails more interactive. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In the “General” tab, scroll down to “Images” and select “Ask before displaying external images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OyvGIew6m_cCzL7vC_d31z8230c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544004/gmail_pixel.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the “General” tab, scroll down to “Images” and select “Ask before displaying external images.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="XrhZKY"&gt;Microsoft Outlook.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xDoAal"&gt;While the browser-based version of Outlook doesn’t let you stop loading images, you can make it load images through its own service. To enable that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="CurYRn"&gt;Click on “Settings” (the gear symbol in the upper-right corner). In the column that opens, click on “View all Outlook settings” at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="exNksS"&gt;Select “General” &amp;gt; “Privacy and data.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oQoFLs"&gt;Scroll down to “External images” and select “Always use the Outlook service to load images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Outlook.com can route incoming images through its own service." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1JWz2g79d9AWZqgrg2XZ_vorNPs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544343/outlook_online__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outlook.com can route incoming images through its own service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GlQKBG"&gt;Microsoft Outlook (Office 365) for Windows 10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MIRvx9"&gt;Click on “File” &amp;gt; “Options.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="132JwF"&gt;In the “Outlook Options” window, select “Trust Center.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bgp9g6"&gt;Click on the “Trust Center Settings” button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8dvLox"&gt;Check the boxes labeled “Don’t download pictures automatically in standard HTML email messages or RSS items” and “Don’t download pictures in encrypted or signed HTML email messages.” You can make a number of exceptions to the first item, if you like, by reviewing the boxes underneath it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="To stop automatic downloads, go to the Trust Center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qvp5woUtECVNQ68MfnG_uWpguBk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545835/outlook_screenshot.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To stop automatic downloads, go to the Trust Center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uyuAUz"&gt;Microsoft Outlook (Office 365) for Mac&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="qY4VZ5"&gt;Go to “File” &amp;gt; “Preferences” &amp;gt; “Reading.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HromHN"&gt;You can choose to automatically download images only from trusted contacts, or to disable all automatic downloads of images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Outlook for Mac lets you download images only from contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UXcH8c61nuzOq35QLJTruuaS1ZE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545842/Screen_Shot_2021_05_28_at_10.05.20_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outlook for Mac lets you download images only from contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sN1ICl"&gt;Apple Mail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0n9f5S"&gt;Select “Mail” &amp;gt; “Preferences.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A7ND3F"&gt;Click on the “Viewing” tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qwEieV"&gt;Uncheck “Load remote content in messages.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Uncheck “Load remote content in messages.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w8iZs_L67HcxBv-XkTah4VGz1-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544037/Screen_Shot_2021_05_27_at_2.46.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncheck “Load remote content in messages.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HHDXvZ"&gt;Gmail for Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c5Wulc"&gt;Tap on the three lines in the upper-left corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R8HSTQ"&gt;Scroll down and select “Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KjX4Gw"&gt;Tap on the email account that you want to configure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="g1X0ro"&gt;Scroll down and select “Images.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEYbil"&gt;Tap on “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In “Settings,” scroll down to “Images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0WEEv9FyZisUtRpDpCK4ZFZ-3Xo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278832/Gmail_a__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In “Settings,” scroll down to “Images.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select “Ask before displaying external images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/06eh5BFw2-SD1ADEUfbDwc4ZXTo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544057/android_Gmail_Screenshot__May_27__2021_2_51_33_PM_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xbW3d5"&gt;Gmail for iOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="eUXclZ"&gt;Open Gmail for iOS, tap the hamburger menu in the upper left, and scroll down to settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dr88Ar"&gt;Tap the account you want to personalize, and tap “Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xTabJG"&gt;Switch from “Always display external images” to “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In your account, tap “Images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NoSwN4PaB3rHfdDHEZ94onCa8uE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544385/IMG_F54686DE212E_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In your account, tap “Images.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select “Ask before displaying external images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p5JdNp-OTCbJbe7CNdrTkklhTpo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544386/IMG_EE6AC65258B6_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="M1JF9m"&gt;Apple Mail for iOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MIPm7O"&gt;Tap on “Settings” &amp;gt; “Mail.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8CgUR7"&gt;Find the “Messages” section and toggle off “Load Remote Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Start by selecting “Settings” &amp;amp;gt; “Mail.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nCVf2wg4XieCCRYZ3mHYj7lymP4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544095/IMG_F6FA2F780CC2_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start by selecting “Settings” &amp;gt; “Mail.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Toggle off “Load Remote Images.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L-e7kXyI_qlSc-mqsYEjVvbURAc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22544124/IMG_5112D83D9012_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toggle off “Load Remote Images.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w1Qtvj"&gt;Another option is to use an email client such as &lt;a href="https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/"&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;, which blocks remote images by default; the application allows you to download embedded content on an individual basis, or to allow pictures from contacts that you trust not to send hidden code in their images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06msoO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 3rd, 2019, 3:47PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include additional information about email clients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbvWNJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 3rd, 2019, 7:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include directions for disabling image autoloading on Gmail for iOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7Bwbn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 17th, 2021, 5:30PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions for Microsoft Mail have been removed, and a few instructions have been updated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mGMbOs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 11th, 2021, 8:00AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions for Outlook.com and Outlook for Mac have been added, and a few other instructions have been updated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22288190/email-pixel-trackers-how-to-stop-images-automatic-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22288190/email-pixel-trackers-how-to-stop-images-automatic-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
