<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-03T15:50:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-03T15:50:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-03T15:50:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reports partial outages for services including iCloud Drive, Photos, Mail, and Notes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UI_BhByGhZJZWtRd84v-Oyf-81w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68764875/vpavic_042020_3980_0037.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZriXvd"&gt;A number of Apple’s cloud services are currently dealing with disruptions and partial outages, according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fsupport%2Fsystemstatus%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F3%2F22264919%2Fapple-icloud-cloud-service-outage-photos-contacts-notes#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company’s system dashboard&lt;/a&gt;. Photos, iCloud Drive, iCloud Mail, Notes, Contacts, Find My, and iCloud Backups are a few of the services that have been hit by the problems, which Apple’s site reflected as of 1:13PM ET (10:13AM PT) with a message acknowledging that “users may be unable to use this service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CecJHW"&gt;The issues don’t seem to be universal or particularly widespread, as iCloud syncing continues to work normally for several editorial employees at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. My own iCloud Drive remains accessible at the moment, but I can see how this is frustrating for those dealing with the downtime. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fY7fZ-k7B5k4JX5efIElEoGonkQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22279320/Screen_Shot_2021_02_03_at_3.31.24_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hWUHHg"&gt;Apple Music, the App Store, Mac App Store, Apple Books, and iTunes dealt with “slow or unavailable” outages earlier on Wednesday, but those have since been resolved. Hopefully it won’t be much longer before the rest of these partial outages are fully ironed out. This article will be updated once that happens. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22264919/apple-icloud-cloud-service-outage-photos-contacts-notes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22264919/apple-icloud-cloud-service-outage-photos-contacts-notes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T19:03:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T19:03:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s next macOS Big Sur update should make iPad apps look less awkward on the Mac</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eiVcuQ_-cPPj7W5HLErWfl5YFQE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68760005/akramer_201113_4290_0023.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alexander Kramer for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CEfu9W"&gt;Apple just yesterday released its latest update for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"&gt;macOS Big Sur&lt;/a&gt; with improved Bluetooth reliability and a handful of bug fixes. And today, it’s rolling out the first beta of macOS Big Sur 11.3, which will bring further refinements to Safari, Reminders, Apple Music, Apple News, and other apps. This update will also try to improve the experience of running iPhone and iPad apps on M1 Macs, which can still be a little awkward at this early stage (and without a touchscreen display). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WxHDgd"&gt;iPadOS apps will now appear larger than before — if your screen size allows for it — and beta testers will find a new preference pane for iPhone and iPad apps that’ll let them better personalize the “touch alternatives” keyboard commands. Touch alternatives allow for “keyboard alternatives for tap, swipe, and drag gestures, and enables multi-finger gestures using the option key and a trackpad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="c8j3Kj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"macOS 11 Big Sur review: a long time coming","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="TPnC0Y"&gt;Big Sur 11.3 will make Safari’s start page more customizable, letting you rearrange the different sections (favorites, Reading List, Siri suggestions, etc.) to your own liking. Developers will gain the ability to make extensions that run on the new tab page, and they can also take advantage of a new web speech API to integrate speech recognition on their web pages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ASHWiF"&gt;As for the Reminders app, you’ll be able to sort your reminders based on title, due date, priority, or creation date. And with this update, Apple will let you easily &lt;em&gt;print&lt;/em&gt; your reminders if a paper copy might prove helpful when running to the store or completing other tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b3YSYK"&gt;Apple Music gets small tweaks like a shortcut to your “Made for You” personalized playlists and mixes. Live and upcoming special events will be highlighted in the For You tab, as well. The Apple News app is undergoing some design improvements in the Apple News Plus tab to make your magazines and newspapers easier to reach (and download). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMd199"&gt;And like the upcoming iOS 14.5 update, macOS Big Sur 11.3 adds support for the latest Xbox and PlayStation DualSense controllers; the same compatibility is coming to Apple’s mobile devices &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260671/ios-14-5-ps5-dualsense-xbox-series-x-controller-support"&gt;as part of iOS 14.5&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263208/apple-macos-big-sur-11-3-features-ipad-apps-safari-xbox-ps5-controller"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263208/apple-macos-big-sur-11-3-features-ipad-apps-safari-xbox-ps5-controller</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T18:42:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T18:42:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>The iCloud for Windows version that let you sync Apple passwords is no longer available</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENAPCS-OGtplT01iFYBniRzXrSI=/0x191:1646x1288/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759891/Screen_Shot_2021_02_02_at_2.06.23_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aRJcj0"&gt;Apple’s rocky rollout of iCloud password sync on Windows has hit another bump: you can no longer download the version of the app that allowed syncing passwords from your Apple devices with your Chrome web browser on a Windows PC (&lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/apple-pulls-update-supports-icloud-keychain-windows-10?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wmexperts+%28Windows+Central%29"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Windows Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Version 12 of Apple’s iCloud for Windows app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252825/apple-icloud-keychain-windows-google-chrome"&gt;released last week with supposed support for the feature&lt;/a&gt;, but the Chrome extension to make it work &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22259720/apple-icloud-passwords-chrome-browser-extension-released"&gt;wasn’t available until two days ago&lt;/a&gt;. Now, version 12 is gone from the Windows Store, with version 11.6 taking its place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8zfrDY"&gt;Weirdly, the changelog on the Windows Store still says that the password syncing functionality is present. However, upon downloading, the app shows the version as 11.6 in the top right. We verified this for ourselves, and you can see there’s no password sync option in our first screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C7oNrUboWdOSOEC6x_1IIm2O0NM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22277292/icloud_11_6_windows_store.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The version of the app we downloaded today, 11.6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Image of the iCloud for Windows screen, with the new Passwords option" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r_KytxKImNL0D4_h7hiRU8q4Gms=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22263753/IMAGE_2021_01_27_11_57_45.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 12 of the app with the passwords option, downloaded January 27.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YwPEQX"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://the8-bit.com/apple-pulls-icloud-12-icloud-passwords-update/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 8-Bit&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, the late-to-the-party Chrome Extension is still available on the Chrome Web Store, at least for now. Anyone still on version 11 of the iCloud for Windows app, though, won’t be able to upgrade and take advantage of the extension anyhow. But if you currently have version 12 on your computer, Windows won’t make you downgrade to the previous version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rpQ4mX"&gt;It’s unclear why Apple pulled the update — the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/icloud-passwords/pejdijmoenmkgeppbflobdenhhabjlaj/"&gt;reviews for the Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; aren’t good, but many of them are users reporting that it doesn’t work on Mac, which it’s not designed for. Whatever the reason, this has been one of the messier rollouts I’ve seen from Apple in recent memory. The story, it seems, is the same as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252825/apple-icloud-keychain-windows-google-chrome"&gt;the last time I wrote about iCloud Passwords for Windows&lt;/a&gt;: if you want them, you’ll have to wait a bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="38qlEt"&gt;Apple was didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263118/apple-icloud-windows-password-sync-version-removed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263118/apple-icloud-windows-password-sync-version-removed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T10:37:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T10:37:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Eero’s Wi-Fi 6 mesh router bundle is back down to its Black Friday price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mx-AgO4e23KUuYC6t-T4AOirH4E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68756937/dseifert_191008_3720_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8OCEr0"&gt;Black Friday 2020 saw many great deals, especially on Eero’s products. If you are looking to improve your Wi-Fi situation at home, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-eero-6-3-pack/dp/B085WSCTS4?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=be0daa10b51fb94192247b0f9b3fa744&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725880696356465941" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; have the Eero 6 mesh router three-pack (which includes one mesh router and two extenders) back down to its Black Friday price of $223, a nice drop from its usual cost of $279. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UkQbdA"&gt;When planning your setup, keep in mind that while the Eero 6 mesh router includes two Ethernet ports, the two Eero 6 extenders that come in this bundle do not include any. Alternatively, you can buy two &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Eero-6-Router/dp/B085VM9ZDD?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=0f0775c8ab5999fe980102572df0f698&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Eero 6 routers&lt;/a&gt; for $206 if you want to wire Ethernet to your routers across different areas in your home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DkfRt8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603441"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iuOujEBTCKPDAX4-WnMr2Tj6_NA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22275631/EtKk3nsUcAAJzen.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: PlayStation&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PS5 owners can play &lt;/em&gt;God of War&lt;em&gt; on PS5 if they own a digital or physical copy or through the PlayStation Plus Collection (subscription required).&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FjDmvd"&gt;Eneba is offering an incredible deal to US &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers who own a PS4 or PS5 gaming console. You can grab a &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergePlayStationDeal020121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one-year subscription to the gaming service for only $28&lt;/a&gt; by entering the code &lt;strong&gt;VERGE28&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="92tR4M"&gt;February is a great month to have an active PS Plus subscription because, starting today, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252475/control-free-date-ps-plus-playstation-ps5-ultimate-edition"&gt;grab &lt;em&gt;Control Ultimate Edition&lt;/em&gt; for free&lt;/a&gt;. And if you own a PS5, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260829/god-of-war-2018-ps5-patch-free-update-playstation"&gt;a new patch for &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; arrives today&lt;/a&gt;, allowing you to run the game at 60fps on Sony’s next-gen console. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8ICsM8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qVsgvK"&gt;Super Bowl Sunday is this weekend, and so it’s a great time of the year to buy a new television without burning a significant hole in your wallet. Over at Best Buy, you can grab a 75-inch &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1728939351250604130" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hisense 4K TV (model H6510) for only $630&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="w26nPO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10265690"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sVnoE4"&gt;Discovery Plus, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22018581/discovery-streaming-service-launch-date-price-shark-week-hgtv-food-network"&gt;new streaming service from Discovery&lt;/a&gt;, launched last month. If you were interested in getting a subscription or gifting one to someone else, both the six-month and one-year subscriptions are discounted for a limited time. You can get six months for $29 or one-year of Discovery Plus for $59. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7O0gHR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10314208"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bjmGjq"&gt;If you are looking for a pair of on-ear noise-canceling headphones, the Beats Solo Pro are a good set to consider. Right now, you can get these headphones for only &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731166287030229399" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$151 at Best Buy if you buy them in navy blue&lt;/a&gt;. Normally, these headphones cost $300. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6srJLr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="C0YcTI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262079/eeros-wifi-6-mesh-router-extenders-ps-plus-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262079/eeros-wifi-6-mesh-router-extenders-ps-plus-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T04:01:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T04:01:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Kuo adds fuel to Apple-Hyundai electric car rumors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yXrYCDYdYJOibfhFi9yCpFUPQtQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68755612/akrales_180329_2351_1027.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eC4sUl"&gt;TF Securities analyst Ming-chi Kuo has corroborated reports that Apple and Hyundai are working together on an electric car. In a research note quoted &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/02/02/kuo-apple-car-to-use-hyundais-e-gmp-platform-gm-and-psa-eye-partnerships"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;AppleInsider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Kuo says that Apple’s first car will be based on Hyundai’s E-GMP platform for battery-powered electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e1KbDg"&gt;The E-GMP platform was &lt;a href="https://www.hyundai.com/worldwide/en/company/newsroom/-0000016584"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; late last year and is expected to be the basis for Hyundai’s electric cars from this year on. Hyundai claims that E-GMP vehicles can theoretically get over 500km (310 miles) in range on a full charge, with the battery able to reach 80 percent capacity in 18 minutes via fast charging — though individual vehicle performance would of course vary based on design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDVpEd"&gt;Kuo claims that the first Apple car will be produced together with Hyundai, but other vehicles involving collaboration with GM and PSA are also a possibility, and Apple will have to make use of automotive partners’ supply chain resources. Hyundai is said to be “taking the lead in component design and production” on the first car, while its smaller subsidiary Kia will be responsible for producing vehicles in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lc0qo3CAP7zdx8V8Gdw61rQRvIU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22275313/csm_hyundai_ev_platform_e_gmp_01_e2e_0eaf8b99a1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyundai’s E-GMP electric vehicle platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fGsiK8"&gt;Last month Hyundai confirmed local reports that it was in talks with Apple before &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-08/hyundai-shares-jump-most-since-1988-after-report-on-apple-tie-up"&gt;walking back its statement&lt;/a&gt;. “We’ve been receiving requests for potential cooperation from various companies regarding development of autonomous EVs,” read the statement’s final version. “No decisions have been made as discussions are in early stage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzLZkb"&gt;Reuters &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-tech-apple-hyundai-motor-focus/hyundai-wrestles-with-the-risks-of-embracing-apple-idUSKBN29Y0FU"&gt;recently reported&lt;/a&gt; that Hyundai leadership was “divided” on the prospect of an Apple partnership. “We are agonizing over how to do it, whether it is good to do it or not,” an unnamed executive was quoted as saying. “We are not a company which manufactures cars for others. It is not like working with Apple would always produce great results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZmWCNm"&gt;Kuo believes that the earliest possible date for an Apple car to hit the market is 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261893/apple-electric-car-hyundai-ming-chi-kuo-rumor-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261893/apple-electric-car-hyundai-ming-chi-kuo-rumor-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-01T14:37:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T14:37:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Fitness Plus will soon let you cast workouts to a smart TV using AirPlay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SDpy89xOjXeCMZCaS-pAHgnAd_Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68752687/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6UNsj9"&gt;Apple’s latest watchOS 7 and iOS 14 beta releases indicate a new casting feature for Apple Fitness Plus subscribers is on the way, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/apple-fitness-is-adding-airplay-casting/?tpcc=ECTW2020"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zPUfEv"&gt;The upcoming software updates will allow AirPlay casting of Fitness Plus workouts to compatible smart TVs, which include any with AirPlay 2 compatibility. That’s good news for Fitness Plus users who may not own an Apple TV, which was previously the only way to get an audio or video workout playing on a bigger screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fgoL0T"&gt;Fitness Plus was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21437578/apple-fitness-plus-classes-subscription-health"&gt;announced in September of last year&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174574/apple-fitness-plus-watch-iphone-release-date-price"&gt;launched in December&lt;/a&gt;, and the paid service costs $9.99 per month or $79.99 per year for access to guided workouts. The service requires at minimum an Apple Watch Series 3 and a paired iPhone 6S or newer, both running the most up-to-date iOS 14 software releases. At launch, the only way to stream a workout from your TV was to have an Apple TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHovFh"&gt;Now, with the watchOS and iOS releases on the horizon, Fitness Plus users need only an Airplay 2-compatible set. Here’s a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fios%2Fhome%2Faccessories%2F%23section-tv&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F1%2F22260722%2Fapple-fitness-plus-airplay-workouts-tv-new-feature-ios-14-5#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;full list of available TVs that meet the requirements&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260722/apple-fitness-plus-airplay-workouts-tv-new-feature-ios-14-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260722/apple-fitness-plus-airplay-workouts-tv-new-feature-ios-14-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-01T13:47:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T13:47:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 14.5 will support PS5 DualSense and Xbox Series X controllers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QrD1EwouzyAN9nxf6IRc-Owc1sc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68752376/vpavic_4278_20201030_0234.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BDAf6V"&gt;Apple is releasing its iOS 14.5 update to beta testers today, and one of the welcome changes is support for the new PS5 DualSense and Xbox Series X controllers. Neither of these new controllers is currently supported in the latest versions of iOS and iPadOS, but 14.5 introduces support for both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xGnCAI"&gt;Apple’s upcoming iOS 14.5 update follows the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21580245/microsoft-apple-xbox-series-x-controller-support-iphone-ipad-ios-ipados"&gt;revealing back in November&lt;/a&gt; that it was working with Microsoft to include support for the Xbox Series X controllers. Steam also added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21591013/steam-input-api-ps5-dualsense-controller-support"&gt;PS5 controller support&lt;/a&gt; last year, followed by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22240383/nvidia-shield-tv-ps5-dualsense-xbox-series-x-controller-support-update"&gt;Nvidia’s Shield TV support last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="95bPrv"&gt;iOS 14.5 will also include the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260639/apple-watch-iphone-unlocked-ios-14-5-app-tracking"&gt;unlock an iPhone with an Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt; while wearing a mask, Siri emergency contact calling, CarPlay ETA sharing, and dual-SIM 5G support. Apple hasn’t said exactly when iOS 14.5 will arrive to all devices, but given it’s entered into beta today, it should arrive for everyone in the next couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260671/ios-14-5-ps5-dualsense-xbox-series-x-controller-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260671/ios-14-5-ps5-dualsense-xbox-series-x-controller-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-01T13:47:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T13:47:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 14.5 tries to solve Face ID’s mask problem with your Apple Watch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A new Apple Watch watch face" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g9_FEWRpWJUCVFO-ueA4mQM50o0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68752372/vpavic_200929_4216_0171.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6lyYwq"&gt;Apple’s latest iPhones stuck with Face ID as the singular method of biometric authentication  in an era when people are wearing face masks everywhere they go. This inevitably means having to enter your passcode &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; throughout the day. But Apple has come up with a stopgap solution that should make it easier to get into your phone during mask life — as long as you’ve got an Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jI7AfK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pocket-lint.com/phones/news/apple/155559-iphone-face-id-will-soon-work-with-masks-but-only-if-you-re-wearing-an-apple-watch"&gt;As first reported by &lt;em&gt;Pocket-lint&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the new iOS 14.5 update, which went into beta today, uses the Apple Watch on your wrist to quickly authenticate and unlock your iPhone. Apple already offers this convenient trick on the Mac, but now it’s coming to the iPhone as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NxEuqC"&gt;It works similarly here. You lift your iPhone to turn on the screen, and you’ll feel a little nudge of haptic feedback on your Apple Watch to indicate that your iPhone has been unlocked. The devices must be in close proximity for this to work in the first place, which is a measure to keep your data secure. (If the Apple Watch is locked, this won’t work either.) And this Apple Watch shortcut is only good for unlocking your iPhone; App Store and iTunes purchases will still require other authentication if your face is covered. And as a final security check, you’ll still be asked to put in your passcode every few hours even when unlock with Apple Watch is enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fD95ik"&gt;This feature hasn’t always been so reliable for some Mac owners, so it’ll take some testing to see whether Apple has made it more seamless on the iPhone, which people unlock a whole lot throughout the day. Android has offered a similar benefit for some time now via the “smart lock” setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2we7Rl"&gt;It’s been rumored (most recently by &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/whats-in-the-next-iphone-check-samsungs-new-galaxy-s21-11611931084"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) that Apple is considering moving to an in-screen fingerprint reader to complement Face ID for the iPhone 13. The latest iPad Air also features a Touch ID fingerprint sensor within the power button, so Apple certainly has options for giving users more choice in future iPhones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJ5yPH"&gt;iOS 14.5 also includes the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22253366/apple-app-tracking-transparency-opt-in-requirement-beta-launch"&gt;app tracking transparency controls (and permission pop-ups)&lt;/a&gt; that companies like Facebook aren’t happy about. It adds support for Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5 controllers, brings 5G dual-sim functionality to users globally, and also offers some Siri enhancements like the ability to call emergency contacts. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260639/apple-watch-iphone-unlocked-ios-14-5-app-tracking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260639/apple-watch-iphone-unlocked-ios-14-5-app-tracking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-01T12:01:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T12:01:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook prompt will encourage ad tracking opt-in ahead of Apple’s privacy push</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z68YP0IKo3HUEpIFV749ErIJVD0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68751770/akrales_180614_1777_0080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wU7A49"&gt;Facebook will begin showing a prompt on its mobile app for the iPhone and iPad that’s designed to convince users to allow ad tracking, in preparation for an upcoming privacy change in which Apple will force developers to obtain permission to track users across apps and websites in the future. The new screen, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/01/facebook-strikes-back-against-apple-ios-14-idfa-privacy-change.html"&gt;first reported on Monday by CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, will be shown to users globally starting today and will provide Facebook with early data on how Apple’s privacy change might affect the social network’s business, ahead of Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22253366/apple-app-tracking-transparency-opt-in-requirement-beta-launch"&gt;planned update in early spring&lt;/a&gt; that will make the opt-in request mandatory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUuqg1"&gt;The prompt will give users a page of information detailing why Facebook thinks a user should give the company permission to track them on iOS. The company argues doing so will make ads more personalized and help support businesses that rely on advertising. Apple’s upcoming change, which it first detailed at its developer conference last year, will let users opt out of letting apps collect the so-called Identifier for Advertisers, or IDFA, code, which companies share with one another to track a user across apps and websites and to measure the effectiveness of digital ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RPd30e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple’s new prompt is designed to present a false tradeoff between personalized ads and privacy.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YHjX7V"&gt;Facebook has spent the last few months &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/ios-14-apple-privacy-update-impacts-small-business-ads"&gt;citing the potential harm to small businesses&lt;/a&gt; posed by Apple’s new privacy measures, which Facebook says will lead to less effective advertising and potentially lower revenues. The company has even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22180102/facebook-new-newspaper-ad-apple-ios-14-privacy-prompt"&gt;taken out full-page newspaper ads&lt;/a&gt; railing against Apple’s changes, and both &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/27/facebook-ceo-zuckerberg-says-it.html"&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/28/apple-ceo-tim-cook-says-f.html"&gt;Apple CEO Tim Cook&lt;/a&gt; have made a series of increasingly hostile public remarks against the other company’s business models. Now, Facebook says under App Store rules allowing developers to educate consumers, it’s using its new prompt “to help people make a more informed decision.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ghw1Dx"&gt;“Apple’s new prompt is designed to present a false tradeoff between personalized ads and privacy; when in fact, we can provide both. Apple is doing this to self-preference their own services and targeted advertising products,” a Facebook spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “To help people make a real choice, we’re also showing a screen of our own to provide more information about how we use personalized ads, which support small businesses and keep apps free. Agreeing to our screen doesn’t result in Facebook collecting new types of data; it just means that Facebook can continue to give people better experiences.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k03wG3q_uPaExC2O-CCo7Jlx4bk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22273120/106832756_1611957023306_Test_screens_FINAL.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qBP3d7"&gt;The prompt is intended to preface the system-level pop-up Apple will make mandatory in an upcoming iOS 14 release this spring. Notably, Facebook does not use the word tracking, but instead asks to “use your apps and website activity,” while the Apple pop-up that follows spells out that Facebook is asking for permission to “track you across apps and websites owned by other companies.” Developers have been able to ask for permission since the release of the new operating system last fall. Yet few have done so, while Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/3/21420176/apple-ios-14-tracking-permission-rule-developers-delay"&gt;delayed its implementation of the opt-in requirement&lt;/a&gt; in September of last year to give developers more time to comply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UTLxHy"&gt;In this case, however, Facebook is asking for permission early in an effort to prepare itself for what may be a substantial amount of its users who decline to opt into ad tracking. According to a &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-looks-to-take-its-fight-with-apple-to-court"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;The Information &lt;/em&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, some internal estimates at the company predict fewer than 20 percent of Facebook users agreeing to allow tracking on iOS. Regardless of the choice a user makes if they see the pop-up today or sometime in the next few weeks, Facebook intends to honor the choice when Apple makes the opt-in requirement mandatory, according to CNBC. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260274/facebook-prompt-apple-ios-ad-tracking-opt-in-permission-privacy-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260274/facebook-prompt-apple-ios-ad-tracking-opt-in-permission-privacy-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-01T10:30:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-01T10:30:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZuVjFm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirPods 2 review: even more wireless|63428" data-volume-uuid="c798b260f" data-volume-id="63428" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-634" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $120 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, $129 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, or for $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHjw-MSSOE9krvMa6cC9qYmHU9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993019/akrales_190327_3315_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. You can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=4781ccd9dac6fb8bf9e60c657cd3fbba&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/979838/2092?sharedid=verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OGXtAu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Uv43TD"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="AirPods Pro review: the perfect earbuds for the iPhone|73652" data-volume-uuid="c840e1e11" data-volume-id="73652" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-337" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. Right now, if you don’t mind buying refurbished, they are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730154636955201273" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$170 at Best Buy (Geek Squad Certified)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/VergeEvergreen/https://electronics.woot.com/offers/apple-airpods-pro-grade-a-refurbished-1?ref=mwj_cd_deal_7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$180 at Woot (Grade A Certified)&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a new pair, the lowest price you can get them for currently is at &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/VergeEvergreen/https://electronics.woot.com/offers/apple-airpods-pro-23?ref=w_cnt_wp_0_1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot for $190&lt;/a&gt;. If that deal sells out, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=c4f3f58040f1804eb1980afa134f1c7a&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; are offering these flagship earbuds for $200; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has it for $210, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-pro%2F-%2FA-54191101&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target is selling the AirPods Pros for $235&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $278&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TuBiVT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FDsE87"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c9yAKy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
