<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-04T15:30:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T15:30:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T15:30:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Targus built Apple’s Find My tracking tech into its Cypress Hero EcoSmart backpack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7cNjAf_-qd8WJS9DIR_KcOVEMMI=/0x71:1590x1131/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347456/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_2.13.10_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Targus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nZotoS"&gt;In addition to designing several new products for people trying to keep germ-free during a pandemic, Targus is targeting iPhone users &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.targus.com%2Fblogs%2Fpress-room%2Ftargus-showcases-new-product-range-at-ces-2022-to-empower-a-seamless-life-at-home-in-the-office-or-on-the-go&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866769%2Ftargus-ces-2022-apple-backpack-find-my" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;with this new Cypress Hero EcoSmart Backpack that has built-in Apple Find My technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lxezy39SPVc--hHUdNwhSVFs1ZE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23144911/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_12.12.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Targus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cypress Hero EcoSmart backpack includes Apple’s Find My technology.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="un67rC"&gt;In turn, users can also use their backpack to track a lost iPhone by pressing a button in the backpack. The backpack has an integrated battery that’s replaceable and can be recharged via USB, which Targus claims will provide better protection from thieves than a simple tag. Like the other bags in the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.targus.com%2Fcollections%2Fcypress-with-ecosmart%3Fnarrow%3D%255B%255B%2522Features%2522%252C%2522filter_features_Eco-Friendly%2522%255D%255D%26sort_by%3Dcreation_date%26utm_source%3Dpress_release%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3DCES_2022_Product_Roundup&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866769%2Ftargus-ces-2022-apple-backpack-find-my" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cypress Hero EcoSmart line&lt;/a&gt;, Targus says this one is built using approximately 26 recycled water bottles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EnhdZV"&gt;Currently, there is no specific release date for the backpack, but Targus says that the new product will be available in spring / summer 2022 for $149.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6Nq4w"&gt;Not an iPhone user or don’t want any built-in tracking? Targus is also expanding &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/targus-showcases-new-product-range-at-ces-2022-to-empower-a-seamless-life-at-home-in-the-office-or-on-the-go-301453009.html"&gt;its antimicrobial accessory line&lt;/a&gt; at CES 2022 — a line meant to stand out in a pandemic consumer market in a way that marketing exec Andrew Corkill says will “address productivity, sustainability, and health and wellness initiatives to enable a seamless life.” That includes other backpacks, plus a briefcase, slipcase, and laptop sleeve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5CZv7M"&gt;Targus also announced a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.targus.com%2Fblogs%2Fpress-room%2Ftargus-and-synaptics-to-introduce-world-s-first-universal-hybrid-dock-with-bio-authentication-via-built-in-fingerprint-id-at-ces-2022&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866769%2Ftargus-ces-2022-apple-backpack-find-my" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;USB-C Hybrid / Universal 4K Quad Dock&lt;/a&gt; with fingerprint ID compatible with Windows, macOS, Linux, Android, and Chrome OS. It supports either single-display 8K resolution output or four 4K displays. It will be available this month as the Dock720 for $442.99 while a Dock710 without enterprise-grade biometrics capabilities will be available for $372.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xQgJQO"&gt;Finally, Targus says &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225509/targus-anti-microbial-keyboard-light-and-backpack-ces-pandemic"&gt;the UV-C LED Disinfection Light it announced at CES 2021&lt;/a&gt; to keep keyboards clean is now “the world’s first certified disinfection unit for commercial use under UL 962” and will be available in February for $299.99. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7FJMPcHbFuWg2PmmeHvMiQGsrZM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23144938/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_10.07.50_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Targus&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;aside id="LYIvg3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Targus announces an antimicrobial keyboard light and backpack ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225509/targus-anti-microbial-keyboard-light-and-backpack-ces-pandemic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866769/targus-ces-2022-apple-backpack-find-my"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866769/targus-ces-2022-apple-backpack-find-my</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T14:58:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T14:58:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>China launches iPhone and Android apps for its digital currency</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="E-CNY App" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y4e_BYJTjmcR5EJVt5qnFHmWhzg=/0x30:4536x3054/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347284/1237534100.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Liu Junfeng / Costfoto/Future Publishing via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A2PvGd"&gt;China has rolled out a pilot version of an app that allows users to store and pay with digital yuan, also known as e-CNY, as reported by the &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3162094/china-digital-currency-e-cny-wallet-lands-app-stores-ahead-winter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And no, the digital yuan isn’t a cryptocurrency — it was developed by the People’s Bank of China (PBOC) to replace banknotes and coins; thus, it isn’t a decentralized form of payment, nor will it operate on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnnz0d"&gt;Although it might sound like we already pay with digital cash when we use a credit card or an online payment service like PayPal and Apple Pay, the digital yuan isn’t anything like that. e-CNY is essentially physical cash converted into a digital form, and it’s been in the works since 2014. According to &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/05/chinas-digital-yuan-what-is-it-and-how-does-it-work.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, distribution of the digital currency will take place using a two-tier system that transfers e-CNY from the PBOC to commercial banks. Banks will then distribute the currency directly to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ROAvbN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As we get closer to the Beijing Olympics, China may use the currency as a way for visitors to easily make payments&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5lvPyq"&gt;Since the e-CNY isn’t a decentralized currency like bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, it doesn’t promise the same kind of privacy. The &lt;a href="https://www.db.com/news/detail/20210714-digital-yuan-what-is-it-and-how-does-it-work"&gt;Deutsche Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; s&lt;/em&gt;ays it will have “controlled anonymity,” meaning users can choose to conceal their identities from counterparties, but it will still let the authorities monitor transactions for illegal activities like money laundering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdVLGG"&gt;Digital payment apps like WeChat and AliPay already have a strong foothold in China, with around &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/chart/17409/most-popular-digital-payment-services-in-china/"&gt;nine in 10 Chinese people&lt;/a&gt; saying they used either app within the past year. It might seem unlikely for the Chinese to want to switch over to the digital yuan, but China has been working hard to promote it. Within the past two years, cities throughout China have even been holding lotteries, distributing a total of &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3104832/chinas-shenzhen-giving-away-millions-sovereign-digital-yuan"&gt;10 million digital yuan (worth about $1.47 million USD at the time)&lt;/a&gt; to people in Shenzen in October 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3112724/chinese-city-hand-out-virtual-red-packets-part-digital-yuan"&gt;20 million digital yuan (or ~$3 million USD)&lt;/a&gt; in Suzhou in December 2020, and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/24/chinese-city-chengdu-launches-6-million-digital-currency-test.html"&gt;40.2 million digital yuan (or ~$6.2 million)&lt;/a&gt; in Chengdu in February 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJDOyi"&gt;Last September, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-14/digital-yuan-goes-head-to-head-with-alipay-wechat-in-beijing"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; covered a trade fair in Beijing, where attendees were shown how to sign up for an account, as well as the many ways to use the digital currency — this includes wearables that users can tap against scanners to pay with e-CNY. As noted in the report, users can fill up their AliPay account with the currency, which suggests both forms of payment might have more of a symbiotic relationship rather than a competitive one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BrnIQy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; even describes how some banks at the event demonstrated how foreigners could sign up for an e-CNY account using their passport and phone number, as well as convert foreign currency to e-CNY. As we get closer to the 2022 Beijing Winter Olympics, this may be a way for China to leverage the currency as a way for visitors to easily make payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGs3Jr"&gt;The new e-CNY app is available on both China’s Android and Apple app stores, but only people in 10 specific cities, including Beijing, Shenzen, Chengdu, and Shanghai, can use it. And as pointed out by &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/04/china-launches-digital-currency-app-to-expand-usage.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the app will be available to use during the upcoming Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866757/china-digital-currency-yuan-iphone-android-apps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866757/china-digital-currency-yuan-iphone-android-apps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The new Chipolo Card Spot puts Apple’s Find My network in your wallet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JjQLmLShIBD-BXGR_YTqOZXhxLI=/30x0:1950x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70346100/Chipolo_CARD_Spot_Blue_Wallet.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9JESOT"&gt;Chipolo has a new Bluetooth tracker it’s announcing at CES 2022: the $35 Chipolo Card Spot, a new version of the company’s credit card-shaped Spot tracker that utilizes Apple’s Find My Bluetooth network for locating missing objects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGQD1s"&gt;The idea of a credit card-shaped tracker for your wallet is nothing new, of course — &lt;a href="https://chipolo.net/en-us/products/chipolo-card"&gt;both Chipolo&lt;/a&gt; and more established competitors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716868/tile-mate-pro-slim-sticker-trackers-update-range-volume-water-resistance"&gt;like Tile&lt;/a&gt; have been making them for years. But like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372099/chipolo-one-spot-bluetooth-tracker-find-my-apple-airtags"&gt;Chipolo One Spot released last year&lt;/a&gt;, the Card Spot ditches Chipolo’s own Bluetooth tracking network in favor of support for Apple’s Find My mesh network, used by AirTags and other Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="va4boc"&gt;Chipolo has been a smaller player in the Bluetooth tracking world for years, but it’s made its presence more known in recent months thanks to its quick support for Apple’s Find My network (the company actually announced its One Spot tracker before Apple’s AirTags were officially revealed). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sogpuBBwK6UeAWr4ukGRawKYYu8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128907/Chipolo_CARD_Spot_Thin_as_it_gets.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zvvBi7"&gt;The Card Spot supports the usual Find My feature set, including marking an item as missing with Apple’s Lost Mode and the recently added iOS 15 feature to “&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212765"&gt;Notify When Left Behind&lt;/a&gt;” which, as the name implies, notifies you automatically if you leave your tracker (and the wallet that presumably contains it) behind. Unlike Apple’s AirTags, though, the Card Spot doesn’t have an ultra-wideband radio, meaning that it won’t be able to do the hyper-local tracking that Apple’s first-party tags can do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YP43Gu"&gt;On the spec side of things, the Card Spot has an audible alert that reaches 105dB in volume with a 200-foot range, while measuring in at 0.09 inches thick (or about three times as thick as an average credit card). The Card Spot also offers IPX5 water resistance, although the battery isn’t removable. Instead, Chipolo says that each Card Spot should offer about two years of battery life, with a return program that lets customers ship in their old tracker to be recycled in exchange for a 50 percent off discount code on a new one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cdkOc"&gt;Preorders start January 4th, with the first Card Spots set to ship in February. Customers will be able to &lt;a href="https://chipolo.net/en-us/products/chipolo-card-spot"&gt;buy the Card Spot for $35&lt;/a&gt;, in a &lt;a href="https://chipolo.net/en-us/products/chipolo-card-spot-2-pack?variant=781948"&gt;discounted two-pack for $60&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href="https://chipolo.net/en-us/products/chipolo-spot-bundle?cl=header"&gt;“Spot Bundle”&lt;/a&gt; of two One Spot trackers and one Card Spot tracker for $77. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856053/chipolo-card-spot-bluetooth-tracker-apple-find-my-airtags"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22856053/chipolo-card-spot-bluetooth-tracker-apple-find-my-airtags</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T09:16:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T09:16:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s latest Nest Hub display is nearly half off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zgWII76WV90UwPBnTDmDt_r4oJc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70345651/dseifert_20210323_4485_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s latest Nest Hub is on sale today for just $59.99, its second-best price to date.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ip6mXW"&gt;If you were secretly hoping for a smart home display for Christmas but didn’t receive one, today you can treat yourself to one of the best for almost half its usual price. Right now, you can grab Google’s second-gen Nest Hub — our pick for one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22535003/best-smart-displays-alexa-google-echo-nest"&gt;best smart displays&lt;/a&gt; — for its second-best price to date at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1629831-REG%2Fgoogle_ga01331_us_nest_hub_2_chalk.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22865019%2Fgoogle-nest-hub-apple-watch-series-7-wacom-one-airtag-loop-lg-a1-tv-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cglklYIiBv6" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/1181395/1036?subId1=verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fga01331us.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt;. Typically $99.99, it’s currently on sale for $59.99, which is only $10 shy of its all-time low during Black Friday. As mentioned in our review, Google’s small second-gen smart display remains an excellent digital photo frame for displaying images from Google Photos, and it offers automatic and reliable sleep-tracking features. It’s also a better speaker than its predecessor and grants you access to Google Assistant’s full suite of features. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22357214/google-nest-hub-2nd-gen-2021-assistant-smart-display-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lntdDM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10881450"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r49OiG"&gt;We’re four days into 2022, and if you’re starting to struggle with your New Year’s fitness resolutions, 1) welcome to the club and 2) today’s Apple Watch Series 7 deal may be just what you were looking for. For those still resolved to get healthier this year, you have another chance to snag Apple’s latest smartwatch for its lowest price to date. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09HF1DC1J/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is once again selling the 41mm, GPS-equipped Apple Watch Series 7 in green with a matching Sport Band for $339 instead of $399 after briefly offering the same discount two weeks ago. The Apple Watch Series 7 offers a larger, edge-to-edge display than its last-gen counterpart, along with IP6X dust resistance. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gFFySg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860351"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OfP5UO"&gt;On the other hand, if you’re more the type of person who prefers lounging around watching TV over going for a run, 1) again, welcome to the club, and 2) we’ve got a solid deal on a relatively inexpensive OLED. LG’s A1 OLED offers deep black levels, great color accuracy, and wide viewing angles, along with support for both Alexa and Google Assistant. It doesn’t offer the advanced gaming features found with the more expensive LG C1, like variable refresh rate and HDMI 2.1 ports, but if features don’t matter to you, this more budget-friendly OLED might be worth checking out. Right now, you can pick up the A1 in the 48-inch configuration at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F164937252697%3Famdata%3Denc%253AAQAGAAAAkPb26u5XMepclSzddcMwulBMyRV7VoW7jhFGXzqcUALNBOfJF40hvardXAswI2hhBD%252FV9LwELQn5%252BpYRjH9OqNpRBcQRO4riIzygFfx%252BN1mdH588QsfiP1SZMz2OOdJxP7SlL7X1TehcgQQNos0bWwl0fLSgnZj%252FDLs22rdTUl7kLyufQSQ053Ou5CEXrYLMZQ%253D%253D%257Ctkp%253ABFBMxO2r1sRf%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3Dvergedeals010422%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22865019%2Fgoogle-nest-hub-apple-watch-series-7-wacom-one-airtag-loop-lg-a1-tv-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-Built-Refresh-AI-Powered-OLED48A1PUA/dp/B092LZNZB7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $846.99, or $849.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cglGbOlG5KN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; instead of paying its original $1,199.99 price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pYtoHG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10959416"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KIdKv3"&gt;Looking for a way to express your creativity at a discount? Wacom’s most affordable drawing tablet is now available for its best price to date. Geared toward entry-level artists and social media content creators, Wacom’s One Drawing Tablet &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B082LZXQ6B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;is $299.95 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is $100 off of the typical listing price. Our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21028405/wacom-one-tablet-pen-display-android-price-macos-windows-ces-2020" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;hands-on impressions left us impressed&lt;/a&gt; with this tablet, namely its matte display, which felt great to draw on. The 13-inch, 1920 x 1080 HD slate is compatible with Windows, macOS, and Chrome OS, as well as some Android tablets and smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SJuiNy"&gt;Additionally, the Wacom One comes with a pressure-sensitive stylus and limited-time access to various creative software services, including a two-month subscription to Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom, along with six months of access to Adobe Fresco. Note, however, that the drawing tablet lacks support for USB-C, so you’ll need a dongle to connect it to newer MacBook models and Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FyisAx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10959354"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nvajca"&gt;Nintendo Switch owners can nab a complimentary 128GB SanDisk microSD card from Best Buy when they purchase an &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cglmcaHay7K" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;annual family membership to Nintendo Switch Online for $34.99&lt;/a&gt;. The membership grants up to eight local Switch users access to more than 70 SNES and NES games, along with perks like online multiplayer, exclusive offers (like access to purchase one of the &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-64-controller.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;hard-to-find wireless Nintendo 64 controllers&lt;/a&gt;), and cloud storage for game saves. SanDisk’s bundled microSD card, meanwhile, gives your Switch an extra 128GB of storage, so you can store more games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="r17La0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10609427"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eAcrxL"&gt;Check out these other great deals happening today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ZTWXm8"&gt;Amazon is selling the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B095NWYQBC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Wyze Cam V3 Spotlight for $41.93&lt;/a&gt; instead of $52.96, its best price ever. The Wyze Cam V3 Spotlight is Wyze’s latest home security camera, but with an added spotlight module you can turn off in the app or automate so that it responds to motion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VQS3KQ"&gt;The standard edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B087XR383W/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt; for the Xbox One&lt;/a&gt; — which you can upgrade to the Xbox Series X / S version for free — is on sale for $17.99 ($42 off) at Amazon, its lowest price yet. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/12/21319059/assassins-creed-valhalla-hands-on-preview-pc-xbox-one-ps4-gameplay-ubisoft-rpg" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HY5ilC"&gt;With the Arlo Audio Doorbell, you can partake in two-way conversations with visitors outside of your door from inside your house, have guests leave audio messages for you, and more. It normally retails for $79.99, but right now &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HXNPJLJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is selling it for just $25.67&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="h-logitech-ergo-k860-ergonomic-keyboard-features"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/1/15/21064263/logitech-ergo-k860-split-keyboard-ergonomic-accessory-lineup-mx" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Logitech’s split Ergo K860 keyboard&lt;/a&gt; is designed to reduce muscle strain on wrists and forearms while typing, and it’s compatible with macOS and Windows. It normally retails for $129.99, but it’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07ZWK2TQT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale right now at Amazon for $109.99&lt;/a&gt;, its lowest price to date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="pHYQ6S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Xl4HSB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/4/22865019/google-nest-hub-apple-watch-series-7-wacom-one-airtag-loop-lg-a1-tv-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/4/22865019/google-nest-hub-apple-watch-series-7-wacom-one-airtag-loop-lg-a1-tv-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Schlage announces first Apple Home Key-compatible smart lock</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i66y4veI_-UCewosbPTB3Dnares=/0x72:4171x2853/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70345536/Schlage_Encode_Plus_with_home_keys_phone_TaptoUnlock__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Schlage Encode Plus is the first Apple home key smart lock.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Schlage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BogEBd"&gt;At CES 2022 this week, lock manufacturer Schlage announced it is launching the first lock in North America to support Apple’s Home Key. The Schlage Encode Plus Smart WiFi Deadbolt is an updated version of the popular Schlage Encode WiFi smart lock, adding an NFC chip for the Home Key function, as well as a Thread radio to support HomeKit over Thread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3m5d9"&gt;Home Key, introduced with iOS 15, lets you store a digital door key in your Apple Wallet and lock and unlock your door by tapping your device on the lock, similar to how Apple Pay or Apple Transit works. The system uses the iPhone’s or Apple Watch’s NFC chip to authenticate a user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3F0yh0"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.schlage.com/en/home/smart-locks/encode-plus.html"&gt;Schlage Encode Plus&lt;/a&gt; will be available in spring 2022 for $300 (that Plus moniker comes with a $50 price hike from the original Encode). The Schlage Sense, a HomeKit-only lock that doesn’t support Home Key, is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YUPDV34/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;still available for $200&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1I2plVQ0OjwEWwwI_fu_WcNcHSE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23134609/Encode_Plus_CEN_Satin_Nickel_Front_Door__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schlage Encode Plus works with HomeKit, Alexa, and Google and doesn’t require a hub or bridge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pCb1Oo"&gt;The addition of Home Key gives the Encode a feature available on other door locks that so far it had been largely lacking — a hands-free way to unlock the door (if you use the watch option, that is). You can also control it with an app, a keypad, a regular key, and voice control using Siri, Alexa, or Google Assistant.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b76WbY"&gt;Home Key has two modes for unlocking: “Express Mode,” where you don’t have to unlock your phone, and “Require Face ID or Passcode,” which adds the step of authenticating with Face ID or Touch ID. If you lose your phone, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210515#markaslost"&gt;enabling Lost Mode through Apple’s Find My feature&lt;/a&gt; will disable all elements of your Apple Wallet, including Home Key. If your phone battery is dying, you can still unlock the door with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/2/20991458/apple-pay-express-transit-london-tfl-feature-available"&gt;Power Reserve feature introduced in iOS14&lt;/a&gt;. It works in the same way it does with Express Transit mode, functioning for up to five hours after the red Power Reserve icon appears on an Apple Watch or iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7RuHQv"&gt;Home Key also brings with it the option to manage access keys in HomeKit, so you can have different codes for different folks. A nice feature for families is that once you set up Home Key on your device, every member of the household who is part of your Apple Home automatically has the key added to their wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6aj6bmUukeqwtTnT3gXqoPN_MsY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23134807/Schlage_Encode_Plus_with_Apple_home_keys_Watch_TaptoUnlock.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Schlage&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;When paired with home key, the Schlage lock can be controlled using just your Apple Watch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dNDpcy"&gt;The Schlage Encode retains the same exterior design and all the existing features of the non-Plus version and integrates with Google and Amazon Alexa smart home platforms for automations and voice control via the Schlage Home app. You can use HomeKit and the Schlage app simultaneously. As a Wi-Fi lock, it doesn’t require any separate hub or bridge for remote access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5fk6Hn"&gt;However, the lock can be set up entirely in HomeKit if you prefer, although it requires an Apple Home hub (such as a HomePod Mini or Apple TV) for remote access in this configuration. The Schlage app also adds a few features not in HomeKit, such as scheduling access and a built-in alarm feature. “With this lock, we’re giving our customers the opportunity to use all the different features and integrations — Alexa, Google Assistant, as well as HomeKit,” says Donald Beene, senior product manager for Allegion (parent company of Schlage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Z2iwcl"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Schlage Encode Plus Smart WiFi Deadbolt|105415" data-volume-uuid="35fe5e45e" data-volume-id="105415" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-982" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;This video produced by Schlage shows the Encode Plus in action.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dhsnYi"&gt;The lock is available in the same styles and finishes as the Encode: the more traditional Camelot design or the more modern Century option. The only physical difference is the addition of two NFC targets on the keypad screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kj7dIS"&gt;The Encode Plus uses four protocols, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, NFC, and Thread. NFC has been part of Schlage’s commercial options previously, but this is the first time it’s used it in residential locks. There are a few other locks that currently support NFC; one is the Level Lock Touch, but Schlage is the first to come to market in North America with a Home Key-compatible lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m4FbFw"&gt;The Thread radio supports HomeKit over Thread specifically, says Beene, and is Schlage’s first Thread-enabled product. The company is closely watching the developing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22787729/matter-smart-home-standard-apple-amazon-google"&gt;Matter smart home standard&lt;/a&gt;, too. “The hardware is here for Matter,” he says. “This will be the first [lock] product with the hardware on board to support something like that, but we still don’t know where those tech specs will land.” Matter is slated to launch in mid-2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nuBXhrxnqWLUTLGTUG3zINky1wE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23134824/Schlage_Encode_Plus_Century_in_Satin_Nickel_Exterior_x_Interior.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Schlage&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schlage Encode Plus comes in two styles: the contemporary Century (above) and traditional Camelot (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yn75H4o2myz_VbPgYBxZeWYo7fA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142274/Schlage_Encode_Plus_Camelot_in_Aged_Bronze_Exterior_x_Interior__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Schlage&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both the Camelot and the Century will come in matte black, satin nickel, and aged bronze (pictured) finishes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="atWqYu"&gt;With all those radios on board, battery life could be an issue. With all-in use — i.e., if you connect the lock over Wi-Fi to the Schlage app and to HomeKit — the battery life is about four to five months, says Beene. Using HomeKit only, it jumps up to about a year, he says, but you will need an Apple Home Hub for remote access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C3UWT9"&gt;The addition of Home Key and HomeKit compatibility makes the Encode Plus one of the most fully featured smart locks on the market (for iPhone owners, although Beene told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company is looking at bringing the NFC function to Android phones). August and Yale’s August-powered smart locks also have wide compatibility with smart home platforms and an auto-unlock feature that uses geofencing to control your lock as you approach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YHL6rO"&gt;My experience with August locks is that the auto-unlock feature is quite hit or miss. Home Key looks to be a more reliable way to easily unlock your door in a hands-free fashion. Currently, a fingerprint reader is my favorite way to unlock a smart door lock, but we’ll have to wait and see whether this will prove to be a more convenient option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HCgEGO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vanv7k"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MlrZ6n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22860197/apple-home-key-schlage-encode-plus-smart-door-lock-thread-ces2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22860197/apple-home-key-schlage-encode-plus-smart-door-lock-thread-ces2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T19:47:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T19:47:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2020 MacBook Air, one of the best laptops you can get, is now available at Amazon starting at $949.99.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YgkMYN"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including ones equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult. It’s a slightly different story for the newer M1 Pro and M1 Max-equipped MacBook Pros, but any bit of savings you can get on the new Pro models is sure to be worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the discounts that are currently available for the latest MacBook models, as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — which are compatible with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22765988/apple-macos-12-monterey-review-macbook-pro-air-imac-m1"&gt;recently released macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; — but we strongly recommend opting for a newer model now that Apple has introduced its M1 chips across the MacBook Air and Pro lines. There is really no downside to opting for Apple’s own silicon, save for Windows Boot Camp holdouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac%2F2020-mac-mini-macbook-air-macbook-pro&amp;amp;subid1=vergemacbookdealsdecember2021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15 to 20 percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. For now, however, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="6Zmiyl"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SBa7t8"&gt;Select a category&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="G7eKsD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals#EVXzol" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The best MacBook Air deals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sczWsj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals#DTHGG6" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The best MacBook Pro deals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uvU72Z"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals#LYpjlZ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The best Mac Mini deals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="TGmZTR"&gt;
&lt;div id="wtaWNU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10961031"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g5HcUQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;The best MacBook Air deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FJU3RG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance. It ticks all right boxes when it comes to performance and price, which is why it’s our top pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best laptop you can buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iF2kto"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and a 256GB SSD. It typically sells for $999, although in the past few months we’ve seen it discounted down to $799.99. The best deal at the moment, however, is only available at Amazon, where you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B08N5KWB9H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;base model for $949.99&lt;/a&gt;. The 512GB model is also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LFLC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; in select colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;The best MacBook Pro deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xStRiT"&gt;The MacBook Pro line has been split into two different segments — for the time being. The M1-powered MacBook Pro of 2020 remains the final Touch Bar holdout. It is a sibling to the MacBook Air, introduced at the same time, with similar innards, save mostly for a fan that allows it to run at peak performance for longer. The new 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros, announced during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s “Unleashed” event&lt;/a&gt; last year, come with the M1 Pro or optional M1 Max CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Id2Hln"&gt;There are multiple variants of both models, however, we haven’t seen any noteworthy discounts on any configuration outside of Amazon’s $78 discount last month on the 14-inch base model. There are no deals available at the moment, either, though Best Buy will throw in some incentives when you buy the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cggHmcuFlcg" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;14-&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cglodJJhkbP" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;16-inch model&lt;/a&gt;, including six months of Apple Music, 15 months of Microsoft 365 for the price of 12, free security software, and a handful of other special offers. You can also get a discount when you trade in select devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KS0G3y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"2021 MacBook Pros compared: how Apple’s laptops stack up","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs"},{"title":"12 great apps ready for your new Mac","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22814365/mac-best-apps-apple-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="h4rH4i"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Our reviews&lt;/a&gt; of the latest MacBook Pro line were absolutely beaming with praise. Whether it was the beautiful display or the remarkable performance and battery life they exhibited, these premium laptops are investments that we can wholeheartedly recommend. As soon as there’s a price break on these impressive laptops, we’d suggest that anyone in the market for a new laptop consider purchasing one, as they’re likely to move fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oXGxIx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="AOJENT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814228"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The Touch Bar-equipped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; is similar to the Air but geared toward slightly more demanding use cases, and starts at $1,299. The M1-powered base model includes 256GB of storage, 8GB of RAM, a brighter screen, longer battery life, and an internal fan designed to maintain performance under increased workloads. In mid-December, we saw the base model drop down to $1099.99, but right now, both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LLDSG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604809-REG%2Fapple_myd82ll_a_13_3_macbook_pro_with.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo are only selling it for $1,199&lt;/a&gt;. That may not be as steep of a discount, but that’s still a savings of $100. The larger, 512GB configuration with 8GB of RAM is also currently &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LM1K3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604810-REG%2Fapple_myd92ll_a_13_3_macbook_pro_with.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo in space gray for $1,349.00&lt;/a&gt;, a $150 discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ue6Q0U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="PGPvTR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;The best Mac Mini deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. If you’re looking for a discount, both &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604799-REG%2Fapple_mgnr3ll_a_mac_mini.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-512GB-Storage/dp/B08N5PHB83/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon are selling the base model&lt;/a&gt; with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for $649 ($50 off), as well as the 512GB variant for $829 instead of $899 (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-512GB-Storage/dp/B08N5P7TLW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604800-REG%2Fapple_mgnt3ll_a_mac_mini.html%2FDFF%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T13:46:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T13:46:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple briefly crossed a $3 trillion market cap</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cUabvvoSkfx96vZLhek6NKJjLLU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70342842/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5VLcZu"&gt;Apple’s market cap briefly passed $3 trillion on Monday more than a year after it surpassed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375223/apple-2-trillion-market-cap-first-us-company-stock-price"&gt;the $2 trillion mark&lt;/a&gt; and three years after eclipsing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/2/17638764/apple-worlds-first-1-trillion-company-market-cap-stock-price"&gt;$1 trillion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z3Hhyj"&gt;Apple’s huge success is due in large part to the iPhone, which revolutionized the smartphone industry and remains a cash cow for the company. But Apple continues to see strong momentum in its other businesses as well, with its services and Mac divisions reporting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751418/apple-q4-2021-earnings-supply-constraints-chip-shortage"&gt;all-time highs in its Q4 2021 earnings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RCrPC4"&gt;Shortly after hitting the $3 trillion milestone at around 1:45PM ET, Apple’s market cap dipped below it again. Apple’s market cap must be above the $3 trillion mark when the market closes at 4PM ET for it to officially be designated as the first publicly-traded company with that valuation, and it ended below $3 trillion on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lvSXK3"&gt;Apple isn’t the only company in the trillion-dollar club; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/4/17819160/amazon-worth-1-trillion-dollars-stock-price-value%5D"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770569/alphabet-google-market-cap-hits-2-trillion"&gt;Google parent company Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/25/18515623/microsoft-worth-1-trillion-dollars-stock-price-value"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744504/hertz-tesla-order-100000-vehicles-electrify-fleet"&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; all have market caps exceeding $1 trillion. (Facebook parent company Meta breached the $1 trillion milestone &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554502/facebook-1-trillion-dollar-market-cap-company-business"&gt;in June&lt;/a&gt; but is currently sitting below it.) In recent years, Apple has also jostled with others for the crown of the world’s most valuable publicly traded company. It passed Saudi Aramco &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21350154/apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-saudi-aramco"&gt;in July 2020&lt;/a&gt;, though it was overtaken for a time &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753251/microsoft-apple-market-cap-business-valuable-company"&gt;by Microsoft in October&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5oQ9fq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 3rd, 4:36PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Apple’s market cap ended the day below $3 trillion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22828277/apple-3-trillion-market-cap-company-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22828277/apple-3-trillion-market-cap-company-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T13:09:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T13:09:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>An Apple HomeKit bug can send iOS devices into a death spiral </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nTqYAp00NgK0PiuWRv3U86YWtgM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70342714/acastro_190218_1777_apple_streaming_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ia3g4y"&gt;You should always be wary of invites to a stranger’s Home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djTWM3"&gt;That’s the upshot of a new piece of security research that has found a vulnerability capable of locking iOS devices into a spiral of freezing, crashing, and rebooting if a user connects to a sabotaged Apple Home device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8v4KJ"&gt;The vulnerability, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/trevorspiniolas/status/1477185285784051712?s=21"&gt;discovered by security researcher Trevor Spiniolas&lt;/a&gt;, can be exploited through Apple’s &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/homekit/"&gt;HomeKit API&lt;/a&gt;, the software interface that allows an iOS app to control compatible smart home devices. If an attacker creates a HomeKit device with an extremely long name — around 500,000 characters — then an iOS device that connects to it will become unresponsive once it reads the device name and enter a cycle of freezing and rebooting that can only be ended by wiping and restoring the iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="idDwXd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the most likely way to trigger the exploit would be through a spoof Home network&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SRvaRh"&gt;What’s more, since HomeKit device names are backed up to iCloud, signing in to the same iCloud account with a restored device will trigger the crash again, with the cycle continuing until the device owner switches off the option to sync Home devices from iCloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aVIby9"&gt;Though it’s possible that an attacker could compromise a user’s existing HomeKit-enabled device, the most likely way the exploit would be triggered is if the attacker created a spoof Home network and tricked a user into joining via a phishing email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdVMO8"&gt;To guard against the attack, the main precaution for iOS users is to instantly reject any invitations to join an unfamiliar Home network. Additionally, iOS users who currently use smart home devices can protect themselves by entering the Control Center and disabling the setting “Show Home Controls.” (This won’t prevent Home devices from being used but limits which information is accessible through the Control Center.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LHQzpH"&gt;Spiniolas &lt;a href="https://trevorspiniolas.com/doorlock/doorlock.html"&gt;released details on his personal website&lt;/a&gt; on January 1, 2022. He was &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-sg/HT209600"&gt;previously credited by Apple&lt;/a&gt; for discovering a vulnerability in macOS Mojave that was patched in 2019. The new vulnerability affects the latest iOS version, 15.2, and goes back at least as far as 14.7, Spiniolas said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0QorAC"&gt;Spiniolas also accused Apple of being slow to respond to the initial disclosure, which was made months before the public release. The researcher shared emails with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that appeared to show an Apple representative acknowledging the issue and requesting Spiniolas refrain from publishing details until early 2022. The blog post detailing the vulnerability claims that Apple was made aware of the issue on August 10, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uvC0YM"&gt;“Apple’s lack of transparency is not only frustrating to security researchers who often work for free, it poses a risk to the millions of people who use Apple products in their day-to-day lives by reducing Apple’s accountability on security matters,” Spiniolas wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1UWFLY"&gt;Apple had not responded to a request for comment by time of publication.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22865145/apple-ios-vulnerability-homekit-devices-bug-crash"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22865145/apple-ios-vulnerability-homekit-devices-bug-crash</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T13:01:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T13:01:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple selling new AirPods Pro coinciding with the Year of the Tiger in certain markets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3OiCFczPA_I9r0afqJmI7VaxiOk=/0x334:2000x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70342687/MN6U3_AV1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="b6AkUG"&gt;Apple is now selling a new set of special edition AirPod Pros (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/01/apple-launches-special-edition-tiger-airpods-pro-for-chinese-new-year/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;via 9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) in time for the Chinese New Year, which begins on February 1st, 2022. Just as the previous &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218360/apple-lunar-new-year-ox-airpods-pro-asia"&gt;Year of the Ox&lt;/a&gt;, Apple is engraving a special emoji on the AirPods Pro case — this time, themed for the Year of the Tiger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6XzHM"&gt;At first glance, it seems like only the standard tiger emoji is featured on the case — but turns out, it’s just a bit more snazzy with sparkles and fireworks surrounding the tiger face topped off with a cute tiger growly-face hood. Other than that, the only other difference is the retail box has the same emoji in red on the sides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/haCVc645ugqdcPA2D9vYCFQrI8M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142021/airpods_tiger.001.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images from Apple Store website&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;New special edition Year of the Tiger AirPods on the left comparing to AirPods Pro with a regular tiger emoji on the right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Tprz5U"&gt;The new Special Edition AirPods Pro - Tiger (the official name) is available to order now in several Asian markets, including Hong Kong (with a heavy backorder until May 1st as of writing), where it retails for HK$1,999 ($256.38 USD). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FCXc4c"&gt;Apple also is &lt;a href="https://m.weibo.cn/status/4720927805801613"&gt;giving away&lt;/a&gt; free red envelopes with a golden embossing of different Chinese zodiac emojis — all wearing the same tiger hood. It’s a cute addition for those traditionally gifting money for the celebration of the new year but is only available if purchased in an Apple Store that sells the special edition AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pyp3H"&gt;While people in markets like the US might feel left out — you could just order regular AirPods Pro and get a free tiger emoji engraving... it’s really not that different. The existence of these yearly special editions is perhaps a literal product of courting the Chinese market — a country in which Apple historically has had to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/4/21423347/apple-freedom-speech-expression-information-china-censorship-policy"&gt;bend&lt;/a&gt; to stay competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4WexEA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The four numbers Apple won’t let you engrave on your iPad in China","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632029/apple-engraving-filter-censorship-keyword-china-hong-kong-taiwan"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="dxj4xJ"&gt;Apple’s Beats by Dre brand also put out a pair of new Beats Studio Buds — which has a case that is adorned with golden tribal-style tiger stripes on a classic Beats red body. The stripes continue onto the actual buds themselves, unlike the standard-fare buds the special edition AirPods Pro come with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gI7PtC"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’re celebrating the Lunar New Year with our special-edition Beats Studio Buds. As a tribute to the Year of the Tiger, the Buds feature an all-red design with gold tiger print accents. Out on January 1st! &lt;a href="https://t.co/hDjDhW15rV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hDjDhW15rV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Beats by Dre (@beatsbydre) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beatsbydre/status/1475632661804761092?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22864887/apple-new-airpods-pro-year-of-the-tiger"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22864887/apple-new-airpods-pro-year-of-the-tiger</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-02T10:55:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T10:55:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>AirPods Pro 2 may come with lossless audio support and a charging case that makes sound</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k2MZr9hKJFLErqLATTZzsy5XyxE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70338848/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i6y4qD"&gt;The second-generation AirPods Pro may support Apple Lossless Audio Codec (ALAC), and could even come with a case that makes a sound to help you find it, according to Apple analyst Ming-Chi Kuo in a note to investors seen by &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/22/01/02/airpods-pro-2-charging-case-trackable-like-airtag-may-come-with-health-sensors"&gt;&lt;em&gt;AppleInsider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/02/kuo-airpods-pro-2-to-offer-lossless-support-new-form-factor-more/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aogMFl"&gt;There currently isn’t an AirPods model that supports lossless audio, a form of file compression that preserves all of the data in the original audio file, resulting in higher quality sound. Each AirPods model — even the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440788/apple-airpods-max-lossless-music-explainer-spatial-audio"&gt;pricey AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; — uses Bluetooth to deliver audio, which limits the devices to using Advanced Audio Codec (AAC), a lossy form of audio compression. Thus far, the only Apple devices that can take advantage of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;lossless audio on Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; (and elsewhere) include the iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple TV 4K, and Apple HomePod. The main downside to lossless audio is that its files take up more storage space on your device, and streaming it online can quickly eat up mobile data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dZtNl1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s a number of tricks we can play to maximize or get around some of the limits of Bluetooth”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gdZRpc"&gt;If the AirPods Pro 2 does support ALAC, Apple will either have to ditch Bluetooth or jump over some of the technology’s hurdles to accomplish that. The limitations of Bluetooth were brought up in &lt;a href="https://www.whathifi.com/features/is-bluetooth-holding-back-apples-airpods-we-asked-the-man-who-made-them"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Hi-Fi’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s recent interview with Gary Geaves, the vice president of acoustics at Apple. During the interview, Geaves said the company will need to work hard to get the most out of Bluetooth technology, and also noted that “there’s a number of tricks we can play to maximize or get around some of the limits of Bluetooth,” but “more bandwidth” would be ideal — a potential hint of what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERAT6V"&gt;As for the possibility of a charging case that emits sound, this may help you find your case if it’s ever separated from your AirPods — right now, only the AirPods themselves make a noise when you try to locate them via the Find My app. Also noted by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;AppleInsider&lt;/em&gt;, Kuo predicts that the AirPods Pro 2 could sport a redesign and may have a focus on fitness, something that was &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458155/new-airpods-pro-2022-fitness-release-dates-report-design-features"&gt;previously rumored by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, Kuo says that Apple may release the AirPods Pro 2 in the fourth quarter of 2022, about three years after the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;release of the first AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/2/22863442/airpods-pro-2-lossless-audio-charging-case-sound"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/2/22863442/airpods-pro-2-lossless-audio-charging-case-sound</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
