<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-18T09:54:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T09:54:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T09:54:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s ‘Unleashed’ Fall 2021 Mac Event: rumors, news, and announcements </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple October 18th event invitation" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PmHxoyaa0VlCwLB0M0BQXVBBz0c=/94x0:1330x824/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70010469/image__7_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The event kicks off at 1PM ET / 10AM PT today&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="Qjl0gC"&gt;Ever since the MacBook Pro line made significant departures from its winning formula with the introduction of the Touch Bar and the removal of MagSafe charging, people have been clamoring for a return to form. Last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;M1-powered MacBook Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; was a step in the right direction — as was the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;revised M1 Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; — but there’s still room to revitalize the “Pro” in MacBook Pro. That is a big part of what’s expected at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;Apple’s next event&lt;/a&gt;, dubbed “Unleashed,” which is scheduled for Monday, October 18th, at 1PM ET / 10AM PT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nPOayy"&gt;The rumors have been widespread that Apple will be refreshing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro with its own silicon&lt;/a&gt; and that a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;new 14-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; will be the proper successor to the old 13-inch models long left behind with their MagSafe plugs, SD card slots, and an array of versatile I/O. With new MacBook Pros might also come a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637477/new-mac-mini-design-ports-m1x-release-date-gurman"&gt;new, super-powered Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; that sports a revised design, as well as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586507/apple-airpods-2021-refresh-rumor-iphone-se-2022-5g-15-details"&gt;third-generation of the standard AirPods&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ORxf4H"&gt;Regardless of what’s announced, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;will keep you updated on all the latest news and announcements to be “Unleashed” by Apple on October 18th, including all the rumors and news leading up to the virtual event.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22725300/apple-event-unleashed-fall-2021-mac-mini-macbook-pro-news-announcements-products"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22725300/apple-event-unleashed-fall-2021-mac-mini-macbook-pro-news-announcements-products</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T08:09:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T08:09:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>The M1 chip saved the MacBook — but now Apple has to win back the Pros</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4l2XlWncu_NJxoMg-48F50FA97w=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70010098/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XmKgkS"&gt;It’s been hard to be an Apple power user for the last half-decade. The glory days of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/6/13/3082649/macbook-pro-review-retina-display-15-inch"&gt;original Retina MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; have long since vanished into the sunset, and recent years have seen computers with too many compromises and too few ports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7sHmmI"&gt;And while Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;first wave of M1-powered computers&lt;/a&gt; have been excellent, they’ve all been — relatively — low-powered. The MacBook Air, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;M1 MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22440059/apple-imac-m1-2021-24-review"&gt;iMac&lt;/a&gt; are the cheapest computers Apple makes, meant more for checking email, writing essays, and the occasional light photo editing than they are for cranking out 4K video or Photoshop projects hundreds of layers deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kGc7pu"&gt;That may be about to change with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;presumed announcement&lt;/a&gt; of new, high-end MacBook Pro models, computers that are rumored to be Apple’s biggest laptop update in years. And new MacBook Pros are an opportunity for the company to get back the professional users that have been underserved and disappointed by the lackluster laptop options that the company has been releasing for several cycles. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GiGuga82ESb5W11HZbajTPY8QeI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/7461807/jbareham_161108_1263_0105.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;James Bareham&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="It3gls"&gt;Apple’s last major redesign for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/14/13616404/apple-macbook-pro-touch-bar-review-2016-13-inch-15-inch-laptop"&gt;MacBook Pro came in 2016&lt;/a&gt; and made several missteps: the stripping away of SD card, HDMI, and USB-A ports (all essential tools for photographers, video editors, musicians, and other professional workers) in favor of exclusively using USB-C. There was the addition of the largely useless Touch Bar instead of reliable function keys. And, of course, the extremely fragile keyboard, which was prone to breaking on contact with dust or debris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQ213a"&gt;Subsequent models have tried to address some of those complaints (Apple finally reverted back to the older style keyboard and added a physical escape key to newer models of the MacBook Pro), but the overall approach of what should be Apple’s most functional devices still focus more on the form. Life as a professional on a Mac has meant dealing with too many dongles, buying new cables, and endlessly hunting around for an SD card adapter just to import files. All while getting processors that are years behind Windows devices, with screens that haven’t meaningfully changed since 2012, on computers that Apple charges a premium. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyk7gX"&gt;And hardcore users have been waiting for a while, especially compared to Apple’s last chip changeover. When &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21295475/apple-mac-processors-arm-silicon-chips-wwdc-2020"&gt;Apple first announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would be transitioning its entire product lineup over to Apple Silicon products in 2020 (and away from the Intel chips that it had used since its last major architecture switch in 2005), it announced a two-year goal of getting all its products switched over. But a year in, and only Apple’s least powerful devices have made the change. If you want a more powerful laptop or desktop, then you’re still getting the old Intel models — models that, while still not on Apple Silicon hardware, also haven’t been updated with new &lt;em&gt;Intel&lt;/em&gt; hardware in over a year and a half either. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The 16-inch MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F2nqxLgoH1jWenTk56aWR8IE3Xw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19395182/vpavic_191118_3800_0077.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hblvj1"&gt;The most powerful 16-inch MacBook Pro you can buy right now — ostensibly Apple’s best and beefiest laptop — features a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/8/17950968/intel-9th-gen-core-chips-2018-desktop-processors-8-core-i9-9900k"&gt;9th-generation Intel Core i7 processor from early 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Mac users aren’t just missing out on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22423545/intel-tiger-lake-h-mobile-processors-11th-gen-laptops"&gt;new 11th Gen Tiger Lake chips announced earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, bringing generational changes in battery life and performance; they didn’t even get the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21203222/intel-10th-gen-h-series-laptop-processors-comet-lake-14nm-5-ghz-clock-speeds-gaming"&gt;more modest upgrades&lt;/a&gt; from Intel’s 2020 10th-gen chips, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FJxb3I"&gt;Compare this whole sluggish Apple Silicon transition to the original Intel one, which happened much more swiftly; Apple announced the change in June 2005, released the first Intel-based Macs in January 2006, and had completely switched over its full product line with the Intel-powered Mac Pro in August 2006 — just eight months later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n2sH5E"&gt;Apple managed to change its entire lineup to Intel in just over a year, from announcement to release, the last time around. But with Apple Silicon, we’re already a year into this transition, and there are still a lot of crucial, unanswered questions. The current M1 chips only offer integrated GPUs, with no discrete graphics options available for more graphically intensive tasks (like those that video editors or graphic designers might need). Apple doesn’t sell an M1 device with more than 16GB of RAM, nor does it offer a laptop with more than two USB4 / Thunderbolt 4 ports — all areas that the company would likely have to address in some fashion on a pro-focused machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5XZas6"&gt;Plus, if Apple does fail at translating the success of its M1 chips to its more powerful machines, Intel is still ready and willing to try and pick up the slack. “I never give up on the idea of anything not running on Intel chips,” commented Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/axios/status/1449891228099694597"&gt;in an interview with Axios&lt;/a&gt;. “Apple decided that they could do a better chip than we could, and they did a pretty good job. So what I have to do is create a better chip than they can do themselves...  I’m gonna fight hard to win Tim [Cook’s] business in this area.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tPsYqp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A year in, and there’s a lot of unanswered questions for professional-level Apple Silicon computers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1eL96N"&gt;There are theoretical benefits to the delay: developers have had a full year to transition their apps over to Apple’s M1 architecture. Things like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176548/microsoft-office-native-m1-apps-apple-silicon-support"&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22584992/adobe-premiere-pro-apple-m1-support"&gt;key creative applications&lt;/a&gt; like Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, and Lightroom have all been natively ported to Apple’s new chips, and those updates took months to roll out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuS6ZX"&gt;Plus, a switch to Apple’s own in-house chips might not just mean the kind of performance and speed boosts that customers have been enjoying on the company’s less powerful machines. It also could mean an end to the glacial pace of upgrades for Mac processors. With Intel chips, Apple’s computers almost universally lagged behind their Windows-based competitors, taking months or even years to upgrade to Intel’s latest chips (and the performance and power benefits that newer silicon provided).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSxEtV"&gt;And if the rumors are correct, Apple is taking the new chips as an opportunity to roll out a new design for its MacBook Pro line, with bigger, better Mini LED displays, smaller bezels, more ports, and even the return of its breakaway magnetic MagSafe chargers — changes that would both modernize the lineup to be more on par with Windows competitors (which have long since lapped Apple in things like display technology) in addition to rolling back some of the more controversial aspects of the Touch Bar era. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="um9Ija"&gt;With the first wave of Apple Silicon Macs, Apple proved it could make the best laptops around for &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; people. But Apple’s new MacBook Pros aren’t just about winning over power users — it’s a chance to prove that Apple Silicon (and the traditionally mobile-focused Arm technology it uses) can not only match but exceed what Intel and AMD have accomplished for years with x86 for high-end use cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S5Ephw"&gt;And if Apple can succeed at that, it won’t just mean better laptops or desktops, but what could be the start of changing how we fundamentally think about designing computers — at least the inside of them — going forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apuU1H"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ZJaLg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725287/apple-macbook-pro-power-user-m1-chips-processors-hardware-refresh-event"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725287/apple-macbook-pro-power-user-m1-chips-processors-hardware-refresh-event</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch Apple’s October ‘Unleashed’ event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vAoo21g2vesfpuBQi45zuAl_5pI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70009811/acstro_190902_apple_event_0005.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5tZSlE"&gt;Apple is hosting its next big hardware event at 10AM PT / 1PM ET. The event is titled “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1447956519132151810"&gt;Unleashed&lt;/a&gt;,” and while we’re not totally sure what Apple will be unleashing, the dotted-font design on the invitation could be a hint at the higher-res &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590004/macbook-air-mini-led-display-apple-silicon-2022-redesign"&gt;Mini LED displays&lt;/a&gt; expected for new MacBook Pros. These new, more powerful MacBook Pros will probably come in 14- and 16-inch screen sizes and may have SD readers, HDMI, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;MagSafe&lt;/a&gt; ports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1FC9o"&gt;And possibly (finally) Apple may release new AirPods as well. It also seems likely we’ll get a release date for macOS Monterey, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;which was announced&lt;/a&gt; at the same time as iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 but remains in beta. The rumor mill also has been predicting the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;end of the Touch Bar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CR1IjE"&gt;WHAT TIME IS THE APPLE “UNLEASHED” EVENT?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="l4kc6b"&gt;You can tune into the livestream, which starts at 10AM PT / 1PM ET on Monday, October 18th. If you miss the livestream, it’s likely you’ll be able to catch a replay after the event wraps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gAIWaj"&gt;WHERE CAN I WATCH IT?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XbxczI"&gt;Apple is hosting the stream on its &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and it is also streaming it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=exM1uajp--A&amp;amp;ab_channel=Apple"&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. The YouTube stream is embedded above for your convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="keBxNR"&gt;Follow &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/verge"&gt;@verge on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dsbJbZ"&gt;Check out our &lt;a href="http://theverge.com"&gt;live blog&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uJ6kUZ"&gt;Keep an eye on &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/verge/"&gt;@verge on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for live updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="cbwsGF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22731401/apple-event-live-stream-time-date-watch-unleashed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22731401/apple-event-live-stream-time-date-watch-unleashed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-17T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-17T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s October ‘Unleashed’ event: what to expect</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple’s event invitation " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oi-uXZIeOn-WK1BMGztkj7lVk2s=/40x0:2026x1324/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70006949/Screen_Shot_2021_10_14_at_9.13.21_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dNYIIT"&gt;Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;announced an event for October 18th&lt;/a&gt;, with a video containing the title “Unleashed.” If you’ve been watching the rumor mill, it won’t come as a surprise — the company still has a lot of products that are expected to come out this year but haven’t shown up in an Apple keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kGTo0P"&gt;Chief among those are new, more powerful MacBook Pros, which will follow the incredible Apple Silicon-powered 13-inch MacBook Pro that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;launched last November&lt;/a&gt;. The company is also expected to release new AirPods, and it’s got an entire OS that was announced but hasn’t shipped. Read on for a deep dive into the rumors surrounding these products and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8GOXLV"&gt;Redesigned MacBook Pros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JOdB06"&gt;Most of the rumors about the event concern redesigned MacBook Pros, which are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;expected to feature 14- and 16-inch screens&lt;/a&gt;, along with a new Apple processor. Mark Gurman and &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/01/15/new-macbook-pro-models-magsafe-ports/"&gt;Ming-Chi Kuo&lt;/a&gt; (who have pretty solid track records when it comes to rumors) have both said that the laptops will feature iPhone 12-esque flat sides with a redesigned MagSafe charging port and that they’ll no longer have the Touch Bar that’s been a staple of many MacBook Pros since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X7XVE4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ports, glorious ports&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yUBXN1"&gt;Apple is also rumored to be bringing ports back to its laptops with the redesign. The new MacBooks Pros may include an SD card reader and HDMI &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;and MagSafe ports&lt;/a&gt;, which will be familiar (and possibly beloved) by people who miss the days when MacBooks had more than one type of port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1IPyTE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-12/apple-set-for-first-macbook-pro-revamp-in-five-years-on-oct-18"&gt;Mark Gurman reports&lt;/a&gt; that the laptops will be powered by new chips, which are expected to be more powerful variants of the M1 processor found in today’s computers. The “M1X” (or M2, or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1448040028832034817"&gt;whatever name Apple actually goes with&lt;/a&gt;) is expected to have more high-performance cores than its predecessor (eight instead of four) and even offer a choice of 16 or 32 graphics cores (compared to the M1’s seven or eight). What’s still unclear is whether the new processor will do away with any of the seeming limitations of the M1: none of the Apple Silicon Macs are configurable with more than 16GB of RAM or 2TB of storage, they can’t run more than two displays, and none of them have more than two Thunderbolt ports (the iMac has at most two Thunderbolt ports and two USB-C ports). Traditionally, the higher-end MacBook Pros have four Thunderbolt ports, though the inclusion of MagSafe and HDMI may make that less necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hi34v1GQ6fbP3rgqAvJmkjaDtJQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22848631/Screen_Shot_2021_09_13_at_5.21.20_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The configuration screen for an Intel-based MacBook Pro. Just having options for graphics cores would be much easier to explain to new buyers than Turbo Boosts and base clocks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZrfJmQ"&gt;If you’re thinking, “Wow, these new computers sound like everything I ever could’ve wanted,” you’re not alone — a lot of people &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless/status/1448073292401815552?s=20"&gt;are hyped about the rumors&lt;/a&gt; (though it’s worth keeping in mind &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676131/apple-2021-rumor-mill-wrong-watch-leaks-airpods"&gt;that those don’t always pan out&lt;/a&gt;). If it turns out that Apple has taken all of the community’s feedback to heart, the chip shortage could make these laptops hot-ticket items for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PcLJiF"&gt;A Pro Mac Mini&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xpSfDk"&gt;Gurman also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637477/new-mac-mini-design-ports-m1x-release-date-gurman"&gt;recently reported&lt;/a&gt; that a more powerful Mac mini would be coming soon, featuring the same processor found in the updated MacBook Pros and more ports than are currently available on the M1-powered Mini. It’s an interesting rumor because the M1 Mini has one of the widest port selections available on an M1 Mac with USB-A, HDMI, two Thunderbolt ports, and optional 10-gigabit ethernet. But the 2018 Intel-based version, which a lot of people think of as the Mac Mini Pro (in part due to its space grey color), has all of that &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; two more Thunderbolt ports. For those looking for a powerful Apple-powered desktop, a replacement for the 2018 Mac Mini could be a great option, given the lack of rumors about a 27-inch iMac.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QY8S1M6eh04Y9-69e2-O4oqQJ9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22925277/Screen_Shot_2021_10_13_at_4.51.17_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple is still selling the Intel-powered 2018 Mac Mini.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zOUVY6"&gt;New AirPods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="chmWak"&gt;Gurman, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/12/kuo-airpods-3-to-be-announced-at-september-event-airpods-2-to-remain-in-the-lineup/"&gt;Kuo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt; have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586507/apple-airpods-2021-refresh-rumor-iphone-se-2022-5g-15-details"&gt;all reported&lt;/a&gt; that Apple is working on a follow-up to its regular, non-Pro AirPods and have said that the headphones will feature the shorter stems found on their more expensive counterparts. It feels like AirPods would’ve fit in better at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"&gt;Apple’s iPhone event&lt;/a&gt;, but given that they were absent, we may end up seeing them on the 18th. There is also always the (hilarious) possibility that Apple just announces them via press release like it did the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20936454/apple-airpods-pro-new-release-date-price-noise-cancellation-design-immersive-sound"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/21438042/apple-max-studio-noise-canceling-headphones-price-date"&gt;Max&lt;/a&gt;, but with how popular the original ones were, it feels like their successors should get some event time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J3Em_kMm_GtLn77cNy7hsc8vIjc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22926861/Screen_Shot_2021_10_14_at_9.29.22_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple announced macOS Monterey in June.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EePdlG"&gt;A macOS Monterey release date&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRQ2vB"&gt;Apple has released iOS and iPadOS 15, but macOS Monterey, which was announced alongside them, is still in beta. It would be a bit strange if Apple released new Macs that were running macOS Big Sur out of the box, especially given that Monterey was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;announced about three months ago at WWDC&lt;/a&gt;. If Apple doesn’t announce that the new version of macOS is shipping with the redesigned MacBook Pros, I’ll be pretty surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/17/22725365/apple-october-macbook-event-unleashed-rumors-pro-airpods"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/17/22725365/apple-october-macbook-event-unleashed-rumors-pro-airpods</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-16T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-16T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A brief chat with the fired #AppleToo organizer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z6gH_pldp31MNJbVlt325SjeG60=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70003556/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uUNI6p"&gt;On October 14th, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727123/apple-fires-leader-apple-too-movement"&gt;fired a leader of the #AppleToo movement&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly failing to comply with an internal investigation. The employee, Janneke Parrish, has been working behind the scenes for months to organize fellow employees who’ve faced harassment and discrimination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mujZpQ"&gt;Now, Apple appears to be cracking down on those efforts — under the guise of trying to stop internal information from leaking to the press. In September, Apple fired Ashley Gjøvik for allegedly violating her confidentiality agreement. Then, it placed software engineer Cher Scarlett on medical leave. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQWGW4"&gt;Both Gjøvik and Scarlett have filed claims with the NLRB. Parrish’s lawyer, Vincent P. White of White, Hilferty and Albanese, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Parrish plans to sue for wrongful termination and will also be filing a charge with the NLRB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLOmo5"&gt;Parrish spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; about her organizing efforts and the circumstances around her termination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hhBFfR"&gt;
&lt;p id="wiYBzL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me what the last few months have been like for you. You started doing internal advocacy with &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432909/apple-petition-hiring-antonio-garcia-martinez-chaos-monkeys-facebook"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the Antonio García Martínez&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;letter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n9xD2s"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Janneke Parrish:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, and that was the first time I really saw employee activism at Apple having an impact. I was already in the remote work advocacy Slack channel at the time, wanting people to be able to make the best decisions for them in regards to how and where they work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PoXJkT"&gt;But with the Antonio García Martínez letter, we saw that activism can be effective — that when we speak up, executives might listen. That led to more letters from the remote work group, asking for flexibility in terms of where we work. But we didn’t get the same response this time — the response was essentially, “We think it would be better to be back in the office.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qOag5Q"&gt;Employee advocacy is incredibly important to help make our voices heard, but there’s a limit to what we can do internally. If you’re speaking to people who don’t want to listen to you, you might as well not be speaking at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I50LGh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you and Cher Scarlett start working together on #AppleToo?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ga1VAc"&gt;While I was doing this work with remote advocacy, Cher was doing work with pay advocacy. We met through needing to advocate for pay equity and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638150/apple-appletoo-employee-harassment-discord"&gt;transitioned it into #AppleToo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTnJak"&gt;I led the employee stories component — telling the stories of workers who’ve been abused and discriminated against, who’ve reached out through the channels Apple tells us to and heard nothing. It’s the story of remote advocacy being told on a macro scale across the entire business — that we are consistently unheard and devalued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JwNQWB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple doesn’t need to know how much money I lost on GameStop.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wVM59P"&gt;I do not know how somebody looks at hundreds of stories like that and does not take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFBYg2"&gt;So I’ve been doing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RxFe7l"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has the impact been? It seems like you haven’t gotten the same pushback internally as Cher and Ashley.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7OPwWQ"&gt;I have received a lot of supportive messages, and no, I haven’t gotten as much criticism. I honestly don’t know why. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XCsT6U"&gt;I’m a program manager. I’m not an engineer, and I’m in a department that doesn’t have the same visibility theirs does. I’m in Maps, and it just doesn’t have the same visibility. I also continue to put myself out of the limelight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0E1v2n"&gt;And I’m in Austin, not California. A lot of Apple’s arguments around coming back to the office are very California-centric and don’t apply to people in Texas. They talk about running into people in the halls — I never run into execs in Austin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5Bb3L"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When did the investigation start?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1FzVHo"&gt;On September 18th, there was a town hall that was live leaked to you. And afterward, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"&gt;Tim Cook sent out a memo&lt;/a&gt; saying we’re disappointed and going to find the leakers. In the wake of that memo, Apple started doing investigations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WYheQe"&gt;On September 30th, I was called into a meeting with HR and global security and told I was being investigated for possibly leaking the meeting. My devices were confiscated, but before they were, I deleted apps with personal information, like Robinhood. Apple doesn’t need to know how much money I lost on GameStop. I work on political campaigns, and Democratic political campaign information has to be kept private. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QbnYEu"&gt;So before turning in the devices, I removed this information. I was given a loaner and asked to continue working, which I did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P5p0Sp"&gt;On October 8th, I was reached out to again by global security and HR, and they said I was being suspended and took the loaner devices and deactivated all my internal accounts. I was in mid-conversation with some people, and then my internal accounts immediately showed “deactivated.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MSsbqu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I believe I was fired in retaliation for speaking out”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C458fa"&gt;Doing this set my work back as well. The very fact that it happened at all — I work in Maps, we work with highly confidential information, and our need to keep stuff secret is vital for our success. So even being investigated, my career on Maps was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdFkzv"&gt;On Thursday, I received a call from global security and HR saying I had been terminated for deleting the files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hvbuT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why was that personal information on your work device in the first place?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hcj7er"&gt;On Maps, we’re encouraged to test out the maps and new features. My particular role was the program manager for tools, so I needed to know our tools behaved correctly. For me, using my work phone as a personal phone gave me a great opportunity to test things in the field, which we are highly encouraged to do. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22648265/apple-employee-privacy-icloud-id"&gt;Apple encourages us to integrate&lt;/a&gt; [our personal and work devices]. When I was first issued the phone, that seemed perfectly legitimate. But in hindsight, it probably was not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ydbDee"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your view on why you were fired?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjioA6"&gt;I believe I was fired in retaliation for speaking out, for my work with #AppleToo, and out of concern that I was organizing to help other employees tell their stories. In my view, this is entirely retaliation for trying to bring Apple’s actions to light and publicly asking the company to do better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBTLRZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is #AppleToo done now that you’ve been fired and Cher is out on medical leave?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LzEsTo"&gt;I absolutely don’t think so. I think seeing that Apple would rather fire an employee for speaking out and asking the company to do better instead of actually &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; better says volumes about the company and its priorities. I hope people see the decision Apple has made and that it is a galvanizing decision. My goal is to make Apple better for everyone. And it seems like Apple is less interested in that than I am. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MVGtAb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vwVyz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/16/22729072/apple-too-organizer-janneke-parrish-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/16/22729072/apple-too-organizer-janneke-parrish-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T19:02:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T19:02:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The watch charger flips up so you can use the Apple Watch in nightstand mode." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P6OOA5yf8u1He-TS4NYA6S22rRU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70002069/dbohn_201109_4283_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QxPh0J"&gt;One year ago yesterday, I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/14/21515490/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-accessories-ecosystem"&gt;how MagSafe could be the biggest reason to buy an iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;. I believed it, too. It looked like Apple had cracked the code to effortlessly accessorize the iPhone and even add modular new capabilities. The company showed its pricey new MagSafe cases and wallets seemingly snapping into place, plus faster wireless charging. The future looked bright. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IzRPOV"&gt;But if you became an early adopter like me, you might have wound up disappointed. As &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1449111887388549126"&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;, two of Apple’s first overpriced MagSafe accessories are already out of date. First, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/15/magsafe-duo-apple-watch-series-7-no-fast-charge/"&gt;we just learned Friday&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s $129 MagSafe Duo Charger can’t fast-charge an Apple Watch Series 7. Second, Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674261/apple-iphone-leather-wallet-magsafe-find-my-tracking"&gt;already replaced the $59 MagSafe Leather Wallet with a better version&lt;/a&gt; that supports Find My so your phone can remember where it was when it got removed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODYxiT"&gt;I think Gurman might actually be undercounting, though. The new Leather Wallet with MagSafe &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t support Apple’s $49 Clear Case with MagSafe, so hope you didn’t buy one of those thinking it’d be futureproof — apparently, it blocks the NFC tags that MagSafe accessories like the Wallet use to passively ID themselves to the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aieFb5"&gt;And while we’re on the subject of cases, &lt;em&gt;every official iPhone 12&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;case&lt;/em&gt; (and likely the vast majority of third-party ones) are incompatible with the iPhone 13 lineup, because the camera bump got wider this time around. I took advantage of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22684911/iphone-13-true-cost-of-free-phone-iphone-13-pro"&gt;those “free” iPhone offers &lt;/a&gt;to upgrade to an iPhone 13 Mini (loving &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22709829/iphone-13-mini-pro-max-battery-tests"&gt;the improved battery life&lt;/a&gt;, by the way), and now I have an expensive but useless Clear Case with MagSafe that I’m not sure what to do with. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/veSIf7yagsYNfzHMXo1A66G1tO4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21958778/iphone_magsafe_gif.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5lxINl"&gt;Those are just the latest disappointments, though. It didn’t take long before iPhone 12 buyers like me discovered that no, Apple’s new cases don’t actually snap into place like they do in the Apple animations I showed you last year (see above and below). They still rely on a rim that grasps the edges of your phone and requires pressure to insert and remove. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FoW1bR2d1LZ27Mtsv47mblNFWzE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21958810/iphone_magsafe_4_gif.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dhjfvk"&gt;Several &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editors have also complained that the $39 MagSafe charging cable doesn’t have a long enough cord to use on the couch or in bed where its quick-detach feature might actually help — but Apple’s still selling the same 1-meter cable a year later. My MagSafe pad now sits unused on a shelf, while I begrudgingly plug in a Lightning cable instead. Meanwhile, both it and the $129 MagSafe Duo still don’t come with charging bricks, even though the previous Apple USB-C chargers you might own (18W and 29W) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169285/apple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible"&gt;aren’t good enough to drive them at full speed&lt;/a&gt;. They require 20W and 30W chargers, respectively, which Apple sells for $19 or $49 each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWq5PO"&gt;And though it took most of a year for Apple to release &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini"&gt;its own MagSafe Battery Pack&lt;/a&gt;, we were underwhelmed by its capacity in our review. I bought and returned one myself, though not for any of the reasons Dieter laid out. I just couldn’t stand how weak the vertical magnet was even with Apple’s own Clear Case, the pack always twisting in my hand. (Without the case, it made my iPhone 12 Mini uncomfortably warm to hold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qry9ui"&gt;Every one of these examples speaks to a lack of foresight around MagSafe, and that’s unusual. Foresight is generally one of Apple’s strengths, bringing out new products and technologies only when their time has come. But to me, the real tragedy of MagSafe’s first year is the lack of a larger ecosystem. The entire time we’ve been waiting for Apple to show us what MagSafe is truly capable of, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;it’s been keeping the rest of the world from getting out ahead&lt;/a&gt; — using its MFi program and artificial charging restrictions built into the iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dc0B0S"&gt;Combining the Qi wireless charging standard with non-patentable magnets, MagSafe should have been a lightning rod to customization and modularity. So far, Apple has insulated itself — and us — from the possibilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dryAbs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"},{"title":"The Lightning port isn’t about convenience; it’s about control","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22690338/apple-iphone-lightning-ports-convenience-control-usb-c-eu-wireless-charging-mfi-magsafe"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T13:43:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T13:43:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple removed a popular Quran app in China</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fr6SfD1_9WZ82v4l6sH0JHOyxoI=/180x0:2574x1596/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70000499/Screen_Shot_2021_10_15_at_10.07.21_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Pakistan Data Management Services&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N1lmKj"&gt;Apple has removed &lt;a href="https://quranmajeed.app/"&gt;Quran Majeed&lt;/a&gt;, a popular app for reading and listening to the Quran, from the App Store in China, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-58921230"&gt;the BBC reports&lt;/a&gt;. The company reportedly removed the app at the request of government officials, a somewhat surprising move given Islam is a protected religion in the People’s Republic of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVvcIw"&gt;Quran Majeed is available for free and “recognized by 25 million Muslim users around the world” &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id365557665"&gt;according to the app’s developer&lt;/a&gt; Pakistan Data Management Services. The app’s removal apparently had nothing to do with its religious content, “according to Apple, our app Quran Majeed has been removed from the China App Store because it includes content that is illegal,” the developer told the BBC. The developer says it’s now attempting to resolve the issue with China’s Cyberspace Administration. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to both Apple and China’s US Embassy for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cGVML3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How China complicates Apple’s chest-thumping about privacy ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/25/18020508/how-china-complicates-apples-chest-thumping-about-privacy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="TcFlQv"&gt;Without clearer explanation, the move seems like a possible overreach, though it does fall within &lt;a href="https://s2.q4cdn.com/470004039/files/doc_downloads/gov_docs/Apple-Human-Rights-Policy.pdf"&gt;Apple’s official stance on human rights abroad (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="HC0Pmo"&gt;We’re required to comply with local laws, and at times there are complex issues about which we may disagree with governments and other stakeholders on the right path forward. With dialogue, and a belief in the power of engagement, we try to find the solution that best serves our users—their privacy, their ability to express themselves, and their access to reliable information and helpful technology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="k2v4Kb"&gt;While it’s logical for business, that framing has placed the company in questionable positions before. Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/29/technology/china-apple-censorhip.html"&gt;removed VPN apps&lt;/a&gt; that allowed Chinese users to avoid censorship and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/17/technology/apple-china-privacy-censorship.html"&gt;proactively filtered out apps&lt;/a&gt; that mentioned Tiananmen Square, the Dalai Lama, or Taiwanese and Tibetan independence. Apple’s suppliers in the region &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22428899/apple-suppliers-china-uyghur-forced-labor-report"&gt;have also been connected&lt;/a&gt; to the oppression of China’s predominantly Muslim Uyghur minority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5wah6"&gt;Apple is in a difficult situation either way. It relies on the business relationships and sales it makes in China. Taking a strong stance against the government could put that in jeopardy. Just this week, Microsoft made the decision &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726189/microsoft-linkedin-china-censorship-shut-down"&gt;to shut down the local Chinese version of LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, acknowledging separately that it is becoming increasingly difficult to comply with the Chinese government’s demands. Apple hasn’t yet found that line for itself, and with how much it relies on China to make its iPhone business work, it might not happen anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728257/apple-quran-majeed-app-removed-china"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728257/apple-quran-majeed-app-removed-china</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T11:48:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T11:48:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple fired a leader of the #AppleToo movement</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MsR1rRZa5V1NA66eGMooeWmxaQA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999823/acastro_210429_1777_epicApple_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wmn5zY"&gt;Apple has fired Janneke Parrish, a leader of the #AppleToo movement, amid a broad crackdown on leaks and worker organizing. Parrish, a program manager on Apple Maps, was terminated for deleting files off of her work devices during an internal investigation — an action Apple categorized as “non-compliance,” according to people familiar with the situation. The files included apps like Robinhood, Pokémon GO, and Google Drive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ZWZrT"&gt;Internally, some employees expressed disbelief that Parrish’s firing could be anything other than retaliation for organizing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DJxKT"&gt;It’s the second time in recent months that an employee has been terminated after speaking out about Apple’s company culture. In September, the tech giant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22666049/apple-fires-senior-engineering-program-manager-ashley-gjovik-for-allegedly-leaking-information"&gt;fired Ashley Gjøvik &lt;/a&gt;for allegedly leaking confidential information. Gjøvik has filed multiple charges with the NLRB related to how Apple treated her and the broader workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KoDODk"&gt;Gjøvik’s latest charge alleges that &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-12/apple-ceo-s-anti-leak-edict-broke-the-law-ex-employee-alleges?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;Tim Cook’s anti-leaking memo might violate US labor law&lt;/a&gt;. In September, the CEO sent a note to all Apple employees saying that “people who leak confidential information do not belong” at Apple. He also said the company was doing “everything in our power to identify those who leaked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66nB9c"&gt;The comments were related to an all-hands meeting on September 17th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"&gt;which leaked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qg3J4K"&gt;Apple’s recent actions seem designed to chill worker organizing. In August, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638150/apple-appletoo-employee-harassment-discord"&gt;employees launched the #AppleToo website&lt;/a&gt; to allow workers across the company — including AppleCare and retail — to submit stories about workplace harassment and discrimination. Parrish and Cher Scarlett, an Apple software engineer, then began &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@UrsulaRa"&gt;sharing these stories on Medium&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g7nECa"&gt;Parrish declined to comment for this story. Her attorney, Vincent P. White of White, Hilferty and Albanese, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge:&lt;/em&gt; “We can confirm she is no longer with Apple but cannot speak further to address the situation at this time.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YacI3p"&gt;Scarlett is &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/14/apple-worker-cher-scarlett/"&gt;currently on paid medical leave&lt;/a&gt; due to internal harassment she’s received while advocating for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22491629/apple-employees-push-back-return-office-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;remote work&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity"&gt;pay transparency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O6l1JD"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727123/apple-fires-leader-apple-too-movement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727123/apple-fires-leader-apple-too-movement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:43:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:43:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use iOS 15’s new Focus modes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dpkQp-pUcc5TNGEA14QrcPezeJA=/0x0:700x467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999461/ios15_iphone12_pro_settings_focus_crop__1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EUGjjn"&gt;These days, it is way too easy to be pulled from your work by notifications and other distractions. In order to help you keep your attention where you want it, Apple has added new Focus features to iOS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1bBad"&gt;The idea is to keep you “in the moment” by filtering out apps or notifications that you don’t want popping up during specific times. The nice thing is that you can create different profiles to keep you from being disturbed, depending on whether you’re at home, at work, getting ready for bed, driving, or for any other activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h134kI"&gt;When you first start to set Focus up, it can seem a little daunting. There are a lot of choices, and a lot of ways you can tweak it. In fact, it may take a while before you get the combination of settings that works best for your lifestyle. But in the end, it will be worth it — it will mean that you won’t be sidelined during times you need to concentrate, and you won’t be bothered by irrelevant notifications when you’ve got other activities in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You’ll find your new Focus button in the Control Center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fqKUrOXcxaTA1c1p2DPG0B19mCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929129/IMG_2E41D6D8A9B5_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll find your new Focus button in the Control Center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on Focus, and you’ll see all your various profiles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rl5IDdE5v4QvQ4Ma02QaTzhVCBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929128/IMG_C5F6B766D9B7_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on Focus, and you’ll see all your various profiles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ho2e9P"&gt;Begin to focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eF8B9R"&gt;You access Focus mode via your Control Center (swipe down from the upper right corner). You’ll see the Focus button with a moon icon next to it. If you tap the icon, then the main Do Not Disturb profile will be active. If you tap anywhere else in the button, you’ll see a selection of other profiles that you can activate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jQRtvY"&gt;Tap on the three dots to the right of each button, and you can set the length of time you want that Focus profile to be active. Or you can tap the Settings button to tweak the settings for that Focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWvVZu"&gt;But perhaps the best way to start is to go to Settings &amp;gt; Focus, where you can set up all the various Focus profiles you are planning to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="V15dui"&gt;Set up your profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2FOIon"&gt;When you first open the Focus page in your settings, you’ll see a list of several profiles, starting with the basic Do Not Disturb and then going on to Personal, Sleep, and Work. If you tap on the plus sign in the upper right corner of the screen, you’ll find the others, including Driving, Fitness, Gaming, Mindfulness, and Readings. If none of those suit, you  can create a custom profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnxcpV"&gt;In addition, there is a toggle that lets you can share the profiles across your various Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzsXlc"&gt;We’ll look at some of the profiles in a moment, but let’s start by tapping on Do Not Disturb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The main Focus page lets you set up a variety of profiles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hqdOC1YwPCOLESS0988eW6n5CQE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929013/IMG_42A19892FE43_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The main Focus page lets you set up a variety of profiles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The initial Do Not Disturb profile offers a basic template." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZPj2xJKtdw0Ss8ckp20CEX2-DS4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929035/IMG_917D02D42034_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The initial Do Not Disturb profile offers a basic template.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FIYrZd"&gt;Do Not Disturb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="21ARpr"&gt;The first thing you’ll see on top of the Do Not Disturb page (and, in fact, on top of all the profile pages) is the toggle to turn the mode on and off. After that, there are a variety of filters that you can tweak to determine when and how Focus will be set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l6AgJT"&gt;Allowed notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JafgFu"&gt;Focus lets you specify people or apps that can continue to notify you even if you have Do Not Disturb active. For example, you may want to allow calls to come in from family members, or notifications from your work Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FV9dc"&gt;To make these exceptions, tap on the People or Apps box to get to the Allowed Notifications page. (It doesn’t really matter which you tap; you’ll end up on the same page.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can allow specific apps to continuing notifying you during Focus times." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sEQxI-DYvD0_AMxW9F-grctJC9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929036/IMG_12BD6DF55162_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can allow specific apps to continuing notifying you during Focus times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on the plus sign and you get a list of apps to choose from." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/49kc4VfarFcKI73BMb04EpaMdpY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929037/IMG_698503BFB14C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on the plus sign and you get a list of apps to choose from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id="GkJBIZ"&gt;Allowed apps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="zPsxL8"&gt;If you’re choosing one or more apps, then tap the App tab and then the plus button. You’ll get a list of your installed apps; check off those you want to add to the Allowed Notifications list, and select Done at the top right of the page. You’ll now see your chosen apps listed under Allowed Apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="poPpBl"&gt;If you change your mind for any of your apps, you can just tap the minus sign next to each icon or select the “Remove All” link on the upper right of the Allowed Apps section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RHtNdN"&gt;You can also allow Time Sensitive notifications to come through by toggling it on. Time  Sensitive notifications are from apps you’ve individually tagged as important enough to break through any filter, no matter what. To select which apps are that important to you, you have to leave Focus and go to Settings &amp;gt; Notifications; select the app or apps you want to qualify — say, Calendar — and make sure Time Sensitive notifications is toggled on for that app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can also select which people can still contact you." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p2aIH9ToanE_9iOj1t68um-wDGI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929042/IMG_092F5ED1AB24_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also select which people can still contact you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap “Calls From” to choose general categories of contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SUhzR5d2dv_4o12ZaWz4KYlDboA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929044/IMG_4EC82D8508B0_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap “Calls From” to choose general categories of contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id="4o02dF"&gt;Allowed people&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="tjHRzU"&gt;The way you allow notifications from specific people to break through the set Focus mode is pretty much the same as with the apps: select the plus sign under the People tab to add from your list of contacts. You can also allow incoming calls from various categories of people: either everyone who calls, no one (if you really want not to be disturbed), people who are tagged as favorites, or anyone in your contact list. You can also allow through any calls that are repeated within three minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ym6FGI"&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pXCwk4"&gt;There are also a variety of other options. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2WPEQX"&gt;You can choose to share your focus status — so if somebody texts you, they will get a display saying that you have notifications silenced. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JvSCV9"&gt;You can hide notifications from your homescreen pages or your lock screen. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AdypEo"&gt;You can have only specific homescreens be active during certain times of the day — for example, you can put all your gaming apps on one homescreen, and keep that screen hidden when you’re at work. To do that, tap on the Home Screen button in your profile, toggle on Custom Pages, and then choose which page or pages you want to be available when that profile is active. (Pro tip: to hide those custom extra homescreens when you’re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in a Focus mode, long-press on your homescreen to put it in editing mode, then tap the dots at the bottom. Uncheck the screens you don’t want to show.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="From the profile’s main screen, select Home Screen and then toggle on Custom Pages." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fySmiX4tfuvb0YJwuvuZKwWO_pE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929209/IMG_09CF86ED709C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the profile’s main screen, select Home Screen and then toggle on Custom Pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uhqUZnABBt0X2pxhJli2CyvfUaM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929210/IMG_F356B3B5F40F_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can then choose which screens you want available when the profile is active.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="I9svS1"&gt;You can arrange to have the focus mode turn on automatically during specific times and on specific days — for example, from 9AM to 5PM on weekdays. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oSnWz5"&gt;You can even — and this is really nice — arrange to have it activate when you are at specific locations or when you’re using specific apps by selecting “Add Schedule or Automation” at the bottom of the mode settings page. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="“Add Schedule or Automation” brings you to a page where you can arrange for Focus to automatically start." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5GTcZYkDbTsvm80u2zz9vXOJclk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929026/IMG_675B90AF3D63_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Add Schedule or Automation” brings you to a page where you can arrange for Focus to automatically start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="For example, you can have a Focus profile automatically start when you are at a specific location." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bAnKcuSxlDLTKLXlH-KxtGKC63E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929028/IMG_F33D365A26CE_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For example, you can have a Focus profile automatically start when you are at a specific location.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XBnb8F"&gt;That brings you to the New Automation page where, for example, you can have it activate whenever you’re at work, or when you’re watching a Netflix video. And if this is something that happens often — for example, when you go to work or read in the evenings — activate Smart Activation, which will (hopefully) learn your habits and turn on Do Not Disturb when you need it. (If it gets things wrong, you can always turn it off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q0BLRx"&gt;Focus profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OOCtg7"&gt;In order to use the profiles, you need to set them up to fit your needs. I listed the ones available at the beginning of this article; in order to get used to them, let’s try setting up two: Personal and Driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOHqUO"&gt;When you tap on a profile that has not yet been set up, you are presented with a set of screens that walk you through the initial processing, including which people and apps should be allowed to notify you when the Focus is active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The preset Focus profiles use wizards to help you start using them." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DItlkXxSgopkn8OgxDK1vmqmqeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929022/IMG_D59C1674EB50_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The preset Focus profiles use wizards to help you start using them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="After the initial setup, you can continue to filter each profile." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v5xPrDVIP-F7vLzxVVPf5ZJPEbw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929023/IMG_CB5C5AB66007_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the initial setup, you can continue to filter each profile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7R325M"&gt;After that, you are dropped into the Focus page for that profile, which will be similar to the Do Not Disturb setup described above. In Personal, you can not only tweak the allowed notifications but decide whether you want to share your Focus status, hide the notifications on your homescreen or lock screen, or create an automation that will turn it on and off at a certain time, in a certain place, or with a certain app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zlrFO6"&gt;Some of the other presets are more specific. For example, when I created a Focus for driving, the opening page of the wizard told me that it was silencing alerts and notifications while I was driving; that it would turn on automatically when I was driving; and that it would arrange auto-reply to let people know why I wasn’t responding to notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Profiles such as “Driving” offer specialized filters." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RE2ZL_O7aPofaUdH2GCZjeiYxXc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929018/IMG_06093F59A446_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Profiles such as “Driving” offer specialized filters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can decide what will cause the profile to automatically start." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/acMGfIxQ6X6xhTu0OLaQ0DduTn0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929020/IMG_0ABB49FDE07B_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can decide what will cause the profile to automatically start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="svlOjw"&gt;And the Driving Focus page had a few differences as well. Allowed notifications include people but not apps (under the assumption that you’re not playing with apps while you’re at the wheel). There is an auto-reply option that lets you edit the message that will be sent to people who try to contact you while the Focus is on. And you can choose how the app will know you’re driving: automatically (based on detected motion), if the CarPlay app is activated, if the phone is connected to a car’s Bluetooth, or when you turn it on manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nyeg1"&gt;If none of the presets work for you, you can create a custom profile by tapping on the plus sign in the upper right corner of the main Focus screen and choosing Custom. You will be asked to name your new profile and to choose a color and icon to represent it.  After that, the process is pretty much the same as for Personal, except that you can also tweak the name and appearance of the Focus in the profile’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UEUvja"&gt;So what next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Nu0Ltz"&gt;Now, when you tap the Focus icon in your Control Center, it will activate all the various features you’ve created for your profile. Note that the last profile that was active will be the one that is featured: for example, if you last used your Driving profile, the Focus button will have the car icon. Touch the icon to active it, or touch the word Focus to switch to a different profile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5qtBR"&gt;The new Focus app in iOS 15 can be very useful by helping you concentrate when you need to, by letting you relax when you want to, by keeping unwanted calls and texts from waking you at night, and by keeping you safe from distractions when driving. It may take a while to figure out which profiles you want to set up, and to discovering what combination of factors works for you. But once you’ve got it working, Focus can really make things easier for you.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22726456/ios-15-iphone-focus-distractions-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22726456/ios-15-iphone-focus-distractions-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T19:08:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T19:08:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple rehires former HomePod engineer to get its software back on track</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/erYLoVBkWHmT94b0ghPPceTy_wc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69997107/jbareham_180202_2266_0089.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sheL58"&gt;Apple has hired a former HomePod engineer, Afrooz Family, to head up the team developing HomePod software, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-14/apple-hires-new-homepod-software-head-as-it-takes-on-amazon-echo?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which could signal a renewed effort from Apple to make the HomePod more competitive. The company released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679870/new-apple-homekit-features-homepod-mini"&gt;HomePod software version 15&lt;/a&gt; in September, bringing some welcome features like the ability to use one or a pair of HomePod Mini speakers as the default with an Apple TV 4K. But Apple’s smart speaker line faces stiff competition, particularly from Amazon’s and Google’s speakers that are equipped with their smart assistants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HPl4RF"&gt;Family left Apple in 2016, where he was a senior audio engineer, to co-found audio company &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsyngspace.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F14%2F22727249%2Fapple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Syng&lt;/a&gt; with ex-Apple designer Christopher Stringer. (A &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; article about Syng described Family as the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b4a88a13-47c3-4bb4-a627-704fdf0c392b"&gt;“secret weapon.”&lt;/a&gt;) Syng’s claim to fame is its Cell Alpha connected speaker, which offers spatial audio in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439925/syng-cell-alpha-wi-fi-speaker-apple-designer-death-star-triphonic"&gt;Death Star-like design&lt;/a&gt;, but it comes with a steep $1,799 price tag. Family left Syng earlier this year, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWEIYP"&gt;The first HomePod, which was released in 2018, was lauded for its sound quality but was criticized for its high price, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328436/apple-discontinues-original-homepod-mini"&gt;Apple discontinued it in March&lt;/a&gt;. The company released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;cheaper and smaller HomePod Mini last year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TJsjrv"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727249/apple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727249/apple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
