<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-22T12:30:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T12:30:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T12:30:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple won’t let Fortnite back on iOS until the Epic v. Apple verdict is final</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tcsPFKxn9iPAteYcqQizaLx-4F8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69893640/acastro_210429_1777_epic_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YVZADu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; will not be returning to the iOS App Store anytime soon, according to a series of emails &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1440711772483186690"&gt;published on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday by Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WmQeCW"&gt;Epic’s iOS developer account had been suspended as a result of company’s intentional violations of the App Store guidelines in August 2020, which set the stage for the companies’ court battle. But in the wake of the ruling earlier this month, the state of Epic’s iOS apps — particularly &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; — has been unclear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XfAoi4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple lied,” says Epic CEO&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ui7pQh"&gt;But the newly published emails indicate Epic is unlikely to return to the store for the immediate future. One letter published by Sweeney — dated September 21st and sent by lawyers representing Apple — informs the company that Apple will not reinstate Epic’s developer account until the appeals have been resolved, a process that could take years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxmgQT"&gt;“Apple has exercised its discretion not to reinstate Epic’s developer program account at this time,” the email reads. “Furthermore, Apple will not consider any further requests for reinstatement until the district court’s judgment becomes final and non-appealable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z88lak"&gt;The message notes that Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers, the judge in &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;, concluded Apple was within its rights to terminate any Epic-related accounts it desires from the App Store. Epic has already paid financial damages for breaching its contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oEzEXJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Without a working developer account, Epic can’t re-release Fortnite&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3fGLng"&gt;The appeals path for &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; is still in flux. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22670269/epic-files-appeal-fortnite-legal-battle"&gt;Epic has appealed&lt;/a&gt; the portions of the ruling it lost, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671736/epic-apple-fortnite-antitrust-case-ruling-appeal-decision"&gt;Apple has stated&lt;/a&gt; that it’s still considering its options. Apple CEO Tim Cook, however, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679724/tim-cook-epic-apple-antitrust-ruling-employee-meeting"&gt;told employees that&lt;/a&gt; he was “looking forward to moving forward” after the ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6pBPok"&gt;Writing on Twitter, Sweeney framed Apple’s refusal as a betrayal of its earlier pledge to reinstate Epic Games once the company assented to follow the App Store guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PghslO"&gt;“Apple lied,” Sweeney wrote. “Apple spent a year telling the world, the court, and the press they’d ‘welcome Epic’s return to the App Store if they agree to play by the same rules as everyone else.’ Epic agreed, and now Apple has reneged in another abuse of its monopoly power over a billion users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lUrBBg"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QOXhPu"&gt;The decision appears to scuttle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666146/apple-epic-korea-fortnite-developer-account-rules-response"&gt;Epic’s attempt to return&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; to the iOS App Store in South Korea, which recently passed rules requiring alternate payment method support. It also leaves &lt;em&gt;Fortnite’s&lt;/em&gt; future elsewhere in question. Epic had recently &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/imgoldenyt/status/1437493375297589248"&gt;updated old copies of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on iOS remotely to remove V-Bucks purchasing options, theoretically putting it back in compliance with Apple’s rules. But without a working developer account, Epic can’t re-release the game in any country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1A1xf"&gt;Still, the decision to publish the emails publicly shows that Sweeney is eager to keep pressure on Apple, even if it means keeping Fortnite off of iPhones. “We’ll fight on,” said Sweeney on Twitter. “The need for regulatory and legislative action is clearer than ever before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DXcevG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Late last night, Apple informed Epic that Fortnite will be blacklisted from the Apple ecosystem until the exhaustion of all court appeals, which could be as long as a 5-year process. &lt;a href="https://t.co/QCD7wogJef"&gt;pic.twitter.com/QCD7wogJef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1440711772483186690?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 22, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="18HJQj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687968/fortnite-ios-epic-apple-appeal-verdict-antitrust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687968/fortnite-ios-epic-apple-appeal-verdict-antitrust</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T10:37:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T10:37:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tim Cook says employees who leak memos do not belong at Apple, according to leaked memo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/41Opj4xCjC4g9vz69eJeot9F-nk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69893014/acastro_170731_1777_0001_v10.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9jxnEY"&gt;Tim Cook sent an email to Apple employees Tuesday evening about an all-hands meeting that leaked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week. He said the company is doing “everything in our power to identify those who leaked” and noted that “people who leak confidential information do not belong” at Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jyp52w"&gt;On September 17th, Tim Cook announced during an internal company-wide meeting that Apple would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679772/apple-vaccine-policy-covid-19-testing-unvaccinated"&gt;requiring frequent testing for unvaccinated employees&lt;/a&gt; — but was stopping short of a vaccine mandate. He also said that he was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679724/tim-cook-epic-apple-antitrust-ruling-employee-meeting"&gt;“looking forward to moving forward”&lt;/a&gt; after the Epic v. Apple antitrust case. Shortly after the meeting, both pieces of news leaked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyulCs"&gt;Now, Cook is tying the news to product leaks — which the company has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22601564/apple-leak-phone-cases-cease-and-desist-trade-secrets"&gt;historically gone to great lengths to track down&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AL0ZSS"&gt;Read the full transcription of Cook’s email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ouaDaK"&gt;Dear Team,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yKTVeL"&gt;It was great to connect with you at the global employee meeting on Friday. There was much to celebrate, from our remarkable new product line-up to our values driven work around climate change, racial equity, and privacy. It was a good opportunity to reflect on our many accomplishments and to have a discussion about what’s been on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dH1oP9"&gt;I’m writing today because I’ve heard from so many of you were were incredibly frustrated to see the contents of the meeting leak to reporters. This comes after a product launch in which most of the details of our announcements were also leaked to the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4hDqzA"&gt;I want you to know that I share your frustration. These opportunities to connect as a team are really important. But they only work if we can trust that the content will stay within Apple. I want to reassure you that we are doing everything in our power to identify those who leaked. As you know, we do not tolerate disclosures of confidential information, whether it’s product IP or the details of a confidential meeting. We know that the leakers constitute a small number of people. We also know that people who leak confidential information do not belong here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZuzat"&gt;As we look forward, I want to thank you for all you’ve done to make our products a reality and all you will do to get them into customers’ hands. Yesterday we released iOS 15, iPadOS 15, and watchOS 8, and Friday marks the moment when we share some of our incredible new products with the world. There’s nothing better than that. We’ll continue to measure our contributions in the lives we change, the connections we foster, and the work we do to leave the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gYdPUg"&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVUzUt"&gt;Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T23:34:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T23:34:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 15.1’s first beta suggests we could see SharePlay soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YnyT9jGz12swQUpHyi1jxKduWE=/13x0:2032x1346/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69891587/D3743FFE_9B62_4074_ADC3_50C2232BB74A.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h4zR8p"&gt;SharePlay has returned in the iOS 15.1 beta, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/21/ios-15-1-beta-1-re-enables-shareplay-feature-following-delay/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629165/apple-shareplay-ios-ipad-os-15-macos-delayed"&gt;Apple delayed the major iOS 15 feature&lt;/a&gt; to “later this fall” instead of having it launch alongside the OS upgrade as planned. It’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684483/ios-15-announced-features-shareplay-airpods-universal-control"&gt;not the only feature&lt;/a&gt; that’s hasn’t made it to release yet, but it could be a useful one during the ongoing pandemic — it lets you watch videos, screen share, or listen to music with other people over a FaceTime call. Its existence in Tuesday’s new beta could indicate that it could be coming sooner than later, though that’s not a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VIWUKs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/21/ios-15-vaccine-card-wallet-app/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the 15.1 beta also lets users add their COVID vaccine card to the Wallet app, once you’ve first added it to Health. Similar to how &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22558245/google-pay-covid-vaccination-card-android-digital-pass"&gt;Google’s version of this feature works&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have to get your vaccine info from your medical provider or your state’s healthcare system before you can add it to your phone. &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=7h3vwlh5"&gt;Apple says&lt;/a&gt; the feature uses the SMART Health Card format, which is currently &lt;a href="https://www.commontrustnetwork.org/verifier-list"&gt;supported by a handful of states and some major vaccination providers&lt;/a&gt;. The list includes states like California, Hawaii, New York, and Louisiana, as well as pharmacy providers like CVS, Rite Aid, and Walmart, but you can click the link for the full details. As always, check with your local healthcare provider for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rBb0fAMdqijdEosAZ6EFa_PFPzo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22868514/2048.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can add verified vaccine records from certain health providers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gO6R9t"&gt;These features showing up in the iOS 15.1 beta don’t necessarily mean they’ll be in the final iOS 15.1 release — after all, SharePlay was introduced during the iOS 15 beta, but was later removed. However, Apple &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fios%2Fios-15%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F21%2F22686897%2Fios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;does still say&lt;/a&gt; that SharePlay will ship “later this fall,” and there’s only so much time left for that (plus, it would be a bit odd if it was removed from &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; beta). The vaccine card feature will be included in an “upcoming software update,” according to the company, so it’s possible it’s further out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdzwDB"&gt;It also may be a bit before we see iOS 15.1, given that iOS 15 was just released yesterday (iOS 14.1 &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201222"&gt;came about a month after&lt;/a&gt; iOS 14). But if this early beta is any indication, it could be bringing some nice new features with it when it does show up. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T16:11:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T16:11:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to get iOS 15 right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k4621G9VcG1A83UwdytSuZtJWvI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890176/cgartenberg_210917_4762_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MvuWwU"&gt;iOS 15 is finally here, and while it can’t be called a revolutionary update, there are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;enough cool new features&lt;/a&gt; that you may not want to wait until Apple notifies you that the update is ready. It’s easy enough to get the update without waiting, though. Here’s what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="JN0zOp"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22673693/iphone-apple-backup-ios-icloud"&gt;Your phone is backed up&lt;/a&gt;, right? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mdmYBQ"&gt;Go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “General” &amp;gt; “Software Update.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7duHTw"&gt;Give it a moment. If the update is ready for you, it may appear on your update screen. In that case, tap on “Install Now.” You’ll probably be asked for your passcode and will have to agree to Apple’s “Terms and Conditions.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Your update to iOS 15 may be waiting for you." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NwBlhb7wPAfb-e43zShyRdsfrgk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867904/IMG_0B14C4232371_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your update to iOS 15 may be waiting for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You’ll have to agree to Apple’s “Terms and Conditions.” " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mqhwew1GrHnrbZIA-mooQyPfI3Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867905/IMG_A3F1E73A0B91_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll have to agree to Apple’s “Terms and Conditions.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="elnD7Z"&gt;If you don’t see the update, look toward the bottom and tap on “Upgrade to iOS 15” &amp;gt; “Download and Install.” (The latter may appear automatically.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BUQygG"&gt;Type in your passcode if prompted, agree to those “Terms and Conditions,” and wait while the upload begins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="OK6qhj"&gt;It will take a while to update your iPhone. So put the phone down, go do something relaxing, and then come back in a little while to your brand new OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="8sY8Xy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 review: foundational fixes","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22686505/ios-15-apple-iphone-how-to-install-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22686505/ios-15-apple-iphone-how-to-install-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T14:51:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T14:51:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple updates macOS Safari with a new look, but you can turn off the big changes  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ClwxmS1tx6h35I4zaLj-NSLsmnU=/72x0:3033x1974/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889701/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_10.13.17_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f7yYKY"&gt;Apple has released a redesigned version of Safari for macOS Big Sur and Catalina. The update, announced as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;the upcoming macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt;, was released the same day as iOS and iPadOS 15, bringing the web browser’s new look and features across Apple’s platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhGyTy"&gt;To update to the new Safari 15, you can go to System Preferences &amp;gt; Software Update, where it should automatically refresh and show up. Unlike updates to macOS, you shouldn’t have to reboot your computer after updating Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ifbP7h"&gt;The development behind this version of Safari has been interesting. The full OS update that it was originally a part of, which also brings features like Universal Control and Quick Notes, isn’t here yet, but Apple decided to ship the new Safari anyway. For those who have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;upgraded to iOS 15&lt;/a&gt;, that’s a good thing — it means that you can immediately use tab groups across all your devices. The update &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmacos%2Fmonterey-preview%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F21%2F22686070%2Fapple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;also includes features&lt;/a&gt; like better tracking protection and automatic switching to HTTPS for sites that support it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K1ya7BytHYBoR43IHnYVerGzVSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867613/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.13.23_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s original vision for Safari 15, which has been toned down slightly over the beta period.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pPxAad"&gt;While the Safari update brings new features, it also brings a new design. Apple’s made several changes to it since it was announced (though not as many as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629183/ios-15-beta-safar-address-bar-fix-options-accessible-controls"&gt;it’s made to Safari for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;), tweaking it to be less starkly minimal. Looks-wise, it’s still a major change from Safari 14, but there are preferences that you can tweak to walk back some of the more distracting changes. If you don’t want websites to be able to change the color of your tab bar, you can go to Safari’s preferences &amp;gt; Tabs, and uncheck “Show color in tab bar.” If you want your tabs to be on their own row, you can switch from Compact mode to Separate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7gw4O1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10765531"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5BhnTyGRWTeUiCyHZHXIlGTEjqs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867568/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.50.16_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “I prefer the old Safari” config.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CBUpAT"&gt;Unchecking “Automatically collapse tab titles into icons” turns the tab bar into a sort of carousel when you have too many of them. I certainly don’t prefer it, but it’s an option if that’s your sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qhpaRgyCNx2coIns0bGV37hs-JM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867576/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.52.35_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unchecking the “automatically collapse tab titles” box hides the true chaos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ux5zvl"&gt;While Safari 15 takes a bit to get used to (I'm still getting over the learning curve myself), Tab Groups is a great feature to share between my iPhone and computer. Safari 15 also comes with the &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212816"&gt;usual host of security updates&lt;/a&gt;, though none seem too severe. After you update, be sure to let us know what you think of the new design — is it a breath of fresh air or just another refresh that you’ll grudgingly get used to?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T11:34:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T11:34:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s how the $329 iPad compares to its last-gen predecessor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M7RUpi_d1NvC6dms8FN9DTfueyo=/35x0:1925x1260/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69888574/Apple_iPad_10_2_inch_Ninth_Gen_09142021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new iPad launches on September 24th at the same starting price as the last-gen model: $329.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eFnM4H"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt; isn’t the only Apple device launching on September 24th — and we’re not just talking about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667216/ipad-mini-6-price-specs-release-date-features-apple"&gt;2021 iPad Mini&lt;/a&gt;. The company also announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672438/ipad-2021-new-price-specs-release-date-apple-a13-chip"&gt;new entry-level iPad&lt;/a&gt; during its recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"&gt;“California Streaming” event&lt;/a&gt;, which comes outfitted with a new front-facing camera, a faster processor, and double the base storage. But are the improvements enough to justify an upgrade from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;last year’s iPad&lt;/a&gt;, or even picking it over its predecessor should you find the 2020 model on sale? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FOtWRe"&gt;To answer those questions, we’ve put together a comparison outlining the similarities and differences between the 2020 iPad and the forthcoming model, ahead of our official review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="q5ZEcA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how the new iPad Mini compares to the last-gen model","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22677944/apple-ipad-mini-2019-vs-2021-comparison-upgrade-worthwhile"},{"title":"The Apple rumors were wrong","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676131/apple-2021-rumor-mill-wrong-watch-leaks-airpods"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XZ_LWLoLuu5J6bEtDlAoP8QPgW4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859056/Apple_iPad_10_2_inch_Connect_09142021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iPad features a 12MP front camera, which should allow for improved visuals during calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bRdkia"&gt;What’s improved on the 2021 iPad?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="TjCqm6"&gt;A 12MP ultrawide front-facing camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zXb2Or"&gt;Greater storage capacity, with base storage starting at 64GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z6T2vb"&gt;The A13 Bionic chip, replacing the A12 Bionic from 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DN1aVS"&gt;A True Tone display that adjusts color temperature to match your environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="QRGUCd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10752834"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TR4t1L"&gt;Undoubtedly, one of the biggest selling points of the new iPad is its front-facing camera, which is a higher resolution than the 1.2MP camera found on the 2020 model. On paper, the this should translate to better video quality, whether for videoconferencing, livestreaming, or other activities. The newer model also provides support for 1080p recording at 25fps and 30fps, while the 2020 version only supports 1080p at 30fps. Additionally, the newer iPad can “follow” the subject as they move around the frame thanks to Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams"&gt;new Center Stage feature&lt;/a&gt;, once reserved for the iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RyVT2g"&gt;There are also some notable improvements when it comes to the display, storage capacity, and performance. Unlike last year’s model, the latest iPad sports twice the capacity at 64GB and 256GB storage variants instead of 32GB and 128GB. In addition, thanks to Apple’s True Tone technology — something Apple introduced in 2016 with the first-gen iPad Pro — the display on the new entry-level tablet can adjust its color temperature to match your environment. If you’re outside, for example, the display will automatically adjust to be easier on your eyes. Finally, the 2021 model features Apple’s A13 Bionic chip, which Apple says is 20 percent faster than the A12 Bionic chip found in the eighth-gen model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="S2BoiQ"&gt;What’s the same on both models?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="i2kFG4"&gt;The 8MP rear camera with f/2.4 aperture and digital zoom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wAQvQz"&gt;Slo-mo video support for 720p at 120fps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v15Er8"&gt;The overall design — height, width, depth are identical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VrGhsf"&gt;Lightning connectivity (no USB-C)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Zygx3w"&gt;They both have a headphone jack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="P6YCYp"&gt;The list of compatible accessories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZC34dY"&gt;Battery life, which Apple quotes at nine to 10 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8Js4ra"&gt;Wi-Fi 5 and optional LTE connectivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XAYdAe"&gt;Both run iPadOS 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="oxxrXk"&gt;In most other ways, the 2021 iPad is identical to its predecessor. The improved front-facing camera should mean better video calls, but aside from that, the device sports the same 8MP wide camera with an f/2.4 aperture on the rear, support for HDR, and a digital zoom. Both tablets also feature similar video recording capabilities, offering slo-mo video support for 720p at 120fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9GNifIWvm_UZCunuitsSeh4gspI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859063/Apple_iPad_10_2_inch_ProCreate_Pencil_09142021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both the 2020 and 2021 iPad feature an LCD display with 2160 x 1620 resolution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iqZB6C"&gt;Design-wise, they’re nearly the same, meaning the newer tablet remains compatible with existing accessories like Apple’s Smart Keyboard and still has a 3.5mm headphone jack, a novelty among Apple’s current device lineup and modern devices in general. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sWgK0z"&gt;Unlike the all-new iPad Mini, however, the 2021 iPad still features a home button with a Touch ID sensor and a Lightning port instead of USB-C, a frustrating liner note that’s also applicable to iPhone 13 models. Both are only compatible with the first-generation Apple Pencil, too, which isn’t nearly as convenient to charge as the second-gen model released in 2018. While the new model charges wirelessly while magnetically docked to the side of the iPad Pro and latest iPad Air and iPad Mini, the last-gen Pencil still relies on the tablet’s Lightning connector and awkwardly juts out the bottom of the device when charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Deycqe"&gt;Both iPads are available in space gray or silver — no gold colorway this time around — with a 10.2-inch display and 2160 x 1620 resolution. They even weigh about the same; only the Wi-Fi version of the new model weighs a little less: 1.07 pounds, as opposed to 1.08.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w74709"&gt;Apple claims battery life is also identical across both devices, with the new iPad offering between nine and 10 hours of battery life, depending upon whether you’re using a cellular connection or Wi-Fi. Meanwhile, the 2021 model boasts twice the storage for the same price. The Wi-Fi-equipped iPad with 64GB of storage now starts at $329 — the same price the last-gen model started at with 32GB of storage. The newer model is also available in a 256GB configuration for $150 more, whereas the 2020 model could only be purchased in either 32GB or 128GB varieties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VEll5t"&gt;As for the operating system, both models are compatible with iPadOS 15. The only difference is that the 2021 iPad comes with it pre-installed — eighth-gen iPad owners will need to download it. That means no matter which model you choose, you’ll be able to make &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522889/apple-facetime-android-windows-web-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;FaceTime calls with Android and Windows users in a pinch&lt;/a&gt;, resize your widgets, filter notifications via &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22579920/how-to-use-focus-modes-apple-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey"&gt;Focus mode&lt;/a&gt;, and make use of a host of new iPadOS 15 features. With the final release of macOS Monterey later in the fall, you’ll also be able to drag and drop content between devices using &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;Universal Control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="w2Wrqe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Goodbye and good riddance to Apple’s 64GB iPhones","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22675300/apple-64gb-iphone-13-128gb-standard-storage-space-photos-videos-apps"},{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 review: fundamental fixes","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zrX4eoQf6IHAkTM73kLYPYG2RUg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859204/Apple_iPad_10_2_inch_SplitView_09142021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kywy7Z"&gt;Why might you stick with the 2020 iPad?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="RdQj5g"&gt;It’s still a good tablet, likely with years of support ahead of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wXzWg6"&gt;You really dig the gold colorway or the white bezels on the silver model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="57ijOI"&gt;Unlike the forthcoming iPad Mini, the latest entry-level iPad is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676532/apple-event-iphone-13-incremental-refinement-upgrade-specs"&gt;more of a refinement&lt;/a&gt; than a notable overhaul. It doesn’t feature a USB-C port or compatibility with the second-gen Apple Pencil, nor does it ditch the home button in favor of an edge-to-edge display. It’s still the most economical tablet in Apple’s lineup, however, and even the incremental upgrades are enough to render it an even better value at $329 than it was before. The faster performance afforded by the A13 Bionic is welcome, as is an upgraded 12MP camera at a time when we’re still all connecting virtually more often than we are in person. It even offers double the storage for the same price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWWBw1"&gt;For some people, the subtle improvements will be enough. But for most? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bU1j6qbU7MsjLoMjDf7M-BCaIkY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859274/Apple_iPad_10_2_inch_Family_09142021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2021 iPad (second from the right) remains Apple’s most affordable tablet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p9EaqZ"&gt;If you’re currently in the market for a new tablet and not just to upgrade, though, the choice gets a little easier when you consider availability. Apple officially discontinued the 2020 iPad with the introduction of the ninth-gen model, and though we routinely saw last year’s model discounted to as low as $300 over the past year, it’s recently been unavailable at nearly every retailer. Even if you wanted to pick up the 2020 model, you can’t, making the 2021 iPad the cheapest Apple tablet you can pick up outside of a used or refurbished model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPFmXm"&gt;If you regularly use your iPad to make video calls or livestream, the new front-facing camera may be enough reason to upgrade — or if you’re really hard-pressed for storage space. Outside that, though, you might be better off waiting for a more substantial refresh to Apple’s entry-level tablet or spending the extra $200 or so on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;2020 iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;, a tablet equipped with an even faster processor, a larger display, and a USB-C port, along with a host of other improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22678374/apple-ipad-2020-vs-2021-comparison-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22678374/apple-ipad-2020-vs-2021-comparison-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T10:00:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T10:00:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge Guide to the iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YGAwO9MdC_JIGsOLki3HTxCErhw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/61483719/acastro_190913_3667_0001.8.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Vergge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="e6fhSf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;guide to the iPhone&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a comprehensive list of how-tos that will help you be the best iPhone user you can be.  Buying a new iPhone 13? Updating to iOS 15? Or carefully sticking with iOS 14? We’ve got helpful hints for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YpMxPg"&gt;If you to upgrade to the latest iPhone, we explain the difference between the various models, tell you how to sell or trade in your old phone, and teach you how to wipe all of your personal information when you do hand it over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbocOO"&gt;We offer you tips and tricks on how to make the most of your phone and the apps that populate it. Want to move all of your data to your brand-new phone? Need to replace a failing battery? Nervous about installing the latest version of iOS before it’s completely safe? Here is step-by-step advice to help you get to where you need to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="cyThSv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EVERYTHING YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT YOUR IPHONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dJqCey"&gt;If you already have an iPhone or you just want to increase your knowledge of using iOS, our how-tos can teach you everything you need to know (or already knew) about some of your phone’s more advanced features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="hNYE5n"&gt;And don’t worry, you can always come back to this page, just in case you can’t finish reading the whole guide in one sitting. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/21/17828022/iphone-user-guide-how-to-ios-tips"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/21/17828022/iphone-user-guide-how-to-ios-tips</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>iPhone 13 Pro review: a better display, the best camera, and incredible battery life</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Smooth operators&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="lVLDlO"&gt;The iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max are phones designed for people who care about the details. The improvements over last year’s iPhones are significant but not obvious at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYOJiC"&gt;Just as with the regular &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"&gt;iPhone 13 and 13 Mini&lt;/a&gt;, the most important upgrades on the 13 Pro are to battery life and the camera system. The 13 Pro adds a third major improvement with a high refresh rate screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZy42V"&gt;Upgrading the battery, camera, and screen sounds like an iterative, yearly update; they sound like the so-called “S” updates that Apple used to do for iPhones before its naming schemes became unpredictable. And it is true that the design is virtually identical to that of last year’s iPhone 12 Pros. But those assumptions — those words — don’t quite do justice to how big the changes really are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SieXlO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10764115"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HDtzdX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We will update this review with a full score and scorecard for the iPhone 13 Pro Max after further battery testing, but see below for initial impressions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Pro is a bit thicker because of a larger battery, so iPhone 12 Pro cases won’t fit." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ny6ArzeT0abX7U_ZwlO2TJfb_0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863285/vpavic_210916_untitled_0027.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 Pro is a bit thicker because of a larger battery, so iPhone 12 Pro cases won’t fit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gMdpOS"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max battery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="6BiRNN"&gt;The change that’s most likely to make the biggest impact for the most people is battery life. Apple is happy to tell you that the battery improvements come from a constellation of updates, including increased efficiency in the new A15 Bionic processor and changes to how the new display uses power. I am sure all that is true, but I’m just as sure that the biggest contributor is simply that the batteries are bigger than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qDhFmY"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678607/iphone-13-reported-battery-sizes-increase-laptop-comparison"&gt;13 Pro has an 11 percent larger battery and the 13 Pro Max’s battery is an astonishing 18.5 percent larger&lt;/a&gt;. Apple’s quoted improvements over the 12 Pro models are one and a half hours more usage on the 13 Pro and two and a half hours on the 13 Pro Max — and the 12 Pro Max was &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; a battery life monster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Scpobu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The battery life improvement isn’t complicated; it’s a bigger battery&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1ln2RL"&gt;I’ve only had the phones for a little less than a week, so I focused most of my use on the smaller iPhone 13 Pro as a kind of worst-case test. And my results are in line with Apple’s claims. On a day when we really pushed the phone with lots of 4K video and max brightness on the screen, it still lasted from early morning to 11PM with 20 percent remaining — with somewhere north of four hours of very heavy use in the screen time tracking app. A day with less intense usage clocked me at seven hours of screen on time before the low battery warning kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G2OPp4"&gt;Although I haven’t used the 13 Pro Max as much, I expect it will do even better. A few times the past week I caught myself doing a double take, wondering why its battery was so full even though I’d been using it intensively. I will check back in to this review with an update after I’ve had a chance to do more testing with it (and with its opposite, the regular iPhone 13 MIni).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WII3Gv"&gt;Bottom line: I have much more confidence walking out of the house for a long day without carrying an external battery pack. For me, the line a smartphone needs to cross is that I trust I can get through a normal day without battery anxiety. Both the 13 Pro and the 13 Pro Max easily get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max keep the major redesigns introduced last year — they still feel fresh and modern." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bLp7mtnBqNSAknvlWtvU99sTY0M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863286/vpavic_210916_untitled_0031.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max keep the major redesigns introduced last year — they still feel fresh and modern.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RQlOiN"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro design and specs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="occrhj"&gt;Last year was a big design update for the iPhone, with flat sides, 5G, and MagSafe charging. This year’s models inherit all of that, changing the design in only minor ways. The most obvious one is the notch on the screen. It’s slightly smaller, but only horizontally — it still pushes down into what you’re looking at to the same degree. Apple also didn’t do anything with that extra space at the top, meaning you still can’t see your battery percentage without pulling down the control center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JK7xVY"&gt;The other design change is that the new iPhones are almost imperceptibly heavier and also thicker across the entire body compared to last year’s models. But the camera bumps on both phones are significantly bigger, which means that 12 Pro cases are not going to fit on the 13 Pro. I think the tradeoffs are worth it for the improved battery life and camera system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="pcyWDI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The design is virtually identical to the iPhone 12 Pro models&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The smaller notch on the iPhone 13 Pro Max (left) compared to the 12 Pro Max (right)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l2z2yR_DeXfOX9MEg6-o6IBv9j8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863283/vpavic_210916_untitled_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The smaller notch on the iPhone 13 Pro Max (left) compared to the 12 Pro Max (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PMFKfj"&gt;Unlike many Android phones with gently curving displays at the edges, Apple does still have a small bezel around the screen. The rails on the edges are glossy stainless steel that pick up fingerprints, the glass on the back is a smooth matte. The front uses Apple’s Ceramic Shield finish to prevent cracks and the camera lenses are sapphire. It’s a beautiful phone, and I think it’s a huge step up from the curved sides we’ve seen on iPhones from the 6 all the way up through the 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EpGUZC"&gt;The important spec outside of the camera system and the screen is the new A15 Bionic processor, which is indeed fast. But as always with iPhones, the primary purpose of that speed is ensuring the phone will still feel fast in years to come, not making it seem faster than last year’s device. There are a bunch of camera features that seem to be enabled by the A15, however. I’ll also just point out that the 13 Pro models get five GPU cores to the regular 13’s four, but that extra core doesn’t seem to enable anything specific beyond more speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l76YW8"&gt;Base storage still starts at 128GB, but at the top end there’s a new 1TB option. That is a ridiculous amount of storage for a phone, but if you’re planning on shooting a bunch of ProRes video then it might be something to actually consider. Screen sizes and resolutions are the same: 6.1 inches at 1170 x 2532 pixels for the 13 Pro and 6.7 inches at 1284 x 2778 pixels for the 13 Pro Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7hoSEK"&gt;In terms of networking, Apple is focused on expanding support for Mid-Band 5G — the kind that will actually matter more than the UWB version that’s only really available on certain street corners. All that really means is that in the US, the 13 Pro is ready for a 5G future that could come if carriers keep their promises (they haven’t so far, but maybe next year). As usual, if you travel a lot you should keep an eye on the bands available on the &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/watch-out-with-iphone-13-there-are-now-5-different-iphone-models-by-country"&gt;several variants that are sold in different regions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OPPFI"&gt;Finally, although I know it’s a lost cause and that I sound like a broken record, I still believe that Apple should switch the iPhone from the Lightning connector to USB-C. I also still believe Apple made a mistake by not taking advantage of the obvious opportunities to do so with the big iPhone X and iPhone 12 redesigns. I understand the reasons why it hasn’t switched and I disagree with them. Especially on a “Pro” phone, the standard cable would be incredibly convenient and useful for both charging and connecting other accessories without adapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The camera system on the iPhone 13 Pro is a major upgrade." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G-51a5mInUeU_ZboyZk_s8FIAOU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863264/akrales_210917_4760_0441.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The camera system on the iPhone 13 Pro is a major upgrade.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8HH3XY"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro cameras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="XjydBk"&gt;The camera systems on the iPhone 13 Pro and the 13 Pro Max are identical this year, which means you don’t have to buy the bigger and more expensive phone to get the best photos.  And I do mean best photos, because there isn’t another phone on the market that can match the iPhone 13 Pro. (Google’s upcoming Pixel 6 hasn’t been released as of writing this, of course, but it will have its work cut out for it.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qQNuIQ"&gt;Apple’s marketing for the camera system on the 13 Pro is that it’s the “biggest advancement ever.” I don’t know that I would go that far, but I also can’t remember the last time I’ve said “whoa, look at this photo” as many times as I have during this review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="f6FaKN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The best cameras on a smartphone&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BwoSXP"&gt;I will start, however, by pointing out that this camera system is one of the things I’m referring to when I say that the 13 Pro is a phone for people who pay attention to the details. In bright sunlight or normal light, the pictures these phones take are very hard to distinguish from the iPhone 13 or even the iPhone 12. In good lighting, almost any high-end smartphone is very competent these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1tB58i"&gt;Where the Pro 13 camera system shines is in low light. The main wide-angle sensor has seen a massive upgrade this year. Unlike Android phones that are chasing big megapixel counts and then “pixel binning” to achieve low light performance, Apple is sticking with 12 megapixels, the same resolution it’s used since 2015’s iPhone 6S. The sensor itself is much bigger now and features 1.9 µm pixels, which are about as big as anything we’ve seen on a smartphone. And on top of all that, the lens now has an f/1.5 aperture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9snyn"&gt;All of that adds up to a camera that can very quickly take in a massive amount of light relative to other phones. Combined with some tuning and improvements to Apple’s computational photography, the low light performance on the 13 Pro is simply second to none. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The 13 Pro and Pro Max have much better low light performance, but it’s not immediately obvious on smaller screens" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xNiF1qTIUPjGNK0aDdI0Hg4KaOQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864637/pro_IMG_387230.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 13 Pro and Pro Max have much better low light performance, but it’s not immediately obvious on smaller screens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Color reproduction in darker scenes is much improved compared to last year" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qELZZp--7dGKjSn1RqYv3uJ8lTI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864636/pro_IMG_384027.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Color reproduction in darker scenes is much improved compared to last year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xHDLat"&gt;There’s less image noise in low light and more dynamic range in low and even medium light. Apple also tells me it has adjusted how it handles the black point so shadow exposure is more accurate now too — the 13 Pro is just more willing to let darks be dark while accurately exposing lighter areas. In situations the 12 Pro would aggressively hop into night mode and lighten everything up, the 13 Pro often doesn’t need night mode. And when the 13 Pro does drop into night mode, it goes through that exposure process twice as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0qEtF5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10763684"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JEN10O"&gt;We used this word last year in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;12 Pro Max review&lt;/a&gt;, but I think it applies even more this year. The camera on the 13 Pro is &lt;em&gt;confident.&lt;/em&gt; As computational photography has become the norm over the past few years, I have seen lots of camera systems — including on the iPhone — just sort of panic and do the wrong things with exposure or tone. The iPhone 13 Pro has almost never done that in my testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SsHBzJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10763672"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Is8rtY"&gt;Let’s bring things back to earth. Will most people notice the quality difference between the 13 Pro and the regular iPhone 13 or even last year’s iPhones? Most of the time, I think the answer is actually no. On phone screens, you really have to zoom in and pixel peep to see it. But if there’s any place where I think it makes sense to call an iPhone “Pro” as in “for professionals,” I think this main wide angle camera is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lrLtfy"&gt;The ultrawide camera also got an upgrade in terms of taking in more light, but it’s not as dramatic a difference. A more interesting upgrade is adding autofocus to that camera, which allows it to pick up a new trick: macro photography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Macro mode kicks in automatically at around 10cm from a subject" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/idnl0a8E2FeczI16Oy53UzoyQbk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864666/pro_IMG_022307.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Macro mode kicks in automatically at around 10cm from a subject&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ultrawide camera has better low light performance, but not dramatically so" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JECJG9xniss22pVNWNxDdoZ_xlE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864676/pro_IMG_388931.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ultrawide camera has better low light performance, but not dramatically so&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6Bqd7"&gt;When you bring the phone in close to a subject, you can see the camera frame switch over to the ultrawide when it’s about 10cm away. It tries to keep the same basic framing with a crop, but apparently not everybody is enthused: Apple emailed us the night before the review to say it would ship a software update later with an option to disable the automatic switchover. Then you can keep pushing in until you’re as close as 2cm away and still have an in-focus shot. The photos it takes are better than the bespoke, throwaway macro lenses on many Android phones these days. It’s a fun feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F6s3uz"&gt;The wide angle camera has gotten the most impressive upgrade, but my favorite is the new telephoto lens. Apple has set it to a 3X zoom, the equivalent of a 77mm focal length and up from the 2.5X / 65mm in the 12 Pro Max. That extended zoom does mean that it drops to an f/2.8 aperture (from f/2.2), but whatever low light losses that entails are more than made up for by the addition of night mode for this lens. Apple isn’t playing the superzoom 100X game; instead, it’s focusing on quality at the 3X optical zoom for things like portrait photography. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The new telephoto lens takes amazing portrait photos, but takes some effort to get good shots in low light" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ylna0kEm-Pig_PHBswqpjhrljDE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864680/pro_IMG_016205.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new telephoto lens takes amazing portrait photos, but takes some effort to get good shots in low light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Lxz8xA"&gt;And that quality is incredible. I simply love taking photos of people with the telephoto at 3X now, getting a natural bokeh effect without having to engage the software portrait mode. The telephoto lens gets the award this year for most improved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V3fn2f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10763698"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8hwkE4"&gt;Apple has held the crown for best smartphone video for a very long time now, challenged (but not losing) only briefly by the Samsung Galaxy Ultra series phones in the last year or two. This year, video quality is simply amazing, at least on the wide angle camera. That larger sensor and the fact that it’s using sensor-based stabilization instead of just OIS makes for stable and beautiful footage even in low light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3QxNQn"&gt;Apple will also let you shoot video in ProRes this year. I didn’t have much time to test that and ProRes isn’t really a part of our video workflow. But it’s there if you buy an iPhone that has enough storage to handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nFmse8"&gt;I’ll state it plainly because it bears repeating: the iPhone 13 Pro has the best camera system on any smartphone available as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photographic Profiles make the iPhone take photos that look more like what Samsung and Google’s phones take" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N2QfiFHTQ51U-p_4X3AdX1z2Fhw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864295/IMG_0281_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photographic Profiles make the iPhone take photos that look more like what Samsung and Google’s phones take&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xNMM6c"&gt;Photographic Profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="TUVWr1"&gt;Apple has added two new camera modes to this year’s iPhones, both Pro and regular. Each is fascinating in its own way. Cinematic Mode is essentially Portrait Mode but for video, while Picture Profiles change the default way the iPhone takes photos. Picture Profiles are particularly interesting because they serve almost as an admission that Apple is feeling competitive pressure from the likes of Samsung and Google, so let’s start there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B5cJno"&gt;Profiles are a new setting in the camera app that change the way your photos look by default. So instead of applying a filter after the photo is taken, you can set your iPhone to have a specific kind of “look” right away. In fact, Apple insists that Profiles are not filters at all, for reasons I’ll get into shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1v5ctq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10764311"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dad4CO"&gt;The default options for Profiles include Standard, Rich Contrast, Vibrant, Warm, and Cool. Each one has its own little sliders that you can manually tweak for both Tone and Warmth. If you tweak those sliders, the name of that profile cleverly changes to match your settings (my personal favorite name is “Rich Cool,” because I imagine that’s Apple’s target demographic). When you set one of these profiles, it becomes the new default way the camera takes pictures, though it will also pop up a button that lets you toggle it off. (The button is also clever, the way it looks changes based on what profile you’ve set). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rlWvlf"&gt;The TL;DR for Profiles is that “Rich Contrast” makes the iPhone’s photos look more like a Google Pixel, with bluer tones and deeper contrast. And “Vibrant” makes the iPhone look more like a Samsung phone, with more extreme colors all around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WbYvA"&gt;Historically, Apple has insisted that what it aims for in photography is the “truth” of what your eye would see. I will (regretfully) set aside philosophical questions about the nature of objective reality and what a photograph is and instead just point out that it’s fair to say that when it comes to photography, Apple is much less opinionated than the competition. Samsung and Google are both more willing to tune their images to be more pleasing to their customers than Apple is. With Profiles, Apple is essentially giving its customers the option to get pictures they like better without having to edit them after the shot.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photographic Profiles on iPhone 13 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fMxkhJb49SGOduYhIN9_P1dLl6A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864389/profiles.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photographic Profiles on iPhone 13 Pro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="usyFdq"&gt;Understanding how Profiles actually works is a little complicated. Apple’s computational photography process is called Smart HDR, and what it does is standard across many phones these days: it takes a bunch of photos at different exposures all at once and then combines them into a single, final image. Part of that process involves making choices about white balance, color, contrast, and so on. Another part of that process is the iPhone semantically recognizing different things in the scene — things like faces, people, grass, sky, cats, or whatever and exposing them differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qspoht"&gt;When you set a profile, the iPhone makes different choices during the Smart HDR capture about white balance, color, contrast, and so on based on the preference you set. It also uses that semantic recognition to make better choices for things like skin tone. That’s why it’s not a filter — it’s not applied evenly across the entire image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ye3iOb"&gt;Profiles are not something you can undo in the edit — though Apple does label them in the metadata when you view them in the Photos app. You should also know that you can’t shoot with profiles and have RAW output on at the same time. Unlike a RAW photo where you can make all sorts of choices in the edit, Photographic Profiles lock your choices in to the file as it’s saved. In theory it might be possible for the iPhone to save all of that extra data, but Apple tells us that it would create huge files that it wouldn’t be worth it for ordinary use, and that people who do want to edit after the fact can just shoot RAW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Editing a Cinematic Mode video on an iPhone 13 Pro Max" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LupFP9L_lzgIe3ei24wHEchPr4s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864301/Screenshot_2021_09_20_at_8.46.04_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editing a Cinematic Mode video on an iPhone 13 Pro Max&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pxIe2Z"&gt;Cinematic Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="HkyZIA"&gt;Apple’s flashiest iPhone ads are for Cinematic Mode. It’s an entirely new mode for iPhone video that uses software to blur the background of a video, much as Portrait Mode does for photos. Unlike Portrait Mode, Cinematic doesn’t take advantage of the iPhone 13 Pro’s LIDAR sensor for creating a depth map — it just uses software to recognize human faces and bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v5BFX5"&gt;The reason Cinematic mode makes for such a great demo is that it can automatically shift the focus when something happens in the scene. It locks on to the biggest face that it sees, but if that face turns away the iPhone can automatically shift focus to somebody else in the background. It is fun to play around with and works with both the rear and front-facing Selfie cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Es4aQ"&gt;You can also change the focus point as you’re shooting by tapping something in the background and lock focus by tapping again. And then after you’re done shooting, you can change your focus decisions moment-to-moment in the Photos app and even change the amount of background blur for the entire video. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Cinematic Mode is limited to 1080p and doesn’t work in low light, despite what Apple’s ads show" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6ANjnyRUm4phHT-0w1eXsBHm6Cg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22864316/cinematic.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cinematic Mode is limited to 1080p and doesn’t work in low light, despite what Apple’s ads show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tY3mZT"&gt;Because it’s the equivalent of Portrait Mode for video, it can have the same problems as Portrait Mode for photos — it rarely works in low light, for example. (Apple’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/apple/status/1438955425265696775?s=21"&gt;own ads for Cinematic Mode show it working in low light&lt;/a&gt;, which I find misleading.) It can also have weird or bad cutouts around hair, which is a little less noticeable because it’s video, but it’s still there. Finally, Cinematic Mode &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; works in 1080p at 30FPS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E9nPrp"&gt;Cinematic Mode really only works well within Apple’s own ecosystem of apps. The depth map information is saved into an ancillary “sidecar” file that goes alongside the video, but only Apple apps like Photos or Final Cut can do anything with it right now. If you AirDrop it to a Mac that isn’t running MacOS Monterey, the iPhone will bake all your depth choices into the file before sending it along. Apple tells us that it hasn’t worked with third party companies like Adobe or Lumafusion to make that data editable in those apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPU6ht"&gt;I think Cinematic Mode is crazy fun but I’m not sure how much value it really adds to people who want to use their iPhone for actual, professional video work. I’m not going to say it’s a gimmick, but it is gimmick-adjacent. Like Portrait Mode in photos was at the beginning, Cinematic Mode feels like it’s a few years away from being truly useful for anything beyond casual use. Despite Apple’s promos, I have a hard time believing real movies will be made with this in its present state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The LTPO displays on the 13 Pros have high refresh rates — finally" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E01KlIJ2W7CxDhf2e731K95T_C0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863263/akrales_210917_4760_0384.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LTPO displays on the 13 Pros have high refresh rates — finally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5NYQWg"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max displays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="T0cjec"&gt;The iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max finally offer iPhone users a screen feature that flagship Android phones have had for quite a long time: higher refresh rates. Apple’s branding for its screen is “Super Retina XDR display with ProMotion,” and the important part is the ProMotion, which previously has only been on the iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xCwRPY"&gt;Historically, the iPhone has been able to refresh its screen at 60Hz (or 60 times every second), but the new iPhone 13 Pros can vary the refresh rates from as little as 10Hz all the way up to 120Hz. Apple is using a type of OLED display called LTPO (&lt;a href="https://www.pcworld.idg.com.au/article/666267/what-an-ltpo-display/"&gt;Low-Temperature Polycrystalline Oxide&lt;/a&gt;) panel, technology &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251977/samsung-display-ltpo-display-power-efficient-panel-galaxy-s21-ultra-debut"&gt;first seen on Samsung phones&lt;/a&gt;. It has a wide dynamic range, can get much brighter, and also uses less power because it can ratchet down the refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DcoWDq"&gt;What all this means practically is that scrolling and animations look much smoother. It also has battery life benefits because if nothing’s moving on the screen, the screen needs to refresh less often and therefore uses less power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4Ni8VQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple waited too long to introduce high refresh rate displays on its Pro phones, but it has implemented them well&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T22XNY"&gt;None of this is news to Android users, but if you haven’t used a high refresh rate display on a phone before it can be a little hard to explain why it makes a difference. This is doubly true on iPhones, because Apple has gotten away with not putting a high refresh rate screen on an iPhone for so long because iOS is itself a very smooth OS without very much jank in its animations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7on6Wr"&gt;When I scroll on the iPhone 13 Pro, the text stays readable instead of turning into a blur. Things moving on the screen are smoother. It feels more like a direct interaction with my finger because the iPhone can literally change its refresh rate to match my movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mv2at6"&gt;Apple’s implementation is also smart: iOS keeps an eye on what activity is happening on the screen and adjusts the refresh rate to match. So the screen matches the 24FPS frame rate in video apps, for example. Apple tells me apps coded with its default tools like Swift will get these benefits for free and that developers will have access to tools to update their apps to support ProMotion if they like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ved8rg"&gt;I get if all this sounds very silly. It is very much a premium feature that is more about experience than anything practical. That’s exactly what ProMotion is and it is exactly what I think we should expect from a phone that costs more than a thousand dollars. It was a similar story when Apple’s own high-density Retina Displays hit the scene. Once many people experienced the nicer thing, they were bothered by its lack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="59ronC"&gt;I have heard all the speculation about why Apple waited this long to implement this feature and I don’t really buy any of them. I admit that high refresh rates are the epitome of “nice to have,” but part of the point of Apple’s extravagant Pro phones is to provide the nicest experience. Now, finally, they do. Crucially, Apple did an excellent job with its implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Pro (left) and Pro Max (right)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ekFDxMXU0-GMcxYU4CYwEStQFpE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863288/vpavic_210916_untitled_0058.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 Pro (left) and Pro Max (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="qLs5Lq"&gt;The ProMotion display is the perfect example of what you get with the iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max. It’s an improvement that may only matter explicitly to a few but will subtly make life nicer for everybody who uses it. The battery life upgrade isn’t quite so subtle, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x4679X"&gt;As for the camera, I can see it both ways. When you’re sharing photos and videos to social media and looking at them on a phone, the differences &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; subtle at most — but they’re there if you look for them. And if you use your iPhone’s camera for more than just Instagram, you’ll appreciate the updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nf4R3E"&gt;The list of significant things I have to complain about with these phones is almost astonishingly short. (Though, as you might expect, I can quibble for days about little things like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;lack of a meaningful MagSafe ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;, the lightning port, or how iOS 15 handles notifications). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ven5Ti"&gt;The story of the iPhone 13 Pro is a story of iteration, sure, but iteration &lt;em&gt;matters&lt;/em&gt;. iPhone 12 Pro owners will have to pay a lot of attention to see some of the differences and an upgrade probably doesn’t make a lot of sense. But if you’re using something older, all that iteration comes on top of the major improvements from the iPhone 12 Pro — the upgrades will be very noticeable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tk2gK9"&gt;Either way, when you start to pay attention to the details, prepare to be impressed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="hi9GQZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10764169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>iPhone 13 review: yep, bigger batteries are better</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;So are bigger cameras&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ar2R52"&gt;What, really, do you want out of a new phone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mAdrAJ"&gt;Assuming you’re starting with a good foundation, I think the list of what really makes a big difference in phone upgrades is actually short. The first thing on the list is improved battery life. The second is an improved camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmuVya"&gt;Those are the two things that make a fundamental difference in your day-to-day experience of a smartphone (assuming, again, that the basics don’t stink). Those are also exactly the things Apple tried to make better in the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YLmhHh"&gt;Those two improvements come on top of the major changes the company introduced last year with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;. If you already have an iPhone 12, this year’s update looks iterative because it is. If you have an older iPhone, the full list of what’s better on the iPhone 13 is almost too long to enumerate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zm6VCR"&gt;The iPhone 12 brought new technologies and a fancy new design (and a new, Mini-sized version). The iPhone 13’s battery and camera updates aren’t so flashy, but they’re more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jTlL1X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10764114"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="POELcK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We will update this review with a full score and scorecard for the iPhone 13 Mini after further battery testing, but see below for initial impressions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13, in pink." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_1xWz-QZRgEvQvbddJAlZgt-Pxw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863269/vpavic_210916_4760_0069.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13, in pink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IL8t4x"&gt;iPhone 13 and 13 Mini design and specs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="5SAQtt"&gt;Unless you look very closely, it’s difficult to tell the difference between the iPhone 13 devices and their predecessors. The iPhone 12 and 12 Mini introduced a striking and new flat-edged design that I still believe is a massive improvement on what came before. And of course, the iPhone 12 Mini was the first phone in a long time to bring a truly great experience to a smartphone with a smaller form factor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jOAz8c"&gt;They also switched over to OLED screens, which offer a superior experience to the LCDs that came before in several ways: contrast ratio, brightness, and power efficiency. They added 5G. They added the MagSafe charging system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHf9VU"&gt;It’s worth revisiting all those big changes because people are hanging on to their smartphones for a longer time now — especially iPhones. I think it’s fair to give the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini credit for the design they’re based on since so many of the people that are likely to buy them will be new to what the iPhone 12 offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="fnVRC3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The iPhone 13 and 13 Mini keep last year’s new design, which is still beautiful and modern&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ad7gks"&gt;There &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; some changes to that design, however. The newer iPhones are just a tiny bit thicker  overall with substantially bigger camera bumps. That means that cases designed for the iPhone 12 and 12 Mini are unlikely to fit the newer phones. The camera bump is not only thicker but the lenses have been rearranged to accommodate the giant new sensor that’s in the main wide-angle camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qOjSnL"&gt;The last change is that the notch housing FaceID and the selfie camera has been shrunk down by 20 percent — but don’t get too excited by that. It’s only been reduced on the horizontal axis, so the extra screen you get doesn’t amount to much (and Apple isn’t using it to show more info, like battery percentage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ijCuBt"&gt;There is a new processor inside the iPhone 13, the A15 Bionic. As usual with iPhones, it’s difficult to discern significant speed improvements, but that is only because there’s so much headroom that iPhones tend to feel fast for longer. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; models get one more GPU core than the regular models, but I haven’t noticed that make a difference at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGFILf"&gt;One difference that does matter this year: the base storage on the least expensive iPhone 13 and 13 Mini has been increased to 128GB. I’m frankly impressed that Apple actually managed to proactively increase the base storage on its own — historically it’s always done it far too late. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lNUALy"&gt;Finally, my favorite design improvement over the iPhone 12 is that there’s a new pink color option. Of all the colors offered on the iPhone 13 and 13 Pro lines, it is the best one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Mini" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OhbF73GPv-Zly2J-mcpTx4bMdD8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863274/vpavic_210916_4760_0323.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 Mini.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UzmY4E"&gt;iPhone 13 battery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="DyoBG1"&gt;Battery life on last year’s iPhone 12 wasn’t quite what I had hoped for. Battery life on last year’s iPhone 12 Mini was sadly exactly what I was expecting: not very good. So for this year’s iPhone 13, Apple did the obvious thing: it made the batteries bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7i3hCp"&gt;Those larger batteries (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678607/iphone-13-reported-battery-sizes-increase-laptop-comparison"&gt;9 percent on the iPhone 13 Mini and 15.1 percent on the iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt;) are the main driver behind Apple’s battery claims this year. It says that the regular iPhone 13 should last for a whopping two-and-a-half hours of usage longer than the iPhone 12 while the Mini will last an extra one-and-a-half hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wjzzSH"&gt;Of course, if you don’t have an iPhone 12 then the 13 lasting more than two hours longer is kind of meaningless. My takeaway for the regular iPhone 13 doesn’t require relative comparisons, though: battery life is &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="D80PRl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Battery life on the regular iPhone 13 is excellent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The best iPhone 13 color is pink." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bz6C5n_5q6wqP6YwubUJe0TiFTs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865100/vpavic_210917_4760_0702.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The best iPhone 13 color is pink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SZq1pC"&gt;On one day of my testing, the regular iPhone 13 made it from 7am to midnight before it tuckered out. That was with some camera testing, watching some video, the usual doomscrolling, emails, work, and some games. It was an intense set of work for the five hours of screentime that day, so that’s impressive. On another day with lighter usage, I didn’t see the battery warning until the following morning. But the iPhone 13’s battery isn’t magic. When we had a day of a lot more 4K video testing, I was looking for a charger by 7 or 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EixJP9"&gt;As for the iPhone 13 Mini, I just have to admit that I haven’t had a chance to fully test it yet. We don’t do video rundown tests here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, instead preferring to base our results on as much real world use as we can do. There are only so many phones I can actually use in the real world at a time. I will be doing a full, longer term battery test on the iPhone 13 Mini over the coming weeks and I will publish a full rundown — and update this review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hoFcnE"&gt;However, I do have an early impression of the iPhone 13 Mini’s battery life. It’s that Apple’s one-and-a-half hour longer claim seems reasonable, but that is faint praise. I used the iPhone 12 Mini a lot over the last year, and what I said when I &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555295/iphone-12-mini-review"&gt;first reviewed it&lt;/a&gt; turned out to be true: if you use this little phone like it’s a big smartphone, you will drain the battery by early afternoon or even lunch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VycbIf"&gt;The iPhone 12 and 13 Minis are meant to be minimalistic both in size and also in how much you use them. If you are constantly using your phone all day, the smaller battery in the Mini isn’t likely to be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DuXlBF"&gt;My takeaway on the Mini is to not assume the improvements are enough to overcome the fundamental physics of smaller batteries. My takeaway on the regular iPhone 13 is also based on fundamental physics: a big battery means good battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 and 13 Mini have the same camera sensor as last year’s iPhone 12 Pro Max" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q72GubsK29ZL7erXjL73Erpry6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865101/vpavic_210918_4760_0703.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 and 13 Mini have the same camera sensor as last year’s iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mx8zAg"&gt;iPhone 13 cameras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="we6MM5"&gt;Both the iPhone 13 and the 13 Mini have the same camera system: a regular wide-angle camera and an ultrawide. Both have been upgraded, but the major improvement comes to the wide angle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsoUUi"&gt;Just like the battery, the improvement to the wide-angle camera sensor is simple: make it bigger. A bigger camera sensor is able to take in more light more quickly and produce better results. Apple happened to have just such a sensor lying around: the one from last year’s iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9fL0gC"&gt;That’s notable because the 12 Pro Max stood apart from all the other iPhones last year by having a larger sensor, and now that sensor is the new default this year. And from the moment the 12 Pro Max was released up until now, it has been the best smartphone camera on the market for both photos and video. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In bright light, it can be difficult to see the improvement over last year’s iPhone 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VjTrGuWAMFmPyScPTB9djo0A8Yo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865823/reg_IMG_349707.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In bright light, it can be difficult to see the improvement over last year’s iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fs2dYr"&gt;I am happy to report that the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini match or improve on those results. Details are sharp and accurate, colors are rich without being oversaturated, focusing is fast and reliable, portrait mode is good enough to use day to day, and low light and night sight are both exceptional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Since the 13 and 13 Mini have the best camera sensor from last year’s 13 Pro Max, night mode performance is excellent" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wK3aL7SdxtoZdNYIDKstB8elqXI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865828/reg_IMG_353019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since the 13 and 13 Mini have the best camera sensor from last year’s 13 Pro Max, night mode performance is excellent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 has good color reproduction at night, though it can tend to yellows sometimes" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5JM7TdrsrLJYm9dbvXOZlnwz7cg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865827/reg_IMG_352918.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 has good color reproduction at night, though it can tend to yellows sometimes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vOttW3"&gt;Video quality is great. The main camera has sensor stabilization, which helps when you’re walking around. It can do all the modes that matter in terms of 4K and slow mo and handles them all super well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZvLuN"&gt;Really, the only way to be unhappy with this camera is to compare it head to head with an iPhone 13 Pro — and even then I think you’d probably need to do it on a big screen with images taken in low light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBEaB7"&gt;The ultrawide sensor was also updated for better low-light performance, but it’s fairly minor. What I mostly see is improved white balance and color when it’s in night mode. That’s something I’ve noticed across the board, actually. Especially in low light, colors are a bit more true to life than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Ultrawide is much less noisy in dark photos" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQUFAlvJMYpW4d7efE8tKjYWaL0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865826/reg_IMG_352216.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultrawide is much less noisy in dark photos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The 13 and 13 Mini have the exact same camera system" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IATdIRnXlBrQ6psXbjhzPFBu__M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865825/reg_IMG_351411.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 13 and 13 Mini have the exact same camera system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lw3g2e"&gt;My main wish is that the selfie camera sensor had been updated. It has some software improvements just like the other cameras and it’s inside a smaller notch now, but the selfie camera is too important for Apple to just leave the same this many years in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qRzGOJ"&gt;Apple has also introduced two new camera modes with the iPhone 13: Photographic Profiles and Cinematic Mode. I have gone in depth on both of those features in the iPhone 13 Pro review, so you can read the full details on how they work there. But I’ll briefly describe each here, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="diFHrJ"&gt;Photographic Profiles are a new option in the camera that change the default look of the picture you’re taking. You can customize the tone and contrast of how all the pictures you take look instead of doing it in edit after the fact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rJvyOk"&gt;You may know that Samsung phones take super vivid photos or that Google Pixel phones take photos that are more contrasty and blue. With Profiles, Apple is essentially admitting that people may prefer those looks and is providing an option to get them automatically.  You can also customize each one to your own personal preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EAxJoO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10764403"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="14G7Xz"&gt;Profiles aren’t like filters in that they don’t apply tone and warmth settings to the whole picture. The iPhone knows when it sees grass or faces or sky and so it adjusts how it applies those color preferences accordingly, so you don’t get weird looking skin tones or purple skies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s27evH"&gt;Photos taken with a Profile can’t have adjustments removed or changed (beyond normal editing) after the fact, and you can’t use RAW at the same time as profiles. It’s handy sometimes to think of them as presets, and I think I will use them from time to time. Apple claims that the A15 Bionic is necessary for the whole Profiles experience to work, but my feeling is that it ought to be possible to get this feature on older iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GXGPhT"&gt;Cinematic Mode is a new feature that is essentially the equivalent of Portrait Mode but for video. It locks on to a face and blurs the rest of the scene, just like if you were using a lens with a big aperture. But it then tries to change the focus as it sees fit, shifting over to a face in the background if a face in the foreground turns away, for example. As you shoot the video, you can manually change focus yourself or you can do it after the fact in the edit — but only inside Apple’s own apps like Photos or Final Cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XSqAOZ"&gt;The results from Cinematic Mode are nowhere near as good as Apple’s own commercials would have you believe. It doesn’t work well (or really, at all) in low light and it has the same problems you may remember from the early days of Portrait Mode photos: weird cutouts around hair and glasses. It also only works in 1080p at 30fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="37B8pX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10764406"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="czKzIA"&gt;But don’t let the fact that Cinematic Mode doesn’t live up the hype distract you. The camera systems on the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini are excellent. If there wasn’t also the iPhone 13 Pro in the world, they’d be the best you could get on a phone as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Mini and iPhone 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4G3eE5B21Pg_Xg9awwQwwBAsnHE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22863273/vpavic_210916_4760_0240.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 13 Mini and iPhone 13.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="RAOPHA"&gt;I think it’s all too easy to look at the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini and not think much of the updates this year. Cameras get better every year and every company promises good battery life, after all. And compared to the massive changes we saw on the iPhone last year, the 13 looks iterative, more like an iPhone 12S than truly new models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="KV4QJn"&gt;I won’t pretend that reading is totally wrong, but I also think it misses the point. Fancy new features are fun, but the fundamentals of battery life and camera are more important. Because if you focus on the fundamentals, your whole game gets better. And the iPhone 13 has got some good game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="llBFDZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10764169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T18:26:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T18:26:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 15 is here, but we’re still waiting on a few new features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uTvpFRQlKmImpD52gaTU3bIBhxs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69885760/cgartenberg_210917_4762_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IXnra3"&gt;Apple’s iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;finally here&lt;/a&gt;, but not all of the features announced at WWDC have made it alongside them. We looked through Apple’s product pages for each OS to find the features that have yet to show up on iPhones and iPads, such as SharePlay, improved AirPod Find My support, Universal Control, and more. Except for Universal Control, which isn’t for iPhones (yet), every feature listed is missing from both platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IuMGZs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 review: foundational fixes","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="T85EhV"&gt;Perhaps the most prominent missing feature is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22577178/shareplay-how-to-apple-facetime-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-apple-tv-video-music"&gt;SharePlay&lt;/a&gt;, which lets users watch videos or listen to music with friends on a FaceTime call. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629165/apple-shareplay-ios-ipad-os-15-macos-delayed"&gt;warned us (and developers)&lt;/a&gt; about the delay after removing SharePlay from beta tests, but it’s still a bit awkward given how &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;significant the feature looked&lt;/a&gt; at first. Its delay is worse because it’s holding other features back — Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673993/apple-fitness-plus-workouts-countries-languages-pilates-snow"&gt;recently announced that Group Workouts for Fitness Plus&lt;/a&gt; is on hold until SharePlay comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="soYqFI"&gt;Apple also says that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522951/apple-airpods-find-my-hearing-accesibility-notification-wwdc"&gt;better Find My support for AirPods&lt;/a&gt; isn’t coming until later this fall. The feature was announced at WWDC, with Apple saying that some of the devices in its headphone lineup are getting an AirTag-like proximity view. The AirPods Pro and Max will be able to connect to the Find My network, making them easier to find even when they’re not physically with you. As someone who is currently missing a set of AirPods (and whose hope of finding them is draining like the earbud’s batteries), this is probably the delay that hurts the most.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vHPq_jOwqHoa1-MxP4HTuNrMMeU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865217/Screen_Shot_2021_09_20_at_12.53.45_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I wouldn’t give...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S5lASs"&gt;The App Store’s in-app events feature, which will show off things like in-game events, live video streams, and other limited-time features, is also not here yet. It’s labeled with the same asterisk as the other features, saying that it’s “coming later this fall.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gNtlEPzGHNePMDIYLsOI70uprtc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865204/Screen_Shot_2021_09_20_at_12.48.44_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/in-app-events/" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An in-app event shown off on the app’s page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oWZy9y"&gt;iPad users will also have to wait for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523322/apple-wwdc-impressive-drag-and-drop-universal-control-demo"&gt;incredible-looking Universal Control feature&lt;/a&gt;, which seamlessly lets you share a cursor between Macs and iPads. It missing the launch shouldn’t be a surprise: unlike SharePlay, Universal Control didn’t show up in the betas, and the feature also requires the not-yet-released macOS Monterey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UcgnEo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How Universal Control on macOS Monterey works","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bfXTov"&gt;Of course, it’s worth mentioning that two of these features could be waiting on new hardware — another Apple event this fall seems likely, with predictions focusing on new MacBook Pros and AirPods. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676131/apple-2021-rumor-mill-wrong-watch-leaks-airpods"&gt;As I try to remind myself&lt;/a&gt;, rumors should be taken with a grain of salt, but it makes sense that Apple will wait to launch a new version of macOS along with new hardware if it’s really that close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSps2j"&gt;If you want to read more about the features that did make it into iOS and iPadOS 15, check out my colleague Chaim’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;titanic review&lt;/a&gt; of Apple’s new updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="oHhDl3"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ek1RV5"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="IFInUf"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPhone 13 Pro review|103918" data-volume-uuid="eecf5f423" data-volume-id="103918" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-355" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="QhZthT"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPhone 13 and 13 mini review|103917" data-volume-uuid="6d1ccf9c1" data-volume-id="103917" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-341" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684483/ios-15-announced-features-shareplay-airpods-universal-control"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684483/ios-15-announced-features-shareplay-airpods-universal-control</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
