<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to change your iPhone’s text size for a specific app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eTnXvK4Xy-tlW_cO9ot1wSwK5Tw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69592681/cgartenberg_210629_4653_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vtitae"&gt;Sometimes you want the text in your app to be smaller, so you can fit more content on a single screen. Sometimes you want it to be bigger, especially if you’ve been putting off buying those reading glasses. But until recently, if you had an iPhone, you had to pick a single text size as a standard for all your apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2h7Pgx"&gt;Not anymore. In iOS 15, you can adjust the text size separately for each of your apps. So you can, for example, keep the text small for your email, but make it a bit larger in Twitter — or vice versa. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmarShahine/status/1416015722174636033?s=20"&gt;@OmarShahine&lt;/a&gt; for the info.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BTHoFE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;One of the best hidden new iOS 15 features is per app font sizes. I like to use the smallest dynamic size system wide but bump up Outlook by one side since I read so much email. &lt;a href="https://t.co/aL8TxOIXVA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aL8TxOIXVA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Omar Shahine   (@OmarShahine) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmarShahine/status/1416015722174636033?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CUdOGB"&gt;If you’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22524845/ios-15-how-to-install"&gt;the public beta of iOS 15 installed&lt;/a&gt;, here’s how you can adjust the text size for each app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3cDHH"&gt;First, you need to make sure the “Text Size” option is in your iOS Control Center:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Zb85Lz"&gt;Swipe from the upper-right corner to get to your Control Center. Check to see if “Text Size” is there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Q0DBBc"&gt;If it isn’t, then quit Control Center and go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Control Center.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f3J3dO"&gt;Under the “More Controls” subhead, find “Text Size” and tap the plus sign on the left to add it to your included controls. This will add it to your Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="To add Text Size, go to Settings &amp;amp;gt; Control Center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pi_CZZK0lWy_Z0gRc8_4uYmFjTU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722289/IMG_ACABE3FA7DC3_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Control Center,” then find “Text Size” and tap the green plus sign.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Text Size will now be part of the included controls." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QKlHTFYFkBpR78OLt5s9WUBYIAE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722291/IMG_AEE5CFDB6AF2_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Text Size” will now be part of the included controls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5tfcoG"&gt;Once that’s done, it’s simple to tweak the text size for each app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oQxLaT"&gt;Open the app that you want to configure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DcG7Nb"&gt;Swipe from the upper-right corner to get to Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If you need to switch text size, swipe from the upper-right corner." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PBe0WUM-qNKs-DLx27LYg-xbSio=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722286/IMG_7CC84A574C5C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need to switch text size, swipe from the upper-right corner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap the double-A Text Size icon." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ucja2xtAn--TcUc-gFqinNjPH6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722287/IMG_3D147AFAD9D1_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap the double-A “Text Size” icon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Hxmd6X"&gt;Tap the “Text Size” icon (the one with the small and large A’s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="o9wtKb"&gt;At the bottom of the screen, you’ll see a toggle on the left for that specific app (for example, the left side of the toggle will say “Twitter Only,” and the right side will say “All Apps.”) Move the toggle to the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wAo1FX"&gt;Once that’s done, use the main control in the center of the screen to set the text size for that app, and then tap anywhere on the screen to get back to the Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The toggle at the bottom lets you switch text size for a single app." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ghQ69r96AUnAqDvBhOr6gJ1p7UA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722282/IMG_B31FFB1D7C1A_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The toggle at the bottom lets you switch text size for a single app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Now you’ve changed the text size just for that app." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vbCFaIN3K1x3rMcvfSlL0LzroLI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722285/IMG_D714DD00DBB5_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now you’ve changed the text size just for that app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="4jwEe9"&gt;Swipe up to get rid of the Control Center and you’ll return to your app. You should see the difference in the text size immediately — but that difference will not be reflected in other apps.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jWTBAd"&gt;And, of course, if you want to switch back to a standard text size, just go back to the Control Center, select “Text Size,” and move the bottom toggle to “All Apps.” But be aware that you’ll be resetting all your apps to that text size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cEjOQy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22580423/ios-15-iphone-text-size-how-to-control-center"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22580423/ios-15-iphone-text-size-how-to-control-center</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T12:51:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T12:51:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use SharePlay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dDiblckRVLHgrtbBPSEcr9coKKI=/248x0:1652x936/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591839/Screen_Shot_2021_07_16_at_11.24.18_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aFX6H0"&gt;The headline feature for Apple’s fall updates (including iOS 15, iPadOS 15, tvOS 15, and macOS Monterey) is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;SharePlay&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a new software feature on top of FaceTime that allows you to watch and listen to movies, TV shows, music, podcasts, and more with friends and family while video chatting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVhoWh"&gt;Right now, the number of SharePlay-compatible apps is a pretty small list: the Apple TV app for movies and TV shows, the Apple Music app for music, and Apple’s Podcasts app for podcasts. The company is promising some bigger third-party partners when iOS 15 launches this fall, including HBO Max, Disney Plus, Paramount Plus, TikTok, and Twitch. Some big names seem to be skipping out for now, though: most notably, Netflix and YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxxapQ"&gt;For now, if you want to try it, here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wyP4fu"&gt;SharePlay with iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nDvm7iXfkPCtVxPnWrw6IuXTGBo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721826/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_TV_Expanse_originals_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starting playback of a TV episode using SharePlay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yCS1B9wBu4EH2FXYdzECRDF6Xdk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721827/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_TV_Expanse_Messages_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePlay allows you to still use your phone while watching shows together.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c2EF2u"&gt;To use SharePlay on an iPhone or iPad, first, make sure that everyone on the call is using iOS 15 and iPadOS 15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ilfgIM"&gt;Next, start a FaceTime call — either one-on-one or a group call — with everyone you want to watch or listen with. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ea1Yzs"&gt;Once you’ve done that, exit out of the FaceTime call (which will automatically move to a picture-in-picture window) and head over to a SharePlay-compatible app. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n0Od7O"&gt;After that, playing something over SharePlay is as simple as it is when you’re just watching or listening alone: just select whatever content you want, and it’ll play for everyone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Widx5O"&gt;Controlling a SharePlay stream just requires that you play, pause, and skip around as you usually would. SharePlay automatically keeps everyone’s streams in sync so that if one person pauses to get a snack, the movie will pause for everyone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="6qSHbT"&gt;You have two options for ending a stream: either end it for everyone on the SharePlay call or end it just for you (letting everyone else continue to watch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vDOHUv"&gt;SharePlay with macOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="p50DLz"&gt;Using SharePlay on macOS Monterey works similarly to iOS and iPadOS: you’ll need to start a FaceTime call, launch a compatible app, and play some content that everyone on the call can access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HktWcy"&gt;When you’re in a SharePlay session, you’ll be able to access controls for the call through a menu bar icon (instead of the pop-over menu that appears on iOS and iPadOS).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zxtzPYaDijnkIvV6LByNzsFSr-U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721810/Apple_macos_monterey_facetime_06072021_big_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;macOS’s SharePlay menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ni0t4U"&gt;SharePlay with Apple TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2BmoYv"&gt;Using SharePlay with an Apple TV works a little differently than the other platforms, given that you can’t actually start (or participate) on a FaceTime call through an Apple TV itself. Rather, when you’re FaceTiming on a nearby iPhone, iPad, or Mac with SharePlay, the Apple TV will offer you the option to hand off the media portion of that call to the bigger screen through Control Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWqzlT"&gt;To access that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Gzk4BJ"&gt;Simply follow the above steps to start a SharePlay FaceTime call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B3ceKN"&gt;Then press and hold the TV button on your Apple TV remote. From there, you’ll be able to select the new SharePlay icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bzMSmjBnB5ZjwW2NfJYmIZIQ5c8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721815/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_FaceTime_expanse_groupfacetime_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iOS interface when watching a show on an Apple TV while using SharePlay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WjF2c5"&gt;It’s important to note that only the music or movie that you’re watching will shift over to the Apple TV. Your FaceTime video will still be playing on the Mac, iPhone, or iPad that you started with. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22577178/shareplay-how-to-apple-facetime-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-apple-tv-video-music"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22577178/shareplay-how-to-apple-facetime-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-apple-tv-video-music</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T11:53:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T11:53:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Counterfeit wireless earbuds are being seized in record numbers at US border</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XOc9geu894FJNlcKQmF2IgkMZ6s=/0x0:1024x683/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591470/AirPods.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/CBPChicago/status/1407021736089079815/photo/1" target="_blank"&gt;US Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kMwSLT"&gt;The number of counterfeit wireless earbuds seized by US border customs in 2021 has already surpassed last year’s total, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/airpods-are-a-huge-hit-with-consumers-and-counterfeiters"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a sign of how eager the makers of these knockoffs are to keep riding the sustained popularity of earbuds like Apple’s AirPods and those from Samsung, Jabra, Bose, Sony, and other companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftpC8P"&gt;According to the report, “roughly 360,000 counterfeit wireless headphones” — valued at $62.2 million — were nabbed in the first nine months of fiscal 2021. That’s well above the 295,000 pairs that were confiscated during the whole of fiscal 2020. Just yesterday, US Customs and Border Protection &lt;a href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/local-media-release/thousands-fake-apple-airpods-worth-13-million-seized-cincinnati-cbp"&gt;announced a major confiscation&lt;/a&gt; in Cincinnati. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Eyvo0A"&gt;Around 80 percent of fakes entering the US come from China, and their manufacturers see a huge opportunity: &lt;a href="https://news.strategyanalytics.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Strategy-Analytics-True-Wireless-Stereo-Headset-Sales-Surge-90-in-2020-as-Chinese-Vendors-Surge/default.aspx"&gt;Strategy Analytics&lt;/a&gt; forecasted worldwide sales of Bluetooth headsets to be more than 300 million in 2020, and the true wireless earbuds market surged by 90 percent. Apple still holds a commanding lead in market share, though a crowded field has cut into that dominance. Research firm Canalys estimates that Apple took in at least $16 billion from AirPods sales last year, according to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; report. The introduction of the AirPods Pro in 2019 gave scammers a chance to try and wring even more money out of unknowing buyers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xJcpfVFw7_W-F1lW4xc5kJPbDgs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721822/clones.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/local-media-release/331000-worth-fake-airpods-seized-cbp-officers-louisville" target="_blank"&gt;US Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A confiscated shipment of AirPods counterfeits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w5v7lp"&gt;OnePlus had to deal with an awkward controversy last September when US Customs and Border Protection &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/13/21435637/us-cbp-counterfeit-airpods-oneplus-buds-mixup"&gt;seized a shipment of the company’s earbuds&lt;/a&gt; and described them as counterfeit AirPods. There are design differences between the two, but the blatant AirPod clones are getting closer and closer to the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LcIAZ"&gt;Some counterfeit earbuds are suspected to have been created “with genuine molds stolen from factories that work with Apple.” Others can mimic the AirPods pairing process on an iPhone and display a proper Apple serial number. But even in these situations, there are still subtle tells (like a bogus firmware version) that reveal a product as a fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DlzhRG"&gt;Highlighting the potential safety risks, Apple says it has a global effort in place to tackle the issue of knockoffs, and it’s working with law enforcement and e-commerce sites to prevent customers from being duped wherever possible. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580089/counterfeit-wireless-earbuds-apple-airpods-us-border"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580089/counterfeit-wireless-earbuds-apple-airpods-us-border</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T08:32:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T08:32:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713 is on sale for $619 at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Acer Chromebook Spin 713 open on a table angled to the right. The screen displays a blue background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0K4bRMF8uE3X0TwniTvSRsb_E8o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69590268/mchin_20190815_4597_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="b9pekq"&gt;Whether you’d like to admit it or not, school is quickly approaching. And if you’re in need of a reliable laptop that won’t force you to completely deplete your savings, Chromebooks aren’t a bad way to go. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; deliver great value for the money, and many offer terrific performance for far less than you would pay for a more premium machine. Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713 is one such device, even if the high-end convertible is one of the more expensive Chromebooks on the market right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aEUc0Y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746320001237385626#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Currently discounted at Best Buy to $619&lt;/a&gt;, the 2021 model packs in 8GB of RAM, 256GB of storage, and an Intel 11th Gen Core i5, which is more than enough processing power for most people. Moreover, it boasts a great keyboard and a brilliant 3:2 screen, along with two USB-C Thunderbolt 4 ports and enough battery life for a full day in the classroom — virtual or otherwise. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22451261/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VhFupn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10652856"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Y8bnup"&gt;
&lt;p id="CDZr8x"&gt;Like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328436/apple-discontinues-original-homepod-mini" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;now-discontinued HomePod,&lt;/a&gt; the HomePod Mini is somewhat easy to forget. Apple’s pint-sized answer to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Echo Dot&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google Nest Mini&lt;/a&gt; still produces good sound for its size, though, and Siri remains a viable alternative to Alexa and Google Assistant, despite lagging behind when it comes to features and functionality. The compact smart speaker also plays nice with HomeKit-compatible devices and Apple Music, rendering it a device really built for those who are already entrenched in the Apple ecosystem. Normally $100, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1598683-REG%2Fapple_aphomepmsg_homepod_mini_space_gray.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F7%2F16%2F22577815%2Facer-chromebook-spin-713-apple-homepod-mini-microsoft-xbox-wireless-controller-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo is offering a rare $10 discount&lt;/a&gt; on Home Pod Mini, bringing the price down to $90 for a limited time. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wq8lTq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10613508"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XVNEKs"&gt;
&lt;p id="xpKyaN"&gt;With COVID-19 restrictions easing and in-person gatherings become more commonplace again, now might not be a bad time to pick up an extra controller for your Xbox One, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt;, or Windows 10 machine. Thankfully, the black incarnation of Microsoft’s latest Xbox Wireless Controller is compatible with all three and remains available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Wireless-Controller-Shock-Blue-one/dp/B08DF248LD/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fxbox-wireless-controller%2F8xn59crbsqgz%3FranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26ranSiteID%3DVZfI20jEa0c-HbHu3oCkeQ1z2svgZK2uRQ%26epi%3DVZfI20jEa0c-HbHu3oCkeQ1z2svgZK2uRQ%26irgwc%3D1%26OCID%3DAID2200057_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%2528ir__iglaeqnhj9kfq1cckk0sohzif22xudv630gxj2fe00%2529%25287593%2529%25281243925%2529%2528VZfI20jEa0c-HbHu3oCkeQ1z2svgZK2uRQ%2529%2528%2529%26irclickid%3D_iglaeqnhj9kfq1cckk0sohzif22xudv630gxj2fe00" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Store for $49&lt;/a&gt;, matching its second-lowest price. Unlike the previous model, the new-ish controller features a textured grip, USB-C support, and a dedicated Share button, letting you quickly capture and share your content with the press of a button. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21452750/microsoft-xbox-series-x-controller-1tb-expansion-cards-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our hands-on review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J4fR6X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10654449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="4fAUAS"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="L0gV2b"&gt;Other deals of note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="E8iykG"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-13697508?url=https://sellout.woot.com/offers/echo-dot-3rd-gen-smart-speaker-with-alexa-38?ref=w_cnt_wp_0_5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon’s third-gen Echo Dot is on sale at Woot for $25&lt;/a&gt;, one of the better prices we’ve seen on the last-gen Echo device outside of Prime Day. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/12/17965806/amazon-echo-dot-3rd-gen-review-alexa-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0oKQ96"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-AirPods-Max-Space/dp/B08PZD76NP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; are available at Amazon in two color configurations (blue or pink) for $465, their lowest price yet. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LPAb7Q"&gt;Woot is offering &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13140756?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fring-video-doorbell-3z%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_lnd_cat_elec_1_7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;42 percent off a used Ring Video Doorbell 3&lt;/a&gt;, knocking the final sale price down to $105. It comes with a 90-day warranty, a far cry from Amazon’s one-year warranty, but Amazon has inspected and verified the condition of each unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CINGB8"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Adapter-Anker-High-Speed-Transfer-Notebook/dp/B08HZ6PS61/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two-pack of Anker’s USB-C adapters&lt;/a&gt; is $9 at Amazon, the lowest price we’ve yet on the basic but convenient peripherals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="q6dHZb"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08FJ7XY3B/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hori’s Split Pad Pro&lt;/a&gt; is $40 at Amazon, matching its best-ever price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20871866/hori-split-pad-pro-controller-nintendo-switch-daemon-x-machina-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mMDGeS"&gt;Jabra’s Elite 85T earbuds are $180 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08HR78C46/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746238517520792548#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, the second-lowest price we’ve seen on the excellent true wireless earbuds. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rnEUsO"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/HyperX-Cloud-Alpha-Adjustable-Leatherette/dp/B081D8TPZZ/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=12&amp;amp;imprToken=eabd5672-7a80-8c5b-a29&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22339428%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/authors%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HyperX’s Cloud Alpha S&lt;/a&gt; is available at Amazon for $90, nearly matching the best-ever price on the wired gaming headset. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/25/21191577/hyperx-cloud-alpha-s-gaming-headset-black-pc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2IfXVt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fblue-yeti-usb-mic-for-recording-streaming-1%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_lnd_cat_elec_1_9%26utm_medium%3Daffiliate%26utm_campaign%3DCJ%26cjevent%3D1e266fcde5d411eb8310809d0a1c0e0d%26utm_source%3DVox%2BMedia&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F7%2F16%2F22577815%2Facer-chromebook-spin-713-apple-homepod-mini-microsoft-xbox-wireless-controller-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Blue’s Yeti mic&lt;/a&gt; is on sale at Woot for $100, one of the better prices we’ve seen on the tried-and-true microphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="vuo79G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/16/22577815/acer-chromebook-spin-713-apple-homepod-mini-microsoft-xbox-wireless-controller-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/16/22577815/acer-chromebook-spin-713-apple-homepod-mini-microsoft-xbox-wireless-controller-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T02:48:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T02:48:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xiaomi overtakes Apple as number two smartphone vendor for first time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RoEJx-ejU8P8R7snEItUUlFIHFo=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69589716/DSCF5698.jpg_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A phone repair store at a technology market in Shenzhen, China. | Photo by Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F52BFY"&gt;Xiaomi is now the second largest smartphone vendor based on worldwide shipments in the second quarter of 2021, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/global-smartphone-market-q2-2021?ctid=2143-0b9f92413ead631983febced55e12cd8"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; from Canalys. The Chinese company captured 17 percent of global market share, according to the research firm, just behind Samsung’s 19 percent but ahead of Apple’s 14 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8gn7Ak"&gt;BBK’s Oppo and Vivo rounded out the list of top five vendors at 10 percent apiece. All five companies grew their shipments year on year, but what’s notable is just how much Xiaomi has managed to increase its volume — it shipped 83 percent more phones than in Q2 2020, whereas Samsung grew shipments 15 percent and Apple by just one percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vxj4as"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We've moved up one more spot! Just in from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Canalys?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Canalys&lt;/a&gt;, we are now the 2nd largest smartphone brand worldwide in terms of shipments. This amazing milestone couldn't have been achieved without our beloved Mi Fans! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NoMiWithoutYou?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NoMiWithoutYou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;RT with ✌️from your Xiaomi smartphone :) &lt;a href="https://t.co/kKfuTK8K7J"&gt;pic.twitter.com/kKfuTK8K7J&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Xiaomi (@Xiaomi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Xiaomi/status/1415731357368471553?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iXhzMt"&gt;“Xiaomi is growing its overseas business rapidly,” Canalys Research Manager Ben Stanton says, citing sales boosts in regions including Western Europe, Africa, and Latin America. “It is still largely skewed toward the mass market, however, and compared with Samsung and Apple, its average selling price is around 40% and 75% cheaper respectively. So a major priority for Xiaomi this year is to grow sales of its high-end devices, such as the Mi 11 Ultra.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McMFbf"&gt;Canalys says global smartphone shipments grew by 12 percent last quarter. Much of the growth seen by smartphone makers is at the expense of Huawei, however, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/30/21114885/huawei-overtakes-apple-2019-analysts-strategy-analytics-counterpoint-research-canalys"&gt;itself overtook Apple in 2019&lt;/a&gt; but has since been essentially shut out of the worldwide market due to US-imposed sanctions and trading bans. So far, Xiaomi appears to be the biggest beneficiary.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579771/worldwide-smartphone-market-share-ranking-q2-2022-canalys-xiaomi-apple-samsung"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579771/worldwide-smartphone-market-share-ranking-q2-2022-canalys-xiaomi-apple-samsung</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-15T17:42:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T17:42:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple employees say the company is cracking down on remote work</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kxNmtVq_JC4s00f9NPfwg0RmLZs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69588204/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="74nfy4"&gt;Apple employees say it’s harder than ever to get remote work requests approved after the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;rolled out a new hybrid model&lt;/a&gt; that will require people to return to the office three days a week starting in early September. Some employees say they will quit if Apple doesn’t change its stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YNMKlT"&gt;While Apple historically discouraged employees from working from home, there were one-off exceptions to the rule, and some teams were more lenient than others. Now, employees say that even those exceptions are being denied. In a company Slack channel where employees advocate for remote work, roughly 10 people said they were resigning due to the hybrid work policy or knew others who’d been forced to quit. The Slack channel currently has more than 6,000 members. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hkEz0"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560586/apple-hybrid-work-internal-survey-tim-cook"&gt;survey on remote work&lt;/a&gt; conducted by employees in June, 36.7 percent of respondents said they were worried they’d have to leave Apple due to the lack of flexibility (1,735 people answered the question).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBg79W"&gt;The return-to-work plan has already been a flashpoint at Apple, where employees wrote a letter in June asking Apple CEO Tim Cook to reevaluate the hybrid model. Deirdre O’Brien, senior vice president of retail and people, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22556615/apple-response-hybrid-work-model-employee-letter-remote"&gt;sent a video in response&lt;/a&gt; saying that in-person collaboration was “essential” and noting the company would not be backing away from its current approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="M1xHzX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I will be out of a job in September”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HielYm"&gt;While Apple’s corporate employees certainly have more flexibility than the retail staff, some say it’s out of step with other big tech companies in Silicon Valley. Twitter and Facebook have already announced a permanent work-from-home policy, and Apple employees say they’ve been flooded with recruiting messages from other tech organizations eyeing a potential opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ld1Cht"&gt;One employee said they were currently on an Americans with Disabilities Act accommodation that allowed them to work from home, but were told that accommodation would be denied when the company went back to the office. “I will be out of a job in September,” they wrote in Slack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4jt11t"&gt;Apple typically gives employees 30 days to find a new job within the company if their current team denies a medical accommodation. But one worker said in Slack that there weren’t any open remote positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRBKN7"&gt;Some employees say they were told only people with documented medical conditions would be approved for permanent remote work. But the form that Apple employees use to request such an accommodation asks them to release their medical records to the company, which made some people uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LoIqvo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Things I'd never sign: &lt;a href="https://t.co/4KUv2DVQTT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4KUv2DVQTT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cher Scarlett (@cherthedev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1415798144726671360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oU6QlI"&gt;Now, employees are discussing how to get Apple’s attention. Some suggested writing another letter to reiterate their concerns, while others have discussed talking to lawyers about possible legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ToWXQ8"&gt;Apple declined to comment for this story. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578804/apple-employees-work-from-home-request-denied-hybrid-model"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578804/apple-employees-work-from-home-request-denied-hybrid-model</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-15T10:39:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T10:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elago’s Siri Remote case has room for an AirTag tracker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RuoLHyBDPGfB8zRCoAsmhJzZeNQ=/164x0:1946x1188/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69585417/siri_remote_airtag_case.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;PREMIUM SILICONE! | Image: Elago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xpvVDC"&gt;Apple’s new Siri Remote arrived &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22448388/apple-tv-4k-siri-remote-no-uwb-u1-couch-thickness"&gt;without a built-in locator chip&lt;/a&gt;, so Elago has created the next best thing: the &lt;a href="https://www.elago.com/apple-tv/2021-apple-tv-siri-remote-r5-case-black-1"&gt;R5 silicone case&lt;/a&gt; with a slot for Apple’s new AirTag tracker. According to Elago, it features a “THICK LAYER OF PREMIUM SILICONE,” which is so dense it can only be expressed in caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCD7LC"&gt;The $14.99 price doesn’t include the cost of the $29 AirTag, but it does promise to put an end to lost Siri remotes, especially if you own an iPhone fitted with UWB to enable precision tracking. It costs a lot more than &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.aliexpress.com%2Faf%2Fsiri-remote-airtag-case.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F15%2F22578412%2Fapple-tv-remote-airtag-case-price-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;comparable AirTag cases available on AliExpress&lt;/a&gt; that list for just a few dollars, but well, this one can be &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/elago-Locator-Compatible-Remote-AirTag/dp/B097WZQV1Z/?tag=9to5toys03-20%5C" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;found on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for whatever that’s worth. Alternatively, you could always &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/5/10/22429238/apple-tv-siri-remote-airtag-case-combine-3d-print-design"&gt;just 3D-print your own case&lt;/a&gt; if you’re in more of a DIY mood. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578412/apple-tv-remote-airtag-case-price-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578412/apple-tv-remote-airtag-case-price-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-14T21:12:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-14T21:12:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon adds AirPlay 2 and HomeKit to two Fire TV Edition TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GRIl6CVdBf_cSWN_jAr9Ezf2gMA=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69584030/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zXQ8jp"&gt;Amazon is adding support for AirPlay 2 and HomeKit to two of its Fire TV Edition TVs in a free update, the company &lt;a href="https://amazonfiretv.blog/apple-airplay-2-and-homekit-now-available-on-toshiba-and-insignia-4k-uhd-smart-fire-tv-2020-models-89188a0b0fb3"&gt;announced on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. Both the 2020 Toshiba 4K UHD Smart Fire TV with Dolby Vision and the 2020 Insignia 4K UHD Smart TV will receive the features, before they arrive on Amazon’s less expensive Fire TV sticks and set-top boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y7OgeT"&gt;On these specific TV sets, AirPlay 2 should function the same on Apple’s own Apple TV, allowing you to send audio and video from your phone, tablet, or computer to the big screen and control playback from your device. Integrating with HomeKit, Apple’s smart home ecosystem, requires a little extra legwork: you’ll have to enable HomeKit in your TV’s settings under Display &amp;amp; Sounds &amp;gt; AirPlay &amp;amp; HomeKit &amp;gt; Set Up, and then add it as a device in the Home app. Once it’s added, you can use Siri to turn your Fire TV on and off, change the volume, or switch inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSRKpf"&gt;Both AirPlay 2 and HomeKit coming to Fire TVs (and hopefully, one day soon, Fire TV sticks) should make using the TVs with Apple’s devices that much easier. Apple already has an in with Amazon’s devices — the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20930244/apple-tv-app-amazon-fire-tv-stick-models-now-available"&gt;Apple TV Plus app came to Fire TVs&lt;/a&gt; in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BX6Z41"&gt;It’s a stark contrast to how these two companies were interacting a little over five years ago, Back then, Amazon had banned sales of competing hardware like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/2/9439281/amazon-ban-apple-tv-chromecast-why"&gt;Apple TV (and Chromecast, and Nexus Player)&lt;/a&gt; in its marketplace because it claimed it was important to only sell media players that “interact well” with Prime Video. The companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/12/14/16777508/amazon-brings-back-apple-tv-google-chromecast"&gt;have since reconciled&lt;/a&gt;, and reached a very favorable deal &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21348108/apple-amazon-prime-video-app-store-special-treatment-fee-subscriptions"&gt;for Amazon that allows it to avoid Apple’s 30 percent App Store commission&lt;/a&gt; and use its own in-app purchase system. Now things are better. At least if you own an iPhone and Fire TV. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577986/amazon-airplay-2-homekit-fire-tv-edition-toshiba-insignia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577986/amazon-airplay-2-homekit-fire-tv-edition-toshiba-insignia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-14T15:56:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-14T15:56:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s latest iOS and macOS betas undo some of Safari’s controversial new design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ex3ewRdUIaBcOxNm-UnH4abg61M=/105x0:3255x2100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69582867/safari.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hy5JjJ"&gt;Apple has released its third developer betas for the upcoming iOS 15 and macOS Monterey, and they bring some much-needed fixes to Safari — namely, undoing some of the more controversial changes introduced in the earlier betas. For macOS, that means a normal tab bar that goes back to the previous design, while iOS is getting a more consistent design when it comes to the URL bar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJjTt2"&gt;iOS 15 is still sticking with its new tab view and the moved URL bar on the bottom of the display, but the latest beta docked it there permanently, instead of bouncing it to the top of the screen when you selected it. Apple’s also added a new refresh option to the pop-over menu when you tap and hold the URL bar. Together, the changes help make the new design a lot more cohesive to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SkcnTe"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As expected, Apple is continuing to tweak the design of Safari in iOS 15.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In beta 3, the address bar is now docked above the keyboard. There is a new search UI and support for quick website searches too. Getting better! &lt;a href="https://t.co/Tm562Djr0i"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Tm562Djr0i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Federico Viticci (@viticci) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1415368283793109000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B1Xser"&gt;The change to macOS is simpler: Apple &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/14/macos-monterey-beta-3-brings-redesigned-safari-tab-interface-to-address-complaints/"&gt;seems to have just brought back&lt;/a&gt; part of its Big Sur design for Safari’s URL bar and tabs, ditching the combined tab/URL bar setup that it debuted in the earlier betas. In the latest beta, there’s once again a URL bar that lives at the top of each Safari menu, with a row of tabs beneath it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MEwSEr"&gt;Each of those tabs still takes up a decently large piece of real estate — the overall Monterey design is the same in that regard — but it’s definitely an improvement over the original betas. That said, if you preferred the new design, that’s still an option too, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/14/revert-safari-redesign-macos-monterey-beta-3/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OI0lCV"&gt;Unchanged, at least for now, is the iPadOS version of Safari. Given that Apple isn’t expected to fully release its latest OS updates until the fall, though, there’s still plenty of time for additional changes to Safari across all of Apple’s platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aAShaI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577475/apple-safari-macos-monterey-ios-15-developer-beta-3-change-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577475/apple-safari-macos-monterey-ios-15-developer-beta-3-change-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-14T14:48:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-14T14:48:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLjcArAq4sGebo8JT2J9VP6QFsQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66976955/vpavic_200930_4216_0258.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Product Red edition of the Series 6 is one of many Apple Watches currently on sale. | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0b7sTV"&gt;Thinking about picking up a new Apple Watch? It’s never a bad idea to wait until there’s a good deal, and thankfully, those happen with some regularity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtR5HF"&gt;There are currently three Apple Watch models to choose from, all of which support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21294434/apple-watchos-7-features-sleep-tracking-face-sharing-fitness-apps-2020"&gt;watchOS 7&lt;/a&gt;. The latest model — and the highest end — is the Apple Watch Series 6 with GPS and cellular connectivity, which starts at $399. If that seems too expensive, you can save about $120 by opting for an Apple Watch SE, which also launched in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Im58vs"&gt;Finally, there’s the three-year-old &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Series 3&lt;/a&gt;, the most affordable Apple Watch to date. It has a starting retail price of $199, but it frequently goes on sale. However, if you want something more future-proof, you may want to consider the other two watches, as it’s not clear how much longer Apple will issue software updates to the Series 3 beyond &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;watchOS 8&lt;/a&gt;. Regardless of which model you prefer, we’ve rounded up the best Apple Watch deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ZqOTAE"&gt;The highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="bRFJnd"&gt;Apple Watch Series 3 (38mm, GPS): $168 at &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-38mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F499753351%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;s&gt;$199&lt;/s&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lREHEL"&gt;Apple Watch SE (40mm, GPS, white): $269 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5XX59T/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-40mm-Silver-Aluminum-Case-with-White-Sport-Band-Regular%2F555062032%3Fselected%3Dtrue%26irgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_xzpTrIW%253AoxyLRAEwUx0Mo36cUkBwh-RgExnTVM0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3DxzpTrIW%253AoxyLRAEwUx0Mo36cUkBwh-RgExnTVM0%26sharedid%3D%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;sharedid=VergeBestAppleWatchDeals060721" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;s&gt;$279&lt;/s&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BR7xFN"&gt;Apple Watch Series 6 (40mm, GPS, red): $319 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J5RBMRN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-Sport-Band-Regular%2F478251261%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; ($&lt;s&gt;399&lt;/s&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="ParVAK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to install the watchOS 8 public beta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22558944/watchos-beta-install-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="OlUIlK"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Apple Watch Series 3&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="c2iEiy"&gt;The regular price for the 38mm Series 3 is $199 ($229 for the 42mm), which is a decent price. It’s a great entry-level Apple Watch if you are looking for a smartwatch with reliable battery life and excellent build quality, especially if the SE and Series 6 seem out of your price range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HTWFvq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q5eI6X"&gt;Currently, the 38mm Series 3 is $168 at &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-38mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F499753351%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; in either white or black, which is $31 off its usual price of $199. If you are looking for the Series 3 in 42mm, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-38mm-Space-Aluminium/dp/B07K3HG6T9/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-42mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F742230355%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; have knocked the price down from $229 to $199.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3G29qi"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GaARPa"&gt;Starting at $279 for a 40mm version or $309 for the 44mm, the Apple Watch SE is a good midrange wearable that shares some features found on the like-minded Series 6, including a built-in accelerometer and hand-washing detection. However, it doesn’t have the always-on display found on Apple’s flagship, nor does it feature blood oxygen monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qq3ebV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ikPbUG"&gt;Right now, you can pick up the 40mm, GPS-equipped white version of the SE for $269 at both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5XX59T/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-40mm-Silver-Aluminum-Case-with-White-Sport-Band-Regular%2F555062032%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking for the larger GPS model, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=38733&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fapple-watch-se-gps-44mm%2Fprod25100056" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sam’s Club has several configurations&lt;/a&gt; of the 44mm model available for $300, a slight discount exclusive to members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rUGNYm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="xtEsXh"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Gold-Aluminum-Case-with-Pink-Sand-Sport-Band-Regular%2F804932402%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt; Watch Series 6&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oTrUCf"&gt;The flagship Apple Watch comes in two sizes, 40mm and 44mm, which start at $399 and $429, respectively. The Apple Watch Series 6 features built-in sleep tracking, a great ecosystem of third-party complications, and more sensors than previous models, including one that allows the device to detect your body's blood oxygen levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PfLoQg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9432291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="60XJAV"&gt;Right now, deals are relatively scarce on the Series 6. If you don’t mind a bit of vibrancy on your wrist, however, the 40mm, GPS-enabled red configuration is on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J5RBMRN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-Sport-Band-Regular%2F478251261%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; for $319. You can also snag the larger, 44mm upgrade at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J5P53JK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-44mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-PRODUCT-RED-Sport-Band-Regular%2F847051571%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; for $349, slightly more than its best-ever price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hjNY0P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
