<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>What is the new Apple Music Voice plan, and who is it for? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oPgqtP1eofYR_1L0cCWkwBn9-1o=/0x87:1306x958/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015526/Apple_HomePod_mini_Apple_Music_Voice_AirPods_3rd_gen_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Music Voice relies entirely on your dulcet tones to play music from any Siri-enabled device&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BKzS5L"&gt;The new Apple Music Voice plan that Apple announced at its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"&gt;“Unleashed” event&lt;/a&gt; on Monday is causing some confusion. I’m here to help you understand this new, cheaper option, which capitalizes on the power of Apple’s smart voice assistant, Siri (don’t laugh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dfonFq"&gt;Put simply, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri"&gt;Apple Music Voice plan&lt;/a&gt; is a voice control-only access to the service’s catalog of 90 million songs. It arrives later this year, and with it, you can play everything — full albums, individual songs, Apple’s playlists; it’s all-you-can-eat Apple Music. The caveat is you have to use your voice to control it, and you have to play it through a Siri-enabled device, such as a HomePod Mini (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"&gt;now in some spiffy new colors&lt;/a&gt;), AirPods, or an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtGi64"&gt;What it is not is a fee to use Siri to play your own music. If you have tracks purchased through or stored on iTunes, you can still play those with the Apple Music app and control them with voice, as before. What paying for this service does is add access to the company’s streaming catalog for a lower price than its Individual or Family plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="anApKx"&gt;Apple Music Voice seems best suited to casual listeners who don’t spend hours carefully curating playlists and just want to listen to some music on the fly. While you can request specific songs and albums, you can also just say, “Hey, Siri plays some ’90s Britpop” or “Hey Siri, play something chill.” There’s also access to Apple Radio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i3X4-3Zt9-7jRKtrziV3ZJqGzuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938603/Apple_HomePod_mini_hero_5up_10182021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HomePod Mini is a Siri-enabled smart speaker you can use to play songs on the Apple Music Voice plan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CNpJMp"&gt;The most significant difference between the two plans — beyond price: one is $4.99, and one is $9.99 — is access to the Apple Music app. With the Voice plan, you can’t open the Apple Music app, search for an artist or song, and select a track. Instead, you have to ask Siri to play the song you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lboR5"&gt;You can use the Apple Music app to see a queue of recently played music and suggestions for using Siri to control your music. There are also “suggestions based on the listener’s music preferences” that include limited content available for playback through the app, &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-introduces-the-apple-music-voice-plan/"&gt;according to Apple&lt;/a&gt;. Apple hasn’t shared how exactly this will look or work yet, so we’ll have to wait for the service to roll out to test it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IFaIVk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The cheaper plan doesn’t let you create playlists&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l42mQc"&gt;The cheaper plan also doesn’t let you create your own playlists, manage your playback queue, download songs to your library, scroll the lyrics on your iPhone or iPad, or stream from any third-party speakers (such as Google Nest Hub, which does support the full Apple Music plan). It also won’t play some of the higher-quality audio formats available in Apple Music, such as lossless and spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wT27Qb"&gt;You can use Apple AirPlay to play music through any and all AirPlay 2-enabled speakers you might have — which makes this plan a notch better than Amazon’s similar voice-only music streaming service. That plan — the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GKLDPRYNF2VUAKMM"&gt;Amazon Music Unlimited Single Device Plan&lt;/a&gt; — costs $3.99 to access Amazon Music’s catalog, but you can only play it on one Echo or Fire TV device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJCX2r"&gt;What’s unique about both these voice streaming plans is that you can just buy a smart speaker — an Amazon Echo or a HomePod Mini — plug it in, and ask it to play music. (You can literally say, “Hey Siri, start my Apple Music Voice trial” and be up and running.) This takes away a lot of friction from getting going with streaming music, providing an easy set-up for someone who’s not very techie. It will probably make a great gift for your parents this Christmas if you’re tired of listening to The Eagles on their FM radio every time you visit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFg4eY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>2021 MacBook Pros compared: how Apple’s laptops stack up</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="macbook pro 2012" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6fylJ4YurnOJCx0mBtJCSSD6stI=/94x0:547x302/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70014785/macbook-pro-2012.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kOeI7V"&gt;Apple just announced new versions of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;14-inch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; explicitly designed around their new Arm-based &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;M1 Pro and M1 Max CPUs&lt;/a&gt;. Both models are configurable with either CPU and can be equipped with up to 8TB of storage. Models that use the M1 Pro can have up to 32GB of unified memory, while models that have the M1 Max can be configured to have up to 64GB. They also feature more powerful speakers and a greater selection of ports, making them more versatile than the MacBooks that only offered USB-C ports with Thunderbolt 4. (You no longer need a dongle for HDMI or SD cards.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GkmecT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 8 biggest announcements from Apple’s Unleashed event ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5Ddl9e"&gt;The last generation of MacBook Pro still has plenty of power, and for a while was the best option in terms of connectivity for Apple laptops. However, the advent of the M1 CPU in last year’s 13-inch MacBook Pro has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;changed what we expect from our MacBooks&lt;/a&gt;, a new bar that currently can’t be met by the older Intel and AMD-based MacBooks in most ways. If you’re a long-time Apple user, it’s hard to go wrong by upgrading to anything that uses the Apple Silicon architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmSAUp"&gt;While all of the MacBooks currently available on the Apple store use some form of the M1 CPU, they’re all just a little bit different, so to help you weigh your options, we’ve put together charts comparing every current MacBook you can buy on the Apple Store, as well as another chart comparing current models to their predecessors if you’re someone that’s been waiting to upgrade. We even threw in the last MacBook Pro that included an HDMI port to show just how far we’ve come since 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ADr6g8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10814420"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YTFcSm"&gt;The new Pros have made some excellent strides in terms of their displays, with 120Hz refresh rates in all the available models, as well as improving the resolution and significantly raising the max brightness. The webcam has also received an upgrade to 1080p. While it’s no surprise that the new versions of the MacBook Pro trump their predecessors in just about every category in terms of performance, the race gets a little more competitive when stacking up the models that you can currently get on the Apple Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7YvwrL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10814467"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KPFrjb"&gt;The M1 Air is the most sensible option for users that want a budget-friendly laptop. Unless you need a brighter display, better audio, or battery life, there's little reason to go with the 13-inch version of the MacBook Pro. However, this new breed of MacBook Pro definitely makes a more convincing argument for spending the extra cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7Rmezh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Want a fully specced-out MacBook Pro? You’ll have to pay more than $6,000 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733173/macbook-pro-specced-out-high-end-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="2YSsqB"&gt;At the lower end of the spectrum, the starting configuration for the 14-inch MacBook Pro costs twice as much as the MacBook Air, but has a larger screen with better resolution and far more ports. You also get twice the amount of memory and storage right out of the gate. The main drawback of opting for the 14-inch Pro is that it's slightly heavier and won’t last quite as long between charges when compared to its smaller siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="x2CEmy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="72notT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814228"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cBrcIE"&gt;For an additional $500, the starting price of the 16-inch MacBook Pro will net you many of the same benefits, with the same amount of memory and storage to start, just with a slightly better processor. While the battery of the 16-inch Pro has more staying power, this model is easily the heaviest out of the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aEFgd5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Bwec7n"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IXkbvP"&gt;There are plenty of reasons to spring for a new MacBook Pro, especially if you’ve been biding your time with an older model. The M1 CPU is certainly worth the investment, but unless you can’t live without a dedicated HDMI port, or need a particularly powerful laptop, the MacBook Air is probably the way to go. However, if you’re a power-user or creator that needs bleeding-edge performance, the new 16-inch MacBook Pro seems like the clear winner — we’ll find out for sure in our upcoming reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SPsOcf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple finally listened to the pros","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xIQCKp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZTeou"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V5e6vB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T08:27:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T08:27:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new 140W charger can fast charge a lot more than just your MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2mgx7QZTzDUej-vXITdzXMtgqEE=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70014599/MLYU3_AV1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new 140W charger.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eXiYsp"&gt;Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYU3AM/A/140w-usb-c-power-adapter?fnode=734a3f2e2d2e806ace8f7808dbb8ba4fd9782dff052da988f418e42ddc3d1a858ec62035f6c5248f220833045d3ac0aab4b093470d39f30395579a4d66521e498d4f45ce651cc927ed283f18e9ec2f2910ffce4b0b4892e5732214994c235270"&gt;140W charging brick&lt;/a&gt;, which works with a new MagSafe charging cable to power the new 16-inch MacBook Pro, uses the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702453/usb-c-pd-240-watt-charging-usb4-data-transfer-logo-branding-standard"&gt;USB-C Power Delivery 3.1 standard&lt;/a&gt;, Apple has confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. As well as being included with the new 16-inch MacBook Pro, the brick is available separately for $99 (not including the USB-C-to-MagSafe cable, which costs &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYV3AM/A/usb-c-to-magsafe-3-cable-2-m"&gt;an extra $49&lt;/a&gt;). Meanwhile, the new 14-inch MacBook Pros come with 67W and 96W chargers, depending on the exact model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLZfCM"&gt;Using the USB-C PD 3.1 standard means Apple’s new charging brick will be cross compatible with other devices that use the same power delivery standard, which was announced earlier this year alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/5/25/22453936/usb-c-power-delivery-extended-power-range-epr"&gt;USB Type-C Release 2.1 specification&lt;/a&gt;. It also means that MacBook owners have the flexibility of using compatible third-party charging bricks with the new MacBooks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8iaKOdN_yKeIIFl_jD6OuOE_oHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938315/MLYU3_AV2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 140W charger has a single USB-C port.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pFmzYu"&gt;That hasn’t been the case with some USB-C laptop fast chargers in the past, which have had to go off-spec to offer charging speeds over 100W (the previous cap on the USB-C Power Delivery spec). My colleague Sean Hollister, for example, has a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/5/25/22453936/usb-c-power-delivery-extended-power-range-epr#:~:text=Previously%2C%20the%20USB,Leaving%20100W%20behind"&gt;Dell dock that outputs 130W&lt;/a&gt;, but it won’t work with other laptops because there previously wasn’t an open standard to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rw0ChM"&gt;As well as its use of the USB-C PD 3.1 standard, Apple also confirmed that the brick is its first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/1/18051974/gallium-nitride-anker-material-silicon-semiconductor-energy"&gt;gallium nitride (GaN)&lt;/a&gt; charger, which means it’s using the material that allows companies to build higher-powered chargers that are smaller in size than their traditional counterparts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BChu3D"&gt;As well as the specs of the charging brick, Apple also confirmed that any of the new MacBooks’ Thunderbolt 4 ports can be used to charge the laptops. On the 14-inch MacBook Pro, these ports can be used for fast charging; but fast charging the 16-inch MacBook Pro requires using MagSafe 3 and the 140W adapter because the Thunderbolt 4 predates the USB-C PD 3.1 standard and tops out at 100W. Lower wattage chargers will be able to provide power to the MacBooks, but Apple says charging may be slower or could even result in power drain if the laptop is using more power than it’s being provided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGg6qx"&gt;Additionally, Apple says that the magnets used in the MagSafe 3 connector are stronger than the previous generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taqmIz"&gt;All in all, it’s great news for anyone planning on buying one of Apple’s new MacBooks; they’ll get a capable fast charger that can power other devices and also aren’t restricted to using Apple’s own brick to charge their laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734233/apple-140w-macbook-charging-brick-gan-usb-c-pd-3-1-third-party-chargers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734233/apple-140w-macbook-charging-brick-gan-usb-c-pd-3-1-third-party-chargers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T07:30:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T07:30:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple updates iMovie to adjust focus in iPhone cinematic mode footage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gr5SwDSEwT7Dzjn67dnacsKoKF4=/73x0:2197x1416/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70014408/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_12.17.21_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dTR5rg"&gt;Apple has updated the iMovie app for Macs to let users edit and adjust the focus in videos recorded using the iPhone 13’s new “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673545/iphone-13-pro-camera-cinematic-mode-video-features-macro"&gt;cinematic mode&lt;/a&gt;” — though you’ll need to wait until you can update to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725047/macos-monterey-release-date-compatibility-features-m1-pro-max-chip"&gt;the latest macOS Monterey on October 25th&lt;/a&gt; to take advantage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8ZSRt"&gt;Introduced in September with the latest clutch of iPhones, cinematic mode uses machine learning to automatically pull focus to the key part of a frame (usually whatever face is biggest and turned towards the camera). It also lets people tap their phone screen to adjust the focal point while recording, and during playback after the video has been shot. Now, iMovie users who have the latest macOS Monterey will be able to make those same adjustments on their computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SGthhm"&gt;Here are the &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/-/id408981434"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for iMovie 10.3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="V3aGZj"&gt;Cinematic Mode&lt;br&gt;• Edit videos recorded on iPhone 13 in Cinematic mode (requires macOS Monterey)&lt;br&gt;• Use the Cinematic control in the inspector to modify the intensity of the depth effect&lt;br&gt;• Choose to focus on faces or other objects by selecting them in the viewer&lt;br&gt;• View and delete focus points in the video timeline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fnvs9Z"&gt;Optimized for Apple silicon&lt;br&gt;• Improved performance and efficiency with optimizations for M1 Pro and M1 Max on the new MacBook Pro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="wZMOhD"&gt;Also of note: iMovie has been optimized for the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;M1 Pro and M1 Max chips&lt;/a&gt;, just like &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/uk/newsroom/2021/10/final-cut-pro-and-logic-pro-updated-on-the-new-macbook-pro-with-m1-pro-m1-max/"&gt;Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The new chips are Apple’s most powerful yet (just like every year), with the M1 Pro delivering 70 percent better CPU performance and twice the graphics performance of the original M1. Check out all the details on the new chips &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734219/apple-imovie-cinematic-mode-focus-support-adjust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734219/apple-imovie-cinematic-mode-focus-support-adjust</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:59:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:59:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple finally listened to the pros</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KTTDxGR_GDqy1WE8K7eDFJB-y0s=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013270/8zIbrHP0R4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fDOFrP"&gt;I nearly bought my first MacBook Pro in 2015. It would have been the first Mac I ever personally owned. But I convinced myself to wait another year for faster Intel chips — and in October 2016, Apple took away almost everything I admired about that Mac in one fell swoop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5sR8gv"&gt;The comfortable keyboard? Replaced with a too-thin slab that also became a nightmare for many a Mac user over the years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246223/macbook-keyboard-butterfly-magic-pro-apple-design"&gt;the butterfly switch mechanism so fragile&lt;/a&gt; a speck of dust could lay it low. The handy SD card slot for photographers and videographers, and the HDMI port to easily connect to monitors or TVs? Both axed seemingly in favor of selling us &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dbreunig/status/792034409788518401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E792034409788518401%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Ftech%2Fcomputing%2Fapple-microsoft-macbook-pro-surface-studio-creative-professionals%2F"&gt;more overpriced dongles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qVGgJu"&gt;In the quest for ever-thinner and flashier laptops, Apple had seemingly forgotten why people bought the MacBook Pro in the first place — and pros were happy to point that out. They ridiculed the tiny strip of touchscreen Apple built into the keyboard, decried the relative lack of RAM, the missing ports, and how Apple’s choice of GPU didn’t match up to the Windows competition. I collected a bunch of those thoughts &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/apple-microsoft-macbook-pro-surface-studio-creative-professionals/"&gt;right here at the time&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2016/10/27/new-macbook-pros-and-the-state-of-the-mac/"&gt;Michael Tsai has more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlZ4Zy"&gt;Five years later, Apple is giving those pros everything they said they wanted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YHT3u1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Fully loaded&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WsytOP"&gt;On Monday, Apple announced an intentionally thicker (in the case of the 16-inch model) and heavier MacBook Pro filled with ports — including HDMI, the SD card slot, and even the return of the MagSafe charging cable — plus three USB-C / Thunderbolt 4 connectors, the most capable port around. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;The new 14-&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;16-inch Macs&lt;/a&gt; feature up to 64GB of memory, and up to 8TB of the fastest PCI-Express storage on the market, with 7,400MB/sec reads. They feature a redesigned keyboard with function keys instead of the dreaded Touch Bar, and 120Hz high refresh rate Mini LED screens that might wind up being the best panels you can purchase on a laptop anywhere (they theoretically offer the benefits of OLED without some of the compromises, though we’ll have to test). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="E48vG2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces 16-inch MacBook Pro with new M1 Pro and M1 Max processors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"},{"title":"Apple announces new 14-inch MacBook Pro with a notch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WfQDSk"&gt;Perhaps most impressively, Apple claims that the 32 GPU cores on its new M1 Max chip give it nearly as much power as the Nvidia RTX 3080 high-end gaming-grade laptop chip you’ll find in a similarly priced &lt;a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Blade-15%2FRZ09-0409CE53-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sAaw8p"&gt;And while Apple was busy making these improvements, it finally added a 1080p webcam too. Yes, there’s a notch, and yes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"&gt;I don’t feel amazing about that&lt;/a&gt;, particularly seeing there’s no Face ID. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iScqEg"&gt;But I think I’m buying a Mac.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hH3bl9"&gt;I’ll probably wait for the dust to settle a bit. As always, there are some big open questions like performance and battery life, not to mention how it feels to use, including things like heat and noise. (No journalist has touched these devices yet, even for a basic hands-on.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiVwtX"&gt;With battery life, for instance, I wonder if Apple might be cherry-picking numbers. While &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-unveils-game-changing-macbook-pro/"&gt;the company says&lt;/a&gt; the 16-inch model has “the longest battery life ever on a Mac notebook,” but the company’s only talking about playing back video in its own Apple TV app, and doesn’t specify important variables like the brightness of the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GFbGwPpCGFfusBdrKFLBrogAoN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937262/battery_life_m1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s own comparison tool suggests the new Macs don’t have the best battery life out there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xi4Zdd"&gt;In Apple’s wireless web test (which uses Safari, not Chrome, last we checked) the company says the 14-inch MacBook Pro only manages 11 hours of battery life, far less than the 17 hours it claimed to get from the 13-inch MacBook Pro with M1 from late last year. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;We saw around 10 hours in real-world use&lt;/a&gt;.) The 16-inch MacBook Pro now claims 14 hours of wireless web, which does at least sound like an improvement from the 11 hours that it claimed to see from the 2019 model with its Core i9 chip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGtDVR"&gt;Look, all I’m saying is I’ll feel more comfortable dropping $2000+ on a new MacBook Pro after Nilay can confirm it’s fast and actually lasts and doesn’t make for sweaty palms or uncomfortably hot laps. If I’m going to switch from Windows to Mac, that’s the least I can ask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojtDoK"&gt;But for Apple’s audience of creative professionals that have been closely clutching their 2015 MacBook Pro with Retina Displays for all these years, or those who begrudgingly upgraded to a Touch ID-equipped laptop because they felt it was their only option, or those who defected to Windows when they saw the writing on the wall, today must feel like a brand-new day. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21559228/apple-new-macbook-air-pro-difference-arm-m1-fan-thermal-performance"&gt;13-inch model aside&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s no longer just &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/new-macbook-pro-should-have-been-named-air/"&gt;trying to sell pros a faster Air&lt;/a&gt;. It took five years to turn this ship around, but Apple is clearly listening to the pros. It built these computers for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qHCwG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rPNic"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s rumored Beats Fit Pro earbuds could have ear-fitting wingtips </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x2TL0PdhiFvtrDhbktt7phF1Pmk=/118x0:1383x843/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013066/beats_leak.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are are the Beats Fit Pro, according to &lt;/em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/exclusive-these-are-the-new-beats-fit-pro-earbuds/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gS21tF"&gt;Apple has just announced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;next generation of AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, but if you’ve been waiting for new Beats earbuds, you may also have something to look forward to there. A &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/exclusive-these-are-the-new-beats-fit-pro-earbuds/"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes the upcoming Beats Fit Pro that, according to the article, will have wingtips that seem to be designed to ensure a better fit in your ear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d6o8Dj"&gt;You can see the rumored earbuds at the top of this post or in this set of images shared by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;, featuring the Beats Fit Pro in black, gray, white, and lavender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G3AD5V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10814453"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4UYPRM"&gt;In addition to the new design, the earbuds will have active noise cancelation, Apple’s H1 chip for speedy pairing and Hey Siri, and support for quick pairing on Android through the Beats app, &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; reports. It also seems as if the Beats Fit Pro will have good battery life: six hours with ANC on or seven hours with Adaptive EQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XxoOy8"&gt;The Beats Fit Pro will be announced on November 1st and will ship starting a few days after, according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/18/beats-fit-pro/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that images of the Beats Fit Pro have appeared in the iOS 15.1 release candidate, lending credence to the possibility that they will be released soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733444/apple-beats-fit-pro-headphones-earbuds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733444/apple-beats-fit-pro-headphones-earbuds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:07:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>macOS Monterey will have the old Safari tab design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qhyLDb8c8-RUeh8c_o_ttrFgDXY=/34x0:645x407/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013016/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.04.52_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you squint, you can see the old tab design.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9bpgJe"&gt;Apple debuted a controversial &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;new Safari tab design&lt;/a&gt; this summer at WWDC 2021, and since then, it has tweaked that look and even let you turn off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back"&gt;many of the changes&lt;/a&gt;. With macOS Monterey, however, the company is going back to the way tabs looked before. On Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/macos/monterey/"&gt;official page&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming software update, if you scroll down to the section titled “Access Tab Groups anywhere,” you can just barely see Safari’s older (and arguably better) design in the example screenshots on both a Mac &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; on an iPad (&lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2021/10/18/safari-15-tabs"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ln4bay"&gt;Perhaps even more surprising is that the old design is now the default, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/18/macos-monterey-reverts-safari-changes/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which observed the reverted tabs in the macOS Monterey release candidate. However, if you want to use the design Apple revealed at WWDC, where tabs also function as URL bars, that will be an option you can flip on in the preferences menu, &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cArQQv"&gt;macOS Monterey will be available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725047/macos-monterey-release-date-compatibility-features-m1-pro-max-chip"&gt;on October 25th&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="m9NgUc"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pzW8h7"&gt;Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="32o9cx"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-564" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="al3BpS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZErK4K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733357/apple-old-safari-tab-design-macos-monterey"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733357/apple-old-safari-tab-design-macos-monterey</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:04:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:04:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>A piece of cloth to clean your Apple devices will cost you $19</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5UJuyDEjnSFKY9XnaRJASlbwqDA=/0x0:917x611/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012992/polishing_cloth_apple_970.10.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IF3LeX"&gt;If you were ever concerned about safely cleaning your Apple products, now you can use an official $19 piece of cloth made by Apple to do so. Apple released this polishing cloth after today’s event in addition to its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;Pros&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;M1 Pro and Max chips&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/apple-introduces-new-polishing-cloth-for-all-devices-sold-separately-for-19/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A folded Apple polishing cloth" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0jsL6Xm15HYes7DTG4K5T20H5xY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937127/folded_polishing_cloth.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="v7g6ew"&gt;The Apple-branded cloth, made of unspecified nonabrasive materials, will be available to purchase separately. Other than having an Apple logo stamped on it, it’s unclear how the cloth is any different from a typical microfiber cloth that you can get for a fraction of the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhJ7FC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204172"&gt;Apple recommends&lt;/a&gt; using “soft, lint-free cloth” and avoiding “abrasive cloths, towels, paper towels, or similar items” when cleaning your Apple devices, which are all worries that this $19 cloth puts to rest. On &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM6F3AM/A/polishing-cloth"&gt;the cloth’s product page&lt;/a&gt;, Apple says it can clean the displays — and nano-texture glass — on any Apple device. Yes, there is a compatibility list if you’re wondering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1COVwH"&gt;It’s reminiscent of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/10/21009928/apples-pro-display-xdr-nano-texture-cloth-clean"&gt;polishing cloth that’s required to clean the pricey nano-texture Pro Display XDR&lt;/a&gt;. Did we mention that the cloth actually comes free with the Pro Display XDR? Apparently, $6,000 is the price you’ll have to pay if you want a single piece of cloth included with your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T18:46:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T18:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s website indicates macOS Monterey will launch without Universal Control</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PqPRz0X5PEk6Blupf5Opn-CIQ-s=/219x0:2472x1502/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012873/Screen_Shot_2021_06_07_at_2.07.23_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KAVpOY"&gt;Universal Control, Apple’s upcoming feature that lets you control multiple devices with the same mouse and keyboard, will probably not be launching at the same time as macOS Monterey. While Apple has said that the OS upgrade &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725047/macos-monterey-release-date-compatibility-features-m1-pro-max-chip"&gt;will be available on October 25th&lt;/a&gt;, its features page has been updated to say that Universal Control will be “available later this fall,” &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/18/universal-control-macos-monterey-later-this-fall/"&gt;a change spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bP4Eiw"&gt;Universal Control was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523322/apple-wwdc-impressive-drag-and-drop-universal-control-demo"&gt;one of the most impressive demos at WWDC 2021&lt;/a&gt;, where Craig Federhigi dragged a file from an iPad across a MacBook’s screen and then dropped it onto an iMac. While Universal Control is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;mostly just Apple combining technologies&lt;/a&gt; that it’s been developing for years, if Apple wants the real-world experience to be as good as that demo, Universal Control will have to be pretty polished — so it’s not surprising that the feature is being pushed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpGs8J"&gt;While betas for Monterey have been available for months, Universal Control has been missing, so the public hasn’t actually gotten to try it out yet. It’s not the only feature that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684483/ios-15-announced-features-shareplay-airpods-universal-control"&gt;Apple’s announced and then delayed&lt;/a&gt;. SharePlay, which promises to let you watch videos and listen to music with friends over FaceTime, also wasn’t released with iOS and iPadOS 15. However, unlike Universal Control, SharePlay has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card"&gt;at least shown up in a few iOS betas&lt;/a&gt;. (Some toggles for Universal Control have shown up in macOS betas but appear to be non-functional, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/13/universal-control-monterey-beta-10-beta-label/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXybZz"&gt;Curiously, on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/macos/monterey/features/"&gt;the macOS Monterey page&lt;/a&gt;, SharePlay and some other features are marked with an asterisk that denotes it as “coming later this fall,” whereas Universal Control is marked with a separate footnote to say that it’ll be “available later this fall.” It’s possible that the different notation is because they’ll be arriving at different times or that it’s just a symptom of the delays being noted at different times. Apple didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="m4uyvz"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-203" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733044/macos-universal-control-later-this-fall-monterey-feature-delay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733044/macos-universal-control-later-this-fall-monterey-feature-delay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T18:28:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T18:28:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Where to get the new 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c1wqsi01nQVfcCWF0ZB0R48QIwo=/121x0:1414x862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012700/1Rm4aV2YiD.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s latest MacBook Pros tout new silicon, a Mini LED display, and a MagSafe 3 connector.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J8SCzS"&gt;As expected, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22488347"&gt;Apple’s “Unleashed” event&lt;/a&gt; brought a number of new additions to Apple’s lineup, including a pair of new laptops in the form of new versions of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22488779"&gt;14-&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third-generation of AirPods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Azd3ng"&gt;Both versions of the 2021 MacBook Pro are configurable with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;newly announced M1 Pro and M1 Max CPUs&lt;/a&gt;, which build greatly on the improvements made by the M1 CPU that debuted last year. Besides the beefier processor, the new versions of the MacBook Pro have enhanced GPU performance, battery life, and a host of new connectivity options, including a trio of Thunderbolt 4 ports, HDMI output, and an SD card reader in addition to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733119/apple-new-macbook-pro-magsafe-back"&gt;MagSafe 3 connector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NS8nXR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder Apple’s third-gen AirPods","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22665643/apple-airpods-3-preorder-how-to-buy-price-availability-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="btJOsc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1019575/7613?subId1=Verge1416MacbookPro101821&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-pro%2F16-inch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;16-inch model starts at $2,499&lt;/a&gt;, and the&lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1019575/7613?subId1=Verge1416MacbookPro101821&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-pro%2F14-inch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; 14-inch model starts at $1,999&lt;/a&gt;. We haven’t had the opportunity to put them through their paces, but if you want to preorder either of the forthcoming models ahead of our full review, both are available starting today at the Apple Store and begin shipping next week. Keep in mind, however, that availability looks to be limited for some configurations, with some models expected to ship as late as early December.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple MacBook Pro ports (MagSafe 3, HDMI, SDXC, Thunderbolt 4 and headphone jack)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SCZpPej4VXBeaCEXwa6l-ZwyN9M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936766/apple_macbook_pro_ports_magsafe_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div id="VLfrUk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="5VposP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814228"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="z2Ys7w"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7AYmbW"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="6C5gwo"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-644" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724608/apple-m1-pro-m1-max-macbook-pro-how-to-buy-price-availability-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724608/apple-m1-pro-m1-max-macbook-pro-how-to-buy-price-availability-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
