<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-01T17:33:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T17:33:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T17:33:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is reportedly trying a ‘retail flex’ work-from-home program for store employees</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mTS4UOxf8ngm7iYOViexxXAdujA=/0x154:3036x2178/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531620/IMG_20171003_180359.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="91L5C2"&gt;Apple is reportedly working on a program called “Retail Flex,” which will give its store employees the chance to work from home some weeks, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-01/apple-to-test-hybrid-work-from-store-and-home-for-retail-staff"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;/a&gt; Mark Gurman. According to the report, the employees would be remotely handling things like tech support and online sales part of the time, and working at the store as usual at other times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuXefm"&gt;Having employees who traditionally work in a store transitioning to a remote role, even if it’s only a partial change, is a big shift, likely brought on by the pandemic. It doesn’t seem like Apple is just jumping into it. The company is reportedly starting a pilot program that will last at least six months, with participating employees being paid the same salary, plus some extra for internet and office equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OleH27"&gt;If Apple does end up adopting a model that sees fewer employees working retail, it likely won’t be alone. With the US starting to enter its post-pandemic stage, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/09/29/how-coronavirus-pandemic-forever-altered-retail.html"&gt;physical stores will have to contend&lt;/a&gt; with the new habits people have formed of shopping online and doing in-store pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yQbKMM"&gt;For its non-retail staff, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;will require at least some office time&lt;/a&gt;, with employees having to return to the office at least three days a week. Some of Apple’s workers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22491629/apple-employees-push-back-return-office-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;pushed back against having to return to the office&lt;/a&gt;, but the company will reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22556615/apple-response-hybrid-work-model-employee-letter-remote"&gt;still go through&lt;/a&gt; with the hybrid work model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4dKmIm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s hard to imagine many retail employees working from home during the iPhone launch&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OTSWdZ"&gt;There’s an interesting contrast with Apple potentially lowering the number of retail employees it has working at most given times, and the other retail moves it’s been making. Over the past few years, it’s been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16296460/apple-self-love-iphonex-iphone8-event"&gt;rebranding some of its stores as “town halls”&lt;/a&gt; where events and classes can take place, and it just recently restored two historic buildings &lt;a href="https://www.macstories.net/stories/a-palazzo-reborn-inside-apples-stunning-new-store-in-via-del-corso-rome/"&gt;in Rome&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/apple-tower-theatre-opens-thursday-in-downtown-los-angeles/"&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt; into decadent stores. Now, with news of this plan, it seems like there could be fewer employees around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipapZ3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;does say that Apple’s plan is to scale employee presence with retail demand — it’s hard to imagine many employees scheduling work-from-home weeks during the iPhone launch — but we may be soon see the first steps toward a different, more online-focused Apple Store experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559713/apple-retail-flex-work-from-home-store-employees"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559713/apple-retail-flex-work-from-home-store-employees</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T17:14:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T17:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the tvOS 15 beta on Apple TV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jIyMLvWhtpqhoZXAlkrSFk2uxUs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531553/DSCF3875_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bi79e4"&gt;The next big software update for Apple TV will arrive with tvOS 15. While it won’t become widely available until later this year, users who are part of Apple’s public beta program can now take it for a spin ahead of time. It’s possible and even likely that Apple will continue tinkering with tvOS 15 features ahead of its official launch, but particularly for those looking to test-drive Apple’s forthcoming SharePlay feature, the public beta has officially landed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx63fz"&gt;The goodies arriving in tvOS 15 that Apple has disclosed so far are small — you’re not going to notice a massive redesign of the tvOS interface, for example — but they’re not insignificant, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgo0ei"&gt;Though, a warning: once you install tvOS 15 on a newer Apple TV 4K box, there’s no turning back. Uninstalling the beta from your Apple TV device may not be possible with newer models. Resetting an Apple TV HD requires &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/tv/reset-apple-tv-atvbf9db0a52/tvos"&gt;connecting a USB-C cable&lt;/a&gt; to your computer (I’ll describe the process more thoroughly later), which isn’t possible on the Apple TV 4K boxes. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has contacted Apple to ask about whether it’s possible to revert back to tvOS 14 on newer Apple TVs and will update this guide if we hear back, but a simple factory reset doesn’t cut it. (This is the case with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22558944/watchos-beta-install-how-to"&gt;watchOS 8&lt;/a&gt; as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SgbbwS"&gt;WHAT ARE THE NEW FEATURES ON tvOS 15?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ebM5qU"&gt;For one, tvOS 15 will bring support for SharePlay to Apple TV, allowing users to stream movies and TV shows with others over FaceTime on an iPhone, iPad, or Mac. It’s Apple’s spin on group watch features that have largely been supported by individual services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4gSHm"&gt;There was just a handful of streaming services that Apple confirmed during WWDC would support the tool — Disney Plus, Twitch, Hulu, and Prime Video included — but we’ll &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;likely see wider support&lt;/a&gt; before tvOS officially rolls out later this year, as Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last month that the feature will be available to any streaming service that wants to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sYXbu7"&gt;Two new rows will appear in the Apple TV app in tvOS 15 as well: For All of You and Shared with You. When enabled, Shared with You will populate content that’s been shared with a user through Messages — for example, if a friend recommends &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Lisey’s Story&lt;/em&gt; from Apple TV Plus. (Though you’ll need to enable it using another Apple device, and I couldn’t seem to set it up this way.) For All of You, meanwhile, will surface content that Apple believes would be a good fit for everyone in the household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cuXTVz"&gt;Some additional features coming to Apple TV in tvOS 15 include support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; with AirPods Pro or AirPods Max as well as on-screen connectivity notifications for AirPods. Additionally, HomeKit will allow users to view multiple camera feeds at once. And lastly, the update will support pairing two HomePod mini speakers to an Apple TV 4K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SKaZG3"&gt;WHAT DEVICES ARE SUPPORTED FOR iOS 15?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W1o1cA"&gt;Apple TV 4K (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bkDwMg"&gt;Apple TV 4K (2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kaLnAz"&gt;Apple TV HD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hMkR9v"&gt;HOW TO DOWNLOAD THE tvOS 15 BETA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="L3z3td"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="From the settings menu, toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mipuoDUWSjpu5UNVRk0Pvu6GaaU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694425/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_4.24.52_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the settings menu, toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vx0KXZ"&gt;On your computer, sign up for &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/"&gt;Apple’s beta program&lt;/a&gt;, or sign in if you’re an existing member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rFbzTY"&gt;Once you’re signed in, navigate to the tvOS tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UM82hE"&gt;Scroll down to the “Get Started” section of the tvOS beta page and &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/enroll#tvos"&gt;enroll your Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pCtpwq"&gt;Now head for the settings menu on your Apple TV and select “Users and Accounts.” Make sure you’re signed in with the same Apple ID you used to register for the beta program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uDuuym"&gt;From the settings menu, select “System” &amp;gt; “Software Update,” and toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AjrqKU"&gt;Once this setting is enabled, update your Apple TV from your system settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6KSLzZ"&gt;How to restore your Apple TV HD to its factory settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Pq3lqu"&gt;If the beta isn’t working for you, you can &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/tv/reset-apple-tv-atvbf9db0a52/tvos"&gt;restore an Apple TV HD&lt;/a&gt; (but again, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the Apple TV 4K) to its factory settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jPNroI"&gt;Disconnect both the HDMI and power cables from the box, then connect it to your computer using a USB-C cable. Apple suggests connecting it to a Mac running macOS Catalina or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0XLP6g"&gt;Open Finder from your computer, and choose “Restore” from the Apple TV menu &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Dn6Uc8"&gt;If you’re attempting to reset your box with a PC, you’ll need to use iTunes to restore the Apple box from the Source list. The same goes for Macs running Mojave or older.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22559665/tvos-15-beta-apple-tv-how-to-install"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22559665/tvos-15-beta-apple-tv-how-to-install</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T15:59:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T15:59:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use iOS 15’s new Live Text feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Grz1iv2Q-EqgdejaZyXhstVLLIM=/311x0:2249x1292/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531103/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_3.24.37_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xDK9Nx"&gt;Apple’s iOS 15 is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"&gt;now available in public beta&lt;/a&gt;, which means that today you can try out all the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;biggest features coming to the iPhone&lt;/a&gt; this fall. That includes Live Text, the most technically impressive feature in the update, which allows you to pull text, email addresses, phone numbers, and more from pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJ8tcg"&gt;Live Text works with both handwritten and typed text, and supports English, Chinese (Traditional and Simplified), Portuguese, French, Italian, German, and Spanish. It’s also important to remember that iOS 15 is still in beta, which means that Apple could tweak or change how Live Text works in the months to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WpYxEg"&gt;Live Text works in a few different ways on iOS, depending on what you’re trying to use it for and where in the OS you are. Here are all the different ways you can use it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JYeuj4"&gt;With text fields&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q_-4CyMdFNBnctjnp2raX6GOmuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694122/Image_from_iOS.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new “Text from Camera” option in the text select menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SKoALRc81vn5sgQ2uh0tGV3l7Ww=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694125/Image_from_iOS__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Live Text works when importing text directly into a messaging field.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pwjojp"&gt;The most powerful — and useful — way to use Live Text is with virtually any text field on iOS. Whether you’re writing a text message to a friend, an email, or something in the notes app, you can add text that you copied from an image. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WegPR2"&gt;Once you’ve got the text you want (see below), tapping on the text field (as you would when accessing the pop-up select / copy / paste menu that’s been on iOS for years) brings up an additional option: text from camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IXuh82"&gt;Tapping that new button will bring up a smaller camera window, which you can point at any block of text. iOS will then highlight the block of text it’s selecting, and you can drop it in just by hitting the “insert” button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SY7pXg"&gt;(You might want to proofread things, of course, before you send or post it — Live Text is pretty good, but its not perfect, especially when working with handwritten text.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qX2cWjC_E_3p4yiYCYuyQqOCqV8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694093/IMG_2826.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Text pulling text from the camera app’s live preview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g6TmP4cBBPKSaemzq6soNwG4k3c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694094/IMG_2825.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Text in the Photos app, pulling handwritten text.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Db9ALA"&gt;In the camera app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PVkw3d"&gt;If you have an iPhone XS or newer, you can also use Live Text directly in the camera app in real time. Just open the camera app and tap the live text button that appears in the corner of the viewfinder (it’ll pop up contextually when you’re pointing it at text) to grab text that you can then copy and paste. You can also interact with it directly in the case of phone numbers, email addresses, and links. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2RbLOQ"&gt;In Photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tRNnpQ"&gt;If you’re viewing any pictures with text in them in the Photos app, you can select and interact with text there. It works just like selecting actual text anywhere else on iOS: tap and hold on the text in an image and you’ll see the familiar-looking blue highlights pop up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g-kF4ZNrLZ53OdaTJ_stZRdbRmE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694096/IMG_2827.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Text’s “Show Text” option in Safari on iOS 15.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-bVwPQgkk47K66Xw4fIh44mL0is=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694100/IMG_2824.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Text pulling text from a screenshot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZiGX9k"&gt;In Safari&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hhf0VN"&gt;Text can also be selected directly from images on the web in Safari. To grab text, tap and hold on an image, and hit the “Show Text” button, which will allow you to highlight and interact with text here.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22559167/ios-15-live-text-feature-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22559167/ios-15-live-text-feature-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T14:55:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T14:55:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to restore your Mac from the macOS Monterey beta to Big Sur</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QsFRv8tXEAOtBo2Aq053anr3AdU=/102x0:1790x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530607/lcimg_71a6f738_86b9_4aed_a194_067e8224a6d4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZoFr15"&gt;If you downloaded and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22323032"&gt;installed the macOS Monterey public beta&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a chance that you may want to return to Big Sur, which is currently the stable macOS version. There are a couple of different ways to restore your Mac’s original software; which one you should follow depends on how you installed the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Y2Oq8"&gt;The path to restoring is easiest if you made a Time Machine backup before updating the operating system, or if you installed the beta on a separate partition via Disk Utility. If you installed the beta on your main partition without a backup, you can still restore your system to the older OS, but you’ll need to start fresh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GY1Bse"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple launches public beta of macOS Monterey, bringing updates to FaceTime and Safari","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="JshbJD"&gt;Whichever path you chose, we’ll walk you through how to find your way back to a more reliable OS. Pick the method that suits you best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OQPMd"&gt;Note: some of these steps may differ, depending on whether your Mac has an Intel processor or Apple silicon, like the M1 processor. If you’re not sure which you have, click on the Apple logo in your system’s upper left corner, and choose “About This Mac.” In the Overview, you’ll be able to see which processor you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2rnonW"&gt;Wait for the next stable update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jtcoqt"&gt;If you aren’t in a rush to go back your previous OS, you can simply unenroll your Mac from the beta program and wait for the next stable update, which will revert you to that OS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0lqDG7"&gt;Go to “System Preferences” &amp;gt; “Software Update.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wstzaD"&gt;Select “Details...” in the bottom-left corner of the window, underneath the message “This Mac is enrolled in the Apple Beta Software Program.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RfLtFP"&gt;Select “Restore Defaults” to unenroll your Mac from the beta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TPgSlk"&gt;Restore to a previous Time Machine backup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZxsIOR"&gt;If you made a Time Machine backup just before you installed the beta, then reverting to your previous stable OS is relatively simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YnLOhK"&gt;Make sure you back up any files that you created while working with the beta (unless, of course, you don’t care whether you lose them). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="loGbwO"&gt;Connect the external hard drive that you used for Time Machine backups to your system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HL6r1r"&gt;If you have an Intel-based Mac, restart your Mac and hold both the Command and R keys through the startup chime until the Apple logo shows. You should then see the macOS Recovery window. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LrJR4a"&gt;If your Mac is equipped with Apple silicon, power down your Mac, then press and hold the power button until you see the “Startup Options” window. Click the gear icon, then click “Continue.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NP3ztg"&gt;Within the macOS Recovery window, select the drive, then find “Restore From Time Machine Backup.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In the Recovery window, find “Restore From Time Machine Backup.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BC-2dGFha7YDFLuk8mgpACs6cqE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693975/macos_big_sur_recovery_reinstall_macos.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Recovery window, find “Restore From Time Machine Backup.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="P1oWcS"&gt;Select the backup that you want to revert to. Note that the window will show the macOS version. Look for the last one that shows version 11 instead of 12.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KmCA0Q"&gt;Once the reversion process is finished, things should be as you left them before installing the beta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i3RLDe"&gt;Erase a separate partition that contains the Monterey beta&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8H4pN6"&gt;If you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22323032"&gt;installed the Monterey beta to a separate partition&lt;/a&gt; (as opposed to overwriting your main partition), you can simply eliminate that one to reclaim some SSD space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="K0Hlog"&gt;If you have an Intel-based Mac, restart your Mac and hold both the Command and R keys through the startup chime until the Apple logo shows. You should then see the macOS Recovery window. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aTowmg"&gt;If your Mac is equipped with Apple silicon, power down your Mac, then press and hold the power button until you see the “Startup Options” window. Click the gear icon, then click “Continue.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EKWrUQ"&gt;Once you see the macOS Recovery window, find the partition that you created and named. Then click “Disk Utility.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VLmv92"&gt;After the Disk Utility window opens, click the partition that you want to delete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VqkWc4"&gt;You can ensure that it’s the correct partition (the one using macOS 12) by looking for the macOS version, which is listed under the partition’s name near the middle of the window. Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; delete the partition for macOS 11, or else you’ll need to follow the steps in the next section to fully restore your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aldzr1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; delete the partition for macOS 11, or you’ll need to fully restore your machine&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="j077hY"&gt;When you’re ready to erase the partition, click “Erase” near the top-right section of the Disk Utility app, then click “Erase.” Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; click “Erase Volume Group” because that may delete your main partition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IX6tFd"&gt;Erasing the partition won’t completely eliminate it. To do that, click the partition once again, and near the “Erase” button along the top-right corner, find “Volume” and click the minus symbol to fully remove it from your SSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="N6SxtE"&gt;After that, you can click the Apple logo at the top-left of the screen and restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q0yuRr"&gt;Restore to a fresh install of macOS Big Sur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zFe2Z8"&gt;If you don’t have a Time Machine backup, or you’d prefer to restore your Mac for a clean start, here’s how to proceed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="E6Nmp0"&gt;If you have an Intel-based Mac, restart your Mac, holding both the Command and R keys through the startup chime until the Apple logo shows. You should then see the macOS Recovery window. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uV8gdJ"&gt;If your Mac is equipped with Apple silicon, power down your Mac, then press and hold the power button until you see the “Startup Options” window. Click the gear icon, then click “Continue.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wkaoUn"&gt;Once you see the macOS Recovery window, click on your intended install drive, then click “Reinstall macOS.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1RwZQq"&gt;This process will restore your Mac to factory settings, so you’ll need to reinstall all of your apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="MkV43L"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AkotG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22559110/macos-monterey-beta-restore-macbook-pro-air-imac-mac-mini"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22559110/macos-monterey-beta-restore-macbook-pro-air-imac-mac-mini</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:22:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:22:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple launches public beta of macOS Monterey, bringing updates to FaceTime and Safari</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A MacBook Pro running macOS Monterey sits on a table in front of a window. The screen displays the Quick note app on top of a pink and purple background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CNYGStZnZP-kSXROO5wLnd6PJpY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530097/mchin_210701_4658_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a quick note? There’s an app for that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="juxc3a"&gt;The public beta of macOS 12 Monterey, Apple’s next big macOS release, is now available for download. The operating system has the same general look and feel as its predecessor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"&gt;macOS 11 Big Sur&lt;/a&gt;, but it brings some new features and a number of tweaks to Apple’s most popular services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxcR1j"&gt;Before we get into this, friendly reminder that Monterey is, for now, a beta. It may not be the best idea to install on a primary device, as you might encounter bugs, unfinished features, and incompatibility with third-party apps. If you will be installing the program on your daily driver, make sure you’ve backed up anything you can’t afford to mess with first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z2tJJv"&gt;For those who take the leap and install the public beta, the component Apple seems most excited about is its updates to FaceTime. My favorite of these is Portrait Mode, which blurs the background behind you while you’re speaking on a call (similarly to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;the iPhone’s feature with the same name&lt;/a&gt;). Portrait Mode didn’t always get everything — sometimes when there were multiple different surfaces behind me, it seemed to get a bit confused and leave some parts un-blurred. But it wasn’t difficult to find areas where the feature worked just fine. Apple says Portrait Mode will be available for adoption in third-party apps as well, but we’ll have to wait for them to issue updates to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xI6srY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 preview: a first look at Apple’s latest software","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"},{"title":"How to install the macOS Monterey public beta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a MacBook screen where a user is on a FaceTime call with a blurred bright bedroom background. A FaceTime drop-down menu is open in the top right with Portrait selected." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2NsKif8IbPqAUClq3MVExUI7Bcg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692197/IMG_9643.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;macOS Monterey’s new FaceTime Portrait Mode did a decent job of blurring out my background.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RPSdWc"&gt;Even though it’s had the ability to make group calls for a few years, I’ve always viewed FaceTime as a tool for calling one person at a time. But Monterey introduces a few other features that are clearly meant to make the tool a stronger Zoom competitor, conducive to meetings and larger calls. It now supports a grid view and Spatial Audio (which makes other people’s voices sound like they’re coming from the area on the screen where their face is positioned). You can generate a link to a FaceTime call ahead of time (the same way you generate a Zoom link), and users of Android and Windows can join from their browsers. And a new Voice Isolation feature uses machine learning to mitigate background noise while you’re speaking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DK3OV"&gt;There’s a new feature called SharePlay, which is like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21191503/netflix-party-stream-movies-tv-chat-watch-friends-social-distance"&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; or Scener but for FaceTime. Like Netflix Party, it allows you and other people on your FaceTime call to watch content from certain streaming services together by syncing everyone’s video playback and controls. (So we’re both watching the video on our own devices, with our own accounts. But when I pause or start, you pause or start as well.) SharePlay isn’t a new idea, but it’ll certainly be convenient to have on FaceTime. While the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522904/apple-shareplay-facetime-music-hulu-videos-tiktok-wwdc"&gt;list of supported services&lt;/a&gt; includes some big players (such as Disney Plus, Hulu, HBO Max, Paramount Plus, Twitch, Pluto TV, and — hilariously — TikTok), it doesn’t appear to include Netflix, which is the one streaming service I and all of my friends and family reliably have in common. Until that’s added to the roster, I don’t see myself using this that often. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bvui2D"&gt;A new feature that I do think I’ll be using a lot is Quick Note. Quick Note gives you an easy way to take notes on an article you’re reading (or items you’re viewing in Maps, Photos, or other apps). You can right-click highlighted text to add it to a Quick Note, and it’ll appear there along with a link to the source. (You can press Fn+Q to pull up a blank one as well.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="On9s5f"&gt;Quick Notes sync across devices and are available in a specific “Quick Notes” folder in the Notes app. The handiest thing, I think, is that if you’ve got an app open where you’ve previously created a Quick Note, you can hover your cursor in the bottom-right corner of the screen and a thumbnail of the note will pop up. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a MacBook Pro screen. The Verge’s review of the Razer Blade 14 is open in Safari. A paragraph is higlighted with “Add to Quick Note” in an adjacent drop-down menu selected. A Quick Note is open on the left side of the screen with more text and a link to the article." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/09b_x2tfr-du0C0QCPK7kHPH8mI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692276/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_4.25.44_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I took some notes on my recent review of the Razer Blade 14. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dIYFeJ"&gt;Apple has introduced a few “continuity” features that are meant to make it easier to use Macs alongside other Apple devices. Arguably the most exciting one, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;Universal Control&lt;/a&gt;, won’t be ready until a future beta. What you can try now is AirPlay, which has made its way to macOS for the first time. AirPlay makes it easier to cast content to a Mac computer: it can mirror or extend your iPhone’s screen, for example, or can function as an AirPlay 2 speaker. I was able to set this up easily (you just need to wait until the devices detect each other and then enter a code on your phone), and it worked well. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a macOS notification that reads “Airplay: Look What You Made Me Do would like to AirPlay to this Mac.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f31vkR0ekMZegf2SG1Ow2M2dQw0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692357/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_4.48.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, that is the name of my iPhone. Long story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o4V6EO"&gt;Safari has some tweaks, mainly concerning tabs. The URL bar now lives next to your tabs, which gives you more browsing space. Tabs have a rounder appearance now, and you can click one to reveal its page’s full address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdaBeU"&gt;The new feature that I think is quite useful is tab groups. The way this works is that if you have, say, five tabs open, you can click a little icon in the top-left corner to make them into a “tab group”. Later on, if you open the sidebar on the left, you’ll see the group listed in the “Tab Groups” section; click on it, and Safari will reopen those five tabs. Also in that sidebar lives a bookmarks list, a reading list, and a list of links that have been shared with you in Messages. You can test-drive the new Safari browser in older versions of macOS without having to update to the Monterey beta by installing the &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/safari/technology-preview/"&gt;Safari Technology Preview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Safari open on a MacBook Pro. A Verge Windows 11 video is open on YouTube. The sidebar is open showing two tab groups: Verge Videos and Verge Articles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NwyeAMV8Q-G7S-8Q1e7rjn0-B7Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692376/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_5.00.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tab groups are almost instant to click in and out of.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7Key8M"&gt;There are a number of other odds and ends built into macOS Monterey. Shortcuts is available on macOS, Focus allows you to filter notifications based on the task you’re doing, it’s gotten easier to save photos that you receive in Messages, etc. I look forward to digging more into these features for our full review, but the things I’ve highlighted here are the ones I see being the most immediately impactful to daily use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtT8tL"&gt;The phrase “odds and ends” really sums up my impressions after using macOS Monterey for a few days. macOS Big Sur completely overhauled the Mac experience. That’s not the case here (which is fine — not every update needs to be a revolution). Apple seems to have made some tweaks here and some tweaks there. My reactions have largely been: “Alright, that could be handy.” Which is fair. I’ll take handy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LjiYcv"&gt;Here’s the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523116/apple-ios-ipados-15-watchos-8-macos-monterey-wwdc-2021"&gt;list of devices&lt;/a&gt; that will support macOS Monterey: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="i7zV7I"&gt;iMac (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201634"&gt;late 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DT8GDM"&gt;iMac Pro (2017 and later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TDG4DT"&gt;Mac Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT202888"&gt;late 2013 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cZc8bq"&gt;Mac Mini (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201894"&gt;late 2014 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SkWfhc"&gt;MacBook Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201300"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FavKjr"&gt;MacBook Air (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201862"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SncFxN"&gt;MacBook (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201608"&gt;early 2016 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="0hkh24"&gt;Notably, this doesn’t include a few models that did get Big Sur last year, including the 2013 MacBook Air, the late-2013 MacBook Pro, and the 2014 iMac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3QPTht"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Some of macOS Monterey’s best features aren’t coming to Intel Macs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive"},{"title":"macOS Monterey lets you run Shortcuts and share files between Macs and iPads","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"},{"title":"How Universal Control on macOS Monterey works","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:14:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:14:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the macOS Monterey public beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oICKh8FKrnULXwm4qBHN2qU3CHg=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530037/Apple_macos_monterey_shortcuts_gallery_06072021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V6zJVU"&gt;Apple has launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22321921"&gt;the public beta for macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt;. This is the next big update coming to Mac computers (the final version is expected later in 2021) and it brings several big changes. In this article, we’re going to walk you through how to get the beta onto your computer, should you want it. Once you install the beta, it will likely receive several updates between now and the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G0YsSM"&gt;(Looking for steps to install the iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 public betas? &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"&gt;We’ve got you covered here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VxGaqm"&gt;What’s new about macOS Monterey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qrSMDX"&gt;One of the most impressive demos that Apple showed during WWDC 2021 was the new drag-and-drop feature called Universal Control that’ll let you seamlessly move your cursor and files between an iPad and Mac computer, as if they were all hard-wired together. Check out Dieter Bohn’s video below to find out more about that feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BzFd4h"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="The best demo at WWDC 2021|102457" data-volume-uuid="8630beec6" data-volume-id="102457" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-284" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yZtXH3"&gt;Macs will also get &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/shortcuts/welcome/ios"&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; and will be able to act as AirPlay targets, so your computer will be able to play content from your iPhone or iPad. There are more changes in the update, and my colleague Mitchell Clark &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;covers all of the highlights here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MpJ1SU"&gt;Here’s some more coverage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hSuGwu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Some of macOS Monterey’s best features aren’t coming to Intel-based Macs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive"},{"title":"iOS 15 and macOS 12 take a small but significant step towards a password-less future","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529266/passkeys-icloud-keychain-ios-15-passwordless-future-security-login"},{"title":"macOS and tvOS are getting spatial audio support with the AirPods Pro and Max","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523914/macos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="aoruii"&gt;What devices are supported for macOS Monterey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="KRiLOM"&gt;Here’s the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="i7zV7I"&gt;iMac (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201634"&gt;late 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DT8GDM"&gt;iMac Pro (2017 and later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TDG4DT"&gt;Mac Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT202888"&gt;late 2013 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cZc8bq"&gt;Mac Mini (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201894"&gt;late 2014 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SkWfhc"&gt;MacBook Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201300"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FavKjr"&gt;MacBook Air (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201862"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SncFxN"&gt;MacBook (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201608"&gt;early 2016 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IYh6eGH4UP7Q5H8ddZjpFtunO8I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693426/macos_monterey_features.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="agPCNn"&gt;How to install the macOS Monterey beta on your main partition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="21T5f4"&gt;First off, &lt;strong&gt;back up your data&lt;/strong&gt; via Time Machine. This will allow you to revert to Big Sur should things not go well with the Monterey beta. If you’re planning to install this beta on your main machine, keep in mind that you may encounter problems (bugs, incompatibility issues, worse-than-usual battery life) that might get in your way — not what you want if you’re on any kind of deadline. Also, make sure that you have around 20GB of free space available on your hard drive before trying to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0EmTzc"&gt;There’s a way to avoid some of this possible drama. If you’re using a machine with macOS High Sierra or later, you can &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208891"&gt;use built-in tools to partition your hard drive&lt;/a&gt; so the beta can live in isolation. This way, you can test out the new features, then boot into your stable macOS partition with the rest of your data when you’re done. We’ll walk through that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cnjek8"&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tusDFy"&gt;Head to &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/"&gt;Apple’s beta software portal&lt;/a&gt; via Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="k1OEft"&gt;If you haven’t previously installed a public beta, you’ll need to sign up for access with your Apple ID. Otherwise, click “Enroll Your Devices” at the top-right corner of the webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xOFsNr"&gt;Click “macOS,” the middle option at the center of the next page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NcQIKX"&gt;Scroll down until you find a button that says “Download the macOS Public Beta Access Utility.” Click on it to download a .DMG file, which will enroll your computer. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AQuRZs"&gt;Upon booting the installer, you’ll be prompted if it doesn’t detect a Time Machine backup. (You did make a backup, right? Like I suggested above?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jIcbwa"&gt;Lastly, head to “Software Update” from the System Preferences app (if it doesn’t open automatically) to install the beta. If you’ve enrolled in the beta program, you should see the message “This Mac is enrolled in the Apple Beta Software Program” located underneath the big “Software Update” icon. Note: the download might not be available to you immediately. You’ll receive a notification once it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5L1JEw"&gt;The update file will take a while to download. Once it’s done, hit install and run through the steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ksY059"&gt;How to create a separate partition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="k9dw4y"&gt;Open Disk Utility (a built-in app you can find by typing its name into the Spotlight search bar). Your hard drive’s partitions will be listed under “Internal” along the left side of the window. You might only see one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If your machine is using APFS, click the plus sign at top to create a new partition." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lj2ov76oEhHDPo6067qC8ptp7Cg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693724/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_12.22.36_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your machine is using APFS, click the plus sign at top to create a new partition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="qoWZtE"&gt;If you’re using a machine with macOS High Sierra or newer, clicking your main partition should reveal that it’s a “&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208891"&gt;APFS Volume&lt;/a&gt;.” If so, you can then simply click the plus button above the word “Volume” at the top-left corner of the Disk Utility window to make a new volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="751ZpM"&gt;You can name the volume anything you want, then hit “Add.” Since storage formatted to APFS is shared across volumes, there’s no need to worry about how much space to set aside in the new volume when you create it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aljRC4"&gt;(Note: If your machine’s drive is formatted to Mac OS Extended instead of APFS, you can select the “Partition” button near the top of the Disk Utility window instead. You’ll need to name the partition, then decide how much storage you’d like to have on that slice of hard drive. Given that previous public betas have been over 10GB in size, I’d suggest at least 30GB to be safe.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6sYvFc"&gt;Now that you have another volume (or partition), you can choose to install the beta to that instead of your main drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IDctbM"&gt;To switch between volumes or partitions, you’ll need to restart the machine and hold down the Option key during startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="LozlSM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WbKXb1"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T10:16:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T10:16:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s iOS app has a secret pinball Easter egg now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7chmpE3ByTsLXOEbWNIQBeMFLkg=/105x0:3255x2100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69528947/Google_pinball.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="G8Qd91"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/google/id284815942"&gt;Google app on iOS&lt;/a&gt; appears to have gotten a new Easter egg: a rather entertaining little pinball app hidden away in the “Tabs” menu. The game appears to have been added a few weeks ago, as spotted by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dN5FFdPL7X8"&gt;several YouTube videos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/teenagers/comments/o2ak9i/the_google_app_on_ios_has_this_neat_easter_egg/"&gt;a Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; in the middle of June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sEYRIm"&gt;Opening the pinball game is simple: switch over to the Tabs, uh, tab in Google’s iOS app, clear out any open tabs, and then wait for the colorful shapes to start creeping up from the bottom of the screen. Swipe up on those shapes, and you’ll launch a surprisingly full-featured pinball game directly in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KFXkk6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A surprisingly good pinball game&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TVeeVS"&gt;Gameplay actually works like a mix of pinball and &lt;em&gt;Brick Breaker&lt;/em&gt;, with each level spawning a variety of colorful shapes that shrink and eventually vanish with each hit. Each level adds new bumper variations and more shapes to the mix, and there are even power-ups: a heart adds an extra life, a blue star splits the pinball into two, and a yellow star makes the ball larger and easier to hit. It also works offline, in the event that you’re stuck on a plane or subway and somehow manage to only have the Google app on your phone for internet-less entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PjqgNm"&gt;Is there a real purpose to the pinball Easter egg? Not really. (The same could be said of regular pinball, I suppose.) But the existential nature of pinball is beyond the scope of this blog post — besides, I need to go back and try to beat my high score. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558872/google-ios-app-secret-pinball-easter-egg-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558872/google-ios-app-secret-pinball-easter-egg-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T10:14:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T10:14:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the watchOS 8 public beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Apple Watch Series 6, in Product Red" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1f0JZyAt5kcMb6KUSfZfeeVP1B4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69528940/vpavic_200929_4216_0128.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 6, in Product Red color.&lt;/em&gt; | Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6d4Phv"&gt;Apple has now released public betas for iOS 15, iPadOS 15, watchOS 8, tvOS 15, and macOS Monterey. We’ve covered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"&gt;how to get the iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 betas here&lt;/a&gt; — follow along below if you’re interested in testing out the latest Apple Watch software, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdurFM"&gt;WatchOS 8 is expected to get a full, stable release this fall. It brings a handful of new features, including more workout types in the Fitness app, a new Mindfulness app, a watchface that works with Portrait Mode photos taken on an iPhone, as well as improved weather and smart home apps, among other things. It’s compatible with the Series 3, Series 4, Series 5, Series 6, and SE Apple Watch models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ukj6DG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to install the iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 public betas","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"},{"title":"How to install the macOS Monterey public beta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Eo25aP"&gt;Before we go through how to install the beta, there are some important things you should know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="DlhMVb"&gt;Beta software is often buggy and you might have issues with third-party apps. Some bugs might include poor performance and bad battery life, an area the Apple Watch isn’t great at even with stable software. It’s best to try it out on a secondary watch if you have one (which, admittedly, most people don’t).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="t4AYKj"&gt;Unlike the iOS and iPadOS betas, there’s no way to revert to the stable version of watchOS 7 if you install the watchOS 8 beta. If it’s buggy and not functioning well for you, you’re stuck with it until Apple releases the stable version in the fall. That’s probably enough of a reason to stay away from this one, particularly if you rely on your Apple Watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p id="EInlh9"&gt;If those don’t scare you away, here’s how to install the watchOS 8 beta on an Apple Watch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Lslpir"&gt;Before you can install the watchOS 8 beta, you must have the iOS 15 beta installed on your iPhone. Go &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"&gt;follow these directions&lt;/a&gt; and come back here when you’re done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TU9jFz"&gt;Go to &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/"&gt;Apple’s beta software page&lt;/a&gt; in Safari on your iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4sTCZE"&gt;Log in with your Apple ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8rmJ65"&gt;Scroll down and tap the “Get Started” link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xb8SJ8"&gt;Tap the watchOS 8 tab at the top of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3iy1P2"&gt;Select “enroll your Apple Watch” in the Get Started section of the watchOS 8 tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z0J81u"&gt;Scroll down and tap the “Download Profile” button and then select “allow” on the pop-up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vNrgIX"&gt;Install the beta profile in the Watch app on your iPhone, which should automatically open once the profile is downloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qYnM9B"&gt;You will be prompted to reboot your Apple Watch. Tap the button to allow this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8lumGX"&gt;Once the Apple Watch is rebooted, go to the Watch app, tap “General,” tap “Software Update.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6n7DA9"&gt;You should see the watchOS 8 beta ready to be installed on your watch. Tap “Install” to proceed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="i0EOG4"&gt;The software update will download to your phone and then transfer to the watch. To complete installation, the watch needs to be on its charger, within range of your iPhone, connected to Wi-Fi, and with 50 percent or more charge. If all of those criteria are not met, it will pause the installation until the watch is ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="MZ9wJX"&gt;Once the beta software is installed, the watch will reboot itself and you’ll be all set to use it. In our experience, some complications and third-party apps did not function until they were opened manually on the watch or the watch was rebooted a second time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22558944/watchos-beta-install-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22558944/watchos-beta-install-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-30T18:11:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-30T18:11:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Music Widget brings back the original Mac OS X iTunes widget </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LBUOzLPYFsArf_EmTmaoJFxcNSY=/180x0:2226x1364/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69526721/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_5.35.17_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TVvWck"&gt;Way back in 2005, Apple released Mac OS X Tiger, and with it, the original implementation of widgets on the Mac through its Dashboard software. One of those widgets was a now-defunct iTunes media player — but thanks to the efforts of programmer Mario Guzman, who’s recreated an &lt;a href="https://marioaguzman.github.io/musicwidget/#download"&gt;exact replica of the widget&lt;/a&gt; for modern Macs, you can once again enjoy your music in retro OS X style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DWlpeF"&gt;Ironically, the new Music Widget isn’t actually a widget (at least, not in the current style of widgets introduced in last year’s macOS Big Sur,) but rather a standalone app that mimics the look of the original iTunes widget from 2005. The app is fully functional, offering the same controls as the original. Music Widget only works with the Apple Music app, though— Spotify (or other music apps) won’t work with the widget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5UzDpD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Alright nerds. I have an early beta version of my Music Widget up for download. Let me know what you think. Retweets/screenshots are welcome.   &lt;a href="https://t.co/51sfimm7LI"&gt;https://t.co/51sfimm7LI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mario Guzman  ️‍      (@MarioGuzman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MarioGuzman/status/1408876166165893122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pCWRTu"&gt;Guzman’s replica also draws most of the artwork and UI elements directly in code, instead of using images, so you’re not stuck with 2005-era visuals on the widget when running on a pixel-dense Retina display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="R2X14x"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Listen to Spotify on this nostalgic iPod-style web music player","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548356/ipod-web-player-spotify-apple-music"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="L6rCTI"&gt;It’s not the only retro-style music player to pop up recently, either: &lt;a href="https://tannerv.com/ipod/"&gt;software developer Tanner Villarete&lt;/a&gt; created a stylistically similar web app that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548356/ipod-web-player-spotify-apple-music"&gt;offers an iPod Classic interface&lt;/a&gt; for listening to your Spotify or Apple Music library earlier this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kcZ2uj"&gt;Right now, &lt;a href="https://marioaguzman.github.io/musicwidget/#download"&gt;Music Widget is still in beta&lt;/a&gt;, and can be downloaded for free from Guzman’s website. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/6/30/22557991/music-widget-mac-os-x-itunes-player-control-tiger-dashboard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/6/30/22557991/music-widget-mac-os-x-itunes-player-control-tiger-dashboard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-30T17:33:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-30T17:33:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to restore your iPhone from iOS 15 beta back to iOS 14</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/436VxKbwU5MbJ4reDRcGvy8orFw=/0x8:1984x1331/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69526531/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_3up_060721.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iOS 15 comes with a number of new features and tweaks&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iyiSDk"&gt;Beta versions of new software are great to try out, but sometimes you realize that they’re not so good for day-to-day usage. If you’ve upgraded your iPhone to the iOS 15 beta, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;now available to the public&lt;/a&gt;, and you realize that you need to go back to the stable world of iOS 14.6, you can do that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="33XqPZ"&gt;The simplest way to go back to a stable version is to delete the iOS 15 beta profile and wait until the next update shows up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4WWqTe"&gt;Go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “General”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="54TVu0"&gt;Select “Profiles and &amp;amp; Device Management”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cRK43P"&gt;Select “Remove Profile” and restart your iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="UOQ9ma"&gt;Unfortunately, you won’t be able to return to a non-beta version of iOS until a new update is available. (You can check if one is available by going to “Settings” &amp;gt; “General” &amp;gt; “Software Update.”) If you don’t want to wait, you can do a more thorough recovery — it’s more complicated, but it will get you back to where you were sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WauVpJ"&gt;The first thing you have to do is put your iPhone into Recovery Mode. This is done by connecting your iPhone to your computer (making sure it’s up to date first). I tested these instructions using a MacBook Pro, but they should work using a PC as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="8garSo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to install the iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 public betas","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="aA7tkf"&gt;You then begin by doing the following (the following three bulleted directions are directly quoted from &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201263"&gt;Apple’s support page&lt;/a&gt;): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="IXr9IH"&gt;For iPhone 8 or later: Press and quickly release the Volume Up button. Press and quickly release the Volume Down button. Then, press and hold the Side button until you see the recovery mode screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="J5BNNc"&gt;For iPhone 7, iPhone 7 Plus,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;or iPod touch (7th generation): Press and hold the Sleep/Wake and Volume Down buttons at the same time. Don’t release the buttons when you see the Apple logo. Continue to hold both buttons until you see the recovery mode screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zQq1vM"&gt;For iPhone 6s and earlier, iPad with Home button, or iPod touch (6th generation or earlier): Press and hold the Sleep/Wake and Home buttons at the same time. Don’t release the buttons when you see the Apple logo. Continue to hold both buttons until you see the recovery mode screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="57A5kp"&gt;Whichever iPhone you have, once you follow the above directions, you should see a symbol showing a cable connecting to a computer on your iPhone. Turn your attention to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Pi5yOq"&gt;There will be a notice asking if you want to update, restore, or cancel. Select “Restore.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JZEKOWpGch4GGahwRN0LFab78Qg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692236/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_3.25.43_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="4UZSYp"&gt;You’ll be asked whether you’re sure you want to restore your phone since you’re about to wipe out any personalization and go back to factory settings. Select “Restore and Update.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2R7InZ5sccPfHMZ-aIdh3y0B6WA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692200/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_3.29.45_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Yd7dQP"&gt;You’ll be told that you’re going to be updated to iOS 14.6 (which is the most recent version of iOS 14). Select “Next.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K6zyi6YMqLVBuLycYtwiiGf4cO4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692209/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_3.30.49_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="inW1XG"&gt;At this point, you’ll be asked to agree to all of the various licensing data that you agreed to last time that you began using your iPhone. Click on “Agree.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8EazkH"&gt;You’ll then be told that your computer is downloading the software for the iPhone. It should take a while, maybe 15 minutes or so, depending on your system and your network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QCF3CvoTljUMX6uPz8AtFFdMsfQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692218/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_3.31.15_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="vNZJFp"&gt;Once the OS has been downloaded, you’ll be told that it is being installed on your phone (and the phone will visibly begin uploading the software and will probably restart once or twice). When it’s done, you’ll be told via your computer screen.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-C3RRC8o0Cul_zf74wV-zJwICAQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692231/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_3.40.31_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VlJLnE"&gt;Okay, now you should have restored your iPhone back to iOS 14.6. That’s all well and good, but you’ve got what is essentially a clean slate — you want to restore all your apps, personalization, and other stuff, right? This is where your backup comes in. (You &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; back up your phone before you installed the iOS 15 beta, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="fGHQsR"&gt;You’ll be asked if you want to set up your iPhone using the settings from another phone. If you’ve got another with all of your settings on it, well and good — just follow the directions. But assuming that you’re going to restore from a backup, tap on “Set Up Manually.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iWdY5K"&gt;At this point, you’ll enter your Wi-Fi connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TvcyXT"&gt;You then choose how you want to restore your backup: from iCloud, from a Mac or PC, from an iPhone, or from an Android phone. You can also decide not to transfer any data at all. Let’s assume you’ve backed up to iCloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0iv157"&gt;Once you’ve made that choice, you’ll be asked to enter your Apple ID name and password and to enter a verification code sent to your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xePpsP"&gt;If you’ve made more than one backup recently, you’ll be able to choose which. (Hopefully it will not be a backup from iOS 15, which will not be transferable.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="q3K0a4"&gt;Once you’ve chosen your backup, it will be transferred to your iPhone, and you should be back where you started before you installed iOS 15. You should be able to use your iPhone fairly quickly; however, it will take a few minutes before everything is uploaded from your backup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="er2aC6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22557790/ios-beta-install-restore-iphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22557790/ios-beta-install-restore-iphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
