<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-16T16:19:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-16T16:19:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-16T16:19:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows users can now manage their iCloud Passwords</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aH7ddqUMVde7u-tV2OpUm4KrLDQ=/0x0:860x573/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69733156/2021_08_16_11_16_34_Settings.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nN9avk"&gt;If you sync your iCloud Passwords with Windows, Apple’s new, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/icloud-windows/manage-passwords-icwa812f1681/1.0/icloud/1.0"&gt;dedicated iCloud Passwords app&lt;/a&gt; is going to give you some much-needed new abilities. The app, which comes with the iCloud for Windows 12.5 update, lets you search through your saved passwords, update them, add new ones, and delete login info you no longer want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yTE5xN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/icloud-windows/manage-passwords-icwa812f1681/1.0/icloud/1.0"&gt;Apple’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; explains how to manage your iCloud Passwords using the new app, but it’s relatively straightforward. You can access the app from the Start menu, and make any changes to your passwords that you need. Those changes will then be synced to your Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-dwpODws0adrDZaDAVXCNNKrA-A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22786016/2021_08_16_11_18_47_iCloud_Passwords.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iCloud Passwords running on Windows 10 (note that all data included in screenshots is example data). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NIyX9i"&gt;Apple rolled out some support for iCloud Passwords on Windows earlier this year. In January, an iCloud for Windows update &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22259720/apple-icloud-passwords-chrome-browser-extension-released"&gt;added support for a Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; that would let you use the passwords already in your iCloud Keychain, as well as add new ones to your keychain from Chrome. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252825/apple-icloud-keychain-windows-google-chrome"&gt;That extension&lt;/a&gt; had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263118/apple-icloud-windows-password-sync-version-removed"&gt;a very rocky rollout&lt;/a&gt;, but it eventually became available to users in a somewhat working state. It’s still part of iCloud for Windows 12.5’s password management system, and the 12.5 update brings support for an Edge version of the extension as well (in theory, Chrome extensions work with Edge, but &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/icloud-passwords/pejdijmoenmkgeppbflobdenhhabjlaj?hl=en"&gt;reviews on the Chrome web store&lt;/a&gt; indicate that this wasn’t the case for iCloud Passwords). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cinlsh7quWa9LdhYGMmxPZseqW4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785982/2021_08_16_11_20_37_Login_on_Twitter___Twitter.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chrome extension lets you use passwords saved in your iCloud Passwords.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hfRvka"&gt;This update makes using iCloud to sync your passwords significantly more viable if you’re someone who jumps between Windows and Mac (or who uses Windows and an iPhone). Being able to see and search through a list of your saved passwords gives you more flexibility than the browser extension, and being able to manage your passwords means that you don’t have to jump to an Apple device if you want to make changes to your logins. While the new app isn’t as fully featured as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22311182/best-free-password-manager-bitwarden-zoho-vault-roboform-sticky-password"&gt;dedicated password manager&lt;/a&gt; (or, indeed, as Keychain Access on Mac), it’s certainly better than the little-to-no management abilities Windows users had before for their iCloud Passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNDC1N"&gt;The 12.5 update for iCloud for Windows is available now, and you can get it by going to the Windows Store and searching for updates. If you don’t already &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/icloud-windows/set-up-icloud-passwords-icw2babf5e03/1.0/icloud/1.0"&gt;have iCloud Password syncing set up on your Windows machine&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have to enable it in iCloud Settings before you can use the password manager, but the process is relatively simple. Doing so requires an Apple account that uses two-factor authentication, along with an Apple device running iOS 14 / macOS 11 or later, which you’ll need to get the security code. You’ll also have to &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/learn-about-windows-hello-and-set-it-up-dae28983-8242-bb2a-d3d1-87c9d265a5f0#ID0EBD=Windows_10"&gt;have Windows Hello set up&lt;/a&gt; — but don’t worry if your computer doesn’t have biometric authentication, because you can also use a PIN. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627512/icloud-for-windows-12-5-password-manager-keychain"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627512/icloud-for-windows-12-5-password-manager-keychain</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-16T15:56:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-16T15:56:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>After Apple rejections, FlickType gives up on popular iPhone keyboard for the blind</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ehPF9Mv6r-SkJs0p-Rf_L-oS06g=/0x84:2016x1428/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69733034/flicktype_photo.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9Upup9"&gt;If you’re a blind or low-vision iPhone user who relies on &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/flicktype-watch-keyboard/id1359485719"&gt;the FlickType keyboard&lt;/a&gt; to type, I’ve got some bad news — you’re about to become a casualty of the fight between Apple and one of its staunchest critics. Developer Kosta Eleftheriou has announced that he’s discontinuing the iPhone keyboard portion of his app, and says that keyboard will automatically be removed in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HZuEIQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It's with a heavy heart today that we're announcing the discontinuation of our award-winning iPhone keyboard for blind users.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Apple has thrown us obstacle after obstacle for years while we try to provide an app to improve people's lives, and we can no longer endure their abuse. &lt;a href="https://t.co/cH1HCQzeP1"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cH1HCQzeP1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— FlickType Watch Keyboard (@FlickType) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FlickType/status/1427292830523744257?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="52ZqXA"&gt;You might have heard the entire app is going away, and that’s not actually true, Eleftheriou tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;In January 2020, he added a swipe-to-type Apple Watch keyboard to FlickType that saw the app skyrocket to the number one paid app in the entire Apple App Store for a time, and that app will continue to exist and continue to contain that Apple Watch keyboard.  Eleftheriou says the app has nearly half a million downloads, but he doesn’t have a breakdown for how many of those users rely on the iPhone keyboard specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The screenshot says “please enable full access for FlickType under the iOS Settings app.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nNV7oi5-nRWEhBwZwSWfE_mixVs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22786073/13_twS_I.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple provided Eleftheriou with this screenshot “proving” the app doesn’t work without access.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eXfm4m"&gt;If his name sounds familiar, that’s because Eleftheriou is the same developer who’s been poking holes in Apple’s App Store image for months, pointing out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;how egregious scams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395907/apple-match-three-game-gambling-marina-misko-vegas-pirates-lucky-stars"&gt;secret gambling dens&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454468/ios-app-scam-review-3-star-force-review-process-apple"&gt;review fraud&lt;/a&gt; keep making it through the company’s filters even though they’re pretty easy for anyone to root out. His fight became personal long before today: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22336380/apple-app-store-scam-lawsuit-kosta-eleftheriou-flicktype-ios-developer"&gt;he sued Apple in March&lt;/a&gt; for some seemingly shady behavior, alleging that Apple erected roadblocks to his FlickType keyboard in order to convince him to sell the technology to Apple for a discount, all while scammy mobile keyboard apps flourished on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfBxvV"&gt;Now, says Eleftheriou, Apple has suddenly decided to reject FlickType yet again — and for a reason that he’s already successfully argued with them in the past. He shared the rejection letter with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s a pretty simple dispute: Apple says the keyboard needs to work even if a user doesn’t give it “full access” to network access and other iOS features. But Eleftheriou says that if Apple actually tried to use the app, or consulted their earlier discussions, they’d see that the keyboard works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="N9YGH5"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We tried reaching out to Apple a total of 9 times last week, with no success. At this point they seem to be ignoring our attempts to contact them directly, despite previously explicitly telling us to "feel free" to contact them if we need "further clarification".&lt;/p&gt;— FlickType Watch Keyboard (@FlickType) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FlickType/status/1427292841676398596?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aqyvCH"&gt;To be clear, Apple’s &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/General/Conceptual/ExtensibilityPG/CustomKeyboard.html"&gt;own developer guidelines specify&lt;/a&gt; that “full access” isn’t a problem: the only dispute here is whether the app continues to work if a user turns it off — which it does, says Eleftheriou, if you turn VoiceOver on. “They’d have to try it as a VoiceOver user, something that they don’t seem to bother doing. I’ve had several rejections in the past because the reviewer didn’t know anything about VoiceOver,” Eleftheriou says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KuUMt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FlickType/status/1427292843928821765"&gt;As his Twitter thread explains&lt;/a&gt;, Eleftheriou sees this as the final straw for this specific feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NEntkf"&gt;“Our rejection history already spans more than FOURTY pages filled with repeated, unwarranted, &amp;amp; unreasonable rejections that serve to frustrate &amp;amp; delay rather than benefit end-users. And dealing with App Review isn’t just time-consuming. It’s also very emotionally draining,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nE4HhJ"&gt;Eleftheriou stops short of accusing Apple of retaliation, in a separate chat over Twitter DM. “I can only speculate about this rejection, but I’ve recently had many more rejections I haven’t talked about yet, and them ignoring my attempts to reach them is also new,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dg4tQe"&gt;“I can’t really know, but definitely feels like some kind of ‘special’ treatment going on,” he tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnhdju"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="67lAWh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s $64 billion-a-year App Store isn’t catching the most egregious scams","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"},{"title":"Amazon just got Fakespot booted off Apple’s iOS App Store","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580611/fakespot-ios-app-apple-amazon-fake-reviews"},{"title":"Scammy iOS app discovered that refuses to open unless you give it a good review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454468/ios-app-scam-review-3-star-force-review-process-apple"},{"title":"Senators target Apple’s App Store exclusivity in new bill","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620454/apple-google-app-store-senate-play-bill-epic-games-fortnite"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627515/flicktype-ios-keyboard-discontinued-blind-visually-impaired"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627515/flicktype-ios-keyboard-discontinued-blind-visually-impaired</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-16T14:53:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-16T14:53:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Local and anonymous social media app Yik Yak is back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3BQsWfGP4HEdBIJluaFa0viqaFo=/94x0:1107x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69732537/YikYakApp_2021_Aug_16.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="knVMtm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yikyak.com/"&gt;Yik Yak&lt;/a&gt; — the anonymous, local social media app that only shows posts from people in your immediate area — has &lt;a href="https://yikyak.com/the-yak-is-back"&gt;returned from the grave&lt;/a&gt; with new ownership after shutting down four years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N5ryfF"&gt;According to the app’s relaunched website, the new incarnation of Yik Yak bought the rights to redevelop the service in February 2021, with the aim of providing a local social media network that’s free from the “labels” that dominate communication on other platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMk0hp"&gt;The new app resembles the original version of Yik Yak from 2014: users can post and comment on short text posts that are only able to be viewed within a five-mile radius. Like Reddit, posts can be upvoted and downvoted, and a separate “hot” feed compiles the top post from the past 24 hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WFVnUx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  ICYMI: After a 4 year hiatus, Yik Yak is available in the App Store again!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  Anonymity, location-based, the hot feed &amp;amp; more — everything you used to love about Yik Yak&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  Now available on iPhone in the US — more countries and devices coming soon!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2B2NCKamdV"&gt;https://t.co/2B2NCKamdV&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/HUAKh4elcA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/HUAKh4elcA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Yik Yak (@YikYakApp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YikYakApp/status/1427310464585900035?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H7OIAS"&gt;Originally launched in late 2013, the app was a flash-in-the-pan success (particularly at college campuses) for most of 2014, when it was valued at $400 million by investors. But while the anonymity made it popular for college students, Yik Yak also was rife with bullying and harassment. In early 2016, in an effort to get things back on track, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/8/11175886/yik-yak-handles-usernames"&gt;Yik Yak added optional social media handles&lt;/a&gt;, which were made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/16/12492152/yik-yak-redesign-local-yakkers-status-updates"&gt;mandatory in August&lt;/a&gt; of that year, effectively removing what had made the service unique. The original incarnation of Yik Yak ended up shutting down in early 2017, when it was sold for $1 million to Square for its engineering talent and IP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYUghr"&gt;The new Yik Yak looks to be taking a serious stance on bullying and harassment on its platform, though — something that the original incarnation of the app failed to do. The new owners have posted an extensive list of its “&lt;a href="https://yikyak.com/community-guardrails"&gt;community guardrails&lt;/a&gt;,” which include prohibiting sharing of personal information, “anything that could be construed as bullying, abuse, defamation, harassment, stalking, or targeted hate or public humiliation,” and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvctrq"&gt;The company also notes that bullying, hate speech, threats, or other violations of any the community guardrails or terms of service can lead to an immediate ban from the platform. And posts that receive a total score of -5 will be hidden from view, too, to ensure that negative or harmful content isn’t surfaced further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ub5lhG"&gt;The new Yik Yak is currently only available to download on iOS for users in the US, but the developers are promising to expand to more countries and devices soon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627452/yik-yak-app-ios-back-local-anonymous-social-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627452/yik-yak-app-ios-back-local-anonymous-social-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-15T09:33:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-15T09:33:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jury decides Apple should pay $300 million in patent dispute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6xHGXD5zXS4Fkr3EsLfkpLlpt6E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69727943/acastro_170731_1777_0006_v1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple ordered to pay $300 million in a patent dispute | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2gSIul"&gt;Apple must pay $300 million in royalties following a retrial in a patent dispute, a Texas jury determined Friday. As &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/jury-awards-optis-300-million-second-patent-trial-against-apple-2021-08-13/"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the jury found that Apple should pay patent company Optis Wireless Technology and its related companies because the technology Apple used in its iPhones, iPads, and Watches allegedly infringed Optis’ patents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uVPd4m"&gt;Last year, a jury &lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/ip-law/apple-told-to-pay-506-million-in-texas-patent-trial-verdict-1"&gt;awarded Optis $506 million&lt;/a&gt; in the dispute, but a judge vacated that award in April, and ordered a new trial focused on damages only. US District Judge Rodney Gilstrap said the first jury had not been allowed to consider whether the amount was awarded on the “fair, reasonable, and non-discriminatory,” or FRAND, terms required in standard-essential patent cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="krgeS3"&gt;The five patents involved in the case once belonged to LG, Panasonic, and Samsung, &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2021/08/14/apple_google_patents/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Register&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;, but were obtained by Optis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9RcXsO"&gt;An Apple spokesperson wrote in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday that the company was disappointed by the verdict and plans to appeal. “Optis makes no products and its sole business is to sue companies using patents they accumulate,” the spokesperson wrote. “We will continue to defend against their attempts to extract unreasonable payments for patents they acquire.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mzv9dF"&gt;Last month &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/07/apple-reports-third-quarter-results"&gt;Apple reported&lt;/a&gt; record third-quarter revenue of $81.4 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WjHqaD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 15th 12:10PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added comment from Apple spokesperson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22625796/jury-apple-pay-300-million-patent-dispute-iphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22625796/jury-apple-pay-300-million-patent-dispute-iphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-14T14:39:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-14T14:39:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s controversial plan to try to curb child sexual abuse imagery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6z3Ld4HzH_dTWyXO8gjMRz1XVXU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69725913/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple ‘s plan to scan iOS devices for CSAM imagery has proven controversial | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why privacy experts are concerned&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="dc6dr1"&gt;When Apple announced changes it plans to make to iOS devices in an effort to help curb child abuse by finding child sexual abuse material (CSAM), parts of its plan generated backlash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="twOtsC"&gt;First, it’s rolling out an update to its Search app and Siri voice assistant on iOS 15, watchOS 8, iPadOS 15, and macOS Monterey. When a user searches for topics related to child sexual abuse, Apple will redirect the user to resources for reporting CSAM, or getting help for an attraction to such content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Jhnc4"&gt;But it’s Apple’s two other CSAM plans that have garnered criticism. One update will add a parental control option to Messages, sending an alert to parents if a child age 12 or younger views or sends sexually explicit pictures, and obscuring the images for any users under 18. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhX8SA"&gt;The one that’s proven most controversial is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611721/apple-csam-child-abuse-scanning-hash-system-ncmec"&gt;Apple’s plan to scan on-device images to find CSAM&lt;/a&gt; before they images are uploaded to iCloud, reporting them to Apple’s moderators who can then turn the images over to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) in the case of a potential match. While &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616381/apple-child-sexual-abuse-material-scanning-icloud-faq-pushback-privacy"&gt;Apple says the feature will protect users&lt;/a&gt; while allowing the company to find illegal content, many &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613365/apple-icloud-csam-scanning-whatsapp-surveillance-reactions"&gt;Apple critics and privacy advocates&lt;/a&gt; say the provision is basically a security backdoor, an apparent contradiction to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617554/apple-csam-child-safety-features-jen-king-riana-pfefferkorn-interview-decoder"&gt;Apple’s long-professed commitment to user privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rh7kyv"&gt;To stay up to speed on the latest news about Apple’s CSAM protection plans, follow our storystream, which we’ll update whenever there’s a new development. If you need a starting point, check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22613225/apple-csam-scanning-messages-child-safety-features-privacy-controversy-explained"&gt;explainer here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/14/22624770/apple-controversial-plan-csam-child-abuse-privacy-ios-messages"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/14/22624770/apple-controversial-plan-csam-child-abuse-privacy-ios-messages</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-13T16:25:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T16:25:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple says its iCloud scanning will rely on multiple child safety groups to address privacy fears</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ia0PCmtxH75mxbYkGpWC9GLEEtk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69723200/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VHOhKl"&gt;Apple has filled in more details around its upcoming plans to scan iCloud Photos for child sexual abuse material (CSAM) via users’ iPhones and iPads. The company &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/pdf/Security_Threat_Model_Review_of_Apple_Child_Safety_Features.pdf"&gt;released a new paper&lt;/a&gt; delving into the safeguards it hopes will increase user trust in the initiative. That includes a rule to only flag images found in multiple child safety databases with different government affiliations — theoretically stopping one country from adding non-CSAM content to the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAlWLt"&gt;Apple’s upcoming iOS and iPadOS releases will automatically match US-based iCloud Photos accounts against known CSAM from a list of image hashes compiled by child safety groups. While many companies scan cloud storage services remotely, Apple’s device-based strategy has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617554/apple-csam-child-safety-features-jen-king-riana-pfefferkorn-interview-decoder"&gt;drawn sharp criticism&lt;/a&gt; from some cryptography and privacy experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNC7E2"&gt;The paper, called “Security Threat Model Review of Apple’s Child Safety Features,” hopes to allay privacy and security concerns around that rollout. It builds on &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-executive-defends-tools-to-fight-child-porn-acknowledges-privacy-backlash-11628859600"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; interview&lt;/a&gt; with Apple executive Craig Federighi, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623336/craig-federighi-apple-icloud-photos-iphone-ipad-csam-scanning-auditability"&gt;outlined some of the information&lt;/a&gt; this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1GWcN8"&gt;In the document, Apple says it won’t rely on a single government-affiliated database — like that of the US-based National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, or NCMEC — to identify CSAM. Instead, it will only match pictures from at least two groups with different national affiliations. The goal is that no single government could have the power to secretly insert unrelated content for censorship purposes, since it wouldn’t match hashes in any other database.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A venn diagram with one circle labeled “Apple Child Safety Organization #1 hash list,” one labeled “Child Safety Organization #2 hash list,” and the overlap labeled “Apple only uses the intersecting hashes of two or more child safety organizations.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gfZtkVvGXvygEumbVZ86p-PnRRc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22781290/Screen_Shot_2021_08_13_at_3.35.42_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/pdf/Security_Threat_Model_Review_of_Apple_Child_Safety_Features.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xv3FdB"&gt;Apple has referenced the potential use of multiple child safety databases, but until today, it hadn’t explained the overlap system. In a call with reporters, Apple said it’s only naming NCMEC because it hasn’t yet finalized agreements with other groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XByiVR"&gt;The paper confirms a detail Federighi mentioned: initially, Apple will only flag an iCloud account if it identifies 30 images as CSAM. This threshold was picked to provide a “drastic safety margin” to avoid false positives, the paper says — and as it evaluates the system’s performance in the real world, “we may change the threshold.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BqgB8O"&gt;It also provides more information on an auditing system that Federighi mentioned. Apple’s list of known CSAM hashes will be baked into iOS and iPadOS worldwide, although the scanning system will only run in the US for now. Apple will provide a full list of hashes that auditors can check against child safety databases, another method to make sure it’s not secretly matching more images. Furthermore, it says it will “refuse all requests” for moderators to report “anything other than CSAM materials” for accounts that get flagged — referencing the potential for using this system for other kinds of surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yBhTTw"&gt;Federighi acknowledged that Apple had introduced “confusion” with its announcement last week. But Apple has stood by the update itself — it tells reporters that although it’s still finalizing and iterating on details, it hasn’t changed its launch plans in response to the past week’s criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623859/apple-icloud-photos-csam-scanning-security-multiple-jurisdictions-safeguard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623859/apple-icloud-photos-csam-scanning-security-multiple-jurisdictions-safeguard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-13T12:34:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T12:34:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Arcade is getting a new Castlevania game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bI9eCXa-GFkTcZnrkrg8Qzu4fsE=/400x0:4720x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69721901/15_5120x2880.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SRo2hd"&gt;With the exception of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/7/15938192/netflix-castlevania-review-animated-video-game-adaptation"&gt;an anime series on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, the last few years have been quiet when it comes to the gothic action series &lt;em&gt;Castlevania&lt;/em&gt;. It looks like that’s about to change, though: developer Konami just announced a new game coming exclusively to Apple Arcade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Z3fkCp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10432584"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WFIiYt"&gt;The new title is called &lt;em&gt;Castlevania: Grimoire of Souls&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s described as “an original side-scrolling action game that features a line-up of classic, well-loved characters from the series’ hit catalogue.” The graphics certainly look like a departure for the series, but there are some notable names on board, including character designer Ayami Kojima and composer Michiru Yamane, both of whom have contributed to the series since the iconic &lt;em&gt;Symphony of the Night&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Grimoire of Souls &lt;/em&gt;doesn’t have a release date, but Apple says that it’s “coming soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ygusmb"&gt;If the name sounds familiar, it’s probably because Konami previously soft-launched a version of &lt;em&gt;Grimoire of Souls&lt;/em&gt; in Canada &lt;a href="https://toucharcade.com/2020/07/09/castlevania-grimoire-of-souls-release-date-closing-canada-ios-android-free/"&gt;before shutting it down last year&lt;/a&gt;. That iteration was free-to-play with added microtransactions, a feature that is absent from all Apple Arcade games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HXzwRr"&gt;The news comes at a fairly busy time for Apple’s subscription games service. Today sees the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616888/fantasian-part-2-apple-arcade-release-date"&gt;part two of &lt;em&gt;Fantasian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22383403/fantasian-review-apple-arcade-rpg-iphone-ipad"&gt;a classic RPG from &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; creator Hironobu Sakaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585353/apple-arcade-tetris-beat-skate-city-tokyo-monster-hunter-stories"&gt;the music-focused &lt;em&gt;Tetris Beat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623498/apple-arcade-castlevania-grimoire-of-souls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623498/apple-arcade-castlevania-grimoire-of-souls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-13T11:23:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T11:23:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Craig Federighi says Apple’s child safety scanning will have ‘multiple levels of auditability’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Epic-Apple Trial Hangs Over Some 50,000 Games On App Store" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MzJYUURQ9UFgjUd0TWsSS-N-4HU=/0x0:3999x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69721417/1232992663.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tPKT38"&gt;Apple executive Craig Federighi says iCloud Photos’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22613225/apple-csam-scanning-messages-child-safety-features-privacy-controversy-explained"&gt;plans to scan for child sexual abuse material&lt;/a&gt; (or CSAM) will include “multiple levels of auditability.” In &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-executive-defends-tools-to-fight-child-porn-acknowledges-privacy-backlash-11628859600"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Federighi — Apple’s senior vice president of software engineering — offered new details about its controversial child safety measures. That includes a claim that the iPad and iPhone’s device-level scanning will help security experts verify that Apple is using the system responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZeals"&gt;Like many companies with cloud storage services, Apple will check iCloud Photos images against a list from the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC), looking for exact matches with known CSAM pictures. But unlike many services, it will run searches on the device, not fully remotely. “Imagine someone was scanning images in the cloud. Well, who knows what’s being scanned for?” Federighi said, referring to remote scans. “In our case, the database is shipped on device. People can see, and it’s a single image across all countries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DjUrf"&gt;Federighi elaborated slightly on how this might give people confidence Apple isn’t greatly expanding the database to include material besides illegal CSAM, particularly in countries with restrictive censorship policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vMPNRl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re making sure that you don’t have to trust any one entity, or even any one country”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B5anlI"&gt;“We ship the same software in China with the same database we ship in America, as we ship in Europe. If someone were to come to Apple [with a request to scan for data beyond CSAM], Apple would say no. But let’s say you aren’t confident. You don’t want to just rely on Apple saying no. You want to be sure that Apple couldn’t get away with it if we said yes,” he told the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;. “There are multiple levels of auditability, and so we’re making sure that you don’t have to trust any one entity, or even any one country, as far as what images are part of this process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y7s92c"&gt;Apple has previously said that it’s only rolling out the system in the United States and that it will &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/06/apple-says-any-expansion-of-csam-detection-outside-of-the-us-will-occur-on-a-per-country-basis/"&gt;consider launching in other countries&lt;/a&gt; on a case-by-case basis. The company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Apple will ship the hash database of known CSAM on the operating system in all countries, but it will only be used for scanning in the US. The &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; further clarifies that there will be an independent auditor who can verify the images involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k7QNze"&gt;Federighi also offered more detail on when the scanning system will notify an Apple moderator of potential illegal content. Apple has said before that a single match won’t trigger a red flag — a measure intended to prevent false positives. Instead, the system generates “safety vouchers” for each match and alerts Apple if the number hits a certain threshold. Apple has declined to publicize the exact threshold, saying this could let abusers evade detection. But Federighi says it’s “on the order of 30 known child pornographic images.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dFkTE8"&gt;Some security experts have offered cautious praise of Apple’s system and acknowledged the importance of finding CSAM online. But many have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617554/apple-csam-child-safety-features-jen-king-riana-pfefferkorn-interview-decoder"&gt;criticized Apple’s abrupt rollout&lt;/a&gt; and a lack of clarity on how the system worked. In his interview with the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Federighi acknowledged the confusion. “It’s really clear a lot of messages got jumbled pretty badly in terms of how things were understood,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623336/craig-federighi-apple-icloud-photos-iphone-ipad-csam-scanning-auditability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623336/craig-federighi-apple-icloud-photos-iphone-ipad-csam-scanning-auditability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-13T08:40:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T08:40:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verge readers can snag three months of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate for $30</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="xcloud" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RZhHb07NlhEI2sul46R8YzM5IoE=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69720439/vpavic_xcloud_20201009_0011_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Microsoft’s flagship subscription combines Xbox Game Pass and Xbox Live Gold in one attractive package. | Photo by Nick Statt / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xJPIOV"&gt;If you’re a gamer, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22530941/xbox-game-pass-e3-2021-bethesda-yakuza"&gt;Xbox Game Pass&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best deals in town. Microsoft’s popular subscription service — which touted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250795/xbox-game-pass-subscribers-growth-microsoft"&gt;more than 18 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year — has been dubbed the “Netflix of video games,” namely because it provides access to more than a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%2Fgames%3FranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DTnL5HPStwNw%26ranSiteID%3DTnL5HPStwNw-NG1EGejqTZh7KDYouebdEQ%26epi%3DTnL5HPStwNw-NG1EGejqTZh7KDYouebdEQ%26irgwc%3D1%26OCID%3DAID2200057_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%2528ir__0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xr3dfzggxj29e00%2529%25287593%2529%25281243925%2529%2528TnL5HPStwNw-NG1EGejqTZh7KDYouebdEQ%2529%2528%2529%26irclickid%3D_0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xr3dfzggxj29e00&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F8%2F13%2F22622197%2Fxbox-game-pass-ultimate-subscription-samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-apple-watch-series-6-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;hundred Xbox titles&lt;/a&gt; for a flat, monthly fee. Xbox Game Pass Ultimate takes things a step further, combining Xbox Game Pass with Xbox Live Gold, giving subscribers access to exclusive deals, online multiplayer, EA Play titles, and Microsoft’s cloud gaming service, xCloud, which is now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554267/microsoft-xcloud-game-streaming-xbox-pass-ios-iphone-ipad-pc"&gt;widely available on iOS and PC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQE5WR"&gt;Typically, a three-month subscription to Xbox Game Pass Ultimate runs $45. And while &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fxbox-game-pass-ultimate%2Fcfq7ttc0khs0%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s ongoing promotion&lt;/a&gt; will knock the price down to $1 for new subscribers, it’s not available for returning players. Thankfully, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers can purchase a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fxbox-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-3-month-membership-xbox-one-windows-10-xbox-live-key-global%2Fbest-pick&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F8%2F13%2F22622197%2Fxbox-game-pass-ultimate-subscription-samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-apple-watch-series-6-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-month subscription at Eneba for $30&lt;/a&gt;, while supplies last. The sale price will fluctuate around $30.85 (with service fees), but if you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;XGPU3VERGE&lt;/strong&gt;, the price should come in just shy of $30 at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="e1485R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9532770"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MdR7AP"&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 isn’t a direct sequel to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21206151/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-review-android-laptop"&gt;Galaxy Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; — and it’s better off for it. The midrange Chromebook hits all the right marks, while retaining an affordable price tag that becomes even more appealing when you factor in its &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsamsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-13-3-qled-touch-screen-intel-core-i3-8gb-memory-128gb-emmc-fiesta-red%2F6448525.p%3FskuId%3D6448525&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;current sale price at Best Buy: $600&lt;/a&gt;. For the money, you get a functional laptop with a gorgeous QLED display, all-day battery life, and a bright, eye-catching finish that’s sure to turn heads no matter where you go (it’s also available in a “mercury gray”). It’s one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; you can buy, and it comes with 8GB of RAM, 128GB of storage, and a Core i3 processor, which should be enough for everyday use. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301481/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gAcR0s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10698797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="PSu4DU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"New Chromebooks will now have Google Meet installed by default","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607620/google-meet-app-chromebooks-chrome-os-now-preinstalled"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0ehdqk"&gt;Like its predecessors, the Apple Watch Series 6 is easily the best smartwatch available for the iPhone. Not only does the Series 6 boast a wealth of health features and an always-on display, but it comes with built-in sleep tracking and a strong ecosystem of third-party complications, a hallmark no other smartwatch manufacturer has yet to replicate. The watch’s deep integration with the iPhone only bolsters the wearable’s appeal alongside watchOS 7, a mobile operating system built to handle all the basic features we’ve come to expect in a smartwatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZaCmI"&gt;Normally $430, you can purchase the 44mm, GPS-enabled &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/b3Do0m"&gt;Apple Watch Series 6 at Target right now for $360&lt;/a&gt;, one of the better prices we’ve seen on this particular model in recent months. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="714qv9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10598305"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="7k7k6b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces watchOS 8 with new health features","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="70rnAa"&gt;Other great deals happening now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="pAgehN"&gt;Both editions of &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748907191883258731#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are available at Best Buy for $75, matching the best price we’ve encountered on the inventive Switch title. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514758/mario-kart-live-home-circuit-review-nintendo-switch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Sx4IwC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00N1YPXW2?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Blue’s Yeti Microphone&lt;/a&gt; is on sale at Amazon for $100 in a variety of colors. It’s not the lowest price we’ve seen on the versatile USB mic, but it’s still a notable discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6uJjUD"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5PHB83/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s M1-powered Mac mini&lt;/a&gt; is $100 off at Amazon, matching the desktop machine’s best price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jKXmIT"&gt;All colorways of the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B096SV8SJG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Studio Buds&lt;/a&gt; are on sale at Amazon for $130, the first significant discount to date on Apple’s latest true wireless earbuds. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wkPJa9"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748914964623059007#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nanoleaf’s Triangle Smarter Pack&lt;/a&gt; is $20 off at Best Buy, bringing the price of the customizable lighting panels down to $180.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2VPteh"&gt;If you own the latest, 11-inch iPad Pro, you can pick up &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-11365093?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-magic-keyboard-case-for-11-inch-ipad-pro-2021-11-inch-ipad-pro-2020%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s Magic Keyboard Case&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-11365093?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-pencil-2nd-generation-ipad-pro%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;second-gen Apple Pencil&lt;/a&gt; for $300 at Verizon. Simply add both items to your cart to receive the sizable $115 discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YkVHp7"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2FLG-C1PU-48-HDR-4K-Ultra-HD-Smart-OLED-TV-2021-Model-%2F184898835257%3F_trksid%3D%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals081221%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F8%2F13%2F22622197%2Fxbox-game-pass-ultimate-subscription-samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-apple-watch-series-6-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG’s 48-inch C1 OLED&lt;/a&gt; is just $1,197 at eBay with coupon code &lt;strong&gt;SAVE20FORBTS&lt;/strong&gt;, saving you more than 13 percent on the brilliant OLED TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cWmsT5"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-13527013?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsellout.woot.com%2Foffers%2Famazon-usb-c-to-lightning-cable-cord%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;foot-long AmazonBasics USB-C to Lightning Cable&lt;/a&gt; is $11 at Woot, the second-best price we’ve seen on the basic accessory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="FN5TjR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/13/22622197/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-subscription-samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-apple-watch-series-6-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/13/22622197/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-subscription-samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-apple-watch-series-6-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T16:09:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T16:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple updates Eddy Cue’s title to better reflect its turn to services</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="eddy cue" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jh0tWKaCOCJsN2Sg4SIygIt4zQ0=/6x0:1020x676/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69717596/2013-06-10eddycue-1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jgwTry"&gt;Apple rolled out &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fleadership%2Feddy-cue%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F12%2F22622178%2Fapple-eddy-cue-job-title-update-senior-vp-services" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a small but meaningful update&lt;/a&gt; to senior executive Eddy Cue’s job title on Thursday that features an area of interest the company has long been focused on: services (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/12/eddy-cue-title-change-services-apple/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Eddy Cue is a longstanding veteran at Apple who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/4/26/4265172/itunes-store-at-10-how-apple-built-a-digital-media-juggernaut"&gt;helped build iTunes&lt;/a&gt; and the App Store, but his new title of “Senior Vice President, Services” reflects the company’s increasingly important side hustle, if not outright transformation into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/20/18273179/apple-icloud-itunes-app-store-music-services-businesses"&gt;a media business and subscription peddler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3iqBM"&gt;Prior to Thursday, Eddy Cue was senior vice president of internet software and services, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210303073700/https://www.apple.com/leadership/eddy-cue/"&gt;with responsibilities&lt;/a&gt; that included overseeing the iTunes Store, Apple Music, Apple Pay, Maps, Search Ads, iCloud, and iWork. His new job description emphasizes Apple’s subscription darlings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6r296t"&gt;Eddy oversees the full range of Apple’s services, including Apple Music, Apple News, Apple Podcasts, the Apple TV app, and Apple TV Plus, as well as Apple Pay, Apple Card, Maps, Search Ads, Apple’s iCloud services, and Apple’s productivity and creativity apps. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ApPa26"&gt;Apple still makes a ton of money selling hardware and software — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596120/apple-q3-2021-earnings-iphone-ipad-mac"&gt;earning a total of $81.43 billion during the third quarter of 2021&lt;/a&gt; — but its services business has specifically been growing as of late, earning an all-time revenue high of $17.5 billion during the same quarter. Apple’s found major success &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;in streaming hits like &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that may have helped, and seems primed to take even bigger, more &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;-sized swings &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547252/foundation-release-date-apple-tv-plus-september"&gt;with shows like &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; later this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mETswq"&gt;Cue’s had a hand in many pies over his time at Apple, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/1/16240584/apple-eddy-cue-siri-craig-federighi"&gt;managing Siri for a period&lt;/a&gt; before Apple began to actively compete with Google Assistant. He’s also now infamously known as one of the few executives &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406303/imessage-android-eddy-cue-emails-apple-epic-deposition"&gt;who pushed for Apple to bring iMessage to Android&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to an email exchange between Cue and senior vice president of software engineering Craig Federighi that was dug up as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; antitrust lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlhLGX"&gt;A title change might not mean that much in terms of what Cue does day to day, but it is yet more evidence that Apple’s services business is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RotckP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sl1ehU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3lvlgv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22622178/apple-eddy-cue-job-title-update-senior-vp-services"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22622178/apple-eddy-cue-job-title-update-senior-vp-services</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
