<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-20T09:15:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T09:15:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T09:15:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>The 2021 iPad Pro has dropped to its lowest price yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPad Pro is great for video editing" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UkLkxjCBbLqTt4uOChrjSfqPs-U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70020067/vpavic_210512_4592_0110.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can save $200 on the 2021 iPad Pro today.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Kayla Murkison / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e8wy1U"&gt;If you can’t wait to get your hands on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs"&gt;Apple’s new MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;, check out this great iPad Pro deal, which will certainly keep you distracted in the meantime. Today &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0932CJZ22/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;at Amazon, you can save $200&lt;/a&gt; on this upgraded 12.9-inch model that has 256GB of storage. Typically $1,199, the retailer is offering the Wi-Fi-only version in space gray for $999 instead, which is an appealing price since it’s the current cost of the 128GB version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWJfvT"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we praised the iPad Pro’s beautiful Mini LED screen, the fast M1 processor, and the Center Stage camera, which follows faces while you make video calls. The iPad also offers good dual rear cameras that are paired with lidar, excellent microphones, support for the second-gen Apple Pencil, and more. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZdRwfE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NOpvli"&gt;Android phone owners feeling left out while the tech world goes nuts over the latest AirPods 3, fear not: we’ve got something for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gC5zXR"&gt;Samsung’s entry-level wireless &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Wireless-Cancelling-Bluetooth-Lightweight/dp/B0942DM32W?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt; are the company’s smallest and lightest true wireless earbuds yet. Typically $150, right now Amazon is selling them for $130, the lowest price it’s offered on the well-reviewed earbuds yet. The discount applies to all styles, ranging from white and graphite to olive green. You can also add a Galaxy SmartTag, paying $155 in total instead of the $180 that it usually costs to buy both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SUZRFZ"&gt;We loved that it offers features like active noise cancellation, wireless charging, and a small, low-profile design with good audio quality and performance. It’s so good and affordable that, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we predicted it would become the default pick for many Android users — especially when the sales start to hit, which it seems they are. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vXnixU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815939"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jQ08n2"&gt;Razer’s Basilisk V2 wired gaming mouse is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21252193/best-gaming-mouse"&gt;one of the best mice you can buy&lt;/a&gt;. It’s already a good deal in and of itself, offering many of the features that comes with the more expensive Basilisk Ultimate, Razer’s wireless version, but for an affordable price. Today, however, it’s a better deal given you can get it for over half off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irxDLw"&gt;Typically $80, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B082G5BDNC/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfPnd39G8ta" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are selling the mouse for $35 instead. For a nearly 60 percent discount, you can buy a mouse that offers a scroll wheel with adjustable tension, tactile buttons, a thin SpeedFlex cable, customizable LEDs, and fast performance. What’s more, Best Buy is also throwing in $10 off a three-month digital subscription to Xbox Game Pass for PC when you buy it there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s8e5U1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221776"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bxVsxx"&gt;You can currently grab a pair of the Jabra Elite 75t earbuds for just $80 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Elite-75t-Earbuds-Comfortable/dp/B07X9VG6ZJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfDfEmv2ecW#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. Jabra has since released an updated version of these earbuds, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Jabra Elite 3&lt;/a&gt;, but we still consider the 75t to be a decent alternative to the AirPods, thanks to their solid sound quality and comfortable design. These earbuds come in black or gray and can last a little over five hours on a single charge. The on-ear mics can be used for calls, as well as for summoning Siri, Alexa, or Google Assistant — and you can connect them to two devices at once, an unusual feature for this price. The matte-finished case can hold an extra 18 hours of juice and can be topped off via USB-C. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HYXLcL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386608"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5SPZ8U"&gt;Another fine deal is on a curved gaming monitor, this time for the lowest price ever. You can currently &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfO4JTzLnAq#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;save $150 on the Samsung CRG5 curved gaming monitor at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. Normally $399.99, it costs $249.99. The CRG5 has a 27-inch 1080p panel with a 240Hz refresh rate and Nvidia G-Sync compatibility, both of which should provide stellar performance in the gaming space that's tough to match at this price. The monitor has HDMI and DisplayPort outputs, but it lacks support for peripheral USB connectivity. Another small pain point is the stand, which has limited adjustment options. Though the CRG5 does have a built-in 75 x 75 VESA mount if you need to make the panel more suitable for your desk setup.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P0C0fE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10816293"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5wi7Os"&gt;Dell’s Alienware lineup may have greater curb appeal, but the Dell G15 brings similar performance, just without the extraterrestrial aesthetic. Right now, you can &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfO4Uf74Sb2#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;save $270 on this excellent gaming laptop at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. It costs $880 instead of its usual $1,150 price. This 15-inch laptop manages to pack in a Ryzen 7 5800H CPU, an Nvidia RTX 3050 Ti, and a 512GB SSD. These specs should provide excellent performance for the 1080p high-refresh panel on the G15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SQrNyL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10816306"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ieW5Na"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Best Gaming Laptop in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="cnKbBq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;is turning 10, and you’re invited to the party taking place in New York City on the 22nd and 23rd of October (that’s this weekend!). On The Verge is going to be a celebration of everything we’ve accomplished over the past decade, and we want you to be a part of it. Right now you can &lt;a href="https://voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/evite" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;snag tickets for just $99 with the &lt;strong&gt;promo code $99NOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which gets you admission for both days and four complimentary drink tickets. The event will include speakers from &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;and from the wider world of tech, as well as musical performances and interactive experiences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fzmXLk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/20/22734880/2021-ipad-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-2-dell-gaming-razer-bailisk-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/20/22734880/2021-ipad-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-2-dell-gaming-razer-bailisk-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: the MacBook Pro 14-inch’s $20 power brick upsell is probably worth it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NIO_tKL0ve33zAqcLcjYg4abcPg=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018348/lcimg_f1ce43fd_90a7_4584_bc4f_63c9935d516b.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dSAcBZ"&gt;If you’re looking at buying the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;$1,999 base model MacBook Pro 14-inch&lt;/a&gt;, there’s one upgrade that you may really want to make — the $20 one that gets you the 96W power adapter instead of the 67W included power adapter. That’s because, according to some wording on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/macbook-pro/14-inch-space-gray-8-core-cpu-14-core-gpu-512gb#"&gt;Apple’s MacBook Pro configuration page&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/19/apple-67w-adapter-cant-fast-charge/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), you’ll need the more powerful charger if you want to take advantage of the computer’s fast charging feature, which can charge the laptop up to 50 percent in half an hour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="om07HD"&gt;Is it ridiculous that Apple is basically taxing the people who want to buy its least expensive (but still very pricey!) new MacBook Pro? Yes, absolutely — but you should still probably pay it if you want to charge your laptop up quickly. The exception is if you already have a charging brick capable of 100W USB-PD power delivery: Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that you can fast charge via Thunderbolt as long as your power brick provides enough power. If you already have a beefy power brick, you can skip the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MVvDLva6vYe47MyboXqOnpcfEkM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940510/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_3.41.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This may be the best $20 you can spend on an accessory for your new MacBook Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qZIY2O"&gt;I know it probably doesn’t feel great to encourage Apple’s nickel-and-diming, but if you want fast charging, this will likely be the best way to get it. There may be, somewhere in the world, a 100W USB-PD charging brick that sells for $20, but there’s no way I would trust it enough to charge a very expensive computer. (If it was $20, I might not even trust it not to burn down my house). I’d pick the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjWk18"&gt;The one silver lining is that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733119/apple-new-macbook-pro-magsafe-back"&gt;this is only a problem on the base 8 CPU core / 14 GPU core model&lt;/a&gt; — if you do any processor upgrades, you’ll get the 96W brick for “free.” Please note, though, that upgrading just the RAM and/or storage on the base MacBook Pro won’t get you that upgrade, but if you’re in the configuration screen anyways, you should absolutely check that box unless you hate fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Pixel 6 doesn’t come with five years of Android updates — only three</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nSPoNXX5eOm7F6oh4iKbTkaetyA=/152x0:1768x1077/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018216/qMm7BP1Fye.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VerlUH"&gt;For the first time ever, Google’s new phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22710844/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-ai-speed-specs-details"&gt;are powered by a Google-designed chip&lt;/a&gt;, giving the company an Apple-like level of control over the inner workings of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;the new Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro.&lt;/a&gt; But if you were hoping that meant they’d also get an Apple-like level of new OS updates, the company is throwing a bit of cold water on that. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/4457705#zippy=%2Cpixel-xl-a-a-xl-xl-a-a-g-a-g%2Cpixel-pixel-pro-phones"&gt;Google’s support page shows it’s only promising&lt;/a&gt; to offer Android updates through October 2024 (via &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-pixel-6-three-years-os-updates-five-years-security-patches/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;), &lt;/em&gt;a total of three years after release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l4ikZY"&gt;“Users will still get at least 3 years of OS updates, after which we’re committing to ensure that Pixels will stay up-to-date and secure,” Google tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The frequency and categories of updates will depend on the capabilities and needs of the hardware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7M9vCk"&gt;While Google prominently announced during its Tuesday keynote that the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro would get five years of &lt;em&gt;security&lt;/em&gt; updates — two years more! — it seems that Android version updates (like Android 11, Android 12, etc) are another story. And though Google is technically saying it will offer new versions of Android until “at least” October 2024, the company hasn’t historically gone above and beyond those sorts of promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qv8tNy"&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523351/ios-15-iphone-6s-plus-se-compatibility"&gt;the six-year-old iPhone 6S recently got an update to iOS 15&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T16:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T16:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is ready to admit it was wrong about the future of laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m12jFAfSID_WEfiedS0EpLEa7mE=/1x0:1911x1273/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70017538/Apple_MacBook_Pro_Ports_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ports, ports, glorious ports.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3hjCdN"&gt;There’s plenty to be excited about when it comes to Apple’s new 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros. As well as souped-up Pro and Max versions of the already capable M1 chip that Apple debuted last year, they also include numerous quality of life improvements like the return of MagSafe, a row of function keys rather than an OLED Touch Bar, and of course, a full selection of ports that won’t have users reaching for a dongle if they just want to import some photos from an SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hYTmsh"&gt;In fact, Apple was so enthusiastic about these “new” features, you’d be forgiven for forgetting that it was the one that killed most of them off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13490774/apple-macbook-pro-review-2016-13-inch-laptop"&gt;in 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="CN7cuC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple finally listened to the pros","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ecOgaI"&gt;“Users value the full-height function row on the standalone Magic Keyboard, and we’ve brought it to the MacBook Pro,” Apple’s Shruti Haldea said &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/exM1uajp--A?t=1957"&gt;as she explained the decision to ditch the Touch Bar&lt;/a&gt;, the touchscreen OLED strip Apple so enthusiastically introduced five years ago. “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/exM1uajp--A?t=1989"&gt;Having a wide range of ports can make life a lot easier for pros&lt;/a&gt;,” Haldea continued, concisely summarizing what professional users have been saying for roughly half a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3ZNF2i9fNRbLByiY1cLh5Kwg-9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22939123/msedge_gtjccFwnty.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Mac product line manager Shruti Haldea introduces the new MacBook Pro — including a physical function row!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nxLP4M"&gt;MagSafe, the convenient magnetic charging connector, is also returning to laptops after Apple stopped including it in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="97eR2f"&gt;Although it’s obviously backtracking, I think Apple is absolutely making the right call with all three of these changes. For the vast majority of users, a proper function row is far more useful than a software-based Touch Bar that failed to catch on with developers; a bevy of easily accessible ports make life easier for Pros and average Joes alike, and MagSafe is faster to connect than a USB-C cable and can prevent your laptop from being damaged when someone trips on the power cord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DwJg1e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;All three features feel like the right call&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pL4riF"&gt;But it’s hard to ignore the broader context of these improvements, which is that they effectively bring the company’s 2021 MacBook Pros back in line with the features they were already offering from 2012 to early 2016. Arguably, the primary reason these new MacBooks are being greeted with overwhelming enthusiasm now is that Apple made the wrong bet on where laptop design was headed back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RppqPt"&gt;The MacBook’s transition to USB-C arguably started with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/4/9/8372335/12-inch-macbook-review"&gt;2015 12-inch MacBook&lt;/a&gt;, which included just two ports: one USB-C port to handle charging, display output, and connecting of any and all accessories and one 3.5mm headphone jack. But it was with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/27/13436750/apple-macbook-pro-announced-laptop-price-release-date-specs"&gt;2016 refresh of the MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s commitment to an exclusively USB-C laptop future became truly apparent. Rather than the collection of Thunderbolt, USB Type-A, HDMI, and SD card ports that previous models had included, the 2016 MacBook Pro lineup included a choice of either two or four USB Type-C / Thunderbolt ports, alongside a headphone jack. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/5/13523372/usb-c-macbook-adapter-donglelife-problems-thunderbolt"&gt;dongle era&lt;/a&gt; had begun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="macbook pro 2016" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8VEWSXvGr9NzOdoclpv_oiaLnzY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/7390289/vpavic_161031_1256_0096.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s 2016 MacBook Pro, and its sadly necessary USB-C adaptors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rD7InI"&gt;Apple was one of the earliest adopters of what was, at the time, a very new connector. And going all-in on USB-C was basically unheard of. USB Type-A was still dominant on laptops and desktops, while Android manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/8/2/12344688/samsung-galaxy-note-7-announced-price-release-date-specs"&gt;like Samsung&lt;/a&gt; were only just starting to switch away from Micro USB in their flagship phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OSJjQ"&gt;Most people know what happened next: owners were forced to invest in adapters for all their old peripherals. Their laptop itself may have gotten slightly slimmer and lighter, but for pro use on the go, any space or weight saved in a backpack or briefcase was tempered by the added bulk and complexity of the extra accessories you needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="z1fiCu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An end to adapters&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bHiVKJ"&gt;We all know what ended up happening, but I think an interesting question to ask is what Apple &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; was going to happen after it transitioned wholesale to USB-C. For what it’s worth, the company seemed, at the time, to have been genuinely caught off guard by the anger from users having to buy endless adaptors to connect basic accessories and, shortly after the release of its 2016 MacBook Pros, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/4/13524272/apple-cutting-usb-c-adaptor-prices-macbook-pro"&gt;cut prices across swathes of its USB-C adapter lineup&lt;/a&gt; to help users “transition” to the new standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2sgIaW"&gt;To me, this suggests Apple thought #DongleLife was going to be a temporary transitional phase rather than the new normal it eventually became. For an example of the kinds of accessories it thought would become commonplace in the future, take a look at the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/27/13440158/apple-event-lg-ultrafine-5k-displays"&gt;5K display from LG&lt;/a&gt; it announced onstage at the same event, which it said was designed to pair with the new MacBook Pro. The display used a single Thunderbolt 3 cable for video, power, and data and also acted as a USB hub, thanks to a trio of additional USB-C ports. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sEP4cX8xXGWzaN321Mhlyhf2RTo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938876/HKN62_AV5.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s 5K monitor, announced onstage alongside the MacBook Pro 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pshcOR"&gt;Had monitors like these quickly become commonplace, we would have ended up with a future where users could dispense with bulky dongles and adaptors and have the convenience of plugging into a static desk setup with just a single cable. But while some monitors did, what generally happened was that monitors continued to ship with a mix of HDMI and DisplayPort connectors, and users were forced to use adapters whenever they wanted to connect. Not to mention, plenty of people happily use the same monitor for far longer than the laptops they plug into them, particularly when they’re secondary displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GAHSZx"&gt;Apple isn’t the only company to have made a bet on USB-C that didn’t quite pay off. In 2018, a consortium of companies that included AMD, Nvidia, Oculus, Valve, and Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/17/17583362/virtuallink-vr-headsets-oculus-valve-microsoft-connect-usb-c-cable"&gt;announced VirtualLink&lt;/a&gt;, a USB-C connection standard for VR headsets that could allow them to be powered and broadcast data over a single cable. But although the USB-C port appeared on Nvidia’s 20-series graphics cards, the standard was beset by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18525827/valve-index-virtual-reality-usb-c-virtuallink-dongle"&gt;silly dongles and adaptors&lt;/a&gt; (sound familiar?) and had been dropped by the time the 30-series rolled around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAkeRP"&gt;It’s easy to see Apple ditching ports as a cynical cash grab in an attempt to drive sales of its own dongles and USB-C accessories. But a more generous reading is that Apple got its bet on the future wrong. It thought it could outsource a laptop’s ports to desk-based accessories like monitors and docks to make its laptops slimmer and more compact. But that ecosystem never seems to have taken off or become ubiquitous, and what happened instead was that people were forced to carry around endless adapters for simple tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wouG49"&gt;I have a couple of theories why Apple’s vision never became a reality. One is Macs just don’t have the market share to force a change like this across the whole industry, so manufacturers of monitors and peripherals were forced to stick with older standards from Windows machines for their most mainstream devices. Another is the confusing mess of standards supported by USB-C cables and accessories. Between Thunderbolt and USB’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/2/27/18243425/usb-3-2-standard-names-connectivity-cables-innovators-forum"&gt;smorgasbord of different versions&lt;/a&gt;, it can be difficult to know if a cable is even capable of making the most out of your device’s charging and data transferring capabilities, or — particularly early on — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/4/10916264/usb-c-russian-roulette-power-cords"&gt;whether it’s going to fry its internals&lt;/a&gt;. It’s far from the easy plug-and-play future Apple seems to have had its sights on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EVCHz"&gt;Or, maybe people are more attached to their older PC accessories than Apple anticipated, particularly when it comes to expensive professional equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="x0ViRR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s bet on wireless audio on the iPhone paid off in ways its USB-C laptop bet didn’t&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tUHPZy"&gt;It’s interesting, in retrospect, to compare Apple’s decision to switch wholesale to USB-C on the MacBook with its decision to remove the headphone jack from the iPhone 7. This was another decision that generated an equal amount of jokes about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/8/12852098/belkin-apple-iphone-7-plus-adapter-dongle-charge-music"&gt;adaptors and dongles&lt;/a&gt; at the time and raised similar suspicions that the move was a cash grab to help the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/8/12839758/apple-is-biggest-winner-from-killing-headphone-jack"&gt;sell more Bluetooth headphones&lt;/a&gt;. But, five years later, Apple’s decision appears to have been vindicated, with its competitors following suit. There’s now a thriving ecosystem of third-party wireless headphones, and I couldn’t tell you the last time I saw someone using one of Apple’s Lightning to 3.5mm adaptors (though, with wired headphones &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/fashion/wired-headphones-cool-airpods-b1936746.html"&gt;reportedly making a retro-styled comeback&lt;/a&gt;, that could change soon). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aar6yt"&gt;Whether that’s because Apple is more dominant when it comes to smartphones or just because the benefits of wireless audio were more obvious to people than USB-C accessories, people seem to have been far more ready to roll with Apple’s annoying headphone jack decision. There’s a valid debate to be had about whether Apple kicked off a trend towards wireless audio or whether its move just turbocharged one that was already taking place, but either way, Apple made a bet that the future of smartphone audio was wireless, and for all intents and purposes, it seems to have paid off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j5LB8D"&gt;Although Apple stopped short of calling out its past MacBook designs, this week’s announcement was Apple’s biggest mea culpa &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/4/15175994/apple-mac-pro-failure-admission"&gt;since the Mac Pro&lt;/a&gt; trash can. The event completed the company’s backtrack on basically every controversial decision it’s made with recent MacBooks, after already having made the decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246223/macbook-keyboard-butterfly-magic-pro-apple-design"&gt;ditch its controversial butterfly keyboard&lt;/a&gt; in favor of more traditional scissor switches. Apple made the wrong call in 2016, but this week, it thankfully got itself back on track. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NIurBg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally listed the 2015 MacBook with the wrong screen size. It was 12 inches, not 13 inches. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="kaiq3j"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LvT7AY"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="0mo6qm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-192" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZLtSRV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22734645/apple-macbook-pro-2021-ports-magsafe-touch-bar-usb-c-future"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22734645/apple-macbook-pro-2021-ports-magsafe-touch-bar-usb-c-future</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T16:21:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T16:21:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Which AirPods model should you buy?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HTnTmHh7T5K_RBCFmA7qmJUhEWo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70017465/cwelch_191031_3763_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods Pro still sells for $249.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zz3GG9"&gt;In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;new MacBooks&lt;/a&gt; on October 18th, Apple finally also introduced its&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22435385"&gt; third-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, which are set to ship on October 26th for $179 and are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22429684"&gt;available for preorder now&lt;/a&gt;. Apple also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733184/apple-second-generation-airpods-wired-charging-case-price-cut-129"&gt;lowered the cost&lt;/a&gt; of the now-entry-level AirPods 2 from $159 to $129 and will now only sell the version that comes with a wired charging case. As a result, the AirPods lineup now consists of four models of AirPods: the $129 AirPods 2, the $179 AirPods 3, the $249 AirPods Pro, and the $549 AirPods Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MVI0Qf"&gt;With such a wide range of AirPods available at various price points, it can be overwhelming to try to figure out which one you should purchase. That’s why we’ve put together this guide comparing the models to each other — so you can find the right fit for you. Note that while we have reviewed most of the AirPods in the lineup, we’ve not yet tested the AirPods 3, but we will soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mTJiJM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple AirPods second-gen review: even more wireless","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Apple AirPods Pro review: perfect fit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"},{"title":"Apple AirPods Max review: luxurious sound for a luxury price","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="IaSfdt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10815614"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aNdTt1"&gt;The AirPods 3, like the AirPods 2 and AirPods Pro, are in-ear wireless earbuds. The AirPods 3 weigh about the same as the AirPods 2 – 4.28 grams and 4 grams, respectively. At 5.4 grams, the AirPods Pro are only slightly heavier. The wireless earbuds all measure about the same as well, with the AirPods 2 offering the greatest length (40.5mm x 16.5mm x 18.0mm). While the AirPods 3 (30.8mm x 18.3mm x 19.2mm) measure about the same in length, they’re wider than the AirPods 2. The AirPods Pro (30.9mm x 21.8mm x 24mm) are wider than both the AirPods 2 and 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4KuKtX"&gt;The AirPods 3, like the AirPods Pro, are sweat and water-resistant, unlike the AirPods 2 (and the Max). That means you don’t need to worry about them during an intense workout or when it rains. The AirPods 3 and AirPods Pro also offer shorter stems than the AirPods 2, while the AirPods Pro come with replaceable silicone ear tips in three different sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lW6egp5N9OIM9pMgY8cw5eZ_Qxg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938958/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_8.26.33_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods Pro versus the AirPods Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hq12um"&gt;In contrast to the small plastic AirPods earbuds, the AirPods Max are a large over-ear pair of headphones that offers stainless steel earcups with a curvy mesh headband. They weigh in at 384.8 grams and measure 187.3mm x 168.6mm x 83.4mm. While the earbuds only come in white, you can buy the Max in a variety of different colors, including silver, space grey, sky blue, pink, and green. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHjw-MSSOE9krvMa6cC9qYmHU9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993019/akrales_190327_3315_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An AirPods case recharging on a wireless pad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TogjVJ"&gt;Each device comes with a Lightning-to-USB-C cable and a charging case. However, the kind of charging case differs. The AirPods 2 include a wired charging case (53.5mm x 44.3mm x 21.3mm) that can only be charged with a Lightning cable. Meanwhile, the cases for the AirPods 3 (46.4mm x 54.4mm x 21.4mm) and the Airpods Pro (45.2mm x 60.6mm x 21.7mm) can be charged wirelessly or with the cable. The AirPods 3 and AirPods Pro also now support MagSafe technology, the same magnetic attachment and charging system you can use with the iPhone. Meanwhile, the AirPods Max have their own Smart Case, which is designed to preserve battery charge by putting the headphones into a very low power state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EM0hCC"&gt;All of the AirPods are compatible with the latest iPhones, iPads, Apple Watches, and Macs. However, the AirPods 2 are also compatible with older devices, like the iPhone 5s, iPad mini 3, iPad mini 2, and the 6th-generation iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Biodu-zsfWv5aKYI9wPm1cEb13s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938890/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_8.29.57_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods 3 will be available on October 26th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1HiQiX"&gt;All of the AirPods in the current lineup are powered by Apple’s H1 headphone chip now that the AirPods 2 — and not the first-generation, which offered a W1 chip — are the entry-level model. As a result, all support Bluetooth 5.0, and you can launch Siri via a voice command on all of the devices. You’ll also be able to automatically switch between your various Apple devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pG2LyU"&gt;The over-ears AirPods Max come with a Digital Control knob borrowed from the Apple Watch and another button you can use to alternate between the Active Noise Cancellation and Transparency modes. However, there is no power button. In contrast, the earbuds rely solely on touch controls — and even in this, they can differ. To play a tune, skip forward, or answer a phone call on the AirPods 2, you need to double-tap. However, with the AirPods 3, AirPods Pro, and the Digital Crown on the AirPods Max, you just need to click once to pause, play, or answer a call. Meanwhile, you can press twice to skip forward and three times to skip back. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vub7LogNg805GYpulKIm1syQA_Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938895/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_8.31.44_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods 3 offers spatial audio with dynamic head tracking and Dolby Atmos in Apple Music.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ou6uo5"&gt;Audio features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AKhVkZ"&gt;As we’ve noted in our reviews — with the exception of the AirPods 3, which we’ve yet to test — all of the AirPods in the lineup offer great sound quality. Each new earbud model offers iterative improvements that enhance the audio experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XJP2Ec"&gt;Of course, the AirPods 3, AirPods Pro, and AirPods Max offer a lot more in comparison to the older AirPods 2 when it comes to audio technology. All three of the newer models boast support for spatial audio, which should result in an immersive, theater-like sound quality experience. While the AirPods 2 featured limited spatial audio through Apple Music only, the other three include spatial audio for group FaceTime calls, Netflix, and other content as well. The AirPods 3 also offer spatial audio with dynamic head tracking across all Apple devices, as well as Dolby Atmos in Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KgwRuU"&gt;The AirPods 3, AirPods Pro, and AirPods Max all boast features like Adaptive EQ, which customizes your audio experience, and an intuitive force sensor for media control. Apple says the custom high-excursion Apple drivers found in all three also deliver powerful bass. Meanwhile, the AirPods Max are built with H1 chips in each ear cup, so you get ample bass. The three models also include a custom high dynamic range amplifier that offers clear sound and lengthens battery life (the AirPods Max lacks this latter feature). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8fSD5"&gt;The AirPods Pro and AirPods Max offer Active Noise Cancellation, which silences background noises so you can better focus on what you’re listening to. These models are also the only ones that offer the option to switch to Transparency Mode, which makes it possible to hear the sounds around you. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7YuNGcz8IBVQajdFqVk6GHwUE70=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22173866/DSCF2681_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods Max offers 44mm drivers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6GEHBn"&gt;As far as call quality is concerned, the AirPods 2, AirPods 3, and AirPods Pro all offer dual beamforming microphones — in other words, every set has two mics in each ear cup, with technology designed to reduce outside noises and better focus on your voice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dKs86B"&gt;However, unlike the AirPods 3 and AirPods Pro, the AirPods 2 doesn’t offer inward-facing microphones. That means it’s not able to listen inside of your ear to reduce internal sounds. The AirPods Max, meanwhile, offer nine microphones: eight for active noise cancellation and three for voice pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mVJwTVLkFjyToscJgHNl1jB0Aoc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19336093/akrales_191030_3763_0378.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Active noise cancelation option on an iPhone paired with the AirPods Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QEKtUN"&gt;The AirPods 2, AirPods 3, and AirPods Pro all offer motion-detecting accelerometers that detect taps and speech-detecting accelerometers. The latter recognizes when you’re speaking, working with the beamforming microphones to silence outside sounds and pick up only your voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LjWSfZ"&gt;Both the AirPods 2 and AirPods Pro offer dual optical sensors that help detect when they’re in your ears, although the AirPods 3 doesn’t. Instead, it offers a skin detect sensor, which uses your skin to determine whether your AirPods are in your ears or not and, thus, whether it should play or pause audio. On the other hand, both the AirPods 3 and the Airpods Pro offer an intuitive force sensor for media control — something the AirPods 2 lacks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qQ5nyc"&gt;The AirPods Max include an optical sensor and accelerometer in each ear cup. The headphones additionally come with a position and a case-detect sensor for each ear to&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;automatically detect when they are on a user’s head. The left ear cup also has a gyroscope; all of these sensors combined make it possible to combine dynamic head tracking with spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple AirPods Max from above" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cMZYNzByXtWocPciu5DPaLatDJo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22159223/npatel_201209_4332_0019sq.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Nilay Patel / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods Max offers an H1 chip and sensors in each ear cup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sFRSTg"&gt;As might be expected, the AirPods Max overwhelmingly outperform the rest of the AirPods when it comes to battery life. Apple says they offer up to 20 hours of listening time on a single charge with Active Noise Cancellation or Transparency mode on. With spatial audio enabled, the AirPods Max also offers up to 20 hours of movie playback on a single charge. Meanwhile, Apple says five minutes of charging provides around 1.5 hours of listening time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xhi7XR"&gt;In contrast, Apple claims the AirPods 2 offer up to five hours of listening time on a single charge, while the AirPods 3 offer six hours. The tech giant also says the entry-level AirPods offer over 24 hours of listening time with the charging case, just like the AirPods Pro. Despite being cheaper than the AirPods Pro, the AirPods 3 beat them and the AirPods 2, offering up to 30 hours. The AirPods Pro also offer the least amount of listening on one charge — only 4.5 hours and up to five hours with Active Noise Cancellation and Transparency turned off. The Pro additionally offer up to 3.5 hours of talk time with a single charge, while the AirPods 3 offer up to three hours of talk time. In contrast, the AirPods 2 beats both, offering up to five hours of listening time with one charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wzO40w"&gt;When it comes to charging case battery life, the AirPods 3 also differ from the AirPods 2 and AirPods Pro, offering up to 30 hours of listening time as opposed to the Pro and AirPods 2 providing over 24 hours of listening time. The AirPods 3 also offer up to 20 hours of talk time versus over 18 hours of talk time for the Pro and up to 18 hours of talk time for the AirPods 2. Apple claims both the AirPods 3 and AirPods Pro, however, take five minutes to provide about an hour of listening time or an hour of talk time. In contrast, the AirPods 2 need to be in the case for 15 minutes to provide up to three hours of listening time or up to two hours of talk time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="OjwqrU"&gt;Which should you buy?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="s4fzuv"&gt;No matter which you buy, each model in the AirPods lineup should offer great sound and call quality. However, which model you should purchase depends upon your needs and budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4uDRQK"&gt;Off the bat, if you want over-ear headphones, obviously the AirPods Max are the ones you should buy. They are also the top choice for sound quality and offer features the others don’t, ranging from active noise cancellation to an H1 chip and sensors in each ear cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjmy7B"&gt;On the other hand, if you’re looking for a great pair of earpods, pick up the AirPods 3 or AirPods Pro, especially if you often engage in intense workouts, both of which offer sweat and water resistance. And if you’ve had trouble in the past with earpods slipping out of your ears, you may want to choose the AirPods Pro for their replaceable and customizable ear tips, which is something the AirPods 3 don’t offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ly2Hgf"&gt;If you’re on a tight budget, however, and want something under $200, consider the AirPods 3. Unless you’re truly strapped for cash, it’s worth forking out an extra $50 for the extra perks the AirPods 2 don’t offer, like a MagSafe charging case, greater spatial audio support, improved battery life, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aeqc8g"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="JJh9LH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10744075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kukwnm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2y5nQl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="GwI6m4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"The 8 biggest announcements from Apple’s Unleashed event","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"},{"title":"Apple quietly added a MagSafe charging case to its AirPods Pro, too","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="93jlI6"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ck7XNP"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="NiNVs0"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-564" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u9QK3y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 19th [3:25 pm PT] Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A previous version of this article incorrectly stated the AirPods 2’s case offers “more than 30 hours” of battery life and includes a “lightning to USB-C” charging cord. The AirPods 2’s case actually offers “more than 24 hours” of battery life, and includes a “lightning to USB-A” charging cord. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lxInyC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T12:22:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:22:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>The new MacBook Pros have one big question mark: battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gqh_ToGRXYPcvFG0NBU8EADjT9o=/240x0:2640x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015925/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_8.43.20_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JmfhOe"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;new MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;are here&lt;/a&gt;, and they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"&gt;may actually live up to the “Pro” moniker&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s one big question that comes with the new sizes and processors: how’s the battery life? To hear Apple tell it, it’s going to be great — the company even &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/exM1uajp--A?t=2638"&gt;said onstage&lt;/a&gt; that the 16-inch had the best battery life ever, besting last year’s M1 Macs (which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558095/apple-silicon-m1-chip-arm-macs-soc-charge-power-efficiency-mobile-processor"&gt;also boasted would have the longest-lived batteries&lt;/a&gt;). But the metric Apple used to back up that claim is a bit suspect, and its other numbers tell a very different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEPp25"&gt;In its keynote and &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-unveils-game-changing-macbook-pro/"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, Apple says the 14-inch MacBook Pro will provide 17 hours of video playback and estimates that the 16-inch model can last for an unprecedented-for-Macs 21 hours. But using video playback as a measure of battery life is really only useful if you’re trying to sell a particular narrative — not if you just want to let people know how long their laptops will actually last. For one, Apple says these figures are derived from watching a movie using the Apple TV app. That’s not generally what people use their laptops for unless they’re marathoning the &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; extended cuts. Plus, modern CPUs have so much silicon dedicated to video playback that it’s almost become effortless for them. It’s a battery flex, not a battery test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V4vz8j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In a more realistic test, the 14-inch MacBook Pro doesn’t beat the Air — those numbers didn’t make it onstage&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zvAbe0"&gt;That point is backed up by the fact that Apple’s more realistic wireless web test tells a very different story. Apple says the test involves browsing 25 popular websites using Wi-Fi, with screen brightness set to “8 clicks from bottom.” Under these conditions, the 16-inch MacBook Pro fails to beat even the M1 MacBook Air — it only gets 14 hours of life compared to the Air’s 15 hours. Apple’s estimate for the new 14-inch is 11 hours, the same as the 2020 &lt;em&gt;Intel&lt;/em&gt; MacBook Air. Even this unflattering test (for the new MacBooks, not the old ones) has limitations: last we heard, Apple runs it using its own Safari browser instead of the more popular (and, according to macOS’s Activity Monitor, more energy-hungry) Chrome. Plus, some websites will drain your battery much faster than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKkaaD"&gt;In terms of hard numbers, the 14-inch MacBook Pro has a 70 watt-hour battery, and the 16-inch takes it all the way up to &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/hazmat/packsafe/more_info/?hazmat=7"&gt;the FAA limit&lt;/a&gt; of 100Wh (the 13-inch M1 MacBook Pro has a 58.2 Wh battery, for comparison). Again, though, these metrics only tell us so much. The 16-inch Intel-based MacBook also had a 100Wh battery, and it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features"&gt;only provided around eight hours of usage&lt;/a&gt;, despite Apple’s quoted 11-hour battery life. Plus, Apple is quoting three hours &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; battery life for the 14-inch than the 13-inch, despite the new laptop having a bigger battery. Yes, that number’s not based on a great metric, but that’s also not necessarily a good sign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M0fVMvkIsOc2hZlL52jl2DPTszI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937340/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_4.33.22_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple quotes less runtime for the 14-inch MBP than the 13-inch one, despite the roughly 20 percent bigger battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NXKL80"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558095/apple-silicon-m1-chip-arm-macs-soc-charge-power-efficiency-mobile-processor"&gt;pulled this same trick last year&lt;/a&gt;, but it almost didn’t matter — the ARM processors lasted so much longer than Intel’s that we were willing to let it slide that the MacBook Air probably wouldn’t actually reach Apple’s estimated 18 hours of battery life. This year, Apple is setting even higher expectations for battery life, even though the new laptops are supposed to be significantly more powerful. It just seems unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bZJKwE"&gt;The MacBook Pro 14- and 16-inch have to feed more power-hungry (in relative terms, at least) performance cores, and they have fewer efficient cores to make use of when you’re doing light work like checking email or browsing a website or two. The standard M1 has four performance and four efficiency cores, where the M1 Pro and Max only have two efficiency cores, having traded in the rest for more performance ones: the cut-down eight-core M1 Pro that comes with the base 14-inch laptop has six performance cores, while the 10-core full M1 Pro and M1 Max have eight performance cores. They also have more powerful GPUs — the old M1 has 7 or 8 GPU cores; the new versions are rocking 14 to 32. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sZcZYF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Different numbers of CPU and GPU cores could also affect battery life&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hoc6ao"&gt;On top of that, the 14- and 16-inch laptops have what Apple calls an “advanced thermal architecture,” which includes an extra fan. Will that make a big impact? Will Apple be able to beat the original M1’s extra efficiency cores using sheer battery size? We simply won’t know until we can test these laptops in the real world — stay tuned for that in our upcoming reviews. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbmERv"&gt;Great battery life has been the biggest story of Apple’s M1 laptops up until this point, with many people describing the Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro’s battery life as “all day.” It’s understandable why Apple would want to keep riding that goodwill and say that it’s done that again — and while it may have, the company hasn’t proven it yet, not with what it’s presented. So, if you want to be sure you’re getting the MacBook with the best battery life, you may want to hold off for a bit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724608/apple-m1-pro-m1-max-macbook-pro-how-to-buy-price-availability-release-date"&gt;on pre-ordering the new ones&lt;/a&gt; — at least for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22733390/macbook-pro-14-16-inch-battery-life-question-usage-processors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22733390/macbook-pro-14-16-inch-battery-life-question-usage-processors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:57:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:57:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple botched the MacBook Pro notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x9TlV48LFAI48qHXlzAIzozo3O0=/25x0:1936x1274/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015766/Apple_MacBook_Pro_16_inch_Final_Cut_Pro_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xxYGjp"&gt;The day that many have been dreading has finally arrived. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732912/apple-macbook-pro-notch-display"&gt;Apple has added a notch to its new MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;. And somehow, Apple — notch pros at this point — managed to utterly botch the notch. Because the new MacBook Pros completely missed out on the most important part of the notch: &lt;em&gt;adding Face ID&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePfAmo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"&gt;I’ve been on the record&lt;/a&gt; of being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/11/6/18057258/macbook-air-update-face-id-notch-bezel-security"&gt;extremely pro-MacBook notch&lt;/a&gt;: back in 2018, I argued that Apple &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do exactly what it’s done here: add a notch to its MacBook laptops, taking up the exact width of the persistent menu bar that already permanently lives on the top of its macOS software (barring the occasional dip into a full-screen app). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VsI5JT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The MacBook Air needs Face ID and a delightful notch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/11/6/18057258/macbook-air-update-face-id-notch-bezel-security"},{"title":"The iPhone’s notch: should it stay or should it go?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tQHLHR"&gt;And to be fair, Apple has actualized most of the benefits of a notch: smaller bezels, particularly at the top of the display, allowing for Apple to at least play in the same ballpark (if still not quite on the same level) as the ultra-thin bezels that have become the norm on premium Windows laptops from companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yZ10E"&gt;Which is why the lack of Face ID here is such a glaring miss. As a means of visual identity across its product lineup, the notch is practically synonymous with Face ID on Apple’s devices. Seeing one here (and then not offering the tech) is incongruous right off the bat. It starts things off on the wrong foot; sure, most people don’t &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the idea of a notch, but usually, there’s the acceptance that you’re getting the addition of Face ID. Here the cost of the notch returns far fewer rewards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9Xq8j"&gt;It’s possible that there are still technical issues here: maybe the Face ID module is just too big to fit into a laptop display, although Apple managed to fit it into both its iPhone and iPad hardware just fine. The existence of any number of IR-powered Windows Hello facial unlock systems would also indicate that the challenges (if they even exist) can be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a68sYc"&gt; Plus, look at the thickness of Apple’s new MacBook Pro lid:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h6ouCH7C7m5U_ybPSfd_JQVpctE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938870/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MBoLCy"&gt;You’re telling me that can’t fit a Face ID module? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phou79"&gt;The hardware is all there: the M1 Pro and M1 Max share the same architecture as the A-series chips that Apple has offered for years, and Apple already offers Face ID on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;its M1-powered iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. And Apple’s notch already conceals a few extra components: as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pogue/status/1450489697382408192"&gt;David Pogue notes on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the cutout also hides Apple’s TrueTone sensor, light sensor, and an LED status light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8Quzzv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As you evaluate your opinion on the MacBook Pro’s notch, keep in mind that it houses more than just a 1080p camera. It also houses the TrueTone sensor (colors consistent in all lighting conditions), light sensor (adjusts brightness/keyboard illumination), and “camera on” LED. &lt;a href="https://t.co/XpKvhvtEWn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XpKvhvtEWn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— David Pogue (@Pogue) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pogue/status/1450489697382408192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KhtKML"&gt;It’s easy to imagine Apple integrating a lot of the useful things that Face ID does on its phones directly into its laptops. The highly marketed ability to instantly boot the new MacBook Pros with the ultra-fast M1 Pro and M1 Max chips could go even faster by unlocking your computer before you’ve even touched the keyboard. Face ID’s password unlocks would be incredibly convenient on websites since you’re already staring at your computer the whole time. And Apple would get to play up its Animoji and Memoji avatars with the sorts of wacky demos the company thinks are hilarious at its events. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VQbge7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple even says that Face ID is more secure&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YwhXQZ"&gt;The lack of Face ID means that Apple is &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; playing catch up to Windows. The past few years have seen Windows Hello facial recognition unlocking become more and more of a standard feature across laptops. Apple, meanwhile, despite arguably doing the most to popularize facial recognition unlocking (and Face ID) for personal tech, is still weirdly sitting on the sideline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="La6en2"&gt;Plus, there’s the security aspect. Apple &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; to brag about how secure its computers are. And yet, the company insists on locking down its computers exclusively with Touch ID — security tech that is, by Apple’s own estimations, orders of magnitudes less secure. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204587"&gt;According to Apple’s documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the odds of guessing a four-digit passcode are 1 in 10,000. The odds of someone else having a matching fingerprint to unlock Touch ID on your computer are 1 in 50,000. But Apple &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208108"&gt;also says&lt;/a&gt; that the probability of a random person managing to unlock your device using Face ID is a whooping 1 in 1,000,000. Apple has better biometric security available that it could put on its laptops; it’s just choosing not to, year after year and redesign after redesign. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PjFa_Ynp8kmOnhpfBkcU_mo9AdU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938880/Untitled.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The notch has arrived, whether you like it or not&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iD84Cf"&gt;Apple — and customers — do both still like Touch ID, at least conceptually. The argument for fingerprint-based biometrics has become a stronger one when wearing a mask for health purposes defeats a lot of the convenience of Face ID. And there have been rumors for years that Apple has been planning to bring back Touch ID to its iPhones in the form of an in-display sensor. But if Apple really is worried about losing some of the convenience of Touch ID, it could simply offer both security options, taking the bold step of actually letting its customers decide which biometric method they’d like to use. Or Apple could really take a stance on security and let users use &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; Touch ID and Face ID for even more secure biometric authentication, giving the company more security stats to tout and customers an extra layer of security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUZrdV"&gt;A notch for Face ID would have been acceptable — even great. Or maybe Apple really, truly believed that Touch ID was the right solution for its computers and that all the new MacBook Pros needed was a higher resolution webcam and smaller bezels. But in that case, Apple could have tried to engineer a hole-punch camera, like those found on virtually every major Android flagship, for a more seamless look and feel that would still allow it to cut down the bezels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hbb7vL"&gt;But instead, the new MacBook Pros are stuck in a terrible no man’s land: all the size of a notch, without any of the utility. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734676/apple-macbook-pro-notch-botch-face-id-missing-feature-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734676/apple-macbook-pro-notch-botch-face-id-missing-feature-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>What is the new Apple Music Voice plan, and who is it for? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oPgqtP1eofYR_1L0cCWkwBn9-1o=/0x87:1306x958/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015526/Apple_HomePod_mini_Apple_Music_Voice_AirPods_3rd_gen_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Music Voice relies entirely on your dulcet tones to play music from any Siri-enabled device&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BKzS5L"&gt;The new Apple Music Voice plan that Apple announced at its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"&gt;“Unleashed” event&lt;/a&gt; on Monday is causing some confusion. I’m here to help you understand this new, cheaper option, which capitalizes on the power of Apple’s smart voice assistant, Siri (don’t laugh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dfonFq"&gt;Put simply, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri"&gt;Apple Music Voice plan&lt;/a&gt; is a voice control-only access to the service’s catalog of 90 million songs. It arrives later this year, and with it, you can play everything — full albums, individual songs, Apple’s playlists; it’s all-you-can-eat Apple Music. The caveat is you have to use your voice to control it, and you have to play it through a Siri-enabled device, such as a HomePod Mini (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"&gt;now in some spiffy new colors&lt;/a&gt;), AirPods, or an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtGi64"&gt;What it is not is a fee to use Siri to play your own music. If you have tracks purchased through or stored on iTunes, you can still play those with the Apple Music app and control them with voice, as before. What paying for this service does is add access to the company’s streaming catalog for a lower price than its Individual or Family plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="anApKx"&gt;Apple Music Voice seems best suited to casual listeners who don’t spend hours carefully curating playlists and just want to listen to some music on the fly. While you can request specific songs and albums, you can also just say, “Hey, Siri plays some ’90s Britpop” or “Hey Siri, play something chill.” There’s also access to Apple Radio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i3X4-3Zt9-7jRKtrziV3ZJqGzuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938603/Apple_HomePod_mini_hero_5up_10182021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HomePod Mini is a Siri-enabled smart speaker you can use to play songs on the Apple Music Voice plan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CNpJMp"&gt;The most significant difference between the two plans — beyond price: one is $4.99, and one is $9.99 — is access to the Apple Music app. With the Voice plan, you can’t open the Apple Music app, search for an artist or song, and select a track. Instead, you have to ask Siri to play the song you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lboR5"&gt;You can use the Apple Music app to see a queue of recently played music and suggestions for using Siri to control your music. There are also “suggestions based on the listener’s music preferences” that include limited content available for playback through the app, &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-introduces-the-apple-music-voice-plan/"&gt;according to Apple&lt;/a&gt;. Apple hasn’t shared how exactly this will look or work yet, so we’ll have to wait for the service to roll out to test it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IFaIVk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The cheaper plan doesn’t let you create playlists&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l42mQc"&gt;The cheaper plan also doesn’t let you create your own playlists, manage your playback queue, download songs to your library, scroll the lyrics on your iPhone or iPad, or stream from any third-party speakers (such as Google Nest Hub, which does support the full Apple Music plan). It also won’t play some of the higher-quality audio formats available in Apple Music, such as lossless and spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wT27Qb"&gt;You can use Apple AirPlay to play music through any and all AirPlay 2-enabled speakers you might have — which makes this plan a notch better than Amazon’s similar voice-only music streaming service. That plan — the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GKLDPRYNF2VUAKMM"&gt;Amazon Music Unlimited Single Device Plan&lt;/a&gt; — costs $3.99 to access Amazon Music’s catalog, but you can only play it on one Echo or Fire TV device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJCX2r"&gt;What’s unique about both these voice streaming plans is that you can just buy a smart speaker — an Amazon Echo or a HomePod Mini — plug it in, and ask it to play music. (You can literally say, “Hey Siri, start my Apple Music Voice trial” and be up and running.) This takes away a lot of friction from getting going with streaming music, providing an easy set-up for someone who’s not very techie. It will probably make a great gift for your parents this Christmas if you’re tired of listening to The Eagles on their FM radio every time you visit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFg4eY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>2021 MacBook Pros compared: how Apple’s laptops stack up</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="macbook pro 2012" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6fylJ4YurnOJCx0mBtJCSSD6stI=/94x0:547x302/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70014785/macbook-pro-2012.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kOeI7V"&gt;Apple just announced new versions of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;14-inch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; explicitly designed around their new Arm-based &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;M1 Pro and M1 Max CPUs&lt;/a&gt;. Both models are configurable with either CPU and can be equipped with up to 8TB of storage. Models that use the M1 Pro can have up to 32GB of unified memory, while models that have the M1 Max can be configured to have up to 64GB. They also feature more powerful speakers and a greater selection of ports, making them more versatile than the MacBooks that only offered USB-C ports with Thunderbolt 4. (You no longer need a dongle for HDMI or SD cards.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GkmecT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 8 biggest announcements from Apple’s Unleashed event ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5Ddl9e"&gt;The last generation of MacBook Pro still has plenty of power, and for a while was the best option in terms of connectivity for Apple laptops. However, the advent of the M1 CPU in last year’s 13-inch MacBook Pro has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;changed what we expect from our MacBooks&lt;/a&gt;, a new bar that currently can’t be met by the older Intel and AMD-based MacBooks in most ways. If you’re a long-time Apple user, it’s hard to go wrong by upgrading to anything that uses the Apple Silicon architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmSAUp"&gt;While all of the MacBooks currently available on the Apple store use some form of the M1 CPU, they’re all just a little bit different, so to help you weigh your options, we’ve put together charts comparing every current MacBook you can buy on the Apple Store, as well as another chart comparing current models to their predecessors if you’re someone that’s been waiting to upgrade. We even threw in the last MacBook Pro that included an HDMI port to show just how far we’ve come since 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ADr6g8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10814420"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YTFcSm"&gt;The new Pros have made some excellent strides in terms of their displays, with 120Hz refresh rates in all the available models, as well as improving the resolution and significantly raising the max brightness. The webcam has also received an upgrade to 1080p. While it’s no surprise that the new versions of the MacBook Pro trump their predecessors in just about every category in terms of performance, the race gets a little more competitive when stacking up the models that you can currently get on the Apple Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7YvwrL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10814467"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KPFrjb"&gt;The M1 Air is the most sensible option for users that want a budget-friendly laptop. Unless you need a brighter display, better audio, or battery life, there's little reason to go with the 13-inch version of the MacBook Pro. However, this new breed of MacBook Pro definitely makes a more convincing argument for spending the extra cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7Rmezh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Want a fully specced-out MacBook Pro? You’ll have to pay more than $6,000 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733173/macbook-pro-specced-out-high-end-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="2YSsqB"&gt;At the lower end of the spectrum, the starting configuration for the 14-inch MacBook Pro costs twice as much as the MacBook Air, but has a larger screen with better resolution and far more ports. You also get twice the amount of memory and storage right out of the gate. The main drawback of opting for the 14-inch Pro is that it's slightly heavier and won’t last quite as long between charges when compared to its smaller siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="x2CEmy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="72notT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814228"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cBrcIE"&gt;For an additional $500, the starting price of the 16-inch MacBook Pro will net you many of the same benefits, with the same amount of memory and storage to start, just with a slightly better processor. While the battery of the 16-inch Pro has more staying power, this model is easily the heaviest out of the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aEFgd5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Bwec7n"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IXkbvP"&gt;There are plenty of reasons to spring for a new MacBook Pro, especially if you’ve been biding your time with an older model. The M1 CPU is certainly worth the investment, but unless you can’t live without a dedicated HDMI port, or need a particularly powerful laptop, the MacBook Air is probably the way to go. However, if you’re a power-user or creator that needs bleeding-edge performance, the new 16-inch MacBook Pro seems like the clear winner — we’ll find out for sure in our upcoming reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SPsOcf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple finally listened to the pros","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xIQCKp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZTeou"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V5e6vB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733406/macbook-pro-13-14-16-inch-m1-max-air-compare-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T08:27:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T08:27:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new 140W charger can fast charge a lot more than just your MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2mgx7QZTzDUej-vXITdzXMtgqEE=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70014599/MLYU3_AV1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new 140W charger.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eXiYsp"&gt;Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYU3AM/A/140w-usb-c-power-adapter?fnode=734a3f2e2d2e806ace8f7808dbb8ba4fd9782dff052da988f418e42ddc3d1a858ec62035f6c5248f220833045d3ac0aab4b093470d39f30395579a4d66521e498d4f45ce651cc927ed283f18e9ec2f2910ffce4b0b4892e5732214994c235270"&gt;140W charging brick&lt;/a&gt;, which works with a new MagSafe charging cable to power the new 16-inch MacBook Pro, uses the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702453/usb-c-pd-240-watt-charging-usb4-data-transfer-logo-branding-standard"&gt;USB-C Power Delivery 3.1 standard&lt;/a&gt;, Apple has confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. As well as being included with the new 16-inch MacBook Pro, the brick is available separately for $99 (not including the USB-C-to-MagSafe cable, which costs &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MLYV3AM/A/usb-c-to-magsafe-3-cable-2-m"&gt;an extra $49&lt;/a&gt;). Meanwhile, the new 14-inch MacBook Pros come with 67W and 96W chargers, depending on the exact model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLZfCM"&gt;Using the USB-C PD 3.1 standard means Apple’s new charging brick will be cross compatible with other devices that use the same power delivery standard, which was announced earlier this year alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/5/25/22453936/usb-c-power-delivery-extended-power-range-epr"&gt;USB Type-C Release 2.1 specification&lt;/a&gt;. It also means that MacBook owners have the flexibility of using compatible third-party charging bricks with the new MacBooks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8iaKOdN_yKeIIFl_jD6OuOE_oHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938315/MLYU3_AV2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 140W charger has a single USB-C port.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pFmzYu"&gt;That hasn’t been the case with some USB-C laptop fast chargers in the past, which have had to go off-spec to offer charging speeds over 100W (the previous cap on the USB-C Power Delivery spec). My colleague Sean Hollister, for example, has a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/5/25/22453936/usb-c-power-delivery-extended-power-range-epr#:~:text=Previously%2C%20the%20USB,Leaving%20100W%20behind"&gt;Dell dock that outputs 130W&lt;/a&gt;, but it won’t work with other laptops because there previously wasn’t an open standard to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rw0ChM"&gt;As well as its use of the USB-C PD 3.1 standard, Apple also confirmed that the brick is its first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/1/18051974/gallium-nitride-anker-material-silicon-semiconductor-energy"&gt;gallium nitride (GaN)&lt;/a&gt; charger, which means it’s using the material that allows companies to build higher-powered chargers that are smaller in size than their traditional counterparts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BChu3D"&gt;As well as the specs of the charging brick, Apple also confirmed that any of the new MacBooks’ Thunderbolt 4 ports can be used to charge the laptops. On the 14-inch MacBook Pro, these ports can be used for fast charging; but fast charging the 16-inch MacBook Pro requires using MagSafe 3 and the 140W adapter because the Thunderbolt 4 predates the USB-C PD 3.1 standard and tops out at 100W. Lower wattage chargers will be able to provide power to the MacBooks, but Apple says charging may be slower or could even result in power drain if the laptop is using more power than it’s being provided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGg6qx"&gt;Additionally, Apple says that the magnets used in the MagSafe 3 connector are stronger than the previous generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taqmIz"&gt;All in all, it’s great news for anyone planning on buying one of Apple’s new MacBooks; they’ll get a capable fast charger that can power other devices and also aren’t restricted to using Apple’s own brick to charge their laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734233/apple-140w-macbook-charging-brick-gan-usb-c-pd-3-1-third-party-chargers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734233/apple-140w-macbook-charging-brick-gan-usb-c-pd-3-1-third-party-chargers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
