<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-19T17:58:36-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T17:58:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T17:58:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple just provided the perfect example of why you can’t trust App Store review scores</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rFx2DPvClVc8nhdFNYoS9B53oYM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70168316/acastro_210817_4721_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="61EF7S"&gt;You pissed off people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630517/apple-podcasts-subscriptions-launch-dashboard"&gt;by somewhat breaking your app&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re leaving angry reviews. How can you salvage your reputation? Apple just found one incredibly effective way — get listeners to submit &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; reviews by interrupting their podcast experience with an in-app prompt to submit a rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4O5ANy"&gt;That’s how the Apple Podcasts app went from a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700805/apple-app-store-built-in-ratings-reviews-stars"&gt;publicly embarrassing&lt;/a&gt; 1.8-star score all the way to 4.6 stars in a little over a month without any actual fixes, as developer and App Store watchdog Kosta Eleftheriou &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1460856187595804676"&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;. And it’s still going up: according to &lt;a href="https://appfigures.com/"&gt;AppFigures data&lt;/a&gt;, the app has been getting thousands of ratings every day since November 9th, with the vast, overwhelming majority of them issuing a 5-star score. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iEKI5P"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;How did “Apple Podcasts” suddenly go from 1.8 to 4.6 stars? Is Apple manipulating their own app ratings now? &lt;a href="https://t.co/bSAr8sFKqQ"&gt;https://t.co/bSAr8sFKqQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/5kJKYd54VP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/5kJKYd54VP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1460856187595804676?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cLSaop"&gt;The app has made it to 4.7 stars overall as of this writing and is firmly the No. 1 App Store search result for “podcast.” It looks far more desirable to a new user than it might have before. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tJ4l36w1J8cs4Ok4ZBg5j-ulUc0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23028458/app_figures2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AppFigures estimates 6,292 five-star ratings were submitted on November 17th alone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DZqFVI"&gt;If you think there’s a perfectly reasonable explanation for this, you might be right — it could definitely be that people who bother to submit reviews tend to be angry, and a lot of people who love Apple Podcasts and never bothered to look it up in the App Store (remember, it’s preinstalled!) are finally balancing things out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ClRKH5"&gt;But do those people &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; love Apple Podcasts? Because if you really look at the reviews, it seems like some funny business is going on. There are new, positive reviews, but they aren’t reviews of the Apple Podcasts app at all — they’re reviews of podcasts themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="omaoOF"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;All the new positive reviews appear to be talking about specific podcasts, instead of the app: &lt;a href="https://t.co/HCo7WCcmH3"&gt;pic.twitter.com/HCo7WCcmH3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1460856197393772547?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E5AtQE"&gt;I kid you not — this is the top review for Apple Podcasts on the App Store: &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_gjlDWMerX2-r8gik_iK5ynV0kk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23028402/apple_podcasts_review.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple deems this the “Most Helpful” review of its Podcasts app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mp9WiE"&gt;Here are a few more of the “Most Recent” reviews of the Apple Podcasts app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2mG2cO"&gt;“Amazing show! Hilarious and well researched,” writes SammyAls, adding, “The dynamic is amazing, and the content is SO needed! Love this.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EjOpm8"&gt;“Mobley has Depth and Insight,” writes xbacksideslider. “Nice to listen to thoughtful and factual podcast. Far from the superficial emotional appeals to envy and self congratulating faux empathy that so dominate popular culture.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9gtRf9"&gt;“The table,” says Jkimble6091. “Being a future young millionaire listening to Anthony Oneal keeps me on track during all the ups and downs of life.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="IdJELO"&gt;I wondered if maybe this was a common confusion with podcast apps, where listeners think they’re reviewing a podcast instead of the app itself. But no, I didn’t see that obvious pattern when I checked reviews for other top podcast apps in the App Store. Almost every review on competing apps was a review of the apps themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="095B9Z"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“With iOS 15.1 released last month, Apple Podcasts began prompting listeners to leave a rating and review”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0pSFJU"&gt;Apple confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it’s using a new prompt but claims it’s nothing out of the ordinary. “With iOS 15.1 released last month, Apple Podcasts began prompting listeners to leave a rating and review just like most third-party apps — using the standard Rating &amp;amp; Review prompt available to all developers,” a spokesperson tells us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJppJu"&gt;We weren’t able to track down a copy of the prompt ourselves to confirm when and where it appears or what it looks like — which seems important if people are getting confused — but it is indeed &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/ratings-and-reviews/"&gt;a standard feature of the App Store&lt;/a&gt;, one you can even turn off if you like under Settings &amp;gt; App Store &amp;gt; In-App Ratings &amp;amp; Reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T6lQcf"&gt;But intentional or not, standard or not, the problem with star scores is there’s no way to tell whether they’re legitimate. We don’t know if someone pressed a five-star button because they loved the app, or thought they were rating the podcast itself, or just wanted to close the prompt as quickly as possible. We don’t know if Apple is prompting everyone, or just its most dedicated fans, or some other algorithmic subset that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528701/apple-rank-own-app-over-competitor-files-dropbox-wwdc-2017"&gt;just happened to give it an advantage&lt;/a&gt;. Some bad actors reportedly even buy star scores for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;their egregious App Store scams&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s impossible for most App Store shoppers to tell. We’ve even seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454468/ios-app-scam-review-3-star-force-review-process-apple"&gt;an iOS app that refuses to open unless you give it a good score&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3UShJ"&gt;These are the reasons why I suggested that Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;should lead the industry by killing off star ratings for good&lt;/a&gt;, among other things it could do to prove it puts people ahead of profits in the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bM5ZQS"&gt;But with Apple Podcasts, the company is using the same broken star score system that uplifts scammers for its own benefit as well. And it’s a crystal clear example of why you can’t trust star scores — because everyone knows this was a 1.8-star app just last month &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/04/29/users-despair-at-apple-podcasts-app-after-update/"&gt;with many valid lingering complaints&lt;/a&gt;, and nothing’s fundamentally changed. It’s the exact same app today as it was then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="V8C5UB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How small developers compete with the defaults on your phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22641201/small-developers-ios-app-competition-replace-apple-defaults"},{"title":"Eight things Apple could do to prove it actually cares about App Store users","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"},{"title":"Apple’s $64 billion-a-year App Store isn’t catching the most egregious scams","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Tblz1S"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSHwKV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791968/apple-podcasts-star-score-review-prompt"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791968/apple-podcasts-star-score-review-prompt</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T14:53:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T14:53:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new Self Service Repair program is an opportunity to repair relationships</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8sIeyKODQ_fL0XnBmh3GLXXXxc0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70167244/akrales_190422_3301_0177.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Tools included | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r5nDrl"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787144/apple-home-repair-iphone-mac-parts-tools-instructions"&gt;newly announced&lt;/a&gt; Self Service Repair program, set to launch in early 2022, will finally provide individual customers access to genuine Apple OEM parts and manuals for DIY iPhone (and eventually Mac) repairs. Although this program has limitations, and there are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FNews%2F55370%2Fapple-diy-repair-program-parts-tools-guides-software&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F19%2F22787245%2Fapple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;many lingering questions&lt;/a&gt; about how it will be implemented, it is an opportunity for Apple to improve relationships with its customers by making repairs easier. If Apple prices the parts right, the program could also be a way for motivated customers to save money on repairs by going DIY while allowing independent repair shops to remain competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="47lmru"&gt;Until now, access to factory OEM parts for iPhones and Macs has been restricted to several Apple-blessed places, including Apple Authorized Service Providers (AASP), Apple Stores, and Apple Independent Repair Providers (IRP), a program that allows independent shops to gain access to genuine Apple parts, tools, and training guides for common out-of-warranty Mac and iPhone repairs. Apple’s new self-service program — just like the IRP program — is focused only on screen, battery, and camera repairs when it comes to iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gVd3Jc"&gt;Apple plans to become the main resource for individuals looking for access to parts and manuals — &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/11/apple-announces-self-service-repair/"&gt;promising&lt;/a&gt; “more than 200 individual parts and tools” for iPhone 12 and 13 models early next year. While that number sounds high given that the self-service program will launch with parts for just two models of iPhones, Kevin Purdy, a writer for online repair guide site iFixit, found it believable. Apple, he says, could sell various adhesives, specialty tools, individual screws, custom presses, electrostatic discharge mats, and much more. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Illustration of girl at a workbench with various tools preparing to work on a replacement screen for an iPhone 12 or 13 pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1LxDtb991b4UeOa2L-dDyebr2h8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23026632/Apple_Self_Service_Repair_self_service_11172021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This illustration from an Apple press release depicts at least 10 parts and tools for a single repair coming out of one shipping box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xdhzC2"&gt;These parts are already available to Apple service providers, and the prices are pretty high because the devices are so new. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/iphone/repair/service/screen-replacement"&gt;Apple itself&lt;/a&gt; charges customers $279 to repair the screen of an iPhone 12 or iPhone 13 Pro. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FNews%2F55370%2Fapple-diy-repair-program-parts-tools-guides-software&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F19%2F22787245%2Fapple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to iFixit&lt;/a&gt;, members of Apple’s IRP program pay about $270 to stock up on these screens (nearly the same as what Apple charges for the repair). However, the out-of-pocket cost for IRP members is reduced to $235 if the old part is sent back, according to iFixit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="H28ygS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This removes a big barrier for Apple in the path to legislation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LU6wXd"&gt;While Apple says that individuals using the Self Service Repair program will receive a credit back for the old part, it’s not clear how much money you can save by taking this path, and Apple didn’t respond to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s request for comment on the matter. In my experience as a former employee of Apple, I recall that it was also Apple Store policy to not allow customers to take back old parts from the repairs we did for them (including bad hard drives from Macs). Based on how important bad part returns seem to Apple, whatever credit Apple will offer to customers using the self-service program could be significant enough to motivate old part returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qNAiXp"&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/apple/2011/11/21/2578547/former-apple-retail-ron-johnson-interview"&gt;Ron Johnson era&lt;/a&gt; of Apple retail, I worked as a Genius repairing many Macs and early-model iPhones in an Apple retail store. While many of the repairs were expensive on paper, our employee training specifically taught us to provide some repairs for free to promote customer satisfaction, as long as devices didn’t show signs of abuse. Those policies tightened noticeably after Johnson’s departure in 2011, with John Browett taking over as SVP of Apple retail and &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2012/10/no-surprise-browetts-reign-over-apple-retail-a-short-7-months/"&gt;focusing on cutting costs&lt;/a&gt;. That same year, Apple also introduced the AppleCare Plus service plan add-on for iPhones, in which accidental damage is covered after paying a $49 service fee. Despite the changes, other former employees &lt;a href="https://bgr.com/tech/apple-retail-store-trick-free-repair-replacement-tiktok-video/"&gt;have talked about how Apple’s push to “surprise and delight”&lt;/a&gt; customers can still lead to customers getting free in-store repairs. Whether that will change in the era of self-service is unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4V0ePk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The hope is that this will be enough to empower more DIY&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NLm56z"&gt;Normally, you could save money by buying aftermarket parts, but right now, aftermarket OLED screens for an iPhone 12 range from $279.99 (iFixit) for just the part to $329.99 (Amazon) for a full kit, which is a heavy cost. Going aftermarket also adds the risk that quality might not be as good as factory OEM pieces, and some parts could lose functionality, such as Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/21/11256118/apple-new-ipad-price-specs-release-date"&gt;True Tone adaptive screen feature&lt;/a&gt;. In theory, customers could save money via Self Service Repair if Apple priced the parts comparable to what IRPs currently pay. However, then IRPs would lose out on business unless Apple offered them a further discount on parts compared with the self-service program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ptnIVc"&gt;Another potential way individuals might use the self-service program is to stock up on parts like independent shops in the IRP program can do. Apple might choose to differentiate the IRP program and the Self Service Repair program by not allowing individuals to stock up, however, making it harder for DIY folks trying to plan ahead for devices they’ll want to repair in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KJXvsb"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MfjWDQOMQdU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2RSETV"&gt;In general, it’s going to be people with older phones who are more likely to need a repair, and right now, Apple’s Self Service Repair program won’t help them. iFixit CEO&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Kyle Wiens notes that replacement batteries aren’t necessary for most customers until about a year and a half after the phone was purchased, when battery cells start depleting. While Wiens is overall excited about Apple’s announcement and direction, he believes that the self-service program is primarily Apple’s strategy for getting out in front of potential &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587331/right-to-repair-apple-iphone-ftc-lina-khan-open-meeting"&gt;regulatory action from FTC &lt;/a&gt;and even pressure from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787336/apple-right-to-repair-self-service-diy-reason-microsoft"&gt;its own shareholders over the right to repair&lt;/a&gt;. Apple has also been under scrutiny &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/2020/7/30/21348240/apple-right-to-repair-legislation-antitrust-investigation-policy"&gt;from lawmakers&lt;/a&gt; over its restrictive repair practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8pjIGB"&gt;Despite its limitations, there is hope that Apple’s new program will empower more DIY repair folks and perhaps give an opportunity to save some cash. And if a customer gets cold feet when the kit arrives, they might have another option: taking it to a local repair shop that doesn’t have access to genuine Apple parts. That shop could then charge a small fee and do the repair for them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22787245/apple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22787245/apple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T11:49:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T11:49:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best early Black Friday deals on Apple devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8qbwNvRtOz3aWm0Swd3D9CY2VoQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70166146/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The AirPods Pro with the MagSafe charging case are on sale for just $190 at Amazon. | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dvAANe"&gt;Ironically, if you’re looking for a great Apple deal this Black Friday season, you shouldn’t shop at Apple. That’s because Apple doesn’t typically offer discounts on its new products in-store or on its website, at least outside of the occasional educational discount. Don’t fear, however, as there are plenty of reliable third-party retailers like Amazon, B&amp;amp;H Photo, and Best Buy that do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KwzsMr"&gt;Even better, these retailers have already started discounting some of the most popular Apple products ahead of Black Friday, dropping prices on everything from the latest MacBook Pro to the Apple Watch Series 7.  Below, we’ve rounded up the best deals we’ve found by category, and we’ll continue to update this piece as more deals are published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nunE44"&gt;Also, if you’re looking to save even more, make sure to check out our detailed guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;best early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt;, where we’re highlighting the best deals across all brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7GCD7S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals at Amazon","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22784145/amazon-black-friday-2021-best-deals-tech-cyber-monday"},{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals at Target","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22783434/target-black-friday-2021-deals-cyber-monday-tech-games"},{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals at Walmart","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22784126/walmart-black-friday-2021-tech-cyber-monday-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="3kzed7"&gt;AirPods deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="7uZofv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10871605" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="tGH865"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10871693" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="DpLcAU"&gt;The third-gen AirPods were released just last month, and now you can buy them with one of their first discounts. Both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FAirPods-3rd-generation%2F510546422%3Fathcpid%3D510546422%26athpgid%3DAthenaHomepageDesktop__gm__1.0%26athcgid%3Dnull%26athznid%3DSeasonalCampaigns_6fe92024-377d-4272-8406-8e51842e092f_items%26athieid%3Dnull%26athstid%3DCS020%26athguid%3D2_N6KcuypFy6YyBudpQEi5znMGyVPE382o95%26athancid%3Dnull%26athena%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; are selling the true wireless earbuds for $175 instead of $179. The latest AirPods boast a MagSafe-ready charging case and shorter stems, as well as better battery life and water resistance. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lLCckh"&gt;Apple’s second generation of true wireless earbuds, the AirPods, are selling for $119 instead of $159 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. This particular model comes with a wired charging case, however, you can pick up a pair with the wireless charging case for $160 instead of $200 from &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-2nd-Generation%2F482532021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="dzmtHj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Which AirPods model should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="MOAtWD"&gt;iPad deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="woXXlJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10871420" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VqyOya"&gt;The 2020 iPad Pro comes with Apple’s A12Z processor, a 120Hz display, quad speakers, and a dual-camera system with lidar. Right now, both the 11- and 12.9-inch models are on sale. Best Buy, for example, is selling the 128GB $1,149.99 LTE model of the larger version for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf1P6NNP9u7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,049.99&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, you can save significantly more if you’re okay purchasing the smaller, Wi-Fi-only model — but with 265GB storage — for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf1P7lnfGaJ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$749.99&lt;/a&gt; instead of $899.99 from Best Buy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nAbiSM"&gt;The 64GB, Wi-Fi version of the 10.9-inch iPad Air is selling for $539 instead of $600 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-9-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Sky-Blue%2F149437127&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; in rose gold, while the space gray version is just $10 extra. Released in 2020, the latest model offers thinner bezels around the display and a Touch ID sensor embedded in the power button. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kOAefm"&gt;MacBook deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="CEowOG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10872789" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="x4aA8b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10872835"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="RVzOFA"&gt;Last year’s M1-equipped MacBook Air is, in our opinion, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the best laptop&lt;/a&gt; you can buy. Right now, you can buy Apple’s entry-level laptop for $949 instead of $999 from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5KWB9H?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you choose the gold configuration with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. Alternatively, the 512GB model with 16GB of RAM is selling for $1,349 in gold or space gray at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604840-REG%2Fapple_z125_mgn7_04_bh_13_3_macbook_air_with.html%2FDFF%2Fd10-v21-t1-x1080441%2FSID%2Fprice-guide&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22787892%2Fapple-black-friday-2021-deals-macbook-ipad-airpods-cyber-monday" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bQ2F0g"&gt;Mac mini deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="GJSTnW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10872894" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="imac-markdowns"&gt;iMac deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="nnRT9Y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10872931" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ULdok1"&gt;Last year’s 27-inch iMac comes with an improved 1080p webcam, as well as a notable performance increase over its predecessor. Right now, you can pick it up for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Retina-Display-27-inch-Storage/dp/B08F8ZPRGW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,699&lt;/a&gt; instead of $1,799 when you choose the Core i5 model with 8GB RAM and a 256GB SSD. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356416/apple-imac-27-2020-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="homepod-mini"&gt;Apple Watch deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="p1KmAS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10873300"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WcbOv3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10873326"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="title"&gt;Amazon is discounting various configurations of the already affordable Apple Watch SE by around $10, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-SE-GPS-40mm/dp/B09G93BDQP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;selling this 40mm, GPS-equipped model&lt;/a&gt; for $270 instead of $279. While a small discount, this smartwatch is a great low-cost alternative we think you should choose over the Series 3, as it has most of the features found on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/19/17875882/new-apple-watch-series-4-review-ekg-bands-screen-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Series 4&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="U7uxx5"&gt;Apple Pencil deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="edj5y0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10874073" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="4UnRx1"&gt;The first-gen Apple Pencil is currently &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MK0C2AM-A-Apple-Pencil/dp/B016NY7784/ref=asc_df_B016NY7784/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon for $80&lt;/a&gt;, its second-best price to date. The stylus is compatible with the latest entry-level iPad and a range of earlier models, and it differs from the second-gen model in that you need to plug it into your iPad’s Lightning port in order to charge.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="b30reg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22787892/apple-black-friday-2021-deals-macbook-ipad-airpods-cyber-monday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22787892/apple-black-friday-2021-deals-macbook-ipad-airpods-cyber-monday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T11:20:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T11:20:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Apple assists DIY repairs, Russia blows up a satellite, and Biden signs infrastructure bill</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12, in blue." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v_beTx37OL-ZU8JIBoEnJ8zs7oA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70165958/vpavic_4243_20201018_0121.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2g6QKI"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSqILT"&gt;We’ve got a well-rounded episode of &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast &lt;/em&gt;today with everything from policy to space to consumer tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b9RmQE"&gt;In the first segment, Nilay and Dieter bring in &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; policy reporter Makena Kelly to talk about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783684/biden-infrastructure-bill-bipartisan-broadband-ev-electrical-grid-climate"&gt;President Biden’s $1 trillion infrastructure package&lt;/a&gt; and what it can do to improve broadband access in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="huCavM"&gt;In segment two, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; senior science reporter Loren Grush joins the show to explain why &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782946/russia-asat-test-satellite-international-space-station-debris"&gt;Russia destroyed one of their own satellites with a ground-based missile&lt;/a&gt; and how it’s causing concern in the space community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avvsQr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;Managing editor Alex Cranz stops by in segment three to chat about Apple announcing that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787144/apple-home-repair-iphone-mac-parts-tools-instructions"&gt;will start selling manuals and tools&lt;/a&gt; for repairing certain iPhone and Mac products at home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ddJbN6"&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP4910521508&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tKTdPK"&gt;Listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U6SX2n"&gt;Stories referenced in this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dbfOfS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783684/biden-infrastructure-bill-bipartisan-broadband-ev-electrical-grid-climate"&gt;Biden signs $1 trillion infrastructure package into law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qQNg4t"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787261/biden-fcc-net-neutrality-jessica-rosenworcel-gigi-sohn-broadband"&gt;Biden’s FCC is still deadlocked, and net neutrality hangs in the balance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SxxqQz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778342/califf-fda-head-alphabet-google"&gt;Biden’s pick for FDA chief works at Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FcLPhq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782946/russia-asat-test-satellite-international-space-station-debris"&gt;Russia blows up a satellite, creating a dangerous debris cloud in space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kUAsNN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22772427/nasa-artemis-program-moon-lunar-landing-2025-delay"&gt;NASA delays ambitious human lunar landing to 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KJmx93"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22783149/nasa-artemis-moon-landing-2026-office-inspector-general-report"&gt;NASA’s Moon landing will likely be delayed ‘several years’ beyond 2024, auditors say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="b4J1Nf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763384/blue-origin-lawsuit-nasa-spacex-lost-human-lunar-lander-artemis"&gt;Blue Origin loses lawsuit against federal government over NASA’s human lunar lander contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bUw4U6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776563/spacex-starlink-rectangular-dish-router-mounting-internet-satellites"&gt;SpaceX’s Starlink reveals new smaller, rectangular user dish to connect to satellites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TsghdR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787144/apple-home-repair-iphone-mac-parts-tools-instructions"&gt;Apple will sell you iPhone parts to fix your own phone at home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lMzN19"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787336/apple-right-to-repair-self-service-diy-reason-microsoft"&gt;The shareholder fight that forced Apple’s hand on repair rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0fi15Y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789615/apple-self-driving-car-project-titan-custom-processor-ev"&gt;Apple reportedly wants to launch a self-driving EV in 2025 with a custom chip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YkTX7s"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22784878/balmuda-phone-announced-specs-price-toaster-japan"&gt;The Balmuda Phone is a compact Android phone from a high-end toaster company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iRRh9E"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22782860/meta-facebook-reality-labs-soft-robotics-haptic-glove-prototype"&gt;Meta’s sci-fi haptic glove prototype lets you feel VR objects using air pockets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dC3toB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786914/sonos-dts-audio-support-beam-playbar-playbase-arc-amp-battery-saver-mode-13-4-update"&gt;Sonos finally adds DTS audio support to its home theater lineup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dcti0R"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783810/hyundai-grandeur-heritge-concept-ev-80s"&gt;Hyundai’s restomod Grandeur is the perfect EV for a supervillain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3k4khh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22788960/pixel-6-pro-charging-speeds-30w-21w-23w-slow-charge-battery-life"&gt;Google explains the tradeoffs that led to Pixel 6’s slow charging complaints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L3A6uV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22787426/netflix-cdn-open-connect"&gt;A look under the hood of the most successful streaming service on the planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="a9E7fG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785397/meta-facebook-leak-lockdown"&gt;Meta goes into lockdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="vqjzUF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791309/broadband-policy-russian-satellite-apple-iphone-repair-manual-vergecast-podcast-476"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791309/broadband-policy-russian-satellite-apple-iphone-repair-manual-vergecast-podcast-476</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T13:47:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T13:47:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple employees will return to offices February 1st in a hybrid work pilot</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lG5ZOWYnElGYRkwdymZupYyprWk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70160990/acstro_190902_apple_event_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple employees will return to offices February 1st | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cmtF4x"&gt;Apple employees will return to offices starting February 1st as part of a hybrid work pilot and will be able to work remotely for four weeks a year. First reported by &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/apple-sets-feb-1-for-return-to-office"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, employees learned of the news Thursday via an internal memo from CEO Tim Cook. The company had previously offered two weeks of remote work per year but added two more weeks to give “more opportunity to travel, be closer to your loved ones, or simply shake up your routines,” Cook’s memo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fPbyzN"&gt;The pilot will start workers at one or two days in the office, then in March, workers will come to the office to work on Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday. They’ll be able to work from home on Wednesdays and Fridays. &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/apple-pushes-back-return-office-plan-february-rcna6026"&gt;Some employees may be asked&lt;/a&gt; to come into the office four or five days a week if their roles require more time in the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QyCOxO"&gt;Cook first announced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;hybrid work model in June&lt;/a&gt;, when the company was planning a September return to offices that was moved back to October, then January, and now, to February. Some Apple employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22491629/apple-employees-push-back-return-office-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;pushed back strongly against the hybrid model&lt;/a&gt;, writing in an internal letter to Cook that they wanted a more flexible policy that allowed anyone who wanted to work from home to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gzcW1d"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request from &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;for more details on the company’s office return. Following widespread closures of Apple stores during the height of the pandemic in 2020, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307723/apple-stores-reopened-us-retail-open"&gt;reopened its retail stores&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, with mask requirements in place. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789631/apple-employees-return-offices-february-1st-hybrid-work-pilot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789631/apple-employees-return-offices-february-1st-hybrid-work-pilot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T13:39:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T13:39:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly wants to launch a self-driving EV in 2025 with a custom chip</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3FVtbo2763oZyprM7_3rrzX2D04=/0x1:2040x1361/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70160939/acstro_190902_apple_event_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R7XrPj"&gt;Apple has completed “much of the core work” on a new processor meant to power its secretive autonomous electric car project known as Titan, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-18/apple-accelerates-work-on-car-aims-for-fully-autonomous-vehicle?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’s &lt;/em&gt;Mark Gurman reports&lt;/a&gt;. The milestone comes as Apple is reportedly now accelerating its timeline for the autonomous car it’s developing, with a new target of launching it in just four years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ynw50V"&gt;Apple’s own silicon team designed the chip, which Gurman says is the “most advanced component” that’s been developed for the project so far. The company is apparently getting ready to put the chip through its real-world paces in its fleet of test vehicles in California and hopes to make a vehicle with “stronger safeguards than what’s available from Tesla and Waymo,” according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fz0Qx5"&gt;The goal now for Project Titan, after multiple pivots, is to create an autonomous car that does not have a steering wheel. The interior would be spacious and look more like the limousine-style seating arrangement that EV startup Canoo has promoted in its electric van prototypes. Apple was at one point in talks to acquire Canoo, as &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225026/apple-canoo-acquisition-investment-electric-car-goev"&gt;reported earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528448/apple-ulrich-kranz-canoo-bmw-electric-car-autonomous"&gt;recently hired one of the startup’s co-founders&lt;/a&gt;. There would be a large, iPad-style touchscreen display that will run a user interface similar to iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zPgvES"&gt;The business model is reportedly still undecided, though. Apple has considered trying to create a self-driving fleet to compete with Uber, Lyft, and Waymo (something Tesla has proposed but is still very far from executing), but Gurman reports that the “more likely scenario” is that Apple will sell the cars to individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZlkdE"&gt;On the electric vehicle side of things, Apple is reportedly not looking to develop a proprietary charging cable for the car. Instead, it wants to make the vehicle compatible with the “combined charging system,” or CCS standard, which would make it possible to charge the vehicle at most public fast charging stations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ib1zFC"&gt;Of course, all of this comes after years of reported changes to the project, which was started in 2014. Five different executives have run Project Titan after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665353/apple-watch-kevin-lync-project-titan-electric-car"&gt;Apple Watch lead Kevin Lynch took over earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The refocusing and timeline shift reported by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; could be a sign that there’s real progress being made with him at the helm, or it could just become the newest footnote in whatever the project turns into next.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789615/apple-self-driving-car-project-titan-custom-processor-ev"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789615/apple-self-driving-car-project-titan-custom-processor-ev</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Belkin’s new $150 3-in-1 charger is the first to get Apple Watch Series 7 fast charging</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2qCus9mdPGv8YvNCxvFWvOMd7sQ=/125x0:1976x1234/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70160686/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_11.40.18_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The BoostCharge Pro 3-in-1 Wireless Charging Pad with MagSafe | Image: Belkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TxkRI0"&gt;Belkin has a pair of new wireless Apple Watch chargers it’s announcing today, which are notably the first third-party chargers to support the newly added fast charging on the Apple Watch Series 7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iw8S32"&gt;The larger of the two is the $149.95 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fp%2Fp-wiz016%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F18%2F22785707%2Fbelkin-apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-magsafe-charger-boost-charge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BoostCharge Pro 3-in-1 Wireless Charging Pad with MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;, which follows in the footsteps of last year’s 3-in-1 Belkin charger. In addition to adding Series 7 fast charging, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/14/21516404/belkin-magsafe-boostcharge-pro-charger-car-mount-iphone-12-accessories"&gt;Belkin has ditched the odd sculptural design&lt;/a&gt; on the previous model in favor of a more normal-looking flat rectangular pad that will probably fit better on a nightstand. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DKUMBJ0Oe14bbCcQ41uUJaZtDvA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024679/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_11.43.05_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Belkin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BoostCharge Pro 3-in-1 Wireless Charging Pad with MagSafe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kl7fHl"&gt;The new charger aims to hit the perfect trio of Apple charging: full-speed 15W MagSafe charging for an iPhone, Series 7 fast charging for an Apple Watch, and a regular Qi charger for the AirPods. Of course, as has always been the case with Belkin’s combination chargers, the $150 price tag is far more than what it would cost to buy individual MagSafe, fast-charging Series 7 Apple Watch, and Qi chargers, meaning that you’re paying a decent premium for style and convenience here. That price also does include a 40W power adapter, so you’re at least getting a one-stop solution for your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZK3Mgx"&gt;The other new charger here is a bit more baffling: the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fp%2Fp-wiz015%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F18%2F22785707%2Fbelkin-apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-magsafe-charger-boost-charge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BoostCharge Pro Portable Fast Charger for Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;, which is a pop-up Apple Watch charging stand that costs $59.95. Despite the “portable” in the name, Belkin’s solo charger isn’t a battery pack-style setup for recharging an Apple Watch while you’re out and about. And even more baffling, that $60 price tag doesn’t include a power adapter: while there’s an integrated USB-C cable built into the stand, you’ll have to provide your own 20W wall adapter to actually use it. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XHQgQgrZSpBYCYdarKvgYBK6G-Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024682/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_11.43.33_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Belkin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BoostCharge Pro Portable Fast Charger for Apple Watch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U6DJhU"&gt;The net result is a larger, bulkier version of the fast-charging cable that Apple includes with every Apple Watch Series 7 — except that Belkin’s version costs literally twice the standalone cable’s $29 price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="63ZAiZ"&gt;Looking more broadly, though, is the fact that the new Belkin fast chargers show — once again — the intentional limits of Apple’s MFi program. The new chargers from Belkin are the only third-party fast chargers on the market right now, and if the pattern of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;last year’s glacial MagSafe rollout&lt;/a&gt; is anything to go by, it’ll be some time before other companies are able to get the approval (and the parts) from Apple to make other options. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LSmFy3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Vp3Hlv"&gt;Both the $59.95 BoostCharge Pro Portable Fast Charger for Apple Watch and 149.95 BoostCharge Pro 3-in-1 Wireless Charging Pad with MagSafe are available to order today from Belkin and Apple’s respective websites in the US, Japan, Hong Kong, and China, with availability in more countries promised in the coming months. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22785707/belkin-apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-magsafe-charger-boost-charge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22785707/belkin-apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-magsafe-charger-boost-charge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T19:45:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T19:45:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple pay equity and harassment organizer will leave the company after reaching a settlement</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XqM3nqv3p-ZADvT0eYbRAvCJlrw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70157708/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TASCwe"&gt;Cher Scarlett, an Apple engineer who helped organize pay equity surveys and anti-harassment / discrimination campaigns at the company, will be leaving the company and requesting the withdrawal of a complaint she made to the National Labor Relations Board (or NLRB), &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-17/apple-worker-who-led-protest-movement-leaving-after-settlement?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to a report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The software engineer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1461078948436054016"&gt;announced on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that Friday would be her last day at Apple. Scarlett’s lawyers told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that she had reached a private settlement with the company, but she declined to provide details about the terms when asked by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lECwx"&gt;Scarlett is leaving voluntarily, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, unlike some other organizers who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727123/apple-fires-leader-apple-too-movement"&gt;were fired from the company after speaking out&lt;/a&gt;. During her time at Apple, she &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/14/apple-worker-cher-scarlett/"&gt;was reportedly accused of leaking information to the press&lt;/a&gt; by other employees, something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"&gt;that’s strongly discouraged by Apple leadership&lt;/a&gt;, and that she denies doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YRB9ez"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Friday is my last day at Apple.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I’m taking a bit of time to decide where I’d like to go next, and will announce when I’ve made that decision.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;— Cher Scarlett   (@cherthedev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1461078948436054016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nV0cDB"&gt;The charge she’s requested be withdrawn was filed in September, when Scarlett said that Apple had “engaged in coercive and suppressive activity that has enabled abuse and harassment of organizers of protected concerted activity,” &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-national-labor-relations-board-investigating-two-complaints-apple-workers-2021-09-02/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. She made the complaint after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity"&gt;she and others at the company struggled to conduct a pay equity survey&lt;/a&gt; for Apple employees, with the company repeatedly shutting down their attempts. Scarlett also told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; that Apple wouldn’t allow employees to create a Slack room to talk about pay equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sqW6Lc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tim Cook says employees who leak memos do not belong at Apple, according to leaked memo","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5l5Esy"&gt;Scarlett withdrawing her complaint won’t necessarily leave Apple in the clear — the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759715/fired-apple-too-organizer-files-labor-charge-nlrb"&gt;faces a number of other complaints&lt;/a&gt;, including ones alleging wrongful termination from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/16/22729072/apple-too-organizer-janneke-parrish-interview"&gt;other employees Scarlett worked with&lt;/a&gt; to organize &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638150/apple-appletoo-employee-harassment-discord"&gt;the #AppleToo movement&lt;/a&gt;. #AppleToo aimed to get support for Apple employees who experienced discrimination or harassment if the company’s policies failed to provide it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0H74v6"&gt;Scarlett’s lawyers told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; that they hoped the company’s employees would continue to organize, a sentiment &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/16/22729072/apple-too-organizer-janneke-parrish-interview"&gt;echoed by other activists&lt;/a&gt; that are no longer with the company. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22788245/cher-scarlett-apple-nlrb-settlement-leaves-company-appletoo-pay-equity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22788245/cher-scarlett-apple-nlrb-settlement-leaves-company-appletoo-pay-equity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T18:30:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T18:30:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rittenhouse defense requests a mistrial after iPhone Mail app compresses key video evidence</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jury Deliberates In Kyle Rittenhouse Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W1HjlvEJ6r9EY5TzKd0ox35zngE=/0x0:5222x3481/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70157401/1236627321.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Krajacic - Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gC8mJP"&gt;The Kyle Rittenhouse trial in Kenosha, Wisconsin has once again gone off track because of basic technology problems: Rittenhouse’s defense attorneys today requested a mistrial because prosecutors sent them a drone video via email, which compressed the video in size. This is after earlier arguments about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22775580/kyle-rittenhouse-trial-judge-apple-ai-pinch-to-zoom-footage-manipulation-claim"&gt;what pinch-to-zoom does or does not do&lt;/a&gt;, and the judge &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778801/kyle-rittenhouse-bruce-schroeder-screenshot-zoom-in"&gt;struggling with the screenshot features on his Galaxy S20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I2bUF6"&gt;Rittenhouse faces five felony charges for shooting three men and killing two of them last year during a protest in Kenosha. &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/kyle-rittenhouse-trial-verdict-watch-11-17-21/index.html"&gt;CNN reports&lt;/a&gt; the motion for a mistrial is focused on when and how defense attorneys received a copy of a drone video showing the shootings that was shown to the jury in open court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t0md2S"&gt;Rittenhouse’s lawyers say they only received a copy of the drone video on November 5th, after the trial started, and that instead of the 11.2MB video possessed by the state, the file they received was just 3.6MB. “What that means is the video provided to the defense was not as clear as the video kept by the state,” the motion for mistrial claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfntYj"&gt;Prosecutors say they only obtained the video file directly from the drone operator after the trial started — the footage was already public, as it had aired on The Tucker Carlson Show on Fox News within days of the shooting during an appearance by the defendant’s first attorney, and a lower-quality version of the video was part of the defense’s exhibits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kg07HA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Going from an iPhone to an Android, it appears, somehow compressed the file. We did not know that this would occur.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QxzwE2"&gt;The prosecutors said the individual who took the footage came to investigators after the trial had started and transferred a higher-quality version of the video to a detective via AirDrop. The detective brought the video to court, and minutes after his arrival the prosecution told defense attorneys that they had obtained a much better quality version of the video than was previously available. The detective emailed a copy to Rittenhouse’s attorney Natalie Wisco, who uses an Android mobile device, and she transferred that file to the defense’s laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjCQTk"&gt;Assistant District Attorney James Kraus told the court that “going from an iPhone to an Android, it appears, somehow compressed the file [...] we did not know that this would occur. We gave what we fully believed was the full file to Ms. Wisco [...] it came in without objection and was an exhibit for four days, displayed for the jury on full screen.” The prosecution says that they did not know the version she received was of lower quality until just a few days ago when Wisco displayed the file she had received on a defense laptop in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M7Bjkb"&gt;The iPhone’s Mail app &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/iphone/add-attachments-iph8580f163b/15.0/ios/15.0"&gt;automatically compresses video files sent as an attachment&lt;/a&gt;, and the defense attorney describes getting a renamed .mov file in a format that sounds exactly like an Apple Mail-app compressed video from an iPhone user. The defense was ultimately able to retrieve the full-resolution video file after sending an attorney to collect it on a USB stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SXKcch"&gt;Wisconsin defense attorney Jessa Nicholson Goetz tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that “it is not normal that video or other electronic evidence is AirDropped to defense counsel in the middle of a trial. That is &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; atypical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GiVoy6"&gt;According to Goetz, Wisconsin law says that “any evidence that the state intends to use at trial must be disclosed ‘at a reasonable time before trial,’” and that “a mid-trial AirDrop in no way meets the requirements.” She also notes that prosecutors and courts in Wisconsin routinely handle video evidence. “Many police departments have body cams required, and virtually all squad cars statewide are equipped with video that turns on automatically if the vehicle’s emergency lights are activated. All of those videos are regularly provided via flash drive or CD-ROM/DVD,” says Goetz. “I have never encountered receiving a different or lower quality version of video evidence than the original video.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NKtsxe"&gt;As for why the procedures for handling evidence in this case seem so sloppy, Goetz tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that evidentiary rules vary from county to county, with some courts that use online portals to transfer files back and forth, some that require mailed hard copies, and others that require prosecutors to allow defense attorneys to physically retrieve whatever files they need on USB drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0XNBYV"&gt;Rittenhouse’s defense initially requested a mistrial with prejudice, which would have prevented the case from being tried again. It has dropped the “with prejudice” from the request, and so far the judge has not ruled on the motion, even as the jury deliberates and looks at the video. &lt;a href="https://www.nbcchicago.com/news/local/kyle-rittenhouse-trial-live-jurors-set-to-begin-second-day-of-deliberations/2686647/"&gt;NBC 5 News&lt;/a&gt; reports that Kenosha County Circuit Judge Bruce Schroeder says resolving the issue will require testimony from an expert witness.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22788080/kyle-rittenhouse-drone-video-compressed-iphone-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22788080/kyle-rittenhouse-drone-video-compressed-iphone-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T15:02:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T15:02:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>If your iPhone 12 or 13 is having issues with calls, updating iOS may help</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13, in pink." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hzOzZiGzLh0VtWA7ztijbsr3KgM=/0x0:2019x1346/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70156363/vpavic_210916_4760_0069.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p8Gk5O"&gt;A new iOS update is starting to hit phones — no, not the seemingly feature-packed iOS 15.2, but iOS 15.1.1, which Apple says will solve an issue with calls dropping. According to the update note, the new version of iOS “improves call drop performance on iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 models.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XWdorh"&gt;While we haven’t seen large amounts of users complaining about their new-model iPhones dropping more calls than normal, it’s nice to see that Apple is paying attention to how its phones perform as, well, phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OWl7X5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;15.1.1 is worth updating to if you’ve been having issues with calls dropping&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="igyTso"&gt;You can update to iOS 15.1.1 by going to Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Software Update. If you find updating to be a pain and haven’t been experiencing any call issues, though, it may be best to just wait for iOS 15.2 — the beta has been absolutely packed with features, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778650/apple-iphone-13-pro-beta-macro-mode-button-auto-switching"&gt;improvements to the iPhone 13 Pro’s macro mode&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749352/apple-app-privacy-report-ios-15-2-beta-feature"&gt;addition of the App Privacy Report&lt;/a&gt;, the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774124/ios-15-2-beta-2-airtag-tracker-scan-privacy-invasion"&gt;manually scan for suspicious AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, and more. That update seems to be coming soon, so waiting to go through the update process would be understandable, especially given that Apple’s &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201222"&gt;not reporting any major security patches in 15.1.1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787756/iphone-ios-update-15-1-1-call-dropping-issue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787756/iphone-ios-update-15-1-1-call-dropping-issue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
