<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-04T10:07:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T10:07:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T10:07:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some must-have Nintendo Switch games are $20 off at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OP-wdeSftWgDpWegiGTX6IdzBPg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69948046/MHRISE_Gathering_Hub_Canteen.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZlBczm"&gt;This is a big week for the Nintendo Switch. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22690483/metroid-dread-nintendo-switch-oled-console-hands-on-preview"&gt;Switch with an OLED screen and &lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; launch Friday, October 8th. Whether you’re a Switch veteran, or you’re prepping for your first console with the $350 OLED model, there are some excellent deals on must-have, cartridge-based titles you should know about. &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword HD&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros. Ultimate&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;New Pokémon Snap&lt;/em&gt; are each $20 off. Amazon is the only retailer honoring this deal for all three games, but Best Buy and Walmart are hosting some deals, too. &lt;em&gt;Monster Hunter Rise&lt;/em&gt; is $20 off, but only at GameStop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KSEqI"&gt;All of these are noteworthy deals because they’re rarely discounted games. Nintendo sometimes hosts price cuts, but only for a select batch of games — many of which have been available since the Switch launched a handful of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MRMOxx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10660223"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="MDXV7k"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10241211"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="6aOgty"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10283625"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="0EdGQj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10415477"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ga2waH"&gt;Outside of Nintendo’s world, the Apple AirPods Pro are back down to one of their lowest prices yet. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07ZPC9QD4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is selling these wireless earbuds for $179&lt;/a&gt;, down from their normal $249 price. It’s not tough to find a decent deal on this model, but it rarely goes below this price point, outside of Black Friday, at least. In case you didn’t know, these high-end AirPods have active noise cancellation, excellent sound quality, and their case can charge via Lightning or wirelessly on a Qi charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4EcugC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hmZwpcv22s4BmrVhLuU7ROGfi4A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9478831/akrales_171013_2047_0017.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wEebVp"&gt;If over-ear headphones are more your style, the Beats Studio 3 noise-canceling headphones in a few colorways are steeply discounted at Amazon. Originally $350, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beats-Studio3-Wireless-Over%E2%80%91Ear-Headphones/dp/B085296FLT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;some of the color options are available today for $170&lt;/a&gt;. This model released in 2017, and just like the first AirPods, they feature the W1 wireless chip that makes connecting to (and switching between) Apple devices a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="meveVx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10521384"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="aM6OQB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/4/22708561/nintendo-switch-games-sale-pokemon-zelda-smash-bros-airpods-beats-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/4/22708561/nintendo-switch-games-sale-pokemon-zelda-smash-bros-airpods-beats-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T09:13:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T09:13:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch Series 7 launches October 15th, preorders begin on Friday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VYJLsuxRPAJ9WlsPRgRLGPEsDnw=/0x47:1960x1354/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947813/Apple_watch_series7_availability_hero_10052021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch Series 7 includes a bigger display.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DEXMH2"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-watch-series-7-orders-start-friday-october-8/"&gt;is opening up preorders&lt;/a&gt; for its Apple Watch Series 7 on Friday, October 8th, with the devices set to ship on October 15th. Apple first revealed the Watch Series 7 at an event last month, but the company simply said it would be available later this fall. Preorders for the Apple Watch Series 7 will now begin at 5AM PT / 8AM ET on Friday, October 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U4rsJI"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7 includes a display&lt;/a&gt; that goes virtually to the edge of the case, with more rounded corners and a softer design. The Series 7 now comes in 41mm and 45mm sizes, up 1mm from the Series 6. The bezels around the display are just 1.7mm, and the always-on mode is 70 percent brighter than the Series 6.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rh_93UzApG97WIOiYk9nH-h8KZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22899644/Apple_watch_series7_availability_contour_face_10052021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new Contour watchface for the Watch Series 7.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CqsEmC"&gt;Apple has also created a variety of new watchfaces to take advantage of the larger screens on the Apple Watch Series 7. An improved modular watchface lets you view activity ring details alongside the regular complications found on the regular modular watchface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCCHDc"&gt;The screen size is really the big change to the Apple Watch Series 7, alongside watchOS 8 improvements like better outdoor cycling support, fall support in workouts, and some Fitness Plus upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NqShL"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 will start at $399 and will be sold alongside the Watch Series 3 at $199. If you buy a Watch equipped with cellular service, whether through Apple.com or directly from a carrier, there’s also a $100 rebate available after activation with T-Mobile/Sprint or Verizon. Preorders for the Apple Watch Series 7 start on October 8th, and devices will start shipping on October 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zALDC9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 10:45AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information regarding cellular activation and rebates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708611/apple-watch-7-release-date-price-preorder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708611/apple-watch-7-release-date-price-preorder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Yes, Siri is my favorite smart home controller and here’s why</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v1fKRWFS8SYv0MquROlM6mooZSA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947472/dseifert_201107_4281_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hey Siri, turn my home on.”&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Speed, brevity, and an abject failure at fart jokes make Apple’s AI voice assistant the winner in my smart home&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="WPTvnX"&gt;I use a fairly simple metric to determine which artificially intelligent voice assistant is the best for controlling my smart home: Which one do I swear at the least? Apple’s Siri, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22468274"&gt;which turns 10 today&lt;/a&gt;, wins hands down. This is slightly to do with the fact it rarely spews useless information at me when it didn’t understand what I was asking (*cough* Google) and definitely because it never asks if I want to buy something (you know who you are). But mainly, it’s because as a smart home controller, Siri is seriously fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49IGjx"&gt;Siri, you say? That same Siri whose lagginess is legendary in its native iPhone home? Yes, that’s the one. Bring Siri into your home, put the power of an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22454960/apple-tv-4k-2021-review"&gt;Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/15/21517945/apple-homepod-mini-homekit-smart-home-system-gateway-price"&gt;HomePod&lt;/a&gt; (maxi or mini) behind it as a HomeKit hub, and the snappiness with which the AI does what you command will floor you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26UCCw"&gt;A simple, “Hey Siri, Good Night” turns off all the smart lights in my home, locks the front and back doors, closes the garage door, pauses any music playing, lowers the shades, and sets the thermostat to my sleep temperature in around 6 seconds, give or take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sh1Q62"&gt;A quick “Hey Siri, lights on” directed at the kitchen HomePod Mini turns just those lights on in under a second. As a bonus, it has never once accidentally illuminated the whole house at 5AM, as some other voice assistants have unhelpfully done (I mentioned the swearing already, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zORgUx"&gt;A whispered “Good Morning” into my Apple Watch while pressing the digital crown, and my home springs gently back to life; turning on just the lights I need to get ready without waking up my partner and playing NPR quietly on the kitchen Mini, all before I’ve made it out of the bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="egleSZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Hey, Alexa. Hey Siri. Hey Google. Hey, can anybody hear me??&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z9Ac9k"&gt;Siri may lack some of the excellent qualities found on competing smart speakers.  It’s not the smartest AI — that goes to Google Assistant with its powerhouse backend. It’s not the most helpful — that goes to Alexa with its frequent (and frequently unsolicited) offers of assistance. But when all what you want to do is turn the lights on and instead your AI launches into a monologue about who invented the light switch, that’s when you say to yourself, “I wish my smart home controller was a little dumber.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qaodwa"&gt;While the smart home dream is one powered by artificial intelligence that uses context to anticipate your every need, we are a long way from that reality. Today, all you really need from your smart home voice control are listening skills and comprehension — we’re talking first grade here, not a master’s degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JdTZeY"&gt;To be helpful, voice control in the smart home just has to be easier and less obtrusive than pulling out a phone and opening an app, and more convenient than walking over to flip a switch. It’s a challenge and one that Apple is the closest to conquering — in my home at least. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="RBU0iX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I do wish Siri was more promiscuous&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sPRgrc"&gt;Yes, fart jokes are fun, and it’s great to have the world’s knowledge just a few words away — Siri is no good at either of those things. But Siri does hear me 100 percent of the time, even when the closest speaker is on the other side of the room, understands my smart home requests 95 percent of the time, and limits its chatty banter to the absolute minimum — “On it” or “Coming right up.” These are qualities I admire in a smart home controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B5Q26x"&gt;However, I do wish Siri was more promiscuous. There are a fair number of gadgets and gizmos in my admittedly out-of-the-norm smart home that can’t talk to Siri. This means I occasionally find a member of my household standing haplessly in the middle of the room saying, “Hey, Alexa. Hey Siri. Hey Google. Hey, can anybody hear me??”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojs8L5"&gt;It was also not a simple nor inexpensive process to set up my partly-Siri-powered smart home. (The nature of my job means I’m contractually obliged to run all four smart voice assistants at once — yes, I have Bixby in here too). Searching for Siri-compatible devices generally means choosing the “highest-priced” filter in the search results and closing your eyes when you hit that buy button. A few more budget-friendly offerings released over the last year from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523877/aqara-smart-home-review-m2-hub-homekit-alexa-google-assistant"&gt;Aqara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.meross.com/home"&gt;Meross&lt;/a&gt; have made it a little easier on the wallet, but there are still a number of categories entirely missing or sparsely populated — such as robot vacuum cleaners, smart smoke alarms, and home security systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="QZyYA5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Searching for Siri-compatible devices generally means choosing the “highest-priced” filter in the search results&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvXGH3"&gt;The coming promise of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;Matter&lt;/a&gt; may fix this interoperability conundrum, which, to be fair, is not just Apple’s problem. But in the meantime, I’ve found that Siri Shortcuts offers a useful way around some of these limitations. &lt;a href="https://gotailwind.com/"&gt;Tailwind, my favorite garage door controller&lt;/a&gt;, didn’t have HomeKit support for a long time. It does now, but in the interim it offered a Shortcut to program in my own command to have Siri open and close the door. The same deal with my ceiling fans. &lt;a href="https://bondhome.io/product/bond-bridge/"&gt;The Bond Bridge&lt;/a&gt; (an RF device that can communicate with a ceiling fan remote control, not a scene from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/27/22252018/james-bond-no-time-to-die-hmd-global-nokia-phones-product-placement"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Time to Die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) can use Siri on your iPhone or Apple Watch to trigger Shortcuts to control my not smart, definitely not HomeKit-compatible fans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0QLWz"&gt;The downside of Shortcuts, however, is they only work on an iPhone or Apple Watch, and smart home control needs to be easily accessible to everyone in the house, whether they’ve bought into the Apple ecosystem or not. Until the advent of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;HomePod Mini&lt;/a&gt;, the price to outfit a modest-sized home with on-demand Siri access was prohibitive, and even the HomePod Mini’s $99 per room is still steep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="GniVqK"&gt;In honor of Siri’s tenth birthday, it looks like the AI is inviting some friends to the party. A new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;Siri-enabled accessories program&lt;/a&gt; allows non-Apple gadgets with speakers and microphones in them to relay requests to a HomePod. As of now, the Ecobee SmartThermostat is the only manufacturer to have committed to this. (Considering &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701965/amazon-fitbit-ecobee-basics-design-halo-view-smart-thermostat-clone-ripoff-regulators"&gt;Amazon just Sherlocked them with its new smart thermostat&lt;/a&gt; I wouldn’t blame Ecobee if it evicted Alexa entirely.) With more ways to talk to Siri in the home and more products that can be controlled by the smart assistant, I’m hoping my swear jar will be gathering cobwebs by Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9OMrqQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hey Siri, what happened?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/suDspLBgHdfFDtXFwilxVwt4Qxw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947342/acastro_211001_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;After a decade as Apple’s assistant, Siri still hasn’t figured out the job&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="XxOI1i"&gt;Ten years ago today, Apple’s digital assistant Siri was revealed with the promise that the iPhone maker had finally figured it all out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQlAfC"&gt;“For decades, technologists have teased us with this dream that you’re going to be able to talk to technology, and it’ll do things for us,” said Apple exec Phil Schiller, taking the stage at the launch of the iPhone 4s. “Haven’t we seen this before, over and over? But it never comes true.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cdxm20"&gt;The problem, said Schiller, was that voice interfaces were too reliant on simple syntax. &lt;em&gt;Call&lt;/em&gt; Mom. &lt;em&gt;Dial&lt;/em&gt; 555-2368. &lt;em&gt;Play&lt;/em&gt; Beethoven. “What we really want to do is just talk to our device,” he said, “and your device — in this case, your phone — will figure out what you mean and help you get what you want done.” He paused before bringing up the next slide, showing a familiar icon of a microphone cut-out in burnished aluminum. “That’s a feature on the iPhone 4s we call Siri.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YX13ru"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“What we really want to do is just talk to our device,” said Schiller&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lXFa7h"&gt;Described by Schiller as a “humble personal assistant,” Siri gave 2011’s iPhone a dose of star power during a difficult time for Apple. Just months before the phone’s unveiling, a relative unknown at the company, then-chief operating officer Tim Cook, had been named CEO. The day after Schiller’s presentation, Apple’s legendary co-founder Steve Jobs would die from pancreatic cancer. Analysts were cool on the company’s prospects but praised Siri as a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2011/oct/05/iphone-4s-icloud-analysts"&gt;potential game-changer&lt;/a&gt;. One called it “a powerful harbinger of the future use of mobile devices,” while another said it was “the beginning of a new user experience [for] all of Apple’s mobile and Mac products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="FOHUYM"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agzItTz35QQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R75LfJ"&gt;A decade later, the sheen has worn off Siri’s star. “It is such a letdown,” was how Schiller described the promise of voice interfaces past, and such a description could easily be applied to Apple’s contribution to the genre. Everyone who uses Siri has their own tales of frustration — times when they’ve been surprised not by the intelligence but the stupidity of Apple’s assistant, when it fails to carry out a simple command or mishears a clear instruction. And while voice interfaces have indeed become widespread, Apple, despite being first to market, no longer leads. Its “humble personal assistant” remains humble indeed: inferior to Google Assistant on mobile and outmaneuvered by Amazon’s Alexa in the home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1AzJI"&gt;Looking back on a decade of development for Apple’s personal assistant, there’s one question that seems worth asking: hey Siri, what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vLyruz"&gt;The wow factor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="khQMdg"&gt;Looking back to 2011, initial reactions to Siri were incredibly positive, with reviewers impressed by the feature’s responsiveness and accuracy. “The crazy thing about Siri is that it works — at least most of the time — better than you’d expect it to,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/apple/2011/10/12/2484524/iphone-4s-review"&gt;was &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s judgment&lt;/a&gt;; “It’s kind of like having the unpaid intern of my dreams at my beck and call,” &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2011/10/12/tech/mobile/review-siri-iphone-voice-wired/index.html"&gt;said &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; “Siri saves time, fumbling and distraction, and profoundly changes the definition of ‘phone,’” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/12/technology/personaltech/iphone-4s-conceals-sheer-magic-pogue.html?_r=1&amp;amp;ref=technology"&gt;said &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. All in all: Apple seemed to be living up to its promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7TLsF1"&gt;But reading these reviews now, it’s clear Siri was graded on a curve. Its novelty and ambition invited generous appraisals, but when reviewers noted frustrations, they caveated that the software was only in beta and that any rough patches would surely be smoothed away in due time. A &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2011/10/iphone-4s-a-siri-ously-slick-speedy-smartphone/"&gt;detailed run-down of Siri in 2011 from &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlights problems familiar today, with the assistant dinged for mishearing instructions in loud spaces and mangling complex commands. An instruction to “Send a text to Jason, Clint, Sam, and Lee saying we’re having dinner at Silver Cloud” is interpreted with Siri texting Jason: “Clint Sam and Lee saying we’re having dinner at Silver Cloud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="MYZdcd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Siri was first on the scene, but soon was just part of the chorus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q860Aj"&gt;Siri had a first-mover advantage, but it didn’t take long for rivals to emerge. Samsung introduced S Voice on the Galaxy S3 in 2012; that same year Google Now was launched for Android (replaced by Google Assistant in 2016); in 2014 Microsoft brought out Cortana for Windows Phone; and also that year, Amazon went its own way by introducing customers to Alexa on the Echo smart speaker. Speaking to your computer quickly became an expected feature not just on mobile devices, but a whole range of gadgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="galXfv"&gt;Looking through reviews and comparisons of digital assistants in this period, two things stick out. The first is that people soon get bored of Siri. As reviewers tackle iPhones after the 4s, they often note incremental updates to the assistant but never dedicate much space to it its features. Partly, this seems just because the changes are so small (e.g., retrieving sports results in iOS 6; integrating Wikipedia in iOS 7; introducing ‘Hey, Siri’ in iOS 8), but also because the novelty has worn off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0N0ZfW"&gt;By the time we get to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/19/technology/iphone-reviews.html"&gt;reviews of the iPhone 8&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, Siri is mentioned in passing, if at all. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/19/16323570/apple-new-iphone-8-review-plus-2017"&gt;Our own review&lt;/a&gt; summarizes the assistant’s contribution in a single line: “Siri sounds a lot nicer as well, although it’s not any more capable than before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone 4S Siri" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e36FE_zxFYAre8sm8lY_SbNQCE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets/938847/iPhone_4S_Siri_1020.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Siri on the iPhone 4s impressed reviewers for its sheer novelty. But Apple never kept up the momentum. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SPA8NE"&gt;The second major trend is that once competitors did arrive, Apple’s advantage evaporated quickly. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/5/24/3040552/siri-vs-s-voice-comparison-video"&gt;comparison of Siri and Samsung’s S Voice&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 notes that the latter already “offers a very good approximation” of Apple’s digital assistant, while a head-to-head test in 2014 shows that “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/9/6951813/google-now-crushes-siri-and-cortana"&gt;Google Now crushes Siri&lt;/a&gt;.” By 2017, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/19/15655558/google-assistant-vs-siri-iphone-ios-apple-locked-down-sandbox"&gt;noted that&lt;/a&gt; Siri “feels largely half-baked,” and a dissatisfaction with digital assistants in general had begun to creep in. We point out that these assistants can answer basic questions just fine but fail to reliably &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; things for the user — like booking cinema tickets or ordering food. At least, not without creating new problems of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lL13Qf"&gt;Looking back, it’s clear that Siri’s big problem is that it failed to maintain momentum. The basic roster of tasks that made Apple’s digital assistant so appealing in 2011 — setting alarms, taking notes, and so on — were never significantly expanded upon. The ability to answer trivia questions and retrieve sport scores is fun, but not as significant an upgrade as telling a computer to complete tasks using just your voice. Meanwhile, rivals replicated and then exceeded what Siri could do. They began to offer more reliable dictation, better language understanding, and integration with third-party skills. Siri just didn’t keep up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="lsd4sf"&gt;Trouble at the top&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="xLN0Rx"&gt;So, where did things go wrong? How did Apple lose its lead? The answer is complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdKpJv"&gt;Many suggest Apple’s dedication to privacy means it can never keep up with rivals like Google whose business involves collecting users’ data because that data is incredibly useful when it comes to improving AI systems. I don’t buy this as a reason for Siri’s failure, though. First, because Apple’s love of user privacy is far from absolute. (In 2019, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jul/26/apple-contractors-regularly-hear-confidential-details-on-siri-recordings"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian &lt;/em&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that “a small proportion” of Siri recordings were being passed to contractors for analysis, with a whistleblower claiming they overhead discussions “between doctors and patients, business deals, seemingly criminal dealings, sexual encounters and so on.”) And secondly, because Apple is a two-trillion-dollar company. If it wants to circumvent the messy problems of collecting user data, it can, simply by paying to generate this data. Yes, analyzing random Siri interactions is helpful, but there are other ways to achieve the same improvements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BJ0NiG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When Steve died the day after Siri launched, they lost the vision”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wABLGp"&gt;A more convincing explanation is management dysfunction. In 2018, &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-seven-year-itch-how-apples-marriage-to-siri-turned-sour"&gt;published a damning report&lt;/a&gt; on the comings-and-goings at team Siri. It noted that there was deep-seated disagreement within the company about how Siri should work (is it a feature focused on search and retrieval, or an assistant that carries out complex tasks?). These disagreements stemmed back to Jobs’ original plans for Siri but had devolved into “petty turf battles and heated arguments” between rival factions. They were exacerbated by a lack of leadership and continuity in the Apple execs overseeing Siri. As one former employee told &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;: “When Steve died the day after Siri launched, they lost the vision [...] They didn’t have a big picture.” This tallies with the feature’s stalled development after its initial launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZANm6e"&gt;Other problems are rooted in Apple’s ideology of technology development. For example, &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;’s report claims that Apple exec Richard Williamson made the decision to only update Siri once a year, following the company’s cadence of new hardware and iOS updates. This seems to have slowed progress. (Williamson, who refuted this claim, left Apple in 2012 after spearheading the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/9/20/3363914/wrong-turn-apple-ios-6-maps-phone-5-buggy-complaints"&gt;disastrous Apple Maps launch&lt;/a&gt;. Scott Forstall, another executive involved in Siri and Apple Maps, &lt;a href="https://www.cultofmac.com/509277/today-in-apple-history-scott-forstall-forced-out-of-apple/"&gt;departed that same year&lt;/a&gt;. Read into that what you will.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oJvTNr"&gt;There’s also Apple’s walled garden approach, which means Siri has always worked well with iOS features but played badly with third-party services. While testing Siri in preparation for this story, I was consistently surprised by its failure to execute simple tasks on popular iOS apps. Siri can’t send a voice memo on WhatsApp; can’t post a story to Instagram; can’t record a run on RunKeeper; and can’t open up &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; crossword. Sure, some of the blame for this lack of interoperability lies with outside developers, but it’s also Apple’s job to encourage such functionality through toolkits and the like. The company certainly doesn’t lead by example, either. When I ask Siri for information I know is stored in iOS, like “show me photos from last August,” it just performs an image search for the phrase “last August.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_CDKU4S2TXG2fNJS-ekOGHqWCM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22893700/Screen_Shot_2021_10_01_at_4.04.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not close, and no cigar: results when you ask Siri to “show me photos from last August.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WnyGFp"&gt;Instead, Apple uses Siri to herd people back to its own inferior apps like a shepherd directing sheep off a cliff-face. If I ask Siri for directions, it prompts me to reinstall Apple Maps (when I habitually use Google Maps and Citymapper). If I try to send an email to my boss, Siri tells me, “I’m sorry I can’t do that,” and then directs me to the App Store to download Apple’s default mail app (I use Outlook). And, here’s a sign of how slipshod Siri’s development is right now: when this happens, Siri sets up a search for “mobilemail” on the App Store. This, of course, isn’t the name of Apple’s mail app, but an ID used by iOS developers, and so it draws a blank when you search for it on the App Store. That’s the kind of broken functionality you get when a company isn’t thoroughly testing its own product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5L0wtM"&gt;This last point, though, highlights a problem particular not just to Apple’s assistant, but to voice interfaces more generally, and that is one of &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="belhu2"&gt;When Schiller introduced Siri in 2011, he stressed time and time again that Siri would understand users — that it knows what they are saying, just like a real person. This set the bar too high for Siri’s functionality. If you treat voice interfaces as if they have the same level of fluency and knowledge as a human being, you will always be disappointed. We speak, and they stumble. We guess what they’re capable of, and they disappoint. Usually because they don’t support the app or command we thought they would. Each failed interaction then teaches users: &lt;em&gt;don’t trust this feature&lt;/em&gt;. By comparison, screens and displays tell us clearly what we can and cannot do. They offer menus, directions, and buttons. A voice offers only itself and our projections of intelligence. For Siri, users have been guided by Apple’s flair for the theatrical. They expect too much, and Apple delivers too little. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="24pjSv"&gt;The future of voice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="UZ8jBr"&gt;Here’s a true story. I took a break just now from writing this article to make a cup of tea and remembered that I had a meeting in an hour’s time. Worried it might slip my mind, I did what I often do in these situations: I asked Siri to set a reminder. “Siri, remind me at ten to five that I have a call,” I said. “Okay,” said Siri, “Setting a reminder for tomorrow at five: you have a call.” I tried again. This time Siri created a reminder for ten o’clock in the evening. The third time, I paused mid-command, trying to think of a clearer way to word my query. Siri got tired of waiting and beeped at me: “What do you want me to remind you of?” And at that, I gave up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xfCE77"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple can’t afford to give up on Siri&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l1xMve"&gt;It’s true that Siri and its ilk are often disappointing, but they still tempt users because they hold great potential. Despite the problems associated with voice interfaces, the technology represents a genuine advance. I regularly use Siri for quick tasks, like taking notes, setting timers, and making searches. And when it works, it works seamlessly and unthinkingly. It’s a genuine time-saver. Siri can do much more, too, especially if you’re willing to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial"&gt;dive into the world of Apple Shortcuts and smart home commands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWPvuM"&gt;As an accessibility tool, voice controls and dictation have opened up modern gadgets to many more users, and since Apple introduced Siri in 2011, the company has launched a number of products that rely heavily on voice. This is either because screen real estate is limited (the Apple Watch) or it’s nonexistent (the AirPods and HomePod). In years to come, we can expect Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654606/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-wireless-connection-stream-data"&gt;augmented reality glasses&lt;/a&gt; to be added to this list. With this in mind, Apple urgently needs to fix Siri — not ignore it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7tmRQiWXwOhvqxy7gSrUc-vv5eI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993026/akrales_190327_3315_0182.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AirPods, HomePod, and Apple Watch — all products where Siri is helpful or essential. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lSIjso"&gt;If you want to be optimistic, then there are some signs the company is turning the ship around. AI, in general, has received much more attention from Apple in recent years. From poaching Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/3/17195076/google-ai-chief-john-giannandrea-joining-apple-machine-learning-siri"&gt;head of machine learning in 2018&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/13/16300464/apple-iphone-x-ai-neural-engine"&gt;designing its own AI processors&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21301511/apple-ai-machine-learning-features-wwdc-2020-convenience"&gt;regular launch of AI-enhanced features&lt;/a&gt;, the company is clearly paying more attention to the field. And, best of all, Siri itself has seen a few significant improvements, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc"&gt;on-device processing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;availability on third-party hardware&lt;/a&gt; added this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Di1z2J"&gt;I’m still skeptical, though. For a start, even when it comes to basic commands, it often seems Siri is not just standing still but moving backward. With iOS 15, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/352142/ios-15-siri-third-party-app-integrations-deprecated.html"&gt;removed a decent chunk of Siri’s functionality&lt;/a&gt;, including tasks related to notes and photos, and third-party integrations like ride-hailing and payments. Other basic commands, like checking voicemail, also seem &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/users-complain-about-siri-no-longer-being-able-to-send-email-and-check-call-history/"&gt;to have recently disappeared&lt;/a&gt; (whether temporarily or not isn’t clear). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdqcXC"&gt;The big problem, I think, is that Apple still doesn’t know what it wants Siri to be. Is the feature simply a way to control your phone with your voice — letting you navigate apps and find content? Or is it something more ambitious — an actual assistant capable of carrying out complex tasks on your behalf? Apple tends to present Siri as the latter in marketing materials, while users find its functionality limited to the former. As someone who reports on AI and machine learning, I think we’re still many, many years away from building computers that truly &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; us. Language is just too complex, too deeply rooted in human experience and culture, to be brute-forced by the sort of statistical models we’re throwing at the problem. And while, yes, there are lots of impressive new language systems out there, none of them are reliable enough to create a flawless digital assistant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="D5vLZ1"&gt;If Apple wants to salvage Siri, I think it needs to reset expectations and focus on core competencies instead. It’s interesting to compare Siri’s launch with that of its competitors. When Google introduced &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/snL88L1DQQ4"&gt;Google Assistant in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, for example, the focus was less on solving complex tasks and understanding users’ every whim, and more on making the company’s basic search functionality accessible in more places. It was a tighter focus that gave Google the space to surprise, rather than disappoint. (Though the company has certainly over-promised in later ads, too.) Siri, by comparison, surprised us all when it launched in 2011, but has since burned out that goodwill. Apple needs to re-focus on the basics rather than push into a future that doesn’t yet exist. It needs to start listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJPM0M"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22704233/siri-apple-digital-assistant-10-years-development-problems-why"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22704233/siri-apple-digital-assistant-10-years-development-problems-why</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T03:32:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T03:32:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple finally lets you report App Store scams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MSLXmSgAgFbhRM3vT8eiqNXDfn8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947070/acastro_210831_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2QeKQk"&gt;One month ago, we laid out a list of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;eight obvious things Apple could do&lt;/a&gt; to prove it puts App Store users ahead of profits. Today I learned the company acted on at least one of these ideas: Apple will now let you directly report a scammy app from its listing in the App Store with a new-and-improved version of its “Report a Problem” button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G8UELa"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mazkewich/status/1444780501949194256"&gt;Richard Mazkewich&lt;/a&gt; and scam hunter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1444801938990657536"&gt;Kosta Eleftheriou&lt;/a&gt; point out on Twitter, the button has not only returned to individual app listings for the first time in years, it now includes a dedicated “Report a scam or fraud” option in the drop-down menu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OagmtA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;In a major reversal, Apple quietly added back the “Report a Problem” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppStore?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@AppStore&lt;/a&gt; button in iOS 15: &lt;a href="https://t.co/UopiPDEV7e"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UopiPDEV7e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1444814469184425988?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BuSUQB"&gt;Until iOS 15, the only way you could find this button was to scroll &lt;em&gt;all the way down to the bottom&lt;/em&gt; of the Apps or Games tab in the App Store, get kicked out to a website where you’d need to re-sign in. Then you could pick from “Report suspicious activity,” “Report a quality issue”, “Request a refund” or “Find my content.” None of the options offered a clear way to report a scam, and the “Report suspicious activity” would redirect you to Apple Support instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kV3tFU"&gt;To add insult to injury, Apple would only let you report “a quality issue” if you’d already paid money (and thus fallen for the scam). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dvpc1F"&gt;But now, it seems like every free app with in-app-purchases appears to offer the “Report a Problem” option. I checked a handful of apps I’ve never paid for (but could have) and they all displayed the button. You’ll still get kicked out to a website where you’ll need to sign in, but overall this seems like a step forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7pUYa5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Is Apple actually hiring scam investigators?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aIfpkS"&gt;Of course, the big question is whether Apple will actually take action on those reports. Another thing we pointed out last month is that Apple only has 500 human app reviewers — compared to 15,000 content moderators at Facebook, 20,000 at Google, and, yes, 2,200 at Twitter (a company &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; from the most valuable and profitable in the world). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aabRXO"&gt;Intriguingly, there may be some movement on that front too: Eleftheriou pointed out to me that Apple began hiring &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:mi2lnsb96ikJ:https://jobs.apple.com/en-us/details/200284943/asi-investigator&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;strip=1&amp;amp;vwsrc=0"&gt;for an “ASI Investigator” position on September 8th&lt;/a&gt;. “ASI Investigators are accountable for investigating fraudulent apps and trends, as well as the developers involved,” part of the job posting read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvTqX3"&gt;Shame that job posting no longer exists; it’s been taken down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9LPlp"&gt;Perhaps, at the very least, Apple’s automated systems can use the new data to sound the alarm when a scam app crosses a predefined threshold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJYUny"&gt;Apple definitely seems to be listening to the recent wave of anger around the App Store. In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22667242/apple-app-store-major-policy-changes-history"&gt;a variety of small forced concessions&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of judicial and regulatory scrutiny, Apple just &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/rate-and-review-apple-iphone-built-in-apps/"&gt;started allowing users to review the company’s own apps that it bundles with every iPhone&lt;/a&gt;. Apple Podcasts, Weather, and even the built in Calculator app are all fair game for angry 1-star reviews. Immunity from user scrutiny may not be the most egregious advantage Apple has enjoyed in its own App Store, but it’s nice to see the company leveling the playing field even a little bit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uqRb8Q"&gt;Here are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;the other suggestions&lt;/a&gt; we had for Apple’s App Store, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22667242/apple-app-store-major-policy-changes-history"&gt;a brief history of significant policy changes&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s made over the years. Yes, we’re keeping track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZZXZth"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The App Store is too big to change","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22645070/apple-app-store-policies-purchases-cut-fees-change-class-action"},{"title":"Sweetheart deals and plastic knives: all the best emails from the Apple vs. Epic trial","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22611236/epic-v-apple-emails-project-liberty-app-store-schiller-sweeney-cook-jobs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-01T13:26:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-01T13:26:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple updates iOS 15 to fix the iPhone 13’s Apple Watch unlock bug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 and 13 Mini have the same camera sensor as last year’s iPhone 12 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wLBCOBtLDUiA0PacI26N6Kb1-JQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69937923/vpavic_210918_4760_0703.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FE8LgD"&gt;Apple’s iPhone 13 lineup just launched last week, but some users ran into a frustrating issue where they couldn’t use their Apple Watch to unlock their new phones while wearing a face mask. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22694679/apple-fix-issue-unlock-apple-watch-feature-iphone-13"&gt;had promised&lt;/a&gt; that a fix was on the way, and it appeared earlier this week &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22699884/iphone-13-apple-watch-unlock-bug-fix-ios-15-beta"&gt;in an iOS 15.1 beta&lt;/a&gt;, but now, the fix is live for everyone as part of the iOS 15.0.1 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64mbPr"&gt;Apple’s official patch notes also say that the update includes other bug fixes, but the company didn’t specify what those might be. The update clocks in at 553.7MB on my iPhone 12 Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ij7SMRdNePJUekUr58RvZ1-1tL8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22894075/IMG_1169.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are Apple’s iOS 15.0.1 update notes, taken from my iPhone 12 Mini.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5vL8HJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403554/apple-ios-ipados-14-5-now-available-iphone-unlock-face-mask-app-tracking"&gt;In April&lt;/a&gt;, Apple added the ability to use your Apple Watch to unlock a Face ID-equipped phone while wearing a mask, and it’s proved to be a handy feature as masks are still recommended in many situations due to the pandemic. With this new software update, it seems that iPhone 13 users who were affected by the bug stopping the feature from working will be able to take advantage of the convenient unlocks once more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704524/apple-ios-15-0-1-update-fix-iphone-13-watch-unlock-bug"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704524/apple-ios-15-0-1-update-fix-iphone-13-watch-unlock-bug</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T17:32:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T17:32:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Surface Laptop Studio and Surface Pro 8 stack up against other creator laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Surface Laptop Studio" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KG1pPCiMFMJcaHhRsaVgZ3en4r0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933878/bfarsace_210921_4770_0019.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5FWQMS"&gt;Microsoft announced a new version of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685923/microsoft-surface-pro-8-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Pro&lt;/a&gt; last week, along with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686010/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt;. The Surface Pro 8 feels very much like a logical evolution of Microsoft’s tablet / laptop. Some of the more notable improvements include a 120Hz display with slimmer bezels, Thunderbolt 4 support, as well as a reworked surface keyboard that includes a dedicated space to store and charge the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vCXxU1"&gt;Meanwhile, the Surface Laptop Studio features a uniquely hinged screen and more powerful hardware. This is effectively a replacement for the Surface Book 3, with a three-point adjustable display that can lay flat for drawing or snap upright to deliver a more traditional laptop experience. This laptop comes equipped with an Nvidia RTX 3050 Ti GPU and a four-core, 4.8GHz, 11th Gen Intel processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CY3oWn"&gt;Perhaps the coolest thing to come out of the event was the Surface Slim Pen 2, which aesthetically appears like any other stylus, but includes haptic feedback to simulate the subtle tactile response you get from putting a pen to paper. While the inclusion of a stylus is hardly revolutionary, improvements to the overall user experience are nice to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mpq31I"&gt;But how do the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686705/microsoft-surface-pro-8-keyboard-screen-photos-video-hands-on"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686706/microsoft-surface-studio-laptop-design-specs-photos-hands-on"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt; stack up against other laptops that occupy the creator and power user space? We’ve collected a few of our favorites below for comparison based on our early impressions and spec sheets, with full reviews to follow in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tYNcsP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder all of the new Surface hardware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683783/microsoft-surface-pro-x-8-3-go-laptop-studio-preorder-price-date"},{"title":"Here’s how much buying into Microsoft’s pro Surface vision actually costs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688403/surface-pro-8-duo-studio-x-go-true-price-keyboard-pen-stylus-bundle"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="ot9Igy"&gt;Versus the Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ma4ruS"&gt;We chose the 14-inch models of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Spectre X360&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22430445/acer-conceptd-7-ezel-2021-review"&gt;Acer ConceptD Ezel&lt;/a&gt; because of their competitive pricing, which includes a stylus, and also for their ability to reorient themselves in some creative ways. (The new Microsoft devices don’t include the Surface Slim Pen 2, which costs $130 separately.) &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeCreatorLaptops093021&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-spectre-x360-laptop-14t-ea000-touch-1q881av-1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Spectre&lt;/a&gt; is technically a 2-in-1 and can operate effectively as a tablet if you flip the screen over, though it doesn’t hold it up at an angle quite like the Surface Laptop Studio. The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Facer-conceptd-7-ezel-cc715-71-7196-laptop%2F8v916pqmq44c%3Focid%3DAID2200057_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%28ir__0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xrv21qkgxj29e00%29%287593%29%281243925%29%28nOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%29%28%29%26activetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab%26ranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DnOD%252frLJHOac%26ranSiteID%3DnOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%26epi%3DnOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%26irgwc%3D1%26irclickid%3D_0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xrv21qkgxj29e00" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ConceptD Ezel&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, can flip out its screen and prop itself up like an easel or lay flat like a tablet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7CWKEi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10777072"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qmwVig"&gt;We also threw in the Laptop Studio’s predecessor, the 13.5-inch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21271796/microsoft-surface-book-3-review-price-specs-features-13-5-screen"&gt;Surface Book 3&lt;/a&gt;. The screen may not fold or flip, but it can still operate as a tablet when detached from its keyboard. We considered adding the 15-inch version of the Surface Book 3, but its &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Book-3%2F8XBW9G3Z71F1%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting price of $2,300&lt;/a&gt; made it just a little too expensive when stacked against its competition.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lS2sz3"&gt;Still, the Surface Laptop Studio sets itself apart by offering a greater battery life and likely a superior dedicated GPU option to any of these other machines. It also has the distinction of being the only laptop in our lineup with a 120Hz refresh rate display, a feature typically reserved for gaming laptops. You’d generally need to look at a gaming-class laptop if you need a higher-end GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="30BNMX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10768014"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HKxepF"&gt;Versus the Surface Pro 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3PomAq"&gt;The unique form factor of Surface devices makes them tough to compare, but the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569871/lenovo-yoga-9i-14-inch-laptop-review"&gt;Lenovo Yoga 9i&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;Apple MacBook M1 Air&lt;/a&gt; make a strong case as ultraportables outside the Surface ecosystem that cater to creatives, and we’re also including the previous-gen &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-7%2F8n17j0m5zzqs%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro 7&lt;/a&gt; for comparison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="04Pq9K"&gt;Like previous generations of Surface, the new Surface Pro 8 doesn’t come with a pen or keyboard to start. The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-slim-pen-2%2F8tb9xw8rwc14%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-signature-keyboard%2F90fj6zkw1rzb%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro Signature Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; will cost you $130 and $180, respectively, but can also be &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-signature-keyboard-with-slim-pen-2%2F8vdb5vrkc5tq%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bundled for $280&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously, the other laptops we’re discussing come with built-in keyboards, and the Yoga i9 includes the pen as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zk9g3e"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771697"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="95GkMo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfFKTLj8MM4#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Lenovo&lt;/a&gt; also shares many of the same hardware specifications as the Surface Pro 8, with options for an 11th Gen Core i5 or i7 CPU. It does make a couple of compromises, most notably in the resolution and refresh rate of its display. These caveats could be overlooked by anyone who needs to save a little more money, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gpMQIw"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook M1 Air&lt;/a&gt; is really the outlier of this lineup, not just because of its OS, but because it’s also the only laptop we picked that doesn’t have a touchscreen or can operate as a 2-in-1. It does, however, strike a solid balance in terms of features, performance, and price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nL0Tae"&gt;The biggest draw for the Surface Pro 8 — besides its unique form factor — is the display, which boasts the highest resolution and refresh rate out of the contenders below. It’s also the only model that features a 4K rear camera.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="u8udLq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10771732"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VhOLDV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction October 1st, 2:13PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The Microsoft Surface Book 3 features a USB-C 3.1 port, not a USB-C Thunderbolt 3 port as initially stated in this article. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22687992/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-pro-8-hp-spectre-macbook-air-creator-laptops-compare-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22687992/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-pro-8-hp-spectre-macbook-air-creator-laptops-compare-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s fortress of secrecy is crumbling from the inside</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UQgpmeLeDb2phUsQM5iLRkfnRVQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69932920/acastro_210913_4747_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The last five months marked a turning point in Apple’s company culture — will it last?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="n53OkX"&gt;On June 14th, 2021, Apple’s remote work advocacy group sent an anonymous email to Tim Cook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aR6Zrr"&gt;“We all agree that we are here at Apple to make insanely great products that enrich people’s lives and the world,” they wrote. “We are convinced that we can create the same, and even better products by adding more flexibility to the announced return to office policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SUAH5O"&gt;Two weeks earlier, Cook had announced that after a difficult year working remotely, Apple was reopening its offices. Starting in September, employees would be asked to return to in-person work three days a week, with the option to work from home on Wednesdays and Fridays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R2MFRX"&gt;The news wasn’t surprising — Apple’s executive team had never pretended they wanted to go fully remote. But it didn’t sit well with staff members who’d moved away from Apple’s offices during the pandemic and had little desire to go back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uE0LFr"&gt;The tension might have stayed at a low simmer were it not for a Slack channel — #remote-work-advocacy — created in September 2020 to promote a more flexible working environment. By the summer of 2021, it had reached roughly 2,800 members, with conversations growing increasingly lively. After Cook made his announcement, employees knew they had to send a message. It was a small push back against management that would lay the groundwork for months of employee organizing and perhaps change the Apple workforce forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="2QL9em"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Not everyone is afraid that their boss at Apple is going to fire them.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IVX1de"&gt;Apple’s remote work struggle is emblematic of a deeper shift taking place inside the company. Since 1976, the tech giant has operated in largely the same way: executives make decisions about how the company will function, and employees either fall in line or leave. What choice do they have? Apple is currently worth $2 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the world, as well as one of the most powerful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i6bFWj"&gt;Over the past few months, however, that culture has started to erode. As workers across the tech industry advocate for more power, Apple’s top-down management seems more out of touch than ever before. Now, a growing number of employees are organizing internally for change and speaking out about working conditions on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZcNzI"&gt;“There’s a shift in the balance of power going on here,” says Jason Snell, the former editor of &lt;em&gt;Macworld, &lt;/em&gt;who’s been covering Apple since the 1990s. “Not everyone is afraid that their boss at Apple is going to fire them. They’re saying, ‘I’m going to say some bad things about Apple, and if you move against me, it’s going to look bad for you.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkVDrp"&gt;The shift is due in part to the fact that the tech giant is two years into a radical new experiment: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22659497/apple-slack-organizing-zoe-schiffer-decoder-interview"&gt;using Slack&lt;/a&gt;. Where Apple employees previously worked in ultra-siloed teams with little opportunity to meet people outside their current project or department, they now have a way to communicate with anyone across the company. Employees have discovered that individual work grievances are shared by people in entirely different parts of Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LNJas1"&gt;The details of these grievances vary. Some employees want the company to invest in internal tools to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22648265/apple-employee-privacy-icloud-id"&gt;better protect their privacy&lt;/a&gt;. Others want more transparency in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22633141/apple-pay-equity-survey-results-wage-gap"&gt;how much people are paid&lt;/a&gt;. Many who’ve spoken to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; feel like Apple’s employee relations team has been woefully inadequate in addressing their workplace concerns. The overarching desire — the thing that connects the tenured software engineer in Cupertino with the retail employee in New Jersey — is that employees want to feel heard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vhXKPi"&gt;So far, it’s not entirely clear Apple executives want to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OjwvBu"&gt;
&lt;p id="73RZT1"&gt;When Kate Rotondo started working as a software engineering author at Apple in August 2018, she did so knowing she was an exception: while most of Apple’s corporate workforce was in person, she would be allowed to work from home once a week, with the option of “earning” a second remote day after six months on the job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="C6IAQY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She made $10,000 to $15,000 less in base pay than the others at her same job level.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QXl9sp"&gt;By Apple’s standards, it was a compromise. What Rotondo wanted, what she’d asked for, was to be fully remote. The last three years had taken it out of her. She’d moved from Tübingen, Germany, to San Francisco, gotten a divorce, and was now raising her nine-year-old son under complicated co-parenting conditions. The last thing she needed was a three to four hour commute. But her manager was firm: working entirely from home wasn’t an option. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1bN4DN"&gt;When she started her new job, Rotondo was surprised to find that this hiring manager was entirely remote himself. As were her three other team members — all men. Rotondo was the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; person on her team required to go into the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="78ttAe"&gt;Still, it was Apple. What was Rotondo going to do? She put it out of her mind for six months, until she spoke to a colleague who was going from contract to full-time and wanted to talk about compensation. He was being leveled as an ICT-4 — one level above Rotondo — and would be making $25,000 more in base pay, with an additional $20,000 more in restricted stock units. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o6xpRk"&gt;The revelation shocked Rotondo. She felt like she was more experienced than her male colleagues. While they’d worked at Apple longer, she’d co-authored a book about the programming language Adobe AIR, taught coding at Mills College and the continuing education department at the Rhode Island School of Design, and was an expert in Apple’s own iOS programming language Swift. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1p24j"&gt;She started chatting with peers and found that — of the eight other engineering authors she’d spoken to in her org — she was the lowest paid. She made $10,000 to $15,000 less in base pay than the others at her same job level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SmwkUK"&gt;During her review cycle the following year, her manager told her she was achieving expectations and praised how quickly she’d gotten up to speed on the team. He said she was getting a $5,000 bump in base pay and a $3,000 refresher in restricted stock units — far less than what she’d expected. The lowest RSU refresher she’d heard of up until that point was $50,000, over 16 times more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hygMR1"&gt;Rotondo explained to her manager that she felt she was being under-leveled and underpaid, citing the conversations she’d had with colleagues. He countered that she needed to outperform her co-workers in order to be considered for a promotion. To Rotondo, it felt like she was being asked to go above and beyond what her male colleagues were asked to do. They’d come in making more money than her — and they were fully remote. She was achieving expectations while commuting three to four hours a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="DMu41C"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the leak felt violating.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ioy4mV"&gt;Rotondo took the issue to her manager’s manager. He roped in a member of the employee relations team — Apple’s version of HR — who said they would open an investigation. Two months later, a representative came back and said the employee relations team had found Rotondo was leveled and paid fairly. “You’re getting a $0.00 adjustment,” they added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BhkXtY"&gt;Shortly afterward, Rotondo resigned. She’d been at Apple nearly two years and felt completely isolated in her battle — gaslit by her managers and Apple’s employee relations team. She had no clear way to air her grievances with colleagues who might feel the same. Five months later, she filed a charge of discrimination with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUrKB9"&gt;It would be months before other Apple employees started connecting on Slack and speaking out on Twitter about pay equity and sexism — the very issues Rotondo was trying to fix. But by then, it would already be too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PK4Vix"&gt;
&lt;p id="M7MrFc"&gt;Before May 2021, the public rarely heard from Apple employees like Kate Rotondo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ObIA5"&gt;“There was a perception that when you went behind the curtain at Apple, you’d never be heard from again,” says Jason Snell. Steve Jobs was so adamant about keeping his workforce under wraps that he removed all the names from the ‘About’ boxes on the software when he returned to Apple in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhUh6X"&gt;Internally, that secrecy is enforced through a series of norms and rules. The norms are simple: don’t speak publicly about Apple unless you’ve been specifically asked. The rules are less so: Employee badges only open certain doors, based on the projects on which they’re disclosed. They’re asked to sign project-specific NDAs. Product documents are coded with internal keywords like “Ultra,” “Black,” and “White,” which connote how secret the work is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ruLLPf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s a strong expectation that internal problems should be kept internal.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fRmMkp"&gt;Ultra projects — reserved for Apple’s biggest product launches — are tracked on an internal Apple system that monitors employees who have prototype devices. Apple requires vendors to sign an NDA as well as an Apple Restricted Project Agreement before they can receive information about this type of work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gZpAyA"&gt;“This environment of secrecy produces an unwritten hierarchy of ‘haves’ and ‘have-nots’ within the company,” &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/9/11/16288896/apple-secrecy-inkling-culture-leadership-transparency-values"&gt;wrote former employee Matt Macinnis&lt;/a&gt;. “For the ‘haves,’ the hierarchy of disclosure is a way to exert influence and demonstrate power beyond one’s role or title. For ‘have-nots,’ it’s a subtle but constant reminder of your rank.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hKdpEK"&gt;The Apple value that underpins all of this, elevating the secrecy concerns from an issue of potential lost revenue to one of core company DNA, is “surprise and delight.” It’s the idea that Apple products should catch the public unaware, giving them something they want before they even know they want it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cf0lSx"&gt;But the secrecy has bled over into other parts of Apple’s culture, too. Although the company specifically says that its policies “should not be interpreted as restricting your right to speak freely about your wages, hours, or working conditions,” the reality is that there’s a strong expectation that internal problems should be kept internal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4Ba1p"&gt;For many Apple employees, these idiosyncrasies are seen as the cost of working at Apple — one of, if not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt;, most prestigious tech firm in Silicon Valley. People know what they’re getting into when they sign up. Employees stay for decades, giving up lucrative opportunities at early-stage startups because they believe in the company’s mission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kB1ouK"&gt;But for others, the company’s refusal to listen to its own workforce is becoming a bigger sticking point, particularly during an era when the balance of power is shifting away from managers and toward rank and file employees — at least, everywhere but Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="C6knp6"&gt;
&lt;p id="i1spFf"&gt;On May 11th, 2021, a group of female Apple employees discovered that Apple had hired Antonio García Martínez, a former Facebook product manager, who’d written a Silicon Valley tell-all book containing misogynistic descriptions of women. One passage that began circulating internally said most women in the Bay Area were “soft and weak, cosseted and naïve despite their claims of worldliness, and generally full of shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5Ylsv"&gt;Employees discussed the issue in the #women-in-swe Slack channel, eventually deciding to write an internal letter to Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior VP of services. They didn’t want García Martínez to be fired necessarily; they just wanted answers as to how he’d been hired in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZqVGmv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the leak felt violating.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="djVjZW"&gt;García Martínez was set to work on privacy on the ad platforms team. His direct working group was all men. Apple’s VP of ad platforms, ​​Todd Teresi, had no women reporting directly to him, save for his chief of staff. The idea that there might not have been any women on García Martínez’s hiring panel infuriated Apple employees and further spurred the organizing effort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JCD0n"&gt;The following day, while the letter was still being finalized, a version of it leaked to the press. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432909/apple-petition-hiring-antonio-garcia-martinez-chaos-monkeys-facebook"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; published it in full&lt;/a&gt;. Hours later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433437/apple-hire-antonio-garcia-martinez-out-petition-investigation"&gt;García Martínez was fired&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hzzKYB"&gt;To many women in the channel, the leak felt violating. They’d meant for the letter to remain internal and genuinely wanted to engage Apple’s leadership and hear what they had to say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="THGN3C"&gt;But it also marked a turning point in Apple employee organizing. After the &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; article was published, another group of employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446059/apple-employees-palestinians-support-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;wrote a letter asking Tim Cook&lt;/a&gt; to publicly support Palestine amid a deadly bombing campaign from Israel. Then, the #remote-work-advocacy channel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22491629/apple-employees-push-back-return-office-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;published a letter&lt;/a&gt; pushing back against returning to the office. They circulated a survey asking people how they felt about going back to in-person work. The results of the survey also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560586/apple-hybrid-work-internal-survey-tim-cook"&gt;quickly became public&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="UyjxTq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Now, employees know that if their tweets get enough attention, they might be insulated from overt retaliation.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUkqLi"&gt;The advocacy brought Apple workers into a widespread campaign for change that had been shaking up the tech industry since at least 2018. Google employees &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/technology/google-walkout-sexual-harassment.html"&gt;staged major walkouts&lt;/a&gt; to protest the company’s handling of sexual harassment. Amazon warehouse workers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/28/22352987/amazon-bessemer-alabama-union-vote-rwdsu"&gt;attempted to unionize&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook employees seemingly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21444203/facebook-leaked-audio-zuckerberg-trump-pandemic-blm"&gt;spent all of 2020 leaking their discontent to the press&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dg5VJ5"&gt;This was the first time, however, that Apple employees had joined the fight: openly pushing back against the decisions — or non-decisions — of company leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G50OCx"&gt;Apple historically dissuaded employees from talking about work on social media — even in seemingly harmless ways. The company’s guidelines are vague: “Be thoughtful about how you present yourself in online social networks,” they read. “The lines between public and private, and personal and professional, are blurred in online social networks. In particular, it’s a priority that we respect the privacy of our customers and other employees.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAGdpF"&gt;Still, multiple employees tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that those who tweet about Apple quickly receive a note from the business communications team asking to chat. They don’t always get in trouble, but the message is clear: Apple executives are watching.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YoZj9v"&gt;In the past, that was enough to stop most employees from speaking out. Now, employees know that if their tweets get enough attention, they might be insulated from overt retaliation. That is, unless Apple claims they’ve violated company policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="KVTxa5"&gt;
&lt;p id="U1YTVe"&gt;Cher Scarlett already had a significant Twitter following by the time she landed at Apple as a software engineer on the security team in April 2020. But for the first year, she didn’t tweet about workplace concerns. It wasn’t until news of García Martínez’s hiring started circulating internally that she finally decided to speak out.  “I have been gutted, as many other folks at Apple were, with the hiring of Antonio García Martínez,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1392618677644767238?lang=en"&gt;she tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “I believe in the strength of community we have at Apple, &amp;amp; that the culture we’ve built can weather this. I also believe in leadership to do the right thing, whatever that is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gp8idF"&gt;Over the next few months, Scarlett became more vocal about issues she was seeing at the company. When she looked at levels.fyi, a website for people to compare salary data, she realized that women on her team seemed to be making less than men — at least in her geographic area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="LN6l2N"&gt;&lt;q&gt;So Gjøvik decided to go nuclear&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CJJqeJ"&gt;She knew that Apple had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity"&gt;shut down three separate employee-run pay surveys&lt;/a&gt;, claiming they either contained personally identifiable information or were hosted on Apple’s corporate Box account, which wasn’t allowed. So she decided to run her own survey. After it got roughly 2,000 responses, she &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1426434491069861895?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1426434491069861895%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F23%2F22633141%2Fapple-pay-equity-survey-results-wage-gap"&gt;tweeted out some of the results&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting that there were far fewer women, non-binary, and non-white people in technical roles or senior positions at the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TIeVdh"&gt;News of the survey inspired others, including Kate Rotondo, to begin tweeting openly about their own issues trying to get paid and leveled fairly. It was too late for Rotondo to get justice from Apple — she’d already left the tech industry and was working as a potter in San Francisco — but the experience of speaking out was cathartic. The EEOC had not taken action on her case — a devastating blow for someone who hoped Apple might be held accountable and stopped from treating other workers unfairly. Now, she felt like the only way to told the company accountable was to speak out against its tactics on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Vz62Sn"&gt;
&lt;p id="e5U3He"&gt;On July 26th, 2021, Ashley Gjøvik, a senior engineering program manager, posed a question in the #women-in-swe Slack channel. “Do we think Apple does a sufficient job at handling employee complaints about discrimination?” she asked. “Do we feel comfortable even reporting issues?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aUHnZg"&gt;The note sparked a long discussion from women who also felt misled by the tech giant’s HR team. Gjøvik herself shared that employee relations had investigated some of her complaints and told her “actions were taken.” “But when I pried further, there was no actual resolution or actions because no Apple ‘policies’ were violated,’” she wrote. Her sentiment was echoed by other women who said they’d experienced similar frustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAbg0O"&gt;During the pandemic, Gjøvik had become increasingly concerned about the physical safety of the office. She already knew that her Apple department was located on a superfund site — meaning it required special oversight due to historical waste contamination. Then she received an email saying Apple wanted to do a vapor intrusion survey in the office and test the quality of the air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="T7bCBH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“ignore the problem, say as little as possible.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t2ClVk"&gt;Gjøvik raised her concerns to her boss, saying she was worried about her safety and the safety of her other colleagues. She says he responded that she shouldn’t share her concerns with any coworkers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W5POGU"&gt;Gjøvik went to the employee relations team and asked them to tell her boss to stop saying she couldn’t talk about workplace safety. Instead, she says they opened an investigation into whether he’d violated any policies related to sexism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQzZag"&gt;About a month later, they came back and said he hadn’t. When Gjøvik asked what her options were, the employee relations representative suggested she file an ADA accommodation request to continue working remotely after September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9p5IG7"&gt;To Gjøvik, the request did not solve her concerns about the physical safety of the office. But she didn’t have many other options, so she filled out the form, writing that she had “serious concerns about [the] workplace safety of my building and Apple’s other buildings on chemical release sites.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aUIKPv"&gt;Apple told her she’d also need to fill out a medical release form that would give her records to Sedgwick, a third-party claims company, as well as Apple, Inc. Gjøvik said she wouldn’t do it unless the form was amended to say her records would just be released to Sedgwick, not Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jea8t8"&gt;She never received the accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o8HEuN"&gt;Gjøvik was frustrated; she felt like she’d been keeping Apple’s secrets for years, staying quiet about mistreatment from her boss and team members, and now — when she had a real health concern — the team was telling her to stay quiet. So she decided to go nuclear: talking about her experience on Twitter and opening up to the press about what she was going through. A few of her tweets contained redacted screenshots of bullying comments from her teammates. One suggested Apple’s access to her work phone was inappropriate, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22648265/apple-employee-privacy-icloud-id"&gt;having resulted in her having to hand over nude photos of herself&lt;/a&gt; during an unrelated legal dispute years before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jhGiAQ"&gt;In August and early September, both Gjøvik and Scarlett &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-national-labor-relations-board-investigating-two-complaints-apple-workers-2021-09-02/"&gt;filed charges with the National Labor Relations Board&lt;/a&gt;. Gjøvik said she’d faced harassment, intimidation, and an unsafe and hostile work environment. Scarlett filed on behalf of all Apple employees, saying the company had been limiting their protected right to organize and discuss pay.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="qWBTEy"&gt;
&lt;p id="LLEDbF"&gt;If Apple had a playbook for how to respond to allegations of discrimination and abuse over the last four months, it was “ignore the problem, say as little as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="22VlkN"&gt;On August 20th, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633616/apple-delays-mandatory-office-return-january-covid-surge"&gt;announced it was delaying its return to work until at least January 2022&lt;/a&gt; due to a rise in COVID-19 cases. Advocacy about the issue quickly died down as employees realized they weren’t going to be forced back to Cupertino anytime soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="6oAxFC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The firing is the first real sign that Apple executives may, in fact, be paying attention.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KClDy2"&gt;The company did start cracking down on non-work Slack channels. After the García Martínez letter, employee relations announced a series of rules that banned channels not related to Apple business unless they were part of an official club or diversity group. The rule did not apply to existing channels, creating a bizarre scenario where Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650751/apple-bans-pay-equity-slack-channel"&gt;banned a company-wide pay equity channel&lt;/a&gt; but left the #fun-dogs, #fun-cats, and #dad-jokes channels alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FGtvUk"&gt;Then, on September 9th, Apple made its first major public move in combating employee dissent: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22666049/apple-fires-senior-engineering-program-manager-ashley-gjovik-for-allegedly-leaking-information"&gt;it fired Gjøvik&lt;/a&gt;. The company said she had leaked Apple’s confidential information in violation of her NDA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9yO3I7"&gt;The firing is the first real sign that Apple executives may, in fact, be paying attention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gbPWEE"&gt;Still, Apple likely won’t be able to stop employees from talking to one another. Too many of them have already met and started to organize. Some have joined non-work Discord channels to talk about pay equity and other issues that span Apple’s various teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="72E1OW"&gt;It’s too early to tell where all this activity is going. Apple employee organizing is helmed by a relatively small group of workers, some of whom are burnt out and ready to leave the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5QOZe"&gt;There’s also the issue of internal resistance coming from other factions of Apple’s workforce. While many employees don’t want to return to the office, they disagree with how the activists have gone about pushing for change. After Gjøvik started to gain momentum on Twitter, multiple current and former Apple employees tweeted about how they were suspicious of her claims and felt like she was merely trying to get attention. On Slack, when employees talk about their concerns with privacy or a general lack of transparency, they’re often met with pushback from people who say they should have known what they were signing up for when they joined the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tk6SIB"&gt;To some employees, the bargain of working at Apple is to endure the hierarchical, secretive nature of the company. But to the workers who are pushing back, the question they’re asking is: does it really have to be this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29ivxQ"&gt;Apple did not respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22700898/apple-company-culture-change-secrecy-employee-unrest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22700898/apple-company-culture-change-secrecy-employee-unrest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T10:29:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T10:29:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch flags multiple types of irregular heartbeats, study shows  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple Watch Series 3" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nI4eE3YWBBmkd5xpULj_tMwBQ0o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69931094/akrales_171113_2119_0074.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple Watch | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="btdYqJ"&gt;People who get irregular pulse notifications on an Apple Watch but don’t have atrial fibrillation — the condition the feature focuses on detecting — could still have another type of problem with their heartbeat, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/pdf/10.1161/CIRCEP.121.010063"&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bwctQo"&gt;The findings show that even if someone with a concerning alert from their Apple Watch doesn’t get an atrial fibrillation diagnosis, they may not be in the clear, says study author Marco Perez, the director of the Inherited Arrhythmia Clinic at Stanford University Medical Center. “Even if you didn’t find atrial fibrillation, we were finding a lot of people who had something else that probably needed some clinical attention,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HIkRfb"&gt;The analysis, published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Circulation&lt;/em&gt;, was done using data from the Apple Heart Study, which was designed to test the Apple Watch’s ability to detect irregular heart rhythms. It launched in 2017 and included over 400,000 participants. In the study, anyone who got an irregular pulse notification from the watch was sent a clinical ECG patch, which could monitor their heart rhythm over a longer period of time. About 2,000 participants got an irregular pulse notification, and an earlier analysis showed that around &lt;a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa1901183"&gt;a third of those people&lt;/a&gt; who then wore an ECG patch had atrial fibrillation show up during that monitoring period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tpZsC6"&gt;This new study looked at the ECG patch data from the remaining participants that &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; have atrial fibrillation detected. “If we didn’t find atrial fibrillation — what did we find?” Perez says. Around 40 percent of those people had some other type of irregular pulse, including premature atrial contractions (extra heartbeats coming from the top of the heart) and premature ventricular contractions (extra heartbeats from the bottom of the heart). “They had a lot of these extra heartbeats,” he says. “Those are things that we pay attention to.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apUjzJ"&gt;Cardiologists still don’t have a good grasp on how dangerous those types of frequent extra heartbeats can be, and often don’t agree on how or if they should be treated, Perez says. They’ve been linked to the development of atrial fibrillation and heart failure, but there isn’t a clear understanding of the best way to manage them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWmqT4"&gt;The study also showed that almost a third of study participants who did not have atrial fibrillation detected on the ECG patch said that they eventually went on to get the condition diagnosed outside of the study. So even if someone doesn’t get a diagnosis on an initial evaluation, it may make sense to keep an eye on them going forward. “We probably have to start thinking about the best strategy for following those patients over time,” Perez says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a63Ifo"&gt;Right now, there’s a wide range of responses to these types of alerts. If someone tells a cardiologist that they had an irregular pulse notification, the doctor might do a quick, 10-second check on an ECG in the office. Other doctors might send them home with a patch for a week. Still others, if there are other factors that make them suspicious, might want to do longer-term monitoring. The technology is still new and the approach is still evolving, Perez says.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IsmnP9"&gt;Additional research will help refine the approach. But for now, this study implies that people who get irregular pulse warnings should keep an eye on their heart health, Perez says. “There might very well be something that is going on that could cause you to have an irregular pulse, and could be a sign of something wrong with your heart.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KY8K5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kmhRf8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702151/apple-watch-heartbeat-irregular-pulse-afib"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702151/apple-watch-heartbeat-irregular-pulse-afib</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T08:43:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T08:43:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Backbone releases free adapter and 3D-print files for iPhone 13 Pro camera bump issue</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BackBone One" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5pTzJYYDGcJV2im_LTmgwbvwrlc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913581/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hk174V"&gt;Backbone Labs has acknowledged the issue that hampers the use of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"&gt;excellent iPhone gaming controller&lt;/a&gt; with the new iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691301/iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-backbone-one-gaming-controller-accessory"&gt;As we noticed last week&lt;/a&gt;, the iPhone 13 Pro’s thicker camera bump means the phone doesn’t sit neatly in the Backbone One controller, either sticking out on one side or causing the bridge on the back to slightly buckle. It’s not unusable, but it’s not great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uV1mXY"&gt;“We spent a tremendous amount of time meticulously crafting every surface of Backbone One (both bits and atoms) and even designing universal support for the iPhones available when it was released,” a Backbone representative wrote in an &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Backbone/comments/pvhl98/backbone_one_iphone_13_pro_pro_max_adapter/"&gt;official post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, we’re disappointed in the situation at hand. Several folks on the team even upgraded to 13 Pro Max for a better gaming experience, and while the fit may be acceptable for some users, it’s not as good as we’d like it to be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WquSRF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Backbone One is a stunning controller that turns your iPhone into a more capable gaming device","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0nAvVr"&gt;To address this, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fplaybackbone.com%2Fadapter%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22695887%2Fbackbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Backbone has designed an adapter&lt;/a&gt; that is intended to improve the experience with the iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. Ordering one will require the latest version of the Backbone app. Once you boot into it, you should see a pop-up that will guide you through the process of ordering one. Otherwise, you can open the app, then go to Settings, find the Help button, then click “Request Adapter.” It’s free to order, but you’ll pay shipping fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZFzsm"&gt;Backbone has also released open-source 3D printable files for the adapter, if you’d prefer to go that route. &lt;a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4977709"&gt;The files are hosted on Thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;. It says on its site that “UPS offers printing services, there are tons of free local printers at libraries, and websites like Shapeways allow you to order prints to your doorstep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwUaUy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 30th, 8:42AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Backbone has added a support page that details the installation process for the iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max adapter. Additionally, it has steps for Backbone One owners, both current and new, to redeem a free adapter or 3D print it themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
