<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-01T10:31:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-01T10:31:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-01T10:31:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can buy an orange Apple HomePod Mini now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KoAQwXDhfahOw3348hXpCyTavFo=/77x0:904x551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70074127/apple_minis.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s HomePod mini is now available in three new colors — orange, yellow, and blue — in addition to white and space gray. | Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dctHY3"&gt;You can now &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/11/homepod-mini-is-available-in-bold-new-colors-starting-today/"&gt;buy Apple’s HomePod Mini in new colors&lt;/a&gt; yellow, orange, and blue (in addition to the standard white and space gray), and &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-homepod/homepod-mini/"&gt;the $99.99 devices&lt;/a&gt; are available for in-store pickup today. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"&gt;announced the new colors at its October Unleashed event&lt;/a&gt;, where it unveiled its new MacBook Pro models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jEne8p"&gt;It’s also where Apple announced its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri"&gt;Apple Music Voice&lt;/a&gt; subscription, a cheaper tier of its music streaming service that you access only via the Siri voice assistant, although there will be a limited app option; it arrives later this year for $4.99 per month and will work with the Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAis36"&gt;The new speakers will have the HomePod mini’s tinted touch surface, fabric mesh, volume icons, and power cable, along with color-matched details. Apple’s competitors already have more colorful options for their small home assistant speakers — Google has blue and orange versions of its Nest Mini speaker, and Amazon’s Echo Dot comes in blue and some animal-themed designs for kids— so it seemed like only a matter of time before Apple caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTbuG8"&gt;You can &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-homepod/homepod-mini/"&gt;order them from Apple’s website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHomePod-mini-Space-Gray%2F159302133&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fapple-homepod-mini-blue%2F5902427.p%3FskuId%3D5902427&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; with pick-ups available as soon as today and delivery dates available for this week, in Canada, Mexico, and the US. In China, Hong Kong, Japan, and Taiwan orders are also opening today, while availability is listed as “later this month” for Australia, Austria, France, Germany, India, Ireland, Italy, New Zealand, Spain, and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22754598/apple-homepod-mini-on-sale-yellow-orange-blue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22754598/apple-homepod-mini-on-sale-yellow-orange-blue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Beats announces Fit Pro earbuds with wing tip design and $200 price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ocF-gwmGtLrClQFPhiePrHWRSns=/0x39:1419x985/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70074042/_BeatsFitPro_4FAM_Lifestyle_0036_WEB_v4.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Beats&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WaG4LB"&gt;Beats today announced its latest wireless earbuds, the $199.99 Beats Fit Pro. The new product slots into the Apple-owned brand’s lineup between the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review"&gt;Studio Buds&lt;/a&gt;, which were released earlier this year, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/10/18563329/apple-powerbeats-pro-review-wireless-fitness-headphones-price"&gt;Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/16/21181088/beats-powerbeats-4-2020-review-wireless-earbuds-fitness-specs-price"&gt;Powerbeats&lt;/a&gt;. The Fit Pros have active noise cancellation, IPX4 water and sweat resistance, and up to seven hours of continuous playback (or 30 hours of total listening when you include case recharges).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xpgqYB"&gt;The most noticeable thing about the new earbuds are the wing tips that are a permanent part of their design. Beats says it did a ton of research and user testing to land on the right material and level of flexibility. The wing tips are intended to help the Fit Pros stay locked in your ears no matter how strenuous your workout routine might be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8nmQN76TlgSQxMzVwRK0kdTCUE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22975264/file.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Beats&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Beats Fit Pro earbuds have flexible, removable wing tips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tidHHI"&gt;Unlike the Studio Buds, which lacked Apple’s usual silicon inside, the Fit Pro buds include the H1 chip and thus come with the entire suite of features like one-step pairing, automatic syncing across your iCloud devices, auto switching between Apple hardware products, and more. They also include dynamic head tracking for spatial audio, and Beats even integrated the brand-new skin detect sensor that only just debuted on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;third-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="r3zqvK"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KZZB-QSsEFg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iHlMY1"&gt;The noise cancellation system is essentially the same as what’s on the AirPods Pro, so it should prove rather effective at quieting the outside world. When ANC and transparency mode are both off, the Fit Pro buds still use Apple’s Adaptive EQ to optimize audio performance based on your particular ear shape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIOOFO"&gt;Beats will offer the Fit Pro earbuds in four colors: black, white, gray, and purple / pink. Preorders start today and they ship on November 5th. You don’t need to wait long to read the verdict on the latest Beats buds: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22517199"&gt;I’ve been testing them for several days now&lt;/a&gt; and have found that they’re the company’s best, most focused product since the Powerbeats Pro. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22753187/beats-fit-pro-announced-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22753187/beats-fit-pro-announced-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Beats Fit Pro review: sporty AirPod Pros with better sound</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The latest Beats earbuds are the company’s best product since the Powerbeats Pro&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="nDxaBa"&gt;Beats has been busy. After releasing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review"&gt;Studio Buds&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, today the Apple-owned brand is back with the more premium Beats Fit Pro wireless earbuds. It’s unusual to see two completely new products from Beats in a single year, but perhaps the company is trying to make a point that it’s not idly sitting by and playing second fiddle to Apple’s AirPods and AirPods Pro. If anything, the $200 Fit Pros demonstrate that Beats has found its focus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O44goa"&gt;The Fit Pros are a wonderfully designed pair of earbuds that integrate the best of Apple tech. They’ve got active noise cancellation that’s on par with the AirPods Pro. The same spatial audio with dynamic head tracking. The same Adaptive EQ. They even have the brand-new skin detect sensor that only just debuted in the third-generation AirPods. There’ve been many questions about where Beats fits into Apple’s long-term plans, and while a single product can’t really provide an answer to that, the Fit Pros are solid evidence that this brand isn’t being pushed to the wayside anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8cPj7p"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10835161"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VQ9YjT"&gt;When I reviewed the Studio Buds, I praised their ambition and Beats’ attempt to cater to Android users as much as iPhone owners. But despite their great comfort, good sound, and compact design, those earbuds had some key missing features and fell a bit flat on execution. Not so with the Beats Fit Pros. They’re exactly what you’d want them to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CXEoWH"&gt;These are the best earbuds Beats has ever made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ro362AyFIV-Gne_F-Aom3OwEGKQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973215/DSCF6033_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Beats Fit Pro earbuds have a permanent wing tip as part of their design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9iFJoD"&gt;As Beats explains it, the Fit Pros are meant to fill a gap in its lineup between the Studio Buds and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/16/21181088/beats-powerbeats-4-2020-review-wireless-earbuds-fitness-specs-price"&gt;Powerbeats&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/10/18563329/apple-powerbeats-pro-review-wireless-fitness-headphones-price"&gt;Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Their wing tips make them more gym-ready than the Studio Buds, but they don’t go as far as including the Powerbeats’ signature hooks that wrap around your ears. I have marathon runner friends who swear by the ear hooks and say nothing comes close to that stability for vigorous activity. But Beats thinks it has found a great alternative with the Fit Pros — all in a design that’s much more compact, lightweight, and comfortable than the Powerbeats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8gtNz"&gt;The Fit Pros come in a case that’s basically a miniaturized version of the Powerbeats Pro case. Just as with those, there’s no wireless charging — a very frustrating omission at this price — but the case at least uses USB-C instead of Lightning. A longstanding gripe with the Powerbeats Pro is they can be finicky with charging unless you place them in the case just right. Their ear hooks make it easy to get this wrong, and on many occasions I’ve gone to use them only to find one earbud fully charged and the other completely drained. I’m happy to say this isn’t something you need to fret about with the Fit Pros: each earbud drops into its cradle with a reassuring magnetic pull and I’ve experienced zero charging mishaps. The lid has a little more play than I’d like, but I can be nitpicky about that sort of thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="we1gy2"&gt;As for the buds themselves, they’ve got a unique look thanks to their permanent, curved wing tips. Beats is selling them in black, gray, white, and a pinkish purple. The gray and purple have gotten the best feedback among &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff. At 5.6 grams per earbud, they weigh in slightly heavier than the AirPods Pro but lighter than some fitness-geared buds like the Jaybird Vista 2s. The new Jabra Elite 7 Active buds are a hair lighter at 5.5 grams. Regardless, the Beats are extremely comfortable and also have microventing to alleviate ear pressure buildup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5cfhDDBbzE9rbvau1NyEFEQBC4c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973216/DSCF6032_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;They’re designed for a secure, stable fit during active use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BfmCQi"&gt;Beats is very proud of how much it crammed into the Fit Pros, which have the company’s smallest enclosure yet — not counting the wing tips, obviously. They contain 30 percent more components than the Studio Buds and the transducer is 15 percent larger. Three sizes of silicone ear tips come in the box, along with a short USB-C cable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SwNfcA"&gt;But what about those wing tips? They’re meant to help the earbuds stay put. But I’ve found that on some earbuds, like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aMKgWMO3fu8"&gt;the second-gen Pixel Buds&lt;/a&gt;, these wing tips and numbs can cause discomfort the longer you wear them, so there’s definitely a risk in Beats making them a permanent part of the design. But the company says it sweated the details over the wing’s shape and material. And after several days spent testing the Fit Pros — often for several hours at a time — I haven’t noticed any soreness. The wing tip is flexible and pliable enough that it doesn’t press into the concha of your ear in an annoying way. You’ll feel it there during extended listening, don’t get me wrong, but at most it produces a little itchiness instead of more serious irritation. And you can alleviate that just by adjusting the earbuds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rqULYd7Vneck60NRlyx1aucD5Hc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973267/DSCF6021_Edited_2.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The charging case disappointingly lacks wireless charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Syd1jUW8K0nbniLo10_UbyMk_2o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973219/DSCF6026_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;But it’s much smaller and more pocketable than the Powerbeats Pro case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S5XkUB"&gt;Beats says it designed the wing tips for “every ear imaginable,” but ears are all different, and there will always be exceptions. That said, I let several people try the Fit Pros and even those with small ears could find a way to make the wing tip work for them and said it resulted in a more steady overall fit. They passed the gym test and didn’t come even slightly loose during high intensity runs. They also stayed in while eating, something that’s a challenge for many earbuds. The Fit Pros are rated IPX4 for water and sweat resistance, which is adequate for workout purposes, but below the IP57 of Jabra’s latest active buds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbL4uu"&gt;Like the Studio Buds, these have a nice and clicky “b” button on each earbud with the usual control scheme: press once to play / pause / answer call, twice to skip to the next track, and three times to go back. But there’s one interesting tidbit: for the first time, you can remap a long press to adjust volume instead of toggling noise cancellation or summoning Siri. This can be done right in the iOS settings menu and is something that the AirPods Pro can’t do, nor can the Beats Studio Buds. I like having the option, even if I ended up sticking with the defaults. Bring that remapping capability to your other earbuds, Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88pUIZ"&gt;Beats has outfitted its latest earbuds with 9.5mm drivers, and they produce very satisfying sound quality that I’d rank above the AirPods Pro. This isn’t the bloated bass Beats of old: the company shed that reputation quite a long time ago. The Fit Pro buds might have slightly less overall boom and oomph than the Powerbeats Pros, in fact, but switching back and forth between the two, it was close — and I preferred the more refined sound of the newer buds. If there’s one weakness I’ve noticed, it’s maximum volume. The Fit Pros seem to have a lower volume ceiling than some of their competitors, so if you tend to crank things up for motivation during a run or fitness routine, you might be underwhelmed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ptNyqVVjvt3IM3On3kkY-q2tLvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973260/DSCF6027_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fit Pros also come in black or white.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I5DKkh"&gt;Unlike the Studio Buds, which didn’t have Apple’s usual earbud chipset inside, the Fit Pros have the H1 and all the features that come along with that. The main benefits are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SUW64G"&gt;Dynamic head tracking for spatial audio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7PiN2B"&gt;Automatic device switching between iPhone, iPad, and Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ks3YKH"&gt;Automatic syncing with all of your iCloud devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JVHpWj"&gt;Audio sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B1kp8M"&gt;Find My integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ek848h"&gt;Hands-free “Hey Siri” voice commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="JFeJdA"&gt;Beats notes that a lot of other functionality — ANC, transparency mode, one-step setup, Apple Music spatial audio (minus head tracking) — works just as well on Android as on iOS. You’ll need the Beats app for some things like control customization and more detailed battery status. The Studio Buds supported Android’s native Fast Pair feature, but the Fit Pros do not. That’s not surprising considering there’s once again Apple silicon inside. But it means that there’s an extra layer of seamlessness when using the Fit Pros within Apple’s ecosystem. You can get most of the way there on Android, but not quite. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LodQQX"&gt;As I mentioned earlier, the Fit Pros essentially have the same noise cancellation system as the AirPods Pro — also powered by the H1 chip. Performance between the two is more or less identical, and transparency mode sounds natural here in the same way it does on the Pros (with the same sound effects as you switch between modes). When ANC is off, Beats refers to this as “Adaptive EQ” mode. That’s where you’ll get the best battery life: seven hours of continuous playback and up to 30 hours including case recharges. Using ANC or transparency drops those figures to six hours and 27 hours, respectively, so you’re not losing much no matter how you’re using the buds. Beats says you’ll get an hour of playback (with ANC) from a quick five-minute top off, and fully recharging both earbuds and the case takes around 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GwSNeI81-knRJSxigKLlbqVaLcY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973283/DSCF6031.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The wing tips rarely cause any discomfort.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zeFH6b"&gt;The Fit Pro buds also include Apple’s new skin detect sensor, first seen in the latest AirPods, for more accurate automatic play / pause when removed from your ears. This sensor can tell the difference between skin and other tight confines like pant pockets, so the earbuds are less likely to resume playing when you don’t want them to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t0axW5"&gt;Voice call performance is quite good but falls short of the AirPods. If you’re wearing one of the earbuds alone, three mics are used for voice calls. When both earbuds are in use, the voice system leverages five mics. The Fit Pros utilize beamforming mics and voice detection algorithms to help isolate your voice from background commotion. My co-workers heard me loud and clear on Zoom calls, and people I chatted with on the phone said I sounded fine, if slightly less pronounced as when using the AirPods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="8auFU5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10838399"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ggRvHJ"&gt;The Fit Pros successfully thread the needle between everyday and fitness-focused earbuds. They’re objectively a better choice than the AirPods Pro for workouts and running, and they handle more casual listening equally as well. They improve upon the lackluster noise cancellation that dragged down the Studio Buds, and they restore Apple’s full arsenal of ecosystem tricks. They also bring back features that Beats left out last time like in-ear detection. Making wing tips part of the core design was a gamble, and there will no doubt be cases where that decision causes issues for some people. All I can say is these are among the most comfortable wing tips I’ve ever had in my ears — and they succeed at their purpose of keeping the Fit Pros locked in place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ink9Ul"&gt;If you already own a set of AirPods or bought the Studio Buds earlier this year, these aren’t a must have. But if you’ve been searching for something worthy of replacing your Powerbeats Pro, the Beats Fit Pro might just be the ticket. They’re the sporty AirPod Pros a lot of people have been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1he22u"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-01T09:55:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-01T09:55:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use iPhone’s location tracking </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/leEXkTb0hpgtXR8qvSk-3L4t47o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69871891/akrales_190913_3628_0277.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TeBzxN"&gt;Your iPhone uses information from your cell service, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and GPS to pinpoint its location, and since you almost always have your phone on you, your location as well. That information can be useful for a lot of things, such as letting others know where you are or finding your phone when it’s lost. Other times, it’s just more data that services and companies collect about you, creating privacy concerns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G2rbnr"&gt;The good news is you can tighten your controls so that apps are only accessing your location when it’s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PGeN94"&gt;Toggling your location settings can differ from phone to phone, depending on what model of iPhone you have and what version of iOS it’s running. The following directions were tested on an iPhone 11 running iOS 15; if you’re running a different version of iOS, there shouldn’t be much difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nJYdGZ"&gt;Turn off location access for specific apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2bachq"&gt;Location data is useful for some apps (for example, if you want to order food) and necessary for others, like maps or ride-shares. However, if an app asks for your location and you don’t feel it needs the data, you can disable location services for that app. Here’s how to do that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="10QMkI"&gt;Open Settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yjxmeM"&gt;Go to “Privacy” &amp;gt; “Location Services.”  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XXWXWw"&gt;“Location Services” will most likely be switched on. Unless you want to completely cut all location services off (see below), leave it alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qwmyHl"&gt;Scroll down to find a list of all the apps that enable location services. Each listing will show the app’s name and the type of permission it has: “Never,” “When Shared,” or “While Using.” “When Shared” refers to the option “Ask Next Time Or When I Share.” Meanwhile, “While Using” will usually mean “While using the App,” but it can sometimes also refer to “While Using the App or Widgets.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="APxPyw"&gt;If you want to change a specific app’s access to your location data, click on the app listing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can adjust location services for specific apps." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zSpH0kbFBBPq3Pdd52RfatmGL9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857412/IMG_13B4445EF110_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can adjust location services for specific apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="How you can allow location access depends on the app." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BpBbvHInOumIiH0y2cORf5Nv3bw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857413/IMG_6D2F84330D37_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;How you can allow location access depends on the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0xJQiW"&gt;If you click “While Using the App,” then that app will have access to your location either when it’s open or when it’s in use in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O4mvxq"&gt;For more ways to limit location access, click on “System Services” at the bottom of the “Location Services” screen. Here, you can toggle location access for a number of things, including Wi-Fi, time zone, emergency calls, and Apple News and App Store ads that are relevant to your location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YugSqN"&gt;To the left of some of the service toggles, you may see a small arrow. A hollow arrow means the item may have access to your location under certain conditions; a purple arrow means the item has recently used your location, while a gray arrow means it used your location sometime in the last 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="For more ways to limit location access, click on “System Services.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1BI4ULPUOLpp4D6EXdpLY1UeSoU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857589/IMG_11AB5BCB37D6_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more ways to limit location access, click on “System Services.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Arrows show which apps are accessing your location." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M0NqNW6ZvUftQBR3XzifVQDNuOs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857582/IMG_4283119948D6_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arrows show which apps are accessing your location.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f9PkYM"&gt;To check whether your phone is still collecting location data, go down to the very bottom of the “System Services” screen and toggle the switch on for “Status Bar Icon.” This will display an arrow at the top of your screen when an app on your phone is accessing your location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pvTXrC"&gt;If you want to truly go off the grid, you can disable location services to prevent your phone from collecting any location data at all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="r8HSiU"&gt;Open Settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hknF2h"&gt;Go to “Privacy” &amp;gt; “Location Services.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4s36Y6"&gt;Toggle the “Location Services” switch to off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="affITu"&gt;You’ll get a notice telling you that, while Location Services will be disabled for all apps, it will temporarily come online if you use the “Find My iPhone” and report your phone lost. Select “Turn Off.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CcJJeH"&gt;If you have an iPhone 11 or later&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NSGXGW"&gt;If you have a phone designed with Apple’s U1 chip — such as an iPhone 11 or later — and have disabled location services for specific apps, you may find that you still sometimes see the arrow. According to Apple, this is because these models &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20997338/apple-ultra-wideband-u1-chip-iphone-11-pro-location-data-request-privacy-issue"&gt;use ultra wideband technology&lt;/a&gt;, which Apple says is regulated, so the phones use location services to determine if they’re in an area where ultra wideband use is restricted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwciFf"&gt;The iPhone requests location data when location preferences are set on an app-per-app basis, so switching off location services for your phone overall will stop these location requests since your phone won’t be able to collect any location data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0BmHZV"&gt;Share your location with individuals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AvJ5VO"&gt;If you’re walking alone at night or you’re in an Uber by yourself, you might want a friend or family member to know your location in real time. If you have iOS 13 or later, you can use the Find My app to share your location with family and friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yd7T8R"&gt;Open “Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qRKhHK"&gt;Go into “Privacy,” and make sure “Location Services” is switched on. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZS7j0A"&gt;Go back to the main “Settings” menu and tap on your name at the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wO93M2"&gt;Select “Find My.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ADpOmK"&gt;Toggle “Share My Location” so that it’s on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aajRcv"&gt;Then go to the Find My app. If this is your first time using the app, it will ask you whether you want it to access your location. Choose either to “Allow While Using App,” “Allow Once,” or “Don’t Allow.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EP4LB6"&gt;You may get a screen explaining that “Find My” can be used with an AirTag or for AirPods, and that there are apps for the watchOS as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C2oZkD"&gt;On the map screen that appears, select “People” at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TJymR1"&gt;Click the button that says “Start Sharing Location.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="poO8DJ"&gt;In the “To:” field, type in either the phone number or name of your friend or family member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MMwj9E"&gt;If the person you select has a phone number that isn’t associated with an iPhone, you’ll be notified with a pop-up. (But you can still share your location.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v9RYlu"&gt;Tap “Send,” then select either “Share for One Hour,” “Share Until End of Day,” or “Share Indefinitely.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Find My app lets you share your location." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IoCeKInZlvEqdEYDXrfO3-0j4qs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857616/IMG_425BFDC7C40D_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Find My app lets you share your location.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select “Start Sharing Location” and choose whom you want to share it with." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FDV8vATBkeqsU6AiIwFDxv73JN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22857538/IMG_80499A0AC888_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select “Start Sharing Location” and choose whom you want to share it with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OLskUW"&gt;It will then start sharing your location. In order to switch it off, click on your contact’s name in the “Find My” app under “People,” then tap “Stop Sharing My Location.” Confirm by clicking on the “Stop Sharing Location” button that pops up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MaDFmh"&gt;(Note: For some reason, the “Share Until End of Day” selection seems to always select midnight Pacific Time rather than the end of day local time. For example, I’m on Eastern Time, and so “end of day” is always somewhere around 3AM. I’ve reached out to Apple to find out if they have a fix for this and will let you know if / when I hear back.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YX8aIT"&gt;Send recurring notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="alLgD7"&gt;You can have your phone send out recurring notifications as well. These are useful if you want your friend or relative to know when a you get to a location (or don’t get there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4aqISQ"&gt;In the “Find My” app, tap the “People” tab at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ikQYZL"&gt;Select the person you want to send notifications to (it should be somebody you’re already sharing your location with).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Oj16lY"&gt;Scroll down until you see “Notifications” and tab “Add.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4QBnWx"&gt;A pop-up from the bottom will give you the option to notify that person. Select it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="TzQf1e"&gt;You can notify the person when you arrive at or leave a specific location, and send the notification just once or every time you arrive or leave (for example, if you want to let somebody know every day when you get home from work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KY2bKD"&gt;Share via Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uB02dt"&gt;You can share your location through Messages as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LrbY2N"&gt;Open a conversation in Messages. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VCb4XE"&gt;Tap on the contact name and then click “Info.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="25EDCT"&gt;This will give you the option to “Share My Location,” which will give you the option to “Share for One Hour,” “Share Until End of Day,” or “Share Indefinitely.” Click one of those to start sharing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ScUruo"&gt;If you want to stop sharing, click “Stop Sharing My Location” where “Share My Location” was. A button labeled “Stop Sharing My Location” will pop up. Click on that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="KqQCyG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 17th, 2021, 10:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on December 12th, 2019, and has been updated to account for differences in iOS and in available services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YMjTmG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 1st, 2021 9:45AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note was added explaining “Share Until End of Day” always assumes you’re on Pacific Time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22676312/ios-iphone-apple-location-tracking-turn-off-on"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22676312/ios-iphone-apple-location-tracking-turn-off-on</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aliya Chaudhry</name>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-31T18:13:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-31T18:13:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s app tracking policy reportedly cost social media platforms nearly $10 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ODq4yfj5scuSF17cA4aH0w65c7I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70072075/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hoTDKd"&gt;An investigation by &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4c19e387-ee1a-41d8-8dd2-bc6c302ee58e"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found that Snapchat, Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube lost around $9.85 billion in revenue following Apple’s changes to its privacy practices. Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22179721/apple-defends-upcoming-privacy-changes-standing-up-for-users-facebook-data"&gt;Apple announced the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) policy&lt;/a&gt; that requires apps to ask permission to track users’ data. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;policy went into effect in April&lt;/a&gt;, barring apps from tracking users if they opt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MoOi1y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178068/facebook-apple-newspaper-ads-ios-privacy-changes"&gt;Facebook notably criticized the move with a full-page newspaper ad&lt;/a&gt;, and thanks to the &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;’s report, now we know why company leaders were so frustrated. According to the report, Facebook lost the most money “in absolute terms” when compared to other social platforms due to its massive size. Meanwhile, Snap “fared the worst as a percentage of its business” because its advertising is mainly tied to smartphones, which makes sense for a product that doesn’t have a desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sje4f6"&gt;“Some of the platforms that were most impacted — but especially Facebook — have to rebuild their machinery from scratch as a result of ATT,” adtech consultant Eric Seufert told &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;. “My belief is that it takes at least one year to build new infrastructure. New tools and frameworks need to be developed from scratch and tested extensively before being deployed to a high number of users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ahNYi"&gt;Apple’s new policy will force social platforms and other apps to get more creative with their advertising. Whether this means focusing on Android devices or investing in Apple’s advertising business — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654121/apple-personalized-ads-ios-15-prompt-app-tracking"&gt;which nearly broke its own rules&lt;/a&gt; by quietly collecting user data in the same way third-party apps did —  they’ll have to figure out another source of revenue that doesn’t involve tracking people on their iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hKAdRK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k5ZxYO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22756135/apple-app-tracking-transparency-policy-snapchat-facebook-twitter-youtube-lose-10-billion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22756135/apple-app-tracking-transparency-policy-snapchat-facebook-twitter-youtube-lose-10-billion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-31T13:41:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-31T13:41:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: The Wheel of Time, The Witcher, Lightyear, House of Gucci, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cewKpItAR-wkhYlwNAx5kLx4woI=/204x0:1089x590/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70071195/wheelotime.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Rosamund Pike stars in The Wheel of Time | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=11ZozKfRqvA&amp;amp;ab_channel=AmazonPrimeVideo" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Prime Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zfaWAk"&gt;I’m close to giving up on &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show&lt;/em&gt;; the latest episode spends a lot of time building up to a twist that makes very little sense given the season so far. They only have three episodes left and a lot of plot to push forward. Luckily, &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt; is getting good and juicy with the Roy siblings choosing sides, and I’m also getting caught up in &lt;em&gt;Maid&lt;/em&gt;, mainly because of Margaret Qualley’s strong performance as Alex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lj9744"&gt;So much to watch, so little time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAZ0Mi"&gt;We’re heavy into the sci-fi and fantasy realms in this week’s roundup, but there’s a little fashion and murder-mystery as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XgKrS7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/11ZozKfRqvA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="x9cdzq"&gt;The Wheel of Time &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="gPYLDh"&gt;We’ve seen a few glimpses of&lt;em&gt; The Wheel of Time&lt;/em&gt; series based on the books by Robert Jordan, but this latest trailer shows us the beginning of the story, with Moiraine Damodred of the Aes Sedai trying to figure out how to stop the Dark One. She finds five magic using people she thinks could be the key (or keys) to saving the world (whether they’re up for it or not). Rosamund Pike, Daniel Henney, Josha Stradowski, Marcus Rutherford, and Zoe Robins star in &lt;em&gt;The Wheel of Time,&lt;/em&gt; which drops the first episode of its eight-episode season on Amazon Prime Video November 19th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hk16bQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: You can watch this trailer as a “360 experience” (I didn’t think it really added a lot here, though)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QZUAXf"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WX6e6ZLNmtA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tptg94"&gt;The Witcher&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="nromUq"&gt;We’ve seen a few &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570627/the-witcher-season-two-teaser-trailer-netflix-henry-cavill"&gt;teasers&lt;/a&gt; and sneak &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22462967/the-witcher-season-2-trailer-netflix-geeked-week"&gt;peeks&lt;/a&gt; and first-look &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22691354/witcher-season-2-blood-origin-trailer-teaser-watch-premiere-date-netflix"&gt;clips&lt;/a&gt; from the second season of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; and now we have a full-length trailer with some juicy details about what’s next for Geralt of Rivia and company. War with the Nilfgaardian Empire is looming, along with the possible “end of days” (which Geralt scoffs at), Geralt is hunting enormous monsters, and Ciri is tapping in to her powers while Jaskier is befriending some small rodents (rats? mice? something else entirely?). Henry Cavill, Freya Allen, Anya Chalotra, Joey Batey, Anna Shaffer, and Kim Bodnia star in season 2 of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;, coming to Netflix December 17th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JOrHoq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BwPL0Md_QFQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Y3IoJ4"&gt;Lightyear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HbroDw"&gt;At last, a Pixar movie that doesn’t immediately look like it will tear the hearts out of parents (honestly, I am still traumatized by &lt;em&gt;Inside Out&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Toy Story 3&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;Lightyear&lt;/em&gt; is the backstory of the “real” astronaut on whom the the Buzz Lightyear action figure from &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;/em&gt; is based. The teaser shows what looks like a familiar space exploration adventure, with the requisite aliens and spaceships, and Chris Evans provides the hero’s voice. &lt;em&gt;Lightyear&lt;/em&gt; will be released June 17th, 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yZ8vMx"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eGNnpVKxV6s?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xyMnmc"&gt;House of Gucci&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rrcHc8"&gt;We have a second trailer for the movie about the Gucci family starring Lady Gaga, and of course everyone looks fabulous and beautiful, even though the “Italian” accents from the lead actors are... a little off? Based on the book by Sara Gay Forden, &lt;em&gt;House of Gucci&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of Patrizia Reggiani’s marriage to Maurizio Gucci (Adam Driver), and her plot to hire an assassin to kill him. Jared Leto, Al Pacino, Jeremy Irons, and Salma Hayek also star in &lt;em&gt;House of Gucci &lt;/em&gt;which arrives in theaters November 24th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uFQHhE"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c_h6DQWE2Mk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aBfFKD"&gt;Servant &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="BF1ATL"&gt;Look, you can only show me so many long, ominous, darkly-lit hallways before the trick gets old. In its first season this show had promise (and Lauren Ambrose gives a tremendous performance as Dorothy), but by season three it defies logic (and is beyond sadistic) that Dorothy’s family would continue to hide from her the truth about what happened to her baby. Maybe they’ll finally do the ethical thing. But now, apparently, the show is more interested in the cult that nanny Leanne (the servant of the show’s title) escaped from. If you’re still hoping for an M. Night Shyamalan plot twist, you can check out season three of &lt;em&gt;Servant&lt;/em&gt; on Apple Plus TV starting January 21st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldIe5z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qp16VV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hMRMN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22752499/new-trailers-wheel-of-time-witcher-lightyear-house-of-gucci-netflix-amazon-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22752499/new-trailers-wheel-of-time-witcher-lightyear-house-of-gucci-netflix-amazon-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-31T10:40:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-31T10:40:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple quietly discontinues the 21.5-inch Intel-powered iMac</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple iMac Hardware Shoot" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mGhr4ZKcZLQ1TaMzQ6tvZW3Xtp4=/0x3:7345x4900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70070602/1065384720.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Olly Curtis/MacFormat Magazine/Future via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EEA47d"&gt;Apple has apparently pulled its 21.5-inch Intel-based iMac from shelves (via &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/30/apple-discontinues-intel-based-21-5-inch-imac/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Its discontinuation doesn’t come as much of a surprise, now that Apple is transitioning from using Intel processors to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;in-house M1 chip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aha88K"&gt;The 21.5-inch iMac was still available after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"&gt;Apple’s October 18th Unleashed event&lt;/a&gt; — it didn’t appear to go missing until sometime this week, according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;. The $1,099 21.5-inch iMac, which came with a 2.3GHz dual-core 7th-Gen Intel Core i5 and an Intel Iris Plus Graphics 640, is no longer found on the list of available iMacs on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/imac-imac"&gt;Apple’s online store&lt;/a&gt;. A “Buy” button also doesn’t appear for the 21.5-inch iMac on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/mac/compare/"&gt;Apple’s product comparison&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kq2X6M"&gt;We reached out to Apple to confirm the changes, but didn’t immediately receive a response. However, the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors &lt;/em&gt;that the machine is being discontinued and won’t be sold through Apple’s online store or in its retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iMac 21.5-inch no Buy button" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b9iluU0J1oDkmKKq_-1Bf_NdmA4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22972383/imac_21_5_inch_apple_store.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XxhHmI"&gt;Apple hasn’t eliminated its entire lineup of Intel-based iMacs just yet — it’s still selling &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/imac-imac"&gt;the 27-inch Intel-based iMac&lt;/a&gt;, which sports up to a 3.6GHz 10-core Intel Core i9 CPU, at a starting price of $1799.99. As &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; notes, you can still purchase &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/30/apple-discontinues-intel-based-21-5-inch-imac/"&gt;a refurbished 21.5-inch iMac&lt;/a&gt; from Apple’s online store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="arlcCG"&gt;In March, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22341882/apple-discontinuing-21-5-inch-imac"&gt;Apple discontinued the 512GB and 1TB configurations&lt;/a&gt; of the 21.5-inch iMac, so the company has been slowly phasing out this model for a while. And since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Apple debuted its thinner, more colorful M1-powered iMacs in April&lt;/a&gt;, it only makes sense for Apple to clear some space on its shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5cMcUQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22755641/apple-pulls-21-inch-intel-powered-imac"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22755641/apple-pulls-21-inch-intel-powered-imac</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-31T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-31T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mac-shaped pillow makers are back so you can cover your couch in computers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kidsmGdfuAQnzGLmB446m_LV7xM=/0x29:680x482/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70070303/9a7f391962bd6d6325579b959c662279_original.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Throwboy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MbSbzA"&gt;A company called Throwboy is &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/throwboy/the-iconic-pillow-collection-2-by-throwboy/description"&gt;back with another Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; for a collection of pillows shaped like classic Macs, following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/8/18/17715884/throwboy-pillow-retro-macintosh-imac-iphone-ipod-nostalgia"&gt;its 2018 line of Apple-inspired plushes&lt;/a&gt;. It’s fittingly called The Iconic Pillow Collection 2, and features pillows shaped like soft versions of Apple’s Lisa, iBook, and both the cheese grater and cube flavors of Power Mac. For Apple history buffs who want to spruce up their living or bedrooms, it may be a campaign worth investigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xB3tvA"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/throwboy/the-iconic-pillow-collection-by-throwboy/description"&gt;its original collection&lt;/a&gt; (which featured pillows shaped like the Finder icon, original Macintosh, and iPods), Throwboy tactfully didn’t mention specific computer names, and it refrained from doing so this time around as well. The Lisa-shaped pillow is called the 1983, the iMac G4-esque one is branded the 2002, and so on. On its Kickstarter page, the company says it picked these specific computers because they were “swing for the fences” designs that people still love.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UM30jdXoFIM2OI-BVvNAt1qCRhQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22968405/d6c64d48dd1df102720c22a37e137832_original.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Throwboy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: a (hopefully) safe naming scheme.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TCp80r"&gt;Truly, there are some stunning designs on display in this Kickstarter. I’m pretty sure I haven’t seen a laptop-shaped pillow like the 1999, and I’m &lt;em&gt;very &lt;/em&gt;sure I’ve never seen an iMac G4-shaped pillow. It’s unclear how comfortable these pillows will be on a couch, or if they’ll hold up in a pillow fight (though I already want to wield the 2002 like I’m Darth Mac), but as conversation starters they’d be hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="ljol61"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1523637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PNym5z"&gt;That’s not even mentioning the ports — yes, at the same time Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"&gt;adding back HDMI and MagSafe back to its real laptops&lt;/a&gt;, Throwboy has gone and added port-shaped stitching to Apple-shaped pillows. I’d say more about how much this fills me with joy, but I think I’ll let the pictures say hello for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/461ynHXR66vvKOB5VQyACkM4x0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22968408/acb9cf6f6c229217ceae429182702802_original.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Throwboy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah, but does your pillow have FireWire?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8YBYUs0eBSsC2-PPtsvE13ht2ok=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22968409/440e63f486ee465a06bbde69888b5321_original.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Throwboy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the only time a keyboard feeling pillowy is a good thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pUMCjw"&gt;While Throwboy’s Kickstarter campaign for the original Iconic collection appears to be successful (&lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/throwboy/the-iconic-pillow-collection-by-throwboy/comments"&gt;the comments&lt;/a&gt; are largely filled with people who received and are happy with their pillows, and you can buy them &lt;a href="https://throwboy.com/collections/throwboy-pillows"&gt;on Throwboy’s website&lt;/a&gt;), it’s always worth proceeding with caution when it comes to crowdfunding. Projects, even from successful creators, can run late, turn out different than expected, or even get cancelled for one reason or another. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NMwdAc"&gt;If that’s a risk you’re willing to take (and it apparently is for a lot of people; the project met its $10,000 goal in its first day), these &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/throwboy/the-iconic-pillow-collection-2-by-throwboy/description"&gt;are some extremely fun pillow designs&lt;/a&gt; if you’re in the market for some Apple-themed home decor.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22753620/mac-apple-plush-pillow-computer-kickstarter-ibook-power-mac-lisa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22753620/mac-apple-plush-pillow-computer-kickstarter-ibook-power-mac-lisa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T18:04:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T18:04:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Facebook goes meta and reviews of the Pixel 6 and MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Igz9YvL8AHurUZ0VNWVkPp4-v5Y=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70065057/verge_vjeran_pavic_meta_3_20211028_3000.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bGeO9G"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BdVvk"&gt;This week on &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast,&lt;/em&gt; managing editor Alex Cranz (that’s me), deputy editor Dan Seifert (that’s not me), and senior reporter Alex Heath (also not me) join Nilay and Dieter to talk about Facebook’s big rebranding, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753184/ifixit-apple-polishing-cloth-19-repair-backorder"&gt;expensive polishing cloths&lt;/a&gt;, our reviews of the Pixel 6, Pixel 6 Pro, and both flavors of the new MacBook Pro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XEKUEK"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP2933149148&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LkN8ED"&gt;You can listen here or in your preferred podcast player for the full discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="NGxouO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22749919/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-meta-company-rebrand"&gt;Mark Zuckerberg on why Facebook is rebranding to Meta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3vvVZU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;Facebook’s new name is Meta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dc1sE1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;What is the metaverse, and do I have to care?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="H3LUCs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751220/facebook-portal-oculus-quest-meta-horizon-renaming"&gt;Facebook’s Oculus Quest will soon be called the Meta Quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="x8T0wr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750569/facebook-oculus-horizon-home-social-vr-space-connect"&gt;Oculus users are getting a new metaverse home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ANZe4y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749567/facebook-presence-platform-oculus-quest-mixed-reality-api"&gt;Facebook is adding a mixed reality platform to Oculus Quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NRXgyT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749008/facebook-oculus-project-cambria-pro-vr-ar-headset"&gt;Facebook teases ‘Project Cambria’ high-end VR / AR headset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7UL2L8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751177/facebook-meta-codec-avatar-real-time-environment-rendering-neural-interface"&gt;Amid the fluff, Meta showed an impressive demo of its Codec Avatars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6xyJ2C"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22740969/facebook-files-papers-frances-haugen-whistleblower-civic-integrity"&gt;Eight things we learned from the Facebook Papers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ha26gU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22740969/facebook-files-papers-frances-haugen-whistleblower-civic-integrity"&gt;Facebook’s lost generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2laHIC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22745622/facebook-young-adults-refocusing-teams"&gt;Facebook says it’s refocusing company on ‘serving young adults’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vgCrjP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"&gt;Google Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro review: finally, more than just good cameras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OL1b5I"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747834/google-pixel-6-pro-android-12-launch-update"&gt;The Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro will arrive with a day-one update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="K3JfxQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747271/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-chips-hybrid-architecture-price-release-date-i9-12900k"&gt;Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake chips usher in a new generation of …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cAZIvQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22745670/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2021-review-usb-c-signature-edition-display-e-reader-books"&gt;Amazon Kindle Paperwhite (2021) review: a bigger and better ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rz9WbS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;Apple AirPods (third-gen) review: new design, same appeal &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UReEfS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22738125/adobe-photoshop-illustrator-web-announced"&gt;Adobe brings a simplified Photoshop to the web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U2IW4O"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22745552/sony-xperia-pro-i-camera-first-smartphone-second-andriod-mobile-5g"&gt;Sony Xperia Pro-I: A camera first, phone second &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qrg42y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747063/samsung-cloud-gaming-service-tizen-tv-announcement"&gt;Samsung announces cloud gaming for Tizen TVs, offers no further details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="WWVVKw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753317/vergecast-facebook-meta-pixel-6-macbook-pro-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753317/vergecast-facebook-meta-pixel-6-macbook-pro-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T17:09:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T17:09:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>iFixit actually tore down Apple’s backordered $19 screen cloth</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X9235Iq9RFn0msZiVqbVb_uj64c=/0x319:6899x4918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70064814/finallayout.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: iFixit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9ZkUv0"&gt;I can’t say I expected there to be more news about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices"&gt;Apple’s $19 Screen Polishing cloth&lt;/a&gt;, but here we are. Not only has iFixit given it the teardown treatment and a (perhaps slightly tongue-in-cheek) repair score, but it’s apparently become one of Apple’s hardest-to-get products. And yes, to reiterate, we are still talking about a cloth made to clean your devices’ screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x42ohl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/29/technology/apple-polishing-cloth.html"&gt;As noted by &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the 6.3-inch-sided square of fabric is now backordered, with Apple’s website saying that you won’t get it for 10-12 &lt;em&gt;weeks&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;meaning it’ll get delivered sometime between January 7th and January 21st, 2022. If you order pretty much any configuration of the redesigned MacBook Pro that the cloth launched with, you’ll get your custom-built laptop at least a week before you get your cleaning cloth — and that’s with the worst-case estimate for the MacBook and best-case one for the cloth. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DthHDomLTUNCKblqE2HtQVOd4RU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22967806/Screen_Shot_2021_10_29_at_13.29.29.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not too bad, in comparison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8Bd9KG"&gt;Why is this happening? How did it catch the attention of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;? Maybe &lt;a href="https://www.ifixit.com/News/54122/macbook-pro-2021-teardown"&gt;looking at iFixit’s teardown&lt;/a&gt; will provide some answers! (Spoiler: nope.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GQbSYT"&gt;iFixit doesn’t have a dedicated page for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shroud_of_Turin"&gt;The Cloth&lt;/a&gt;, so you’ll have to scroll past a bunch of boring details about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"&gt;the MacBook that I’m definitely not drooling over&lt;/a&gt; to see the results. Once you do, though, its a surprisingly in-depth look at the accessory. iFixit reveals that it’s actually two pieces of material glued together and even takes a microscope to it to compare it to regular old microfiber. The teardown is brief (obviously, it’s literally a cloth), but well worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1VBQZsZkcoliO91AQdlJeqkmpgM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22967824/interiorshot.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: iFixit&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Breaking news: it’s a cloth &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; a potential ravioli.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dIUev8"&gt;But when compared to the actually decent (for Apple, at least) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22517104"&gt;reparability of the new MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, the Polishing Cloth gets a disappointing 0 / 10 repair score for distracting the iFixit crew. That’s really a bummer, because if you accidentally cut yours to pieces like iFixit did, you’ll have to wait a couple months to get a replacement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhLKrw"&gt;Finally, if you needed yet another reason to check out &lt;a href="https://www.ifixit.com/News/54122/macbook-pro-2021-teardown"&gt;iFixit’s article&lt;/a&gt; (besides, you know, the in-depth technical breakdown of Apple’s new laptops) just know that it has one of the funniest &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aZVkW9p-cCU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Psycho&lt;/em&gt; references&lt;/a&gt; I’ve seen for a while. Hats off to you, iFixit, for providing us with something fun to look at on a Friday (and for coming to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22702324/on-the-verge-event-date-tickets-guests-creators"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s birthday party&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@verge/video/7022385139283922182?is_copy_url=0&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;sender_device=pc&amp;amp;sender_web_id=6998606657735525894"&gt;teach people how to fix JoyCon&lt;/a&gt; last weekend). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="gcAD2R"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6oELVz"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="SZ6FK9"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="VRG VRV 379 2021 macbook review v03|104584" data-volume-uuid="29fcb94dc" data-volume-id="104584" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-976" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753184/ifixit-apple-polishing-cloth-19-repair-backorder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753184/ifixit-apple-polishing-cloth-19-repair-backorder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
