<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Apples</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-12T12:10:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/apple/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/apple" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T12:10:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T12:10:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces October 18th event after months of Mac rumors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwcLVU9Zc6oaoeUaND30QeSIpAE=/94x0:1330x824/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984773/image__7_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xRoatW"&gt;Apple’s next hardware event will take place on October 18th, according to invites it sent out today. The company is widely expected to use its second fall event to launch a pair of new MacBooks, a redesigned higher-end Mac Mini, and possibly a pair of third-generation AirPods. The invite video teases one word: Unleashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTTWne"&gt;There have been reports for months that Apple is on the cusp of releasing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;new 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pro models&lt;/a&gt;. The new MacBooks would be the latest step in Apple’s transition away from Intel chips and are expected to use an Arm-based processor called the M1X designed by Apple. The new chip should offer a boost in performance compared to the M1 chip that made its debut last year. Other anticipated features include the return of fan-favorite MacBook features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;magnetic MagSafe charging&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/apple-readies-macbook-pro-macbook-air-revamps-with-faster-chips?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;HDMI port, and an SD card slot&lt;/a&gt;. The maligned OLED touch bar is expected to be nixed. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1447700808821260292?s=20"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman recently noted&lt;/a&gt; that stock of the company’s existing MacBook Pro appears to be running low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="A370IL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Unleashed! These next six days are going to speed by. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AppleEvent?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AppleEvent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/0ops2bVPvl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0ops2bVPvl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Greg Joswiak (@gregjoz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1447956519132151810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IisHHU"&gt;The same M1X processor is also expected to feature in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637477/new-mac-mini-design-ports-m1x-release-date-gurman"&gt;redesigned higher-end Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;. The new machine will reportedly have more ports than last year’s M1 model, which had two Thunderbolt / USB 4 Type-C ports and two USB Type-A ports. The changes should make the new Mac Mini much better suited to power users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlrkgz"&gt;Finally, Apple is also expected to announce a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586507/apple-airpods-2021-refresh-rumor-iphone-se-2022-5g-15-details"&gt;pair of redesigned AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, which would be the third generation of the company’s original true wireless earbuds. The AirPods are expected to adopt a design similar to the AirPods Pro, including shorter stems and a redesigned charging case. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:15:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:15:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google says it’s dropping Material Design components on iOS in favor of Apple’s UIKit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_d2JPeeoLspqwU5NWsblSUfPouE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982999/acastro_210121_1777_google_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EtzZAf"&gt;Google is phasing out its use of Material Design user interface components for its iOS apps in favor of leaning more on Apple’s own UIKit. The company says the result of the switch should be less work for its iOS development team, but, more importantly, it’s likely the change will mean that Google’s iOS apps will feel less like interlopers on Apple devices. Instead of obeying Android’s UI conventions, they should look and feel more like they belong on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZafr9"&gt;The change was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781"&gt;announced on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Verkoeyen, engineer lead for Google Design on Apple’s platforms. I recommend reading the full thread if you’re interested, but Verkoeyen says his team “shifted the open source Material components libraries for iOS into maintenance mode” earlier this year. Material Design is Google’s in-house set of design conventions, which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/25/5841044/material-design-new-google-interface-2014"&gt;introduced in 2014&lt;/a&gt; in order to unify the look and feel of its apps and services across mobile devices, Chrome OS, and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8w0gsG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This year my team shifted the open source Material components libraries for iOS into maintenance mode. Why?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A  ...&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lRkPxb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This evolution of how we approach design for Apple platforms has enabled us to marry the best of UIKit with the highlights of Google's design language.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The result? Many custom components simply aren't needed anymore. And the ones that are, they now get more attention and focus.&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151524934107137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Dyg4Zp"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The time we're saving not building custom code is now invested in the long tail of UX details that really make products feel great on Apple platforms. To paraphrase Lucas Pope, we're "swimming in a sea of minor things", and I couldn't be more excited about this new direction.&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151530508398596?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wzR3QC"&gt;Verkoeyen said Google developed its own Material Design components for iOS, but, over time, found that these have been “slowly drifting further and further from Apple platform fundamentals because those fundaments were also evolving year over year.” Instead of creating work for itself by filling those gaps, Verkoeyen says Google has now decided to use Apple’s own UIKit for it iOS apps. He notes that doing so will “result in much tighter integrations with the OS than what we can reasonably achieve via custom solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6phvRk"&gt;Verkoeyen’s phrasing is somewhat oblique here, but many are &lt;a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2021/10/googles-apps-to-embrace-ios-on-ios/"&gt;interpreting&lt;/a&gt; the thread — including that mention of “tighter integrations” — as meaning that Google’s iOS apps will, in the future, follow more of the design conventions of Apple’s mobile OS. That might mean using fewer custom buttons that look like they belong on Android, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yCt1qG"&gt;As long-time Apple journalist Jason Snell &lt;a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2021/10/googles-apps-to-embrace-ios-on-ios/"&gt;commented&lt;/a&gt;: “This is good news. It’s good for Google’s developers, who no longer have to build that custom code. And more importantly, it’s good for people who use Google’s apps on iOS, because with any luck they’ll be updated faster, work better, and feel more like proper iOS apps, not invaders from some other platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dp3l8A"&gt;The proof of the pudding is in the eating, though, and until Google actually starts updating it iOS apps over the coming years, we won’t really know how it plans to marry the two design approaches. Let’s hope it does the right thing, and just makes things easiest for users. We will see.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722130/google-ios-app-material-design-components-uikit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722130/google-ios-app-material-design-components-uikit</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T05:30:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T05:30:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>The first USB-C iPhone is here thanks to a mod</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_KjgyEsT7H_83UmuQxkRKm6XWnw=/0x0:1320x880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982903/usbciphone.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A USB-C port on an iPhone X.&lt;/em&gt; | Ken Pillonel (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SAekbJf4Gsw" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VfmGgU"&gt;Apple hasn’t created a USB-C iPhone despite years of rumors, but that hasn’t stopped a robotics engineering student from creating one. Ken Pillonel has placed a working USB-C port inside an iPhone X, allowing the phone to charge and transfer data over USB-C instead of Lightning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTV91e"&gt;Pillonel has spent months on the project in his spare time, as spotted by &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/10/11/iphone-gets-usb-c-thanks-to-creative-robotics-engineer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and opened up plenty of USB-C and Lightning cables to get to his final goal of a USB-C iPhone. Pillonel originally created &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WCEzdj_8YwU"&gt;a simple prototype&lt;/a&gt; in May that allowed an iPhone battery to be charged over the USB-C port. The proof of concept was rather large and didn’t fit inside an iPhone, so the next stage was to remove all the wires and squeeze it inside. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZW5bEZwG-y8Mu1A5XrwHbW8zQec=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920198/usbciphone.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Ken Pillonel (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SAekbJf4Gsw" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C port on an iPhone X.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2IOb6v"&gt;Pillonel reverse-engineered Apple’s custom C94 connector, creating his own flexible PCB design that fits inside an iPhone. Pillonel revealed the flexible cable in a final teaser video this week, demonstrating how the iPhone X with USB-C charges and transfers data. A full video is currently being edited, which will detail exactly how Pillonel managed to reverse-engineer the C94 connector and fit his custom PCB inside the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KAzNxU"&gt;The USB-C iPhone comes just weeks after the European Commission announced plans to force smartphone and other electronics manufacturers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22626723/eu-commission-universal-charger-usb-c-micro-lightning-connector-smartphones"&gt;fit a common USB-C charging port&lt;/a&gt; on their devices. Apple could be forced to create an iPhone with USB-C in the next couple of years, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689432/eu-iphone-usb-c-switch-portless-design"&gt;launch a portless iPhone&lt;/a&gt; that relies on wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2BiVcz"&gt;It’s not clear whether Pillonel plans to release details of his custom flexible PCB so others can attempt the modification. He’s currently studying for a master’s degree in robotics at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, EPFL. He has previously used his talents to &lt;a href="https://kenp.io/galaxy_fold_car/"&gt;modify a car mount for Samsung’s Galaxy Fold&lt;/a&gt;, releasing a 3D printed mod to allow a Xiaomi Mi Wireless Car Charger to work with the Galaxy Fold.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722123/first-iphone-usb-c-port-robotics-engineering-student-custom"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722123/first-iphone-usb-c-port-robotics-engineering-student-custom</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-11T13:50:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-11T13:50:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2020 MacBook Air, one of the best laptops you can get, is now available at Amazon starting at $850.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YgkMYN"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including some equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the discounts that are currently available for the latest MacBook models, as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — which will be compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; upon its release later this year — and we’ll highlight those when we find them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1022323/7613?sharedid=VergeBestDealsAppleMacbook042721&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15- to 20-percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. For now, however, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="15A2tS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;The best MacBook Air deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FJU3RG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance. It ticks all right boxes when it comes to performance and price, which is why it’s our number one pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best laptop of 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iF2kto"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and a 256GB SSD. It typically sells for $999, however, it’s currently available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5M7S6K?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747531561997035408#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $850. The $1,249 512GB configuration is also on sale in all three colorways at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LFLC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747532219045612135#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $1,100, its best price to date. These deals can come and go quickly, though, we expect more to come as the holiday shopping season draws near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;The best MacBook Pro deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The touch bar-equipped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; comes in more sizes and options than the Air, and it’s geared more toward demanding use cases. The base model is the 13-inch, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1-powered variant&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a brighter screen, longer battery life, and an internal fan designed to maintain performance under increased workloads. The M1 MacBook Pro 13 normally starts at $1,299, but the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is on sale for $120 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5N6RSS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it down to $1,179. The larger, 512GB variant is also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LM1K3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $1,349, its second-best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjmE4B"&gt;While there have been rumors throughout the year of a r&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;edesigned MacBook Pro, one with an M1X processor and additional ports&lt;/a&gt;, we might not see it until further into the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ue6Q0U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="44XxWs"&gt;Of course, you can also buy some older MacBook Pro models, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21256520/apple-13-inch-macbook-pro-2020-review-keyboard-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch, mid-2020 model&lt;/a&gt;. The older device features four Thunderbolt ports, Windows bootcamp-ready Ice Lake processors, the current scissor-switch keyboard, increased RAM, and various storage configurations. Right now, the 13-inch model is available in several configurations at Amazon, including one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-Pro-10th-Generation-Quad-Core/dp/B08DTPQ9XB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10th-gen i7 Intel processor and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; for $1,999 and one with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B08821TJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB of storage and a 2.0GHz 10th-gen Intel Core i5 processor&lt;/a&gt; for $1,700, which is $300 off the list price. You can also pick up the model with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B0881Z844Y?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of storage and a 10th-gen Intel Core i5&lt;/a&gt; for $1,500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hij1MQ"&gt;If you want a bigger laptop with more horsepower, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2019 MacBook Pro 16&lt;/a&gt; is the top-of-the-line model. Compared to its predecessor, it has a better keyboard, newer processors, and improved speakers. There are several configurations available with more storage and speedier processors — you can also get the 16-inch model with an Intel Core i9 CPU and 1TB of storage &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FTNGNC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $2,695 at Amaz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FV1Y57/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt;, for instance — but deals are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zjWXtS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10469149"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;The best Mac Mini deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. The outright best deal on the base Mac Mini is at Amazon, where you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB model for $600&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5P7TLW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB configuration for $799&lt;/a&gt;. B&amp;amp;H Photo is also &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604800-REG%2Fapple_mgnt3ll_a_mac_mini.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;matching Amazon’s current price&lt;/a&gt; for the 512GB model, though, no other retailers are at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-11T13:32:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-11T13:32:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple releases iOS 15.0.2 with some Find My fixes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pJ0CrmeKrfc3RniV9709J3cIJ0s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69980678/cgartenberg_210917_4762_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5fu32v"&gt;Apple released iOS 15.0.2 on Monday, and it has some important bug fixes, including a couple specific to Find My. For the iPad and iPhone, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212846"&gt;it also fixes a security flaw&lt;/a&gt; that Apple says may already be under attack, so update ASAP. Credited to an anonymous researcher, CVE-2021-30883 could allow an attacker to exploit the IOMobileFrameBuffer to “execute arbitrary code with kernel privileges,” and take over your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fhHCdF"&gt;On my iPhone 12 Mini, the update clocks in at 531.1MB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8yv5S"&gt;Here are the patch notes from Apple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="FopdTk"&gt;This update includes bug fixes for your iPhone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P3MJUf"&gt;Photos saved to your library from Messages could be deleted after removing the associated thread or message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5CT2w"&gt;iPhone Leather Wallet with MagSafe may not connect to Find My&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bMpUfp"&gt;AirTag might not appear in the Find My Items tab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w7QEnL"&gt;CarPlay may fail to open audio apps or disconnect during playback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r0DXbL"&gt;Device restore or update may fail when using Finder or iTunes for iPhone 13 models&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="J3QrME"&gt;iPadOS 15.0.2 is also out. Here’s what’s included in that, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/11/ios-15-0-2-release-bug-fixes-features/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="g9dGNd"&gt;Photos saved to your library from Messages could be deleted after removing the associated thread or message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="viecq8"&gt;AirTag might not appear in the Find My Items tab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZHtKI"&gt;Device restore or update may fail when using Finder or iTunes for iPad mini (6th generation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="MFXd1s"&gt;Apple released iOS 15 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;on September 20th&lt;/a&gt;, and already updated it once &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704524/apple-ios-15-0-1-update-fix-iphone-13-watch-unlock-bug"&gt;to iOS 15.0.1&lt;/a&gt; to fix an issue where people couldn’t use their Apple Watch to unlock their iPhone 13 while wearing a mask. Apple is also testing iOS 15.1 in beta, which currently includes features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card"&gt;SharePlay&lt;/a&gt;, support for adding a COVID-19 vaccination card to Apple Wallet, and new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713135/iphone-13-camera-features-prores-macro-ios-15-1-beta-3"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro camera features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="juV9qt"&gt;Apple posted watchOS 8.0.1 on Monday, too. According to Apple, here’s what’s fixed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jXq4WQ"&gt;Software update progress may not be displayed accurately for some Apple Watch Series 3 users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aelWgd"&gt;Accessibility settings may not have been available for some Apple Watch Series 3 users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jKrbSj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22721014/apple-ios-ipados-15-0-2-find-my-fixes-watchos-8-0-1"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22721014/apple-ios-ipados-15-0-2-find-my-fixes-watchos-8-0-1</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-08T19:21:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T19:21:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is appealing the Epic Games ruling it originally called a ‘resounding victory’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rw1L-2fRK2yD6eV4lSRtlNc_Ofs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69972129/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple is appealing the Epic Games ruling | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HXBaCg"&gt;With &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667047/apple-epic-ruling-games-app-store-fortnite-revenue-purchases-business"&gt;potentially billions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; and some control over the App Store at stake, Apple has filed for an appeal of the ruling in its major trial against Epic. While Apple largely won that case (the company went so far as to call the ruling &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667769/apple-epic-lost-lawsuit-verdict-ruling"&gt;a “resounding victory”&lt;/a&gt;) with Judge Gonzalez Rogers ruling in favor of Apple in nine of the ten claims Epic brought against the company, it did lose in one important way: the judge found that Apple violated California’s anti-steering rules, and demanded that Apple let developers link to outside payment systems. That policy would have taken over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662320/epic-apple-ruling-injunction-judge-court-app-store"&gt;in December&lt;/a&gt;, but it may be pushed out beyond that — and it seems that’s the point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UzMH0j"&gt;As part of the appeal, Apple is asking for a stay to prevent the company from having to implement the new anti-steering rules, arguing that it “will allow Apple to protect consumers and safeguard its platform while the company works through the complex and rapidly evolving legal, technological, and economic issues.” And the company’s arguments there are pretty revealing if we’re reading the document right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yxijeu"&gt;For instance, Apple claims that the new anti-steering rule is unnecessary because the company had already agreed to delete the offending section of its App Store Guidelines in the &lt;em&gt;Cameron v. Apple &lt;/em&gt;settlement, but that’s news to us: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643807/apple-developer-class-action-lawsuit-collect-information-ios-apps-anti-steering"&gt;at the time&lt;/a&gt;, Apple only agreed to “clarify” that app developers were allowed to communicate with consenting customers, not link to outside payment systems. That clarification was widely seen by developers as a red herring. At the time, Apple didn’t say anything about deleting a section of its App Store Guidelines entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="yPUaOe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple and Epic both lost today","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667769/apple-epic-lost-lawsuit-verdict-ruling"},{"title":"The future of the App Store depends on the difference between a ‘button’ and an ‘external link’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667161/app-store-epic-ruling-difference-button-external-link"},{"title":"What comes next for the App Store?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671574/epic-apple-app-store-new-rules-meaning-ruling-decision"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fPZLBZ"&gt;It also seems like Apple is genuinely afraid that the court order &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; force them to open up the App Store to alternate payment mechanisms, despite what some Apple pundits have claimed. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667161/app-store-epic-ruling-difference-button-external-link"&gt;A button might actually be a button&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="32fHay"&gt;Links and buttons to alternate payment mechanisms are fraught with risk. Users who click on a payment link embedded in an app—particularly one distributed through the curated App Store—will expect to be led to a webpage where they can securely provide their payment information, email address, or other personal information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="2k0SHS"&gt;Apple goes on to argue that if it were forced to allow app developers to link to external payment systems, it wouldn’t be able to protect users from fraud: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="07eXrO"&gt;While Apple could examine the links in the version of the app submitted for review, there is nothing stopping a developer from changing the landing point for that link or altering the content of the destination webpage. Additionally, Apple currently has no ability to determine whether a user who clicks on an external link actually received the products or features she paid for. Apple already receives hundreds of thousands of reports each day from users, and allowing links to external payment options would only increase this burden. In essence, the introduction of external payment links, particularly without sufficient time to test and evaluate the security implications, will lead to the very same security concerns that Apple combats with the use of IAP more generally, which the Court agreed were legitimate, procompetitive reasons for the design of the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="9GgANe"&gt;There are a number of open questions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;about how well Apple protects App Store users&lt;/a&gt; — it was only this past week that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams"&gt;added a feature to easily report obvious App Store scams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="67W2hL"&gt;The company even cites a blog post from (and &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s story about) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714677/apple-in-app-payment-competitor-paddle-epic-ruling"&gt;Paddle, a would-be rival to Apple’s in-app payments that emerged after the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple &lt;/em&gt;ruling&lt;/a&gt;, using it to illustrate one possible threat to consumers. Not because of its lower fees, of course, but because “In contrast to Apple’s strict rules surrounding privacy, that developer intends to provide access to user email addresses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kSOivG"&gt;Other arguments are raised as well, which you can read in full in the document embedded at the bottom of this post. Overall, the company says that the “precipitous implementation of this aspect of the injunction would upset the careful balance between developers and customers provided by the App Store, and would irreparably harm both Apple and consumers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HCH4s7"&gt;Apple also cites a previous case, &lt;em&gt;Ohio v. AmEx&lt;/em&gt;, as evidence that transaction platforms like the App Store can promote competition despite steering restrictions. (AmEx doesn’t double as a software marketplace, though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ay66qJ"&gt;It’s important to note that Apple has only filed for appeal; we don’t know if the court will grant the appeal — and the stay— just yet. When the ruling originally hit in in September, Apple said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671736/epic-apple-fortnite-antitrust-case-ruling-appeal-decision"&gt;at the time&lt;/a&gt; that it hadn’t decided whether to appeal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xc5yqh"&gt;For its part, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667208/epic-games-appeal-apple-judge-rogers-ruling-court"&gt;Epic announced its intent to appeal&lt;/a&gt; on the same day Judge Gonzalez Rogers issued her order and permanent injunction against Apple. It was clear from the beginning that Epic wasn’t happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9nQVyH"&gt;Epic CEO Tim Sweeney issued his response to the appeal, and it’s pretty much what you’d expect: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wDiEtX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Apple filed a peel &lt;a href="https://t.co/hvnfgg8lZC"&gt;https://t.co/hvnfgg8lZC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/TouBIrKiSp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TouBIrKiSp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1446627338058350599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="LZuWUO"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21081062-apple-incs-notice-of-motion-and-motion-for-stay-of-injunction-pending-appeal-and-memorandum-of-points-and-authorities-in-support-therof/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Apple Inc.'s Notice of Motion and Motion for Stay of Injunction Pending Appeal and Memorandum of Points and Authorities in Support Therof (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22717271/apple-appeals-epic-games-ruling-anti-steering"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22717271/apple-appeals-epic-games-ruling-anti-steering</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-08T17:12:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T17:12:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>If you want to use the Apple Watch Series 7’s new fast charging, make sure to use the cable in the box</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TFzmi6Ppf8-Ek9wq06qiHdRiaw8=/74x0:820x497/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69971643/Capto_Capture_2021_09_14_01_24_25_PM.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KhEdj0"&gt;One of the best features on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt; is its newly added fast charging system, which Apple claims is 33 percent and capable of charging the watch to about 80 percent charge in about 45 minutes. But if you want to take advantage of the fast charging, you’ll need to make sure to use the charger that comes with the Series 7, which is a brand new “&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMLWJ3AM%2FA%2Fapple-watch-magnetic-fast-charger-to-usb-c-cable-1-m&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22716294%2Fapple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-cable-magnetic" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Watch Magnetic Fast Charger&lt;/a&gt;” that’s different from the old model (which doesn’t offer similar charging speeds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQsaH0"&gt;The old USB-C charger and the new model look identical from the outside, but only the new cable can charge the Series 7 at full speed (assuming you’ve got a USB-C charger that can put out the proper wattage, that is — Apple recommends its own 20W USB-C charger, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6tihBM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Make sure to actually use the cable that comes with the Series 7&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wRBb8G"&gt;And while Apple has already stopped selling the old USB-C charger that doesn’t offer fast charging on its site, they’re still available from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Magnetic-Charger-USB-C/dp/B07XR9TYQ1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;other retailers like Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, so you’ll want to make sure you’re buying the right one if you’re looking to pick up a spare. It also means that if you own an existing Apple Watch charging dock or stand that has a built-in charger, you won’t be able to take advantage of the faster charging available on the Series 7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lquMvi"&gt;Of course, none of this matters if you own an older Apple Watch: even if you’re using the proper fast charging cable, the fast charging technology still needs a Series 7 watch to work. As Apple’s website notes: “Fast charging is only compatible with Apple Watch Series 7. Other models will have regular charge times.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22716294/apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-cable-magnetic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22716294/apple-watch-series-7-fast-charging-cable-magnetic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-08T14:31:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T14:31:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to preorder the Apple Watch Series 7</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OaNqWaV5j4cx0WB5BjSpqEwDxr4=/154x0:1807x1102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69949627/Apple_watch_series7_availability_stainless_steel_10052021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 features larger screens.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WAQ6pp"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;new Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt; Series 7 was announced alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672438/ipad-2021-new-price-specs-release-date-apple-a13-chip"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22696652/ipad-mini-2021-6th-gen-review"&gt;iPad Mini&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s the final device of Apple’s new fall products to launch. This newer model sits atop Apple’s current lineup of smartwatches, which still includes the SE and Series 3 rounding out the line. Featuring a slightly revamped design and larger display, the Series 7 comes in either a 41mm (up from 40mm) configuration starting at $399 or a 45mm (up from 44mm) configuration — each with optional cellular radios if you want to pay for service with your carrier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMTfvS"&gt;After Apple’s initial announcement billed them for release “later this fall,” we now know &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708611/apple-watch-7-release-date-price-preorder"&gt;the new models are set to release on October 15th&lt;/a&gt;, and you can &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-watch%2Fapple-watch&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;preorder them now through Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfKhcuwgnDQ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-watch-series-7-gps%2F-%2FA-84736576%3Fpreselect%3D77640209%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Fapple-watch%2Fapple-watch-series-7%2F3944_1229722_1890925_1696849_6549129&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LuD92a"&gt;What’s new&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="roSEq8"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 prominently features that new, larger display that stretches the screen closer to the edges for a more full-bleed aesthetic and showing more actionable information at once. It has a slight curve at its farthest edges, though Apple says the watch is overall more durable thanks to a 50 percent thicker glass cover and IP6X rating for better dirt and sand resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9RLkrZ"&gt;New watch faces exclusive to the Series 7 promise to put that extra screen real estate to work, while the watch maintains a physical footprint that is close to its predecessor. Apple has also improved charging speeds, including a new USB-C wireless magnetic fast charger with the watch that it claims will offer up to a 33 percent quicker charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lttaJ7"&gt;On the software side, the Apple Watch Series 7 runs watchOS 8, supports a full swiping keyboard for text input, is compatible with new workouts, and maintains all the health-tracking features found on prior iterations: sleep tracking, heart rate and blood oxygen monitoring, and fall detection that now registers during workouts. There is plenty to take advantage of if you’re in the market for a new Apple Watch and prefer to have Apple’s latest and greatest iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LxippD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Should you wait for the Apple Watch Series 7?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674258/apple-watch-series-7-upgrade-worth-waiting-for"},{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0ZdgqF"&gt;The aluminum-encased Series 7 watches come in midnight, starlight, an updated blue, (PRODUCT) RED, and a new dark green colorway, so there is a bit to choose from whether you’re going for a discreet, bold, or rugged look. Let’s break down all that there is to offer here before we dive further into specific configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FWKvlA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10743503"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s2wxGivMl3xRoA_Lx7GJydjaaKM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900348/Apple_watch_series7_availability_aluminum_10052021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch Series 7 in midnight, starlight, green, blue, and PRODUCT (RED).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ixNYqI"&gt;How to preorder the Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="yBbMqA"&gt;You can preorder your preferred configuration directly from Apple or a variety of retailers right now, with the earliest orders shipping on October 15th. The main options for you to decide on, aside from your preferred color, are size and connectivity. The base Apple Watch Series 7 configuration is a 41mm, GPS-only model that retails for $399. The 41mm version with a cellular connection runs $100 more at $499. If you have a larger wrist or prefer bigger screens, the 45mm GPS-only model is $429, while its cellular-equipped counterpart climbs up to $529. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CYcjeM"&gt;Preorder all sizes, colors, and configurations at Apple&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ybj2aF"&gt;If you want an Apple Watch with your pick of the litter for bands — standard, premium, or fixed-length — then Apple has the most on offer. It’s the only place you can order an Apple Watch with custom-sized solo loop straps, though be sure to use the size guide. Shipments are initially expected for October 15th, however, select models won’t ship until early to mid-November. If you opt for in-store pickup at an Apple Store, it might still be the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Iin96H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10743802"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1oQQDo"&gt;Preorder at Best Buy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UewUYo"&gt;Best Buy’s site is indicating that the base 41mm GPS model will arrive on release day, while some other configurations with cellular connectivity are to be expected around October 25th. The retailer has all colors available for the size and connectivity of your choice, each with a matching sport band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6zF2jz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797140"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="r0rafV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qmXurY"&gt;Preorder at Walmart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5PezQJ"&gt;Walmart has a variety of anticipated shipping dates for preorders. All preorders are expected to ship by October 15th, though, some individual configurations have delivery dates ranging from the 15th to the 21st. Oddly, the red, 45mm LTE model notes a shipping date of October 11th, though we would advise not putting too much confidence in its accuracy. There can sometimes be errors in retailer listings as soon as a product is put up for sale, which is often corrected later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h4THAO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797290"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="5A8W7H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797296"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="h2Dlds"&gt;Preorder at Target&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eWiJze"&gt;Target lists each and every color and configuration of the aluminum Apple Watch Series 7 as shipping by the release date of October 15th. This can always change on the fly, but it is worth considering if you want to get your new watch as quickly as possible. Target RedCard members will also receive free shipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NR6Vib"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797306"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kSl7XQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10797315"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uoprLg"&gt;How to preorder the Apple Watch Series 7 from phone carriers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3dbtKG"&gt;Most major phone carriers in the US offer the cellular Apple Watch Series 7 for preorder, which can help if you prefer to purchase the smartwatch on a monthly installment plan that you might already have for your phone. For the cellular models, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-11557999?sid=VergeAppleWatchSeries7100821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fconnected-smartwatches%2Fapple-watch-series-7%2F%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836598-13761603?sid=VergeAppleWatchSeries7100821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fwearables%2Fapple-watch-series-7-41mm-green-aluminum-clover-sport.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsmart-watch%2Fapple-watch-series-7-41mm%3Fsku%3D194252566381&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664661%2Fapple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; all offer the Series 7 in each of its sizes and colors at the same starting price as Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gdxgiN"&gt;Apple has confirmed that when you &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-watch%2Fapple-watch%2Faluminum-case&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy a cellular-equipped Apple Watch Series 7 through its own store&lt;/a&gt; and activate it on &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100009682-14498937?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fshop%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664661%2Fapple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sprint / T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, you will get $100 back.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g50QyqEKJq0rPdmM51JUYxdmD-g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900357/Apple_watch_series7_availability_hermes_10052021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch Edition with Hermès strap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VH7yJz"&gt;More premium case options and custom configurator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="T46tsH"&gt;Apple has also offered the latest top-end watch in additional case materials for years. This generation is no different, with the Series 7 available in &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-watch%2Fapple-watch%2Fstainless-steel-case&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;stainless steel starting at $699&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-watch%2Fapple-watch%2Ftitanium-case&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;titanium starting at $799&lt;/a&gt;, as well as band options from luxury fashion boutique Hermès. The easiest way to preorder these is directly from Apple, as it carries the most options and not all retailers sell the more luxurious watches — though &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfKhlKGfOGa" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-watch-stainless-steel-series-7-gps-cellular%2F-%2FA-84783483%3Fpreselect%3D77640146%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Fapple-watch%2Fapple-watch-series-7%2F3944_1229722_1890925_1696849_6549129%3Fsort%3Dprice_high&amp;amp;subid1=vergeapplewatchseries7preorder" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; do have some stainless steel models available for preorder. Most people opt for aluminum, which offers the same functionality at a lower price, but the premium models have a unique fit and finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NR4t55"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fstudio%2Fapple-watch&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22664661%2Fapple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Watch Studio&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s own online boutique for creating exact custom Apple Watch configurations, makes a return for the Series 7. If you prefer an Apple Watch in a particular combination of size, finish, color, and band, you can make your selection and pay the configured price directly from Apple. This is the only way to order one of the popular solo loop straps with your Apple Watch, as those fixed-length straps are only sold through Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22664661/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22664661/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-08T14:14:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T14:14:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>This iPhone 13 case adds what the phone was always missing — a candy launcher</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZvQwDjQwcpWnaum9SmBD2GhMXhc=/213x0:2130x1278/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69970698/Screen_Shot_2021_10_08_at_10.34.53_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vOXkPc"&gt;No matter how much Apple hypes Ceramic Shield — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509008/apple-iphone-12-pro-max-mini-displays-ceramic-hardened"&gt;the special glass mixture introduced with the iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt; — and the build quality of the metal and glass sandwich that is the modern iPhone, expensive phones need cases. Maybe you ordered one alongside &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"&gt;your new iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt;, but if you didn’t, may I propose an exciting and undeniably useful option — &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hX46nzE9wmw"&gt;a giant case that rockets hard candy&lt;/a&gt; into your mouth (&lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-perfect-iphone-13-case-holds-a-bunch-of-candy-and-s-1847825950"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kTtUK1"&gt;YouTube creator and inventor Matty Benedetto is responsible for the DIY case, which he calls the Candy Catapult. It’s 3D printed from flexible TPU filament with a hard candy container back for your poison of choice, be it M&amp;amp;Ms, Skittles, or Reese Pieces (only sickos would mix all three). To actually launch the candy out of the case, Benedetto added a pinball machine-esque spring-loaded plunger. It’s hard to gauge just how hard it launches its little sugary missiles, but it definitely seems strong enough to send a piece of candy clear across the room.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nDDmDGco2eD9u6gy6eIIBJQCbAI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22910798/gif__1_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Candy Catapult works!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g924kt"&gt;My first thought watching Benedetto’s video is not relief that I suddenly have a way to dispense with my industrial-sized bag of lozenges (no help needed there) but really excitement over the other possible things one could launch from it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6kyZmu"&gt;I’m really just wondering how quickly this becomes a weapon with metal ball bearings in it. Is it launching it hard enough to break a window if you were to swap candy with something more... damaging? Some things are perhaps best left unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Y0XtvA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The most innovate phone cases are made in a Los Angeles shed","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/3/18287292/phone-case-design-bailey-hikawa-kame-art-unconventional"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Qbp2Rb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/10/8/22716481/iphone-13-candy-shooter-case-diy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/10/8/22716481/iphone-13-candy-shooter-case-diy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-08T12:19:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T12:19:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple removes the Apple Watch Series 6 from its official lineup</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MYWFlMkuzt0_wwbCBJd7o5Dp_Ag=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69970023/vpavic_200929_4216_0121.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dtqCI4"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 is finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22664661/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"&gt;available to preorder&lt;/a&gt;, nearly a month after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple announced the new smartwatch&lt;/a&gt;. But the launch of the Series 7 also brings the removal of the Series 6 from the company’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fwatch%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F8%2F22716438%2Fapple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;official Apple Watch lineup&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jHP2Nv"&gt;If you want to buy a brand new Apple Watch from Apple, you now only have three options: the Series 7, which starts at $399; the still-very-good SE, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;introduced last year&lt;/a&gt; and starts at $279; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;years-old Series 3&lt;/a&gt;, which starts at $199. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFwQ27"&gt;There are still a few ways to get a Series 6, though, and given how many features are shared &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/guide/apple-watch-series-6-vs-apple-watch-series-7/"&gt;between the Series 7 and the Series 6&lt;/a&gt;, the previous generation model could be a good option to consider if you want to save some money. Apple’s refurbished store has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fwatch%2Fapple-watch-series-6&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F8%2F22716438%2Fapple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three different Series 6 models for sale right now&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and Amazon is currently offering many &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=apple+watch+series+6&amp;amp;ref=nb_sb_noss_1"&gt;refurbished Series 6 watches at a discount&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22716438/apple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22716438/apple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
