<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-02T10:03:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:03:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:03:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Morbius has ‘some form of bat radar’ in the first trailer in two years</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5DelPtskZlkWWSSUDY9do80Ez1k=/457x0:1966x1006/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70079045/Screen_Shot_2021_11_02_at_9.48.11_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eY7998"&gt;For the first time in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/13/21062568/morbius-trailer-jared-leto-marvel-sony-pictures-venom-michael-keaton-vulture"&gt;nearly two years&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oZ6iiRrz1SY"&gt;new trailer&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming Spider-Man spinoff &lt;em&gt;Morbius&lt;/em&gt;, which stars Jared Leto as Dr. Michael Morbius, an ailing scientist who inadvertently turns himself into a “pseudo-vampire” while searching for a cure for his rare medical condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMxOU9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morbius&lt;/em&gt; is an unusual film, even by Sony’s Spider-Man universe standards. The character is what can best be described as a C-list Spider-Man villain, which &lt;em&gt;Morbius &lt;/em&gt;is reimagining as a &lt;em&gt;Venom&lt;/em&gt;-style antihero who wars between his doctoral duties as a healer and his newfound bloodlust. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="87zbPj"&gt;The new trailer helps give a broad introduction to the character, including his origin story and his powers, which include the usual super-strength and speed, “some form of...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759140/morbius-jared-leto-sony-spider-man-spinoff-trailer-vampire"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759140/morbius-jared-leto-sony-spider-man-spinoff-trailer-vampire"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759140/morbius-jared-leto-sony-spider-man-spinoff-trailer-vampire</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to find the best deals during Black Friday and Cyber Monday 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DzZhQZ73bJ1oqBaQXgqy240kVjI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67838743/acastro_191031_1777_blackFriday_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EkLaRj"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday are the biggest shopping days of the year, a relentless, deals-packed week when you can often find the best prices on tech products like laptops, 4K TVs, phones, video games, and more. And of course, these good deals are all accessible online. Some of them may, in fact, be online exclusives, though many should be available in-store, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnndf2"&gt;You can always count on us to publish the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals"&gt;best deals that you need to know about&lt;/a&gt;, but if you want to be among the first people to discover price drops on products you’re interested in, you’ll want to get set up with a price-tracking tool. We’ve included a few of our favorite examples below, pointing out how each can help you track deals in slightly different ways, each with...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21587765/black-friday-cyber-monday-best-deals-how-to-find"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21587765/black-friday-cyber-monday-best-deals-how-to-find"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21587765/black-friday-cyber-monday-best-deals-how-to-find</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Know the price-matching policies for Apple, Google, Microsoft, and others </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Opening day at the Amazon 4-Star brick and mortar store located in Soho in New York City." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VyUG7BE3sU0uVmia7hA3FBoPa-M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67804971/akrales_180927_2984_0073_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="woOIOK"&gt;Nothing is more frustrating than buying a new computer, phone, game console, or backpack and finding out that you could have gotten it for a lot cheaper somewhere else. In order to keep customers happy — and prevent them from going elsewhere — many retailers offer price-matching policies where they promise to match a lower price that you’ve found elsewhere. They will also sometimes match themselves if you buy something that goes down in price a week later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ax9brN"&gt;What follows are the price-matching policies for a variety of major retailers. There are a few things to make note of here. First, all price-matching policies have a number of rules attached to them. We’ve summarized some of the rules here, but you’d be advised to go to the links that...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570383/price-matching-policy-apple-google-microsoft"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21570383/price-matching-policy-apple-google-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21570383/price-matching-policy-apple-google-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Black Friday deals: what time sales start at Amazon, Best Buy, Walmart, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hxKEWGafBF6eqWYiT_yUeO8xj_g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67851019/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0004.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Nj1X37"&gt;Black Friday officially kicks off on November 26th, but if you plan to make that the only day you buy gifts this holiday season, you’re missing out. Several retailers, including Best Buy and Target, are already getting a head start on rolling out their holiday discounts. Best Buy has even been offering price protection for Black Friday deals since mid-October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qjhxYw"&gt;Whether you take advantage of the slew of early Black Friday deals or hold off until the day after Thanksgiving, it’s important to know how every major retailer is handling the shopping event this year. Some retailers, for instance, are still approaching things a bit differently due to the ongoing pandemic, with many offering deals over the weeks leading up to Black Friday and...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569881/black-friday-deals-start-time-hours-cyber-monday-stores"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21569881/black-friday-deals-start-time-hours-cyber-monday-stores"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21569881/black-friday-deals-start-time-hours-cyber-monday-stores</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Know the holiday shipping and return policies for Apple, Google, Microsoft, and others</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="samsung experience store" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f97dE635Tu-ZVkNyI4aPVE0cHiM=/105x0:795x460/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67804922/experience_stores_middle_row1.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hDTB22"&gt;With the holiday season right around the corner, everyone is double-checking their lists and figuring out the best places to fulfill those orders. Thankfully, there are often a number of options when it comes to retailers that have what you want. Because of this, online retailers aren’t just dropping prices to compete with each other, but offering more generous shipping and return policies for their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LjdpKv"&gt;Most people will still be doing the majority of their shopping online this year, which means that most retailers will be offering free shipping for anyone who spends a set dollar amount. However, this sudden surge in online shopping does increase the possibility for delays as online retailers become flooded with orders and their...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570161/holiday-shipping-return-policy-apple-google-microsoft-amazon"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21570161/holiday-shipping-return-policy-apple-google-microsoft-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21570161/holiday-shipping-return-policy-apple-google-microsoft-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best early Black Friday deals to look out for</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rXQWmv3b7ZzV_0ejKkOfEHazEuc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67798744/Early_Black_Friday_Deals.18.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7vZvx2"&gt;Black Friday officially starts on November 26th, however, we’re already starting to see significant discounts on some of this year’s most popular pieces of tech. Beginning in early October, some retailers — including Amazon, Best Buy, Target, and Walmart — have been lowering prices on goods ranging from Apple’s AirPods to LG’s C1 OLED as a part of their early Black Friday sales. The great news is these stores are now starting to drop prices even more aggressively as we approach the big day, and many of them have price-matching policies that guarantee you’ll get the lowest price. Below we’ve compiled some of the best early Black Friday deals available so far, along with some information about upcoming Black Friday sales so you can prepare...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T10:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T10:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s Guide to Black Friday 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Mspf2aQxkdLOwYnorCovtLcAh4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67851504/The_Verges_Guide_to_Black_Friday_2021.9.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aqtAPK"&gt;Black Friday usually begins the day after Thanksgiving in the US, but in 2021, that’s just when it’ll morph into its final form. The once-a-year deal extravaganza is already happening at a couple of retailers, including Best Buy, Target, and Walmart. Each has marked down a batch of tech products weeks ahead of schedule, and each retailer is frequently sharing more deals and details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eHXA0k"&gt;If you want to get your shopping started earlier than usual, you can and absolutely should. Most retailers that are offering early Black Friday deals also have good price-matching (or at least price protection) policies for many of them, so you likely won’t regret crossing off your checklist now instead of later this month. You’ll find all of the latest...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T09:32:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T09:32:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nest smart speakers and displays are up to 50 percent off this week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lGujrEqAiGxOE0k4oHPgH1XizoQ=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70078841/dseifert-nest-audio-4225-10.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Audio is a well-reviewed option from Google, and even more worth considering now on discount.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S285r3"&gt;The world of smart home accessories grows each year, with the occasional &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price"&gt;new idea&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker"&gt;latest iterations on mainstay staples&lt;/a&gt;. This segment also heats up around the holiday shopping season and Black Friday as discounts become available, which is ideal because so many of them make great gifts. If you’re invested at all in Google’s Nest products — or you’re looking to dive in and test the waters — this week’s deals have a variety options you might want to strongly consider. Right now, there are significant discounts on Google Nest products at multiple retailers, including Best Buy, Wellbots, and more, encompassing smart speakers, video doorbells, home security, and smart displays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCuzTH"&gt;First off, and leading our selection of Nest deals, is...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757318/google-nest-smart-home-audio-speaker-assistant-video-doorbell-home-hub-cam-deal-sale"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757318/google-nest-smart-home-audio-speaker-assistant-video-doorbell-home-hub-cam-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757318/google-nest-smart-home-audio-speaker-assistant-video-doorbell-home-hub-cam-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T09:12:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T09:12:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Grab the Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 for its lowest price ever at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: Asus Zephyrus G15" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YNVVTBeiBAMHfZrct8xQ4CCD0tc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70078722/akrales_210226_4440_0022.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3ex7aC"&gt;One of our favorite gaming laptops, the Asus ROG Zephyrus G15, is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfUwzwuYGlu" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently available for its lowest price ever at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. And this is the model to get, as it features an RTX 3070 graphics chip, 1TB of NVMe SSD storage, and 16GB of RAM. Topping it all off, the laptop is powered by an AMD Ryzen 9 5900HS processor, and it has a 1440p display with a 165Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0SXPPe"&gt;This deal knocks $300 off the regular price, dropping it down to just $1,550, which is actually the same price that Asus is asking for its lesser 14-inch G14 laptop that has an RTX 3060. Our reviewer Monica Chin was impressed by the G15’s ability to compress such impressive performance into a lightweight and portable package. If this wasn’t sweet enough, this laptop also...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757246/asus-zephyrus-g15-msi-gaming-laptop-xbox-game-pass-microsoft-deal-sale"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757246/asus-zephyrus-g15-msi-gaming-laptop-xbox-game-pass-microsoft-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/2/22757246/asus-zephyrus-g15-msi-gaming-laptop-xbox-game-pass-microsoft-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T09:00:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T09:00:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Firefox’s new mobile homescreen makes it easier to jump back to pages you’ve recently visited</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rOfPYJofQ88gskq3TZNmGEujYlg=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70078678/Untitled_1.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part of Firefox’s new mobile homescreen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Mozilla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qJN2fq"&gt;Mozilla is updating the homescreen on its Firefox mobile apps to help you more easily jump back to pages you had viewed recently. With Firefox 94, which will be available Tuesday, you’ll be able to see things like your last open tab, recently-viewed bookmarks, and recent searches grouped by topic right on the mobile homescreen. You can get an idea of what it looks like in this image from Mozilla:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Firefox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Firefox mobile homescreen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xKQcuX"&gt;Firefox 94 is also giving Android users the ability to tailor Pocket recommendations that show up on the homescreen by selecting different story topics they are interested in. According to a screenshot shared by Mozilla, topics include things like technology, health,...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758289/firefox-94-new-mobile-homescreen-mozilla"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758289/firefox-94-new-mobile-homescreen-mozilla"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758289/firefox-94-new-mobile-homescreen-mozilla</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
