<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-07T14:39:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:39:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:39:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple introduces Siri for third-party devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Na6kHEQOPltkp6vsxMt9OfrGW3A=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418452/lcimg_bdd5a604_baa2_4518_a03e_bf828a525d3e.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TfREqO"&gt;Siri is finally coming to third-party devices. Apple announced at its WWDC keynote that HomeKit accessory makers will be able to integrate Siri voice control into their devices later this year. The voice assistant will be routed through a HomePod if the devices are connected to your network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4EfaW1"&gt;Apple hasn’t released a comprehensive list of devices and brands that will support Siri. The company demoed it on an Ecobee thermostat during its WWDC keynote presentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ugvo3D"&gt;Apple also announced a number of new smart home features. Home Keys, which allow you to remotely lock and unlock doors, are now supported in the Wallet app. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BAAvmp"&gt;The HomePod Mini will support lossless audio in Apple Music later this year and will be able to function...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:33:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:33:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple lets users see family members’ Health data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e5CY5t2zUbaXFVslJ_h3STUGkC0=/5x256:806x790/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418399/image__3_.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PvtRRE"&gt;Apple will let people share the data from their Health app with family members or others, the company announced. It’s one of a new slate of heath features for iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPLlL9"&gt;With permission, someone can share access to their overall heart rate and movement data. They’ll also be able to share access to alerts like a high heart rate or change in mobility. The person they’re sharing the data with can message them directly about any changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EY2NwH"&gt;Apple is also adding another health metric, called walking steadiness, to the Health app. It will use mobility data already collected by the iPhone to monitor for any changes to factors like balance or walking patterns, and will tell users if they’re at an increased risk of falling. The app will also include...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522872/health-app-family-mobility-fall-risk-wwdc-2021"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522872/health-app-family-mobility-fall-risk-wwdc-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522872/health-app-family-mobility-fall-risk-wwdc-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:26:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:26:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>macOS Monterey lets you run Shortcuts and share input and files between Macs and iPads</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lbbg3kwo6UfUluS7bo1ST7-BCvM=/5x0:1564x1039/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418342/image.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cSXpW2"&gt;Apple has announced the next version of macOS at its WWDC keynote, after showing off iOS, iPadOS, and watchOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8Ih2W"&gt;The company is promising even more interoperability with iOS, including the ability to share a keyboard and mouse between a Mac and an iPad. The feature is similar to the one found on Logitech keyboards and mice, letting you seemingly move your cursor and files between a Mac and iPad. Macs are also getting the ability to act as an AirPlay target, allowing you to use your Mac’s screen and sound to play content from your iPhone and iPad (or even other Macs if you’re feeling spicy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shoSvl"&gt;Apple has also announced that Macs would be getting its Shortcuts automation application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCx6Qj"&gt;In addition, Safari is getting a bit of a redesign, with tab...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:11:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:11:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces watchOS 8 with new health features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sdhKXMz81ZBxPVMiDspBUy5xYk4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418263/vpavic_120916__1220_0325_close.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Vjeran Pavic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lnGUo5"&gt;Apple has just announced watchOS 8, the latest version of the company’s smartwatch platform for the Apple Watch. The new software succeeds last year’s watchOS 7 and is going to be first available for developers to test their apps with starting today, with a public beta coming in July. A final public release is expected later this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fBSX64"&gt;Apple is debuting a new Mindfulness app, an extension of the Breathe app that nags you to breathe throughout the day. It’s adding new animations and other features to help you relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLsMth"&gt;The Fitness app is getting more workout types for tai chi and pilates. The Apple Watch’s Health app will explicitly track your respiratory rate and notify you if it’s outside of your normal patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:07:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:07:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple adds welcome privacy features to Mail, Safari</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eqpTNvKXHPluqTh87_h-ccAycoM=/99x0:1140x694/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418247/Screen_Shot_2021_06_07_at_1.49.43_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6NgMr4"&gt;Apple has always stressed user privacy as part of its core mission. At its WWDC 2021 event, it announced it would be adding a spate of powerful new functions to Mail and Safari, as well as giving users broader insight into what their installed apps are doing with their information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eY8N9Y"&gt;First, Apple’s Mail appears to have declared war on tracking pixels, which can be included in some emails to give third parties insight into if or when their messages have been opened — though it didn’t provide much detail on how it will win said war. Mail will also, according to Apple’s manager of user privacy software Katie Skinner, now hide user IP addresses by default. Safari, likewise, will hide IPs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xjyDso"&gt;More surprisingly, Apple announced it’s adding an App...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22502877/apple-app-privacy-report-ip-hiding-safari-mail-wwdc"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22502877/apple-app-privacy-report-ip-hiding-safari-mail-wwdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22502877/apple-app-privacy-report-ip-hiding-safari-mail-wwdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:07:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:07:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s iCloud Plus bundles a VPN, private email, and HomeKit camera storage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A promo image showing the logo of iCloud Plus." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bLa9GHinmTSBll7xopCL1PzMms8=/17x0:1682x1110/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418241/lcimg_49079014_177d_4b21_a9d0_f8e66c52c9a3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WuFNaz"&gt;Apple is amping up iCloud with a new set of features called iCloud Plus. The cloud storage service will now come with access to a VPN, burner email addresses, and unlimited storage for HomeKit-enabled home security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ng1oBX"&gt;The VPN, called Private Relay, will route your internet traffic through two relays in order to mask who’s browsing and where that data is coming from. The burner email feature, called Hide My Email, lets you create single-use email addresses that will forward to your actual account; that way, you can provide a junk email to a service you don’t trust in case it starts spamming you. Apple already offers a similar feature through Sign In With Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QOfF98"&gt;Apple will also include unlimited storage for video from HomeKit-enabled...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522998/apple-icloud-plus-subscription-vpn-scurity-wwdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T14:07:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:07:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s Siri will finally work without an internet connection with on-device speech recognition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KK8VisBxpuvt5CYcB2Ws-Sue0E8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418233/acastro_180510_1777_siri_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t9Cvuf"&gt;Apple’s digital assistant Siri will process audio on-device by default in iOS 15, meaning you will be able to use the feature without an active internet connection. Apple says the upgrade will also make Siri faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a6WPQc"&gt;Processing audio on-device will make using Siri more private, says Apple. This follows the company’s well-established preference for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/13/16300464/apple-iphone-x-ai-neural-engine"&gt;implementing machine learning features on-device&lt;/a&gt;, rather than sending data away to the cloud to be processed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m0a4j3"&gt;“This addresses the biggest privacy concern we hear from voice assistants, which is unwanted audio recording,” said an Apple presenter during WWDC. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vFORhs"&gt;Obviously, if you don’t have an internet connection then you won’t be able to carry out certain Siri functions like &lt;em&gt;s...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T13:52:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T13:52:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is making AirPods easier to hear with and find</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pSYfrFbbC6ou2fLLS_00fXB5Syo=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418106/image.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NZ65dj"&gt;Apple has announced that AirPods will be getting some quality-of-life improvements with iOS 15, including the ability to boost the sound of people talking to you, better Find My support, and the ability to announce a wider range of notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KRWshn"&gt;Apple says the “Conversation Boost” feature will help people who have difficulties hearing other people’s voices when they’re talking. It will try to isolate the voice of the person in front of you, with sliders that let the user control how much ambient noise is let in.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hs690I"&gt;AirPods can already announce messages and texts, but now they’re getting the ability to read out other important notifications, like when a food delivery is made. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="svmuIk"&gt;The easy-to-lose headphones are also getting more...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522951/apple-airpods-find-my-hearing-accesibility-notification-wwdc"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522951/apple-airpods-find-my-hearing-accesibility-notification-wwdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522951/apple-airpods-find-my-hearing-accesibility-notification-wwdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T13:46:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T13:46:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>You’ll soon be able to use your iPhone as ID at the airport </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Qjszg5OO_jfubA5zEIYL7HVl5E=/8x255:1780x1436/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418088/lcimg_b1bc491d_e93b_41f1_8ac3_a0717ab1150b.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5F16ta"&gt;Apple has announced a forthcoming update to its Wallet app that will allow you to use your iPhone as digital identification in US airports. The company showed how you’ll be able to scan your driver’s license or state ID in participating US states, which will then be encrypted and stored in the iPhone’s secure enclave. The company says it’s working with the TSA to enable the iPhone to be used as identification at airport security checkpoints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zW2bsG"&gt;As well as secure ID, Apple says it’s working to allow hotels to distribute room card keys via Apple Wallet, allowing you to collect a room key before you arrive at a hotel. Home keys and work keys were also announced as coming to the Wallet app. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;ID cards can be...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-07T13:40:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T13:40:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces iPadOS 15 with homescreen and multitasking improvements</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QC65DFvSMlddSn8fgPa76KdVy2k=/81x0:2136x1370/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69418064/Screen_Shot_2021_06_07_at_1.39.39_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Widgets can be placed anywhere on the home screen in iPadOS 15.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0W3pe4"&gt;Weeks after introducing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;most powerful iPad Pro devices ever&lt;/a&gt;, Apple is today announcing the latest version of iPadOS — and there’s a clear focus on making Apple’s tablets more capable productivity machines. At least if you find yourself using split-screen mode a lot, that is. Otherwise, there aren’t any radical changes for the platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWsVrl"&gt;As rumored, iPadOS 15 will make the homescreen more customizable and allow for more flexible placement of widgets. You can now stick them anywhere you’d like, a capability that came to iOS 14 last year. But iPadOS 14 didn’t offer the same functionality, and widgets could only be placed in the Today View sidebar despite the tablet’s vast screen real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uasWDl"&gt;Apple is also bringing the App Library to...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463812/apple-ipados-15-features-productivity-release-date"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463812/apple-ipados-15-features-productivity-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463812/apple-ipados-15-features-productivity-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
