<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 10:25:37 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Google Stadia adds free trials for 'Control' and 'Riders Republic']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in October, Google Stadia <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-introduces-free-trials-with-its-own-hello-engineer-game-092557521.html">introduced</a> free trials with its <em>Hello Engineer</em> game. While the service lets users try any game they want with a $10-per-month Pro subscription, it was the first time free users were given the chance to test a game before purchase. Now, according to <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/02/google-stadia-adds-more-free-trials-control-for-30-minutes-riders-republic-for-2-hours/"><em>9to5Google</em></a>, Stadia is giving free users the opportunity to take two more games for a spin before they have to buy them. One of those games is <em>Control: Ultimate Edition</em>, which recently just came out for the platform.</p><p><em>Ultimate Edition</em> contains the core <em>Control</em> game, along with the expansions that were released for it. Like <em>Hello Engineer</em>, players will be able to test it out for 30 minutes before they have to decide whether to pay $40 for a copy. The other game is Ubisoft&#39;s recently released <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-riders-republic-release-date-195412051.html"><em>Riders Republic</em></a>, a massively multiplayer extreme sports game, where teams can battle each other on bikes, skis, snowboards and in flying wingsuits. Players will get the chance to try it out for two hours instead of just 30 minutes, perhaps because half an hour might barely be enough to cover tutorials when there are several extreme sports to choose from. Besides, <em>Riders Republic</em> isn&#39;t cheap and costs $60 to purchase.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>With the addition of these two games, we can probably expect Google to make more titles available for free trial in the future. It could be an effective way to get people who&#39;d rather own the titles they play interested in purchasing from Stadia instead of from other gaming platforms.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-free-trials-control-riders-republic-102537840.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">80facd8b-7d43-4426-895c-6e25ec416689</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 10:25:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635934766</ingested><modified>2021-11-03T10:19:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/47f78210-3c86-11ec-bfff-741576379f38" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/47f78210-3c86-11ec-bfff-741576379f38" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Stadia]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Stadia]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple sold a record number of MacBooks last quarter, says Strategy Analytics]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple got some of its MacBook sales mojo back last quarter thanks to discounts on the MacBook Air, according to the research firm <a href="https://news.strategyanalytics.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Strategy-Analytics-Notebook-PC-Demand-Remained-Healthy-in-Q3-2021-Growing-8-Year-on-Year/default.aspx"><em>Strategy Analytics</em></a><em>. </em>The company sold a record 6.5 million MacBooks in Q3 2021, up 10 percent over last year — no doubt contributing to its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-q3-2021-earnings-financial-results-205158698.html">blockbuster Mac quarter</a>. Meanwhile, Chromebook sales actually declined for the first time since the pandemic started, <a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS48346621"><em>IDC</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p><p>Laptop sales in general were up eight percent over last year to 66.8 million units, due largely to commercial and educational sales. That was aided in part by &quot;higher discounts on premium products like MacBook Air and gaming notebooks,&quot; according to <em>Strategy Analytics</em>.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e21f57d0-3c83-11ec-adbf-16c446036650" style="height:720;width:1280;" alt="Report: Apple sold a record number of MacBooks last quarter" data-uuid="2cb6e9a9-2c9e-3f76-84cd-4a1ef48bea5c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Strategy Analytics</div></figure><p>Sales could have been even higher if not for a shortage of components and higher freight costs that drove prices higher and caused some delays. Lenovo topped the sales list for the fourth quarter in a row with 15.3 million units shipped, with HP, Dell, Apple and ASUS rounding out the top five.&nbsp;</p><p>Chromebook and tablet sales didn&#39;t fare so well though, according to <em>IDC</em>. Chromebook sales tumbled by 29.8 percent year-over-year to 6.5 million units, thanks largely to &quot;saturation&quot; in the education market. &quot;Many schools and governments blew out their budgets to provide devices for remote learning and even consumers aggressively purchased devices for learning in 2020,&quot; the firm wrote. Lenovo again topped the sales list for Chromebooks, followed by Acer, Dell, HP and Samsung.</p><p>Tablet sales slowed 9.4 percent to 42.3 million units, due to reduced demand and limited supply. The exception to that trend was Apple, which saw iPad sales grow 4.6 percent over last year to 14.7 million units. That dominated the category, as Samsung sold just over half that number (7.5 million), followed by Amazon, Lenovo and Huawei.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/report-apple-sold-a-record-number-of-mac-books-last-quarter-091233817.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">86a17759-c468-4efb-9539-c2ff5ccc6b87</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 09:12:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635930761</ingested><modified>2021-11-03T09:12:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0ff55a10-3c84-11ec-adff-773fc86dedf8" width="2000" height="1334" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0ff55a10-3c84-11ec-adff-773fc86dedf8" width="2000" height="1334" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Report: Apple sold a record number of MacBooks last quarter]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Report: Apple sold a record number of MacBooks last quarter]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HBO Max teases post-apocalyptic series 'Station Eleven']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>HBO Max has <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22759800/station-eleven-teaser-hbo-max-mackenzie-davis">released</a> the first teaser video and images for its adaptation of Emily St. John Mandel&#39;s post-apocalyptic novel, <em>Station Eleven</em>. In the short video, you&#39;ll get glimpses of Jeevan (Himesh Patel), Kirsten (Matilda Lawler as her younger version and Mackenzie Davis as her older version) and the other main characters of the story, as they face a pandemic that ravaged most of the planet.&nbsp;</p><p>The teaser trailer starts off with Jeevan and young Kirsten purchasing carts upon carts of food from a nearly empty supermarket, as well as a a lone cashier who didn&#39;t know where to go. From there, we see a montage of bleak landscapes, a ferris wheel and a building on fire, a theater performance (which is a central element to the story), a mysterious figure, people panicking and then trying to rebuild what they lost.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Mandel&#39;s novel is set in the Great Lakes region before and after a fictional swine flu pandemic killed most of the world&#39;s population. According to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22759800/station-eleven-teaser-hbo-max-mackenzie-davis"><em>Polygon</em></a>, it started shooting in Chicago in January 2020, but because of the real-life pandemic still affecting us right now, production had to be moved to Mississauga, Ontario and concluded in July. The 10-episode limited series was directed by Hiro Murai (<em>Atlanta</em>), while Patrick Somerville (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-made-for-love-surveillance-chip-tech-dystopia-202900680.html"><em>Made for Love</em></a>) served as writer and showrunner. It will be available to stream on HBO Max, starting on December 16th.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-teases-station-eleven-071727998.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ae2fe7d7-24b2-41ca-8ccd-e6d6e52c0b69</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 07:17:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635923830</ingested><modified>2021-11-03T07:17:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/db0dcfa0-3c6d-11ec-b19f-aae7f39315b8" width="1600" height="984" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/db0dcfa0-3c6d-11ec-b19f-aae7f39315b8" width="1600" height="984" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[University of Adelaide built a robot spider to scan Australia’s Naracoorte Caves]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the southeast of South Australia lie the <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=Naracoorte+Caves&amp;rlz=1C1FHFK_enCA963CA963&amp;oq=Naracoorte+Caves&amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j69i60l3.296j0j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">Naracoorte Caves</a>. The national park is an UNESCO World Heritage Site known for its stalactites, stalagmites and prehistoric fossils. Recently, a group of students from the University of Adelaide built a robot to complete a 3D scan of the site. The project, called <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/matthewkingprofile_ingenuity-ai-autonomoussystems-activity-6858925387511152640-OAnH/">CaveX</a>, saw the group create 15 iterations of the model you see above before they settled on a final design. They went with a robot that walks on a set of six legs out of a fear that one with treads or wheels would damage the surface of the caves. The design also allowed it to traverse uneven terrain with a variety of different gaits.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/178eaf50-3c2b-11ec-ba56-36ef267c6394" style="height:338;width:600;" alt="CaveX scan" data-uuid="7d108654-aca4-3dab-9ace-41be51c6b6b1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Matthew King</div></figure><p>As for the 3D scans, the hope is that they’ll lead to new discoveries at the site. &quot;We&#39;re looking at the cave surface to find new cave entrances which will hopefully lead to new fossil deposits,&quot; Craig Williams, one of the PhD students who worked on the project, told <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-10-30/naracoorte-caves-robot-3d-map/100572344"><em><ins>ABC Australia</ins></em></a><em>. </em>&quot;That will help us enhance the range of knowledge on the fossils that are here.&quot; The team that worked on the project hopes a new generation of engineering students will continue to work on the robot. One day, they&#39;d like to see it take advantage of technologies like computer vision AI to make it better at its job.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/university-of-adelaide-cavex-spider-robot-224851184.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9b66109d-ad79-4733-a8d7-cd76c8a50c5c</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 22:48:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635892499</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T22:35:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/f3f1dd10-3c2a-11ec-9ef2-a20dacf13b37" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/f3f1dd10-3c2a-11ec-9ef2-a20dacf13b37" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Matthew King]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[CaveX Spider Bot]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[CaveX Spider Bot]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blizzard's first female leader, Jen Oneal, steps down amid ongoing gender discrimination suit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jen Oneal has stepped down from her role as co-leader of Blizzard, leaving Mike Ybarra as the head of the studio known for making Overwatch, World of Warcraft and Diablo. Oneal will temporarily transition to a new position, but will leave Activision Blizzard (fine, and King) at the end of the year.</p><p>Activision Blizzard is facing a handful of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html">lawsuits and investigations</a> into reports of sexual harassment, gropings, and systemic gender discrimination at the studio, stemming from the leadership down. Oneal and Ybarra took over as co-leaders of Blizzard <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-leader-j-allen-brack-steps-down-133538233.html">in August</a> after president J. Allen Brack was named in the original California lawsuit, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-leader-j-allen-brack-steps-down-133538233.html">leading to his dismissal</a>. Oneal was the first woman in a president role since Activision&#39;s founding in 1979.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Oneal published <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/blizzard/23738005/a-message-from-jen-oneal">an open letter</a> to the Blizzard community, reading in part as follows:</p><p><em>I have made the decision to step away from co-leading Blizzard Entertainment and will transition to a new position before departing ABK at the end of the year. Effective immediately, Mike Ybarra will lead Blizzard. I am doing this not because I am without hope for Blizzard, quite the opposite — I’m inspired by the passion of everyone here, working towards meaningful, lasting change with their whole hearts. This energy has inspired me to step out and explore how I can do more to have games and diversity intersect, and hopefully make a broader industry impact that will benefit Blizzard (and other studios) as well. While I am not totally sure what form that will take, I am excited to embark on a new journey to find out.</em></p><p>After months of pressure from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-activision-walkout-184945869.html#">employees</a>, shareholders and government agencies, Activision Blizzard <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-ends-forced-arbitration-151427460.html">ended its policy</a> of forced arbitration in cases of sexual harassment and discrimination, and implemented a zero-tolerance approach to harassment at the studio. The original California lawsuit is ongoing.</p><div id="c1101ed7748145be8948184913123039"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/we5QWDLHwXE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Blizzard announced two big delays alongside news of Oneal&#39;s departure: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-delays-overwatch-2-diablo-4-212039519.html"><em>Overwatch 2 and Diablo IV</em></a>, neither of which was given a release window.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-leader-jen-oneal-step-down-mike-ybarra-213704384.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8cae657c-2c6b-44dc-8599-5f5b735b7fc1</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 21:37:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635889354</ingested><modified>2021-11-03T09:38:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/3650ce30-3c23-11ec-83ef-926953a4522f" width="2400" height="1350" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/3650ce30-3c23-11ec-83ef-926953a4522f" width="2400" height="1350" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blizzard]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Overwatch 2' and 'Diablo IV' have been delayed indefinitely]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Activision Blizzard is once again delaying <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-01-blizzard-overwatch-2-blizzcon-gameplay-trailer.html"><em>Overwatch 2</em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-20-diablo-iv-level-cap-ancient-items.html"><em>Diablo IV</em></a>. Following months of upheaval at its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-ends-forced-arbitration-151427460.html">Blizzard Entertainment subsidiary</a> stemming from a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html">sexual harassment lawsuit</a> the State of California filed in July, the publisher announced during its recent third-quarter 2021 earnings call that it&#39;s pushing those games back to give the teams working on them more time.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;While we are still planning to deliver a substantial amount of content from Blizzard next year, we are now planning for a later launch for <em>Overwatch 2 </em>and<em> Diablo IV </em>than originally envisaged,&quot; the company said.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="f764af15cba14511b1de97c5f750d1ab"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Diablo IV and Overwatch 2 delayed <a href="https://t.co/4pr9c0OEdz">pic.twitter.com/4pr9c0OEdz</a></p>— Stephen Totilo (@stephentotilo) <a href="https://twitter.com/stephentotilo/status/1455635542054477831?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>It did not share a revised release date for either title. &quot;These decisions will push will push the financial uplift that we had expected to see next year,&quot; Activision said. &quot;But we are confident that is the right course of action for our people, our players, and the long-term successes of our franchises.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>Blizzard unveiled <em>Overwatch 2 </em>and <em>Diablo IV </em>at Blizzcon 2019. At the time, the studio made it clear that both games were in early development, but the expectation was that it would release them sometime in 2021. Activision dashed those hopes at the start of the year when it said <a href="https://www.engadget.com/overwatch-2-diablo-4-not-2021-234552414.html">neither title would come out in 2021</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-delays-overwatch-2-diablo-4-212039519.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">029783a0-cf7c-4396-986e-57b8bfe06805</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 21:20:39 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635889354</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T21:42:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0a49bc60-3c1f-11ec-afff-3507d96ceced" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0a49bc60-3c1f-11ec-afff-3507d96ceced" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blizzard Entertainment ]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Diablo 4]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Report links most climate change denial on Facebook to 10 publications]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most climate change misinformation comes from only a handful of sources. That’s according to a new <a href="https://f4d9b9d3-3d32-4f3a-afa6-49f8bf05279a.usrfiles.com/ugd/f4d9b9_16ccca9c25a04445a69dcd0298fd530d.pdf">report</a> from the <a href="https://www.counterhate.com/toxicten">Center for Countering Digital Hate</a> (CCDH). The organization found that ten publishers are responsible for 69 percent of all interactions with climate change denial content on Facebook. Included in the group, which the CCDH titled “The Toxic Ten,” are <em>Breitbart</em>, <em>Russia Today</em> and <em>Media Research Center</em>, which has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2019/01/10/how-fossil-fuel-industry-got-media-think-climate-change-was-debatable/">ties to the fossil fuel industry</a>.</p><p>The findings broadly mirror that of another report the CCDH published earlier in the year, which found that as much as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/anti-vaccine-misinformation-report-12-accounts-212245856.html">73 percent of vaccine misinformation</a> on Facebook can be linked to only 12 individuals dubbed the “disinformation dozen.” That study has been widely cited by US lawmakers who have called on social media platforms to do more to address the “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-surgeon-general-health-misinformation-advisory-191241209.html">urgent threat</a>” misinformation represents to public health.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As it did with the earlier disinformation dozen report, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-new-name-meta-182151399.html">Meta</a>, Facebook’s parent company, disputed the methodology the CCDH used to compile its latest study. “The 700,000 interactions this report says were on climate denial represent 0.3 percent of the over 200 million interactions on English public climate change content from Pages and public groups over the same time period,” a spokesperson for the company said. It also pointed to the recently announced expansion of features like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/meta-facebook-climate-change-000051729.html">Climate Change Information Center</a> as evidence of its commitment to tackling misinformation on the topic.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/11/02/facebook-climate-change-misinformation-breitbart/"><em>The Washington Post</em></a>, Imran Ahmed, the chief executive of the CCDH, said the organization looked at approximately 7,000 articles published between October 2020 and October 2021. He called the sample “robust” and said there was enough data “to derive representative finds of trends.”</p><p>Additionally, the report examined the financial incentives involved in publishing climate change denial content. The CCDH estimates eight of the companies included in the Toxic Ten made $5.3 million in Google ad revenue over the last six months, with $1.7 million going to the search giant. &quot;We recently <a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/11221321?hl=en">announced a new policy</a> that explicitly prohibits publishers and YouTube Creators from monetizing content that promotes climate change denial. This policy will go into effect on <a href="https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/9336650?hl=en">November 8</a> and our enforcement will be as targeted as removing ads from individual pages with violating content,&quot; a spokesperson for Google told Engadget.</p><p>“When you put it all together, you’ve got these two industries, Big Oil and Big Tech, and they are the two industries that pose the greatest threat to the survival of our species,” Ahmed told <em>The Post</em>.</p><p>The timing of The Toxic Ten report comes as delegates from around the world meet at the UN’s COP26 climate summit in Scotland in what’s been described as “<a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-government-and-politics-china-climate-environment-and-nature-01317e4c6f5630f29024753209b48aef">the world’s last best chance</a>” to curb greenhouse gas emissions. Without dramatic reductions, the planet is currently on track for a “catastrophic” 2.7 degree Celsius rise in global temperatures. With every additional degree of warming beyond the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-08-major-un-report-climate-change-worse.html">1.5-degree target</a> put forward by the Paris Agreement, there’s a greater risk of the planet passing specific tipping points that could lead to even more dramatic changes to the climate.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/climate-change-denial-report-ccdh-205333083.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">da9a489c-6a25-4dd1-9ba9-c4951bcaf89b</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:53:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635886763</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T20:59:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Climate Change]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ea2d9b80-3c15-11ec-b9f7-4763ab09fc55" width="3907" height="2605" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ea2d9b80-3c15-11ec-b9f7-4763ab09fc55" width="3907" height="2605" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[POOL New / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden puts on headphones to listen to speeches during "Action on Forests and Land-Use" event at the UN Climate Change Conference (COP26) in Glasgow, Scotland, Britain, November 2, 2021. Erin Schaff/Pool via REUTERS]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[CLIMATE-UN/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roku will effectively ban porn channels on March 1st, 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Porn fans with Roku players will have to turn to other devices before long. <em>Protocol</em> has <a href="https://www.protocol.com/roku-porn-ban-private-channels">learned</a> that Roku will effectively ban channels from Pornhub and other porn services on March 1st, 2022. The company is <a href="https://blog.roku.com/developer/2021/10/26/idk">dropping</a> support for &quot;non-certified&quot; private channels on that day in favor of beta channels that are limited to 20 users. That&#39;s potentially better for testers, but a headache for adult content providers who used those channels to get around Roku&#39;s restrictions on regular channels.</p><p>Roku has been accused of largely ignoring private channels before. That didn&#39;t necessarily clash with porn sites, but it did create issues with both rights holders <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-06-29-mexican-court-halts-sales-roku-hackability.html">worried about privacy</a> as well as critics concerned Roku was enabling the spread of harmful misinformation and violence. Roku eventually <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-15-infowars-has-a-platform-new-roku-channel.html">pulled InfoWars&#39; channel</a> and issued warnings that it might remove illegal private channels without warning.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We&#39;ve asked Roku for comment. Unlike policy decisions (however temporary) at sites <a href="https://www.engadget.com/onlyfans-big-banks-war-adult-content-174041161.html">like OnlyFans</a>, though this isn&#39;t likely the result of anti-porn mindsets from partners. Rather, this may be more about control. Roku doesn&#39;t have to worry about channel operators bypassing its official system, particularly those that might get the company in trouble. Whatever the reasoning, this may prompt porn fans to switch to Android TV, Fire TV or browser-equipped platforms that still offer ways to watch racy material.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roku-porn-ban-201136254.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">705c0e7e-5539-4ac8-841e-7f6920cac34f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:11:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635883901</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T20:11:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/094af260-3c11-11ec-aaf3-0cf9eb086737" width="5184" height="3364" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/094af260-3c11-11ec-aaf3-0cf9eb086737" width="5184" height="3364" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Marvin Samuel Tolentino Pineda via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Front left view of a Roku box on a white background]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Front left view of a Roku box on a white background]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lenovo's Flex 5 Chromebook is on sale for $300 right now]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;re going to use a Chromebook as your daily driver — or even just more than once or twice a day — you should get a decently powerful one. Perhaps unsurprisingly, even Chrome OS machines can get expensive when you start to spec them out, but <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Lenovo&#39;s Flex 5 Chromebook" href="https://amzn.to/3wcZ2W2">Lenovo&#39;s Flex 5 Chromebook</a> has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-chromebooks-160054646.html">one of our favorites</a> precisely for how much value it packs at a relatively affordable $430. Amazon now has this versatile Chrome OS laptop at the best price we&#39;ve seen — only $300. That&#39;s $130 off its normal price and an all-time low.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3wcZ2W2" id="f335e64448da4c46a7c67e6c52bee178" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook at Amazon - $300</a><p>The model on sale runs on a 10th-generation Core i3 processor, 4GB of RAM and 64GB of storage. While the latter two are pretty common in entry- to mid-level Chromebooks, the Core i3 processor will help this laptop feel zippier than others. While we initially weren&#39;t thrilled by the 4GB of RAM, we found that the Flex 5 Chromebook was more than capable of running multiple tabs simultaneously. As for storage, 64GB should be enough for most people who do most of their work in the Chrome browser anyway. Even at its normal price, the Flex 5 Chromebook provides a lot of power compared to other similarly priced devices — but at $300, it&#39;s a fantastic value.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Most Chrome OS machines in this price range tend to sacrifice on style, and while Lenovo&#39;s laptop isn&#39;t ugly by any means, it&#39;s not the slickest either. It weights about three pounds and measures 0.66-inches thick, but it does have a handy convertible design so you could use it as a tablet or even in tent mode to watch TV shows and movies. It has a decent 1080p touchscreen, too, along with a decent array of ports that includes two USB-C ports and a USB-A port. Lenovo did a good job of combining most key features of a good Chromebook into this laptop, which is why we continue to recommend it both when it&#39;s on sale or at regular price.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-flex-5-chromebook-is-on-sale-for-300-right-now-183046713.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8185a6c0-1029-47d2-8d7f-a117aa6157a9</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635876489</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T18:08:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/81be5090-bae2-11ea-9fff-2a17206d93cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/81be5090-bae2-11ea-9fff-2a17206d93cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Harry Potter: Wizards Unite' is shutting down on January 31st, 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Niantic is ending support for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-24-harry-potter-wizards-unite-launch-hands-on.html"><em><ins>Harry Potter: Wizards Unite</ins></em></a>. The studio <a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/wizardsunite-finale/?hl=en"><ins>announced today</ins></a> it will shutter the AR game on January 31st, 2022. Ahead of the sunset, it plans to delist the title from the App Store, Google Play and Galaxy Store on December 6th. That same day, it will also remove all in-app purchases from the experience.</p><p>Niantic first launched <em>Wizards Unite</em> back in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-20-harry-potter-wizards-unite-available-early.html"><ins>2019</ins></a>. And in many ways, it never replicated the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-31-pokemon-go-1-billion-downloads.html"><ins>runaway success of </ins><em><ins>Pokémon Go</ins></em></a>. “Not all games are meant to last forever,” the company said of the decision to stop working on the title. “Our goal with <em>Harry Potter: Wizards Unite</em> was to bring the magic of the wizarding world to life for millions of players as they stepped outside and explored their neighborhoods. We accomplished that together, delivering a two-year narrative story arc that will soon complete.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>For Niantic, this is the second game it has decided to shut down in less than two months. In September, it announced it was discontinuing development on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/niantic-shutting-down-catan-world-explorers-201434004.html"><em><ins>Catan: World Explorers</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>before the game was even widely available outside of a few select markets. Then, as now, Niantic says it will take what it learned from the experience and apply it to future projects.</p><p>Presumably that includes <a href="https://www.engadget.com/niantic-pikmin-bloom-rollout-052408547.html"><em><ins>Pikmin Bloom</ins></em></a>, which recently launched in Singapore and Australia, as well as the upcoming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/niantic-hasbro-transformers-heavy-metal-ar-game-144544180.html"><em><ins>Transformers: Heavy Metal</ins></em></a>. In total, the studio says it’s working on nine games and apps, some of which will soft-launch next year.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/harry-potter-wizards-unite-shut-down-january-31-2022-181008602.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">18de2fac-1173-42a0-8f66-12dfa740fcfe</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 18:10:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635876016</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T18:00:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/f8bf4370-3c05-11ec-bfdb-528c4382b93d" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/f8bf4370-3c05-11ec-bfdb-528c4382b93d" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Niantic, Warner Bros.]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Harry Potter: Wizards Unite]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Harry Potter: Wizards Unite]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Skyrim' is getting the board game treatment]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ready to buy yet another version of <em>Skyrim</em>? After coming to nearly <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bethesda-10th-anniversary-edition-skyrim-084030796.html"><ins>every system imaginable</ins></a>, Bethesda’s seminal 2011 RPG is about to get the tabletop treatment. Modiphius Entertainment, the company behind <a href="https://www.modiphius.com/fallout.html"><em><ins>Fallout: Wasteland Warfare</ins></em></a>, is working on <a href="https://www.gamespress.com/Battle-Dragons-Draugr-Trolls-and-More-as-You-Fight-to-Save-Skyrim-in-t"><em>The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim - The Adventure Game</em></a><em>. </em>Set to come out sometime next summer, the game will allow you to revisit Tamriel’s frozen north as an agent of the Imperial Blades. You can play either by yourself or with up to three other friends.</p><p>The narrative-driven game will ship with two campaigns made up of three chapters. Modiphius says each one should take about 90 to 120 minutes to complete. Provided you don’t get distracted by side quests and exploration (not an easy feat in any Elder Scrolls game), you can expect your initial playthrough to take about 12 hours. Worry not, you can “save” your progress at any point, and pick up where you left off. The decisions you make during a playthrough will shape how the story unfolds. And with a deck of about 600 cards driving the narrative, no two sessions should play out exactly the same.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you want to read more about the game, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/22757411/skyrim-board-game-campaign-price-release-date"><em><ins>Polygon</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>has a detailed preview. You can pre-order <em>The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim - The Adventure Game </em>through <a href="https://gamefound.com/projects/modiphius/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-the-board-game#/section/project-story"><ins>Gamefound</ins></a>. The first 2,011 people to back the project’s base tier can get the game by itself for £68 (approximately $92). For everyone else, it will start at £82 ($111).</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/modiphius-entertainment-skyrim-the-adventure-game-174250349.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bad74ce5-032a-4900-bd67-4b0135c5ccb6</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:42:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635873128</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T17:12:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/807b4650-3bfd-11ec-a7af-54887cae2396" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/807b4650-3bfd-11ec-a7af-54887cae2396" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Modiphius Entertainment]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Skyrim]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Skyrim]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook is shutting down its face recognition system]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Meta is further <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-03-facebook-stops-scanning-faces-by-default.html">backing away from facial recognition</a>. The company has <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/11/update-on-use-of-face-recognition/">announced</a> it&#39;s shutting down the Face Recognition system on Facebook in the &quot;coming weeks.&quot; You&#39;ll no longer be automatically recognized in photos if you opted in to the feature, and the Facebook team will delete over a billion facial recognition templates. Automatic Alt Text&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-explains-ai-alt-text-for-photo-descriptions-154018448.html">descriptions for the visually impaired</a> will also stop naming people detected in photos.</p><p>The company said it made the decision following &quot;growing concerns&quot; about the broader use of facial recognition, including &quot;uncertainty&quot; about regulation of the technology. While Meta believed face recognition could still be helpful in some situations, such as gaining access to a locked account, it felt a &quot;narrower,&quot; more privacy-oriented approach was a better fit than the broader outgoing strategy. On-device recognition wouldn&#39;t require sharing data with outside servers, for example.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There was already significant pressure to shut down the system. Meta (then Facebook) <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-facial-recognition-lawsuit-650-million-191451396.html">settled a privacy lawsuit</a> over facial recognition for $650 million in 2020, and it likely isn&#39;t eager to grapple with similar cases. Governments ranging from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/massachusetts-statewide-police-ban-facial-recognition-bill-064534909.html">Massachusetts</a> to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/european-parliament-facial-recognition-ban-ai-bias-165833826.html">European Union</a> have either passed or are strongly considering at least partial bans on facial recognition use. Facebook&#39;s opt-in system may not have explicitly run afoul of those laws, but the message is clear: wide-ranging facial recognition systems aren&#39;t very welcome.</p><p>As it stands, Meta isn&#39;t alone. Amazon now has an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rekognition-police-ban-222425615.html">indefinite ban</a> on police use of its Rekognition platform, and Google has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-13-google-hold-off-selling-facial-recognition-technology.html">declined to sell</a> facial recognition tech since 2018. Although Meta hasn&#39;t completely given up on the concept, it&#39;s clearly eager to be seen as forward-thinking — and continue mending its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tim-cook-privacy-cpdp-2021-slams-facebook-184333398.html">less-than-stellar reputation</a> for privacy.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-shuts-down-face-recognition-171737198.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">774cc24b-d5b3-42c9-bcfa-b4727bc4e71d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:17:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635874794</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T17:40:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-08/9be91600-ba1e-11e9-9c9e-5422a36fc275" width="3500" height="2275" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-08/9be91600-ba1e-11e9-9c9e-5422a36fc275" width="3500" height="2275" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A picture illustration shows a Facebook logo reflected in a person's eye, in Zenica, March 13, 2015. Facebook Inc recorded a slight increase in government requests for account data in the second half of 2014, according to its Global Government Requests Report, which includes information about content removal.Requests for account data increased to 35,051 in the second half of 2014 from 34,946 in the first half, with requests from countries such as India rising and those from others including United States and Germany falling, the report by the world's largest Internet social network showed. Facebook said it restricted 9,707 pieces of content for violating local laws, 11 percent more than in the first half, with access restricted to 5,832 pieces in India and 3,624 in Turkey. Picture taken on March 13. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic (BOSNIA AND HERZEGOVINA - Tags: SOCIETY PORTRAIT SCIENCE TECHNOLOGY BUSINESS TELECOMS TPX IMAGES OF THE DAY)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FACEBOOK-DATA/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix starts rolling out mobile games to all Android subscribers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/netflix/">Netflix</a> is taking a big step forward with its gaming ambitions. <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/let-the-games-begin-a-new-way-to-experience-entertainment-on-mobile">Starting today</a>, all subscribers can play five mobile games on Android devices at no extra cost by downloading them from the Google Play store on phones and tablets. The games will be available through the Netflix app starting on November 3rd as part of a gradual rollout. As for iOS users, they can access the games at a later date.</p><p>In August, Netflix started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-mobile-games-app-subscription-test-android-poland-stranger-things-155325550.html">testing games</a> in its Android app in Poland with <em>Stranger Things 1984</em> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-30-stranger-things-3-the-game-ios-android.html"><em>Stranger Things 3</em></a><em>. </em>The test <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-mobile-games-casual-spain-italy-154522886.html">expanded to Spain and Italy</a> the following month with three other casual games — <em>Shooting Hoops</em>, <em>Teeter Up</em> and <em>Card Blast</em> — none of which are connected to Netflix shows or movies.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The games have no ads or in-app purchases. You can access them on your phone or tablet by going to the games section of the app&#39;s homepage or through the games tab. Once you select a game, you can download it from the Google Play Store or (soon) the App Store, and play it via the Netflix app.</p><div id="0aa86214f7174e2f867f898d081a48ee"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🎮📱 Let the Games Begin📱🎮<br><br>Tomorrow, Netflix Games will start rolling out on the Netflix mobile app. First on Android, with iOS on the way.<br><br>It’s early days, but we’re excited to start bringing you exclusive games, with no ads, no additional fees and no in-app purchases. <a href="https://t.co/ofNGF4b8At">pic.twitter.com/ofNGF4b8At</a></p>— Netflix Geeked (@NetflixGeeked) <a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1455580571959054341?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Games will default to the preferred language in your Netflix profile. However, if a game isn&#39;t yet available in that language, it will default to English. Some games will work offline too.</p><p>Everyone with a profile on a Netflix account can play the games without the need for a separate subscription. However, the games aren&#39;t available on kids profiles. Users who have set up a PIN to prevent access to adult profiles will need to enter their code to play games too.</p><p>After experimenting with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-headspace-unwind-your-mind-june-15-170552142.html">interactive shows</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-wwe-interactive-horror-movie-escape-the-undertaker-the-new-day-185934596.html">movies</a> over the last few years, Netflix has made it clear it&#39;s eager to gain a bigger foothold in gaming. During its Q2 earnings call in July, the company said its most serious gaming push to date would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-q2-2021-earnings-204531144.html">start on mobile</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Netflix says the initial batch of five titles are just the beginning of its gaming aspirations. In September, the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-buys-night-school-studio-221737286.html">bought a game studio</a> for the first time in the form of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/oxenfree/"><em>Oxenfree</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>developer Night School Studio.</p><p>&quot;Just like our series, films and specials, we want to design games for any level of play and every kind of player, whether you’re a beginner or a lifelong gamer,&quot; Mike Verdu, Netflix vice president of game development, <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/let-the-games-begin-a-new-way-to-experience-entertainment-on-mobile">wrote in a blog post</a>.</p><p><strong>Update 11/2 2:15PM ET: </strong>Clarifying the rollout timeline on Android.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-games-mobile-stranger-things-android-ios-171232076.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1451bb35-2edb-453f-a05a-d5de1b6ec691</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:12:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635876956</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T18:16:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b4111380-3bff-11ec-b337-c90ed481b33e" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b4111380-3bff-11ec-b337-c90ed481b33e" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Games on the Netflix app]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Games on the Netflix app]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft makes a vague commitment to metaverse gaming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft&#39;s metaverse ambitions extend well beyond a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-mesh-for-teams-multiverse-work-150047792.html">handful of Teams features</a>. <em>The Verge</em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759379/microsoft-xbox-metaverse-halo-minecraft-flight-sim">reports</a> chief executive Satya Nadella <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-02/microsoft-s-own-metaverse-is-coming-and-it-will-have-powerpoint?sref=ExbtjcSG">told <em>Bloomberg</em></a> the company is &quot;absolutely&quot; planning on creating a gaming metaverse with &quot;full 3D&quot; worlds. The claim was about as vague as can be, and didn&#39;t include a timeline or software, but it&#39;s (eventually) in the works.</p><p>The question, of course, is just what those metaverse experiences will look like. Nadella wasn&#39;t exactly clear on the definition of a metaverse and believed that games like <em>Halo</em>, <em>Minecraft</em> and even <em>Flight Simulator</em> were simpler &quot;2D&quot; metaverses. Sorry, Nadella, but they&#39;re not — merely having a multiplayer space doesn&#39;t create a metaverse, especially not with match-oriented games like <em>Halo</em>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The potential is there, though. Microsoft has dabbled in metaverse-like projects such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-07-08-minecraft-hololens-minecon.html"><em>Minecraft</em> on HoloLens</a> and the defunct <a href="https://www.engadget.com/minecraft-earth-shutdown-june-30-181516498.html"><em>Minecraft Earth</em></a>. The software creator could easily translate lessons learned from that software to a shared virtual environment, even it looks nothing like any of the company&#39;s best-known franchises.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-metaverse-gaming-xbox-170401641.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3875366b-6f3f-4507-b60e-1ceb0f6358b1</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:04:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635872645</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T17:04:08+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/84acc260-3bfa-11ec-bf17-5cb7377c5968" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/84acc260-3bfa-11ec-bf17-5cb7377c5968" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ian Gavan via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LONDON, ENGLAND - NOVEMBER 07: In this image released on November 10th Xbox launches the Xbox Series X in the UK with a spectacular holographic installation at One New Change on November 7, 2020 in London, England. (Photo by Ian Gavan/Ian Gavan/Getty Images for Xbox UK)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Xbox Launches The Xbox Series X In The UK With A Spectacular Holographic Installation]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Razer's latest Productivity keyboard and mouse have 'silent' mechanical switches]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many members of the workforce are returning to the office after over 18 months of working from home. But folks might not be quite ready to give up on some of the luxuries they treated themselves to while they were cooped up in a private workspace. Perhaps you picked up a fancy <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/mechanical%20keyboard/"><ins>mechanical keyboard</ins></a>, but don&#39;t want to take it to the office, since the clacking might annoy your coworkers.</p><p>Perhaps with that in mind, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/razer/"><ins>Razer</ins></a> has a couple of new products in its Productivity lineup that might give you that enjoyable tactile typing and clicking sensation without infuriating those around you. The Pro Type Ultra wireless keyboard and new Pro Click Mini mouse have &quot;silent mechanical switches,&quot; which Razer says will offer a quieter experience wherever you&#39;re working from.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c0299990-3bf9-11ec-bbff-2ba22719d33c" style="height:3005;width:4583;" alt="Razer Pro Type Ultra keyboard." data-uuid="08057927-fc56-3120-92bb-a50042266956"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Razer</div></figure><p>The keyboard also has dampening foam to mitigate the sound, and Razer claims the keys will be good for up to 80 million presses. The fingerprint-resistant keycaps have a &quot;soft-touch coating for a luxurious, cushioned feel,&quot; according to the company. A wrist rest is included too.</p><p>Razer says you&#39;ll get up to 214 hours of use over Bluetooth and up to 207 hours of use via the low-latency Razer HyperSpeed Wireless connection before you need to recharge the keyboard. You can use it in wired mode over USB-C too. In addition, you&#39;ll be able to connect up to four devices and switch between them without having to re-pair them with a Pro Type Ultra.</p><p>If you&#39;re buying a new keyboard, you might want a matching mouse. As luck would have it, the Pro Click Mouse shares the Pro Type Ultra&#39;s white, dull-by-Razer-standards design. You can also pair the mouse (which isn&#39;t entirely silent <a href="https://www.razer.com/productivity/razer-pro-click-mini"><ins>based on an audio demo</ins></a> on Razer&#39;s website) with up to four devices.</p><p>There are a few scroll-wheel modes you can switch between depending on your current task. The free-spin mode is designed for zooming through long documents and webpages, tilt-click is geared toward horizontal scrolling and tactile mode is centered around more precise scrolling.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/cefa7a20-3bf9-11ec-97ff-b31d30f17c23" style="height:1966;width:3466;" alt="Razer Pro Click Mini mouse" data-uuid="d0ffc457-a2f2-3529-a442-43d4e032bebf"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Razer</div></figure><p>The mouse is rated for up to 15 million clicks. Razer claims you&#39;ll get up to 725 hours of battery life over Bluetooth and up to 465 hours via Razer HyperSpeed Wireless if you&#39;re using two AA batteries. There&#39;s an option to use only one battery if you&#39;d prefer to reduce the weight. If you decide to pick up both the keyboard and mouse, you can pair them to the same USB dongle to free up a port on your computer.&nbsp;</p><p>The new peripherals follow the Pro Type keyboard and Pro Click mouse Razer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-productivity-suite-keyboard-mouse-150056960.html"><ins>released in August 2020</ins></a>. Those devices had more muted designs than Razer&#39;s gaming-focused products to help them blend in a bit more.</p><p>The <a href="https://fave.co/3w8uQv2"><ins>$80</ins></a> Pro Click Mini is available now from Razer&#39;s website and other retailers. The Pro Type Ultra keyboard costs <a href="https://fave.co/3GFRMXo"><ins>$160</ins></a>, and will be available by the end of the year. Razer also introduced an enormous Pro Glide XXL mousepad with &quot;thick, high-density rubber foam,&quot; which will run you $30.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/razer-productivity-keyboard-mouse-silent-mechanical-switches-pro-type-ultra-pro-click-mini-164230459.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d9d57c15-4f82-4d1e-b14c-a74f9f9e44f2</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:42:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635871355</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T16:42:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Electronics Accessories]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/30a57cd0-3bf9-11ec-af1d-f08fc26b8d95" width="1465" height="824" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/30a57cd0-3bf9-11ec-af1d-f08fc26b8d95" width="1465" height="824" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Razer's Pro Type Ultra keyboard and Pro Click Mini mouse on top of the Pro Glide XXL mousepad.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Pro Type Ultra keyboard and Pro Click Mini mouse ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon Music now offers synchronized transcripts for podcasts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spotify isn&#39;t the only one banking on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-automatically-transcribe-podcasts-accessbility-mobile-165029865.html">podcast transcripts</a> to reel you in. Amazon Music is rolling out synchronized podcast transcripts in the US for both original shows and popular third-party series like <em>Modern Love</em> and <em>This American Life</em>. Listen on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.amazon.mp3">Android</a> or <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/amazon-music-songs-podcasts/id510855668">iOS</a> and you can read what&#39;s being said, much as you would song lyrics.</p><p>This helps with search, too. You can scroll through the transcript and tap on a line to jump to that point in the podcast. You can read what you missed, or get a preview of what&#39;s coming up.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Transcripts are available today. Amazon hasn&#39;t said when it might expand the feature to other countries. This is clearly a move to draw you away from rival podcast services. Still, it could be more than a little helpful to follow along when loud noises drown out your podcast — or to skip to the most interesting segment when you&#39;re pressed for time.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-music-synchronized-podcast-transcripts-160548838.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6df70c26-421e-4896-84a9-0e00d76fe182</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:05:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635868623</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T15:57:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/81eb2f30-3beb-11ec-beff-96c710e3c564" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/81eb2f30-3beb-11ec-beff-96c710e3c564" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Music synchronized podcast transcripts]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Music synchronized podcast transcripts]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung's 1TB T7 Touch portable drive drops to $150 at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Engadget, we’ve long been fans of Samsung’s T7 portable SSDs for their fast performance and compact design. They tend to be more expensive than some competing options, but if you’re patient, you can usually find them on sale. To that point, Amazon has discounted the <a href="https://amzn.to/3w6X8pR">black 1TB Touch model</a> from $190 to $150, matching the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-t7-portable-ssd-500gb-sale-amazon-133505208.html">previous all-time low price</a> for the SSD.  You can also get the silver colorway for less than MSRP, but it’s only discounted by $20. Additionally, the 2TB variant is $70 off, making it $300 currently. If you want to save an extra $10, the non-Touch model, which doesn’t include a built-in fingerprint sensor, is <a href="https://amzn.to/3EzQ08r">$140 at the moment</a>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3w6X8pR" id="8931f0984a344dcab7f4c9986eb31aa7" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Samsung T7 Touch (1TB)">Buy Samsung T7 Touch (1TB) at Amazon - $150 </a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3EzQ08r" id="6124459b94fe4ec8a089c8565df7b0b5" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Samsung T7 1TB">Buy Samsung T7 (1TB) at Amazon - $140</a><p>Whether you go for the standard or Touch model, the T7 has a lot going for it. Both variants feature an aluminum outer casing that will protect the solid-state drive from drops. They also include ePCM technology and a Dynamic Thermal Guard feature to assist with heat management. When it comes to performance, the T7 can read files at up to 1,050 MB/s and write them at up to 1,000 MB/s. And while it only features a single USB-C port, the T7 comes with both USB-C and USB-A cables inside the box, allowing you to use it with almost any modern device, including some video game consoles. For those reasons, we think the T7 is a solid option for storing your photos and other important files.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-t7-touch-ssd-amazon-deal-155643217.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3a6788ae-df22-405a-8b1f-78fabacd509e</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:56:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635868608</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T15:56:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/42d0bab0-3bf3-11ec-bbf7-a1146cd20671" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/42d0bab0-3bf3-11ec-bbf7-a1146cd20671" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung T7 Touch]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung T7 Touch]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's budget WH-CH710N ANC headphones drop back down to $78]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>More and more <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-early-black-friday-tech-deals-so-far-november-1-2021-amazon-best-buy-123511788.html">early Black Friday deals</a> are popping up, and if you&#39;re looking to snag an entry-level set of active noise cancellation (ANC) headphones, you can&#39;t go too far wrong with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-04-01-sony-wh-ch710n-headphones-announced-price-specs-availability.html">Sony&#39;s WH-CH710N</a>. The headphones are on sale for <a href="https://amzn.to/3BGGb6C">$78</a> on Amazon, which is $102 less than the standard price.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3BGGb6C" id="a802787336b741a5b14a675d629450e0" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Sony WH-CH710N at Amazon - $78</a><p>The discount matches the lowest price we&#39;ve seen for the headphones, which occurred <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wh-ch710n-anc-headphones-amazon-prime-day-2021-122523717.html">during Amazon Prime Day</a>, though the headphones have dipped to $88 on several occasions. Given the solid sound quality and ANC, the WH-CH710N was already a decent option at the regular price, so it&#39;s even more worthy of consideration at $78.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There are tradeoffs, of course, for a pair of ANC headphones in this price range. The WH-CH710N set has &quot;decent range and good clarity, but they lack deep, punchy bass that would help create a fuller sound,&quot; as Engadget senior news editor Billy Steele <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-headphones-150030794.html">noted</a>. Still, you&#39;ll get up to 35 hours of use before you need to recharge the headphones and sensors can monitor surrounding noise to select the optimal ANC settings. There&#39;s also an ambient-sound passthrough option for when you need to hear what&#39;s going on in your environment.</p><p>The WH-CH710N can&#39;t quite measure up to Sony’s WH-1000XM4, which we reckon are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-headphones-150030794.html">the best wireless headphones</a> you can buy right now. That said, this set is hard to beat at the lower end of the scale — even more so when the cans are available for such a hefty discount.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-whch710n-anc-headphones-amazon-black-friday-cyber-monday-2021-151121840.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e52b98b8-db8e-4bd9-a081-01981cf437e1</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:11:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635882382</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T19:46:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0cf95430-3bec-11ec-9f2b-2cfe3a60a276" width="960" height="583" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0cf95430-3bec-11ec-9f2b-2cfe3a60a276" width="960" height="583" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A person wearing Sony's WH-CH710N headphones.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony WH-CH710N headphones]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft's Mesh for Teams brings mixed reality to work]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Meta may be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-connect-metaverse-zuckerberg-171507437.html">grabbing most</a> of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-metaverse-meta-explained-or-not-120032885.html">metaverse headlines</a> for now, but it&#39;s far from the only company exploring how we can experience virtual events across a variety of devices. Microsoft gave us a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-mesh-holograms-hololens-ar-vr-164001796.html">glimpse of its vision earlier this year with Mesh</a>, a platform for virtual meetings that can take place across HoloLens 2, mixed reality headsets, computers and smartphones. It&#39;ll be a while before we&#39;re stepping into meetings as holographic projections, though, so Microsoft is announcing something a bit more grounded: Mesh for Teams.</p><p>The pitch, as you&#39;d expect, combines the virtual environments and personas that Mesh delivers with Teams&#39; established workplace collaboration. Instead of hopping on a Teams meeting with your webcam, for example, you could pop up as a customized avatar that talks and animates along with your voice. Eventually, Microsoft plans to animate your avatar by following your face and movements with your webcam, something that should get even better as you step up to devices with more microphones, cameras and sensors like the HoloLens 2.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5511bff0-3bec-11ec-9dee-87727154e1c4" style="height:720;width:1280;" alt="Mesh for Teams large" data-uuid="4ab6e868-ec68-3d94-9bc3-f0cad94e1789"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>It&#39;s all about delivering that elusive sense of &quot;presence,&quot; the feeling that you&#39;re right beside your colleagues virtually. And while it may seem silly at first, Mesh for Teams could be a huge step forward for people who don&#39;t always feel comfortable on webcams. After all, there are plenty of times, like when you&#39;re working early in pajamas, or covered in your kids&#39; lunch mess, where you may be working but not exactly camera ready.</p><p>In addition to avatars, Mesh for Teams will also include pre-built immersive spaces to hang out virtually. That could let groups create a customized meeting space, much like an actual office. There&#39;s also the potential for those spaces to replicate hanging out in an office kitchen or water cooler. That seems a bit more fanciful, but it makes sense to experiment with virtual spaces. Having a virtual coffee chat with your avatar could end up being less stressful than flipping on your camera. Microsoft says companies will eventually be able to design spaces themselves, allowing them to reflect their actual offices.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/551198e0-3bec-11ec-bb5f-8d453ce88f2b" style="height:1080;width:1920;" alt="Mesh for Teams large" data-uuid="bc0bf28a-6be8-3220-af22-2916913a4f11"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Mesh for Teams will start rolling out in 2022. Microsoft isn&#39;t giving up on its more expansive Mesh vision though: companies can still use that platform to create complex 3D environments, which workers can access through a variety of devices.</p><p>Alex Kipman, the Microsoft technical fellow who spearheaded the Kinect and HoloLens, originally pitched Mesh as a way for first-line workers to remotely collaborate on complex 3D models. Mesh for Teams boils that idea down for the typical knowledge worker, the sort of person who spends most of their day at a desk hopping between meetings, emails and office apps. It may not seem as exciting as Meta&#39;s pitch for a metaverse filled with multiplayer games and virtual events, but for many people, it&#39;s a far more useful way of thinking of a more connected internet.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-mesh-for-teams-multiverse-work-150047792.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a1c6efde-a70f-4b25-b597-f3bf7a29f592</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635865339</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T15:02:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/55114ac0-3bec-11ec-a7ef-943a5eef1284" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/55114ac0-3bec-11ec-a7ef-943a5eef1284" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Mesh for Teams large]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Mesh for Teams large]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Loop is a new Office app built for collaborative work]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Loop, a new Office collaboration app announced today, takes the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-06-microsoft-fluid-framework-collaboration.html">company&#39;s Fluid Framework vision</a> one step further. You might remember that technology from Microsoft&#39;s recent developer events: It&#39;s  a way to collaborate on specific chunks of content, say a table or chart, synchronized across multiple Office apps. A table you create in Outlook, for example, would instantly update if someone plugs it into a Word document and adds new information. Up until now, we&#39;ve only seen that<a href="https://www.engadget.com/fluid-framework-office-online-outlook-160022166.html"> implemented in Office online as a sort of test</a>. Microsoft Loop is a far bigger bet on the future of document collaboration.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/35c874e0-3be2-11ec-9dff-fdeae9ef59b7" style="height:1080;width:1920;" alt="Microsoft Loop" data-uuid="9cbbe3df-1193-3d48-9b36-65fce1e0ff32"><figcaption>Multiple people collaborating on a Fluid Framework poll.</figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Like Fluid Framework, one of the core parts of the new app are Loop Components, which Microsoft calls &quot;atomic units of productivity.&quot; They can include anything from as a list to a complex Dynamics 365 project, all of which will stay in sync when they&#39;re deployed in Office apps. You can organize your Components in Loop Pages, a new type of document that can also include files and links. Think of them like unstructured Word documents (or perhaps more like how people typically use Google Docs).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Finally, there are Loop Workspaces, a way to view components and pages related to specific projects. According to Microsoft,  &quot;Workspaces make it easy for you to catch up on what everyone is working on, react to others’ ideas, or track progress toward shared goals.&quot;</p><p>If you&#39;re getting serious <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-05-19-google-wave-opens-doors-to-public-asks-old-friends-for-new-chan.html">Google Wave</a> vibes from all of this, you&#39;re not alone. But Microsoft Loop sounds a bit more focused than that failed attempt at team collaboration. For one, the core idea of Fluid Framework makes sense. Now that we&#39;re all working across multiple documents online, it makes sense to have a way to synchronize elements within those files. Wave felt like a solution in search of a problem, whereas Microsoft Loop, despite its seeming complexity, addresses a growing problem many office workers face today.</p><p>Microsoft says it&#39;ll share more about Loop in the upcoming months. Until then, though, you can expect to see Loop components coming to Teams, Outlook, OneNote and other Microsoft 365 apps later this month.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-loop-office-365-fluid-framework-150029033.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4e9e7a5f-4e59-4450-b299-d167f37dab8e</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635860923</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T13:48:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/2fa84f90-3be2-11ec-af9a-39c4f9c9c66a" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/2fa84f90-3be2-11ec-af9a-39c4f9c9c66a" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Microsoft Loop]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft Loop]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Video editing and audio recording are coming to Microsoft Office apps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.microsoft.com/">Microsoft</a> is boosting <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-office-2021-october-5-2021-170152304.html">Office</a> with some (arguably overdue) media creation tools. As part of a sweeping set of updates, the company is adding Clipchamp video editing to the Office suite. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-acquires-clipchamp-040823250.html">recently acquired</a> web-based tool helps you make &quot;professional-looking&quot; clips regardless of your skills. You can produce videos for your other Office projects, of course, but Microsoft also sees Clipchamp as a straightforward editing tool for personal footage.</p><p>It will also be much easier to add that professional sheen to your PowerPoint presentations. Microsoft is adding a &quot;recording studio&quot; to PowerPoint that lets you capture audio for those moments when you can&#39;t (or just don&#39;t want to) present live. You can annotate slides, customize the background and pick the view that will best help you record. When you&#39;re done, you can preview the presentation and re-record as much as necessary. Be patient for this feature, though, as Microsoft only expects it to become &quot;generally available&quot; in early 2022.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Other updates are subtler, but could be just as helpful in the right circumstances. Microsoft is trotting out Context IQ, a set of AI &quot;experiences&quot; for Microsoft 365 that will initially make situationally-aware recommendations in Editor. It will suggest relevant contacts when you want to tag people, for instance, or recommend meeting times when everyone is available.</p><p>Developers will also have a better reason to try Excel. Microsoft is introducing a JavaScript framework in the spreadsheet app that lets you create custom data types and functions using the web-based language. JavaScript will be available later in November in preview form. Many (if not most) Excel users won&#39;t have much need for this, but it could be valuable if your job revolves around data.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-office-clipchamp-video-editing-150014886.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e52538aa-21d7-43cc-bc29-d8b09b509ccd</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:00:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635863044</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T14:24:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/aec386a0-3be2-11ec-b76f-d6b96a9a5498" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/aec386a0-3be2-11ec-b76f-d6b96a9a5498" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Windows on Unsplash]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Microsoft Word on a Surface Laptop in a collaborative work environment]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft Word on a Surface Laptop in a collaborative work environment]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zoom starts showing ads to free users in limited test]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/zoom/"><ins>Zoom</ins></a> users on the free Basic plan may start seeing ads starting today. At the outset, ads will only appear on the browser page after a call ends, and you&#39;ll only see them following meetings hosted by other Basic users. The test is limited to certain countries too.</p><p>The company has updated its privacy policy to reflect the change. Zoom says it won&#39;t use content (in other words, video, audio, messages and files) from meetings, webinars or messaging &quot;for any marketing, promotions, or third-party advertising purposes.&quot; The company&#39;s advertising partners might use cookies to track your activity on Zoom&#39;s website. You can block them from doing so via Zoom&#39;s cookie management tool.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Zoom expects the ad program &quot;will enable us to support investment and continue providing free Basic users with access to our robust platform,&quot; chief marketing officer Janine Pelosi <a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-continued-access-for-basic-users-with-advertising-program/"><ins>wrote in a blog post</ins></a>.</p><p>Basic users can take part in as many meetings as they like, but there are time limits of 30 minutes on one-on-one calls and 40 minutes on group meetings. They don&#39;t have any cloud storage for meeting recordings or access to features like transcripts, either, though the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/zoom-automatic-closed-captions-free-users-172250054.html"><ins>just rolled out</ins></a> a live transcription/closed captioning option on the free tier.</p><p>Zoom became an essential tool <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-04-02-zoom-user-trust-privacy-security-review.html"><ins>for millions</ins></a> amid a widespread shift to remote working as the COVID-19 pandemic took hold last year, and many opted for the free plan, given its solid capabilities. It shouldn&#39;t be too surprising that Zoom is moving into advertising, but it seems that, at least for now, the ads will be fairly unobtrusive while respecting users&#39; privacy preferences.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/zoom-ads-basic-plan-free-users-144015591.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6203a973-fc24-4919-bc87-cc316dfa79b9</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:40:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635862226</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T14:10:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/00fe7b30-3be5-11ec-a2b9-597eaf666b1a" width="1682" height="942" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/00fe7b30-3be5-11ec-a2b9-597eaf666b1a" width="1682" height="942" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Zoom]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A mockup of how Zoom will display ads to users of its Basic plan after a call has ended.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Zoom browser ad]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The home theater gear worth gifting this year (even if the giftee is you)]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you&#39;ve got all the gifts you need for the kids, your family and the friends who really matter. But it&#39;s been a tough year, surely <em>you</em> deserve some joy as well. Maybe it&#39;s time to upgrade that HDTV to a 4K OLED, or to finally move on from using sad TV speakers. It&#39;s time to treat yourself, in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSjM5B3QNlw">true <em>Parks and Rec</em> fashion</a>. Here are some of the best home theater gadgets we&#39;d recommend when budget isn&#39;t an issue.</p><h2>Apple TV 4K</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/83878a90-2dc8-11ec-aeff-8fd814c68cf5" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="9069f039-3e31-3805-a246-825e304dd391"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>While <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:the latest Apple TV model" href="https://amzn.to/306jX0K">the latest Apple TV model</a> isn’t a massive leap over its predecessor, there are a few updates that make it worthy of a holiday splurge. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-4k-review-2021-new-siri-remote-150054255.html">redesigned Siri remote</a> is a big improvement over the previous version, both app and streaming performance is quicker than ever and there’s support for Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision. As always, there’s deep integration with iOS, and HomeKit compatibility is a nice bonus. And when you tire of music and movies, the Apple TV also works as a gaming console with access to Apple Arcade and support for Bluetooth gamepads. <em>— Billy Steele, Senior News Editor</em></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/306jX0K" id="c838b921f1d74308bca511e4d8424c26" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Apple TV 4K at Amazon - $169</a><h2>BenQ HT2050A projector</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838a49b0-2dc8-11ec-be9f-384496a1acc3" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="61b5cc5c-7005-39f7-a1f0-9cfc8f1473de"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>A projector is a great gift for any of the cinephiles or gamers in your life, and for around $800, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:BenQ HT2050A" href="https://amzn.to/3lGEJN2">BenQ HT2050A</a> is the best budget 1080p projector available. Its DLP tech delivers where it counts with the best contrast (ANSI 1,574:1) and color accuracy in its class, and is reasonably bright as well, with 2,200 lumens in &quot;vivid&quot; mode. On top of that, it comes with a 1.3x zoom and vertical lens shift option for maximum installation flexibility. It’s also a nice option for gaming, thanks to the relatively low 16 millisecond input lag. The drawbacks include slightly excessive fan noise, rainbow effect and red-tinted 3D. <em>— Steve Dent, Associate Editor</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3lGEJN2" id="22a98855c3034bceaac920ea149a5f82" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy BenQ HT2050A projector at Amazon - $850</a><h2>65-inch LG C1 OLED TV</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838b8230-2dc8-11ec-b4ff-57e2fd0e411c" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="e250c9d5-1d93-3ab9-b3f4-3bb0d4a076b9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">LG</div></figure><p>If you&#39;re looking for the best possible TV to buy, there’s no question: Pick an OLED model. Personally I&#39;d stick with <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:LG&#39;s C1" href="https://amzn.to/3FGtXOM">LG&#39;s C1</a>, the latest generation of the company&#39;s astounding OLED screens. Unlike LCD TVs, which rely on backlights, pixels on OLED TVs can turn themselves on and off individually. That allows them to capture inky blacks and deliver better contrast than most LCD panels. The C1 isn&#39;t much different from last year&#39;s CX line, but it&#39;s LG&#39;s most evolved OLED yet. It has a 120Hz refresh rate for speedy gaming, as well as support for G-SYNC and Freesync to avoid annoying frame stuttering. Its wide viewing angles also mean everyone can get a perfect picture, no matter where they&#39;re sitting. <em>— Devindra Hardawar, Senior Editor</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3FGtXOM" id="937f9d14eb084e7b9a5d55b182ea53ab" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 65-inch LG C1 OLED TV at Amazon - $2,500</a><h2>Monoprice Monolith THX Atmos home theater speakers</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838d08d0-2dc8-11ec-bcf7-bc5ee1842864" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="0c25706d-42ae-37e5-aab9-59d81850e6dc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Monoprice </div></figure><p>Sometimes, a soundbar just doesn&#39;t cut it. No matter how many drivers you can cram in, or how good the virtual surround sound is, <em>nothing</em> beats the immersion of a full home theater speaker setup. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Monoprice&#39;s Monolith series" href="https://fave.co/3iTvhE9">Monoprice&#39;s Monolith series</a> is one of the best options around: It sports a powerful center channel, your choice of towers or bookshelf speakers with upward-firing Dolby Atmos drivers, and subwoofers powerful enough to rattle your walls. There are tons of surround sound systems to choose from, but the beauty of the Monolith line is that it has all of the latest speaker tech and it’s reasonably priced, at least compared to other Hi-Fi systems. It used to be that you had to mix and match speakers to create an affordable surround setup. You can start small with a few towers and a subwoofer—and once you&#39;ve got a complete system, you may never need to go to the cinema again. <em>— D.H.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3iTvhE9" id="a6bd1a4cb36c48189c7b2c7ba9061ae4" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Monoprice;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Monolith speakers at Monoprice starting at $250</a><h2>Optoma Cinemax P2</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838e6861-2dc8-11ec-a76e-ffe8cf2c8960" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="1a2e2572-a4bc-335c-991f-0307375eab53"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Optoma </div></figure><p>With high brightness and ease of setup, ultra short throw projectors are all the rage right now — making one the ultimate gift for any movie lover. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:CinemaX P2" href="https://amzn.to/3j2hUkY">CinemaX P2</a> is the best among those for the price thanks to a good combination of features. It delivers 3,000 lumens of brightness, while offering good contrast and accurate colors, with 80 percent DCI-P3 coverage. The 40-watt NuForce Dolby Digital 2.0 soundbar is one of the best on any ultra-short-throw projector and it’s relatively stylish in white. On the downside, while it does offer apps, they’re not as good as you’ll find on, say, Google’s Chromecast — though that’s an easy fix as it has three HDMI 2.0 ports. <em>— S.D.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3j2hUkY" id="9ef28f1dc4c14a60b17cdbff379a39e3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Optoma CinemaX P2 at Amazon - $3,300</a><h2>Roku Ultra</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838e6860-2dc8-11ec-97f5-b6875b1e2850" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="37704d5c-ceb9-3be9-8066-677bfc80797e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>If you&#39;re not a fan of the Apple TV, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Ultra" href="https://amzn.to/3p2C8Pg">Roku Ultra</a> is the only other set-top box worth considering. It&#39;s fast enough to stream 4K video with Dolby Vision, and it supports just about every streaming app you&#39;d want. It also has a solid remote with voice-search capabilities, <em>and</em> you can still access all of Apple&#39;s streaming video via the Apple TV app. And while Roku&#39;s interface isn&#39;t pretty, it&#39;s fast and gets the job done. <em>— D.H.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3p2C8Pg" id="29b8601b5489482db3e08c8c96d59db0" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Roku Ultra at Amazon - $99</a><h2>Sonos Arc</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838e8f70-2dc8-11ec-b767-9e00eb78eba7" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="a245aad4-e2d9-3609-8c6c-16f084144a43"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Sonos finally <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sonos-arc-review-dolby-atmos-soundbar-010039560.html">introduced an upgrade</a> to its aging Playbar last summer when it debuted the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Arc" href="https://fave.co/3FAIED2">Arc</a>. In addition to an updated design, the soundbar also supports Dolby Atmos which makes it an excellent choice for the living room. True to Sonos’ lineage, the Arc is also well-suited for music and you have the ability to add a subwoofer or satellite speakers as you see fit. It will also function as part of a new or existing Sonos multi-room setup and any time you add on to the main living room configuration, the Arc automatically adjusts to compensate for the extra gear. <em>— B.S.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3FAIED2" id="2127bea371684593ad9e0b4f8d6f746b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Sonos;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Arc at Sonos - $899</a><h2>Sony HT-A7000 soundbar</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8387b1a0-2dc8-11ec-a55c-4ce5cb7b34c1" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="03b0094b-1248-3653-b550-e0a6f545e7e1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>Sony’s Atmos-enabled soundbars are among the best and its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-ht-a9-home-theater-system-140038379.html">most recent top-end model</a> is no different. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:A7000" href="https://fave.co/3iQKUMs">A7000</a> replaced the HT-ST5000 as the flagship in the company’s lineup, only this time, the soundbar doesn’t come with a wireless subwoofer in the box. Instead, Sony is offering you the ability to add to your home theater setup as needed. The company offers two subwoofer options, as well a pair of rear speakers. The A7000 on its own though, is a 7.1.2-channel unit equipped with HDMI 2.1 with eARC, plus both 8K and 4K/120 Hz passthrough. This means Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision are both in play as well as ample support for gaming. Plus, wireless connectivity includes Chromecast, AirPlay 2 and Spotify Connect when you just need some tunes. <em>— B.S.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3iQKUMs" id="6db7ac5d71124798adefd2cd795ec732" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Crutchfield;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Sony A7000 at Crutchfield - $1,298</a><h2>65-inch TCL 6 Series smart TV</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/838ce1c0-2dc8-11ec-bbff-fe4669d7f698" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="68deb9fc-67ef-3beb-bb95-83ca318afc5a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget / TCL</div></figure><p>If OLED is too rich for your blood, consider <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:TCL&#39;s MiniLED-powered 6-series" href="https://amzn.to/3mO5RZE">TCL&#39;s MiniLED-powered 6-series</a> line. It features far more backlight zones than typical LCDs, which can lead to black and contrast levels that are approaching what you&#39;d see from OLED. The lower cost is the big selling point here though, giving you enough leftover cash to invest in your sound system. It&#39;s a solid entry both for movie watching and gaming. The 6-series also includes some of the cheapest 8K TVs on the market, though we&#39;d recommend holding out on 8K until more content is actually available. (Something that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-13-8k-at-ces-2020.html">may take a long while</a>.) <em>— D.H.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3mO5RZE" id="e179832dc8d0498782e81507beb66891" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 65-inch TCL 6 Series TV at Amazon - $1,139</a><h2>Valencia Theater Seating Verona seats</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/83895f50-2dc8-11ec-96db-afd0dd0cd107" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="c4c70c55-486e-36c0-b3cf-d630e0a36fa8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Valencia Theater Seating</div></figure><p>Where your butt sits is just as important to your home theater as your screen and sound setup. You&#39;ll want seats that you can lounge in for hours without hurting your back, and they need to be sturdy enough to survive real-world usage with pets and kids. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Valencia&#39;s Verona seats" href="https://amzn.to/3BBaZqm">Valencia&#39;s Verona seats</a> are a solid option if you want to replicate the experience of high-end theaters with reclining seats. They&#39;re made out of genuine leather, and they offer separate reclining options for your back <em>and</em> head. And sure, they&#39;re pricey, but a decent couch will set you back just as much as three Veronas. And, let&#39;s face it, they&#39;ll be far more comfortable for movie watching and gaming than your typical West Elm option. <em>— D.H.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3BBaZqm" id="0f08502c04734b74a2aeec7b220ce576" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Verona seats at Amazon - $1,750</a><h2>Vizio M-Series 5.1 soundbar</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8389ad70-2dc8-11ec-9397-69877f7243c9" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide" data-uuid="e7dd7042-cbda-399d-9b4e-4c6617051d79"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Vizio</div></figure><p>If you&#39;ve got a smaller space, or you can&#39;t justify stringing wires around your living room for a complete home theater system, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Vizio&#39;s M-series 5.1 soundbar kit" href="https://amzn.to/3vbNVMn">Vizio&#39;s M-series 5.1 soundbar kit</a> offers plenty of value. It supports Dolby Atmos, for enveloping surround sound, and it comes with wireless rear channels and a subwoofer. Best of all, it&#39;s far cheaper than competing systems (though if you want, you can also step up to other Vizio Atmos options, like the<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-vizio-elevate-soundbar-ces-2020.html"> rotating Elevate</a>). Consider the M-series a solid entry into the world of surround sound (and one you won&#39;t feel too bad about replacing when you want bigger speakers). <em>— D.H.</em></p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3vbNVMn" id="d55ca341724e4872a5c1e72e2d4d3cc5" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Vizio M-Series 5.1 soundbar at Amazon - $328</a><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/home-entertainment-gift-ideas-143038506.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f4b6f6d2-60d2-42c6-8966-7317113eb9e9</guid><dc:creator>Engadget</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:30:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635780352</ingested><modified>2021-11-01T15:25:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Engadget]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/46464d40-328e-11ec-babb-c430231e72d4" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/46464d40-328e-11ec-babb-c430231e72d4" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Home entertainment items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Home Entertainment - 2021 Holiday Gift Guide]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Broadcast is kinda underrated]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What if I told you that a graphics card could be the quickest way to improve your livestream or podcast audio? It sounds counterintuitive, but think about it: A GPU often has an extreme amount of processing power sitting idle, so why not use that redundant hardware for other things?</p><p>Fortunately, NVIDIA is way ahead of us, and has already harnessed the potential of its own GPUs to do things beyond, well, graphics. For example, you might remember <a href="https://www.engadget.com/obs-nvidia-noise-removal-integration-184501842.html"><ins>RTX Voice</ins></a>, which as the name implies, is a tool for upping your microphone game. Then, it quietly released <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-gb/geforce/broadcasting/broadcast-app/"><ins>Broadcast </ins></a>— a more comprehensive tool aimed squarely at streamers and content creators. Both offer great audio enhancement features, but we’ll focus on Broadcast here as that has effectively (though not entirely) replaced RTX Voice.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Right up the top, I should set some expectations. While Broadcast offers some helpful tools for all streamers, the real benefit is for those with more entry-level gear. For example, if you have something like a Blue Yeti and an older webcam you’re going to get more out of this tool than someone with a Shure SM7B and a Sony A7.</p><p>Broadcast specifically “uses Tensor Cores on NVIDIA RTX GPUs to accelerate AI calculations so you can game, livestream and run AI networks at the same time.” It’s compatible with any RTX GPU — “GeForce RTX 2060, Quadro RTX 3000, or higher” — according to a company spokesperson.</p><p>If you don’t already own a compatible GPU, now isn’t exactly the best time to be looking for one, thanks to the ongoing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-tsmc-joint-chip-factory-200540698.html"><ins>chip shortage</ins></a>, but things do seem to be slowly easing up. If you <em>do</em> have a supported card then you can simply download the Broadcast app and get cracking. The better news is, if you have a Logitech headset or Blue mic, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-broadcast-adds-direct-logitech-headset-and-blue-microphone-support-140614960.html">as of today</a>, Broadcast is natively supported so you won’t even need to dive into the app.</p><p>Supported models at launch are Logitech&#39;s G733, Pro X and Pro X Wireless headsets, and Blue&#39;s Yeti X, Yeti Classic and Yeti Nano microphones. While that’s only a fraction of the companies’ offerings, it still represents a lot of headsets and microphones that today have new, untapped potential.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/57db73d0-3bd7-11ec-9ddd-12a570ddf312" style="height:435;width:851;" alt="NVIDIA Broadcast." data-uuid="ff5888c7-d9a6-37da-a9d0-c82c048ad6c6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">NVIDIA / James Trew</div></figure><p>The Logitech partnership, to date, only works with some products and only with some of the features on offer in NVIDIA Broadcast. Those looking for the full audio-visual featureset will still need to download the standalone app. Once you’re in Broadcast you’ll see three main tabs: Microphone, Speaker and Camera. We’ll focus mainly on the microphone section, but the other two are just as useful and it all combines into one hub for tweaking your stream, be it video, audio or both.</p><p>Under the Microphone tab you’ll find a drop down on the left to select your input source and a space below for adding effects. The area on the right is given over to a tool for testing these effects before you commit to them.</p><p>Right now, there are only two effects to choose from. But both are useful and there’s no novelty chaffe (get your robot voices elsewhere!). Broadcast is focused on shaping up your stream, not bending it into something else. And importantly, all in realtime, unlike something like iZotope RX which is incredibly good at repairing sound, but aimed at post production.</p><h2>Audio tools</h2><p>The first effect is Room echo removal. For anyone who has a space with less than favorable acoustics, this is going to help you dial down that dreaded “cave” sound you have probably been battling with. Reverb reduction is actually quite a science, given that you’re trying to remove elements of a sound that are… well, very very similar to the source. So you can’t just hack out the errant frequencies and be done with it, you need to leave the original signal intact.</p><p>NVIDIA kept things nice and simple. Other pro tools (like iZotope’s RX) give you an bevvy of settings and controls. Broadcast? Just two: on/off and “strength” (amount of reverb to be removed). To test this, I used a condenser microphone as those are most prone to picking up reverb. In the recording below, I start with no effect applied before dialling in about 50 percent and then finally with strength set to maximum.</p><div id="118174bd3c5d4dcfaeb260edcf6e13c0"><iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/1337669500&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/sets/nvidia-broadcast-room-noise-removal-tests" title="NVIDIA Broadcast Room noise removal tests" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">NVIDIA Broadcast Room noise removal tests</a></div></div><p>As you can hear, the effect is, well, effective. The acoustics in the room I recorded the samples in aren’t terrible, but they’re definitely not optimal. But the difference between the raw recording and then with the reverb removed is stark. The effect is most obvious in the first recording with the condenser mic. The raw signal is… fine, but things are much improved with the echo removal tool set to around half way. The recording feels much more present and there’s no distracting room echo. More, isn’t always better though. Once I dial the effect up to 100 percent, reverb might be eliminated, but at the expense of the original signal. In short, play around with the settings to find the best balance for your tastes and recording space.</p><p>You’ll notice in the second recording that there’s not really all that much reverb to remove. This is thanks to the dynamic microphone which does a pretty good job of that itself. You can hear a difference once I start adding the effect, but it might not be worth the risk of degrading your source audio for such a minor benefit.</p><p>Perhaps more impressive than the echo removal is the second effect on offer: Noise reduction. While reverb tends to be a constant, outside noises are unpredictable. Things might be quiet when you sit down to record, only for a loud motorbike or barking dog to invade your stream moments later. Not with noise removal applied though.</p><p>This effect is impressively adept at removing anything but your voice from your stream. Be that a jackhammer, a crying baby next door or even a song played loudly on a speaker right by your microphone. Honestly, listen to the below.</p><div id="d54c9f2675b54cc98257df9dece9e108"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:400px;position:relative;"><iframe src="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/hsF1fsN" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div></div><p>Notice how you can’t hear the song when the effect is applied? That’s coming from a speaker barely a foot behind the microphone. When I recorded it, it’s fully audible to my ears, but almost entirely inaudible on the recording. I say <em>almost</em> as those with sharp ears might notice the odd fragment popping through, but you really have to listen closely. I actually asked NVIDIA about this and was given this response:</p><p>“The AI networks are trained to recognize some patterns, and as such there will be gray areas where the AI can have doubts. [...] As such we wanted to give our users flexibility to run the effects in a comfortable range, or dial things up in case they needed help in extreme situations. For example, for audio effects we recommend running them at 75-90 percent, depending on how much background noise or room echo there is.”</p><p>As mentioned, Broadcast largely replaced RTX Voice, but NVIDIA decided to patch it with support for NVIDIA GeForce GTX GPUs meaning you can still get the noise reduction tools even if your GPU doesn’t support Broadcast. Though, the company says, experiences will vary on older cards.</p><p>As with the reverb removal, the strength setting will ultimately impact the quality of the output so trial and error is needed to find the sweet spot. You might also want to consider time of day. If, for example, you live near a noisy road, you could dial in a second pair of settings for when you have to record around rush hour.</p><p>The noise removal filter is impressive, but it’s not without limitations. For one, the “strength” slider doesn’t seem to fade out sounds like music, instead it falls off only once you apply the maximum amount. At least in my testing. I doubt you’re intentionally streaming with music only you want to hear, so that’s a minor thing to be aware of, but if you <em>do </em>need to keep the strength at maximum, be aware of that degradation in signal which will get worse the more noise Broadcast is eliminating.</p><p>As a companion to the vocal effects, the middle tab in Broadcast is “Speakers.” We can sum this section in one shot: It’s the same as Microphone, just for incoming audio. That’s to say, you can go ahead and remove room echo or background noise from people you are speaking <em>with</em>. If you’ve ever been on a Zoom call during these pandemic times and someone’s baby starts crying or has a really loud road nearby, then you can selfishly spare your ears here.</p><h2>Camera tools</h2><p>Conceptually, the effects for your camera work in a similar way to the ones for your microphone. NVIDIA’s AI cores are “looking” out for noise or, depending, your entire background. Yup, with Broadcast you can achieve a green screen effect without the actual screen. You might be thinking “well, Zoom/Meet/TikTok does that” and you’d be right, but those don&#39;t do it nearly as well. Below is an example of what background removal/replacement looks like in Broadcast</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ff50de20-3bd7-11ec-bb06-7627b6ed50c5" style="height:360;width:640;" alt="NVIDIA Broadcast." data-uuid="1ae4825e-081f-312f-9bc5-47da07da3349"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>You can definitely see where the effect isn’t perfect around my hair, but in general it works really well. I did notice that it struggled with the headrest on my chair, with the image flickering around that area as I moved around, but again, it’s leagues above what you might hope for from a free chat app.</p><p>In total, there are five effects for cameras. Three for your background: Blur, removal and replace (images or videos work!). Then there is Auto Frame, which crops in and then keeps your face in the center. Last, but not least, is Video noise removal — this is apt for recording in low light and your camera starts to go all grainy. You can see some examples in the picture below. Two were taken using a GoPro and the other pair are from an old DSLR repurposed as a webcam.</p><p>If you have good lighting, you probably won’t need the noise removal tool. But if your camera struggles with anything other than an abundance of photons, this filter can help. Again, as with the audio tools, be aware that more is not always better. I found with the effect applied at 100 percent you get the tell-tale “smoothing” that will tell your viewers that you’re papering over the cracks.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/1b22cbd0-3bd9-11ec-8e5f-b7dc9a25796e" style="height:1121;width:2000;" alt="NVIDIA Broadcast" data-uuid="e9da1be8-397a-34e0-bf99-4b6104ad3494"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>The background tools, on the other hand, are a little more forgiving. The blur tool does a good job at obscuring the items behind you, but there’s a very unnatural contrast between you, in focus, and literally anything else in shot. This is similar to how iPhone “portrait” mode photos often appear. The background is blurred, but the subject looks unnatural as there’s almost no transition between foreground and background.</p><p>This is, of course, a benefit when you want to remove the background completely. With this filter, NVIDIA does a surprisingly good job of isolating you and deleting everything else. If you want to stream via OBS (or similar) with a game or video on screen while you play in the corner, this is the effect you want and no green screen required.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/4b0fbca0-3bd8-11ec-adff-8b2f3f7c715a" style="height:793;width:2000;" alt="NVIDIA Broadcast." data-uuid="5c931ddc-886a-336d-823b-b6615b1e99f0"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>As seen above, NVIDIA does a much better job of removing the background than, say, Zoom or Google Meet does. There’s almost no bleed around hair or hands meaning your background rarely pokes through and spoils the green-screen illusion. Background replacement is essentially an extension of this effect with the option of choosing your own image or video to replace whatever happens to be behind you.</p><p>The last of the video effects is Auto-Frame which, as the name suggests, keeps you locked into the center of your shot. To do this, the video crops in a little bit and it uses the extra space to gently shift the video from left to right or vice versa as you move around. The movement isn’t jarring, it looks pretty smooth, and is a good way to make sure you don’t accidentally drift off to the side if you are a fidgeter (like me) and don’t keep still.</p><p>You can also combine these effects if you want. Auto-Frame can be stacked with either noise removal or one of the background effects for example, or you could use remove background with noise removal applied. Right now you can only stack two though, but that’s probably a good thing as all three at the same time might be a bit much.</p><p>The camera suite of effects is currently in beta, and NVIDIA has been adding new features and improving performance at a rapid pace. Version 1.2 in May integrated Broadcast into popular streaming apps like OBS, while the latest 1.3 version released in September added support for many virtual camera apps and made combining video effects much more viable by reducing their VRAM usage by 40 percent.</p><p>While performance and memory usage is never going to be an issue for those using Broadcast for their chats, one-PC streamers who are using the app while gaming will be grateful for the additional frames. Perhaps, one day, we can dare to dream about many other features such as multi-mic support (with different effects) live transcribing for closed captions and even smart detection of licensed music so your streams don’t flag a DMCA violation.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-broadcast-is-kinda-underrated-141026195.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8a8ecb42-16d4-449b-81e3-6560b9c67c63</guid><dc:creator>James Trew</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:15:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635862052</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T14:07:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|James Trew]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/66598400-3bd8-11ec-bc5f-d346603e0ac3" width="640" height="360" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/66598400-3bd8-11ec-bc5f-d346603e0ac3" width="640" height="360" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[James Trew / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NVIDIA Broadcast.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Broadcast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Logitech puts NVIDIA Broadcast features directly into its headsets and Blue mics]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you stream or do videoconferencing and own certain GeForce RTX GPUs, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-broadcast-app-streamers-165218841.html">NVIDIA&#39;s Broadcast app</a> can be a magical helper. It uses a streamlined, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qblSdDZMmi0">AI-powered toolset</a> to remove background noise, add virtual effects, auto-frame shots and more. Now, Logitech has <a href="https://blog.logitech.com/2021/11/02/logitech-g-hub-nvidia-broadcast-integration-enters-open-beta/">announced</a> that it&#39;s incorporating some of those features directly into certain headsets and Blue microphones via a new beta, with no need to run any NVIDIA apps.&nbsp;</p><p>Thanks to a partnership between Logitech and NVIDIA, some of the Broadcast tools will be available through the G Hub drivers for the following products: Logitech G733 Gaming Headset, Logitech PRO X Gaming Headset, Logitech PRO X Wireless Gaming Headset, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-17-blue-yeti-x-microphone-streaming-podcasting-recording.html">Blue Yeti X Microphone</a>, Blue Yeti Classic Microphone and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-08-28-blue-yeti-nano-usb-microphone.html">Blue Yeti Nano</a> Microphone.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="d3b7b858379745a39694459a697df2dd"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here&#39;s the full list of compatible Logitech G and <a href="https://twitter.com/BlueMicrophones?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BlueMicrophones</a> devices: <br><br>G733 Gaming Headset <br>PRO X Gaming Headset<br>PRO X Wireless Gaming Headset<br>Yeti X Microphone<br>Yeti Classic Microphone<br>Yeti Nano Microphone</p>— Logitech G (@LogitechG) <a href="https://twitter.com/LogitechG/status/1455429903663255555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The drivers will make it possible for users to eliminate unwanted background noises and/or echo in a single click and clean up their mic signal. &quot;You can even test your mic signal to find the perfect settings for your set up,&quot; Logitech wrote. NVIDIA previously showed that it was possible to completely remove the sound of a hair dryer running in the background from your mic, so it&#39;s not just some minor noise reduction. It can also remove noise on the listener&#39;s end, like someone&#39;s clattering keyboard.&nbsp;</p><p>The feature is now available to everyone via an open beta with the latest version of Logitech G Hub. You can also, of course, run NVIDIA Broadcast as a separate app that works with all of Logitech&#39;s audio products (or any other audio products, for that matter). The feature is supported on GeForce RTX 2060 and up GPUs, along with Quadro RTX 3000 and Titan RTX or higher.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-broadcast-adds-direct-logitech-headset-and-blue-microphone-support-140614960.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5b27cd27-918f-4dfd-9ae8-e7608a3ab636</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:06:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635862079</ingested><modified>2021-11-02T14:08:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/eca3ff10-3bdb-11ec-bf12-3701b3edcbb4" width="1600" height="871" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/eca3ff10-3bdb-11ec-bf12-3701b3edcbb4" width="1600" height="871" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NVIDIA Broadcast adds direct Logitech headset and Blue microphone support]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Broadcast adds direct Logitech headset and Blue microphone support]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>