<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 09:52:58 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter gives paid 'Blue' subscribers early access to more new features]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter has rolled out Labs for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-blue-subscriptions-australia-canada-launch-140042065.html">Blue</a> subscription service, which will give its paid users early access to select experimental features. At the moment, one of the first two Labs experiments available to subscribers will give them the capability to upload videos up to 10 minutes long, which is much, much longer than its standard limit of 2 minutes and 20 seconds. That is, so long as they upload their video from a PC. The other experimental feature will allow them to pin their favorite conversations at the top of their inbox by swiping on those particular DM convos.&nbsp;</p><p>Labs will accept experimental features from various internal Twitter teams, allowing them to get early data from users. Just like any other test feature, the Labs experiments could be vastly different by the time they&#39;re ready for general release, if Twitter does decide to roll them out.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="55db6af653314ed88e945b27b060b1ba"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Like being ahead of the curve?<br><br>Today, we’re rolling out Labs 🔬, giving you *early access* to some new features we’re building before everyone else like: <br>🔹 Pinned Conversations on iOS<br>🔹 Longer video uploads on desktop only <br><br>Here are some questions you might be asking:</p>— Twitter Blue (@TwitterBlue) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterBlue/status/1453457352426803202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>A Blue subscription will set users back $3 a month and will give them access to exclusive features, including folders for organizing bookmarks and a &quot;reader mode.&quot; It also gives users a way to &quot;undo&quot; their tweets. At the moment, it&#39;s only available in Canada and Australia, and it&#39;s still unclear when it will roll out in the US and other countries.</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-blue-labs-095220405.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9b20d066-fdac-4af8-bfc9-c2c06c7106e0</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 09:52:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635414832</ingested><modified>2021-10-28T09:54:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/52d77790-218d-11eb-a6be-8bf8455a30b4" width="6016" height="4016" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/52d77790-218d-11eb-a6be-8bf8455a30b4" width="6016" height="4016" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[oatawa via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Women's hand typing on mobile smartphone, Live Chat Chatting on application Communication Digital Web and social network Concept. Work from home.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Women's hand typing on mobile smartphone, Live Chat Chatting on application Communication Digital Web and social network Concept.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla's Sentry Mode now offers drivers a live view of their car]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tesla has long <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-remote-autopilot-sentry-camera-access-224816342.html">hidden</a> hints in its code that it&#39;s giving owners live view access to its EVs&#39; Autopilot cameras — now, the automaker is finally rolling out the feature. Its latest software update <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/10/27/tesla-launches-remote-sentry-mode-live-view-premium-connectivity-feature/">includes</a> a feature called Sentry Mode Live Camera Access, which will allow owners to remotely view their car&#39;s surroundings when parked. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-09-teslas-sentry-mode-has-already-caught-a-suspected-carjacker.html">Sentry Mode</a> is Tesla&#39;s integrated surveillance system that uses a 360 dash cam to record damage and any attempted break-in. It has resulted to arrests of people who attempted to steal Teslas in the past, but owners haven&#39;t been able to use it to view their car&#39;s current surroundings until now.</p><p>In its update notes, Tesla says the live camera function is end-to-end encrypted and cannot be accessed by the company. To enable or disable it, owners need to go under Safety &amp; Security in Controls. According to <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/10/27/tesla-launches-remote-sentry-mode-live-view-premium-connectivity-feature/"><em>Electrek</em></a>, however, owners must have an active <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-07-tesla-starts-charging-for-premium-connectivity.html">Premium Connectivity</a> subscription to activate live view. The subscription package gives them access to satellite maps and live traffic visualizations, as well as media streaming and web browsing on data. It does cost $10 a month, but owners can sign up for free trial before paying for the service.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>At this point in time, live camera is only available to iOS users who can view the footage around their cars via Tesla&#39;s app. The automaker has unfortunately yet to announce when its Android app will also get the capability.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-sentry-mode-live-view-091026473.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cb29c7a7-e2d4-4aed-ab5c-28eaa3390aec</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 09:10:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635408644</ingested><modified>2021-10-28T08:10:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/38c3c450-0a2e-11ec-afef-cb72bb49b07f" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/38c3c450-0a2e-11ec-afef-cb72bb49b07f" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[winhorse via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Hong Kong - August 13, 2021 : People walk past the Tesla official showroom in Queens Road East, Wan Chai, Hong Kong.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tesla Showroom in Hong Kong]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony has sold 13.4 million PS5s]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony&#39;s PlayStation 5 sales remain relatively steady and strong, with 3.3 million units sold in fiscal Q2 compared to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-ps5-10-million-sold-144729654.html">2.2 million last quarter</a>, bringing total sales to 13.4 million units, Sony <a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/er/archive.html">announced</a>. Game sales were also up significantly at 76.4 million units compared to 63.6 million in the previous quarter, due in large part to third-party sales.</p><p>All told, this amounted to a healthy 27 percent boost in gaming revenue to 645.4 billion yen ($5.68 billion). However, operating income of 82.7 billion yen ($728 million) was down compared to last quarter by 3.4 billion yen ($29 million). Sony&#39;s fiscal year ends on March 31, 2022.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>So how can profit be lower when sales and revenue are up? While Sony did sell more games last quarter, first-party titles dropped very significantly, from 10.5 million last quarter to 7.6 million in Q2. That was offset in numbers by third-party games, but those don&#39;t tend to be as profitable. Both <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-buys-zenimax-bethesda-id-arkane-131006192.html">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-19-sony-interactive-snaps-up-spider-man-developer-insomniac-games.html">Sony</a> have acquired gaming studios to boost their Xbox/PS first-party titles, but Microsoft has been more prolific in that regard.&nbsp;</p><p>And while PS5 sales were up, PS4 units dropped considerably, down to just 200,000 from a half a million the quarter before. Other factors that Sony mentioned are a &quot;loss resulting from strategic price points for PS5 hardware that were set lower than manufacturing costs.&quot; That means that Sony may have sold the PS5 with minimal or negative profits this quarter, although in August, the company said it was <a href="https://www.vg247.com/ps5-no-longer-selling-at-a-loss">no longer</a> selling the PS5 at a loss.&nbsp;</p><p>Despite the drop in quarterly income, Sony&#39;s gaming division appears to be on pretty solid footing. In its August earnings call, Sony CFO Hiroki Totoki told investors that its PS5 sales target is set higher than the 14.8 million unit sales achieved by the PlayStation 4 in its first year. Based on today&#39;s figures, PS5 sales are closely tracking that trajectory.</p><p>The company also said at the time that it had secured enough components for 22.6 million units sold by March 2022. That would be enough to meet its sales projections, but if sales really explode during the holidays, it may not have a lot of margin for error — meaning shortages could continue through next year.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-has-sold-134-million-ps5s-084114658.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2bab9ba0-b9da-4144-a72f-827bbb38dd55</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 08:41:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635411970</ingested><modified>2021-10-28T09:06:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Earnings]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/58115730-37c1-11ec-bfba-667c8280e1fd" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/58115730-37c1-11ec-bfba-667c8280e1fd" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony has sold 13.4 million PS5s]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony has sold 13.4 million PS5s]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Star Trek: Prodigy’ centers technology by focusing on those who don’t have it]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post contains moderate spoilers for the first episode and slight spoilers for episode two of ‘</em><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Paramount+;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Star Trek: Prodigy" href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/n12OYa"><em>Star Trek: Prodigy</em></a><em>.’</em></p><p>How do you make a series that can draw in newcomers while still appealing to long-time fans? In the case of <em>Star Trek: Prodigy</em>, you set it in a place where the United Federation of Planets has little to no presence — the Delta Quadrant — and make your cast a bunch of misfit kids who have never heard of the Federation or Starfleet. That puts them on the same level as the children this show hopes to draw in, while offering up just enough tidbits to intrigue their Trekkie parents.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="1c31ae1e21af4b5c8b4e1f37907ddd94"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EBE7d8sH5Rg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The pilot, ‘Lost and Found,’ is a feature-length episode that debuted today on <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Paramount+;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Paramount+" href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/5bM07o">Paramount+</a> (that means it’s technically two parts). It was originally planned to air on Nickelodeon first, but it was changed to a streaming-exclusive for 2021 with the cable channel airing it later at a still-unknown date. The animated show fills in the content gap between the end of <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Paramount+;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Lower Decks" href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/a1Wk1R"><em>Lower Decks</em></a> earlier this month and the premiere of <a href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/EaZn7n"><em>Discovery</em></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-discovery-november-18-paramount-plus-014439729.html">season four</a> in November — which in turn, should carry fans through to the start of season two of <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Paramount+;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Picard" href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-25-star-trek-picard-technology-evolution.html"><em>Picard</em></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-picard-paramount-plus-2022-034119473.html">in February</a>. The idea is to keep Star Trek fans from dropping their subscriptions to Paramount+ during the downtime, something that was fairly common during <em>Discovery</em>’s first three seasons.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ef1a9730-3763-11ec-b5fe-7dc4933d8c37" style="height:1202;width:2910;" alt="Pictured: Environmental coverage of the Paramount+ series Star Trek: Prodigy . Photo Cr: Nickelodeon/Paramount+ &#xc2;&#xa9;2021, All Rights Reserved." data-uuid="3824d428-ab1e-3147-894f-411ce3d0c410"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nickelodeon</div></figure><p>That assumes, however, that <em>Prodigy</em> has something to offer those adult fans. And that’s where the deeper ties to Trek lore come in. Though Voyager spent seven years in the Delta Quadrant, the ship’s mission to get back to Federation space meant it couldn’t stick around in any one place too long, or return to previous locales. There’s a ton left to explore — as well as plenty of room for Prodigy’s creators, Dan and Kevin Hageman, to populate their own corner of the universe.</p><p>First, they have to introduce their main characters, and that’s what ‘Lost and Found’ is largely dedicated to doing. Our cast of misfits, led by Dal (voiced by Brett Gray), lives on a mining colony populated by prisoners and orphans. It’s the last place anyone would want to be, especially a Star Trek character, which is why the main drive is to just get off this bleak rock. But right away the series makes its point about being far from Federation space and technology, as the inhabitants can’t even talk to each other due to a lack of universal translators. That system has been how, for over 55 years, Star Trek has managed to populate its cast with aliens who all speak English. It’s the future! Different languages aren’t a problem!</p><div id="6ded429095d343f49f76765bc22e338f"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y-1VLAt_UjU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Except here, they are. It keeps the characters from even knowing each other’s names, which makes the discovery of the <em>USS Protostar</em> and its built-in translator the perfect opportunity for everyone to re-introduce themselves to each other and thus, to the audience. And, when Dal and Rocktok discover a lost Starfleet ship buried under the surface of the planet, the ship itself may fill them with awe, but it’s the translator that truly elicits the most enthusiastic reaction: Rocktok calls it “magic.” It’s a rather fitting introduction to a franchise with a goal to “seek out new life and new civilizations,” in how it puts the connection between these disparate aliens up front.</p><p>When I saw the pilot at New York Comic Con <a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-prodigy-first-look-183049340.html">a few weeks ago</a>, I compared it to shows like <em>Clone Wars</em> and <em>Rebels</em>. The Star Wars influence that J.J. Abrams brought to the Star Trek franchise is still present in <em>Prodigy</em>, notably in its action sequences and score, the latter composed by frequent Michael Giacchino collaborator Nami Melumad. Giacchino is best known for his work on various Pixar and Star Trek films, and he also supplies the main theme for <em>Prodigy</em>. You can hear his influence on Melumad’s score, which does a great job of blending a quirky style with the signature Trek leitmotifs.</p><div id="5654405eac214090b0555ebfac963ae8"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bm9Zv8D70hA?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The final action sequence feels like pure Star Wars, as the <em>USS Protostar</em> makes its way off the planet and Dal is trapped on its hull, battling the villainous Drednok. The bad guy’s insect-like cyborg body reminds me of General Grievous — if the general could turn into a giant gun, that is. It’s the kind of thing that works best in CG and, like <em>Lower Decks</em> before it, <em>Prodigy</em> seems more than willing to embrace the extra freedom offered by animation as a medium. We’re long past the clunky microfiche displays and <a href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Unnamed_non-humanoids_(23rd_century)#Alfa_177_canine">cosplaying dogs</a> of the original series.</p><p>That freedom is probably best illustrated in the character of hologram Captain Janeway, voiced by Kate Mulgrew (of course). It’s been over 20 years since <em>Voyager</em> last graced the small screen, and Mulgrew has kept busy on shows like <em>Warehouse 13</em> and <em>Orange is the New Black</em>. But in the Star Trek universe, it’s only been six years (though an exact date is never given on-screen in <em>Prodigy</em>). Animation means they can easily erase the decades from Janeway without resorting to the creepy live-action simulacrums seen in <em>Rogue One</em> of Moff Tarkin and Princess Leia.</p><div id="75b15dc6009244ccb45c9541f1791597"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lp2MfWFF2Wk?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Hologram Janeway makes her debut at the end of today’s pilot episode, but she’ll make a much fuller appearance in next week’s ‘Starstruck.’ That’s where the new “cadets” get to explore the ship and learn more about the distant “Federation.” While there’s still plenty of banter and conflict between the characters, the real star of the second episode is the ship itself — what it looks like, and what it’s capable of. While there is a plot — which I won’t divulge details of — it serves as a showcase for all the different features of this new prototype ship. You can almost imagine Janeway as a car salesman, slapping the hood of the <em>Protostar</em> and saying “this baby’s warp core can travel to so many planets.”</p><p>Star Trek has always been a humanist franchise, devoted to exploring social themes and dilemmas. It also has a tendency to take its technology and the “post-scarcity utopia” for granted. <em>Prodigy</em> goes against the grain by showing from the start how technology can change lives.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-prodigy-first-episode-lost-and-found-070033462.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">28afb0c2-e566-46b9-b5b0-81b41cc36261</guid><dc:creator>Kris Naudus</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 07:00:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635367336</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T20:42:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Naudus]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3509a530-3762-11ec-bfff-73234ee97e27" width="2910" height="1308" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3509a530-3762-11ec-bfff-73234ee97e27" width="2910" height="1308" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nickelodeon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Pictured: Environmental coverage of the Paramount+ series Star Trek: Prodigy . Photo Cr: Nickelodeon/Paramount+ Â©2021, All Rights Reserved.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[STAR TREK: PRODIGY]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung posts record-high revenue thanks to its chip and mobile businesses]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The third quarter of 2021 was a record breaker for Samsung, which <a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-electronics-announces-3q-2021-results?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=direct">posted</a> a revenue of 73.98 trillion Korean won or US$63.1 billion. That&#39;s 10 percent higher from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-q3-2020-012410766.html">same period</a> last year. It also reported an operating profit of 15.82 trillion Korean won or U$13.5 billion, which is 26 percent higher than the previous quarter&#39;s.&nbsp;</p><p>Despite the pandemic, the tech giant&#39;s semiconductor business posted 26.4 trillion won or US$22.6 billion in revenue, thanks to a strong demand for computers due to companies implementing work-from-home arrangements. Its DRAM sales, mainly for servers, continue to grow and is the leading factor for the division&#39;s stellar performance. Samsung says it was able to do business as usual despite the global shortage in chip components &quot;by flexibly operating its product mix.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition to its chip business, Samsung&#39;s mobile division also contributed greatly to its record-breaking third quarter. It saw an improvement from the previous quarter, with its 28.42 trillion won or U$24.2 billion in revenue, thanks to strong sales of its mass-market lineup and its flagship models. The latter includes its new foldable devices, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review-s-pen-camera-battery-test-190051606.html">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-drops-to-850-at-amazon-samsung-week-deals-143712131.html">Galaxy Z Flip 3</a>, though the company admitted that the bigger marketing investments for its foldables affected the division&#39;s total profits.&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s also thanks to the high demand for its phones that Samsung&#39;s display business was able to post 8.86 trillion won or US$7.5 billion in revenue. Display earnings were up from the previous quarter primarily due to the higher demand for small to medium OLED panels despite a sluggish demand for bigger panels.</p><p>Samsung remains optimistic for the fourth quarter, as well as for next year, but it didn&#39;t provide specific guidance for its chip business due to the ongoing component supply issue affecting various industries. It expects continued high demand for PCs and servers, nonetheless. For the fourth quarter specifically, it&#39;s expecting even higher earnings &quot;due to expanded supply of SoCs and related products for launches of new 5G smartphones in 2022.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-q3-earnings-chip-mobile-record-high-030342880.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">83f6b95f-9f4c-4683-a1a2-39b51c55038d</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 04:10:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635394309</ingested><modified>2021-10-28T04:11:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Earnings]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/11a79e70-d24b-11eb-be8f-cf4a23cb519b" width="4074" height="2716" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/11a79e70-d24b-11eb-be8f-cf4a23cb519b" width="4074" height="2716" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JHVEPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Toronto, Canada - May 16, 2020: Samsung store at Eaton Centre in Toronto, Canada. Samsung is a South Korean multinational conglomerate.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung store at Eaton Centre in Toronto, Canada.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Everybody gets hats in the first free 'Bugsnax' DLC, The Isle of BIGsnax]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PlayStation exclusive <em>Bugsnax</em> is getting a lot bigger in a few different ways next year with the Isle of BIGsnax update. Heading to PlayStation 4 and PS5 in early 2022, The Isle of BIGsnax unlocks a new landscape filled with oversized Bugsnax, plus it adds challenges to complete and hut-decorating options back on Snaktooth Island. And of course, the cutest part of the update is the ability to dress up your Bugsnax in various hats.&nbsp;</p><p>The Isle of BIGsnax update will be free for all <em>Bugsnax</em> owners (try saying that ten times fast).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="e70878d00f80497b9872a0a3ecd12c22"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HAVakaioxRY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p><em>Bugsnax</em> was a PS5 launch title, dropping alongside a tight roster of big names like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/miles-morales-ps5-review-spider-man-161228925.html"><em>Spider-Man: Miles Morales</em></a> and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/demons-souls-ps5-remake-gameplay-trailer-212138725.html"><em>Demon&#39;s Souls remake</em></a>. It comes from independent studio Young Horses, which was previously known for making <em>Octodad</em>, a surprisingly heartwarming physics game about an octopus pretending to be a normal father.</p><p>Recently, Young Horses has <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bugsnax-developer-four-day-work-week">made headlines</a> for establishing a permanent four-day work week, in the interest of cultivating a healthy work-life balance for employees. This is a big deal in the video game industry, where <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-25-red-dead-redemption-2-review-crunch-rockstar.html">crunch</a> — implementing 100-hour weeks and otherwise overwhelming employees&#39; lives — is a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-04-anthem-crunch-bioware-ea-game-development.html">common business practice</a>.</p><p>“While I enjoy making weirdo games, it&#39;s also just very important that I&#39;m making responsible decisions to take care of the people I work with, stuff like that,” Young Horses co-founder Philip Tibitoski <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bugsnax-octodad-young-horses-ps5-indie-interview-201014684.html">told Engadget in January</a>. “That&#39;s become much more of a thing than it used to be, or at least I&#39;ve moved further into a business-y, boss role, I guess. Weird, but feels right.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bugsnax-dlc-isle-bigsnax-early-2022-ps4-ps5-222144847.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ab2fbb90-5fb5-4c49-a8c3-e379be021ce5</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 22:21:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635373541</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T22:25:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ddadff50-3772-11ec-bebf-dd8d02be9fe7" width="2802" height="1468" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ddadff50-3772-11ec-bebf-dd8d02be9fe7" width="2802" height="1468" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Young Horses]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bugsnax: The Isle of BIGsnax]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bugsnax: The Isle of BIGsnax]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mercedes' electric delivery van concept cleans the surrounding air]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mercedes is using the impending <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apples-announces-new-climate-initiatives-ahead-of-cop-26-climate-conference-131617869.html">COP26 climate conference</a> to highlight its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-plans-to-go-fully-electric-by-the-end-of-the-decade-171002680.html">EV efforts</a> — and show how sustainability can involve more than a switch to battery power. The newly <a href="https://media.mbusa.com/releases/release-e803d79216fbe40bc5b04c733e09d303-the-mercedes-benz-sustaineer-an-innovation-driver-for-sustainable-urban-mobility">unveiled</a> Sustaineer delivery van concept is fully electric, as you&#39;d guess, but it also improves the environment around it. Fine particulate filters on the front and underbody purify the air around the van no matter what its speed. It even uses cast iron, ceramic-coated disc brakes that both reduce the amount of dust in the air and limit brake wear.</p><p>The Sustaineer also has solar panels on its roof to extend range and  reduce the need for plug-in charging (this sometimes contributes to CO2 emissions). It can further power devices whether or not the van is running, such as tools and laptops. Solar power on electrified vehicles is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-12-26-fisker-raises-karma-plug-in-hybrid-base-price-to-95-900-brings.html">nothing new</a>, but Mercedes clearly hopes implementations like this would keep EVs as green as possible.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Other eco-conscious technology includes an energy-saving heating system that hews close to the body (including the seatbelt) and a heavy use of recycled materials. The filler is made from household waste, the cab partition is built from natural straw and the underbody includes recycled polypropylene and used tires. Mercedes lowers noise pollution, too, thanks to a quiet electric drivetrain, low rolling resistance tires and a hushed automatic delivery door.</p><p>Safety is a concern as well. A camera monitors road conditions to share reports of potholes and other hazards with cities, while digital mirrors provide a clearer field of view than you normally get with cargo vans. A &quot;biologically active&quot; light keeps the driver alert by filling the cab with illumination similar to daylight while maintaining a natural rhythm.</p><p>There are no mentions of plans to mass-produce the Sustaineer. With that said, Mercedes stressed that all the van&#39;s technology was crafted with large-scale production in mind. You might see this in other vans, not to mention other Mercedes vehicles. The company already has other green tech on the horizon, such as sustainable repairs for EV batteries in 2022, and Sustaineer is ultimately a logical extension of those plans.</p><div id="e505d0933d35491496070d00b00a7601"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K6jazJy425o?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-benz-sustaineer-electric-delivery-van-concept-215050891.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">65ef94cb-fabc-489e-b6a9-df9aba6cef19</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 21:50:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635370266</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T21:31:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/58b71c70-3766-11ec-b9ff-5fb3824b8b74" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/58b71c70-3766-11ec-b9ff-5fb3824b8b74" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Mercedes Sustaineer electric delivery van concept]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Mercedes Sustaineer electric delivery van concept]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelda-like 'Death's Door' heads to PlayStation and Switch on November 23rd]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Death&#39;s Door</em>, one of the best indie games to come out earlier this year, is heading to PlayStation consoles. During Sony&#39;s State of Play presentation on Wednesday, Devolver Digital announced it will release the Zelda-like action-adventure game on November 23rd, allowing PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 fans to experience it. After the event, Devolver <a href="https://twitter.com/devolverdigital/status/1453469703846903811">said</a> the game would come to Nintendo Switch on the same day.&nbsp;</p><div id="897f3f9a6238426a979bb93e4f6ff808"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MxzoW_fUx_8?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Released this past summer on PC, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S, <em>Death&#39;s Door</em> is the latest project from Acid Nerve, the studio behind 2015&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-08-17-titan-souls-one-hit-point-one-bow-one-arrow-lots-of-deaths.html"><em>Titan Souls</em></a>. You play as a crow whose job it is to collect souls for a bureaucratic organization called the Reaping Commission Headquarters. In addition to The Legend of Zelda, it has a lot of similarities to From Software&#39;s Dark Souls. The game has earned praise for its art direction, music and gameplay. If you pre-order <em>Death&#39;s Door </em>on PlayStation before its November 23rd release date, you&#39;ll get <em>Titan Souls </em>for free<em>.</em>&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><strong>Update 6:12PM ET</strong>: Added information on the Nintendo Switch release.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/deaths-door-playstation-november-23-213345948.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5cfe8fa9-3adb-4dad-ba9f-14ad9b8d9275</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 21:33:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635372856</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T22:14:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/46f8aa20-376c-11ec-b67f-a1266bac8c09" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/46f8aa20-376c-11ec-b67f-a1266bac8c09" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Acid Nerve, Devolver Digital]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Death's Door]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Death's Door]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Volvo's self-driving loader prototype is based on a Lego model]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Volvo is eager to bring <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volvo-autonomous-long-haul-semi-truck-prototype-145800300.html">self-driving technology</a> to construction crews, but it&#39;s taking a decidedly unusual route to get there. The automaker has <a href="https://www.volvogroup.com/en/news-and-media/news/2021/oct/news-4100018.html">unveiled</a> an autonomous wheel loader prototype, the LX03, that&#39;s based on a Lego model — 42081 Lego Technic Concept Wheel Loader Zeux, if you&#39;re looking for it. The machine can haul 5 tons and can make its own decisions in a wide variety of situations, including team-ups with human workers.&nbsp;</p><p>The LX03 is also uniquely modular. Volvo can make &quot;just one or two changes&quot; to produce a larger or smaller loader to meet a customer&#39;s demands. It&#39;s unsurprisingly electric and can last for up to eight hours depending on the job. It should be available for a typical workday, then.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The prototype isn&#39;t indicative of a production model. It does represent the &quot;next stage&quot; in Volvo&#39;s efforts to both explore AI and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volvo-first-vehicle-fossil-free-steel-055542393.html">decarbonize construction</a>, however. And there&#39;s little denying the appeal of building a real, fully functional vehicle <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-08-30-driveable-bugatti-chiron-made-of-1-million-lego-blocks.html">based on a plastic building system</a>, particularly when it could usher in a futre that keeps humans away from dangerous and monotonous tasks.</p><div id="e3713f4b725141eab058d4fc228d08af"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r9hQXcZuU4o?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/volvo-lx03-autonomous-wheel-loader-lego-model-201519677.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">38547ed7-e80f-468e-ae94-72fd7fed170e</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 20:15:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635367078</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T20:38:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ca86f3c0-3761-11ec-9577-9ef3348bf98d" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ca86f3c0-3761-11ec-9577-9ef3348bf98d" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Volvo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Volvo LX03 autonomous wheel loader prototype]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Volvo LX03 autonomous wheel loader prototype]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple lets devs promote in-app events on the App Store]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10171/">promised at WWDC</a> earlier this year, Apple today will start letting developers <a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=zghdvfza">highlight their in-app events on the App Store</a>. You&#39;ll need iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 to see the event listings, and they work as you&#39;d expect, allowing you to see seasonal competitions, livestreams and more. It&#39;s a pretty straightforward feature, but it&#39;s the sort of thing that could encourage more people to install and use their apps.&nbsp;</p><p>Hopefully, developers won&#39;t rely on it as a spammy way to rack up engagement. Many mobile gamers would love to know when they can log on for special item drops, for example. And if you encounter a particularly intriguing upcoming event, you can also create a notification or calendar reminder of when it begins. You&#39;ll also be able to share events to get your friends on board too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-in-app-events-app-store-194526022.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">35781029-1ee3-43aa-8924-7972941bff13</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635363969</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T19:46:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/45e9a8f0-375d-11ec-aed6-6a847d138de2" width="1950" height="1184" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/45e9a8f0-375d-11ec-aed6-6a847d138de2" width="1950" height="1184" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple in-app events App Store]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple in-app events App Store]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[FCC proposes text support for the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The FCC wants to make it easier to reach the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fcc-designates-988-suicide-prevention-hotline-165133970.html">National Suicide Prevention Lifeline</a> for those who can&#39;t (or prefer not to) call. Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel has <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-consider-text-988-expand-suicide-prevention-services">proposed</a> an order that would let people text 988 to reach the Lifeline. Carriers would have to automatically route texts to 988 to the Lifeline&#39;s full number (1-800-273-8255) no later than July 16th, 2022. Providers would have to support every messaging format the Lifeline can handle, and the FCC would explore the possibility of texting the Veterans Crisis Line.</p><p>The move would not only accommodate younger people more familiar with texting, but would make the Lifeline more accessible to people with disabilities, according to the FCC. The regulator also suggested this would offer a &quot;certain level of anonymity&quot; for people who aren&#39;t comfortable with phone conversations. The FCC will hold a vote on the proposal at its November 18th meeting.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Lifeline already supports <a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/chat/">online chats</a> through the web. As Rosenworcel explained, however, this is a bid to &quot;meet [people] where they are&quot; and give them a choice in a moment of crisis. Americans would have more opportunities to get help, and might be more inclined to get that help in the first place.</p><p><em>In the U.S., the number for the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is </em><a><em>1-800-273-8255</em></a><em>. Crisis Text Line can be reached by texting HOME to 741741 (US), 686868 (Canada), or 85258 (UK).</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/fcc-text-to-988-national-suicide-prevention-hotline-191909411.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">11d59a0a-eac2-4dd8-ad3c-67ad25df0b17</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 19:19:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635364179</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T19:49:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2a57a410-3754-11ec-bfaf-f1815bd66042" width="4944" height="3324" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2a57a410-3754-11ec-bfaf-f1815bd66042" width="4944" height="3324" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Boston Globe via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BOSTON, MA - FEBRUARY 28: Sunday, a volunteer at the Samaritans Call Center takes a call at the office in Boston on Feb. 28, 2020. The volunteers answer phone calls from the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline. (Photo by Jonathan Wiggs/The Boston Globe via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samaritans Call Center]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[ESA will try to fetch data from China's Mars rover with a new method: listening]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next month on Mars, the ESA and China&#39;s National Space Administration (CNSA) will try something that&#39;s never been attempted before in space: Sending data from a planet-based rover to an orbiter that it can&#39;t receive any messages from. Specifically, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-zhurong-rover-selfie-photo-212920780.html">China&#39;s selfie-taking Zhurong rover</a>, which has been on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/cnsa-zhurong-rover-095207429.html">Red Planet since May</a>, will try to shoot data over to the ESA&#39;s Mars Express Orbiter.&nbsp;</p><p>As the<a href="https://blogs.esa.int/mex/2021/10/27/mars-express-keeps-an-ear-out-for-chinese-rover/"> ESA explains</a>, Zhurong can&#39;t actually receive any communications from the Express Orbiter, due to a radio incompatibility. That means it can&#39;t hear the hail signal sent from the orbiter, which is typically what a rover waits for before it starts sending out data. Instead, next month Mars and the ESA will attempt a new method that&#39;s previously only been tested on Earth. During five tests, Zhurong will send a signal blindly into space, and the Mars Express will listen for that signal and any potential data.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;If [Mars Express] detects the magic signal, the radio will lock on to it and begin recording any data,&quot; <a href="https://blogs.esa.int/mex/2021/10/27/mars-express-keeps-an-ear-out-for-chinese-rover/">ESA&#39;s Josh Tapley writes</a>. &quot;At the end of the communication window, the spacecraft will turn to face Earth and relay these data across space the same way it does for other scientific Mars missions. When the data arrive at ESOC, they will be forwarded on to the Zhurong team for processing and analysis.&quot;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s not unusual for rovers to send data to foreign orbiter — that&#39;s commonly been seen as a smart backup method — but this test opens the door for communication between incompatible systems. That&#39;ll be useful if China has any issues with its Tianwen-1 orbiter down the line, or if the US and other countries need help in turn.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/esa-mars-express-china-zhurong-rover-test-190629849.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3a59b8ee-55f6-44c9-8f8e-6229a2011956</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 19:06:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635363064</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T19:31:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/036ed3c0-3757-11ec-bdb6-4770ac15da6d" width="1200" height="498" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/036ed3c0-3757-11ec-bdb6-4770ac15da6d" width="1200" height="498" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[CNSA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[China's Zhurong rover and Tianwen-1 lander]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[China's Zhurong rover and Tianwen-1 lander]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Olympus cameras will be rebranded as OM System]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/olympus/"><ins>Olympus cameras</ins></a> are getting a new name. Parent company OM Digital has chosen <a href="https://omsystem.com/en/"><ins>OM System</ins></a> as the brand&#39;s new moniker.</p><p>There are still some Olympus cameras on the market and those won&#39;t be rebranded, so the two names <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-new-name-for-olympus-cameras-is-om-system-1847945086"><ins>will co-exist</ins></a> for a while. But eventually the old name will fade away as OM System introduces new models and phases out the current ones.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="f244fe509f194e56b3fd879658f9502d"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EqIsKqf03F4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>In addition to cameras and lenses, OM System plans to sell audio products, binoculars and other services. It&#39;s currently developing a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-15-micro-four-thirds-future-interview.html"><ins>Micro Four Thirds-based</ins></a> interchangeable lens camera. OM Digital plans to make more compact and lightweight systems using that standard while &quot;accelerating the improvement of image quality and photographic expression through the use of computational photographic technology,&quot; according to a press release.</p><p>Olympus finalized <a href="https://www.engadget.com/olympus-selling-consumer-camera-business-093750446.html">the sale of its imaging division</a> to Japan Industrial Partners (JIP) at the start of the year. JIP swiftly <a href="https://petapixel.com/2021/01/04/it-is-done-olympus-finalizes-sale-of-imaging-business/"><ins>spun out</ins></a> OM Digital Solutions as a separate company to oversee Olympus (now OM System) cameras.</p><div id="f2800efb315847cd804150516a881ae6"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AnS9tthnOKY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/olympus-cameras-rebrand-om-system-184727433.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8384bcff-dc5a-4e4a-859f-ef94e1a18e91</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:47:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635359858</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T18:37:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4422b020-3753-11ec-bffb-a1f8e93e30a3" width="800" height="420" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4422b020-3753-11ec-bffb-a1f8e93e30a3" width="800" height="420" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[OM System]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The logo for OM System and a tag line that reads "break free" laid over a silhoutter of a person looking at distant lights.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OM System]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adobe's Project Morpheus uses AI to automate frame-by-frame video edits]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Something Adobe does at nearly every one of its annual design conferences is preview experimental features that may one day make their way to its apps. In 2020, it was a tool called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-sharp-shot-213047501.html"><ins>Sharp Shots</ins></a>. This year, it was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-project-in-between-preview-130017575.html"><ins>Project In-Between</ins></a> and a feature called Project Morpheus.</p><div id="1fa0dae85cbe4b27ac7e82ee6bdf98cf"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bpABm6XcRMw?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Building on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/photoshop-desktop-ipad-update-artificial-intelligence-130024695.html"><ins>Neural Filters</ins></a> Adobe debuted last year, Project Morpheus is capable of automating frame-by-frame video edits in a way that produces consistent results. In the demo the company showed off, one of its employees modified a video of themselves where they had a neutral expression throughout to put a smile on their face. They did it in mere moments, with Adobe’s Sensei AI most of the heavy lifting. You only need to see the demo once to understand the potential for misuse, something Adobe told Engadget it&#39;s taking into account.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>“As with all Adobe Max Sneaks, Project Morpheus is a way in which we preview exploratory and forward-looking technologies from our research labs and engineering teams. These proof-of-concept ideas aren’t always destined for inclusion in products,” a spokesperson for the company said. “We recognize that we have to balance innovation with our responsibility to ensure our technology is being used for the good of our customers and society. Our development of AI is guided by the principles of Accountability, Responsibility and Transparency.”</p><p>Additionally, the company pointed to its work on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-content-authenticity-initiative-photoshop-213332681.html"><ins>Content Authenticity Initiative</ins></a>. First announced in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-04-adobe-twitter-nyt-digital-content-attribution.html"><ins>2019</ins></a>, the project has seen Adobe work with <em>The New York Times</em> and Twitter to develop a metadata tagging system designed to limit the number of altered images and videos that circulate online. At Max 2021, it also started beta testing Content Credentials. It allows professionals, including photojournalists and artists, to attach attribution data to their images that detail the edit history of a file.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/adobe-max-sneaks-project-morpheus-183702995.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5e6adbb5-126d-4aaf-9c49-b729bfbfa95e</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:37:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635359871</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T18:38:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/036ae380-3754-11ec-bee7-8661342566dd" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/036ae380-3754-11ec-bee7-8661342566dd" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Adobe Project Morpheus]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Adobe Project Morpheus]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Call of Duty: Vanguard' install size maxes out at 93GB on consoles, thankfully]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-duty-vanguard-california-fires-2020-stalingrad-153029085.html"><em>Call of Duty: Vanguard</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>won&#39;t eat up as much console disk space as previous games in the series, but you still might need to delete some downloads to make room for all this <a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-november-5-174533819.html">WWII frenzy</a>. Here&#39;s how much space you&#39;ll need on each console to install <em>Vanguard</em> at launch, including the pre-load:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Xbox One:</strong> 56.6GB</p></li><li><p><strong>Xbox Series X/S:</strong> 61GB</p></li><li><p><strong>PS4:</strong> 93.12GB (54.65GB download)</p></li><li><p><strong>PS5:</strong> 89.84GB (64.13GB download)</p></li></ul><p>This marks a significant decrease from last year&#39;s Call of Duty installment, <em>Black Ops Cold War</em>, which hit <a href="https://gamerant.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-cold-war-200-gb-file/">200GB of required space on PS5</a> and <a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/call-of-duty-black-ops-cold-war-requires-up-to-250gb-of-storage">250GB on PC</a>, with similar numbers on other platforms. Meanwhile, 2019&#39;s <em>Modern Warfare</em> launched at 175GB and grew with updates, while <em>Warzone</em> added an additional 15GB - 22GB, or 80GB - 100GB on its own. Activision rolled out <a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-update-smaller-file-size-warzone-122042711.html">a big update in March</a> to reduce the footprint of <em>Modern Warfare</em> and <em>Warzone</em>, and Call of Duty developers have long been aware that <a href="https://twitter.com/Tyrael/status/1227301301886713856">file sizes are an issue</a> for many players.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;Good news for hard drives everywhere,&quot; the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2021/10/vanguard-console-preloading-launch-file-size">Call of Duty blog</a> reads. &quot;Due to new on-demand texture streaming tech<em>, Vanguard’s </em>install<em>&nbsp;</em>size at launch will be significantly below that of previous Call of Duty releases — up to 30% - 50%+ of a file size difference on next-gen console and PC.&quot;</p><p>Activision has yet to release details on the size of the PC install for <em>Vanguard</em>, but pre-loading on PC begins November 2nd.</p><p>Pre-loading for PS4 and PS5 versions of the game begins on October 28th at 9PM PT in North and South America, and midnight local time on October 29th in other countries. Xbox One and Series X/S pre-loading starts at the same time across the board: October 28th at 9PM PT. Anyone who pre-ordered the game digitally can pre-load it so it&#39;s ready to rock at launch on November 5th.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/call-duty-vanguard-install-size-consoles-180936454.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">da77cdb9-ed14-4fc4-ae3a-d35bf79aba92</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:09:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635358954</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T18:22:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a4491600-374f-11ec-ad7f-905c5fb292fd" width="960" height="540" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a4491600-374f-11ec-ad7f-905c5fb292fd" width="960" height="540" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Activision]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Vanguard]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Vanguard]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Onewheel GT is Future Motion's first three-horsepower electric board]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two more <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/onewheel/">Onewheel</a> electric boards have arrived to expand Future Motion&#39;s lineup. The Onewheel Pint X is an upgraded version of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-12-onewheel-pint.html">Onewheel Pint</a> from 2019. It has double the range of the previous model at up to 18 miles per charge and a faster top speed of 18 mph (compared with the Pint&#39;s 16mph limit).</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/117236c0-3689-11ec-bf5d-8b3bc4437a17" alt="Onewheel Pint X" data-uuid="040cdab1-9e1c-3f5a-80e1-244c64811fa5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Future Motion</div></figure><p>Although it has similar specs to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-01-10-onewheel-plus-xr-electric-skateboard-hands-on.html">Onewheel+ XR</a> (which tops out at 19mph), the Pint X is smaller than that machine. The cost is lower too, at $1,400, compared with the Onewheel+ XR&#39;s starting price of $1,799. It&#39;s more expensive than the $950 Onewheel Pint. Still, for those looking for a Pint-sized model with higher performance, the Pint X, which is available now, might fit the bill.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>At the higher end of the lineup is Future Motion&#39;s new flagship electric board: the Onewheel GT. The company designed the board from scratch, and it includes a new control system with a higher voltage. That, according to Future Motion, will deliver more power, torque and dynamic performance at all speeds. In fact, it&#39;s the first three-horsepower Onewheel.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2ba2ed00-3689-11ec-bdfb-639b04e51d09" alt="Onewheel GT" data-uuid="87885ac1-9ff9-3e20-853e-b12f4c60969f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Future Motion</div></figure><p>A new battery system will keep the Onewheel GT rolling for up to 32 miles on a single charge, the company claims. Elsewhere, Future Motion says the built-in Maghandle Pro and LED headlights are over 300 percent brighter than lighting in other models, so the GT might be more viable for nighttime rides. The footpads might be more comfortable too, since they&#39;re concave on both sides. In addition, there&#39;s a version with a treaded tire for increased traction.</p><p>The Onewheel GT is also available starting today, but a premium product means a higher price. It starts at $2,200. However, Future Motion is sweetening the deal for the first 48 hours with promotional offers such as bundle savings up to $275, free fenders and free priority shipping to the lower 48 states.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/onewheel-gt-pint-x-future-motion-180021707.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0e65bfb8-69e1-45a6-a571-7d4edf4c4dc8</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 18:00:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635359514</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T18:31:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/598af0a0-3689-11ec-af7d-20caf4cdfc2d" width="5884" height="3393" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/598af0a0-3689-11ec-af7d-20caf4cdfc2d" width="5884" height="3393" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Future Motion]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Onewheel GT and Pint X]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Onewheel GT and Pint X]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[US Copyright Office provides a path to allow for more device repairs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The right to repair movement just got a big boost from the US Copyright Office. Responding to proposals from a variety of organizations, including the <a href="https://www.eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation</a> and <a href="https://www.ifixit.com/Right-to-Repair/Intro">iFixit</a>, the office on Wednesday recommended new exemptions to <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/1201">Section 1201</a> of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act as it relates to the repair of consumer electronics. The statute prohibits the circumvention of software copy protection and has been the target of right to repair advocates for years.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747310/us-copyright-office-dmca-section-1201-exemption-rulemaking-report"><em>The Verge</em></a>, the Copyright Office <a href="https://cdn.loc.gov/copyright/1201/2021/2021_Section_1201_Registers_Recommendation.pdf">recommends</a> additional protections for many consumer-facing devices that rely on software to function. As one example, it adopts a recommendation from Public Knowledge and iFixit that involves video game consoles. It says “the repair of software-enabled consumer devices is likely to be fair use, the Register finds that certain video game console repair is also likely fair use.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>It notes consumers can access the firmware on their systems as long as it’s with the intention of fixing the device’s optical drive and they restore any protective measures afterward. The rulemaking stops short of protecting non-consumer devices. However, the Library of Congress has <a href="https://public-inspection.federalregister.gov/2021-23311.pdf">signed off on the recommendations</a>, paving the way for them to go into effect on October 28th. In a statement to Engadget, the EFF applauded the decision but said Congress needs to modify Section 1201.&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>The new rules enacted by the Librarian of Congress represent a victory for security research, accessibility, education, preservation, and repair. While the exemptions do continue to contain unnecessary and harmful limitations, we&#39;re pleased with the additional freedom to operate that the Librarian granted in this rulemaking. The largest disappointment, however, is that the agency failed to protect the public&#39;s ability to make non-infringing modifications of device software as we requested. This kind of user innovation has been a profoundly important driver of advances in technology and lets communities who are not served by a technology&#39;s default functions to customize them to their own needs. We are also mindful that the rulemaking process is inherently limited: while the Librarian can authorize people to engage in circumvention, they cannot create exemptions to the part of the law (Section 1201(a)(2)) that prohibits the dissemination of the technology needed to achieve circumvention. Congress needs to remove that restriction in order to give these legal rights to circumvent their full practical effect.</p></blockquote><p>iFixit had a similar take on the decision.&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>We&#39;re glad the Register of Copyrights finally agreed that copyright law shouldn&#39;t keep you from fixing your stuff — regardless of what &#39;type&#39; of device it is. A legal solution for repairing optical drives on Xboxes and PlayStations is long overdue, and will help put desperately needed bricked consoles back in service. Unfortunately, the new rules still maintain some absurd limitations — like excluding commercial devices and noninfringing modification of software-enabled devices (like changing the settings on a software-enabled cat litter box). Particularly troubling is the Register&#39;s reliance on potential service contracts with manufacturers in order to deny the exemption for repair of commercial or industrial equipment. If repair is non-infringing (which it is) then manufacturers&#39; monopoly-preserving service contracts shouldn&#39;t prevent the Office from granting anbear on the issuance of the exemption. Moreover, the Copyright Office&#39;s process has some fatal flaws: exemption proponents have to return every three years to argue that their exemptions be renewed (a process that is both time and resource intensive), and it doesn&#39;t address whether people can make or distribute repair tools that circumvent manufacturer&#39;s digital locks. Without access to those tools, the exemptions are largely academic. This is why Congress needs to step in an permanently exempt repair, and repair tools, from Section 1201. Copyright Law should never stand in the way of repair. Until Congress finally fixes Section 1201 and grants a permanent right to repair, we’re going to be stuck on this ferris wheel with the Copyright Office every three years.</p></blockquote><p>The decision will complement the efforts of the Biden administration on the same front. At the start of July, the president <a href="https://www.engadget.com/president-biden-right-to-repair-executive-order-211328084.html">ordered the Federal Trade Commission</a> to draft new rules to empower consumers and businesses to repair their devices on their own and at independent shops. The executive order marked the first time a US president had ever weighed in on the right to repair movement. Later that same month, the FTC complied with the directive, voting unanimously to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-right-to-repair-policy-statement-203721173.html">tackle unlawful repair restrictions</a>. At the time, it said it would work with law enforcement and policymakers to update existing regulations to protect small businesses and companies that would prevent them from fixing their own products.</p><p><strong>Update 2:03PM ET</strong>: Added comment from the Electronic Frontier Foundation. We&#39;ve also changed the headline to better reflect the nature of the Copyright Office&#39;s rulemaking.</p><p><strong>Update 2:51PM ET</strong>: Added comment from iFixit.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/us-copyright-office-section-1203-exemptions-172514601.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">94a8f974-13dc-42bd-b8fb-08a3cd143078</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:25:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635361057</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T18:57:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Legislative Branch]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f0e0c00-3747-11ec-bfd3-bdafb5f07762" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f0e0c00-3747-11ec-bfd3-bdafb5f07762" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[aldarinho via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Toronto, Canada - May, 23,2020: Close up of disassemble game controller repairing, cleaning or diagnostic.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Close up of disassemble game controller repairing, cleaning or diagnostic.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's own TVs will support AirPlay 2 and HomeKit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fire-tv-2021-update-omni-fire-tv-4-series-130041393.html">first in-house TVs</a> may be showcases for Alexa, but that isn&#39;t precluding the company from supporting someone else&#39;s ecosystem. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747811/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-apple-airplay-2-homekit">According</a> to <em>The Verge</em>, Amazon has unveiled plans to add support for Apple&#39;s AirPlay 2 and HomeKit to both higher-end Omni and budget 4-series Fire TV sets now that they&#39;re available. You can use AirPlay 2 to cast content from your iPhone, iPad or Mac, but the HomeKit integration may be the most notable — yes, you can use Siri to control an Amazon TV as part of your wider smart home network. Amazon would only say the support was coming &quot;soon.&quot;</p><p>The TVs themselves start <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon Fire TV 4-series" href="https://amzn.to/3jJyUgd">at $370</a> for the 4-series, which provide the usual Fire TV integrations along with 4K and HDR support in sizes ranging from 43 inches to 55 inches. Omni sets, meanwhile, deliver Alexa-friendly far-field microphones and (on the two largest models) Dolby Vision HDR. They start <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08T6DZ81T/">at $410</a> and range from 43 inches to 75 inches.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The expansion isn&#39;t a complete shock. Insignia- and Toshiba-made Fire TV Edition sets <a href="https://www.engadget.com/toshiba-insignia-fire-tv-airplay-2-homekit-update-013526800.html">received AirPlay and HomeKit support</a> in July. We&#39;d add that Apple and Amazon are relatively cozy. Amazon <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-14-apple-music-works-on-echo-speakers.html">Echo speakers have streamed Apple Music</a> since 2018, for instance, while Prime Video integrates with the Apple TV app. Amazon has a strong incentive to include AirPlay and HomeKit, if just to fend off competition from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-tv-update-features-from-google-tv-160004195.html">Android TV</a> and sets that rely on Google Assistant.</p><p>As <em>The Verge</em> observed, though, there&#39;s no mention of either Apple platform coming to add-on media players like the Fire TV Stick 4K Max. For now, you&#39;ll have to buy hardware like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-4k-review-2021-new-siri-remote-150054255.html">Apple TV</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-os-10-airplay-2-homekit-support-hd-devices-130003400.html">modern Roku devices</a> to bring AirPlay and HomeKit to TVs where they aren&#39;t built-in.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-airplay-2-homekit-support-171505953.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bde172a4-c133-4022-9648-c748645b344c</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:15:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635353597</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T16:53:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f5a0d50-3740-11ec-be3e-c8f57be2f9d0" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f5a0d50-3740-11ec-be3e-c8f57be2f9d0" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Fire TV Omni]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Fire TV Omni]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to use SharePlay on iOS 15]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>iOS 15.1 was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-group-workout-shareplay-available-now-170031703.html">released yesterday</a>, which means you can finally start checking out Apple&#39;s long-awaited <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-wwdc-2021-facetime-messages-notification-summary-live-text-172526551.html">SharePlay feature</a>. After seeing how buggy it was on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html">the iOS 15 beta</a>, I was able to check out SharePlay this week during a briefing with Apple, and the experience was surprisingly smooth. Though SharePlay works with just <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/story/id1583059388">a small collection of apps</a> at the moment, it&#39;s also coming soon to Disney+, while the NBA and TikTok apps will be updated today to support it. I watched a few videos and a Milwaukee Bucks game via these apps on my demo, and beyond being impressed by how much more stable everything is since the beta, I also found some tips particularly useful.</p><h2>Setup and starting a SharePlay session</h2><p>First, make sure you and your friends all update your devices to iOS 15.1 or iPadOS 15.1. Just like we observed in the beta, you need to start a FaceTime call before you can SharePlay anything. Once you&#39;re on a call, open a supported app and you&#39;ll see an alert at the top of the screen asking if you want to stream your content. When you start a session, your callers will see a box pop up at the top of the screen to join you.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>For the most part, everyone you&#39;re SharePlaying with will need to have the relevant apps installed (i.e. TikTok, HBO Max, Showtime, Paramount, Apple TV etc). In some cases, they&#39;ll also need to have a subscription or at least an account.&nbsp;</p><p>While you watch a show together, anyone on the call can pause, skip forward or rewind, and that will bring everyone to the same point on the stream. As you watch something, FaceTime will run in picture-in-picture mode on top of your display, and whoever on your call is talking will appear in that box.&nbsp;</p><h2>Share your screen</h2><p>If you want to share your screen instead of watching a show, though, you&#39;ll need to tap on the screen while on your FaceTime call to pull up the commands panel and press the button on the right that resembles a person in front of a rectangle.&nbsp;</p><p>While you&#39;re sharing your screen, your friend can pinch to zoom on what you&#39;re showing them. But during a screen share session, your alerts (or other notices that pop up) won&#39;t appear on their screen, in case there&#39;s sensitive info you don&#39;t want others seeing. The pill on the top left of your screen will also turn purple to let remind you you&#39;re screen-sharing.&nbsp;</p><p>When I was watching someone share their screen, by the way, I could still go back to my own phone and open another app. FaceTime&#39;s picture-in-picture tile showed my caller&#39;s screen with their face in an embedded picture-in-picture. Inception!</p><h2>Other features</h2><p>The controls box also lets you access the iMessage window for everyone on the call. You can continue to watch a game on the NBA app with your family without your camera or mic on, and send texts instead. That&#39;s particularly helpful when you need a toilet break when a game runs long.</p><p>Apple also built a feature called smart volume to automatically lower the streaming audio when you&#39;re speaking so everyone can hear you. This works best with AirPods, but it&#39;ll also work with your device&#39;s speaker.</p><p>Depending on each app&#39;s developers, other tools can be embedded to make them more useful. In Apple Music, for example, you can look at the song&#39;s lyrics as they play in real time, and tapping on a specific lyric will bring you and your callers to that point in the track. When you&#39;re all on TikTok together, each person can like the videos they want, too. The popular game Heads Up will also be coming to SharePlay so you can guess the word on your face while your friends act it out for you.&nbsp;</p><p>SharePlay works with iPhones, iPads and Apple TVs, and most playback features are the same across Apple&#39;s ecosystem. Those with Apple Watches will also be able to use this feature for group workouts or meditations on Fitness+ with up to 32 callers. So far, SharePlay works with just a few apps, but as more developers integrate it, iOS users could find more ways to socialize and digitally gather with loved ones soon.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/shareplay-on-ios-15-hands-on-how-to-guide-170020600.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">74c073cf-7de1-44c1-88d7-ad4eb826e218</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:00:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635353980</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T16:59:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/91f1f5e0-3744-11ec-bea7-46a0fa6a73ae" width="3900" height="2310" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/91f1f5e0-3744-11ec-bea7-46a0fa6a73ae" width="3900" height="2310" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A composite of three images showing how SharePlay on iOS 15 works.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SharePlay on iOS 15]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google is giving Android on tablets another shot]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case there wasn&#39;t enough news this week, Google is revealing a new version of Android that&#39;s designed for larger screens like tablets and foldables. It&#39;s called Android 12L, and is really just a set of new features for the existing OS that are optimized for big screens. The developer preview is available today as an SDK <a href="https://developer.android.com/">on Google&#39;s site</a> so app makers can begin taking in some of the new features that should make for a more cohesive experience on devices with bigger displays. The public version of 12L will arrive early next year, &quot;in time for the next wave of Android 12 tablets and foldables,&quot; the company said. The preview will also be &quot;coming soon to the Lenovo P12 Pro.&quot;</p><p>While Android already supports a sort of multi-window experience, there are still areas of the interface that feel more like a blown up version of a phone OS, rather than something that makes better use of the increased space. One of the things coming to Android 12L is a two-column layout for the notification shade and lockscreen when the system detects that the screen is above <a href="https://material.io/design/layout/pixel-density.html#pixel-density">600dps</a> wide. Google said other system surfaces and apps will adopt this look too, though it didn&#39;t specify which yet.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Android 12L will also feature a taskbar at the bottom of larger screens that will let you more easily open apps. This will also simplify the process of launching things in split-screen mode: just drag and drop an icon from the taskbar. Google is also enabling all apps to run in split screen, regardless of whether they are resizable.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b044ea20-373a-11ec-97ce-94d84a270f05" alt="An animation showing how to drag and drop icons from the new task bar on Android 12L to launch an app in split screen." data-uuid="502dde2b-0193-37bf-8e27-f4e35398c566"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Cosmetically, Google is also adding tools that let developers make their apps look better in various windows or views. They&#39;ll be able to use custom letterbox colors or treatments, apply custom rounded corners and adjust the position of inset windows.&nbsp;</p><p>The above features are already available for preview in the developer software, but there are also changes coming that app creators have to apply for users to experience them. Google recommends that developers create versions of their UI tailored to the window size class of each device, and it&#39;s added reference devices for programmers to see their layouts across phones, tablets, foldable&#39;s larger internal displays and desktops.&nbsp;</p><p>For devices that can fold, Android 12L will offer an API that will allow developers to make their apps aware of hinges or other boundaries, and use them &quot;as natural separators.&quot; This means that when supported, you might be able to use an app like Kindle and have it show a two-column layout when your device is folded and expand to fullscreen when you open your phone completely flat.</p><p>Google is also adding ways to make adopting this easier for developers with a new Activity embedding tool and other updates in the Jetpack Window Manager library. The interface will be backward-compatible, so those using older versions of Android can still use apps that are optimized for 12L.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/79125420-36a9-11ec-afff-89ccaa22737b" alt="An animation showing the Messages app expand into a two-column layout when its screen is extended." data-uuid="a0620ac0-d661-3648-b9ce-57e07d5e6d4d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>The company is also releasing its Material You design system to Jetpack Compose, so that developers can add the adaptive theming capabilities to their apps. This means that, when supported, third-party apps can also take on the color scheme that Google derived from your wallpaper, and buttons or menu highlight hues can reflect the palette for a more cohesive look throughout Android 12.&nbsp;</p><p>Finally, to give developers a reason (or disincentive) to get their apps optimized for Android 12L, Google is updating the Play Store. It will check each app against its <a href="https://developer.android.com/docs/quality-guidelines/large-screens-app-quality">large screen app quality guidelines</a> and take the results into ranking and search listing considerations. It&#39;ll go even further by warning people on bigger devices with notices on an app&#39;s Play Store page if it&#39;s not been optimized for 12L.&nbsp;</p><p>Android has long faced criticism over being a poor OS for tablets and bigger displays, and 12L does appear promising. Google also announced some updates to make it easier for developers to code for WearOS, including offering Jetpack Compose support for the platform. It looks like the company is working hard to improve areas that it&#39;s been behind Apple on, and we&#39;ll have to see how developers take to these changes to know if Google&#39;s tablet, foldable and smartwatch dreams might succeed.</p><p></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/android-12-l-tablets-foldables-170002343.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c9443d30-d371-468b-b5a8-a37777773a6c</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635354372</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T17:06:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5a3bbc80-36a9-11ec-befe-f81a460fcf06" width="1600" height="848" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5a3bbc80-36a9-11ec-befe-f81a460fcf06" width="1600" height="848" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Examples of Google's Android 12L on four different devices: A phone, foldable, tablet and vertical tablet.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Android 12L]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hinge users can send voice messages and add audio notes to profiles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/hinge/"><ins>Hinge</ins></a> is the latest dating app that&#39;s making a push into audio. Starting today, users can attach voice clips to profiles, in what&#39;s said to be a first for a major dating app. You can also send audio notes to your matches.</p><p>You can add an audio clip to your profile by going to the Edit Profile section of the settings and selecting Voice Prompt. You can choose a prompt (a question or comment suggested by the app to highlight something about you) and respond with a 30-second recording. “This is just the beginning of a lot of things that we’ll see come out over the next six to 12 months that really help people tell a richer story in their profiles,” Hinge CEO Justin McLeod told <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/27/hinge-adds-audio-recording-features-to-its-app.html"><em><ins>CNBC</ins></em></a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e710cd50-3742-11ec-8ffe-b64f737ab17c" style="height:416;width:740;" alt="Screenshots showing the voice messaging feature in the dating app Hinge." data-uuid="49bc78e8-8189-334d-a893-4edacdd5ae94"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Hinge</div></figure><p>Some users might find it easier to get to know matches through voice messages rather than text. Many dating apps have added <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tinders-face-to-face-video-chat-is-now-available-globally-090000141.html"><ins>video</ins></a> and audio features, particularly after the onset of COVID-19 made in-person dating more difficult.&nbsp;</p><p>Rival dating app Bumble has allowed would-be lovebirds to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bumble-virtual-dating-coronavirus-165215408.html"><ins>send audio messages</ins></a> to each other since April 2020, while Tinder started allowing users to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tinder-video-profile-update-130041493.html"><ins>add videos</ins></a> to their profiles this summer. Hinge, however, has had the latter feature <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-06-27-hinge-video-seduce-dating-app.html"><ins>since 2017</ins></a>.</p><p>Hinge is introducing more features for LGBTQ+ users too. As of Thursday, the app will introduce a non-binary gender category to its algorithm. McLeod noted that although other apps let users identify as non-binary, they typically require those users to say whether they want their profile to be seen by people looking for men or women. Prompts designed for LGBTQ+ users will also be added in November.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hinge-dating-app-voice-messages-audio-notes-profiles-lgbtq-non-binary-164728473.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">63a02cb9-de27-4d23-bfd3-138ad9b08a3a</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:47:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635353250</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T16:47:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category><category><![CDATA[Family & Relationships]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f6019c80-3743-11ec-b3f6-4465e07f5263" width="740" height="416" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f6019c80-3743-11ec-b3f6-4465e07f5263" width="740" height="416" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Hinge]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A screenshot of the dating app Hinge, showing a feature that allows users to record voice clips and add them to profiles to show off their personality.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Voice Prompts in Hinge]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The all-electric i4 is a no-compromise BMW that happens to be an EV]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="01400d4d3c754cb0a0eade2fbf8dc0a0"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xz7HI8GY17Q?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Electrified versions of vehicles typically end up trading eco-friendly driving for the handling of a gas-powered counterpart. Batteries are heavy and while they lower the center of gravity, the extra weight does make itself known. Enter the 2022 BMW i4 M50, the first M-powered electric BMW that makes you forget about the 4-Series with all its petrol power.</p><p>Starting at $65,900, the i4 M50 is an all-wheel-drive delight behind the wheel that surprised us with its impressive handling and interior that’s actually more like a traditional BMW but with the latest version of the automaker’s infotainment system. We had a chance to drive it in the mountains and on the autobahn in Germany and, if you’ve been waiting for an electric BMW sedan that delivers that ultimate driving machine feeling, look no further. For the full story, check out the video above.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bmw-i4-m50-first-drive-video-163055887.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c592dc2e-b36e-4aa0-bf28-2e1cec13f56d</guid><dc:creator>Roberto Baldwin</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:30:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635373470</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T22:24:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Roberto Baldwin]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/70022570-3746-11ec-9dbf-4bbabffc42ca" width="1721" height="890" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/70022570-3746-11ec-9dbf-4bbabffc42ca" width="1721" height="890" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A blue BMW i4 M parked on a bucolic roadside near a lake.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW i4 M]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alienware's redesigned Aurora gaming desktop is now available]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alienware didn&#39;t wait long to release its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alienware-aurora-redesign-airflow-noise-performance-040051724.html">redesigned Aurora gaming desktop</a>. The Dell brand has <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:released" href="https://bit.ly/3ElGu8S">released</a> both the Intel-powered Aurora R13 (above) and AMD-based Aurora Ryzen Edition R14 with their expected chassis redesign and, for the R13, a processor upgrade. The Intel machine now uses 12th-generation Core (aka Alder Lake) processors ranging from a 10-core 3.7GHz Core i5 through to the unlocked 16-core, 3.2GHz Core i9K and i9KF. The AMD models continue to use Ryzen 5000-series chips up to and including the 16-core 5950X.</p><p>The highlight, as you might expect, remains that distinct Legend 2.0 chassis. You can expect 50 percent more internal volume, tool-free entry, more customizable lighting and a more widely available clear side panel. That and an overall cleaner layout should help the Aurora run cooler and quieter than its predecessor while still allowing for easier upgrades. It probably won&#39;t sway you if you&#39;re determined to build your own rig, but it could make life easier if you&#39;re content to buy a pre-built system.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The R13 and Ryzen R14 models are available today starting at $1,250 for the AMD machine and $1,480 for its Intel-equipped counterpart. Upgrade options will remain familiar and include up to 128GB of RAM, GeForce RTX 3090 or RX 6900 XT graphics and 4TB of total storage (2TB SSD and 2TB spinning disk).</p><p>And don&#39;t worry if you&#39;re a creator who&#39;d prefer a more sedate case — Dell has you covered as well. The company has <a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/scc/sr/desktops/xps-desktops">teased</a> a new XPS Desktop (below) that maintains the &#39;safe&#39; design of before, but in a much larger (27L versus 19L) form that improves airflow and customization in the toolless chassis. You&#39;ll have to be content with &#39;just&#39; 12th-gen Intel Core i5, i7 and i9 processors, but you&#39;ll have the same memory, graphics and storage choices. You can use liquid cooling, too, if fan noise or throttling are issues.</p><p>The new XPS tower arrives later in the fall starting at $919. As such, it might be the better buy if you&#39;re more interested in raw power than an attention-grabbing enclosure.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a7140900-36a3-11ec-bfb7-f0c6f39b0c8c" alt="Dell XPS Desktop (2021)" data-uuid="ae2f4c6e-39cd-3de6-83c4-01fe34512537"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dell</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/alienware-dell-12th-gen-intel-core-160047036.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3325f503-d70d-47ff-8151-eceac8877386</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635351405</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T16:16:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6a956b80-369f-11ec-bfff-d64308d7454f" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6a956b80-369f-11ec-bfff-d64308d7454f" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dell]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Alienware Aurora R13 gaming desktop]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Alienware Aurora R13 gaming desktop]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel's hybrid 12th-gen chips are a major strike against AMD]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ve been hearing about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/intel-tiger-lake-superfin-xe-graphics-130023003.html">Intel&#39;s powerful hybrid chips</a> for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/intel-chip-roadmap-7nm-20a-210033768.html">so long</a>, they&#39;ve achieved almost mythical status. The idea behind them is intriguing: they feature both performance-cores (P-cores) and efficient-cores (E-cores) on a single die, giving you chips that can be beefy and a bit more power-conscious, depending on the task. Previously, all of Intel&#39;s CPU cores were pretty much the same, which led to the energy-hungry designs we&#39;ve seen over the last few years.&nbsp;</p><p>Now the company is ready to launch those chips, previously codenamed &quot;Alder Lake,&quot; as its 12th-gen desktop processors. And maybe, just maybe, it&#39;ll be able to steal the spotlight <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-zen-3-ryzen-5000-cpu-162431364.html">back from AMD</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-m1-pro-m1-max-chips-macbook-pro-172415918.html">Apple</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition to their hybrid configuration, these 12th-gen chips are also the first under the &quot;Intel 7&quot; process technology, which was previously seen as a refined 10nm design. When Intel <a href="https://www.engadget.com/intel-chip-roadmap-7nm-20a-210033768.html">revised its product roadmap in July with new names</a>, it seemed to just be steering us away from its 7nm delays. But the performance of these 12th-gen chips may be enough to justify the new branding.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b34acd90-372e-11ec-87ff-d055a4a78504" alt="Intel 12th-gen CPU die from the bottom" data-uuid="7b3d587d-c12a-37da-91f4-9df855a7fa46"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Intel</div></figure><p>Intel is throwing some major numbers around: it says 12th-gen chips are up to 19 percent faster than 11th-gen CPUs overall, and they&#39;re twice as fast in the Adobe After Effects Pulse benchmark. When it comes to multithreaded performance (tasks built specifically for more than one core, like video and 3D rendering), the company claims the top-end i9-12900K is 50 percent faster than last year&#39;s 11900K while using less power. And even better, it can achieve performance parity while using only around a quarter of the power. Basically, everyone who held off on upgrading over the last few years is in for a treat, as these chips promise to be a big leap forward.</p><p>Intel&#39;s 12th-gen Core chips can fit in up to 16 cores on the i9-12900K. That&#39;s a combination of 8 P-cores and 8 E-cores, with a total of 24 process threads (every P-core counts double, since they support hyper-threading, but the E-cores don&#39;t). Given that this is an entirely new way of designing its chips, the company also worked together to develop a new Thread Director with Microsoft, which intelligently assigns tasks to the appropriate core. That way you don&#39;t have to manually assign a background thread to an E-core, or start mucking about your settings once you start working on concurrent tasks. (If the hybrid core design seems familiar, it&#39;s because ARM has been pushing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2011-10-20-arm-unveils-cortex-a7-processor-big-little-computing.html">something similar for the past decade</a> with its big.LITTLE technology on mobile CPUs.)</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/711eb070-372f-11ec-9fff-558e2a400f99" alt="Intel 12th-gen CPU charts" data-uuid="c7ce7f97-77be-30e6-a8b5-d815d383c930"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Intel</div></figure><p>Intel claims P-cores can perform up to 28 percent faster than its 10th-gen Comet Lake S chips in single-threaded performance. The E-cores, meanwhile, are just as fast as the 10th-gen hardware on their own. As you&#39;d expect, these chips shine best when you&#39;re throwing serious workloads at them. Intel says the i9-12900K can get around up to 84 percent higher framerates while playing <em>Mount and Blade II</em> and streaming over OBS, compared to the previous generation chip. Similarly, it&#39;s 47 percent faster while multi-tasking with Adobe Lightroom Classic and Premiere Pro.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/711e6250-372f-11ec-afff-eca5e1ce9e18" alt="Intel 12th-gen CPU charts" data-uuid="844d2340-0d62-35ef-836a-6feeb98cbb52"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Intel</div></figure><p>Intel&#39;s figures sound impressive when compared to its own hardware, but the company also noted that its Ryzen benchmarks were run before <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-microsoft-ryzen-processor-windows-11-bug-fixes-190439836.html">AMD and Microsoft deployed Windows 11 updates</a> to fix some performance bugs. At the time of its testing, the i9-12900K appeared to have a commanding lead over the Ryzen 5950X in many games, like <em>Troy: A Total War Saga </em>and <em>Grid 2019</em>. But it&#39;ll be interested to see what those numbers look like now. And of course, AMD could easily come back with speedier hardware of its own early next year.</p><section data-eng-breakout="23217911933441c886aac3adc2f24e02" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/711e3b40-372f-11ec-bdfb-d6f6fb882503" alt="Intel 12th-gen CPU charts"></section><p>The new 12th-gen chips are also looking towards the future, with support for up to 16 lanes of PCIe 5.0 and DDR5-4800 RAM. Intel&#39;s new 600-series chipset will feature PCIe 4.0 support, integrated WiFi 6E, and an updated Direct Media Interface (DMI) that&#39;ll offer &quot;double and faster bandwidth between the chipset and the processor.&quot; There&#39;s also support for up to 4 USB 3.2 Gen 2x2 ports, as well as far more USB 3.2 Gen 2 connections in general.</p><div id="e1df6fa89ad4463f84514b29648f7ade"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FOFXO9HRZG4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>As you&#39;d expect, it&#39;ll cost a bit more to jump into Intel&#39;s 12th-gen chips. The Core i9-12900K will go for $589, compared to the 11900K&#39;s $539 to $549 price range. You could always save $20 or so by getting the &quot;KF&quot; chip without onboard graphics, but in general I&#39;d recommend keeping graphics in case your GPU gets fried. The more approachable Core i7-12700K, thankfully, hasn&#39;t budged from its predecessor&#39;s $409 price, while the Core i5-12600K is around $20 more than before if you want onboard graphics.</p><p>The real question for Intel is how this new hardware stacks up against what AMD and Apple have coming. <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/intel-core-i9-12900hk-benchmarks-leaked-geekbench-scores-wild">Benchmark leaks suggest</a> that the i9-12900K is faster than Apple&#39;s M1 Max chip, but that&#39;s also a power-sipping laptop part. A faster, desktop-focused chip from Apple would likely leave Intel lagging behind again. Still, this uncertainty is a good thing for the PC industry as a whole. Now we&#39;ve got several companies producing powerful processors. Their attempts to one-up should ultimately be a very good thing for consumers.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/intel-12th-gen-core-cpu-hybrid-alder-lake-160014440.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">55637a1c-d0dd-45b7-a9ed-a18a8c5a5c33</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635397491</ingested><modified>2021-10-28T05:05:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b34aa680-372e-11ec-bddd-727031a83618" width="1925" height="1284" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b34aa680-372e-11ec-bddd-727031a83618" width="1925" height="1284" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Intel]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Intel 12th-gen CPU box]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Intel 12th-gen CPUs]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung is building a cloud gaming platform for its TVs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung doesn&#39;t want to cede the game streaming space to the likes of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-173003693.html">Google</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-xbox-console-cloud-gaming-test-insiders-190628810.html">Microsoft</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-now-introduces-an-rtx-3080-tier-for-up-to-1440-p-120-fps-gaming-130011568.html">NVIDIA</a>. <em>IGN</em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/samsung-cloud-game-platform">reports</a> Samsung has <a href="https://youtu.be/ElMqHkG26sM?t=1520">teased</a> plans for a TV-based &quot;Cloud Game Platform&quot; during its developer conference presentation. Details were scarce, but this would let <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-neo-qled-4k-8k-tvs-release-date-pricing-170114864.html">Samsung TV</a> owners play games without &quot;high-end hardware.&quot; This would be more likely used to play console- or PC-quality titles, then, rather than mobile games.</p><p>The tech firm tried cloud gaming through a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-06-05-gaikai-powered-cloud-gaming-coming-to-samsung-smart-tvs.html">team-up with Gaikai</a> in 2012, although that clearly didn&#39;t go far when <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-07-02-sony-buys-streaming-game-service-gaikai-for-380-million-to-est.html">Gaikai sold to Sony</a> and transitioned to working on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-09-21-david-perty-talks-playstation-now.html">PlayStation Now</a>. However, circumstances were also different then — internet connections are much faster, and many more people are familiar with the concept of game streaming. Samsung&#39;s potential audience is considerably wider, even if it&#39;s focused primarily on TVs.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Whether or not Samsung grabs that audience is another matter. The cloud gaming market already has a few heavyweights, and even those are facing challenges. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-game-studios-shut-down-montreal-los-angeles-201811811.html">closed Stadia&#39;s internal game studios</a> in February, and this month started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-tech-licensing-att-batman-arkham-knight-160913912.html">licensing Stadia tech</a> to companies like AT&amp;T. Samsung hasn&#39;t yet shown how it might stand out from that pack.</p><div id="b82574808ce34f6cba6599a172d58cdf"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ElMqHkG26sM?start=1520" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-cloud-gaming-platform-smart-tv-155226529.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">66bbb33a-738d-42d9-945e-5b00ee233715</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 15:52:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635349951</ingested><modified>2021-10-27T15:52:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4eac33c0-3737-11ec-bf7e-0f7d074fb860" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4eac33c0-3737-11ec-bf7e-0f7d074fb860" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung announces cloud game platform for TV]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung announces cloud game platform for TV]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>