<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 18:30:43 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[First look: Cadillac’s luxury EV debut seems like a winner]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="1515e0a843fa4f5dae26b1850fc89944"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l3utXrXvmFE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>As parent company GM begins its rollout of EV’s based on the Ultium battery platform, automaker Cadillac is readying its very first electric Caddy, the Lyriq, for production. With a range of over 300 miles, a starting price of $60,000 and all the bells and whistles expected from the brand, the Lyriq could be a surprise hit when it starts landing in dealerships in the first half of 2022.</p><p>Cadillac gave us an opportunity to check out the vehicle at a studio in Los Angeles and while we can’t comment on how well it drives, it does look the part. It&#39;s a Caddy with some extra bits of flair afforded to an EV including vertical headlights and taillights that are an homage to the automaker’s classic fin era. Reservations for the 2023 Lyriq will open in September. Check the video above for the full story.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/cadillac-lyriq-luxury-ev-first-look-video-171543752.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a7825d2e-7cdd-43d0-ad2a-a4a684d9b3c3</guid><dc:creator>Roberto Baldwin</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 18:30:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629558825</ingested><modified>2021-08-21T15:13:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Roberto Baldwin]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b0e8c210-01c2-11ec-bff3-33aaf03ec63c" width="2560" height="1517" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b0e8c210-01c2-11ec-bff3-33aaf03ec63c" width="2560" height="1517" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cadillac]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Cadillac Lyriq]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Cadillac Lyriq]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[ICYMI: We open (and close) the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 3]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was all about smartphones at Engadget. Cherlynn Low spent some time with the Galaxy Z Flip 3 to determine who it’s really for. Terrence O’Brien compared and contrasted the Pixel 5a against previous versions to find out where the value lies in the upgraded model. Cherlynn also put the ASUS-Qualcomm Snapdragon smartphone through its paces to see how it stacks up against mainstream devices.</p><h2>The Galaxy Z Flip 3 is now <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">in the same price range as regular flagships</a></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/a255b890-01e8-11ec-98dd-64816f12051f" alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 3" data-uuid="243f6279-f8a0-3b72-8ff4-741a60b4ca45"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Cherlynn Low was upfront about the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy Z Flip 3" href="https://fave.co/3gch6c6">Galaxy Z Flip 3</a> in her review. Not only is it the best foldable phone yet with a fast, large screen, neat software tricks and water resistance, but it’s also now available at a (relatively) reasonable $1,000. She says it’s basically a regular smartphone that folds in half with a satisfying snap. The stronger aluminum, refined hinge and tough screen made it the first foldable she was willing to throw into a purse without worrying about scratching. She liked the widgets available for the Cover Display window, the new color options and the Flex mode, which assisted with one-handed use.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Despite that, she still feels the Z Flip 3 is a hard sell. The battery life was woefully short and rarely lasted an entire day, and the software was a bit buggy. While most apps fit nicely on the screen, there was an occasional mismatch of aspect ratios that caused difficulties. For example, the pop-up dialogs in <em>Settlers of Catan </em>disappeared into the edges of the display. Plus, it was hard to find the benefit for more mainstream audiences who could purchase an iPhone or Samsung handset for the same price. For those who are nostalgic or curious enough to buy the Z Flip 3, they ‘ll find themselves with a capable device that has the best any foldable can offer.</p><h2>Google’s Pixel 5a is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-a-review-android-midrange-5g-smartphone-160051630.html">an incremental (and somewhat boring) update</a></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f2a45860-01e8-11ec-a72a-a04ffd5920b1" alt="Google Pixel 5a" data-uuid="7d3c6a5e-ce4a-31fb-9e6a-599347857814"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Terrence O’Brien is quick to point out that the <a href="https://store.google.com/product/pixel_5a_5g?hl=en-US">$449 Pixel 5a</a> is a bit of a stop-gap: The Pixel 4a 5G was a solid offering and the Pixel 6 should be right around the corner. That being said, there’s still a few things about the 5a that make it worth considering. While the 5a keeps the same processor, RAM and camera experience as the previous version, it adds IP67 water and dust resistance and an incredible battery. Terrence said the 4,680mAh battery survived through nearly 23 hours of video play before powering down, and was still at 40 percent after 24 hours of general heavy usage.</p><p>The rest of the features on the 5a include a metal unibody with a matte texture, an upgrade to Gorilla Glass 6 and a 6.34-inch OLED panel with HDR support and 2,400 x 1,080 resolution. Terrence admits that the Snapdragon 765G processor is a bit outdated, but also says that the 5a still felt responsive and quick while reading email or playing <em>The Elder Scrolls: Blades. </em>However, it stuttered a few times while navigating YouTube and editing photos. The camera experience is also excellent, though the same as the features on the 4a 5G: an 8-megapixel front-facing camera, a 12.2-megapixel main lens and a 16-megapixel ultra-wide-angle. Overall, Terrence’s biggest objection to the 5a was that it was a bit boring in that it’s very close to a reproduction of the 4a 5G.</p><h2>The Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders <a href="https://www.engadget.com/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-for-snapdragon-insiders-review-140014488.html">truly isn’t for everyone</a></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/18b8e160-01e9-11ec-bffa-ac03ce015c64" alt="Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders" data-uuid="0137e639-e049-3625-9d3d-5eb957b784ad"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Qualcomm and ASUS teamed up to create a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:smartphone" href="https://fave.co/37XhKFP">smartphone</a> for fans of the Snapdragon chipset, but Cherlynn Low says it&#39;s a bit too niche to broadly recommend. With a 6.8-inch screen and weighing in at 210 grams, this is one of the heavier phones that she’s tested recently — and its looks differentiate it from the competition. Cherlynn says its rounded-rectangle body, matte blue finish and shiny red accents make it stand out, but she was less fond of the illuminated icon on the rear which can glow on and off.</p><p>The rest of the $1,499 device includes a 144Hz refresh rate display, comprehensive 5G support and rapid charging. The AMOLED panel runs at a resolution of 2,448 x 1,080 and delivers vibrant colors and deep blacks. However, the 20.4:9 aspect ratio cut off some content like the ends of longer messages in Telegram. The phone includes a pair of wireless Master and Dynamic earbuds to pair with Qualcomm’s High Dynamic Range Audio Record to support high-res 24-bit 96kHz audio. However, there were several features that had yet to be released, and the phone did tend to run hot. Cherlynn says unless you’re a <em>big</em> Qualcomm fan or really need the refresh rate, you’ve got better options elsewhere.</p><h2>Loupedeck Live is a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/loupedeck-live-versus-the-stream-deck-170020781.html">control surface ideal for desktop apps</a></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4411d5b0-01e9-11ec-aded-190ddf22a41a" alt="Loupedeck Live" data-uuid="d2832d11-fc0d-3802-96dc-d2f48adb4272"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>First, James Trew wants you to understand what the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Loupedeck Live" href="https://amzn.to/3y83Xqm">Loupedeck Live</a> is: a Mac or PC control surface with multiple configurable dials and buttons. He also wants you to understand what it’s best for, which is audio- or image-editing and a workflow of dynamic profiles. When using these profiles, the Loupedeck will automatically switch to the assigned buttons and rotaries you’ve selected for that program. This means the Live is adaptive and will follow you with a variety of actions and choices as you navigate.</p><p>That puts it in contrast to the competition, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Elgato Stream Deck" href="https://amzn.to/2W4LwpS">Elgato Stream Deck</a>, which works as more of a program launcher. The Loupedeck Live offers three models of control surface with each being physically distinct and intended for different uses; James says the Live version looked good on his desk. He particularly liked the mini LCD displays on the buttons, which show what each does, and the rotary dials, which he found useful for volume control or scrolling through a list. James felt the particular strength of the Loupedeck was the large amount of native-app support it offers — not only can it be helpful for streaming, but it will also lend a hand when editing or designing a logo.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/icymi-we-open-and-close-the-samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-smartphone-160006766.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">83939644-5886-41bb-ae73-733a12cc2705</guid><dc:creator>Amber Bouman</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 17:15:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629558798</ingested><modified>2021-08-21T15:13:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Amber Bouman]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bd8ba9d0-01e8-11ec-9f7e-794b7a8c5e52" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bd8ba9d0-01e8-11ec-9f7e-794b7a8c5e52" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[ICYMI: We open (and close) the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google has already discontinued the Pixel 5 and Pixel 4a with 5G]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google just released the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-a-review-android-midrange-5g-smartphone-160051630.html">excellent and relatively inexpensive Pixel 5a</a>, and the company has also already given us a look at the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-first-look-tensor-processor-better-cameras-160005582.html">upcoming Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro</a>. So you could easily guess that the Pixel 5 is not long for this world, and you&#39;d be right. According to a statement <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/pixel-5-4a-5g-discontinued-after-5a-launch/">received by <em>DigitalTrends</em></a><em>, </em>Google is done selling the Pixel 5 as well as the Pixel 4a 5G.&nbsp;</p><p>“With our current forecasts, we expect Google Store in the U.S. to sell out of Pixel 4a (5G) and Pixel 5 in the coming weeks following the launch of Pixel 5a (5G). The Pixel 5a (5G) is a great option for customers and delivers valuable hardware upgrades compared to the Pixel 4a (5G), all at a lower price point,” Google said to <em>DigitalTrends</em>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On Google&#39;s store in the US, both phones are showing as out of stock currently, which means the only Pixel phones currently available are the Pixel 5a (which doesn&#39;t arrive until August 26th) and the Pixel 4a, which doesn&#39;t have 5G. And since the Pixel 5a is only being sold in the US and Japan, at least for starters, Google will be going without a 5G-capable phone in other markets until the Pixel 6 arrives.&nbsp;</p><p>That situation will likely be remedied soon — Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-5g-182238671.html">announced the Pixel 5</a> on September 30th last year, so it seems likely that we&#39;ll get an official reveal of the Pixel 6 sometime in the next month, as well. Google&#39;s Pixel phones have never exactly sold like gangbusters, but it&#39;s still somewhat surprising to see them pull the Pixel 5 so quickly in areas where they aren&#39;t seeing the 5a. But given that Google is already showing off the Pixel 5&#39;s successor, chances are good most people would wait that extra month to get the the company&#39;s next flagship. As the first phone with Google&#39;s own custom silicon, it&#39;s definitely a lot more intriguing than the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-review-camera-performance-battery-price-150051832.html">somewhat stale Pixel 5</a>, anyway.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-discontinued-161225173.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">56c464d1-b599-4976-b882-ad1cd7529475</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 16:12:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629558757</ingested><modified>2021-08-21T15:12:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4d8a5e70-0291-11ec-ad5f-e93424dc3ff6" width="3000" height="1622" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4d8a5e70-0291-11ec-ad5f-e93424dc3ff6" width="3000" height="1622" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixel 5]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 5]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hitting the Books: How Tesla engineers solved the problem of exploding EV batteries]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Between CEO Elon Musk&#39;s often erratic antics, strident competition from existing industry titans, and a public that is still not fully sold on the idea of traveling via electrical charge, Tesla&#39;s road to prominence has not been a smooth one. But facing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-autopilot-investigation-nhtsa-141310451.html">a federal investigation into its driver assist systems</a>, is far from the biggest roadblock the company has navigated. As journalist Tim Higgins explains in his new book, <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/611077/power-play-by-tim-higgins/"><em>Power Play</em></a>, back in the early aughts, Tesla&#39;s engineering team had to overcome an even tougher challenge: keeping the first iterations of its EVs from randomly exploding.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/cd6ea130-ff78-11eb-b6fd-124c5ed6f3d7" alt="Power Play cover" data-uuid="00cf36c0-73c2-3e55-991c-82cf5ea3eba1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Knopf Doubleday - Penguin Randomhouse</div></figure><p><em>From the book </em><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/611077/power-play-by-tim-higgins/"><em>POWER PLAY: Tesla, Elon Musk, and the Bet of the Century</em></a><em> by Tim Higgins, published in the US on August 3, 2021 by Doubleday, an imprint of The Knopf Doubleday Publishing Group, a division of Penguin Random House LLC, and in the UK on August 5, 2021 by WH Allen. Copyright © 2021 by Tim Higgins.</em></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><hr><p>A panicked letter from LG Chem arrived at Tesla with a dire demand: Return its batteries.</p><p>Just as Tesla was proving it could craft a lithium-ion battery pack on its own, the battery industry was grappling with the danger that cells posed when they were handled incorrectly. AC Propulsion had learned this the hard way months earlier, in one of an increasing number of incidents that sent shudders through the battery industry. En route from Los Angeles to Paris, a shipment of AC Propulsion’s batteries caught fire as it was being loaded onto a FedEx airplane while it refueled in Memphis, triggering an investigation by the National Transportation Safety Board and prompting concerns about how to transport batteries in the future. Personal electronics companies, such as Apple Inc., were recalling devices with lithium-ion batteries out of concern they could overheat and catch fire. In 2004 and 2005, Apple recalled more than 150,000 laptops — with batteries made by LG Chem.</p><p>When LG Chem realized it had sold a large number of its batteries to a Silicon Valley startup that planned to use all of them for a single device — a car, as it happened — its legal department sent a letter demanding the cells be returned. The battery maker didn’t want to be associated with a potentially fiery experiment.</p><p>[Tesla&#39;s first CEO, Martin] Eberhard ignored the request. He had little choice. His bet that Tesla would be able to find a ready battery supplier was proving harder to cover than expected. Without these batteries, there might not be a second chance to get more.</p><p>Amid all of the attention on lithium-ion batteries, [Tesla Co-Founder/CTO, JB] Straubel thought back to his former house in LA, where he and [Tesla employee number 7, Gene] Berdichevsky celebrated the idea of an electric car by setting cells afire. If struck with a hammer, they put on quite a show. Cars were always in danger of that kind of impact, but there was also a more insidious threat. He began to wonder what might happen if one of the cells in the tightly packed cluster that would form a car’s battery pack got too warm.</p><p>One day in the summer of 2005, he and Berdichevsky decided to find out. With the office cleared out for the day, they went to the parking lot with a brick of cells — a cluster of batteries glued together. They wrapped one of the cells with a wire that would allow them to heat it remotely. Then, from a safe distance, they flicked the heater on. The individual cell quickly rose to more than 266 degrees Fahrenheit (130 degrees Celsius), causing the battery to flash into a blinding flame as the temperature spiked to 1,472 degrees, then explode altogether, sending the remaining skin of the battery into the sky like a rocket. Then another cell in the pack caught fire, launching into the air. Soon all of the cells were on fire. <em>Bang. Bang. Bang.</em></p><p>Straubel recognized the implications of his amateur pyrotechnics. If an incident like the one he cooked up were to happen in the wild, it could spell the end for Tesla. The next day, after they disclosed their experiment to Eberhard, they showed him the scorched pavement, pitted with holes from the night before. Eberhard urged them to be more careful, but he couldn’t deny that more testing was needed. He gathered the team at his rural house on the hills above Silicon Valley for more experiments. This time, they dug a pit and put a brick of cells in it, then covered it with plexiglass. They heated one of the cells and again the batteries ignited, causing a chain of explosions. Straubel had been right: this wasn’t good. They needed outside help to understand exactly what they were dealing with — the team needed battery experts.</p><p>Days later, a small group of battery consultants were gathered with what at first seemed like a manageable message: Yes, even the best battery manufacturers produced a random cell that would have a defect, causing it to short and catch fire. But the odds were remote. “It happens really, really infrequently,” one of the consultants said. “I mean like between one in a million and one in ten million cells.”</p><p>But Tesla planned to put about 7,000 cells in a single car. Sitting near Straubel, Berdichevsky pulled out his calculator and computed the likelihood that a cell in one of their cars might catch fire by chance. “Guys, that’s like between one in 150 and one in 1,500 cars,” he said.</p><p>And not only would they be churning out cars with defective batteries that, if ignited, could set off a chain reaction, but their cars could be detonating in the garages of the richest of the rich—burning down mansions and lighting up local TV news. The mood in the room shifted. The questions became more urgent: Was there anything that could be done to avoid defective cells?</p><p>Nope. Random cells were always going to get too hot and spark thermal runaway — basically an explosion sparked by overheating.</p><p>Straubel and the team returned to their work deflated. The stakes couldn’t have been higher for Tesla. This wasn’t just about solving a hard problem, one that threatened to drain limited resources and derail development of the Roadster. If they forged a solution that seemed to work, only to see Tesla vehicles catch fire in years to come, the company would be doomed. And it would be a failure not just for Tesla; their dreams of the electric car could be set back a generation. They could not only cause injury or death, they might kill the electric car in the process.</p><p>If they wanted to truly become an automaker, they had to face the challenge that GM, Ford, and others had been dealing with for a hundred years: They had to ensure they were putting safe cars on the roadway. A solution to thermal runaway could amount to a true breakthrough, one that would set Tesla apart from the auto industry for years to come. Using lithium-ion batteries had seemed like a smart idea, one that a number of thinkers had alighted on. But figuring out how to use them without turning the car into a ticking time bomb could be their greatest innovation.</p><p>They stopped work on all aspects of the Roadster project and formed a special committee to find a solution. The team set up whiteboards, listing what they knew and what they needed to learn. They began running daily tests. They’d configure a battery pack with the cells spaced differently, to see if there was an ideal distance for containing chain reactions. They tried different methods of keeping the batteries cool, such as having air flow over them or tubes of liquid brush past them. They’d take the packs to a pad used by local firefighters for training and ignite one of the cells to better understand what was taking place.</p><p>The danger of the situation was driven home while en route to one of those tests. Lyons, their recruit from IDEO, began to smell smoke coming from the back of his Audi A4, where he had loaded a pack of test batteries. It was a sign that a cell was heating up and approaching thermal runaway. He immediately stopped and yanked the batteries out of the car and threw them to the ground before his car could catch fire — a close call.</p><p>Eventually, Straubel began to narrow in on a solution. If they couldn’t keep a cell from warming, maybe they could keep it from reaching the point where it set off a chain reaction. Through trial and error, the team realized that if they had each cell lined up a few millimeters from its neighbor, snaked a tube of liquid between them, and dumped a brownie-batter-like mixture of minerals into the resulting battery pack, they could create a system that contained overheating. If a defective cell within began to overheat, its energy would dissipate to its neighboring cells, with no individual cell ever reaching combustibility.</p><p>Where just months earlier they had been struggling to set up a workshop, now they were on to something utterly new. Straubel was thrilled. Now he just needed to figure out how to convince the battery suppliers to trust them. Straubel was hearing from Eberhard that the established manufacturers weren’t interested in their business. As one executive at a supplier told Eberhard: You guys are a shallow pocket. We’re a deep pocket. If your car blows up, we’ll probably get sued.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hitting-the-books-power-play-tim-higgins-penguin-randomhouse-153052075.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">84c69033-b971-4706-921c-92be29eb8177</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629501957</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T23:26:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/327de810-ff79-11eb-bd9d-5ab9fdc4c80d" width="4000" height="3000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/327de810-ff79-11eb-bd9d-5ab9fdc4c80d" width="4000" height="3000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Thomas Koehler via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BERSTELAND, GERMANY - MARCH 02: A Tesla Model 3 plugged in and charging at a Supercharger rapid battery charging station for electric vehicles in Bersteland, Germany, on March 02, 2021. (Photo by Thomas Koehler/Photothek via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tesal Supercharger]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Recommended Reading: Apple's inside man with the leakers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3aqyz8/apples-double-agent">Apple’s double agent</a></h2><p><strong>Lorenzo Franceschi-Bicchierai, </strong><strong><em>Motherboard</em></strong></p><p>Andrey Shumeyko, known as YRH04E and JVHResearch in online circles, spent years trading secrets in the leak and jailbreak community. He was also sharing what he found with Apple. As <em>Motherboard </em>explains<em>, </em>Shumeyko was collecting <em>&quot;</em>personal information of people who sold stolen iPhone prototypes from China, Apple employees who leaked information online, journalists who had relationships with leakers and sellers and anything that he thought the company would find interesting and worth investigating.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/8/19/22629431/sony-playstation-vr-studio-csar-combat-search-rescue-canceled">Sony spent five years building a new PlayStation VR studio, then abruptly shut it down</a></h2><p><strong>Jack Yarwood, </strong><strong><em>Polygon</em></strong></p><p>Sony&#39;s Manchester studio opened in 2015, and when it was shuttered in 2020, it had yet to release what <em>Polygon </em>describes as &quot;a throwback to old-school action games like Genesis shooter <em>Desert Strike</em> — albeit in 3D and utilizing modern technology on PlayStation 4.&quot; While the studio had &quot;AAA aspirations,&quot; it never had a staff of more than 30 people.&nbsp;</p><h2><a href="https://www.polygon.com/22633591/madden-nfl-22-review-franchise-mode-changes-upgrades-ps5-xbox-series-x">Madden NFL 22’s Franchise is a slow — and overdue — burn</a></h2><p><strong>Owen S. Good, </strong><strong><em>Polygon</em></strong></p><p>EA finally reworked Madden NFL&#39;s Franchise mode for this year&#39;s release. While the updates might not be apparent at first, give it some time. A feature like Gameday Momentum, <em>Polygon </em>explains, &quot;doesn’t seem like much, until it seems like a lot.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/recommended-reading-apples-inside-man-with-the-leakers-140018827.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">341a7f60-9881-4b54-8bbe-1f597082f9bd</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629501926</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T23:25:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/4f438b80-c7ca-11eb-9bfd-d90b9c3cd30c" width="5000" height="3335" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/4f438b80-c7ca-11eb-9bfd-d90b9c3cd30c" width="5000" height="3335" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[TOKYO, JAPAN - 2021/06/06: In this photo illustration, Apples iPhone 12 seen placed on a MacBook Pro. (Photo Illustration by Stanislav Kogiku/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, Apples iPhone 12 seen placed...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM expands fire risk recall to cover all Chevy Bolts sold worldwide]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in November 2020, GM <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-recalls-chevy-bolt-over-battery-fire-reports-230044311.html">recalled</a> over 68,000 Chevrolet Bolt EVs after five of the vehicles caught fire between 2017 and 2019. Now, the automaker has <a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-joe-biden-business-health-environment-and-nature-bbe51b0c8e644c4448d634fc3c0f3461">expanded</a> the recall to cover all Bolt EVs and Bolt EUVs sold worldwide, starting from the first model up until the latest ones. This recall covers 73,000 additional vehicles, 60,000 of which are in the US, on top of the first batch of recalled Bolts.&nbsp;</p><p>Upon investigating the initial incidents, GM found a manufacturing defect in the Bolt&#39;s batteries manufactured at an LG Chemical Solution plant in South Korea. That became the basis for the models the automaker included in the first recall. AP reports that GM started investigating the newer Bolts after a 2019 model that wasn&#39;t included in the recall last year caught fire in Chandler, Arizona a few weeks ago, bringing the total number of battery-related fire incidents to 10. The company found that batteries made in LG&#39;s other sites could also suffer from defects, hence the recall expansion.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>GM will <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-replace-chevy-bolt-battery-modules-fire-risk-100027066.html">replace</a> all five battery modules for models 2017 to 2019, while only defective modules will be replaced in newer vehicles. All fresh modules installed will come with a new eight year, 100,000 mile warranty. Until owners can get their cars in for module replacement, GM is advising them to limit charging to 90 percent of the battery capacity and to park outdoors. (The company previously determined that the vehicles that went up in flames were almost fully charged.) An email sent to owners contained a link to <a href="https://my.chevrolet.com/how-to-support/safety/boltevrecall">instructions</a> on how to do just that by using the Target Charge Level mode. The automaker is also advising owners to charge their vehicle more frequently to avoid depleting their battery until there&#39;s less than 70 miles of remaining range.</p><p>This second batch of recalls will cost the company $1 billion in addition to the $800 million it&#39;s had to spend for the first one. Further, it remains to be seen how it would affect GM&#39;s EV push. In June, the automaker <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-self-driving-ev-investment-35-billion-035316455.html">increased</a> its combined EV and self-driving investment from 2020 through 2025 to $35 billion, in hopes that it can have 30 electric vehicles on the market by the end of 2025 and that it can exclusively sell EVs by 2035. For now, the company said it will stop producing and selling Bolts until it determines that there are no longer problems with LG&#39;s batteries.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gm-expands-fire-risk-recall-all-chevy-bolt-115934063.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">af905ee3-fcd7-463c-871d-1858a10b962d</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 11:59:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629547180</ingested><modified>2021-08-21T11:59:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/151533b0-026b-11ec-9f5d-06b039cc0b7d" width="1600" height="1008" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/151533b0-026b-11ec-9f5d-06b039cc0b7d" width="1600" height="1008" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chevrolet]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[2022 Chevrolet Bolt EV]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Chevrolet]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[California judge finds Prop 22 gig worker measure unconstitutional]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A California judge has ruled that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-voters-reaffirm-that-uber-drivers-are-indeed-employees-091216147.html">Proposition 22</a>, the measure that allows companies like Uber and Lyft to keep classifying app-based drivers in the state as independent contractors, is unenforceable and unconstitutional. According to the <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/tech/article/Prop-22-the-gig-worker-exemption-for-Uber-and-16401915.php"><em>San Francisco Chronicle</em></a>, Alameda County Superior Court judge Frank Roesch found that Prop 22 illegally &quot;limits the power of a future legislature to define app-based drivers as workers subject to workers&#39; compensation law.&quot;</p><p>Proposition 22 passed by a wide margin in the state when most people voted in favor of it in last year&#39;s November elections. Companies were legally obligated to classify gig workers as full-time employees under Assembly Bill 5 A (AB5), which was passed in 2019, but some (like the aforementioned ride-sharing firms) continued to treat them as contractors. Uber, Lyft, Instacart and DoorDash poured over $220 million into <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-drivers-sue-prop-22-popups-194405188.html">campaigning</a> for Prop 22 in order to overturn AB5, and the move clearly worked.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The measure requires gig companies to provide their contractors with healthcare subsidies and a wage floor, but it also exempts them from having to classify their workers as employees with appropriate benefits and protections. While those in favor of the proposition argue that it would allow workers to keep their independence while enjoying benefits they didn&#39;t have before, not everyone&#39;s happy with the development. A group that includes the Service Employees International Union and the SEIU California State Council <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rideshare-drivers-challenge-prop-22-california-223019411.html">sued California</a> earlier this year to overturn the proposition.&nbsp;</p><p>In his ruling, Roesch specifically singled out Section 7451 of the measure, which states that any future law related to collective bargaining for app drivers must comply with the rest of the proposition. &quot;It appears only to protect the economic interest of the network companies in having a divided, ununionized workforce, which is not a stated goal of the legislation,&quot; he wrote in his decision. He also found it unconstitutional that any amendment to the measure requires a seven-eighths vote of approval to pass in the state Legislature.</p><p>If the ruling stands, gig companies like Uber and Lyft may have to spend hundreds of millions paying for healthcare and other additional benefits for their drivers. At the moment, though, Prop 22 is still in effect, and gig companies are already planning to appeal. An Uber spokesperson told <em>The Chronicle</em>:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;This ruling ignores the will of the overwhelming majority of California voters and defies both logic and the law. We will appeal and we expect to win. Meanwhile, Prop. 22 remains in effect, including all of the protections and benefits it provides independent workers across the state.&quot;</p></blockquote>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/california-judge-finds-prop-22-unconstitutional-043822868.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">35c3dc55-1131-4252-b96a-30f0fddb63bf</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 04:38:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629520706</ingested><modified>2021-08-21T04:38:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Referenda]]></category><category><![CDATA[Local Elections]]></category><category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-11/2aa89790-0c8f-11ea-bf93-5fc6d8839547" width="4379" height="2921" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-11/2aa89790-0c8f-11ea-bf93-5fc6d8839547" width="4379" height="2921" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Andrei Stanescu via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[August 21, 2019 San Francisco / CA / USA - UBER headquarters in SOMA district; Uber Technologies, Inc. is an American multinational transportation network company (TNC)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[UBER headquarters in SOMA district, San Francisco]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rhythm game 'Tetris Beat' is now available on Apple Arcade]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the nearly 40 years since Alexey Pajitnov created <em>Tetris</em>, the game has inspired many permutations. The latest example is <em>Tetris Beat</em>, an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-18-apple-arcade-review.html">Apple Arcade</a> exclusive that adds rhythm elements to the title&#39;s classic line-clearing formula. In the game’s beat mode, the more you keep to the rhythm of a song, the more points you’ll earn. However, if you want a more traditional <em>Tetris</em> experience, the included Marathon mode offers that. As with all Apple Arcade titles, <em>Tetris Beat</em> does not include any in-app ads or purchases.</p><div id="74472d51a4af4ad5951ddfd3de280b7c"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YploNGdrn80?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>With today’s launch, the game features 18 exclusive songs, with more to come every month. Some of the current contributors include well-known artists like Alison Wonderland, Hannah Diamond, and my personal favorite among the group, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uXeJeoRxXA0&amp;ab_channel=Dauwd-Topic"><ins>Dauwd</ins></a>. What’s more, if you own a pair of AirPods Pro or Max, the game supports Apple’s Spatial Audio technology, so you can look forward to a more immersive experience.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You can download <em>Tetris Beat</em> on iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple TV starting today. An Apple Arcade subscription costs<a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-spire-blast-survival-z-review-170054041.html"> $5 per month</a>. It’s also included in the company’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-one-launch-date-210455448.html"><ins>Apple One membership</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tetris-beat-available-today-apple-arcade-225345729.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b956dd82-7a11-4a2c-a0d8-3d860e7d3166</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 22:53:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629493918</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T21:12:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/173b1d30-01f8-11ec-aeee-6c44184c57c0" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/173b1d30-01f8-11ec-aeee-6c44184c57c0" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[N3twork]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tetris Beat]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tetris Beat]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Peacock's 'Frogger' looks equal parts 'Wipeout' and 'The Floor is Lava' in first trailer]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NBC has shared the first trailer for <em>Frogger</em>. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/frogger-competition-tv-show-peacock-194150547.html">As expected</a>, the show is a mix of <em>Takeshi’s Castle </em>and <em>Wipeout</em>. The clip offers a look at some of the whimsical sets contestants will need to traverse in order to claim a grand prize of $100,000.&nbsp;</p><div id="7f683e07f94a4c0a86b7733e5ce56164"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PX5g9__S0OE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>When NBC announced it was adapting Konami’s seminal 1981 video game into a Peacock series, it said the initial season would feature 13 hour long episodes and 12 different obstacle courses. One unexpected treat is that Damon Wayans Jr. of <em>Happy Endings</em> is on co-hosting duties.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Frogger will debut on September 9th, with new episodes to follow every Thursday. While we wait, you can play <em>Frogger in Toy Town</em>, the latest game in the series, on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-10-apple-arcade-exclusive-games-subscription-service-2019-frogger.html"><ins>Apple Arcade</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nbc-frogger-peacock-first-trailer-202918318.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b108a4df-112a-42b1-894c-bf5114762f8f</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 20:29:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629489571</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T19:59:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Television]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1cbb79b0-01f0-11ec-abbd-bbd2e3bb7530" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1cbb79b0-01f0-11ec-abbd-bbd2e3bb7530" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NBCUniversal ]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Peacock Frogger]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Peacock Frogger]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Duolingo is adding a family plan and five more languages]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At its annual <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/duocon"><ins>Duocon</ins></a> conference on Friday, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/duolingo"><ins>Duolingo</ins></a> announced several updates for the language-learning app. Among them is <a href="https://twitter.com/duolingo/status/1428737358061580288"><ins>a family plan</ins></a>, which gives up to six people access to Duolingo Plus with a single subscription.</p><p>The plan includes <a href="https://support.duolingo.com/hc/en-us/articles/115004068043-What-is-Duolingo-Plus-"><ins>benefits</ins></a> like unlimited hearts (so you can keep learning for longer after making mistakes) and an option to keep your lesson streak going if you happen to miss a day. Subscribers won&#39;t see any ads in the app either. New features <a href="https://twitter.com/duolingo/status/1428736727225614337">include</a> a hub where you can review all of your mistakes and a more advanced Legendary Level to put your language skills to the test.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The family plan costs around $120 per year, but there&#39;s no monthly payment option. The standard plan is $80 per year or $13/month. You can add accounts on shared devices with ease and follow your family members to see their progress.&nbsp;</p><div id="6deb17644a304c1aac8900e516ad79cf"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h4bDrMw-OyQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>In addition, Duolingo is hoping to make it easier for users to learn languages with non-Latin based alphabets, such as Japanese, Korean, Russian, Greek, Arabic and Hindi. The company says it has built new kinds of exercises to help folks get to grips with the character-based languages.</p><p>Meanwhile, five more languages are coming to the app soon: Haitian Creole, Zulu, Xhosa, Tagalog and Maori. Duolingo worked with South African organization Nal&#39;ibali on the Zulu and Xhosa courses.&nbsp;</p><p>“For years, we’ve been working to elevate the status of South African languages by creating and distributing high-quality stories for children,&quot; Nal’ibali COO Katie Huston said in a statement. &quot;Partnering with Duolingo to create these courses is another step towards elevating and protecting our local languages, and sharing them with new audiences around the world.&quot;</p><p>Duolingo is also working on an app that teaches elementary-level math. The app will harness the same tech the company uses for language learning and it should emerge next year. On top of that, Duolingo is upgrading the BirdBrain AI learning system. It says the AI will create personalized lessons at the correct difficulty level.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/duolingo-family-plan-more-languages-math-app-200429512.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ce2cf848-abe4-4a95-8431-272292af6309</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 20:04:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629488143</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T19:35:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Small Businesses]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/0792e5e0-01ec-11ec-95f7-7c116b5c1705" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/0792e5e0-01ec-11ec-95f7-7c116b5c1705" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Duolingo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Duolingo Family Plan]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Duolingo Family Plan]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Peloton's Android app hints at long-rumored rowing machine]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Conducting an APK teardown of the latest version of the Peloton Android app, <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/08/20/peloton-app-confirms-rower-prepares-scenic-waterways/"><em>9to5Google</em></a> found evidence the company is preparing the software to support a rowing machine in the near future. The outlet found various code snippets that mentioned a device codenamed &quot;Caesar&quot; and &quot;Mazu.&quot; The latter is a reference to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mazu">Chinese sea goddess</a>. Like the company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-21-living-with-peloton-bike.html">stationary bike</a>, it appears the rowing machine will include a &quot;scenic rides&quot; feature that will showcase waterways from around the globe. And if you want to just row, that will be an option too.</p><p>Another set of snippets reference the four positions of a proper rowing technique. &quot;This is the drive position of your stroke,&quot; the app explains. &quot;Sit tall on the rower with your arms straight and your back upright. Your knees should be just above the ankles.&quot; Digging deeper into the updated software, <em>9to5</em> also found code suggesting the app will track metrics like your average and max stroke rates.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A rowing machine is something Peloton has been rumored to be working for a while now, with a <a href="https://connectthewatts.com/2021/07/30/new-job-listing-confirms-peloton-rower-is-coming/">recent job listing mentioning the device</a>. We&#39;ve reached out to Pelton for confirmation, but we&#39;ll note here what we say with all APK teardowns: the fact there&#39;s code pointing to a new hardware release doesn&#39;t mean a company will follow through on that work or that a launch is imminent.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/peloton-android-app-apk-rowing-machine-193223438.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">17cfe973-a084-4aa5-bc36-0714fc3f1b58</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 19:32:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629487353</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T19:22:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-09/de2c9580-e09a-11e9-bfef-975f47bdb2e8" width="5371" height="3580" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-09/de2c9580-e09a-11e9-bfef-975f47bdb2e8" width="5371" height="3580" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Shannon Stapleton / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Peloton exercise bike is seen after the ringing of the opening bell for the company's IPO at the Nasdaq Market site in New York City, New York, U.S., September 26, 2019. REUTERS/Shannon Stapleton]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[PELOTON-IPO/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Halo Infinite' won't have campaign co-op or Forge modes at launch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/halo%20infinite"><em>Halo Infinite</em></a> is on track to hit Xbox consoles, PC and Xbox Cloud Gaming sometime this holiday season, but some key modes will be missing at the outset. In a development update, 343 Industries said campaign co-op and Forge won&#39;t be available at launch, as the studio is focusing on the single-player campaign and multiplayer modes.</p><p>&quot;Unfortunately, as we focused the team for shutdown and really focused on a quality experience for launch, we made the really tough decision to delay shipping campaign co-op for launch,&quot; Halo Infinite head of creative Joseph Staten said <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yct2QKgF5e4">in the video</a>. &quot;We also made the tough call to delay shipping Forge past launch as well.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="5179453bc46a48af907e14955284d800"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yct2QKgF5e4?rel=0&amp;start=999" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>343 Industries will roll out the modes next year as part of its seasonal roadmap. Right now, the plan is to release campaign co-op in season two (around three months after the game debuts) and Forge in season three (approximately six months after launch). Those plans may change though.</p><p>&quot;Our number one priority is making sure that whatever we ship, whenever we ship it, it meets the right quality bar across all platforms,&quot; Staten said. &quot;When we looked at these two experiences, campaign co-op and Forge, we made the determination they&#39;re just not ready.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>Campaign co-op has long been a staple of the Halo series, with up to four people being able to tackle the main campaign together. In Forge, players can create custom game modes with modified maps and unique rules.&nbsp;</p><p>The delays will likely come as a disappointment to fans, who&#39;ve already had to wait longer than expected for the next game in the flagship Xbox franchise. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-director-steps-down-183805905.html"><em>Halo Infinite</em></a> wasn&#39;t ready in time for the Xbox Series X/S launch last November. As such, Microsoft <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-delay-2021-193546027.html">delayed the game</a> until <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-update-release-date-235826926.html">a year after</a> it was initially supposed to arrive.</p><p>As for the specific <em>Halo Infinite </em>release date, Staten said 343 Industries plans to announce that soon. Along with the single-player campaign, there&#39;s a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-multiplayer-beta-110518513.html">free-to-play multiplayer mode</a>. You&#39;ll just have to remain patient a bit longer if you want to play through the campaign with your buddies.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-forge-release-date-343-industries-190153091.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef3f3cba-fe83-41e8-9ffb-02b9ab621a3d</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 19:02:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629486128</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T19:02:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/38b44370-7840-11eb-9dff-c6bc9a7d303a" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/38b44370-7840-11eb-9dff-c6bc9a7d303a" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[343 Industries/Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['Halo Infinite' screenshot of Zeta Halo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Halo Infinite' screenshot of Zeta Halo]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[China's new user data protection law goes into effect on November 1st]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>China has passed a new data protection law, according to the country’s <a href="http://www.xinhuanet.com/english/2021-08/20/c_1310138698.htm"><em><ins>Xinhua</ins></em><ins> state media outlet</ins></a>. The newly enacted <a href="http://www.mod.gov.cn/big5/regulatory/2021-08/20/content_4892505.htm"><ins>Personal Information Protection Law</ins></a> (PIPL) lays out a comprehensive set of rules around how companies collect, process and protect user data. Like GDPR, the law enshrines data minimization, the practice of limiting data collection to only the information needed for a specific purpose. It also mandates companies give users control over how their personal information is used. For instance, they’re allowed to opt out of targeted advertising.</p><p>Per <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-passes-new-personal-data-privacy-law-take-effect-nov-1-2021-08-20/"><em><ins>Reuters</ins></em></a>, another requirement put forward by PIPL is that companies designate someone who is personally responsible for user data protection. Platforms must also submit themselves to periodic audits to ensure compliance. Any foreign company operating in the country that handles the data of Chinese citizens must comply with those same rules, making the law extraterritorial in much the same way that GDPR is.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>PIPL comes as China has worked to rein in its tech giants. The company recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-tencent-wechat-youth-mode-lawsuit-211811555.html">sued Tencent</a> over WeChat’s “youth mode,” alleging the feature violates laws protecting children. What’s more, the country recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-big-tech-anti-monopoly-135529282.html"><ins>implemented new anti-monopoly measures</ins></a> aimed at companies like Alibaba, Didi and Tencent. PIPL is slated to go into effect on November 1st.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/china-passes-personal-information-protection-law-182326563.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e1391304-5460-49c1-94f9-8431d5c205e9</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 18:23:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629482017</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T17:53:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5c429e40-01de-11ec-bbee-6dc1b5837849" width="6588" height="4392" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5c429e40-01de-11ec-bbee-6dc1b5837849" width="6588" height="4392" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AerialPerspective Works via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Asian Woman Using Mobile Phone in Downtown District]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Social Connecting at Night]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify and WWE are tag-teaming on podcasts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#39;s a big weekend in the world of pro wrestling. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/wwe"><ins>WWE</ins></a> has two major shows lined up, including one of its marquee events, SummerSlam, which takes place at Allegiant Stadium in Las Vegas on Saturday. The company is making some strides elsewhere, thanks to a new audio content partnership with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/spotify"><ins>Spotify</ins></a>.</p><p>WWE and The Ringer (which Spotify <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-05-spotify-buys-the-ringer.html"><ins>bought last year</ins></a> for around $200 million to bolster its sports lineup) are <a href="https://corporate.wwe.com/investors/news/press-releases/2021/08-18-2021-140113410"><ins>building</ins></a> a podcast network together. The Ringer podcast <em>The Masked Man Show </em>has been rebranded as <em>The Ringer Wrestling Show</em>. More podcasts are on the way, including a narrative series produced by Bill Simmons (a self-professed lifelong WWE fan) and additional shows from WWE talent. WWE&#39;s current podcasts, including <em>The New Day: Feel the Power</em> and <em>WWE After the Bell with Corey Graves,</em> are becoming Spotify exclusives too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Along with the podcasts, there&#39;ll be live audio discussions on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-launches-its-clubhouse-live-audio-rival-greenroom-130034550.html"><ins>Spotify Greenroom</ins></a> after every big WWE pay-per-view event. The Ringer is recording some podcast episodes and hosting Greenroom conversations live in Las Vegas this weekend.</p><p>WWE is a solid get for Spotify, given the brand&#39;s popularity and global reach. Although SummerSlam might become overshadowed <a href="https://www.cagesideseats.com/aew/2021/8/15/22625877/cm-punk-aew-rampage-chicago-tony-khan"><ins>by events elsewhere</ins></a> in the pro wrestling sphere this weekend, it seems as good a time as any to kick off the partnership.</p><p>Earlier this year, the WWE Network <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wwe-network-peacock-exclusive-streaming-us-155406623.html"><ins>moved to Peacock</ins></a>. So, if you&#39;re a Peacock Premium member, you can watch SummerSlam and Sunday&#39;s NXT TakeOver 36 at no extra cost.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-wwe-podcast-network-greenroompodcast-180202849.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">350c60d9-bbe0-4691-b601-3d912a81dec2</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 18:02:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629481515</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T17:45:26+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Wrestling]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2b2f0a90-e92f-11eb-b65f-042b5215fdff" width="4113" height="2742" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2b2f0a90-e92f-11eb-b65f-042b5215fdff" width="4113" height="2742" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[USA TODAY USPW / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Jul 18, 2021; Fort Worth, TX, USA; John Cena (green shirt) returns to WWE after Roman Reigns (black pants) and Edge (not pictured) battled for the WWE Universal Championship during Money in the Bank at Dickies Arena. Mandatory Credit: Joe Camporeale-USA TODAY Sports]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[WRESTLING/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[OnlyFans’ policy switch is the latest victory in Big Banking’s war on sex]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OnlyFans, the platform that allows creators to sell material directly to customers, will soon implement new restrictions on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/onlyfans-sexually-explicit-content-ban-184819350.html">publication of adult content</a>. Starting in October, the company will ban the sale of sexually explicit content and depictions of sexual acts. The move does not cover all nudity, but says that specific rules will be outlined in an as-yet unpublished acceptable use policy. In a statement, OnlyFans said that the changes were prompted by “requests” made by its “banking partners and payout providers.” In short, the company’s arm has been twisted by the same big banks that have waged war on online sex work for years.</p><h2>Big Business</h2><p>The business can certainly attribute much of its success to enabling sex work and helping sex workers to get paid. Over the last two years, OnlyFans has grown from relative obscurity into a brand that is synonymous with adult content. Earlier this year, it boasted that its creators had earned more than $3 billion, and the platform was name-checked in a <a href="https://www.highsnobiety.com/p/beyonce-onlyfans-savage-remix/">Beyoncé remix</a>. It’s believed that the company, which had around 7 million users in 2019, has seen that figure reach closer to 130 million in recent months. And, on June 16th, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-16/onlyfans-is-said-to-seek-funding-at-valuation-above-1-billion?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> reported that the site was looking to attract investors in order to raise more funding at a valuation of more than $1 billion.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="ffbff4f39fbb4ff79f771ddb750616a1"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">here&#39;s OF full statement. nice of them to throw the transparency report in there. here&#39;s that too: <a href="https://t.co/xfFrfmX4Wp">https://t.co/xfFrfmX4Wp</a><a href="https://t.co/8WqjSGjLUk">pic.twitter.com/8WqjSGjLUk</a></p>— Samantha Cole (@samleecole) <a href="https://twitter.com/samleecole/status/1428427032971649028?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>It is clear, however, that a number of people who both create content for, and use, the site feel that the impending adult content ban is a betrayal. In a statement shared with Engadget, Isaac Hayes III, founder of Fanbase — a social media site that lets users sell their content — summed up the general sentiment rather neatly. Hayes said that the move was “disgraceful,” and that OnlyFans had “made billions off that user base.” He added that dumping sex workers after becoming a household name was “exactly what these platforms do. Discard the users who make it popular once they get what they want.” And in this case, it does seem as if the twin aims of securing more money from investors and retaining access to banking is what prompted the move. It’s a story that we’ve heard several times before.</p><h2>Deja Vu</h2><p>The most recent example, and one that we covered extensively at the time, was the cultivation and subsequent dumping of a sex work community on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-27-patreon-adult-content-crowdfunding-uncertainty.html">Patreon</a>. Before 2017, the site had passionately and <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/paypal-again-6071429">publicly courted sex workers</a>, encouraging them to use its platform. In 2016, it <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/gv5dmb/patreon-paypal-adult-content">loudly defied</a> PayPal’s longstanding ban on payments to sex workers, allowing users to support content creators through its platform. At the time, Patreon even criticized PayPal’s lack of transparency, saying that its opaque policy “impacts the lives of Adult Content creators.”</p><p>This attitude did not, however, last very long. On September 15th, 2017, Patreon raised $60 million from investors, and updated its content policy a month later, seeming to repudiate the sex workers it had previously courted. In <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-27-patreon-adult-content-crowdfunding-uncertainty.html">subsequent interviews</a>, the updated policy was described as not a big deal, with the company pledging to work with creators to ensure compliance. The general notion was that Patreon would crack down on content that was illegal or otherwise nonconsensual.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-06-29-patreon-crackdown-sex-worker-accounts.html">A year later</a>, however, and the site would further toughen its rules, saying that any and all adult content — including the famous erotic art project Four Chambers — was no longer permitted. (Four Chambers, the name of a British art-erotica collective led by artist Vex Ashley, was long held as the canary in the Patreon coal mine.) Patreon said that it had stepped up “proactive review of content [...] due to requirements from our payment partners.” In short, the same banks that Patreon had battled so loudly the year before had tied the site in knots, demanding it hunt out any and all content that could be considered adult.</p><p>It&#39;s worth noting that swerving away from sex work doesn&#39;t ensure the future prosperity of a business. In 2019, Patreon CEO Jack Conte told <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/01/23/crowd-funding-platform-patreon-announces-it-will-pay-out-half-a-billion-dollars-to-content-creators-in-2019.html"><em>CNBC</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>that its business model was not sustainable, and in April 2021, the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/patreons-valuation-triples-to-4-billion-as-creators-and-fans-flock-to-platform-11617762374?mod=djemalertNEWS"><em>Wall Street Journal</em></a> said the site was still not profitable. Tumblr meanwhile, which under Engadget’s parent company mass-purged adult content from its site in 2018 but left a wide variety of <a href="https://thinkprogress.org/far-right-content-survived-tumblr-purge-36635e6aba4b/">neo Nazi content</a> on its platform, saw its valuation fall from $1.1 billion in 2013 to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/08/13/tumblr-once-sold-billion-owner-wordpress-just-bought-site-fraction-that/">just $3 million</a> in 2019.</p><h2>Tangled up in Paperwork</h2><p>Back in April, <a href="https://www.mastercard.com/news/perspectives/2021/protecting-our-network-protecting-you-preventing-illegal-adult-content-on-our-network/">MasterCard</a> announced that it would further toughen the reporting requirements around adult content. John Verdeschi, Senior Vice President, wrote that banks using its network would need to “certify that the seller of adult content has effective controls in place to monitor, block and, where necessary, take down all illegal content.” This includes rules requiring platforms to keep a record of the identity of every performer shown, as well as who uploads the content. In addition, all content would need to be reviewed prior to release, and all platforms need to run a beefed-up complaints resolution process to take down illegal or non-consensual material within seven days.</p><p>As <a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20210415/11413646621/mastercard-lays-down-new-rules-streaming-sites-that-require-them-to-review-content-before-publication.shtml"><em>TechDirt</em></a> wrote back then, as reasonable as these policies sound, they seem intentionally designed to block all adult content, not just the illegal stuff. As it explains, “the new policy [...] makes it impossible for streaming platforms to comply with the new rules. Since they’re not able to prescreen streamed content, they’re [sic] just going to start blocking anything that seems like it might lead to MasterCard pulling the plug.” Mary Moody tweeted, upon announcement of the policy change, that “OnlyFans, MyFreeCams &amp; more are in danger.” As with Patreon, MasterCard&#39;s reporting requirements appear to be such a burden that companies would rather avoid the issue altogether than attempt to comply.</p><div id="a63b5570a7a84f39b42b1234e2f08423"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today MasterCard introduced a policy that will ban much of online sex work, especially live streaming. <br><br>OnlyFans, MyFreeCams &amp; more are in danger. <br><br>We need <a href="https://twitter.com/ACLU?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ACLU</a><a href="https://twitter.com/RoKhanna?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RoKhanna</a><a href="https://twitter.com/AOC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AOC</a><a href="https://twitter.com/ewarren?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ewarren</a><a href="https://twitter.com/RonWyden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RonWyden</a> to investigate this financial discrimination immediately.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MasterCensors?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MasterCensors</a><a href="https://t.co/DUR93QXCXQ">pic.twitter.com/DUR93QXCXQ</a></p>— OF SALE🌈Mary Moody in VICE, NBC, &amp; BBC ✨ (@missmarymoody) <a href="https://twitter.com/missmarymoody/status/1382405311210745858?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 14, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>This isn’t a new story, however, and in 2015 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-12-02-paypal-square-and-big-bankings-war-on-the-sex-industry.html">Engadget laid out in detail</a> how banks were systematically withdrawing access for adult content platforms. This isn’t just prohibitions on working with select adult content sites, but a blanket-ban that impacted individuals beyond their life in the sex industry. JPMorgan Chase shut down a number of bank accounts owned by adult performers, and refused banking services to a company that makes condoms. This crackdown had an disproportionate impact on individual accounts held by women and LGBTQ people.</p><h2>The Right</h2><p>This crackdown is part of a broader alliance between banks, lawmakers, right-wing pressure groups and religious extremists. As <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/160488/nick-kristof-holy-war-pornhub"><em>The New Republic</em></a> explained late last year, these groups have been able to use the cover of <a href="https://wagner.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/congresswoman-ann-wagner-leads-bipartisan-coalition-calling-for-doj-to">sex trafficking</a> to push an anti-porn, anti-sex agenda. The movement’s most successful victory was the passing of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-11-fosta-sesta-silencing-sex-workers.html">FOSTA-SESTA</a>, a US law designed to tackle human trafficking by neutering the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-31-sex-censorship-killed-internet-fosta-sesta.html">safe harbor provisions</a> of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-31-s230-repeal.html">Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act 1996</a>. Despite contravening the first amendment, the move has not shut down many groups of human traffickers, but has closed safety services created for, and used by, sex workers, and even forced Barnes &amp; Noble to purge its ebook store of erotica.</p><p>Naturally, OnlyFans became a clear target of those campaigners both because of its success and because it contradicted their narrative. By enabling individuals to sell their material to consumers without intermediaries, it was <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-fragile-existence-of-sex-workers-during-the-pandemic">allowing people to make a living</a>. You can also argue that sites like OnlyFans have enabled people otherwise excluded from the workforce — this report from <a href="https://arousibility.com/blog/my-sex-work-story/"><em>Arousability</em></a> explains that a person with chronic pain who can’t work a 9-to-5 job found that sex work offered them financial independence they couldn’t have found otherwise.</p><h2>Alternatives</h2><div id="2396859e80a740a9950eecaac5f5fa60"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We are drawing together a list of resources for sex workers impacted by the OF ban. <br><br>If you are a sex worker with experience of online work and you have a bit of time today to add any advice, tips or recommendations to it, please DM us or email mutualaid@swarmcollective.org</p>— SWARM (@SexWorkHive) <a href="https://twitter.com/SexWorkHive/status/1428677388729212936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>While creators wait for OnlyFans to detail just what content will be allowed, in its brave new world, many may wish to take their business elsewhere. There are a number of platforms that occupy a similar space in the market, including AVN Stars, FanCentro, Unlockd and AdultNode. Just For Fans, for instance, says that it is a sex worker owned-and-operated platform, and that it will welcome any and all creators that OnlyFans has “abandoned.” Similarly, a number of in-progress projects to build more sex-worker owned and operated platforms are currently underway.</p><div id="104d906c6d1f435f8a197a30a47e55c9"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our statement based on today’s news. <a href="https://t.co/3PHKmkQ5qQ">pic.twitter.com/3PHKmkQ5qQ</a></p>— JustForFans (@JustForFansSite) <a href="https://twitter.com/JustForFansSite/status/1428430713708290048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>It’s likely that this will be seen as another reason to switch to a blockchain and cryptocurrency-based system as a way of escaping the reach of big banking. There are several, including SpankCoin and Nafty, that offer sex workers the ability to sell content through their systems. And as more major platforms are picked off by a combination of payment processors and regulators, this space is going to grow.&nbsp;</p><p>But there are inherent risks to switching, including currency fluctuations and the risk that a sex work-specific currency can still be excluded from mainstream exchanges. And then there’s the fact that if a platform gets big enough, it gets noticed — and targeted — by anti-sex advocates. Crypto can shore up the finances, but pressure can always be exerted on providers, hosts and platform owners wherever they may be.&nbsp;</p><p>And that often forces creators to leap from platform to platform to keep one jump ahead of the people who want to strip them of their ability to make money. But every time they do so, they risk losing their user bases, and have to expend time and energy to recover the fans that they already had. Either way, until there is better political and corporate leadership who can handle the nuanced situation of online sex work, individuals will often be left with no choice but to keep moving, or sink.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/onlyfans-big-banks-war-adult-content-174041161.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">24594e7c-1749-4992-b28c-0b3a81b3f941</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 17:40:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629481013</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T17:36:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c859e9f0-0150-11ec-bdef-9838cd66df81" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c859e9f0-0150-11ec-bdef-9838cd66df81" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OnlyFans logo displayed on a phone screen and a website in the background are seen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on April 27, 2021. (Photo Illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OnlyFans Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Researchers say they built a CSAM detection system like Apple's and discovered flaws]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since Apple announced it was working on a technology for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html">detecting child sexual abuse material (CSAM)</a>, the system has been a lightning rod for controversy.  Now, two Princeton University academics say they know the tool Apple built is open to abuse because they spent years developing almost precisely the same system. “We wrote the only <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity21/presentation/kulshrestha">peer-reviewed publication</a> on how to build a system like Apple’s — and we concluded the technology was dangerous,” assistant professor Jonathan Mayer and graduate researcher Anunay Kulshrestha wrote in an op-ed <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/08/19/apple-csam-abuse-encryption-security-privacy-dangerous/"><em>The Washington Post</em> published</a> this week.</p><p>The two worked together on a system for identifying CSAM in end-to-end encrypted online services. Like Apple, they wanted to find a way to limit the proliferation of CSAM while maintaining user privacy. Part of their motivation was to encourage more online services to adopt end-to-end encryption. “We worry online services are reluctant to use encryption without additional tools to combat CSAM,” the researchers said.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The two spent years working on the idea, eventually creating a working prototype. However, they quickly determined there was a “glaring problem” with their tech. “Our system could be easily repurposed for surveillance and censorship,” Mayer and Kulshrestha wrote. “The design wasn’t restricted to a specific category of content; a service could simply swap in any content-matching database, and the person using that service would be none the wiser.”</p><p>That’s not a hypothetical worry either, they warn. The two researchers point to examples like WeChat, which the <a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2018/08/cant-picture-this-an-analysis-of-image-filtering-on-wechat-moments/">University of Toronto’s Citizen Lab</a> found uses content-matching algorithms to detect dissident material. “China is Apple’s second-largest market, with probably hundreds of millions of devices. What stops the Chinese government from demanding Apple scan those devices for pro-democracy materials?” Mayer and Kulshrestha ask, pointing to several instances where Apple acquiesced to demands from the Chinese government. For example, there’s the time the company gave <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-chinese-government-control-data-131343119.html">local control of customer data</a> over to the country.</p><p>“We spotted other shortcomings,” Mayer and Kulshrestha continue. “The content-matching process could have false positives, and malicious users could game the system to subject innocent users to scrutiny.” Those are concerns privacy advocates have also raised about Apple’s system.</p><p>For the most part, Apple has attempted to downplay many of the concerns Mayer and Kulshrestha iterate in their opinion piece. Senior vice president of software engineering Craig Federighi recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-on-confusion-over-child-safety-updates-csam-150121989.html">attributed the controversy to poor messaging</a>. He rejected the idea the system could be used for scanning for other material, noting the database of images comes from various child safety groups. And on the subject of false positives, he said the system only triggers a manual review after someone uploads 30 images to iCloud. We&#39;ve reached out to Apple for comment on the op-ed.&nbsp;</p><p>Despite those statements, Mayer and Kulshrestha note their reservations don’t come from a lack of understanding. They said they had planned to discuss the pitfalls of their system at an academic conference but never got a chance because Apple announced its tech a week before the presentation. “Apple’s motivation, like ours, was to protect children. And its system was technically more efficient and capable than ours,” they said. “But we were baffled to see that Apple had few answers for the hard questions we’d surfaced.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/princeton-university-researcher-apple-csam-oped-162004601.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">72a03e1b-26a7-441d-a0a1-d7764c20d021</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 16:20:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629476354</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T16:19:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/3afef9f0-7ab5-11eb-bd7f-121fb1272d3e" width="3000" height="1658" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/3afef9f0-7ab5-11eb-bd7f-121fb1272d3e" width="3000" height="1658" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[iPhone 12 lineup]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[iPhone 12 lineup]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[T-Mobile says data for 6 million additional customers was compromised in breach]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/t-mobile">T-Mobile</a> says millions more people have been impacted by its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/t-mobile-confirms-data-breach-203719462.html"><ins>recent data breach</ins></a> than initially believed. In a Securities and Exchange Commission filing, the company <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/0001283699/000119312521251974/d362750d8k.htm"><ins>said</ins></a> an additional 6 million or so accounts were affected, taking the total to more than 54 million.</p><p>On Wednesday, T-Mobile <a href="https://www.engadget.com/t-mobile-data-breach-affected-people-103104868.html"><ins>disclosed</ins></a> that data from around 40 million former or potential customers had been compromised in a cyberattack. The data included names, birth dates, social security numbers, driver’s licenses and information from other types of identification. The company now says another 667,000 accounts of former customers were accessed, with attackers obtaining some personal data from those, but no SSNs or ID details.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In the previous disclosure, T-Mobile said approximately 7.8 million current holders of T-Mobile postpaid accounts were impacted, with attackers gaining at least some customers&#39; personal data. The company now says phone numbers and IMEI and IMSI details (identifiers for mobile devices and SIM cards respectively) were compromised as well.</p><p>On top of that, T-Mobile has identified another 5.3 million affected postpaid accounts. No SSNs or driver’s license/identification details were compromised from those, the company said, but the attackers accessed other identifiable information.</p><p>Around 850,000 active T-Mobile prepaid customers have been impacted as well. The attackers may have garnered up to 52,000 names connected to current Metro by T-Mobile accounts too. Accounts of former Sprint prepaid and Boost Mobile customers are unaffected.</p><p>Other data was stolen in the cyberattack, including additional phone numbers and IMEI and IMSI numbers, but the company claims there was no personally identifiable information in those files. Meanwhile, T-Mobile still has &quot;no indication&quot; that customer financial details, such as credit card data, were affected.</p><p>A member of an underground forum <a href="https://www.engadget.com/t-mobile-data-breach-investigation-202913474.html"><ins>claimed over the weekend</ins></a> to have data for more than 100 million T-Mobile customers. They reportedly attempted to sell information of around 30 million of those for about $270,000 worth of Bitcoin.</p><p>T-Mobile&#39;s investigation into the breach is ongoing and it will provide more details if it finds more affected accounts. The company says it&#39;s &quot;confident that we have closed off the access and egress points the bad actor used in the attack&quot; and that it has taken steps to mitigate the impact on customers. For instance, it has offered two years of identity protection service to anyone who thinks they might have been affected.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tmobile-data-breach-number-of-people-affected-cyberattack-160353536.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bcec026e-c7d9-4b8a-99e2-ff73686285b3</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 16:03:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629475437</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T16:04:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/00a273e0-01ce-11ec-93bb-3f4f8012b9e4" width="5324" height="3549" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/00a273e0-01ce-11ec-93bb-3f4f8012b9e4" width="5324" height="3549" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chip Somodevilla via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ARLINGTON, VA - AUGUST 18:  People walk past the front of a T-Mobile retail store on August 18, 2021 in Arlington, Virginia. T-Mobile announced Wednesday that a data breach exposed the personal information of 7.8 million current customers and 40 million people who had applied for credit. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[T-Mobile Data Breach Affects 40 Million People]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's AirPods Pro fall to $180, plus the rest of the week's best tech deals]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The internet was awash with tech deals this week, with some of the best coming from Apple and Amazon. Apple&#39;s AirPods Pro dropped to $180 while the MacBook Pro M1 received at $200 discount. Amazon kicked off its &quot;off to college&quot; sale by reducing the prices of its Echo speakers, including the Echo Dot, Kindle e-readers and a handful of Fire tablets. And those looking for a new streaming gadget can get the Roku Streambar or the NVIDIA Shield TV for less. Here are the best tech deals we found this week that you can still get today.</p><h2>AirPods Pro</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/62dce390-a1b4-11ea-b6ff-c327709bc1d2" alt="Apple AirPods Pro" data-uuid="56fad2ce-20fe-4841-a21a-9403dcf739e3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele / Engadget</div></figure><p>Apple&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:AirPods Pro" href="https://amzn.to/3iKKAzf">AirPods Pro</a> are down to $180 right now, or $70 off their normal price. These are the best sounding earbuds you can get from Apple, and we gave them a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-06-apple-airpods-pro-review.html">score of 87</a> for their better, more secure fit, IPX4 water resistance and solid audio quality.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3iKKAzf" id="da4d835bb48e48fb893f176150749693" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy AirPods Pro at Amazon - $180</a><h2>MacBook Pro M1</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/d37e0460-3eeb-11eb-b7f9-449e864b9135" alt="Apple&#39;s latest MacBook Pro with an M1 chip." data-uuid="27c0a73c-bb19-3bde-9444-9b63933a333c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar / Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:MacBook Pro M1" href="https://amzn.to/2W2U2Fr">MacBook Pro M1</a> is $200 off at Amazon thanks to a sale price and an automatically applied coupon on top of that. That means you can get the model with 256GB of storage for $1,099 and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:512GB version" href="https://amzn.to/2UthwTI">512GB version</a> for $1,299. We gave the Pro M1 a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/macbook-pro-m1-review-163011742.html">score of 84</a> for its powerful performance, solid keyboard and trackpad and healthy battery life.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2W2U2Fr" id="086b5fc57ebf46dbb8f3a7d752a95b1e" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy MacBook Pro M1 (256GB) at Amazon - $1,099</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2UthwTI" id="e4efca63abe04f8890b10786543cc67a" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy MacBook Pro M1 (512GB) at Amazon - $1,299</a><h2>iPad Pro</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/419d9f70-a204-11eb-beff-582c25470f07" alt="2021 Apple iPad Pro" data-uuid="be0f69be-1a76-3f24-b2f0-4073663e4a1d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>Those looking to invest in an iPad Pro as a laptop alternative need look no further than Amazon&#39;s most recent sales on the 1TB models. The WiFi version of the latest <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:11-inch iPad Pro" href="https://amzn.to/37UtatC">11-inch iPad Pro</a> is down to $1,399 while the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:WiFi + Cellular version" href="https://amzn.to/3iVpNJA">WiFi + Cellular version</a> is down to $1,599. These <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-pro-2021-m1-review-liquid-retina-xdr-5g-features-price-130049005.html">iPad Pros</a> run on Apple&#39;s M1 chipset, so you&#39;re getting the latest processor technology and formidable performance in these slabs.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/37UtatC" id="a8ada5cdaa5545079da96bc3bb8609d5" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy iPad Pro (1TB, WiFi) at Amazon - $1,399</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3iVpNJA" id="757acdf9a1654c79bfaddf9a718f23d9" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy iPad Pro (1TB, WiFi + Cellular) - $1,599</a><h2>Echo smart speakers</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/305a54e0-2b4b-11eb-bd76-0fc9e489604d" alt="Amazon Echo 2020" data-uuid="3331f9e3-8e89-3715-a411-6bf1969da330"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo Dot" href="https://amzn.to/3yTexCO">Echo Dot</a> has been discounted to $35 while the regular <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo" href="https://amzn.to/3m8NT5s">Echo</a> smart speaker is down to $80 as part of Amazon&#39;s &quot;off to college&quot; sale. While not all-time lows, these sale prices are great for those that want to save a bit and add an Echo device to their home, or college students who want a convenience speaker for their new dorm room.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3yTexCO" id="c3bc810eb0f248469b56d5011208ae53" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Echo Dot at Amazon - $35</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3m8NT5s" id="950de6af433f4667b3dcef6015040443" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Echo at Amazon - $80</a><h2>Kindle devices</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/20d06bc0-0a55-11eb-8fed-d4d161d274f8" alt="Amazon Kindle Paperwhite" data-uuid="88db10c6-55a0-3d29-ae34-bbcdf4fe8f54"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Both Amazon&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Kindle Paperwhite" href="https://amzn.to/37OoTrW">Kindle Paperwhite</a> and regular <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Kindle" href="https://amzn.to/3m7Gd3x">Kindle</a> are on sale right now for $80 and $65, respectively. These are some of the best prices we&#39;ve seen on both e-readers since Prime Day back in June. We recommend the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-13-kindle-paperwhite-review-2018.html">Paperwhite</a> to those that can afford it, but the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-10-amazon-kindle-review-2019.html">standard Kindle</a> is an even better buy now than it was a couple of years ago thanks to its new front light and higher-contrast display.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/37OoTrW" id="c5e1ba1ca2b546e2904b027905143c2f" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Kindle Paperwhite at Amazon - $80</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3m7Gd3x" id="98271765dca944cdb38ec30f2ea7b4cb" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Kindle at Amazon - $65</a><h2>Fire tablets</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/39df5b50-ab3f-11ea-ace3-4aaf1bd717c4" alt="Amazon Fire HD 8 (2020)" data-uuid="1f382f2e-269e-4b48-816e-b8d1cfcb9a7f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Valentina Palladino / Engadget</div></figure><p>A number of Amazon Fire tablets are on sale this week, including the new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fire HD 10" href="https://amzn.to/3iPTWK9">Fire HD 10</a>, which is down to a record low of $100. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fire HD 8" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fire-HD-8-tablet/dp/B07TMJ1R3X?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=b99673f6ecdbc25e6e9b71ff47cbb173&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Fire HD 8</a> has been discounted to $60, which is a great price for a basic tablet that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fire-hd-8-review-130005977.html">we praised</a> for its long battery life, USB-C charging and hands-free Alexa capabilities. And if you&#39;ve been eyeing a Fire tablet for your child, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fire 7 Kids Pro" href="https://amzn.to/3xNUUeg">Fire 7 Kids Pro</a> and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fire 8 Kids Pro" href="https://amzn.to/3m4eLnd">Fire 8 Kids Pro</a> are both on sale for $60 and $90, respectively.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3iPTWK9" id="e5daa169a0144c39b5fdf83f0589ffd3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Fire HD 10 at Amazon - $100</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fire-HD-8-tablet/dp/B07TMJ1R3X?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=b99673f6ecdbc25e6e9b71ff47cbb173&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" id="52276585981f41928d000d9f69ac7cc3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Fire HD 8 at Amazon - $60</a><h2>Fire TV Cube</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/0e391a70-a1b4-11ea-87df-55c2397a8320" alt="Amazon Fire TV Cube streaming device." data-uuid="e67b832a-8886-44f0-86cd-4022bad2063f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nicole Lee / Engadget</div></figure><p>Amazon knocked $20 off its <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fire TV Cube" href="https://amzn.to/3CJhI2t">Fire TV Cube</a>, bringing it down to $100. It&#39;s been around for a while, but the Fire TV Cube remains the most powerful streaming device in Amazon&#39;s lineup. It has solid performance and supports 4K HDR output as well as voice commands via Alexa for both your TV and other smart home devices.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3CJhI2t" id="798d39dba8754af8bbc72f0d1fa3c851" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Fire TV Cube at Amazon - $100</a><h2>NVIDIA Shield TV</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/e74d3150-2f5a-11eb-bfaf-57f20715fb51" data-uuid="95d0df94-1e59-3d17-bf0c-a5649e22eeca"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:NVIDIA Shield TV" href="https://amzn.to/3smeHQQ">NVIDIA Shield TV</a> is $20 off right now, bringing it down to $130. We like it for its Tegra X1+ processor and its support for Dolby Vision HDR, Dolby Atmos audio, Chromecast 4K and AI-powered HD-to-4K upscaling.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3smeHQQ" id="1820bdcd4b464311ab5581b65ec41dfa" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy NVIDIA Shield TV at Amazon - $130</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/3P95Pn" id="b8af78086fa841ec859b7f2b515eb2ab" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Best Buy;elmt:impactRadius;pdid:">Buy NVIDIA Shield TV at Best Buy - $130</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3sqEuaH" id="3492b5cc44bd441ca11e5358644e33f6" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy NVIDIA Shield TV at B&amp;H - $130</a><h2>Roku Streambar</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/9ef272e0-1794-11eb-bffd-21e2290ccd64" alt="Roku Streambar soundbar on a white table." data-uuid="1efc2e9b-98d8-36fc-b6da-9c4b43f0eac8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Valentina Palladino / Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Streambar" href="https://amzn.to/2VZw2Tw">Roku Streambar</a> is down to $99 right now, or $30 off its normal price. It&#39;s a relatively affordable device to get to upgrade an old TV in your home, or up the audio chops on your main set. We gave it a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-streambar-review-133013675.html">score of 86</a> for its compact size, good sound quality and 4K HDR streaming chops.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2VZw2Tw" id="a8d6268280114065b7e9011317b5c255" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Streambar at Amazon - $99</a><h2>Galaxy Buds Pro</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/a6a069b0-5746-11eb-bf77-06c3b850750f" alt="Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro review" data-uuid="ef6b61dd-6625-3bc8-8872-4270c544ff3f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>Samsung&#39;s premium <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy Buds Pro" href="https://fave.co/2W5cLk6">Galaxy Buds Pro</a> are on sale for $127 at B&amp;H Photo right now. That&#39;s 37 percent off their normal price and close to a record low. We gave them a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-review-163027027.html">score of 85</a> for their comfy fit, good sound quality and wireless charging case.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/2W5cLk6" id="4de7806cf6d74f2da4cea3b0d8e40420" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Galaxy Buds Por at B&amp;H - $127</a><h2>Virgin Galactic sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fo.aolcdn.com%252Fimages%252Fdims%253Fimage_uri%253Dhttps%25253A%25252F%25252Fs.yimg.com%25252Fos%25252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%25252F2021-07%25252F079c6ce0-e25d-11eb-9ff7-705aa7bbb4fc%2526thumbnail%253D675%25252C%2526client%253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%2526signature%253Db3417e6882ae2d86a626d582960e8881cc8a5d72%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3D0985ecf955db8ed12c665b4fbff24d79a5e58447&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=4ecd01508dba893a8384ebae5666f89b5dcbba5a"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>In this Omaze giveaway you can win <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:two seats on one of the first Virgin Galactic flights to space" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fvirgin%2Dgalactic%2D2021&amp;afftrack=07132021VirginGalactic">two seats on one of the first Virgin Galactic flights to space</a>. In addition, you&#39;ll go on a tour of Spaceport America in New Mexico with Richard Branson. You don&#39;t have to pay to enter, but funds from all paid entries will support Space for Humanity, an organization that hopes to make space more accessible for all. The sweepstakes is open through September 1, so you still have time to enter.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fvirgin%2Dgalactic%2D2021&amp;afftrack=07132021VirginGalactic" id="c16ee5eb0e9e40d7a7d9eeba21772fd9" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Omaze;elmt:other;pdid:">Enter to win at Omaze</a><h2>Gaming PC sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fo.aolcdn.com%252Fimages%252Fdims%253Fimage_uri%253Dhttps%25253A%25252F%25252Fs.yimg.com%25252Fos%25252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%25252F2021-06%25252F067d0cd0-d8de-11eb-bf7f-328a4f92ae83%2526thumbnail%253D675%25252C%2526client%253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%2526signature%253D7b90f9f0acdc474ea6ab7ece951c9ed87fcc507e%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3D03cd24acc60acb8d1d2ae232a919aa9a74a77afe&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=48a869d75c4d50227479e64583a971137a7169a2"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Through September 18, Omaze is giving away another <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:$20,000 to build your ultimate gaming PC" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fgaming%2Drig%2D6%3F&amp;afftrack=6292021GamingPC">$20,000 to build your ultimate gaming PC</a>. This sweepstakes is free to enter, but funds donated with purchased entries will benefit Schools on Wheels, an organization that provides free tutoring and mentoring services to children experiencing homelessness across Southern California.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fgaming%2Drig%2D6%3F&amp;afftrack=6292021GamingPC" id="02016026b82f4fd983e8e131eca4ebde" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Omaze;elmt:other;pdid:">Enter to win at Omaze</a><h2>Comic-Con 2022 sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%252F2021-07%252F619b2930-eed7-11eb-bd17-d6cba8d900bc%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3D8b6e9d101a1e6ef829b56dc2e4f42e2d3d2e3020&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=578a294cfbe03b96f5848f37d835b889db486118"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Through December 8, you can enter to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:win four-day passes to San Diego Comic-Con 2022" href="http://shrsl.com/339h5">win four-day passes to San Diego Comic-Con 2022</a>. Along with the passes, you&#39;ll get access to a special preview night, reserved seating in Hall H, a personal concierge, a private tour of the Comic-Con Museum, dinner in Balboa Park and tickets to the &quot;Night at the Comic-Con Museum&quot; event. It&#39;s free to enter, but funds from this sweepstakes will go to the San Diego Comic Convention.</p><a class="athena-button" href="http://shrsl.com/339h5" id="054c19b3574443789107c4cfb56c0ed3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Omaze;elmt:other;pdid:">Enter to win at Omaze</a><p><em>Pricing and availability is subject to change. No donation or payment necessary to enter or win this sweepstakes.</em><a href="https://www.omaze.com/pages/rules"><em>See official rules on Omaze.</em></a></p><h2>New tech deals</h2><h3>GOG.com Games Festival</h3><p>The Games Festival at GOG.com runs through September 2 and it features a bunch of discounted games. Currently you can get <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:Mortal Shell for $27" href="https://adtr.co/5utrFw"><em>Mortal Shell for $27</em></a>, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:Dishonored: Complete Collection for $20" href="https://adtr.co/gSATZQ"><em>Dishonored: Complete Collection for $20</em></a>, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt for $10" href="https://adtr.co/qoAwXR"><em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt for $10</em></a> and more.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://adtr.co/Geaz6y" id="c6c367caa09a47d08afca3b0603f315a" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:GOG.com;elmt:other;pdid:">Shop Games Festival sales at GOG.com</a><h3>Logitech C922x Pro webcam</h3><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Logitech&#39;s C922x Pro webcam" href="https://amzn.to/3AYampR">Logitech&#39;s C922x Pro webcam</a> is on sale for $75, or $25 off its normal price. While not a record low, it&#39;s a good sale price on a solid webcam that you&#39;ll actually be able to get relatively soon — Amazon estimates orders will ship in the first few weeks of September. This version of the C922 webcam is optimized for streaming, so it could be your Zoom-meeting webcam as well as your main game streaming camera.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3AYampR" id="e5376fa08bc94f82851736dfc26e4d7b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy C922x Pro webcam at Amazon - $75</a><h3>NordVPN</h3><p>One of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-vpn-services-130028530.html">our recommended VPNs</a> is running a decent sale on a two-year subscription. You can sign up for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:NordVPN" href="https://fave.co/3uCgyAL">NordVPN</a> for $99 for the first two years, which comes out to $49.50 per year, and get three additional months of access for free. We like NordVPN for its speed, its no-logs policy, the thousands of servers it has to choose from and that one account supports up to six connected devices.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3uCgyAL" id="fa8521f0647c4bc3bac0850662b3d5d1" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:NordVPN;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy NordVPN (2 years) - $99</a><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-fall-to-180-best-tech-deals-this-week-155010874.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6fe0751d-7a6a-4e4d-824a-06c743f1e45a</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 15:50:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629474275</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T15:44:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hobbies & Personal Activities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/bd13d570-cdc0-11ea-bddb-696b5bd00b0a" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/bd13d570-cdc0-11ea-bddb-696b5bd00b0a" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[AirPods Pro]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AirPods Pro]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The best SSD for your PlayStation 5]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony, arguably nine months too late, is finally unlocking the 10 million PlayStation 5s around the world to accept expandable SSD storage. At launch, the next-gen console offered only 667GB of space for storing your PS5 games, with no way to expand that. While that’s been fine for some (like me), others (like my son) have been performing a near-daily juggling act, having to frequently delete and re-download games due to the restrictive storage size and the apparent need to have constant access to every Call of Duty game.</p><p>With the upcoming system software update — currently in beta testing — you’ll be able to increase your storage by slotting in a standard PCIe Gen4 x4 M.2 NVMe SSD. If that mess of acronyms has you recoiling, don’t worry, you’ll see that it’s not all that complicated, and if you want to know which drives we recommend, you can skip to the end.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>How much storage do I need?</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/341eb080-1ec1-11eb-bffb-88f330aaaf35" alt="Sony PlayStation 5 gaming console." data-uuid="7ad959d1-4d5d-3176-b02c-ebf74f05f30c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Aaron Souppouris / Engadget</div></figure><p>The PS5 will accept drives between 250GB and 4TB in capacity. If you already have a PlayStation 5, chances are you have a reasonable idea of how much storage you want. If you’re buying an SSD with a new PS5, or buying for someone else, though, it’s difficult to tell.</p><p>PS5 games are a little smaller on average than their PS4 equivalents, typically ranging between 30GB and 100GB, with some notable (and very popular) exceptions. If you’re a fan of the Call of Duty series, just having <em>Cold War</em> multiplayer and <em>Modern Warfare</em>/<em>Warzone</em> installed will require 307GB of space. A full <em>Warzone</em>-<em>Modern Warfare</em>-<em>Cold War</em> install will take up almost two thirds of the PS5’s internal storage. If you’re not a CoD fan, though, chances are you’ll be good to store between six to 10 games on your PS5 internally before running into problems.</p><p>One additional thing to consider is your internet speed. If you live in an area with slow broadband, the “you can just download it again” rationale doesn’t really work out. A 100GB download takes me around eight hours, during which time it&#39;s difficult to simultaneously watch Twitch or, say, publish articles about upgrading PS5 SSDs. Keeping games around on the off-chance you’ll want to play them at some point make sense, at least for my household.</p><p>Off the bat, there&#39;s basically no point in going for a 250GB drive. Economically, 250GB drives aren’t that much cheaper than 500GB, and practically, that really isn’t a lot of space for modern games to live on. 500GB drives, coming in at around $90 to $150, are a decent bet, but the sweet spot for most is to opt for a 1TB drive, which should run you between $160 and $250. That will more than double the space you have available for games without breaking the bank. (Seagate’s official 1TB Xbox Series expansion card, for comparison, sells for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:$220" href="https://amzn.to/3yejTrr">$220</a>.)</p><p>If you have the money, 2TB drives sometimes offer marginal savings per gigabyte, and can often be found when other models are out of stock. Unless you’re rolling in cash and want to flex, 4TB models should mostly be avoided, as you’ll end up paying more per gigabyte than you would with a 1TB or 2TB drive.</p><p>One final note: While the 825GB PS5 only provides 667GB of storage, that’s largely due to storage being reserved for the operating system and caching. If you install a 1TB SSD, you&#39;ll have, within margin of error, 1TB of storage available for games.</p><h2>What about external SSDs?</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f9a78850-01b4-11ec-bdf1-6047ddc9fc71" alt="Samsung T5 SSD" data-uuid="9b8670dd-cabf-369b-abb2-5fdce42dfcf5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>These are dramatically cheaper than the high-end internal SSDs, but there are restrictions on what you can do with them. An external SSD connects to your PS5 via USB, and is only suitable for playing PS4 games, or storing PS5 titles. This is useful if you have anything but the best internet — it’s faster to move a PS5 game out of “cold storage” on an external drive than it is to re-download it — or just want a large number of PS4 games to hand.</p><p>Due to the limitations here, you don’t need the highest performing model, although you should opt for SSDs over HDDs for improved transfer speeds. Any basic portable drive from a reputable brand will do, with the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Crucial X6" href="https://amzn.to/3ASyw56">Crucial X6</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Samsung T5" href="https://amzn.to/3mjYrPm">Samsung T5</a> being options we’ve tried and can recommend.</p><h2>What SSDs are compatible with PS5?</h2><h2></h2><p>The official answer to this question is an “M.2 Socket 3 (Key M) Gen4 x4 NVME SSD.” But even within that seemingly specific description, there are still more things to consider. The main requirements Sony has laid out for compatibility come down to speed, cooling and physical dimensions.</p><p>For speed, Sony says drives should be able to handle sequential reads at 5,500MB/s. Early testing has shown that drives as slow as 4,800MB/s are accepted by the PS5, and using them to play a game that taps into the SSD regularly — such as <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</em> — causes no issues. Pretty much the only thing the PS5 will outright reject is one that doesn&#39;t match the Gen4 x4 spec.&nbsp;</p><p>In our opinion, though, using a drive slower than the specification is a risk that, if you don’t already have that drive lying around, is not worth taking. Just because we haven’t found issues now, that doesn’t mean there won’t be games that will be problematic down the line. The price difference between these marginally slower Gen4 drives and the ones that meet Sony’s spec is not huge, and you may as well cover all your bases.</p><p>Slightly more complicated than speed is cooling and size. Most bare SSDs are going to be just fine; the PS5 can fit 22mm-wide SSDs of virtually any length (30mm, 42mm, 60mm, 80mm or 110mm, to be precise). The vast majority of drives you find will be 22mm wide and 80mm long, so no problem there.</p><p>It should be noted that the system can fit a 25mm-wide drive, but that width must include the cooling solution. Speaking of, Sony says SSDs require “effective heat dissipation with a cooling structure, such as a heatsink,” which is where most of the complications arise.</p><p>The maximum height supported by Sony’s slot is 11.25mm, of which only 2.45mm can be “below” the drive. This is intensely specific, and rules out some popular heatsinked Gen4 SSDs such as Corsair’s MP600 Pro and Sabrent’s Rocket 4 Plus. With time, it’s likely that manufacturers will want in on this new avenue for high-end SSD sales, and these heatsink size limits are going to become the de facto standard for the industry. In the meantime, however, only a couple of heatsinked drives fit out of the box.</p><p>If you’re looking to save some money, bare drives are often much cheaper and prevalent than their heatsinked alternatives, and it’s trivial to find a cooling solution that will work for the PS5.</p><p>The only component in an NVMe SSD that really requires cooling is the controller, which without a heatsink will happily sear a (very small) steak. Most SSDs have chips on only one side, but even on double-sided SSDs, the controller is likely to be on top, as manufacturers know it needs to be positioned there to better dissipate heat. So, head to your PC component seller of choice, and pick up basically anything that meets the recommended dimensions. A good search term is “laptop NVME heatsink,” as these will be designed to fit in the confines of gaming laptops, which are even more restrictive than a PS5. They’re also typically cheaper than the ones popping up now that are labelled as “PS5 heatsinks.”</p><p>One recommendation is <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:this $7 copper heatsink" href="https://amzn.to/3xdeKiO">this $7 copper heatsink</a>, which attaches to the SSD with sticky thermal interface material. It works just fine, and really, performing stress tests on a PC, we couldn’t find anything metal that didn’t keep temperatures under control. When you’re searching, just make sure the solution you go for measures no more than 25mm wide or 8mm tall including the thermal interface material and has a simple method of installation that’s not going to cause any headaches.</p><p>Now, if all of that was very boring, here are some ready-to-go recommendations:</p><h2>Best PS5 SSD: Patriot Viper VP4300</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/ab964370-01b6-11ec-8bff-65f2c8067859" alt="Patriot Viper VP4300" data-uuid="97fb5b32-e3fe-330e-b607-d170560a28b6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Patriot</div></figure><p>Patriot may not be the biggest name in components, but it has a long history in the PC market, and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Viper VP4300" href="https://amzn.to/3j2iPRD">Viper VP4300</a> is a solid drive for the PS5. With a sequential read rating of 7,400MB/s and a slim heatsink preinstalled, it meets all the necessary requirements for a simple upgrade. The reason it tops our list is the cost. It comes in 1TB and 2TB varieties, both of which are competitively priced. Expect to pay around $210 for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1TB version" href="https://amzn.to/3j2iPRD">1TB version</a> or $430 for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3z9bKFO">2TB</a>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3j2iPRD" id="1209b349694b484983e529c7277411a8" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Viper VP4300 at Amazon - $210</a><h2>Best cheap PS5 SSD: PNY XLR8 CS3040</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f43d81b0-01b6-11ec-bfef-76903fd39692" alt="PNY XLR8 CS3040" data-uuid="6958812f-39d6-356f-8745-8be542d1c3d2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">PNY</div></figure><p>If you’re not a PC user, PNY is another company you probably haven’t heard of. Again, though, it has a good track record, operating for three decades out of the US. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:XLR8 CS3040" href="https://amzn.to/3rGOLPD">XLR8 CS3040</a> is a fantastic value option, though it will require you to add your own cooling solution, as the one PNY sells won’t fit in the PS5.</p><p>While that may sound like a hassle, maybe the pricing will convince you: The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:$90 500GB option" href="https://amzn.to/3fb2GIo">$90 500GB option</a> is great, but the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:$160 1TB drive" href="https://amzn.to/3rGOLPD">$160 1TB drive</a> is a steal, and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:$307 2TB model" href="https://amzn.to/3fcXtzM">$307 2TB model</a> is also outrageously cheap. As mentioned, we don’t really recommend 4TB drives but, among the typically four-figure options on the market, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:PNY&#x002019;s $700 CS3040" href="https://amzn.to/381m5rj">PNY’s $700 CS3040</a> is the only one that makes any sense.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3rGOLPD" id="6888687e21244add8458bf91a50867bf" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy PNY XLR8 CS3040 at Amazon - $160</a><h2>Other compatible drives</h2><h3><strong>WD Black SN850</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/14127680-01b7-11ec-bfdf-40eab6d7d81a" alt="WD_Black SN850" data-uuid="0dbcf2c7-972a-3466-b2f5-59a8db08c6bc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Western Digital</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:SN850" href="https://amzn.to/3ygD18K">SN850</a> is a plug-and-play option for the PS5, with a sequential read rating well above the necessary numbers and a 6.5mm-high heatsink preinstalled. It comes in 500GB, 1TB and 2TB varieties, all of which are priced fairly competitively, though the price-per-GB of the 1TB and 2TB is significantly lower than the 500GB.</p><p>Expect to pay around $140 for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:500GB drive" href="https://amzn.to/3BXv0Ik">500GB drive</a>, $250 for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1TB version" href="https://amzn.to/3ygD18K">1TB version</a> or $430 for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3j4W7Zd">2TB</a>. If you’re willing to go it alone on the heatsink, those prices drop to around $120, $200 and $400, respectively.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3ygD18K" id="5f0434be461a4c84a426e94893ef84a9" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy WD Black SN850 at Amazon - $230</a><h3><strong>Seagate FireCuda 530</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/2ae50da0-01b7-11ec-a40f-b40f7bf96945" alt="Seagate FireCuda 530" data-uuid="2c0e4708-133f-3973-b7c9-dc7bf4dd350e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Seagate</div></figure><p>We haven’t been able to test this one ourselves, as it starts shipping “this summer,” but given Seagate is a trusted brand and has outright said its heatsinked drive supports PS5, we’re happy to include it on this list. Unfortunately, the list pricing on the 530s is high, at $160 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:500GB" href="https://amzn.to/3yfsZow">500GB</a>, $260 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1TB" href="https://amzn.to/3ferHCz">1TB</a>, $540 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3fdYp7g">2TB</a> and $1,000 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:4TB" href="https://amzn.to/37etRO4">4TB</a>. The non-heatsink version will retail at $140, $240 and $490, for the 500GB, 1TB and 2TB versions. These aren&#39;t a million miles away from the RRP on other drives on this list that have a lower real-world price now, so we’d expect that you’ll be able to find some deals at similar rates down the line.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3ferHCz" id="6aaf8aae39ea4a238a874d48f023a95a" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Seagate FireCuda 530 at Amazon - $260</a><h3><strong>Samsung 980 Pro</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/469ab630-01b7-11ec-bbff-91da2b760dac" alt="Samsung 980 Pro" data-uuid="deb408a7-b9b2-36d6-902d-60c4cb2a8cbf"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>Samsung does not sell a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:980 Pro" href="https://amzn.to/2V7DhJ1">980 Pro</a> with a heatsink attached, but it does have a fantastic reputation for reliability, and prices that are competitive with WD, Seagate and others on this list. Expect to pay around $130 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:500GB" href="https://amzn.to/3icSQro">500GB</a>, $190 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1TB" href="https://amzn.to/2V7DhJ1">1TB</a>, or $370 for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3yqVFuA">2TB</a>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2V7DhJ1" id="4b87c83c0d624f4eae294c008b95db6b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Samsung 980 Pro at Amazon - $190</a><h3><strong>Crucial P5 Plus</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5ad64ec0-01b7-11ec-b3ff-1755e34a8b54" alt="Crucial P5 Plus" data-uuid="0c7d648b-7ce5-3699-a9f6-935f7cbc4861"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Crucial</div></figure><p>Crucial’s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:P5 Plus" href="https://amzn.to/3szxyYF">P5 Plus</a> is another budget model, which missed out on the “best cheap SSD” spot thanks to PNY’s marginally lower prices. Again, this one has no heatsink, so you’ll need to supply your own. The 1TB drive is the sweet-spot option, coming in at $180, while the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:500GB" href="https://amzn.to/2UzTCWH">500GB</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3z476cj">2TB</a> drives will set you back $108 and $368, respectively.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3szxyYF" id="fa82dc8ef0544aad8a6f52e257a55b9b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Crucial P5 Plus at Amazon - $180</a><h3><strong>Sabrent Rocket 4 Plus</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/72838e70-01b7-11ec-bd7f-64e4da38dc6b" alt="Sabrent Rocket 4 Plus" data-uuid="d9a681aa-e024-3c91-8799-257d613212d7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sabrent</div></figure><p>Sabrent sells a bunch of Rocket drives, but only the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Plus model" href="https://amzn.to/3zRRcSi">Plus model</a> actually meets Sony’s requirements, so be sure you’re looking at the correct model before you buy. The Rocket 4 Plus’ heatsink is too chunky to fit in the PS5, so you’ll again have to fit your own cooling solution. Sabrent typically has aggressive pricing, but as of writing the Plus hasn’t seen any major discounts. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1TB model" href="https://amzn.to/3zRRcSi">1TB model</a> can be found at around $180, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:2TB" href="https://amzn.to/3BYj4px">2TB</a> $360 and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:4TB" href="https://amzn.to/3z4Ru8k">4TB</a> for $900.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3zRRcSi" id="4b9bf147271449d9a2048fe0910d6473" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Sabrent Rocket 4 Plus at Amazon - $180</a><h2>How to install an SSD in a PS5</h2><p>As of writing, the first thing you’ll need to install an SSD is access to the semi-closed system software beta. From an admittedly small sample, I’ve yet to hear of people being denied access to this; everyone I know who&#39;s applied was accepted within a week. You can enroll <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps5/ps5-beta-program-sign-up/">here</a> if you’re in the US, or you can google “PlayStation 5 System Software Beta Program sign-up” to find your local sign-up link.</p><p>Once you have the beta on your PS5, installation of a PS5 SSD is fairly straightforward. Sony recommends a #1 Phillips or crosshead screwdriver, but this isn&#39;t rocket science. Any crossed screwdriver of similar size will do fine.</p><p>Begin by powering down your PS5, unplugging everything, removing the stand and flipping it over to its underside. If you have the regular PS5, that’s the side with the disc drive, if you have the Digital Edition, it’s the side without the PlayStation logo cutout.</p><p>Sony has a video guide to popping off the outside cover <a href="https://youtu.be/CaAY-jAjm0w?t=133">here</a>, but the gist is you gently lift up the opposing corners and slide the panel towards the flat end of the console. There’s a knack to this, and it requires very little effort or strength. If you’re not getting it, rather than force it just readjust your grip and try again. A member of our video team managed to break one of the tabs on our review unit doing this last November so… yeah, don’t force it.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/ebf0c2f0-01b7-11ec-afbf-853a752af0d1" alt="Sony PlayStation 5 SSD slot" data-uuid="7398e559-d696-3bd4-a7d9-cd721de48919"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Once you’ve got everything open, you’ll see a rectangular piece of metal with a screw holding it in place. Remove that screw, and you’ll be able to access the drive bay.</p><p>You’ll see five holes inside, each numbered corresponding to the standard SSD drive lengths I mentioned earlier. The one numbered 110 will have a metal insert and screw inside. You need to unscrew the screw with a screwdriver, and then unscrew the insert with your fingers and move it to the relevant hole. Your eyes should tell you which is the right one for your drive, but it’s most likely going to be 80.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e67cea90-01b4-11ec-bbfb-4b7c19b43bb9" alt="PlayStation 5 SSD slot" data-uuid="b2916301-d0af-3271-9358-25c34f3b604e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Aaron Souppouris/Engadget</div></figure><p>Then take your SSD — mine is a 980 Pro I bought on Prime Day with a $2 piece of aluminum attached to the top — and slot it in. The slot is at the edge closest to the number “30,” and SSDs are keyed to only fit in one way, so again, no force is required. If it’s not sliding in, don’t force it. You’ll notice the SSD doesn’t sit flat — that’s fine, and is as intended.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/cbfb0a40-01b8-11ec-affd-fd9517dd0c1c" alt="Sony PlayStation 5 SSD upgrade" data-uuid="0e1237c5-5456-36b6-9c2d-d372b49da727"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Once the SSD is seated, take the screw you removed from the insert, line it up with the little notch at the end of your SSD, and push down so it meets the insert. Give the screw it a few turns — it doesn’t need to be very tight — and you’re done.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4dcf1fc0-01b9-11ec-a75f-13723fe12887" alt="Sony PlayStation 5 SSD upgrade" data-uuid="8d923548-517c-3d99-af3f-2e4d23bc98ab"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Replace the metal cover and screw it down, and then slide the plastic outer shell back on. When you first turn on the PS5, it’ll prompt you to format the drive. Do that! You have now successfully expanded your console’s storage, and can set about downloading and moving games to it. Personally, I moved all of the PS4 games I had to the new drive, along with all of my clips and screenshots. The PS5’s built-in SSD is always going to be the most compliant, so I’m keeping my important stuff there.&nbsp;</p><p>We&#39;ll be updating this guide as more SSDs come to market and onto our test bench, so feel free to bookmark it for when you need it.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-ps5-ssd-expansion-upgrade-150052315.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e75133dc-8c16-459b-9bf8-6f3892cd7c77</guid><dc:creator>Aaron Souppouris</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629470247</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T14:37:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Aaron Souppouris]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e67cea90-01b4-11ec-bbfb-4b7c19b43bb9" width="2560" height="1621" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e67cea90-01b4-11ec-bbfb-4b7c19b43bb9" width="2560" height="1621" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Aaron Souppouris/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 SSD slot]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 SSD slot]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stunning 'Black Myth: Wukong' trailer shows off Unreal Engine 5 gameplay with DLSS on]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A year after it wowed many with its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/back-myth-wu-kong-trailer-193209475.html"><ins>first gameplay video</ins></a>, Chinese developer Game Science Studio is back with an even more impressive look at <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>. The studio has switched from Unreal Engine 4 to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/unreal-engine-5-early-access-152553496.html"><ins>UE5</ins></a> for the action RPG. <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/news/black-myth-wukong-geforce-rtx-unreal-engine-5-nvidia-dlss-trailer/"><ins>According to NVIDIA</ins></a>, it&#39;s the first peek at a UE5 game that uses Deep Learning Super Sampling (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/dlss"><ins>DLSS</ins></a>), the company&#39;s AI-powered upscaling tech.</p><div id="b25c978a06204b3b91be2a10498e5b57"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TRDCCKiUSWo?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The 12-minute preview, which you can watch in 4K at 60 frames per second, shows off much more action from the game. It features a couple of stunning boss fights, including one with an electric dragon on a frozen lake. The visuals here are eye-popping: expect buttery-smooth animations, gorgeous environments and dazzling snow and ice effects.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>Black Myth: Wukong </em>is based on the story of the Monkey King and the <em>Journey to the West</em>. Game Science Studio seems to have taken inspiration from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sekiro-shadows-die-twice-free-fall-update-213843186.html"><em><ins>Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</ins></em></a> here, but that&#39;s hardly a bad thing. The gameplay and creature design certainly draw from the Souls-like approach popularized by From Software — for instance, you see the protagonist evading the terrible beasts&#39; attacks while looking for an opportunity to leap in with their staff.&nbsp;</p><p>The studio was formed by a group of former Tencent Games employees, according to prominent games industry analyst Daniel Ahmad. There&#39;s no confirmed release window as yet for <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>. Game Science Studio said last year it was aiming to bring the game to PC (which is a sure bet given the DLSS support) and consoles by 2023.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/black-myth-wukong-trailer-unreal-engine-5-dlss-144528378.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">16e2d1b0-8e74-4430-a72e-f3732cb4b2cc</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:45:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629469598</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T14:26:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d35b7e20-01c0-11ec-bede-e18ec250d796" width="1919" height="953" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d35b7e20-01c0-11ec-bede-e18ec250d796" width="1919" height="953" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Game Science Studio]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple has a new app for collecting feedback on Siri]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While Apple may have released Siri before Google Assistant and Amazon Alexa, in many ways its voice-activated assistant is the least advanced of the three. A lot of that has to do with the amount of data and training digital assistants need to understand different languages, dialects and speech patterns. In an effort to improve its digital assistant, Apple recently launched a study to collect speech data and feedback with the help of an app called <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1564003829"><ins>Siri Speech Study</ins></a>.</p><p>“The Siri Speech Study app allows participants to send certain data to Apple for product improvement, as detailed in the informed consent form,” the company says in a listing spotted by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/"><em><ins>TechCrunch</ins></em></a>. The software is available in the US, Canada, Germany, France, Hong Kong, India, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Mexico, New Zealand and Taiwan. According to data from analytics firm Sensor Tower, Apple uploaded Siri Speech Study to the App Store on August 9th, and recently updated the software on August 18th.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Apple isn’t being exactly secretive about the app, but nor is it advertising its existence either. You can’t find the software by searching for it, nor is it listed as one of the apps published by Apple. Similarly, you can’t join the study simply by installing the software on your phone; you need an invite from Apple to participate. We&#39;ve reached out to Apple for more information on the app.&nbsp;</p><p>Notably, the app allows those involved to choose what Siri requests they send to the company. That&#39;s an important point. In 2019, <em>The Guardian </em><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jul/26/apple-contractors-regularly-hear-confidential-details-on-siri-recordings"><ins>published a report</ins></a> that detailed an Apple program where third-party contractors listened to anonymized Siri recordings to analyze the assistant’s responses. A whistleblower told the outlet there had been “countless instances” where graders listened to private conversations, including some that involved criminal dealings and sexual encounters. Apple subsequently moved the program in-house, and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-28-apple-siri-recording-user-data-changes.html?utm_medium=newsletter&amp;utm_source=morningafter"><ins>switched to opt-in transcripts</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/siri-speech-study-app-142022577.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e4034658-9dcb-4dda-a951-17fff3dee3ed</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:20:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629469227</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T14:20:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/ff858b80-b4af-11ea-b7ef-b4112c8cdda8" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/ff858b80-b4af-11ea-b7ef-b4112c8cdda8" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[iOS 14 Siri interface]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[iOS 14 Siri interface]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung's Galaxy Buds Pro are 37 percent off at B&H Photo]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While Samsung redesigned the latest <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-150002889.html">Galaxy Buds 2</a> with the budget-conscious in mind, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy Buds Pro" href="https://fave.co/2W5cLk6">Galaxy Buds Pro</a> are its complete-package wireless earbuds. They debuted in January and we found them to be Samsung&#39;s best wireless earbuds to date — but they&#39;re also the company&#39;s most expensive at $200. But B&amp;H Photo has a limited-time sale going on right now that knocks 37 percent off the buds, bringing them down to $127. That&#39;s close to an all-time low and a great price on the most premium Samsung earbuds.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/2W5cLk6" id="f564968e9ff54704af6d6798375a435d" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Galaxy Buds Pro at B&amp;H - $127</a><p>Samsung had many iterations of its earbuds before the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-review-163027027.html">Galaxy Buds Pro</a> came along, and it took all previous criticism to hear when designing the Pros. They have a compact, comfortable design with an IPX7 waterproof rating, so you could use them while working out. Active noise-cancellation is solid, blocking out sounds from things like running dishwashers well, and Android users can download the companion mobile app to change noise-cancellation settings.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The mobile app also lets you do things like enable hands-free Bixby and disable voice detection, which will automatically lower the volume and switch to ambient sound mode when you&#39;re speaking. We were also impressed by the buds&#39; sound quality — the 11mm woofer handles the low-end well and highs are crisp and punchy. The Galaxy Buds Pro also support 360 Audio, which is Samsung&#39;s equivalent to Apple&#39;s Spatial Audio on AirPods Pro.</p><p>As far as battery life goes, it&#39;s decent but nothing to write home about. You&#39;ll get roughly 18 hours of listening time out of the buds, and that includes the extra charges carried by its case. We do like that the case supports wireless charging, though, so you can sit them on any Qi pad in your home to get extra juice. These remains the most premium earbuds you can get from Samsung, and considering B&amp;H&#39;s sale makes them more affordable than even the new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Galaxy Buds 2" href="https://amzn.to/3k98kfR">Galaxy Buds 2</a>, it&#39;s a solid buy if you want the best Samsung has to offer.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-limited-time-deal-bh-photo-124159210.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c343fb46-225b-4c0c-a74d-af4f78f4582a</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:41:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629463321</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T12:42:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/a6a069b0-5746-11eb-bf77-06c3b850750f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/a6a069b0-5746-11eb-bf77-06c3b850750f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro review]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro review]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast: Reviewing Samsung's Galaxy Z Flip 3, Fold 3 and the Pixel 5a]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, Cherlynn and Devindra are joined by Washington Post Staff Writer (and former Engadget colleague) Chris Velazco to dive into all of the latest phone reviews. What’s up with Samsung’s Galaxy Z Flip 3 and Fold 3? Who needs the Pixel 5a? And why did Qualcomm try to make a phone of its own? Tune in for our discussion, as well as to find out what you should be looking for in your next phone upgrade.</p><p>Listen below, or subscribe on your podcast app of choice. If you&#39;ve got suggestions or topics you&#39;d like covered on the show, be sure to <a href="mailto:podcast@engadget.com?subject=Engadget%20Podcast%20Feedback"><strong>email us</strong></a> or drop a note in the comments! And be sure to check out our other podcasts, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-01-engadget-podcasts.html">Morning After and Engadget News</a>!</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="undefined"><iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1109289202&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/reviewing-all-the-phones-samsungs-foldables-pixel-5a" title="Reviewing ALL the phones: Samsung&#x002019;s foldables, Pixel 5a" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Reviewing ALL the phones: Samsung’s foldables, Pixel 5a</a></div></div><h2><br>Subscribe!</h2><ul><li><p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-engadget-podcast/id1142790530?mt=2">iTunes</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3EC3dMIRB99dkvoSBeSO7G?si=f7UALGKmRDWtOrU8Z4-uiQ">Spotify</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://pca.st/mlY3">Pocket Casts</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/engadget/the-engadget-podcast">Stitcher</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://podcasts.google.com/?feed=aHR0cDovL2ZlZWRzLnNvdW5kY2xvdWQuY29tL3VzZXJzL3NvdW5kY2xvdWQ6dXNlcnM6MjQ1MjIwOTU4L3NvdW5kcy5yc3M&amp;ep=14">Google Podcasts</a></p></li></ul><h2><br><strong>Topics</strong><br></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/8aa18c60-012a-11ec-bfcf-70c9110e3192" style="height:1080;width:1920;" alt="Facebook Horizon Workrooms" data-uuid="069fb176-9e14-394a-9a1d-abe6981ac4d3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Facebook</div></figure><ul><li><p>The current state of 5G coverage and what we expect from mobile hardware season – 2:17</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 3 </a>and Fold 3: final reviews – 13:55</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-a-review-android-midrange-5g-smartphone-160051630.html">Pixel 5a review</a>: a great buy for most people – 39:26</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-for-snapdragon-insiders-review-140014488.html">Smartphone for Snapdragon Insiders (it’s bad)</a> – 45:02</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-horizon-workrooms-oculus-vr-meeting-collaboration-110018369.html">Facebook gets into VR meetings with Horizon Workrooms </a>– 52:19</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-twitter-taliban-afghanistan-content-151603761.html">What do social platforms do now that the Taliban is Afghanistan’s governing party? </a>– 1:02:56</p></li><li><p>CES 2022 is happening…maybe – 1:08:35</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/onlyfans-announces-the-launch-of-oftv-a-new-streaming-platform-and-app-301356960.html">OnlyFans announces SFW branch </a>(and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/onlyfans-sexually-explicit-content-ban-184819350.html">announced they’re banning most NSFW</a>) – 1:13:14</p></li><li><p>Working on – 1:17:13</p></li><li><p>Pop culture picks – 1:20:07</p></li></ul><h2><br>Video livestream</h2><div id="55487695a3014bdb9acf4bb77adb2044"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2zhK3llEwPg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p><strong><em>Credits</em></strong><br><em>Hosts: Cherlynn Low and Devindra Hardawar</em><br><em>Guest: Chris Velazco</em><br><em>Producer: Ben Ellman</em><br><em>Livestream producers: Julio Barrientos, Owen Davidoff</em>, <em>Luke Brooks</em><br><em>Graphics artists: Luke Brooks, Kyle Maack</em><br><em>Music: Dale North and Terrence O&#39;Brien</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/engadget-podcast-samsung-flip-3-fold-3-reviews-123025925.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">efbcfd08-64e3-4724-9c42-b74d4b1c8e65</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629431449</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T03:51:08+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c8e851c0-2b3d-11eb-baea-6c6fe29971fb" width="703" height="469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/f43b53b0-909f-11ea-87fd-d8d721459924" width="1600" height="719" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NASA puts SpaceX's lunar lander contract on hold following Blue Origin's lawsuit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX won&#39;t be working on its $2.9 billion lunar lander contract for a while after NASA agreed to put the project on hold. The space agency told <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/nasa-temporarily-halts-work-lunar-lander-contract-pending-court-case-2021-08-19/"><em>Reuters</em></a> that it temporarily ceased all work on the project after Jeff Bezos&#39; company Blue Origin <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-federal-claims-court-nasa-challenge-163927526.html">filed a complaint</a> against it with the US Court of Federal Claims. &quot;In exchange for this temporary stay of work, all parties agreed to an expedited litigation schedule that concludes on November 1st,&quot; the space agency said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p>Blue Origin sued NASA over its decision to award a lunar lander contract to SpaceX alone when it originally planned to award two contracts. The agency historically works with more than one contractor for each mission to ensure that it can launch in time. However, it only received a fraction of the budget it requested for the Artemis lunar lander, which will be designed to carry human astronauts to the surface of the moon from the Orion spacecraft, and chose to forgo awarding a second contract.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Bezos&#39; company first <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-blue-origin-225547469.html">challenged</a> the decision back in April and filed a protest with the Government Accountability Office. As <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632990/spacex-lunar-lander-contract-paused-blue-origin-nasa-lawsuit"><em>The Verge</em></a> notes, that complaint put the SpaceX contract on hold for 95 days, so this is the second time NASA and Elon Musk&#39;s company have to temporarily halt the project. Blue Origin argued that the selection process was unfair, because it wasn&#39;t given the opportunity to revise its bid like SpaceX was able to.&nbsp;</p><p>GAO ultimately <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gao-denies-blue-origin-dynetics-protest-nasa-human-landing-system-181019362.html">dismissed</a> the case, concluding that NASA&#39;s evaluation of all the proposals for the mission &quot;was reasonable and consistent with applicable procurement law, regulation, and the announcement&#39;s terms.&quot; Before GAO revealed its decision, though, Jeff Bezos <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-nasa-open-letter-181522642.html">wrote</a> an open letter to NASA, telling the agency that Blue Origin is willing to waive up to $2 billion in payments in return for a fixed-price lander contract.&nbsp;</p><p>In both of the lawsuits it filed, Blue Origin said it&#39;s making &quot;an attempt to remedy the flaws in the acquisition process found in NASA&#39;s Human Landing System.&quot; For its more recent complaint, the company explained that it &quot;stand[s] firm in [its] belief that there were fundamental issues with NASA&#39;s decision, but the GAO wasn&#39;t able to address them due to their limited jurisdiction.&quot; We&#39;ll know soon enough which side the court will pick: A judge has set a hearing for the case on October 14th.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nasa-spacex-lunar-lander-on-hold-blue-origin-lawsuit-120527376.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">879e2f05-c235-44cf-9e4e-a5cdfebf0781</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:05:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629459877</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T11:44:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/2193a790-01a1-11ec-9dfd-dafc76faa5db" width="1600" height="996" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/2193a790-01a1-11ec-9dfd-dafc76faa5db" width="1600" height="996" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Neon Genesis Evangelion’ is coming to Blu-ray in the US for the first time]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If streaming the Neon Genesis Evangelion saga on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-22-evangelion-netflix.html">Netflix</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-evangelion-rebuild-movie-release-date-115525221.html">Amazon Prime Video</a> has made you an acolyte of the hit anime, then we have good news. The original series is <a href="https://store.gkids.com/pages/neon-genesis-evangelion?utm_source=gkids&amp;utm_medium=vanity&amp;utm_campaign=gkidseva&amp;utm_id=NGE">coming to Blu-Ray</a> for the first time in North America.&nbsp;</p><div id="649edfef922d4534b0aea78b28ea98e0"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Own the legendary series NEON GENESIS EVANGELION on Blu-ray in North America for the first time ever with the Ultimate Edition.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EVANGELIONUltimate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#EVANGELIONUltimate</a><br>Pre-order: <a href="https://t.co/MN2UaY6NEs">https://t.co/MN2UaY6NEs</a><a href="https://t.co/BOS9dESRFy">pic.twitter.com/BOS9dESRFy</a></p>— GKIDS Films (@GKIDSfilms) <a href="https://twitter.com/GKIDSfilms/status/1428386524731641860?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>But, this isn&#39;t just a regular physical release. Billed as &quot;Neon Genesis Evangelion: Ultimate Edition,&quot; the box set is spread across 11 discs, contains over 7 hours of bonus features, along with extras that span a 156 page book, art boards and limited edition artwork, a Sachiel resin paperweight and a NERV ID Card with lanyard.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The release includes the official and classic dubs and subtitled versions, plus the follow-up films, <em>Evangelion: Death (True)²</em> and <em>The End of Evangelion</em>. All of that will cost you $275 during the current pre-order period, which ends December 7th. Afterwards, you&#39;ll have to fork out $350 for the special release. As of now, the Blu-Ray is listed as sold out in the US, probably because fans quickly snapped up the 5,000 copies that were available. Though it still appears to be in stock in the UK, where it&#39;s limited to just 2,500 copies.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/80b7b140-01a0-11ec-8776-a8d9a116aa8a" style="height:1204;width:1200;" alt="GKIDS Films" data-uuid="4e7767a7-68c3-3e54-a4ae-114118f4e9c6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">GKIDS Films</div></figure><p>Despite all the riches on offer, what you won&#39;t get here is the series&#39; &quot;Fly me to the Moon&quot; ending theme, likely due to licensing issues. As fans will know, the song was also missing from <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em> on Netflix. The streamer opted to replace it with &quot;Hostility Restrained&quot; from the show&#39;s score. Those feeling wistful can listen to it in the video below.&nbsp;</p><div id="1043e931e8f341debb4f9ba8e5c928eb"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4S6STxv9LDE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/neon-genesis-evangelion-blu-ray-us-114530370.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5bd34d4c-451e-4dec-ab7c-f75127c9e627</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:45:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1629456424</ingested><modified>2021-08-20T10:47:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Conglomerates]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/fe74c270-01a1-11ec-bad5-9c379382cfb7" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/fe74c270-01a1-11ec-bad5-9c379382cfb7" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Neon Genesis Evangelion]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Neon Genesis Evangelion]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Neon Genesis Evangelion]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>