<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2022</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's 2022 Quantum Dot OLED TVs can tweak quality settings using a camera]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony thinks it knows how to counter the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-oled-g2-c2-annoucement-020045964.html">latest OLED</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-2022-qled-microled-8k-4k-tv-020046596.html">mini-LED</a> TVs from its rivals: add a dash of intelligence. Its 2022 A-series 4K OLED TVs, plus its Z- (8K) and X-series (4K) mini-LED and basic LCD models, can use a new Bravia Cam (the &#39;bump&#39; shown at top) for video chat, gesture control and even optimizing the picture and sound quality. They can tweak the brightness, voice emphasis and sound balance based on your viewing distance and direction. You can also have the picture dim when you leave the room, or display a warning when your kids get too close to the screen.</p><p>The camera is bundled with the flagship <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/televisions/all-tvs/p/xr65a95k">A95K</a> and <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/televisions/all-tvs/p/xr75z9k">Z9K</a> models, and is optional for Sony&#39;s other 2022 sets. You&#39;ll need a firmware update to unlock more than video chat, but the company hasn&#39;t said when that might arrive. And yes, Sony is aware of privacy concerns. There&#39;s a hardware switch to disable the camera, and neither the camera nor the TV will store private data. You can delete any positional data through the TV menu.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/f84e6be0-6d6b-11ec-afef-2942f6fa5981" style="height:1280;width:1920;" alt="Sony Bravia Z9K mini-LED 8K TV" data-uuid="10b30ad4-ca06-3830-b164-d3786efc2230"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>The new TVs improve image and sound quality whether or not the camera is present. The A95K uses a new Quantum Dot OLED panel to reproduce a larger color range at wider viewing angles, while the Z9K and X95K have smarter backlighting that reduces mini-LED&#39;s characteristic light blooming without lowering brightness. A Netflix Adaptive Calibrated Mode adjusts output based on ambient light, while Bravia Core Calibrated Mode alters quality to match a director&#39;s &quot;original vision.&quot; And yes, there&#39;s tight integration with other Sony products — they can harmonize with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-preorder-163641637.html">higher-end soundbars</a> and speakers (the built-in speakers are also richer), while <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-review-130048353.html">PlayStation 5</a> owners can take advantage of both automatic picture mode switching as well as auto HDR tone mapping.</p><p>Other improvements include a switch to the unified, media-centric <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chromecast-with-google-tv-review-163024220.html">Google TV</a> interface and smaller, simpler remotes that add backlighting and a find-my-remote feature. A95K uses also have a stand that can sit at the front or back to suit your viewing environment.</p><p>Sony won&#39;t provide pricing and ship dates until the spring, but it&#39;s using a familiar size strategy. The Z9K is unsurprisingly limited to 8K-friendly 75- and 85-inch sizes, while the A95K sits in the sweet spot with 55- and 65-inch variants. The A90K is built for gamers&#39; desks and dorm rooms with 42- and 48-inch sizes (and an optional high position stand), while the &#39;entry&#39; A80K courts the mainstream with 55-, 65- and 77-inch panels. The X95K comes in 65-, 75- and 85-inch flavors, while the full array LED-lit X90K comes in 55-, 65-, 75- and 85-inch versions. The X80K and X85K have &#39;just&#39; direct LED backlighting, but are available in a wide range of sizes from 43 inches through to 85 inches.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-2022-oled-mini-led-google-tv-lineup-150041942.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dc33959c-9b6a-47c0-9cc4-7b2e36673af3</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641307825</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T14:50:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e24eaec0-6d63-11ec-ad8d-7d72c1737289" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e24eaec0-6d63-11ec-ad8d-7d72c1737289" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony Bravia A95K OLED TV with camera]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony Bravia A95K OLED TV with camera]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony is bringing 360-degree sound mapping to its latest soundbars]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Sony debuted its premium home theater gear for 2021, the company&#39;s pricey <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-ht-a9-home-theater-system-140038379.html">HT-A9 speaker set</a> had a key feature that its soundbars didn&#39;t. It&#39;s called 360 Spatial Sound Mapping and it creates &quot;phantom speakers&quot; to help the actual speakers produce room-filling sound. Today at CES, Sony announced that it will offer an upgrade to both the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-ht-a9-home-theater-system-140038379.html">HT-A7000</a> (7.1.2) and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a5000-soundbar-announced-specs-price-availability-140034265.html">HT-A5000</a> (5.1.2) soundbars that adds the 360-degree audio mapping later this spring.&nbsp;</p><p>360 Spatial Sound Mapping first uses a combination of Sound Field Optimization tech and built-in microphones to measure the height and position of both a soundbar and rear speakers. Once that&#39;s done, the setup creates virtual speakers by positioning sound waves based on the collected location information. Sony says the result is a &quot;wide spatial sound field&quot; capable of filling a room and it promises that everyone will get &quot;the same sound experience&quot; no matter where they&#39;re sitting. The company also reminded us that an Acoustic Center Sync feature on Bravia XR TVs will work with the sound mapping to become a center speaker that enhances dialogue. Both the A7000 and A5000 already support <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-360-reality-audio-ces-2021-130027671.html">Sony&#39;s 360 Reality Audio</a> for more immersive music listening.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/72b05150-6d03-11ec-aeaf-cceeaae020f2" style="height:1000;width:1600;" alt="Sony SA-RS5 speakers" data-uuid="03615776-e7af-3557-857c-5df45308b64c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>To help you make the most out of the soundbars&#39; new ability, Sony is debuting a new set of wireless rear speakers. Unlike most rear satellites that connect wirelessly but rely on a cord for power, <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/audio/soundbars/all-soundbars/p/sars5">the new SA-RS5 speakers</a> are totally wireless and can be charged out of sight. The company says you can expect up to 10 hours of use when they&#39;re fully charged and 10 minutes will give you 90 minutes of play time if you forget to replenish the batteries. They also feature up-firing speakers, wide directional woofers, dome tweeters and dual passive radiators for a more robust soundstage and better clarity. The SA-RS5 can run Sony&#39;s Sound Field Optimization with the press of a button so they&#39;re easily calibrated with your soundbar each time you reposition them. Lastly, the cylindrical speakers have a flat back side so they&#39;ll sit nicely against a wall.&nbsp;</p><p>You&#39;ll need a set of rear speakers to employ the forthcoming 360 Spatial Sound Mapping upgrade on the aforementioned soundbars — hence the new model. If you can live without all the bells and whistles of the SA-RS5, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-ht-a9-home-theater-system-140038379.html">SA-RS3S</a> is also compatible. They&#39;re a plain ol&#39; set of two-way rear satellite speakers in comparison, but they&#39;ll save you some money over the upcoming model at $350. And <a href="https://www.engadget.com/home-entertainment-gift-ideas-143038506.html">based on my experience</a>, they should get the job done just fine.&nbsp;</p><p>The new SA-RS5 wireless rear speakers will be available this spring for $600. That&#39;s $250 more than the SA-RS3S that debuted alongside the HT-A7000 last year.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-360-spatial-sound-mapping-update-ht-a7000-ht-a5000-150035957.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">97f90428-b87f-4750-b202-a37848794198</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641265431</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T03:03:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Speakers & Headphones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/cff960a0-e904-11eb-a7ff-cc0e36ef054f" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/cff960a0-e904-11eb-a7ff-cc0e36ef054f" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony HT-A7000 soundbar, SA-SW5 subwoofer, SA-SW3 subwoofer and SA-RS3S speakers.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony HT-A7000 soundbar]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's Mac Mini M1 is $50 off at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While we saw the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Mac Mini M1" href="https://amzn.to/3JFEqMj">Mac Mini M1</a> drop in price during the holiday shopping season, you have another chance to grab the desktop for less right now. Amazon has the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for $649, or $50 less than usual. It&#39;s not a record low — the machine dropped to $570 last month thanks to a sale combined with an addition coupon — but it&#39;s a noteworthy discount for this time of year in which most gadgets return to normal prices after the seasonal rush.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3JFEqMj" id="0efeded9dd8042bc9be0554396349d9f" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Mac Mini M1 at Amazon - $649</a><p>The Mac Mini M1 runs on the same processor as the latest <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-140031323.html">MacBook Air</a>, which means you should notice a big improvement in performance, especially if you&#39;re coming from an aging device. It has an eight-core CPU and an eight-core GPU, along with a Neural Engine that handles machine-learning tasks. In our experience with the Air, the M1 chipset was blazing fast, helping sites load almost instantly and running native apps smoothly. And you&#39;ll get all of that in the most affordable M1 machine if you go with the Mac Mini — even at its normal price of $699, the Mini is $300 cheaper than the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:$999 MacBook Air" href="https://amzn.to/34kZGqy">$999 MacBook Air</a>, making it a good option for those who don&#39;t want to break the bank while investing in a newer, faster computer.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you appreciated the minimalist design of previous Mac Minis, you&#39;ll like the latest model because it hasn&#39;t changed much. Its silver exterior is only interrupted on one edge by the machine&#39;s port array, which includes two Thunderbolt ports, two USB-A connectors, an HDMI port, an Ethernet port and a 3.5mm headphone jack. If you&#39;ve been itching to update your family&#39;s computer, or you just want to add a capable desktop to your home without spending too much money, this sale on the Mac Mini M1 is worth considering.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apples-mac-mini-m1-is-50-off-at-amazon-140511856.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">55d836a9-2f45-4c20-8790-5f4d71961963</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:05:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641304713</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:58:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Finance Trading]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/b90d6ba0-e088-11ea-bf7d-559c3cbc732c" width="1600" height="1069" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/b90d6ba0-e088-11ea-bf7d-559c3cbc732c" width="1600" height="1069" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple Mac mini]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Mac mini]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TCL's affordable 30 Series phones are coming to Verizon and T-Mobile]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TCL continues its tradition of launching a barrage of devices at CES, and it’s a similar story to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tcl-20-pro-5g-tcl-20l-plus-tcl-20l-cheap-phones-150041628.html"><ins>last year,</ins></a>  with two new 30 series smartphones headed to the US later this year.</p><p>Let’s start with the TCL 30 XE 5G. It has a 6.52-inch display at 1,600 x 720 resolution and up to 90Hz refresh rate. With a 4,500mAh battery, it runs on one of Mediatek’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mediatek-5g-nr-dimensity-820-processor-070036831.html">Dimensity chips</a>, the Dimensity 700, which have been designed to work better with AI tasks like image processing.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Talking of images, there’s a triple camera system, but no need to get too excited. There’s a depth sensor and a 2-megapixel camera, meaning that most of the work will be done by the single 13-megapixel main camera sensor. It’ll be able to record video up to 1080p – another reminder that these are affordable phones first, impressive specs are less of a priority. Much less.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b7ff7a60-6d44-11ec-bd7f-b614bba4a971" style="height:1496;width:2120;" alt="TCL 30 series 2022" data-uuid="0dedf598-33b6-30ba-8c22-158de1c5bab5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">TCL</div></figure><p>The TCL 30 V has a bigger 6.67-inch display, running at 1,080 x 2,400 resolution. That’s more pixels than the 30 XE, but lacks the 90Hz refresh rate. Compromises! It runs on a Qualcomm Snapdragon 480 chip — again different to the XE – with a more substantial 50-megapixel primary camera working alongside a 5MP super-wide shooter and a 2MP macro lens. Unlike the notched front-facing camera of the 30 XE, the bigger 30 V has a pinhole in the screen for its 16MP selfie cam. It also has a 4,500mAh battery which should ensure it lasts the day, given the lightweight specs of the device. Both devices are coming exclusively to the US, but on different carriers. The TCL 30 XE 5G launches on T Mobile – date TBC – while the 30 V is landing on Verizon.</p><p>Adoption from two US carriers will make TCL&#39;s phones a more realistic option than in previous years.  However, we’re missing one big piece of the puzzle: how affordable they actually are. Expect to hear pricing in the coming weeks. If you’re looking for bigger specs (and prices, possibly), TCL is teasing more 30 series news at MWC in Barcelona later this year.</p><p></p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tcl-30-series-ces-2022-smartphones-launch-date-price-140051967.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">56c6ca9c-594a-40e2-823c-f38ad7251898</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641295343</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T11:22:26+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b8017630-6d44-11ec-9e7f-170f0b0e36eb" width="2126" height="1500" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b8017630-6d44-11ec-9e7f-170f0b0e36eb" width="2126" height="1500" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[TCL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[TCL 30 series 2022]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TCL 30 series 2022]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seoul Robotics' autonomous 'Control Tower' remotely manages self-driving vehicle fleets]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite Tesla&#39;s ambitious claims of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-full-self-driving-10-beta-145035031.html">its vehicles&#39; Full Self-Driving capabilities</a>, today&#39;s autonomous navigation technology generally tops out at <a href="https://www.synopsys.com/automotive/autonomous-driving-levels.html">Level 2</a>. More advanced self-driving systems are in development but likely still years away from being safe and cost-effective enough for everyday use. Seoul Robotics, however, has developed a mesh network that reportedly imparts Level 5 autonomy to vehicle fleets, if only for the &quot;last mile.&quot;</p><p>The company&#39;s Level 5 Control Tower system sidesteps some technical challenges of self-driving technology by embedding sensors in the surrounding infrastructure — traffic lights, nearby buildings, freeway overpasses, etc — rather than on the vehicles themselves. Instead of each vehicle looking out for itself and responding autonomously to surrounding traffic, the Level 5 Control Tower uses its meshed sensor network to collect data on the overall traffic situation and automate vehicles in the area accordingly, using V2X communications and 4/5G radios.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/75e07d70-6d15-11ec-bd13-b75397c8adda" style="height:748;width:1018;" alt="LVL 5 CTRL TWR" data-uuid="830176dd-5d0b-353b-8c74-e9117bb02bee"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Seoul Robotics</div></figure><p>“Ultimately, these systems will be deployed in additional public and business settings, powering aspects of our everyday lives, such as autonomously navigated parking and public transit,&quot; HanBin Lee, CEO of Seoul Robotics, said in a prepared statement Tuesday. Eventually the technology could find its way to a number of commercial applications from vehicle distribution centers to car rental lots.&nbsp;</p><p>BMW is currently trialling the system to manage fleet logistics at its manufacturing facility in Munich. That system utilizes Seoul Robotics&#39; SENSR software and a network of hundreds of LiDAR sensors embedded around the facility to autonomously move newly-constructed vehicles across the factory floor. Because the system has vantage points from virtually every angle, rather than the half dozen or so sensors on the vehicle itself, Control Tower can easily guide individual vehicles around blind spots and through cross traffic — even while simultaneously &quot;driving&quot; hundreds of other automotive drones.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-level-5-control-tower-is-a-puppet-master-for-autonomous-vehicle-fleets-140041909.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b9449a3a-5ab8-4733-a9ca-67cfcd6b5fea</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641270215</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T04:23:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-03/9af28970-6df6-11ea-bdfe-fc7d6d7d78c3" width="5465" height="3641" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2020-03/9af28970-6df6-11ea-bdfe-fc7d6d7d78c3" width="5465" height="3641" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Jackal Pan via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Aerial view new cars lined up in the port for import and export]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TCL's Nxtwear Air cinema glasses are lighter and more stylish]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TCL has been banging on the Personal Cinema door for quite some time, first with a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tcl-project-archery-version-3-111504533.html">series of</a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-07-tcl-personal-cinema-visor-prototype.html?">concept devices</a> and, last year, with its first commercially-available model. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tcl-nxtwear-g-wearable-display-140057578.html">The Nxtwear G</a>, which I reviewed in the summer, was the best personal cinema I’ve ever tested, but it still had some major flaws. The biggest was comfort, both for eye-strain and the problem of resting a 130 gram (4.5oz) piece of hardware on your nose. Thankfully, it looks as if TCL has sought to address that issue with its second model, the TCL Nxtwear Air.</p><p>Essentially, the TCL Nxtwear Air takes many of the same components from the first one, but has managed to shave off around a third of the weight. The glasses now weigh 75 grams, and look to be a lot more stylish than the first model, including interchangeable fascias to customize the glasses to your style. As much as I’d loathe adding more weight to my face, I do quite like the look of the faux-Wayfarer panel.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Far as I can tell, the displays remain the same: Two 1080p Micro OLED panels designed to replicate the feel of a 140-inch screen. The press release does, however, say that color reproduction has been improved, since the pictures on the first model were occasionally washed out. You’ll also get spatial audio, and given the speakers are sited in the arms, that sounds like a smart improvement for movie watching.</p><p>Naturally, TCL isn’t talking about when we can get our hands on one, or how much it’ll cost when we actually do. But if it’s less than the frankly outrageous prices you had to fork out for the first model, it’ll be a good start.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tcl-nxtwear-air-ces-2022-140023313.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">09278745-1081-4a21-993b-28e62b72ab0e</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641299620</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T12:33:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/38ee6560-6d58-11ec-bdb5-9c1e65b5e71d" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/38ee6560-6d58-11ec-bdb5-9c1e65b5e71d" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[TCL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[TCL Nxtwear Air (2022)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TCL Nxtwear Air]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TCL's first laptop is the $349 Book 14 Go]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TCL, which is mostly known for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tcl-update-fixes-google-tv-performance-issues-103044084.html">TVs</a> and other electronics, has launched its very first laptop called the Book 14 Go. It&#39;s a 14.1-inch Windows 11 laptop that&#39;s powered by a Qualcomm Snapdragon chip, with a 12-hour battery life and 4G LTE connectivity. While Snapdragon laptops are traditionally on the pricier side, the Book 14 Go will only set you back $349 when it launches in select regions in the second quarter.&nbsp;</p><p>The company was likely able to keep its price down, in part because it&#39;s powered by Qualcomm&#39;s affordable <a href="https://www.engadget.com/qualcomm-snapdragon-7c-gen-2-165508430.html">Snapdragon 7c</a> platform meant for use with entry-level PCs and Chromebooks. Snapdragon 7c enables both LTE connectivity and lengthy battery life for laptops meant to be always switched on. TCL designed the Book 14 Go to be portable, with a depth of 13.95 mm and a body that weighs 2.9 pounds.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition to its first laptop, TCL has also announced its new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tcl-nxtpaper-tablet-lcd-paper-color-video-price-specs-availability-tab-10s-5g-160025391.html">NXTPAPER tablet</a>, the 10s. The NXTPAPER 10s features the brand&#39;s full color paper-like display technology, which is a low-power reflective LCD that doesn&#39;t need backlighting. It has an anti-glare finish that allows you see what&#39;s playing from any angle and reduces blue light by over 50 percent. TCL says the display&#39;s attributes make looking at the screen more comfortable, thereby making it ideal for studying and for taking notes with its accompanying T Pen stylus. The NXTPAPER 10s will initially be available later this month in Europe and China for $249.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/1bdf7c20-6d5d-11ec-9f64-9b602c62318c" alt="TCL" data-uuid="76e4af6a-8b2d-30ed-86e1-bd26047e2528"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">TCL</div></figure><p>TCL will also release a pair of budget tablets, the $129 TAB 8 4G and the $99 TAB 10L, in the first quarter. If you&#39;re looking for even cheaper tablets for kids, it will release the $89 MINI, $149 MID and $119 MAX tablets in the same quarter for select markets, as well. All new tablets will come with support for the TCL Kids service that&#39;s launching in the second quarter to give subscribers access to a child-friendly library of educational and entertainment videos, storybooks and apps for $4 a month. TCL will also roll out Kids service support for the Book 14 Go laptop &quot;soon.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tcl-first-laptop-snapdragon-powered-book-14-go-140018174.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b40788de-20bf-4bb2-9fef-1bb7bb1abc15</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641301179</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T12:59:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Books & Publishing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/ee829b20-6d54-11ec-b1ff-0aac92d07557" width="1600" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/ee829b20-6d54-11ec-b1ff-0aac92d07557" width="1600" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[TCL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[TCL]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TCL]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Schlage's latest smart lock works with Apple's virtual home keys]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You won&#39;t have to look far to find a smart lock that takes advantage of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-home-keys-wwdc-2021-183759604.html">Apple&#39;s virtual house keys</a>. <a href="https://www.schlage.com/en/home/about-us/news-and-events.html">Schlage</a> has introduced an Encode Plus deadbolt lock that is the company&#39;s first smart lock to support iOS 15&#39;s Home Keys. Once you&#39;ve set it up, you can tap your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-and-13-mini-review-130035113.html">iPhone</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-review-all-about-the-screen-130036181.html">Apple Watch</a> to lock or unlock your door. As you might imagine, this could be more than a little helpful when your hands are full — or you&#39;d just rather reach into your bag or pocket.</p><p>The new Encode supports WiFi. You can manage it through either Apple&#39;s Home app or Schlage&#39;s own client, and you can still remotely control the deadbolt if you forgot to lock the door on your way out.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Schlage will release the lock this spring for $300, and will offer a variety of finishes to help the lock match your door. Like any Home Keys product, this only really makes sense if you&#39;re comfortably entrenched in the Apple ecosystem. If you are, though, this could easily save you time (or at least, pocket space) when you&#39;re in a hurry.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/schlage-encode-plus-smart-wifi-deadbolt-apple-home-keys-140008134.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">40a56ca7-5adc-4b73-ad44-d9df79cffc81</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641221560</ingested><modified>2022-01-03T14:52:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/bbc4dcf0-6748-11ec-a3c5-b72ada469081" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/bbc4dcf0-6748-11ec-a3c5-b72ada469081" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Schlage]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Schlage Smart WiFi Deadbolt opened with iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Schlage Smart WiFi Deadbolt opened with iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Skydio's budget-friendly drone gets a battery and range boost]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a few short years, US drone maker Skydio has gone from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-02-13-skydio-r1-smartest-consumer-drone-in-the-sky.html">relative unknown</a> to a legitimate DJI competitor. In 2019, the company took a big step forward with its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-11-skydio-2-review.html">Skydio 2</a>, releasing a UAV that had one of the best obstacle avoidance systems we had seen up to that point. With CES 2022 underway, it’s back with an updated model of that drone called the Skydio 2 Plus that adds both hardware and software enhancements.</p><p>The new model features two additional antennas compared to the Skydio 2, allowing you to fly it up to 6 kilometers away in any one direction. By contrast, its predecessor had a range of 3.5 kilometers. Additionally, Skydio claims an improvement in battery life extends the new model’s flying time by 20 percent. The company has also updated its Beacon remote to extend its range to 3 kilometers.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Alongside the Plus model, Skydio introduced KeyFrame, an AI-powered feature the company says will allow “anyone” to “design impossible camera motion that is smooth, precise and repeatable.” As the name suggests, you select a handful of keyframes you want the drone to capture, the software then links them together in one continuous motion. Compared to DJI, Skydio hasn’t had the most expansive or robust set of camera modes, so the addition of KeyFrame is an important one for the company.</p><p>The Skydio 2 Plus is available today starting at $1099. The KeyFrame feature is also available today on both Skydio 2 and 2 Plus drones.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/skydio-2-plus-annoucement-140001073.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3af7a653-6b5f-4bb3-b1eb-af8375f5e1d7</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641221543</ingested><modified>2022-01-03T14:52:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c34145e0-6432-11ec-9fa6-47f8be4e665c" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c34145e0-6432-11ec-9fa6-47f8be4e665c" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Skydio]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Skydio 2+]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Skydio 2+]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[JBL's first gaming microphone is the USB 'Quantum Stream']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:JBL" href="https://fave.co/3eP7ToN">JBL</a> has expanded its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-06-jbl-quantum-gaming-headphones-speaker.html">Quantum</a> gaming line with new products, including its first USB microphone aimed at  streamers and podcasters. The JBL Quantum Stream is a dual-condenser mic with two selectable voice pickup patterns. One of those patterns gives you a way to make sure the mic focuses on your voice, while the other was designed to capture everyone&#39;s voice, in case you&#39;re in a group call or recording a podcast with someone. The Quantum Stream also has a mute button and controls that allow you to adjust your voice volume directly on the device itself. It will set you back $100 when it makes its way to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:JBL&#39;s website" href="https://fave.co/3eP7ToN">JBL&#39;s website</a> and to retailers this spring.</p><p>The company has also introduced its first true wireless earbuds for the line, the JBL Quantum TWS. They have Adaptive Noise Cancelling and ambient aware features, giving them the capability to automatically adjust how much noise gets in based on your surroundings. They have JBL&#39;s QuantumSURROUND feature that enables spatial surround sound, as well, along with support for various voice assistants. The wireless earbuds can connect to a mobile device via Bluetooth, but they also come with a USB-C dongle for low latency connection to PCs, the PlayStation and the Nintendo Switch. When it comes to battery life, the earbuds can last for eight hours, with the charging case providing 16 additional hours. The earbuds will also be available this spring and will sell for $150.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e373a160-6d50-11ec-bbfe-bd75befe5aa5" alt="JBL" data-uuid="65343a57-9f86-3696-b754-4c53aa57676d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JBL</div></figure><p>Finally, JBL has added three new over-ear headsets to the line: the JBL Quantum 910, JBL Quantum 810 and JBL Quantum 610. The Quantum 910 comes with the JBL QuantumSPHERE 360, which is the brand&#39;s proprietary head-tracking technology, making it the first wireless device with the feature. Both the Quantum 910 and 810 headsets have Active Noise Cancelling and can connect to consoles, PCs and mobile via 2.4G wireless or Bluetooth. Meanwhile, the 610 only has 2.4G wireless connection, though it has the longest battery life of the three and can last for up to 40 hours. The Quantum 910 will sell for $250, the Quantum 810 for $200 and the Quantum 610 for $150 when they come out this spring.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jbl-usb-quantum-stream-gaming-mic-130057253.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">454ecb46-e677-4e7d-964b-b352886dfe74</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641302787</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:26:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/05eb43a0-6d48-11ec-bf7e-0f92ea91daa4" width="1600" height="1074" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/05eb43a0-6d48-11ec-bf7e-0f92ea91daa4" width="1600" height="1074" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harman would like to sell you some $1,000 headphones]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not so long ago, the internet was debating what the folks at Apple were thinking charging $549 for the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/airpods-max-review-143019326.html">AirPods Max</a>. At CES 2022, luxury audio brand <a href="https://www.marklevinson.com/">Mark Levinson</a> would like a word. The Harman-owned company (which also owns AKG, JBL and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Harman Kardon" href="https://fave.co/3sUTM9L">Harman Kardon</a>, and is itself <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-11-14-samsung-buys-harmon-auto-audio.html">a Samsung subsidiary</a>) mostly known for its high-end home and car audio systems has announced its first wireless headphones: the No. 5909. While they offer everything you&#39;d expect from a premium set, they have a nearly $1,000 price tag that only a select few might commit to.&nbsp;</p><p>The over-ear No. 5909 packs 40mm Beryllium drivers &quot;expertly tuned to the Harman curve.&quot; The company explains that &quot;the Harman curve&quot; is acoustic response that it says has taken decades of research to construct. The result here is &quot;incredible acoustic performance&quot; in a set of &quot;reference class&quot; wireless headphones. Mark Levinson says that audio performance meets the guidelines for Hi-Res Audio certification thanks to 24-bit/96kHz signal processing and 40kHz acoustic response. The No. 5909 supports LDAC, AAC and aptX Adaptive wireless codecs via Bluetooth 5.1.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Mark Levinson promises you&#39;ll hear details you haven&#39;t before, like &quot;the slightest breath an artist takes&quot; or &quot;a hidden harmony.&quot; The company explains that the same &quot;world-class sound engineers&quot; that built the luxury brand&#39;s amps, turntables and streaming players are behind the tuning of the ultra pricey No. 5909.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/9a00d660-6cfb-11ec-adeb-cb245e3c0565" alt="Mark Levinson No. 5909" data-uuid="f771396c-63a4-3ce1-aa37-5d997b52d8ba"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Mark Levinson/Harman</div></figure><p>Sound quality isn&#39;t the only consideration though. The No. 5909 has adaptive active noise cancellation (ANC) with three modes &quot;for premium sound isolation&quot; and an Ambient Aware feature that lets you tune into your surroundings as needed. The company also packed in four microphones for calls that are equipped with a so-called Smart Wind Adaption feature. The materials used to make the headphones are also better than the mostly plastic sets we typically see. The No. 5909 is built with an aluminum frame, painted metallic earcups, leather headband and replaceable leather ear cushions. An included hard shell travel case comes stocked with a USB-C charging cable, USB-C to USB-A adaptor, two USB-C to 3.5mm cables, 3.5mm to 6.3mm adaptor, airplane adaptor and a polishing cloth. Basically, it&#39;s everything you&#39;d need to use the headphones on any setup — wired, wireless or while traveling.&nbsp;</p><p>Mark Levinson says you can expect up to 30 hours of use with adaptive ANC active and up to 34 hours with the feature disabled. A quick-charge feature will give you up to six hours of play time in 15 minutes. Via an app for Android and iOS, you&#39;ll get some control over the headphones, but the company didn&#39;t go into specifics there.&nbsp;</p><p>The No. 5909 will be available in black, pewter and red color options starting today for $999.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mark-levinson-5909-headphones-announced-price-specs-130056543.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f15e4641-f202-40a5-bdec-e72b9a1736da</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:00:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641302864</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:27:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/63064510-6cd2-11ec-bffb-5e01fa94904b" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/63064510-6cd2-11ec-bffb-5e01fa94904b" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[JBL Mark Levinson 5909 headphones]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[JBL Mark Levinson 5909]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[JBL expands its true wireless lineup with three new ANC models]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It wouldn&#39;t be CES without a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-07-jbl-live-headphones-ces-2019.html">barrage of audio devices</a> from JBL. Part of that annual deluge is <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:a collection of true wireless earbuds" href="https://fave.co/3EUZfQ6">a collection of true wireless earbuds</a>, and this year is no different. Today, the company is debuting three new models with active noise cancellation (ANC) and at least seven hours of battery life. Each one is also at least IPX5 rated for water and sweat resistance, so all three can stand up to your workouts in the new year.&nbsp;</p><p>First, the JBL Live Pro 2 offers an AirPod-like stickbud design and adaptive ANC. This model also has a &quot;smart ambient&quot; mode that allows you to adjust the amount of background noise the earbuds let in. JBL says you can enable hands-free voice control through its headphones app for either Amazon Alexa or Google Assistant while on-board touch controls are available for core functions. Six microphones &quot;deliver superior call quality,&quot; according to JBL, by isolating noise (and wind) and focusing on your voice. The company says you can expect up to 10 hours of use on the earbuds themselves with another 30 hours in the case. That case supports wireless charging via Qi-compatible accessories and 15 minutes will give you four hours of playback.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/19fa1560-6cd0-11ec-a6bd-2944402a486e" alt="JBL Live Free 2" data-uuid="ba25d005-84c0-375b-b310-0e97bfe9e345"><figcaption>JBL Live Free 2</figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JBL</div></figure><p>For those who prefer a more &quot;traditional&quot; true wireless earbud design, the tiny JBL Live Free 2 might be more your speed. Like the Live Pro 2, they feature adaptive noise cancelling, smart ambient mode, hands-free voice control, a six-mic setup for calls and on-board touch controls. The main difference, aside from the design, is that the Live Free 2 only lasts seven hours on a charge with an additional 28 hours in the case. There&#39;s no quick charge mode and wireless charging isn&#39;t on the spec sheet here. However, the Live Free 2 is the most compact of the three new models when it comes to overall earbud size.</p><p>Lastly, The JBL Reflect Aero is built specifically for workouts, complete with an adjustable ear fin to hold them in place. They&#39;re IP68 rated, so they offer protection from dust in addition to improved water proofing over the other two models. Adaptive ANC, smart ambient mode, hands-free voice control, on-board touch controls and six microphones to handle calls are all part of the features list. JBL says you can expect up to eight hours of battery life on the earbuds with two full charges in the case (16 hours). There&#39;s no mention of quick charging or compatibility with Qi accessories here, so if that&#39;s a dealbreaker, you&#39;ll have to live with the stickbud Live Pro 2 out of the company&#39;s trio of new devices.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/568a3be0-6cd0-11ec-af79-ad5b36edeb13" alt="JBL Reflect Aero" data-uuid="477121f8-e5b7-3bbd-904b-6b3796d40589"><figcaption>JBL Reflect Aero</figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JBL</div></figure><p>The Live Pro 2, Live Free 2 and Reflect Aero are all priced at $149.95 and are scheduled to arrive sometime this spring.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jbl-true-wireless-earbuds-lineup-ces-2022-130052913.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0929dc39-a3bb-4c26-85ee-72f0944cef00</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641302966</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:29:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e5cd4d70-6ccf-11ec-b5fe-d2cf76d8fb60" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e5cd4d70-6ccf-11ec-b5fe-d2cf76d8fb60" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[JBL Live Pro 2]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[JBL Live Pro 2]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Theranos founder Elizabeth Holmes found guilty of defrauding investors]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a months-long trial, and a jury that was eventually deadlocked on several of 11 total charges, Elizabeth Homes, the former CEO and founder of Theranos, has been found guilty on four charges.</p><p>Holmes, who <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/elizabeth-holmes-trial-testimony.html">testified</a> during the trial, said she hadn’t intended to mislead the public or investors, and had been advised to protect the company’s “trade secrets.” The founder, who will likely appeal the charges, could face up to 20 years in prison, though it&#39;s not yet clear when she will be sentenced.</p><p>The tale of Elizabeth Holmes captured the fascination of many Silicon Valley watchers, leading to a best-selling book, several podcast series and an HBO documentary. That was just the start: Hulu is preparing a miniseries about the saga, with Amanda Seyfried starring as Holmes, set to arrive in March, while Apple recently nabbed the Jennifer Lawrence-led film adaptation of Bad Blood, a book on the Theranos saga.</p><p>-Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-10-pro-reveal-launch-date-specs-price-010013479.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">This is the OnePlus 10 Pro</a></h2><h3>Followed swiftly by Samsung’s Galaxy S21 FE, and the…</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-10-pro-reveal-launch-date-specs-price-010013479.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/6e03dc80-6c90-11ec-affc-66e46087487a" alt="OnePlus 10 Pro" data-uuid="afde3a4d-a6cb-3f98-aaf6-3f2085ee4f88"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">OnePlus</div></figure></a><p>The smartphone train never stops. By the end of January 3rd, we had two new phones on the block. OnePlus is eking out the launch of its new flagship, happening during CES despite no in-person presence there. For now, we know it’ll come in two colors, have three cameras, and look a little sleeker than its predecessors. But expect to hear more very soon.</p><p>Meanwhile, Samsung’s “Fan Edition” of the S21 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-specs-price-availability-hands-on-020006151.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">finally broke cover</a>. It’s $100 cheaper, has a larger battery (and screen), than the OG S21, making for a rather intriguing device, ahead of our full verdict.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-10-pro-reveal-launch-date-specs-price-010013479.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/targus-smart-backpack-apple-find-my-tracker-docking-station-monitor-disinfection-light-230012642.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Targus’ new backpack has a built-in Find My tracker</a></h2><h3>The company also unveiled a docking station with a fingerprint reader</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/targus-smart-backpack-apple-find-my-tracker-docking-station-monitor-disinfection-light-230012642.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e6577680-6d47-11ec-bbbf-fd79a0ec3d43" alt="TMA" data-uuid="84b2ee8d-9069-3ff0-901a-de03941519fe"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Targus</div></figure></a><p>Targus’ Cypress Hero Backpack has a built-in location tracker that could help its rightful owner find it through the Find My network if it goes missing. Conversely, if you misplace your iPhone, you can press a button on the backpack to ping your phone, as long as you&#39;ve set things up in the dedicated app. For better or worse, it looks like a totally Targus backpack, and will cost $150.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/targus-smart-backpack-apple-find-my-tracker-docking-station-monitor-disinfection-light-230012642.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/loreal-hair-color-at-home-device-colorsonic-ces-170049309.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">L’Oréal reveals its first at-home hair color gadget</a></h2><h3>The company says Colorsonic mixes the product via a mess-free process.</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e657c4a0-6d47-11ec-9e7f-6440c5a56c6c" alt="TMA" data-uuid="d85f9c7d-1ccb-336a-9453-f42e0fa7e789"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">L&#39;Oreal</div></figure><p>L’Oréal is showing off its first hair color device at CES, promising the ability to mix and apply coloring products evenly, according to the company. If it works as promised, Colorsonic should help users get consistent hair color results without having to go to the salon.</p><p>L’Oréal? At CES? Yep, the company has been pushing the boundaries of cosmetics and tech for a few years now, including a smart skincare dispenser and even lipsticks you could make at home.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/loreal-hair-color-at-home-device-colorsonic-ces-170049309.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-oled-g2-c2-annoucement-020045964.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">LG&#39;s C2 OLED TV line will include brighter &#39;evo&#39; panels</a></h2><h3>The company is adding more sizes to its OLED family, too.</h3><h3></h3><p>Much like last year, the company is touting improved brightness as one of the main reasons to buy its 2022 sets. That&#39;s because this year LG&#39;s more affordable C2 lineup will also include the &quot;evo&quot; panel technology the company debuted in 2021. Additionally, LG claims its new Alpha 9 Gen 5 AI processors will help further increase luminance through smarter algorithms.</p><p>LG has yet to share pricing, but what we do know is that the new G2 series will consist of 55-, 65- 75-inch models, as well as two new 83- and 97-inch sets. The more affordable C2 series will consist of six models total, including a new smaller 42-inch size LG says is a great fit for console and PC gaming.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-oled-g2-c2-annoucement-020045964.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/kohler-stillness-bath-pricing-availability-hands-free-faucet-home-energy-storage-155808475.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Kohler&#39;s fog-emitting smart &#39;Stillness Bath&#39; is yours for $8,000</a></h2><h3>There’s a hands-free faucet and home energy storage system in the works, too.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/kohler-stillness-bath-pricing-availability-hands-free-faucet-home-energy-storage-155808475.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e655c8d0-6d47-11ec-9eef-bccb05982959" alt="TMA" data-uuid="02688771-0ba0-3a3d-8970-1b4f5347b6de"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Kohler</div></figure></a><p>Kohler has revealed its Stillness Bath, which it unveiled at CES last year, will finally launch later this year in Q3. The bath takes inspiration from Japanese forest bathing, and aims to replicate a spa experience with the help of light, fog and aromas. Spooky. Even scarier? The Soak Freestanding Bath model will cost around $8,000.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/kohler-stillness-bath-pricing-availability-hands-free-faucet-home-energy-storage-155808475.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><h3></h3><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-nighthawk-300-ces-2022-010041387.html">Netgear expands WiFi 6E router lineup with two new options for 2022</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-latest-scale-has-a-handheld-lead-to-measure-fat-in-different-body-parts-010059582.html">Withings&#39; Body Scan scale can measure the composition of different parts of your body</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-chromebook-spin-513-2022-price-specs-170038270.html">Acer&#39;s new Chromebook Spin 513 channels the Pixelbook&#39;s tall screen</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-external-monitor-half-the-price-of-pro-display-xdr-090005453.html">Apple&#39;s rumored new monitor could be a lot more affordable than the Pro Display XDR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-benz-solar-powered-long-range-ev-concept-183758507.html">Mercedes-Benz boasts 620-mile range for its latest EV concept</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/y-brush-2-concept-010037878.html">Y-Brush shows off a concept for its second-generation, uh, Y-shaped toothbrush</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apples-airtag-is-the-cheapest-its-ever-been-at-amazon-153819504.html">Engadget Deals: Apple&#39;s AirTag is the cheapest it&#39;s ever been at Amazon</a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-theranos-founder-elizabeth-holmes-found-guilty-of-defrauding-investors-130022837.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ffb24644-71b9-4ddc-a44d-fa1ca193af64</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641293222</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T10:47:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ab180100-6d49-11ec-bfde-d06356301f2d" width="4603" height="3069" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ab180100-6d49-11ec-bfde-d06356301f2d" width="4603" height="3069" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Brittany Hosea-Small / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Theranos founder Elizabeth Holmes and her family leave the federal court after a U.S. jury found Holmes guilty in her fraud trial, in San Jose, California, U.S. January 3, 2022. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[THERANOS-HOLMES/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[JBL updates its range of portable speakers for 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For every friend who turns up to a party without a bottle in hand, there’s one that turns up with 10, and that’s the friend you should always cherish. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:JBL" href="https://fave.co/3ePFaQO">JBL</a> is a bit like that, except not at all, but what we’re trying to say is that it has, as usual, rocked up to a trade show with armfuls of new tech. A number of its <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:portable speaker lines" href="https://fave.co/3ePFaQO">portable speaker lines</a> are getting an update, including redesigned bodies and internals, as well as a pretty tasty exclusive model just for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Sam&#x002019;s Club members" href="https://fave.co/3zpy0fp">Sam’s Club members</a>.</p><p>First on the line is the JBL Boombox 3 (pictured) which gets a new three-way speaker system, including a racetrack-shaped subwoofer, two mid-range drivers and two tweeters. JBL promises that you&#39;ll get deeper bass, more intense clarity and even more powerful sound than before, as well as 24 hours of playtime on a single charge. It’s IP67 water-and-dust-proof, and can be used as a portable battery for other devices. It’ll arrive this summer, and will set you back $500.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/ac7fe6b0-6d4f-11ec-befe-8f6fa38e47c6" alt=" JBL Pulse 5" data-uuid="a2629d88-d244-350f-8143-beb2515d1b3a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JBL</div></figure><p>Meanwhile, the JBL Pulse 5 is getting a refreshed design with a larger passive radiator and acoustic volume for deeper bass, as well as a refined woofer for better mid-low frequency sound. It’ll run for up to 12 hours of play on a single charge, and is IP67 water-and-dust-proof making it useful for trips to the beach and pool. Plus, with the vibrant LED light show and ability to pair any number of companion speakers through JBL PartyBoost, you could easily use this to run your own music and light show during a balmy evening. It’ll arrive this summer, priced at $250.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/2b959f80-6d50-11ec-a8fe-bdf9bbc3669c" alt="JBL PartyBoxes" data-uuid="52ea7948-04eb-38bb-b871-3257b0c55b6e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JBL</div></figure><p>The JBL PartyBox is getting two different variations, the PartyBox Encore (pictured, right), as well as the PartyBox Encore Essential (left). The former, which is exclusive to Sam’s Club, packs a 100W speaker and a built-in lightshow that syncs to the music you’re playing. As you can see from the image, it’s also equipped with two wireless microphones, enabling that friend who’s really into karaoke to do their thing all night long. Naturally, it’s got IPX4 splashproof design, Bluetooth v5.1 and playback from USB and aux-in, ensuring you’ll have a great night whatever you’re doing. You’ll be able to pick one up from Sam’s Club in the summer for $400.</p><p>The Essential version, meanwhile, offers the same basic 100W speaker and lightshow, but in a smaller, more portable body. The battery will run to six hours, and you can connect Bluetooth, USB or aux-in to get the sound out, plus there’s a single wired microphone input for that karaoke friend you like a little less. This model will be available in March for $300.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jbl-summer-2022-portable-speaker-collection-update-130006329.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bf76754b-ea2c-4163-9f3a-a300365b2e53</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641303062</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:31:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/63f33550-6d4f-11ec-aae6-49d57e33ef0e" width="1280" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/63f33550-6d4f-11ec-aae6-49d57e33ef0e" width="1280" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JBL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[New version of the JBL Boombox in black.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[JBL Boombox 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roland's AeroCaster VRC-01 is a wireless video mixer for streamers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Roland has been making inroads into the Pro AV space for a while. The <a href="https://proav.roland.com/global/products/aerocaster/features/">AeroCaster VRC-01</a> is its latest hardware offering in this space with a focus on streamers and creators. The mini video-switching console operates almost entirely wirelessly and allows a multi-source video setup using just phones and laptops over WiFi or cellular.&nbsp;</p><p>You&#39;ll need to connect the AeroCaster to an iPad to run the main mixing software, but all the other video inputs are wireless via either Roland&#39;s own AeroCaster Camera mobile app or laptop users can remote screen share via Chrome. In short, if you ever wanted to make a multi-cam podcast or music video, but don&#39;t want the headache of several dedicated cameras, AeroCaster will let you do it with the phones you might already have.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Roland has some pretty strong credentials in this space thanks to its V-series of <a href="https://proav.roland.com/global/categories/video_switchers/">Pro AV video switchers</a> and mixers. The VRC-01 appears to be a more consumer-friendly option with a focus on Twitchers and YouTubers (though you can also stream to Facebook Live or any RTMP channel too). From the console you can switch cameras and mix audio in real time. There are two combo XLR inputs for pro-grade microphones or TRS/phone input along with some simple audio effects such as reverb and lip sync delay.</p><p>A lot of the above functionality was already possible via some of Roland&#39;s higher-end gear and its AeroCaster Switcher app, but the VRC-01 and new companion iPad app seem more streamlined and accessible. In many ways, it feels like the video-friendly sibling to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rolands-go-mixer-pro-x-studio-in-your-pocket-160021589.html">GO:Mixer Pro X</a> with both offering &quot;prosumer&quot; features in a smaller, more affordable package.&nbsp;</p><p>The VRC-O1 will be available in March and cost $295.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roland-aero-caster-vrc-01-wireless-streaming-setup-112113739.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4d63a088-4795-49a7-a7f3-9b6baa20e648</guid><dc:creator>James Trew</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 11:21:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641295277</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T11:21:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|James Trew]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b49c5890-6d4c-11ec-bfff-67768332a6ca" width="8688" height="5792" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b49c5890-6d4c-11ec-bfff-67768332a6ca" width="8688" height="5792" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roland]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roland AeroCaster VC-01]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roland AeroCaster VC-01]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ford is doubling F-150 Lightning production to 150,000 vehicles a year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ford is making new efforts to double production capacity of the F-150 Lightning electric pickup to 150,000 vehicles per year, the company announced. That follows <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ford-stops-f-150-lightning-reservations-at-200000-192434385.html">news from December</a> that it capped pre-orders at 200,000 units, with CEO Jim Farley saying &quot;we are completely oversubscribed with our battery electric vehicles.&quot; In addition, the company will start inviting the first group of reservation holders to place orders for the F-150 Lightning starting on Thursday, January 6th.&nbsp;</p><p>To boost production, Ford said it created a small task force of employees from &quot;manufacturing, purchasing, strategy, product development, and capacity planning&quot; to find ways to accelerate production. It&#39;s also working with key suppliers &quot;to find ways to increase capacity of electric vehicle parts, including battery cells, battery trays and electric drive systems,&quot; the company said in a press release.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The company noted that the F-150 Lightning is now in the the final pre-build phase before moving into mass production for retail and commercial customers, with deliveries starting this spring. The aim is to test production vehicles over a million miles or so in real-world customer conditions.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/7d856c00-6d2b-11ec-a224-4cbc90225d4d" alt="One year after Ford confirmed construction of the Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Dearborn, Mich., the first Ford F-150 Lightning pre-production units begin leaving the factory. Pre-production model shown. F-150 Lightning available starting spring 2022." data-uuid="cf340d9c-862d-34b9-a5be-ee7dcb156ec7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Ford</div></figure><p>On the order side, Ford said it&#39;s using a wave-by-wave reservation process, asking pre-order holders to watch for an invitation via email or check their Ford.com account. The automaker indicated that later pre-order holders might have to wait for vehicles from the following model year. (Ford also noted that over 75 percent of reservation holders were new to the brand.)&nbsp;</p><p>Deliveries of the 2022 F-150 Lightning pickup will begin in spring of 2022 with a starting MSRP of $39,974 before any available tax incentives. However, <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/12/30/ford-dealers-taking-advantage-strong-demand-f150-lightning-marking-up/">some reports indicate</a> that some dealers may be dinging customers up to $30,000 extra to be among the first to receive their vehicles.&nbsp;</p><p>Ford recently announced that it would triple production of the Mustang Mach-E to reach 200,000 units per year by 2023, with plans to have the &quot;global capacity to produce 600,000 BEVs annually.&quot; To do that, it&#39;s building what it calls its &quot;most advanced, most efficient auto production facility in its 118-year history in Tennessee,&quot; along with three battery plants built in collaboration with SK Innovation. All of that represents a total $11.4 billion investment with 11,000 new jobs created.</p><p>The F-150 Lightning is eligible for a full $7,500 US BEV tax credit as of today (along with any state subsidies), but Ford is expected to hit its 200,000 vehicle eligibility limit later this year. At that point, the credit will gradually be phased out unless <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-trade-agency-backs-proposed-ev-tax-credit-despite-mexicos-objections-2021-12-03/">new legislation is passed</a> that would change the rules.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ford-doubling-f-150-lightning-production-150000-vehicles-per-year-110034432.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">069f160e-1976-4fdc-a248-5d92f1c92c79</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641284205</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T08:16:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/3bdd2810-6d30-11ec-bfcb-e6d1849eb349" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/3bdd2810-6d30-11ec-bfcb-e6d1849eb349" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ford]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[One year after Ford confirmed construction of the Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Dearborn, Mich., the first Ford F-150 Lightning pre-production units begin leaving the factory. Pre-production model shown. F-150 Lightning available starting spring 2022.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ford doubling F-150 Lightning production capacity to 150,000 vehicles a year]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oral-B’s new flagship iO toothbrush puts your brushing stats on its charging base]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oral-b-io-ai-electric-toothbrush-134200732.html">Oral-B’s iO</a> has marked itself out as the smartest and fanciest of all the fancy smart electric toothbrushes on the market. With a pressure sensor, OLED display and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-oral-b-io-electric-toothbrush-ai-app.html?guccounter=1">smartphone coaching</a>, the iO Series 9 is, or was, the most luxurious way to clean your teeth. Today, however, the company has decided to broaden out the range of iO toothbrushes with both an even higher-end flagship above, and some more affordable models below.</p><div id="62934d6c91ba4c498b7ba7493920378d"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9gLqcbD-skI?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The new flagship is the iO10 with iOSense, which the company is calling the “ultimate oral health coach,” which eliminates one of the biggest problems with the iO9. With the existing model, the pressure warning light — which tells you if you’re pressing too hard on your teeth — and countdown timer is on the brush itself. That makes it very hard to tell when you’re done unless you’re staring intently at yourself in a mirror.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The iO10, meanwhile, duplicates that information on its new beefier charging base, with a digital countdown timer, pressure warnings and even a ring of lights that correspond to the six areas of our mouths. That means you don’t have to open your phone every single time you brush in order to check all of your teeth are getting an equal amount of attention. Of course, it does mean that you’ll need to have your charger plugged in your bathroom at all times, which might be an issue for some.</p><p>There’s no price for the iO10 as it stands, just an invitation to <a href="https://oralb.com/en-us/join-oralb-iO10-waitlist">sign up for the waitlist</a> for whenever this particular product is available for sale.</p><p>At the same time, the company is launching the iO4 and iO5, which are scaled-down versions of the iO model for various budget buyers. Both come with the smart pressure sensor and the same high-end rotating head as the flagship. But the iO4 only has four brushing modes, and no digital display, while the iO5 has a fifth mode and the benefit of on-board AI and access to live coaching via the app. Those models will be priced at under $100, and will be made available nationwide at some point in 2022.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/oral-b-io-10-2022-102526477.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">aa1c2889-9c33-4215-ba4b-09518a985fb1</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 10:25:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641291930</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T10:25:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e8ece3e0-6d46-11ec-beff-54ac26a4590f" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/e8ece3e0-6d46-11ec-beff-54ac26a4590f" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Oral-B]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Promotional image of the Oral-B iO10]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Oral-B iO10]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook suspends Marjorie Taylor Greene's account for a day]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marjorie Taylor Greene says she also lost access to Facebook, a day after Twitter <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-marjorie-taylor-greene-permanent-ban-160838201.html">banned</a> her personal account. Unlike Twitter&#39;s suspension, which is permanent, Facebook&#39;s penalty will only last for 24 hours. According to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/03/technology/facebook-marjorie-taylor-greene.html"><em>The New York Times</em></a>, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-removes-marjorie-taylor-greenes-post-a-day-after-her-twitter-suspension-11641248121"><em>The Wall Street Journal</em></a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/rep-marjorie-taylor-greene-suspended-facebook-misinformation-n1286883"><em>NBC News</em></a> and other sources, Greene shared a screenshot on Telegram and Gettr (a social media platform for conservatives) showing a Facebook notification telling her that can&#39;t post or comment on the website for 24 hours.&nbsp;</p><p>A spokesperson has confirmed to the publications that the social network removed one of her posts for violating its policies, but that &quot;removing her account for this violation is beyond the scope of [its] policies.&quot; In particular, her post violated the Meta-owned platform&#39;s COVID-19 misinformation rules. It&#39;s worth noting that Facebook and Twitter have only suspended her personal accounts. Her verified government accounts remain active.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Greene reportedly posted about &quot;extremely high amounts of COVID vaccine deaths&quot; with unverified raw data from the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System, or VAERS. The system is a government database managed by the CDC and the FDA, but it relies on individuals to send in reports of their experience. VAERS&#39; website <a href="https://vaers.hhs.gov/about.html">states</a> that it&#39;s &quot;not designed to determine if a vaccine caused a health problem&quot; and that &quot;additional work and evaluation [of its data] is necessary to further assess a possible safety concern.&quot; Facebook started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-bans-vaccine-misinformation-193754704.html">taking a tougher stance</a> against misinformation about COVID-19 vaccines and vaccines in general in early 2021.</p><p>Greene is known for questioning the public health measures put into place to prevent the further spread of COVID-19. In addition to opposing vaccine mandates, she also famously <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/greene-masks-house-rules-pandemic/2021/11/01/8b2e8ace-3b46-11ec-a493-51b0252dea0c_story.html">refuses</a> to wear a mask on the House floor and has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/29/us/politics/mask-mandate-fines-greene-clyde.html">racked up</a> tens of thousands of dollars in fines. Talking about her Facebook suspension on Telegram and Gettr, Greene wrote:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;Facebook has joined Twitter in censoring me... Who appointed Twitter and Facebook to be the authorities of information and misinformation? When Big Tech decides what political speech of elected Members is accepted and what’s not then they are working against our government and against the interest of our people.&quot;</p></blockquote><p>Conservative politicians have long complained about being censored by the biggest social media platforms. Back in October, former President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.engadget.com/trump-truth-social-061457538.html">announced</a> that he&#39;s planning to launch his own social network this year as part of his camp&#39;s efforts to fight back against &quot;the Big Tech companies of Silicon Valley, which have used their unilateral power to silence opposing voices in America.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-suspends-marjorie-taylor-greene-account-for-a-day-090853662.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8e3637a5-547e-4f7b-9799-2d236d8f6984</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 09:08:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641287335</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T09:09:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/16ce4080-6d36-11ec-ade3-f5c1b3e0bbb8" width="5000" height="3330" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/16ce4080-6d36-11ec-ade3-f5c1b3e0bbb8" width="5000" height="3330" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[OLIVIER DOULIERY via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[US Republican Representatives Marjorie Taylor Greene of Georgia, speaks to reporters after attending testimony by US Attorney General Merrick Garland before a House Judiciary Committee hearing on "Oversight of the United States Department of Justice," on Capitol Hill in Washington, DC, October 21, 2021. (Photo by Olivier DOULIERY / AFP) (Photo by OLIVIER DOULIERY/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-POLITICS-HEARING-GARLAND-JUSTICE]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[AT&T and Verizon will delay 5G expansion over aircraft interference concerns]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AT&amp;T and Verizon won&#39;t start rolling out their C-band 5G service on January 5th after all. The carriers have agreed to comply with a request from the Federal Aviation Administration and the Transportation Department to push back their 5G expansion by two more weeks. Authorities asked the companies for extra time to investigate concerns regarding possible interference with aircraft systems and electronics.&nbsp;</p><p>Both AT&amp;T and Verizon were supposed to to roll out their potentially faster C-band service using newly purchased frequencies back in December, but they <a href="https://www.engadget.com/att-verizon-delay-c-band-5g-due-to-faa-164549890.html">held off</a> on the expansion as requested by the Federal Aviation Administration. Airlines and aircraft manufacturers are worried that the new frequencies are too close to those used by airplanes&#39; radar altimeter, which provides data on the distance between the plane and the ground. Interferences could then lead to unsafe landings. Wireless industry giants <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-02/at-t-verizon-reject-u-s-request-for-delay-in-new-5g-service?sref=10lNAhZ9">argue</a>, however, that the C-band service&#39;s powers are low enough and that the gap in frequencies is large enough to prevent interference.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Shortly before the supposed January 5th rollout, the agencies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/att-verizon-5g-expansion-delay-faa-pete-buttigieg-224552929.html">asked</a> the carriers for a delay of two more weeks to look into the issue. They initially <a href="https://www.engadget.com/att-verizon-reject-us-5g-c-band-delay-191634365.html">rejected</a> the authorities&#39; call for an additional delay, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-02/at-t-verizon-reject-u-s-request-for-delay-in-new-5g-service?sref=10lNAhZ9">issuing</a> a joint letter that says honoring the request would be to the &quot;detriment&quot; of customers. The carriers tried to negotiate a compromise instead and told authorities that they&#39;re open to a six-month pause in deployment near some airports.</p><p>It&#39;s unclear what changed the companies&#39; minds, but both have agreed to put a pause on their plans for now.</p><p>A Verizon spokesperson told <em>Engadget</em> in a statement:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;We&#39;ve agreed to a two-week delay which promises the certainty of bringing this nation our game-changing 5G network in January, delivered over America’s best and most reliable wireless network.&quot;</p></blockquote><p>An AT&amp;T spokesperson sent us a similar response:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;At Secretary Buttigieg&#39;s request, we have voluntarily agreed to one additional two-week delay of our deployment of C-Band 5G services.  We also remain committed to the six-month protection zone mitigations we outlined in our letter. We know aviation safety and 5G can co-exist and we are confident further collaboration and technical assessment will allay any issues.&quot;</p></blockquote>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/att-verizon-delay-5g-expansion-061847173.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">19f1659d-bce1-4ad7-be2a-b26b3ea482fe</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 06:18:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641277189</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T06:19:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/43af8be0-6d1d-11ec-b5f7-b1c0f59997e9" width="4000" height="2667" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/43af8be0-6d1d-11ec-b5f7-b1c0f59997e9" width="4000" height="2667" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[rbkomar via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A commercial airplane flies through storm clouds. Flying in bad weather, turbulence in the sky]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[A commercial airplane flies through storm clouds]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[LG's C2 OLED TV line will include its brighter 'evo' panels in 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As is something of an annual tradition for the company, LG is using CES as a venue to share the first details on its 2022 TV lineup. Much <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-c1-g1-series-oled-tvs-ces-2021-133053674.html">like last year</a>, the company is touting improved brightness as one of the main reasons to buy its 2022 sets. That&#39;s because this year LG&#39;s more affordable C2 lineup will also include the &quot;evo&quot; panel technology the company debuted in 2021. Additionally, LG claims its new Alpha 9 Gen 5 AI processors will help further increase luminance through a smarter algorithm and better heat dissipation. Those chips will also improve upscaling performance and offer virtual 7.1.2 surround sound up-mixing, according to LG.</p><p>The new OLEDs will ship with the latest version of LG’s webOS operating system. The updated software adds support for individual profiles, allowing you to customize the menu for quick access to your favorite streaming services. By creating a profile, you’ll also get personalized content recommendations and notifications related to your favorite sports teams.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/d67d76e0-6ce5-11ec-bcb7-577a52a11609" alt="LG G2 Gallery OLED" data-uuid="b777d3de-a545-37c3-b1b2-e60547ae48ae"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">LG</div></figure><p>Another new webOS feature allows you to mirror what you’re watching to a second LG TV. In that way, the company says you watch cable and satellite content on two television sets without an extra set-top box. It’s hard to say how useful that feature will prove since if you have more than one TV in your home, there’s a good chance it’s because your family can’t agree on what to watch in the first place.</p><p>Out of the box, LG’s 2022 TV lineup will support the smart home industry’s new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chip-rebrand-matter-221410229.html">Matter</a> standard, allowing you to control devices lights and thermostats from the TVs. LG also promises a better gaming experience thanks to its updated <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-c1-oled-tv-game-optimizer-google-stadia-135907267.html">Game Optimizer</a>. The company is adding additional feature and preset toggles to the menu to make it easier to access those when you need them. As before, all G2 and C2 sets will support G-Sync, FreeSync and variable refresh rates. HDMI 2.1 also comes standard across the lineup.</p><p>LG has yet to share pricing, but what we do is that the G2 series will consist of 55-, 65- 75-inch models. The company will also offer two new 83- and 97-inch sets. The more affordable C2 series will consist of six models total, including a new 42-inch size LG says is a great fit for console and PC gaming. The rest of the C2 lineup consists of 48-, 55-, 65-, 77- and 83-inch sets. LG also plans to expand its QNED TV lineup for 2022. Those sets will include the company’s Quantum Dot NanoCell technology and offer 100 percent color volume.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lg-oled-g2-c2-annoucement-020045964.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">db5afdf4-4fd4-45ae-a7f5-3f004b6fbe9f</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 02:00:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641301797</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:10:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/885ba1b0-6d5f-11ec-a2fd-55ef9d807fcd" width="1311" height="807" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/885ba1b0-6d5f-11ec-a2fd-55ef9d807fcd" width="1311" height="807" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LG]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG OLED evo TVs - 2022]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG OLED evo TVs - 2022]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Galaxy S21 FE hands-on: Last year’s flagship without the frills]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At CES 2022 today, Samsung has finally unveiled the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy S21 FE" href="https://fave.co/32OxLi7">Galaxy S21 FE</a> (or “Fan Edition”) phone. This is basically a tweaked version of <a href="http://engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-camera-samples-screen-specs-160033680.html">last year’s S21</a> that the company is <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s21-5g/buy/galaxy-s21-ultra-5g-128gb-unlocked-sm-g998uzkaxaa/?link=galaxy-s21-ultra-5g/">selling</a> for $700 starting January 11th. That’s $100 less than the regular S21, and for the price this year’s model offers the same 5nm processors, same 120Hz refresh rate (in a slightly bigger screen) and a similar triple camera system. The S21 FE has a larger battery, though, and comes with Android 12. We’ll have a full review coming soon, but based on our brief hands-on with a test unit, the S21 FE appears to be a well-rounded device.</p><p>At first glance, the S21 FE isn’t as eye-catching as last year’s flagship. While it features a similar bump on the top left corner for its camera module, its housing doesn’t have a shiny finish like the original S21. I prefer the previous style — this one’s kind of bland. But the S21 FE feels sturdy and its matte finish helps it resist fingerprints, too</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The S21 FE is also available in a different set of colors than the original: This time, you get to choose from lavender, olive, silver or black (which is the color of my sample unit).</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/9efbe500-6ced-11ec-bf9d-5248e03722f3" alt="The Samsung Galaxy S21 FE in black held in mid-air with its right side facing the camera." data-uuid="f8b8a5af-f6c5-3a63-a3f6-a14fd526e3f7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>At 177 grams (or 6.2 ounces), the S21 FE is slightly heavier than the S21, which is reasonable given the newer model’s bigger 6.4-inch screen. The display still runs at Full HD+, and looks bright and sharp. But don’t expect S Pen support here like you’d get on the S21+ and Ultra. Like the S21, the Fan Edition doesn’t support Samsung’s stylus.</p><p>Aside from size, the biggest difference between the S21 FE and the original model lie in their rear cameras. While both versions have a similar 12-megapixel main camera with a f/1.8 aperture, the FE’s ultra-wide lens has a slightly wider field of view of 123 degrees. Also, the FE’s telephoto camera uses an 8-megapixel sensor while the S21’s is 64 megapixels, though they both offer 30x Space Zoom.</p><p>During my hands-on period with the S21 FE, I haven’t really put its cameras through rigorous testing and so far I haven’t noticed any major issues with picture quality. Images came out colorful and clear. Oddly, the FE’s front camera is 32 megapixels sharp while the original’s is just 10 megapixels. The selfies I’ve shot with it so far were indeed tack sharp and individual strands of my damaged hair were painfully clear.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/f9bf8880-6cf1-11ec-9eef-3a2b6cbfba70" alt="A close up of the Samsung Galaxy S21 FE&#39;s triple camera system on its back.." data-uuid="87a3e5a0-a4f4-39d5-96ab-f77cdbc808fd"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>These tweaks are similar to how <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s20-fan-edition-5g-700-dollars-price-specs-140005996.html">the S20 FE</a> varied from the S20. Samsung said it sold 10 million units of the S20 FE in just over a year since the phone’s launch in Q4 2020, making that model one of the best-selling Galaxy smartphones over the past year.</p><p>Since this is just a brief hands-on and not our full review, I can&#39;t yet tell how the S21 FE will stack up to other phones in this price range. But already it faces stiff competition from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">the Pixel 6</a>, which offers excellent cameras and software at the same cost, although it has a polarizing design.</p><p>Though the combination of features for the relatively lower price might make the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:S21 FE" href="https://fave.co/32OxLi7">S21 FE</a> an appealing phone to many Samsung fans, the company picked an awkward time to release this device. With next-gen flagships presumably on the horizon, Galaxy shoppers might be inclined to wait and see what the company might bring at that launch. Even if you’re <em>dying</em> to buy a new Galaxy S series handset already though, at least wait till we can test the S21 FE out more comprehensively before spending your money.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-specs-price-availability-hands-on-020006151.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">afdc0b0e-3b50-4cf2-9ee3-509f26fe6d31</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 02:00:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641307368</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T14:42:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/a3ad4a00-6ceb-11ec-bddf-4611bb3189e0" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/a3ad4a00-6ceb-11ec-bddf-4611bb3189e0" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cherlynn Low / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy S21 FE in black held in mid-air with its screen facing the camera.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S21 FE]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Withings' Body Scan scale can measure the composition of different parts of your body]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over five years after the release of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-07-02-withings-body-cardio-scale-review.html">Body Cardio</a> (and one <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-05-31-withings-return-tough-wearable-market.html">flirtation</a> with Nokia later), French company <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Withings" href="https://fave.co/31nFMtK">Withings</a> has released its far most technologically advanced connected scale yet, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Body Scan" href="https://fave.co/3FZgmSj">Body Scan</a>. The big change over the last model is the addition of a handle with four stainless steel electrodes that allows it to measure ECG, segmented body composition (fat/water in your arms, legs and torso) and even esoteric things like nerve activity. All of these features will also make it one of the most expensive scales yet when it arrives to market.&nbsp;</p><p>Withings says it&#39;s the number one US smart scale manufacturer and created the Body Scan &quot;because users are demanding more and more medical and health data and information,&quot; Withings CEO Mathieu Letombe told Engadget in French.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/7f7ee360-6c6d-11ec-87d7-9b16c1c5b796" alt="Withings Body Scan scale" data-uuid="9dd382ce-e4cb-31c6-aa7b-bf67d934c2ee"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Withings</div></figure><p>The new scale is certainly designed to deliver that. Though the design and high-strength tempered glass construction are similar to the previous Body Cardio, it&#39;s loaded with extra sensors that can tell you more than ever about your body. That includes four weight sensors, 14 ITO (Indium tin oxide) electrodes within the platform and four stainless steel electrodes on the new handle. The battery can now go for a year between charges compared to nine months before and it packs a larger, higher-resolution 3.2-inch LCD color display.</p><p>The handle allows safe, low-level electrical signals to pass through your entire body, not just your feet — much as you may have seen on some <a href="https://tanita.eu/rd-545-hr/">advanced gym scales</a>.  To start with, that enables a new 6-lead ECG that can detect heart arrhythmias via two sets of electrodes on each side of the handle and one within the base of the sale. That compares to a single lead on smartwatches, so the Body Scan can deliver more specific results &quot;that can easily be ready by a cardiologist,&quot; said Letombe.&nbsp;</p><p>An embedded algorithm can detect heart patterns associated with atrial fibrillation, showing the results on the display or Withings&#39; Health Mate app. Those can be stored to show trends or &quot;shared with medical professionals from the app,&quot; according to Withings. &quot;Each time you weigh yourself, the scale can deliver that information, thanks to the new handle.&quot;&nbsp;</p><section data-eng-breakout="d559f4121dfb464da5d6712175dbeb58" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/c86a37e0-6c5f-11ec-8ffa-f89ae9fdc719" alt="Withings Body Scan can also record your ECG and assess nerve activity"></section><p>In terms of your weight, Withings claims the Body Scan is accurate to within 0.1 pounds (50 grams) or double the previous model, but that&#39;s just the start of showing your body makeup. It uses multi-frequency bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA) to measure whole-body fat and water percentage, visceral fat, muscle and bone mass and extracellular and intracellular water. It can even provide readings for individual body parts, including your torso, arms and legs. All of that allows you to spot things used by health experts and sports professionals like dangerous localized fat or muscle imbalance, Withings said.&nbsp;</p><p>Working with a French company called Impeto Medical, Withings also developed a feature to assess nerve activity. It can track sweat gland activity in the feet (sudomotor function) using a small direct current via the electrodes located in the plate. Impaired function in that regard could show signs of degeneration of small nerve fibers, something that can be corrected with regular activity and a healthy diet.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;It&#39;s a useful function, because there are a lot of chronic health issues like obesity associated with poor nerve function,&quot; Letombe told me. &quot;Impeto creates devices used by neurologists and others doctors that can cost upwards of 10,000 euros, and the Body Scan is a consumer product that, again, does that every time you weigh yourself.&quot; At the same time, Withings will be able to collect nerve activity data from millions of users that could be useful for medical research and patient care.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b3bb3fe0-6c66-11ec-beff-2b499c4f7182" alt="Withings&#39; Body Scan scale has a handle that can measure fat in different parts of your body" data-uuid="56fa5485-428c-3da1-969b-76572f52c5c0"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Withings</div></figure><p>Along with the scale, Withings is also introducing (yep) a subscription service, with the price yet to be announced. It will &quot;allow users to connect with medical specialists for advice and consultation while providing clinical teams with data in real-time,&quot; Withings said. It&#39;ll also offer personalized health plans, videos and more covering topics like nutrition, sleep, exercise and stress management to help users with their health goals.&nbsp;</p><p>With the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Body Scan" href="https://fave.co/3FZgmSj">Body Scan</a>, Withings will be offering consumers one of the more advanced health, sports and medical home devices out there — at a price. It&#39;s expected to cost $300 when it arrives to the US and Europe in the second half of 2022 following FDA clearance, or $100 more than the Body Scan&#39;s launch price. That will include three free months of the subscription service, but it&#39;s still big chunk of change for a scale.&nbsp;</p><p>A lot will depend on whether it delivers on all the promised features with reasonable accuracy and if it receives its FDA clearance in a timely manner. That&#39;s not necessarily a given, as it took Withings well over a year to get its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-hybrid-scan-watch-is-set-to-arrive-in-the-us-next-month-135842112.html">ScanWatch cleared</a> by the FDA after it was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-scanwatch-hands-on-ifa-2020-070001875.html">first released</a>. The company also had issues with its Pulse Wave Velocity (PVW) heart health feature, and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-18-withings-restores-pulse-wave-velocity-eu.html">pulled it</a> in some regions over regulatory concerns.&nbsp;</p><p>Given all that, it&#39;s fairly bold on Withings&#39; part to introduce a scale with even more advanced medical and health functionality. &quot;We think that&#39;s how we can advance a user&#39;s health, not by asking an extra effort, but delivering more targeted information on a product they use every day,&quot; said Letombe.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/withings-latest-scale-has-a-handheld-lead-to-measure-fat-in-different-body-parts-010059582.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f3261398-60ac-4b7b-a5d1-50b7bc062fe6</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:00:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641303135</ingested><modified>2022-01-04T13:32:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Health Care Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b15b9b10-6c10-11ec-aeef-af44dad92c2c" width="2000" height="1393" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/b15b9b10-6c10-11ec-aeef-af44dad92c2c" width="2000" height="1393" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Steve Dent/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Withings' latest scale has a handheld lead to measure fat in different body parts]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Withings' latest scale has a handheld lead to measure fat in different body parts]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Moen's latest faucet can be controlled entirely with gestures]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/moen/"><ins>Moen</ins></a> has pulled back the curtain on its latest faucet, and it&#39;s one that you can control without touching at all. The Smart Faucet with Motion Control allows users to adjust both the temperature and flow using gestures. There are a variety of styles to fit in with homeowners&#39; design preferences and so confident is Moen about the tech that there are even versions without a handle.</p><p>Selecting hot, cold or warm water is as simple as swiping one&#39;s hand across a sensor. Default temperatures and a preferred gesture scheme can be set on the Moen Smart Water App. The faucet is available in a variety of styles to fit in with homeowners&#39; design preferences.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Smart Faucet with Motion Control incorporates all of the features from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-moen-voice-activated-faucet.html">Moen&#39;s previous faucet</a>, including Alexa and Google Assistant voice control. There are options to dispense precise quantities of water with exact temperatures (which could be great for bakers). There&#39;s also a &quot;wash hands&quot; command, which pauses the water flow for 20 seconds while you scrub your fingers and palms. In addition, you can monitor water consumption through the app.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/7cbcd430-6cd0-11ec-abbb-2ce4ca1d01fe" style="height:1626;width:2000;" alt="Moen Smart Water Network products, including Smart Faucet, Smart Leak Detector, Smart Sump Pump Monitor, Flo Smart Water Monitor and Shutoff, and Smart Shower." data-uuid="c47d8e59-be77-3725-a67a-4f9d2f5a9002"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Moen</div></figure><p>This year, the app will offer integration with Moen&#39;s other products as part of the Smart Water Network, which comprises the faucet, a leak detector, Flo Smart Water Monitor and Shutoff, sump pump monitor and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-06-u-by-moen-google.html"><ins>smart shower</ins></a>. According to Moen, the system will help provide protection against issues like extreme cold temperatures. The system will be able to automatically take action when it detects risks, such as notifying the homeowner and shutting off water.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/moen-smart-faucet-with-motion-control-home-network-010056555.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8115ee05-7e59-401f-9317-e57bd816c901</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:00:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641240877</ingested><modified>2022-01-03T20:14:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Home & Garden]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/a78632b0-6cd0-11ec-af7e-102e5ae12e18" width="3150" height="2100" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/a78632b0-6cd0-11ec-af7e-102e5ae12e18" width="3150" height="2100" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Moen]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Moen Smart Faucet with Motion Control.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Moen Smart Faucet with Motion Control]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netgear expands WiFi 6E router lineup with two new options for 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>January has arrived, and with it, new entries to Netgear’s long list of wireless routers for both gamers and professionals. This year, the major talking point is likely to be the new Nighthawk RAXE300, which sits a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-nighthawk-raxe500-170003612.html">little below the flagship RAXE500</a> in the company’s high-end line. The RAXE300 offers a combined top WiFi speed of 7.8Gbps, plus the benefit of being able to leverage the 6GHz band for faster connectivity. Netgear promises that you’ll get around 2,500 square feet of coverage from the device, plus enough gigabit ethernet ports to connect the rest of your smart home to.</p><p>At the same time, Netgear wanted to take the opportunity to remind the world of the <a href="https://www.netgear.com/home/wifi/mesh/nbk752/">Orbi 5G WiFi 6 Mesh NBK752</a>, which was released late last year. It’s the first 5G tri-band mesh system, which can leverage the 5G modem inside for always-on mobile broadband or as a backup should a standard wired connection fail. Not to mention that, as like many of Netgear’s tri-band products, the backhaul network between the router and its satellite(s) should ensure a stronger, more reliable connection.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Rounding out the list is the Orbi Pro, SXK50, the company’s new mid-range device for small businesses and professional types working from home. It’s a little behind the top-tier SK80, with a cap of 75 concurrent devices, down from 100 for the flagship, as well as a slightly slower WiFi 6 speed, but it’s likely to be an ideal option for some businesses looking for faster and more reliable connectivity.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/5ea6a530-6cb6-11ec-8e7f-92114fa2c34c" style="height:844;width:1501;" alt="Promotional image for Netgear&#39;s new Game Booster add-on" data-uuid="6d8a8fba-dee2-30e8-9ef0-817d2bb54592"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Netgear</div></figure><p>Rounding out the announcements for this year is Game Booster, a paid-for add-on service for Orbi users so that they cam get the same <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-nitehawk-pro-gaming-xr1000-123031339.html">lag-banishing features found in the Nighthawk routers</a>. That includes the ability to track pings and pick the fastest server for specific online games, as well as a built-in ad-and-tracking blocker. Unfortunately, such features will set you back $50 per year after a 30-day free trial, and only if you currently own the Orbi series 750, 850 and 960.</p><p>The Netgear Nighthawk RAXE300 will be available in the first quarter of 2022, and will set you back $400, while the Orbi 5G is already available, priced at $1,099.99. The Orbi Pro SXK50, meanwhile, will be available in the US at some point in January 2022, and can be pre-ordered now for $450.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netgear-nighthawk-300-ces-2022-010041387.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6a397519-7d7e-423d-8717-0402d35acd3e</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:00:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641238219</ingested><modified>2022-01-03T19:33:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/4d117480-6cb6-11ec-afdb-793409bb74da" width="1498" height="844" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/4d117480-6cb6-11ec-afdb-793409bb74da" width="1498" height="844" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netgear]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Netgear Router]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netgear Router]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Y-Brush shows off a concept for its second-generation, uh, Y-shaped toothbrush]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been the better part of two years since <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-ybrush-10-second-electric-toothbrush-final.html">Y-Brush started shipping</a>, offering people a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1283858434/y-brush-the-10-second-deep-cleaning-toothbrush/">different way</a> to clean their teeth. The retainer-shaped device is filled with nylon bristles which you put into your mouth, promising to sanitize your chompers in just 10 seconds. Now, at CES 2022, the company is showing off the concept for its second-generation device that’ll offer a lot more than its predecessor ever did.</p><p>The new Y-Brush concept has bristles on both sides of the retainer, meaning that users don’t need to pull the device out and flip it over to do the bottom half of their mouths. Instead, you’ll just need to move it to the sides a bit to ensure perfect coverage. More importantly, however, is that rather than just one program, this proposed new model will offer six vibration modes, including Gum Care, Whitening and Polishing.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A beefier base both enables inductive charging and helps reduce toppling while sat on the countertop, while a companion app will help you set different programs based on your brushing habits. Although given that the whole point of this thing is to shove in your mouth and not do much at all, we’re not sure how useful that would be.</p><p>For now, this second-generation Y-Brush is little more than a concept that the company wants to show off here at CES. But the thought is that this initial idea can be refined ready for the second-generation Brush, whenever that turns up.</p><p><em>Follow all of the latest news from CES 2022 </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/CES%202022/"><em>right here</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/y-brush-2-concept-010037878.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a78bacec-1ec2-4f1e-8b0f-bce28435b74f</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 01:00:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641221999</ingested><modified>2022-01-03T15:00:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/bee926f0-6ca4-11ec-beda-47c90ad40b26" width="1920" height="1344" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2022-01/bee926f0-6ca4-11ec-beda-47c90ad40b26" width="1920" height="1344" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Y-Brush]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Concept design for the second-generation Y-Brush]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Y-Brush 2]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>