<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[The books and movies we’re gifting this year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having somehow made it through a second year of global pandemic and political unrest, give the loved ones on your holiday shopping list the greatest gift of all: an alternative to doom-scrolling. In Engadget’s 2021 Media Gift Guide you’ll find a diverse selection of books — fiction and nonfiction alike — as well a host of streaming content suggestions that will keep their recipients entertained through the holidays and beyond. If you’ve got a book, show or movie that you think would make the perfect present, tell us all about it in the comments below!</p><h2>Fiction</h2><h3><em>Black Sun</em> by Rebecca Roanhorse</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/da307080-4166-11ec-9bfd-58525f629143" alt="Books and other media for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="b76eb3be-f20b-3490-a3ff-115b43e98ffe"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p><em>NYT</em> bestselling author, Rebecca Roanhorse — the literary force behind <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Star Wars: Resistance Reborn" href="https://amzn.to/3AwdAAx"><em>Star Wars: Resistance Reborn</em></a> — has done it again. Her latest fantasy series, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Between Earth and Sky" href="https://amzn.to/3Byo7fU"><em>Between Earth and Sky</em></a>, takes readers on an epic journey of trauma, healing, vengeance, and eventual redemption. The first book in the series, 2020’s <em>Black Sun,</em> weaves a masterfully engrossing — and markedly inclusive — tale that eschews the common Arthurian Legend retellings in favor of a unique fantasy world inspired by pre-Columbian America cultures. If you’ve got a fan of fantasy on your holiday shopping list, pick up Black Sun for them before the sequel, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fevered Star" href="https://amzn.to/3mHJMvZ"><em>Fevered Star</em></a>, drops next April.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3Byo7fU" id="1c8f908f4823487eb682274d065223e5" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Black Sun at Amazon - $13</a><h3><em>Age of Madness</em> trilogy by Joe Abercrombie</h3><p>The ending of <em>Game of Thrones</em> was nothing short of a slap in the face to fans. I mean, really, all that and Bran wins? GTFOH. If you’ve got a fan of George “Double R” Martin on your holiday shopping list, do them a favor and turn them on to Joe Abercrombie’s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Age of Madness trilogy" href="https://amzn.to/3BxiT47"><em>Age of Madness trilogy</em></a>. Set in a world in which the seeds of industrialization have just taken hold even as the age magic and mysticism stubbornly refuses to be uprooted, <em>AoM</em> tells a tale of mighty nations at war while the powerful elites who rule them vie for control over both their countries’ external fates and their courts’ internal politics. Packed with captivating characters, political intrigue, incredible reversals of fortune and stunning betrayals, <em>Age of Madness</em> is a grimdark masterpiece where everybody, for once, gets exactly what they deserve.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3BxiT47" id="0e50fc26797a40d28190b191710d85a3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Age of Madness trilogy at Amazon - $35</a><h3><em>1414º</em> by Paul Bradley Carr</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/da24d7c1-4166-11ec-bcff-6819ec865b62" alt="Books and other media for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="4fb3f579-b29b-37c1-b9e2-88ef90afe0f3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Whether we like it or not, this is Jeff Bezos’ world and the rest of us just live in it. Our current slate of 21st century techno-robber barons have achieved unfathomable wealth and unassailable power; but as Paul Bradley Carr’s latest novel, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:1414&#xba;" href="https://amzn.to/2YIYqLo"><em>1414º</em></a>, illustrates, you can’t spend that money or wield that influence when you’re dead. If you’ve got a fan of high-tension whodunnits and techno-thrillers on your holiday shopping list, <em>1414º </em>will be a surefire hit.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2YIYqLo" id="cd97b20c6c8e45c1acdcad14f01acacc" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 1414º at Amazon - $5</a><h3><em>Fugitive Telemetry</em> (The Murderbot Diaries) by Martha Wells</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/da268570-4166-11ec-a70f-c1339c04d9b4" alt="Books and other media for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="f992b245-7358-34b1-8231-46c63ffd2b5c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Martha Wells can’t stop, won’t stop, dropping Murderbot hits. The reigning queen of hard sci-fi released<em>&nbsp;</em><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fugitive Telemetry" href="https://amzn.to/3D1bHOm"><em>Fugitive Telemetry</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>— the sixth book in her Hugo, Nebula, Locus and Alex Award <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:winning series" href="https://amzn.to/2YGWiDK">winning series</a> — earlier this year and let me tell you from experience, it is a banger. Our self-aware SecUnit anti-hero is back in another standalone adventure, this time on the trail of a vicious murderer aboard Preservation (space) Station. If the sci-finatic on your holiday shopping lists enjoys space intrigue and robotic mysteries, you can’t go wrong with <em>Fugitive Telemetry</em>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3D1bHOm" id="204f2ec88301491aa7e5006f62ccf222" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Fugitive Telemetry at Amazon - $12</a><h3><em>Undying Mercenaries</em> series by B.V. Larson</h3><p>The year is 2052 and Earth finds itself unwillingly annexed into a galactic empire it didn’t even know existed and is presented with a simple choice: provide our new alien overlords with a viable commercial product or face extermination. Thus, Earth’s mercenary legions are born. Armed with alien-made weaponry and a mysterious technology that allows soldiers to be reconstructed after being killed in battle — like reloading from a previous save point but far more gooey — Earth’s legions set out across the stars to fight the wars that the galaxy’s elder races are too self-important to fight themselves. Already <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:16 books deep" href="https://amzn.to/3oT1cbK">16 books deep</a>, author B.V. Larson continues to lead the genre of military sci-fi from the front, so if you’ve got a fan of <em>Starship Troopers</em>, <em>Aliens</em>-style space marines, or Tom Cruise’s <em>Edge of Tomorrow</em> on your holiday shopping list, congrats! You can cross them off now.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3oT1cbK" id="c422eaa7bce24614ae072828aad53770" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Undying Mercenaries series (16 books) at Amazon - $110</a><h2>Nonfiction</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/da26c1a0-4168-11ec-babd-bc80182eda17" alt="Young girl reading a robotics book in a library. Okayama, Japan" data-uuid="a1c2a236-b944-3a9f-9f6b-b6393f2fc844"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JGalione via Getty Images</div></figure><h3><em>Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter, and Beyond</em> by Ashley Jean Yeager</h3><p>Far from a household name, astronomer Vera Rubin’s pioneering research helped convince the scientific community of the possibility that dark matter — the mysterious materials that make up a vast majority of the universe but cannot be observed — actually exists. In <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter, and Beyond" href="https://amzn.to/3mM3mXK"><em>Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter, and Beyond</em></a> (not to be confused with <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter" href="https://amzn.to/3BLH66V"><em>Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter</em></a>, a collection of Rubin’s own essays), author Ashley Jean Yeager takes readers on an inspiring biographical journey through the astronomer’s early year before examining the challenges she faced working in an often hostile, male-dominated field, and her eventual vindication and professional triumphs — looking at you <a href="https://www.lsst.org/science">Vera C. Rubin Observatory</a>. If you’ve got  a younger someone on your holiday shopping list who’s interested in pursuing STEM, this could well be the book that puts them on a path towards scientific greatness.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3mM3mXK" id="332fc6b213d84d97aa20bc655900dbc7" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Bright Galaxies, Dark Matter, and Beyond at Amazon - $15</a><h3><em>N-4 Down</em> by Mark Piesing</h3><p>During the Zeppelin’s heyday, airships weren&#39;t just a means of the well-to-do to slowly get to distant destinations in comfort and luxury, they also offered a new means of (albeit pokey) exploration. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:N-4 Down" href="https://amzn.to/3BwGBgR"><em>N-4 Down</em></a> by Mark Piesing takes readers on a thrilling, nail-biting adventure of the largest arctic rescue operation in history as famed Norwegian explorer, Roald Amundsen, rushed to save the surviving crew of the airship <em>Italia</em>, which crashed during its attempt to land men at the North Pole in 1928. The history and aeronautical buffs on your holiday shopping list are going to absolutely love it.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3BwGBgR" id="d767961002144ad3b83c855fd44f532f" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy N-4 Down at Amazon - $15</a><h3><em>Under a White Sky</em> by Elizabeth Kolbert</h3><p>For the last 10,000 years, humanity has had an unprecedented and largely destructive impact on the environment around us. But as climate change increasingly wreaks its own havoc on us in return, humanity must now work to reverse or at least mitigate the harm that we have caused. In <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Under a White Sky: The Nature of the Future" href="https://amzn.to/3lu0IGB"><em>Under a White Sky: The Nature of the Future</em></a>, Pulitzer Prize-winning author Elizabeth Kolbert examines just what we can do to make things right with Mother Earth and avoid a catastrophic climate crisis.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3lu0IGB" id="550bd503adad43a0bf0bddc418ba6a7b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Under a White Sky at Amazon - $13</a><h3><em>The Quiet Zone</em> by Stephen Kurczy</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/da291d80-4166-11ec-bbff-15260ec13f77" alt="Books and other media for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="695ef3d3-a483-3253-89f9-361649d78f68"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Green Bank, West Virginia is, technologically speaking, stuck in the 1950s. And for good reason! This bucolic Appalachian town is home to the ultra-sensitive radio telescope at the Green Bank observatory, which necessitates that basically every device that can emit a radio signal — everything from iPads to microwaves — be heavily restricted. In <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:The Quiet Zone" href="https://amzn.to/3mGcFIR"><em>The Quiet Zone</em></a>, journalist and author Stephen Kurczy, embeds himself in Green Bank to give readers a firsthand look at what life could be like without our precious digital tech. <em>The Quiet Zone</em> is the perfect gift for the aspiring luddite on your holiday shopping list.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3mGcFIR" id="98143b9c05c84e8691a3ce84c7a8ce7e" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy The Quiet Zone at Amazon - $13</a><h2>Streaming</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/54e5ca80-4169-11ec-b5cf-ad582025c2d6" alt="Young woman watching tv on her laptop in bed at night." data-uuid="de456839-fd6d-3848-a9c1-dd9c1c6118f4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">thianchai sitthikongsak via Getty Images</div></figure><p>Given the myriad COVID-induced supply chain challenges that retailers are girding for this upcoming holiday season, finding physical copies of these titles could prove to be a bit of a challenge. So, perhaps consider gifting the book worms on your holiday shopping list <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:the Kindle Paperwhite" href="https://amzn.to/2YC1FEw">the Kindle Paperwhite</a> and a subscription to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon Kindle Unlimited" href="https://amzn.to/3FBoOHH">Amazon Kindle Unlimited</a>? Virtually every one of the books listed above are available on the digital service along with millions of others as well as magazines and periodicals.</p><p>But there’s only so much one can read during those long winter nights so why not curl up on the couch with a nice cup of hot cocoa and watch some sterling examples of our new Golden Age of Television? If you’ve got a Trekkie on your holiday shopping list, you really can’t go wrong with a subscription to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Paramount+" href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/LPmd1O">Paramount+</a>. The $5 - $10 a month service unlocks a plethora of Star Trek shows including the Emmy award-winning <a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-picard-paramount-plus-2022-034119473.html"><em>Picard</em></a> and the hilarious <a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-lower-decks-season-two-premiere-strange-energies-070032163.html"><em>Lower Decks</em></a>.</p><p>For the cinephile on your list, assuming you can’t get your hands on the upcoming <a href="https://www.criterion.com/current/posts/7494-citizen-kane-to-lead-criterion-s-first-4k-slate">Criterion 4K collections</a>, an <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:HBO Max subscription" href="https://fave.co/3dZW91S">HBO Max subscription</a> works just as well. For $10 a month, you’ll give the gift of a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:massive movie selection" href="https://fave.co/3kkDbao">massive movie selection</a> as well as popular weekly news and interview series like <a href="https://www.hbo.com/pause-with-sam-jay"><em>Pause with Sam Jay</em></a> and <a href="https://www.hbo.com/last-week-tonight-with-john-oliver"><em>This Week Tonight with John Oliver</em></a>, not to mention incredible documentaries like <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5618690/"><em>Street Gang: How We Got to Sesame Street</em></a>.</p><p>Got someone with small children on your gift list? Throw them a bone with a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Disney+ subscription" href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/P0Vdgq">Disney+ subscription</a>. The service hosts nearly the entirety of Disney’s massive, decades-deep archives along with new family-friendly series and episodes arriving daily.</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-books-movies-music-of-the-year-130030165.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">699cce8b-b712-3748-87a8-1242eecda04f</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636470027</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T15:00:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[VMHoliday2020]]></category><category><![CDATA[movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[news]]></category><category><![CDATA[books]]></category><category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[giftguide20]]></category><category><![CDATA[Music]]></category><category><![CDATA[thebuyersguide]]></category><category><![CDATA[hgg2020]]></category><category><![CDATA[holiday20]]></category><category><![CDATA[commerce]]></category><category><![CDATA[gear]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Books & Publishing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/1e5da610-416c-11ec-9ff7-fb89329f5308" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/1e5da610-416c-11ec-9ff7-fb89329f5308" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Books for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide - Media gifts]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NVIDIA created a toy replica of its CEO to demo its new AI avatars]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NVIDIA has been steadily advancing its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidi-as-latest-tech-makes-ai-voices-more-expressive-and-realistic-130021480.html">AI assistant technology</a> in recent months, and now it&#39;s clear just how all the pieces fit together. The company has introduced <a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-platform-for-creating-ai-avatars">Omniverse Avatar</a> (for 3D assistant creation) and <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/11/09/riva-enterprise-custom-voice-speech-ai/">Riva</a> (custom AI voice creation) platforms that, combined, lead to surprisingly realistic virtual personas with relatively little effort — or, in one case, deliberately unrealistic.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIaUhWXjzwo">one demo</a>, used to highlight NVIDIA&#39;s AI-powered Maxine toolkit, the company created an Omniverse Avatar from a woman&#39;s photo and used Riva to train the voice based on that woman, convert text to speech and translate to different languages. The digital stand-in looks and sounds much like the real person (aside from a couple of stiff-sounding translations), and can even turn its head while maintaining natural-looking eye contact. As you might imagine, this could lead to more relatable virtual helpers at kiosks and websites.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="5b9a6e465f904c10bd3a638330ed4964"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jIaUhWXjzwo?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U9Zh57dGsH4">Another demo</a>, for NVIDIA&#39;s Project Tokkio &quot;talking kiosk&quot; reference app, shows what could happen when you created a wholly artificial character. The tech showcase centers on a 3D, ray-traced toy version of CEO Jensun Huang (complete with his signature outfit and a Riva-trained voice) using AI to hold a conversation with real people on subjects like climate change and the role of proteins in the body. Various Omniverse systems animate his face and hands. It&#39;s not meant to be highly authentic, of course, but it shows how you can craft a 3D virtual assistant considerably more engaging than a disembodied voice.</p><div id="d9d93bb57d7147419dae905ca7c97023"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U9Zh57dGsH4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Most of the Maxine development kit is already available. Riva is usable now in an open beta, and will be free for &quot;small-scale&quot; work. Larger rollouts will depend on a Riva Enterprise program launching early in 2022. You&#39;ll have to wait longer for Omniverse Avatar, though. While the basic Omniverse platform is in open beta now, Avatar is only &quot;under development&quot; with no specified launch date. Still, this points to a future where an airport or favorite restaurant can provide an assistant that&#39;s (hopefully) useful without seeming too robotic.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-ai-voice-avatar-omniverse-project-tokkio-142456487.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9303bcd6-a08e-4816-a7b3-78ec3ba3d81e</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 14:24:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636467898</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T14:25:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5e38a840-4160-11ec-a7f5-89406dc123a8" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5e38a840-4160-11ec-a7f5-89406dc123a8" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NVIDIA Omniverse Avatar toy version of Jensen Huang]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Omniverse Avatar toy version of Jensen Huang]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung's Galaxy Buds 2 are on sale for $100 right now]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung&#39;s affordable Galaxy Buds 2 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-wireless-earbuds-120058222.html">impressed us</a> with all of the premium features they offer at a decent $150 price tag. But now you can grab the wireless earbuds for $50 less thanks to a new sale at Woot. The online retailer has the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy Buds 2" href="https://fave.co/31PqXAh">Galaxy Buds 2</a> for $100, which is a new record low. As always, we recommend checking out <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Woot&#39;s return policy" href="https://fave.co/3hQFqju">Woot&#39;s return policy</a> before purchasing from them as their rules are different than those of their parent company, Amazon.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/31PqXAh" id="2e766f1c305f4ba5be00695f69296be6" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Woot;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Galaxy Buds 2 at Woot - $100</a><p>Samsung brought a select bunch of features from its higher end Galaxy Buds+ earbuds down to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-150002889.html">Galaxy Buds 2</a>. Notably, these buds have solid sound quality plus active noise-cancellation and an adjustable ambient sound mode. While the ANC isn&#39;t as strong on these buds as some more expensive models, it still blocks out most environmental noise well. They also have a small, comfortable design that&#39;s easy to wear for hours on end, and with their five-hour battery life (with ANC turned on), you&#39;ll be able to do just that. We also appreciate that their case supports wireless charging — something that&#39;s often left out of affordable wireless earbuds.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The biggest caveat with the Buds 2 is that they&#39;re best for Android users, and particularly great for those with Samsung smartphones. Whereas other Samsung earbuds offer better integration with iOS, the Buds 2 focus on Android. Sure, you <em>could</em> use the Buds 2 with an iPhone or an iPad, but you&#39;ll be stuck with the default settings. If you or someone on your holiday gift list is an Android users in need of a new pair of earbuds, the Galaxy Buds 2 are a solid option — especially at this sale price.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-are-on-sale-for-100-right-now-141102918.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">45738882-704b-4b83-83b5-fa2a0a8d67a4</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 14:11:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636467064</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T14:11:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/51d43930-faa6-11eb-bfff-007b5841bd5a" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/51d43930-faa6-11eb-bfff-007b5841bd5a" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[With the Galaxy Buds 2, Samsung adds active noise cancellation to its most affordable true wireless earbuds. This successor to the Galaxy Buds+ are smaller and more comfortable with premium features like wireless charging and adjustable ambient sound. However, ANC performance is only decent and there’s no deep iOS integration like previous models. Still, at this price, Samsung has created a compelling package despite the sacrifices.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Buds 2]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[THX's tiny Onyx USB-C DAC is $50 off at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to improving audio for your wired headphones, a USB DAC (digital to analog converter) can do wonders for sound quality. However, a lot of them are large enough they need to say on your desk. THX <a href="https://www.engadget.com/thx-onyx-dac-amp-announced-specs-price-140015870.html">built a USB-C version</a> to remedy this, with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-headphones-speakers-audio-180019755.html">the tiny Onyx</a> clocking in at about the size of a thumb drive. And the connectivity means you can use it with both your computer or your phone. After only being available through Razer before, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:THX&#39;s DAC" href="https://amzn.to/3EWdpB6">THX&#39;s DAC</a> is now available through Amazon and it&#39;s currently on sale for $50 off the original asking price of $200.&nbsp;</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3EWdpB6" id="d044a25fb2d14fd19d073c43ec39a1c4" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:THX Onyx">THX Onyx on Amazon - $150</a><p>The THX Onyx supports master-quality audio content and LEDs indicate which format you’re listening to — standard, high resolution, Direct Stream Digital (DSD) and Master Quality Authenticated (MQA). Inside, the Onyx packs a THX AAA-78 amplifier chip: the highest-powered mobile THX Achromatic Audio Amplifier configuration. THX says the AAA-78 makes the Onyx just as powerful as a desktop DAC or amplifier setup, but obviously it&#39;s much smaller. The chip reduces three types of distortion by up to 40dB and maximizes output power for more dynamic range and sound pressure level (SPL).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>THX&#39;s sale on the Onyx runs through November 29th. The discounted price will only be available at Amazon.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/thx-onyx-usb-c-dac-discount-134554775.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fe758af2-1002-426c-a3ad-5b880ecd7c77</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 13:45:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636468538</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T14:35:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/d659b400-9746-11eb-afff-669d2afb94b7" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/d659b400-9746-11eb-afff-669d2afb94b7" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[THX]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[THX Onyx]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[THX Onyx]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google's Pixelbook Go falls to an all-time low at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-15-google-pixelbook-go-hands-on-price-specs-availability.html">Pixelbook Go i5</a> offers very solid performance and battery life, with the major drawback being that it&#39;s pricey for a Chromebook. Now, Amazon is offering the 8GB and 16GB models at the lowest prices we&#39;ve seen at $749 and $849, respectively — $100 and $150 off the regular prices.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/301dqVc" id="1d3b87d5b0674409a57857c89fb9271b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Google Pixelbook Go i5">Buy Pixelbook Go i5 8GB at Amazon - $749</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3BT1pOU" id="5e391eec8f7c4ac2bd9a4555b203c9be" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Google PixelBook Go i5 16GB">Buy Pixelbook Go i5 16GB at Amazon - $849</a><p>Most of Google&#39;s past Pixelbooks offered bleeding edge design and performance at a price of $1,000 or more, at a time when most Chromebook&#39;s cost under $100. The company changed that equation with the current Pixelbook Go, a premium yet affordable Chromebook with performance to spare.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The design is more basic than the sophisticated glass-and-aluminum designs that came before it. While it&#39;s around the same weight as the previous Pixelbook, it&#39;s considerably thicker and more rounded. It&#39;s arguably more practical, though, thanks to the easy-to-grip ridged base and display that you can open with just one hand.&nbsp;</p><p>More importantly, it shines where it counts. In our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-25-google-pixelbook-go-review.html">Engadget review</a>, we noted that the Pixelbook Go delivered good performance and battery life, outshining most Chromebook models out there. That&#39;s helped by the Intel Core i5 processor with 8GB or 16GB of RAM, which is more than enough to power Chrome OS. It also comes with an excellent keyboard that offers plenty of travel.&nbsp;</p><p>The only drawbacks are a 1080p display that&#39;s not quite as good as the original and a trackpad that isn&#39;t the smoothest. Still, for the sale price of $749, the Pixel Go i5 is easily one of the best Chromebooks you can get.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/googles-pixelbook-go-i-5-falls-to-an-all-time-low-at-amazon-132316033.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cc49f658-6bea-459f-804b-22e2e5702bf6</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 13:23:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636464200</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T13:23:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/13366730-4159-11ec-bffe-91a5bdf24e9a" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/13366730-4159-11ec-bffe-91a5bdf24e9a" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google's Pixelbook Go i5 falls to an all-time low at Amazon]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google's Pixelbook Go i5 falls to an all-time low at Amazon]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon will accept Venmo payments starting in 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting next year, you&#39;ll be able to use the money anybody <a href="https://www.engadget.com/venmo-payment-app-redesign-160045898.html">Venmos</a> you to buy products directly from Amazon — so long as you live in the US. PayPal has <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-11-08-PayPal-and-Amazon-to-Enable-Customers-to-Pay-with-Venmo-at-Checkout">announced</a> that it has struck a deal with the e-commerce giant to allow US customers to pay with Venmo at checkout. It doesn&#39;t have an exact date for the feature launch, but when it does become available, you&#39;ll be able to pay either with your Venmo balance or your linked bank account.&nbsp;</p><p>Amazon typically only accepts credit/debit cards and gift cards for payment, and you can&#39;t even purchase from the website using PayPal itself. But when Venmo payments arrive next year, you&#39;ll be able to check out using the option not just on the Amazon website itself, but also on the mobile app. Ben Volk, Director of Global Payment Acceptance at Amazon, said in a statement: &quot;We understand our customers want options and flexibility in how they make purchases on Amazon. We&#39;re excited to team-up with Venmo and give our customers the ability to pay by using their Venmo accounts, providing new ways to pay on Amazon.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We&#39;ll likely hear more about the payment option the closer we get to its availability. PayPal made its announcement alongside the release of its third quarter earnings results for 2021, wherein it reported a $6.18 billion net revenue that&#39;s 13 percent higher than the same period last year. The company <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/paypals-venmo-strikes-new-partnership-with-amazon-earnings-outlook-comes-up-short-11636406821">said</a> it&#39;s off to a solid start in the fourth quarter but that growth rates still remain slightly below its expectations.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-venmo-payments-2022-124555703.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b551d38b-c53b-40b6-9590-cded31641e32</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 12:45:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636461980</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T12:46:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1eae8ae0-38c9-11ec-bdef-85e448de6930" width="5568" height="3712" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1eae8ae0-38c9-11ec-bdef-85e448de6930" width="5568" height="3712" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Daria Nipot via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sydney, Australia - 2020-10-17 Amazon prime boxes and envelopes delivered to a front door of residential building.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon prime boxes and envelopes delivered to a front door of residential building]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Engadget’s 2021 holiday gift guide]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s only a payday (or possibly two) away from the holiday season, and with supply difficulties for retailers, manufacturers and everyone in between, it might pay to get ahead of the crowd for some of the most desirable gifts.</p><p>While we can’t promise to source you a PS5 or OLED Switch, we’ve <a href="https://www.engadget.com/introducing-engadgets-2021-holiday-gift-guide-173010821.html https://www.engadget.com/...">got ideas</a> for the game streamer, the creative, the pet parent and more. Naturally, we’ve got camera, laptop and smartphone buying guidance, too. We’re Engadget, after all.</p><p>We also have the return of our popular sub-$100 gift selections, along with ideas for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-tech-stocking-stuffers-affordable-gadget-gifts-133012560.html"><ins>stocking stuffers</ins></a> that come in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-tech-stocking-stuffers-affordable-gadget-gifts-133012560.html"><ins>under $50</ins></a>. My pick would be Anker’s tiny Nano II charger. It’s USB-C and ready for high-speed device charging. If you’ve picked up a new phone in the last year and a half, you might have missed the in-box charger. This is probably faster at charging than your years-old Apple charging brick.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/zhiyuns-latest-gimbal-has-an-led-light-and-small-display-110014863.html">Zhiyun&#39;s three-axis camera gimbal has pretty much everything</a></h2><h3>Including an LED light, small display and Bluetooth camera control.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/zhiyuns-latest-gimbal-has-an-led-light-and-small-display-110014863.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/189f63c0-4154-11ec-bdbf-5a96c7d7cfd0" style="height:380;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="fffa9a93-27d5-3133-acf9-12cec73199c1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>You’ve probably heard or seen DJI&#39;s gimbals, but rival Zhiyun actually carries more models — particularly those designed for mirrorless, DSLR and cinema cameras. Its three-axis <a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__store.zhiyun-2Dtech.com_products_crane-2Dm3-3Futm-5Fsource-3Dmk-26utm-5Fmedium-3Dpr&amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;c=sWW_bEwW_mLyN3Kx2v57Q8e-CRbmiT9yOhqES_g_wVY&amp;r=xBh4qrZHzH-A4SJ2NivNNdBzNWZBAjTsDJEJZG5k5-s&amp;m=b9Cpt14Rn7N4EfLrINHuOqfTXUTMTVS_wIyE2aJSs9o&amp;s=C6Q2UTeWQWRReHwkQHB1BxVNZ-Y2Mt4IA76odOBbTwA&amp;e="><ins>Crane M3</ins></a>, designed for mirrorless cameras, is about the size of a water bottle and offers tilt, roll and pan axes, with locks for each. It works with smartphones and, Zhiyun claims, 90 percent of mirrorless cameras. It also has a quarter-inch adapter, so you can connect a professional microphone to an expansion base and run a second cable to the camera. It’s now available to order starting at $369 (£369) for the standard package.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/zhiyuns-latest-gimbal-has-an-led-light-and-small-display-110014863.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><div class="inline-emphasis"><p><strong>Sponsored by CISCO</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/smb-security-outcomes-study.html?ccid=cc001540&amp;oid=rptsc025200&amp;dtid=psolin000008">2021 Security Outcomes Study for Small Businesses</a></p><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/smb-security-outcomes-study.html?ccid=cc001540&amp;oid=rptsc025200&amp;dtid=psolin000008"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/26261d50-22e5-11ec-a9dd-8d658ab0308c" style="height:370;width:640;" alt="CISCO Image 1 " data-uuid="9244ec91-dd0b-35e0-87c6-2c4e90b113ae"><figcaption></figcaption></figure></a><p></p></div><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/wind-solar-energy-needs-study-172901659.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Wind and solar could meet 85 percent of current US electricity needs</a></h2><h3>Renewable sources may meet most power demands in &#39;advanced, industrialized nations&#39;.</h3><h3></h3><p>Wind and solar power could meet around 85 percent of US electricity needs, according to a paper published in <em>Nature Communications</em>. Batteries, capacity overbuilding and other storage options could increase that figure. The report found that most reliable systems, in which wind power is prevalent, can meet energy needs between 72 and 91 percent of the time in the countries they studied, and that&#39;s before any storage considerations. Add the capacity to store up to 12 hours of energy, and these renewable energy sources can meet between 83 and 94 percent of hourly energy needs.</p><p>There is a caveat though: The researchers noted even when wind and solar sources can power over 90 percent of a region&#39;s energy needs, there would still be hundreds of hours per year when demand isn&#39;t met.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/wind-solar-energy-needs-study-172901659.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/walmart-is-using-driverless-trucks-to-complete-a-7-mile-delivery-loop-143016425.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Walmart is using driverless trucks to complete a seven-mile delivery loop</a></h2><h3>It&#39;s between a fulfillment center and store in Arkansas.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/walmart-is-using-driverless-trucks-to-complete-a-7-mile-delivery-loop-143016425.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/18828cf0-4154-11ec-a3fd-5af3ec156e65" style="height:401;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="4e939ec8-9bfb-37b3-bd5e-7128976e38aa"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Walmart</div></figure></a><p>Walmart, working with startup Gatik, has started its fully driverless box truck deliveries between its own locations on a fixed seven-mile loop in Bentonville, Arkansas. The route involves negotiating &quot;intersections, traffic lights and merging on dense urban roads,&quot; the companies said.</p><p>The new service is part of Walmart&#39;s transition to a hub-and-spoke model with warehouses or fulfilment centers closer to customers. This means smaller warehouses, so &quot;there is a growing need for doing repeated trips from the fulfilment centers to the pickup points,&quot; Gatik CEO Gautam Narang told <em>CNBC</em>.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/walmart-is-using-driverless-trucks-to-complete-a-7-mile-delivery-loop-143016425.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-imax-enhanced-marvel-mcu-140052678.html">Disney+ will let you watch &#39;Shang-Chi&#39; and 12 Marvel films in a large IMAX format</a></h2><h3>You&#39;ll see smaller black bars on your TV during IMAX sequences.</h3><h3></h3><p>You can expect to see <em>Shang-Chi</em> and an array of Marvel movies in movie-theater style large IMAX proportions later this week. The 1.90:1 IMAX aspect ratio will look up to 26 percent taller than the typical 2.35:1 widescreen format in Marvel films, so those annoying black bars will almost disappear while you&#39;re watching scenes shot in IMAX. It’s not properly IMAX, which is so square it has enormous black bars on the sides of your TV — see Zack Snyder&#39;s <em>Justice League </em>for how that goes.</p><p><em>Shang-Chi </em>will come to the service on November 12th, along with 12 other IMAX-enhanced Marvel movies.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-imax-enhanced-marvel-mcu-140052678.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-zen-4-genoa-bergamo-cxpu-191633260.html https://www.engadget.com/...">AMD&#39;s first Zen 4 CPUs include a 128-core chip built for the cloud</a></h2><h3>Ryzen chips for we mere commoners will have to wait.</h3><h3></h3><p>AMD has unveiled its first processors based on its new Zen 4 architecture, and they promise a lot of brawn... at least for some users. <em>AnandTech</em> notes AMD has outlined its early Zen 4 roadmap during a virtual data center event, and the first two CPU families are Epyc chips, aimed at servers and other heavy-duty computing tasks.</p><p>The star of the show may be Bergamo. It&#39;s designed for cloud computing and emphasizes core density — AMD is promising up to 128 cores in a single CPU. This beastly chip won’t appear until the first half of 2023.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-zen-4-genoa-bergamo-cxpu-191633260.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><h3></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/anova-sous-vide-precision-cooker-pro-half-price-amazon-good-deal-150721840.html"><ins>Anova&#39;s Sous Vide Precision Cooker Pro is half price at Amazon</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/konami-metal-gear-solid-games-removed-digital-stores-155616537.html"><ins>Konami pulls some Metal Gear Solid games from digital stores</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-digital-and-subscription-gifts-160041638.html"><ins>The best digital gifts to send your friends and family</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-headphones-speakers-audio-180019755.html"><ins>These are the headphones, speakers and audio gadgets to gift this season</ins></a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-engadget-holiday-gift-guide-121542631.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">887b8478-3ec1-41b9-b662-4073c4b9fce2</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 12:15:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636459851</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T12:10:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Renewable Energy & Energy Saving]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a8f75b50-3d6f-11ec-a8be-803b227818f7" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a8f75b50-3d6f-11ec-a8be-803b227818f7" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Under $50 items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide - Under $50]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yelp's new iOS home feed makes it easier to discover local restaurants]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yelp seems like it&#39;s been on the internet <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-01-19-yelp-updates-with-check-ins-foursquare-not-happy.html">forever</a>, but it still helps <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yelp">millions of people</a> figure out where to eat. Now for the first time, the company is introducing a vertical home feed featuring images of dishes and more, designed to help people discover local restaurants.&nbsp;</p><p>The feed will first and foremost feature &quot;popular dishes and other trending photos from consumers, including food photos or interior and exterior shots of the restaurants,&quot; Yelp said. Much like Google and other types of news feeds, the content shown is based on your proximity to the business, the freshness of content and a dish&#39;s popularity.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>When you click on a restaurant&#39;s dish, you&#39;ll be directed to see more photos and reviews of that dish. Yelp uses machine learning to pick out those dishes based on reviews, then pairs them with photos and reviews of the dish. Clicking on other images, like the interior or exterior of a restaurant, will take you to the business page and show you more photos and info.</p><p>The other feature, Yelp Connect, is a paid feature for restaurant owners. It allows businesses to share updates with new and existing customers directly to home feed, helping their posts gain visibility (and Yelp more ad revenue, no doubt). Yelp said that it&#39;s initial testing showed it may lift a restaurant&#39;s consumer engagement up to 30 percent.&nbsp;</p><p>The new experience is arriving today on iOS exclusively in 150 cities in 25 US states, Yelp said. There&#39;s no word yet on an Android release, but the company said to &quot;stay tuned for additional updates.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/yelps-new-home-page-makes-it-easier-to-discover-local-restaurants-120042081.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d2879dab-f9b1-4ff7-8423-54ea4cf32695</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636447324</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T08:42:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/2e778660-4135-11ec-987c-aed1e00f3939" width="1500" height="890" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/2e778660-4135-11ec-987c-aed1e00f3939" width="1500" height="890" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Yelp]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Yelp's new iOS home fee makes it easier to discover local restaurants]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Yelp's new iOS home fee makes it easier to discover local restaurants]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix is bringing a TikTok-style feed of short 'Kids Clips' to its app]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix will roll out a new TikTok-inspired featured that specifically targets its younger viewers this week, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-09/netflix-to-roll-out-tiktok-like-short-clip-feature-aimed-at-kids?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>. The streaming giant is reportedly launching &quot;Kids Clips&quot; on its iOS app, which will show short video clips from its library of children&#39;s programming to help young viewers find something to watch. Bloomberg says the feature builds upon <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-fast-laughs-comedy-clips-tiktok-ios-app-182351543.html">Fast Laughs</a>, the comedy feed it launched earlier this year.&nbsp;</p><p>Unlike Fast Laughs, however, Kids Clips videos will be horizontal instead of vertical and will take over the entire screen. In addition, kids will only be able to view 10 to 20 clips at any one time. Netflix will add new clips every day based on the current shows and movies available on the platform, as well as future ones slated to arrive on the service. Both features are part of the company&#39;s efforts to combat decision fatigue, which ails many of its subscribers. Netflix also launched a shuffle play feature called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-play-something-android-launch-140045356.html">Play Something</a> back in October to help viewers find something to watch based on their viewing patterns without having to scroll endlessly through the app.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Netflix still refers Kids Clips as a &quot;test,&quot; <em>Bloomberg</em> said, and it won&#39;t be available to all its users just yet. For now, it&#39;s rolling out in select markets, including the US, Canada, Australia, Ireland and Latin American countries.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-kids-clips-112219037.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d460b32a-37a4-43cf-a636-84488a6ad6c1</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 11:22:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636458081</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T11:41:35+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/246baa20-4144-11ec-b7de-91f27bdf8674" width="1600" height="1027" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/246baa20-4144-11ec-b7de-91f27bdf8674" width="1600" height="1027" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NVIDIA's new AI brain for robots is six times more powerful than its predecessor]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NVIDIA has launched a follow-up to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-12-nvidia-jetson-agx-xavier-robot-processor-available.html">Jetson AGX Xavier,</a> its $1,100 AI brain for robots that it released back in 2018. The new module, called the <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/autonomous-machines/embedded-systems/jetson-agx-orin/">Jetson AGX Orin</a>, has six times the processing power of Xavier even though it has the same form factor and can still fit in the palm of one&#39;s hand. NVIDIA designed Orin to be an &quot;energy-efficient AI supercomputer&quot; meant for use in robotics, autonomous and medical devices, as well as edge AI applications that may seem impossible at the moment.&nbsp;</p><p>The chipmaker says Orin is capable of 200 trillion operations per second. It&#39;s built on the NVIDIA Ampere architecture GPU, features Arm Cortex-A78AE CPUs and comes with next-gen deep learning and vision accelerators, giving it the ability to run multiple AI applications. Orin will give users access to the company&#39;s software and tools, including the NVIDIA Isaac Sim scalable robotics simulation application, which enables photorealistic, physically-accurate virtual environments where developers can test and manage their AI-powered robots. For users in the healthcare industry, there&#39;s NVIDIA Clara for AI-powered imaging and genomics. And for autonomous vehicle developers, there&#39;s NVIDIA Drive.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The company has yet to reveal what the Orin will cost, but it intends to make the Jetson AGX Orin module and developer kit available in the first quarter of 2022. Those interested can register to be notified about its availability on <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/autonomous-machines/embedded-systems/jetson-agx-orin/">NVIDIA&#39;s website</a>. The company will also talk about Orin at NVIDIA GTC, which will take place from November 8th through 11th.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nvidi-as-new-ai-brain-for-robots-is-six-times-more-powerful-than-its-predecessor-093024102.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">29019828-9abd-46a9-ae58-010d88e9bb59</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 09:30:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636448676</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T09:04:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/7720b2b0-4130-11ec-96e3-0babf84499b8" width="1152" height="648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/7720b2b0-4130-11ec-96e3-0babf84499b8" width="1152" height="648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roland replicates more classic synths with the JD-08 and JX-08 sound modules]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Roland is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rolands-tr-6-s-recreates-the-legendary-sounds-of-its-808-and-909-drum-machines-071934759.html">again</a> diving into its past with the JX-08 and JD-08 Sound Modules, emulating the vintage analog JX-8P and digital JD-800 synths from the &#39;80s and &#39;90s, respectively. Both reproduce the sounds of those classic synths digitally, while adding new effects and patches tuned for contemporary styles.</p><p>Roland&#39;s JX-8P came out in 1985 as one of the company&#39;s last analog synthesizers. It married analog synthesis with digital control, offering &quot;warm pads, shimmery chorus and crystalline textures into the most popular songs of the era,&quot; Roland said. The JX-08 recreates those sounds with new effects and a polyphoric sequencer.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/af2408a0-4131-11ec-bbdf-8c967ea0395e" style="height:1303;width:2000;" alt="Roland replicates more classic synths with the JD-08 and JX-08 sound modules" data-uuid="01f2c40b-0c2a-334e-8688-4ccb1bf4174d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roland</div></figure><p>It features expanded polyphony, two-part multitimbral capability and dual/split modes, along with 32 presets from the original hardware and over 100 new patches more in line with modern needs. Plus, it&#39;s available with a panel derived from the synth&#39;s companion PG-800 programmer unit for the original hardware, letting you store creations in 256 preset slots.&nbsp;</p><p>The JD-800, meanwhile, was a digital synth introduced in 1991 with a &quot;control laden panel and aggressively electronic sound palette,&quot; according to Roland. The JD-08 recreates that using &quot;the original JD-800 waveforms&quot; and advanced modeling techniques. IT also adds expanded polyphony, a two-part polyphonic sequencer and other modern updates.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/19157360-412e-11ec-9ed3-64ea49b41c96" style="height:1012;width:1698;" alt="Roland replicates more classic synths with the JD-08 and JX-08 sound modules" data-uuid="97ca679b-550a-3d18-9c3b-c8c0832a927b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roland</div></figure><p>Both synths are highly portable, can run on USB bus power or batteries, and include a built-in speaker for mobile sound monitoring. They also feature a built-in USB-C audio/MIDI interface to connect to computer production systems, along with a full-sized MIDI I/O. The JX-08 and JD-08 Sound Modules will arrive in the US in January for $400 each.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roland-replicates-more-classic-synths-with-the-jd-08-and-jx-8-sound-modules-080042484.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8ca71e71-78c3-4ee4-86c7-0b80ced09d9f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636444442</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T07:54:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8da422f0-4131-11ec-becf-9a44d954a213" width="1800" height="1100" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8da422f0-4131-11ec-becf-9a44d954a213" width="1800" height="1100" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rolalnd]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roland replicates more classic synths with the JD-08 and JX-08 sound modules]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roland replicates more classic synths with the JD-08 and JX-08 sound modules]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Robinhood security breach compromised data of 7 million users]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Robinhood has <a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/11/8/data-security-incident">revealed</a> that it experienced a security breach incident on November 3rd, which exposed the data of as many as 7 million users or around a third of its userbase. The bad actor, the financial services company said, obtained the email addresses of 5 million people and the full names of a different group of around 2 million customers. In addition, the infiltrator managed to steal additional personal information of 310 users, including their name, date of birth and zip code. More extensive account details were exposed for 10 customers among those 310.&nbsp;</p><p>No Social Security numbers, bank account numbers or debit card numbers were exposed in the incident, Robinhood said, but it&#39;s still making the appropriate disclosures to the affected customers. The company, which allows users to make commission-free stock and crypto trades, said it had already contained the attack. Upon cutting the hacker&#39;s access off, the attacker demanded payment for the stolen data and made threats on what they would do with the information if they weren&#39;t paid.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A Robinhood spokesperson told <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-08/robinhood-data-breach-exposes-data-on-millions-of-customers?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> that it wasn&#39;t a ransomware attack, but they also declined to say if they paid up — and if so, how much money changed hands. It did say, however, that it informed law enforcement about the breach and that it had secured the services of security firm Mandiant to investigate the incident. Charles Carmakal, Mandiant&#39;s CTO, told <em>Bloomberg</em> that this could just be the start of a series of breaches. Apparently, the firm expects the attacker to target and extort other companies and organizations over the coming months.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/robinhood-users-compromised-security-breach-063802932.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d0dacc10-65c6-4cd6-82f0-96b4159864a3</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 06:38:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636439907</ingested><modified>2021-11-09T06:38:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b4ae97f0-4121-11ec-bf7f-f91f216a21ef" width="6240" height="4160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b4ae97f0-4121-11ec-bf7f-f91f216a21ef" width="6240" height="4160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[towfiqu ahamed via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Close up of hacker hand stealing data from digital tablet.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Close up of hacker hand stealing data from digital tablet]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google can now find your pet's doppelgänger in works of art]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in 2018, the Google Arts &amp; Culture app <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-01-15-googles-museum-app-finds-your-fine-art-doppelganger.html"><ins>introduced a feature</ins></a> that looks your doppelgänger in works of art. It&#39;s searched for matches for more than 120 million selfies so far. Now, the app can look for animals in art that resemble your pets too.</p><p>Using a machine learning algorithm, Pet Portraits matches a snap of your furry, finned or feathered friend against tens of thousands of works from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-arts-and-culture-expeditions-183056532.html">Google&#39;s partner institutions</a>. The app might determine that the best match for your pet is in a piece of street art from Mexico or a cat figurine from ancient Egypt.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You can share your Pet Portraits as still images or choose a few of them to turn into a GIF slideshow. To get started, tap the rainbow camera button at the bottom of the screen on the  <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20arts%20and%20culture/"><ins>Google Arts &amp; Culture</ins></a> app, which you can download on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/google-arts-culture/id1050970557?ct=keyword-petportraits"><ins>iOS</ins></a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.cultural"><ins>Android</ins></a>.</p><p>The Pet Portraits feature wasn&#39;t available at the time of writing, so unfortunately I wasn&#39;t able to test it out with snaps of the Engadget team&#39;s pets. However, Google has shared a few examples of the tool in action, including one or two that maybe aren&#39;t super close to being a perfect match.</p><p></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e248e5d0-3e65-11ec-97df-ee690689b2ff" style="height:1098;width:1181;" alt="The Pet Portraits feature in the Google Arts &amp; Culture app." data-uuid="b13b8a06-52a5-3cad-872e-9e4e12f79caf"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/dfcbfef0-3e65-11ec-91d0-31ec13b3797f" style="height:1107;width:1176;" alt="The Pet Portraits feature in the Google Arts &amp; Culture app." data-uuid="a8714da8-96de-30cc-8d0c-cd20ef626aa3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/dcf6e5f0-3e65-11ec-b633-0e1d733dc65a" style="height:1140;width:1181;" alt="The Pet Portraits feature in the Google Arts &amp; Culture app." data-uuid="3f4e0bd8-e76f-3e6e-8984-afd18f2c4bf4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-arts-and-culture-app-pet-potraits-machine-learning-000149433.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e9d8d3a2-7afc-4617-87a3-6f227a86353b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:01:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636137491</ingested><modified>2021-11-05T18:38:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Pets]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/3d5c9760-3e65-11ec-89fd-1fb143feafa2" width="1641" height="922" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/3d5c9760-3e65-11ec-89fd-1fb143feafa2" width="1641" height="922" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Pet Portraits feature in the Google Arts & Culture app.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Pet Portraits feature in the Google Arts & Culture app]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[DOJ charges alleged Kaseya ransomware hacker tied to REvil group]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Department of Justice has unsealed charges against a Ukrainian national over a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ransomware/"><ins>ransomware</ins></a> attack against IT company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/kaseya/"><ins>Kaseya</ins></a> in July. Authorities in Poland arrested Yaroslav Vasinskyi last month and proceedings are underway to extradite him to the US.&nbsp;</p><p>He has been charged with conspiracy to commit fraud and related activity in connection with computers, several counts of damage to protected computers and conspiracy to commit money laundering. If convicted on all charges, Vasinskyi faces a maximum sentence of 115 years in prison.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>According to <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1447126/download"><ins>the indictment</ins></a>, Vasinskyi used a Kaseya product to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kaseya-warned-of-security-flaws-before-ransomware-210226358.html"><ins>distribute ransomware</ins></a>. As many as 1,500 businesses and organizations around the world were affected. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/REvil/"><ins>REvil</ins></a>, the ransomware group Vasinskyi is linked to, originally demanded $70 million in exchange for unlocking victims&#39; systems. Three weeks after the attack took place, Kaseya <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kaseya-master-decryption-key-revil-attack-081230168.html"><ins>deployed a decryption key</ins></a>, which allowed its customers to regain access to their computers.</p><p>The DOJ also revealed it has <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1447131/download"><ins>seized</ins></a> $6.1 million in alleged ransom payments obtained by Russian national Yevgeniy Polyanin, another alleged member of REvil. Polyanin, who remains at large, has been accused of carrying out Sodinokibi/REvil ransomware attacks against several targets, including businesses and government departments in Texas, in August 2019. Polyanin <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1447121/download"><ins>faces similar charges</ins></a> to Vasinskyi. If convicted, Polyanin is looking at a maximum prison sentence of 145 years.</p><p>“Cybercrime is a serious threat to our country: to our personal safety, to the health of our economy, and to our national security,” Attorney General Merrick Garland <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/ukrainian-arrested-and-charged-ransomware-attack-kaseya"><ins>said in a statement</ins></a>. “Our message today is clear. The United States, together with our allies, will do everything in our power to identify the perpetrators of ransomware attacks, to bring them to justice, and to recover the funds they have stolen from their victims.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/kaseya-ransomware-attack-hacker-charged-doj-224654498.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8c6e3ea1-0af9-4ee6-be4f-5cc928b64590</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 22:46:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636409407</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T22:10:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[Crime & Justice]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/998322b0-1e05-11eb-9cbc-52ea38f56ac6" width="5000" height="3338" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/998322b0-1e05-11eb-9cbc-52ea38f56ac6" width="5000" height="3338" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Zephyr18 via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Young Asian male frustrated, confused and headache by ransomware attack on desktop screen, notebook and smartphone, cyber attack and internet security concepts]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Young Asian male frustrated by ransomware cyber attack]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Clubhouse now lets hosts record conversations for later listening]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-is-clubhouse-app-130015640.html">Clubhouse</a>’s defining characteristics was that all of the audio chats that happened on its platform were live. Once the conversation was over, it was over. That helped build an air of exclusivity around Clubhouse’s audio chat rooms, especially in the earlier days where only influencers and celebrities had access to the app.</p><p>But now, the company seems to have changed its tune. Clubhouse has just <a href="https://blog.clubhouse.com/clubhouse-replays-room-recording/"><ins>announced a new feature</ins></a> called Replay, where users can choose to record the audio chat and then save it to a club or profile. They can be downloaded and shared externally too, just in case someone wants to use it as a podcast or a TikTok soundtrack.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="c05c44d401044ac997dffb96ebc4e340"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">the best of live ✨ but later! <br><br>Replays are here and they&#39;re so much more than just a recording. Creators can download audio, and when you listen on Clubhouse, you&#39;ll see all the dynamics of the stage, PTRs, *and* hop from speaker to speaker.<br><br>live now on iOS &amp; Android 💖 <a href="https://t.co/zDtenNy60c">pic.twitter.com/zDtenNy60c</a></p>— Clubhouse (@Clubhouse) <a href="https://twitter.com/Clubhouse/status/1457798431175430149?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Replay will also support <a href="https://blog.clubhouse.com/introducing-pinned-links-so-many-new-ways-to-use-rooms/">pinned links</a>, a recent feature that allows chat moderators to link out to different sites during a conversation. Those links will remain fully interactive to those who are listening to the recording later on as well.</p><p>Listeners to a recorded conversation can skip to the next speaker, pause, scrub, or make a 30-second clip. They can also listen to it at 1.5 or 2x speed. However, be aware that creators will be able to see who’s listening to their Replays. They’ll also be able to have a “total room count” to see how many people in total — both live and recorded — listened to the room. Starting next week, Replays will appear on Clubhouse’s discovery pages, which includes search.</p><p>As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/clubhouse-record-room-replay/"><em>TechCrunch</em></a> points out, Replay is obviously great for those who don’t have time to catch a live audio event, which in turn makes Clubhouse more appealing to those with busy schedules. As Clubhouse gets more competition such as Twitter Spaces and Facebook’s Live Audio Rooms, it’ll likely need even more features to help differentiate itself from its rivals.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/clubhouse-replay-215630367.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">37d6d10a-eb50-4713-a03d-d692a945ddaa</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 21:56:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636407714</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T21:41:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/a82865a0-7c5b-11eb-92ef-30897adf6e8b" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/a82865a0-7c5b-11eb-92ef-30897adf6e8b" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BRAZIL - 2021/03/01: In this photo illustration the Clubhouse logo seen displayed on a smartphone screen. (Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration the Clubhouse logo seen displayed...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[It took Peloton until 2021 to add a pause button]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somehow, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/peloton/"><ins>Peloton</ins></a> has not offered users a way to pause on-demand classes until this very moment in time. At long last, a pause button is rolling out on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-bike-price-cut-230347867.html"><ins>Bike</ins></a> and Bike+. So, if you need to take a break for any reason, you can come back and finish your workout later.</p><p>To pause a workout, tap the screen and hold the pause button for a moment. You&#39;ll still appear in the Here Now section and others can send you encouraging high fives while your workout is paused, but you will lose your spot on the leaderboard for that class. So, if you&#39;re a hyper-competitive Peloton user, perhaps the pause button isn&#39;t for you. That said, pausing a workout doesn&#39;t have any impact on other aspects of your Peloton progress, including programs, challenges, achievements, streaks, milestones and personal records.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>For what it&#39;s worth, Peloton <a href="https://blog.onepeloton.com/pause-button/">says</a> it hopes that &quot;this feature is everything you imagine.&quot; However, it won&#39;t work on live workouts — it&#39;s not like pausing live TV. The pause button will come to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-tread-sale-120039581.html"><ins>Tread</ins></a> devices in the future.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/peloton-bike-plus-pause-button-tread-205410305.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ab871fa7-4b1b-478e-923c-f6fe1981b4ac</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:54:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636404853</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T20:54:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/a1529080-06b6-11ec-bedd-6a95d843b171" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/a1529080-06b6-11ec-bedd-6a95d843b171" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Peloton]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Peloton Bike]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Peloton Bike]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Pokémon Go’ maker Niantic is helping others create AR metaverse apps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/niantic/">Niantic Labs</a> is offering everyone the chance to get their hands on the tech behind <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Pokemon%20Go/"><em>Pokémon Go</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/niantic-pikmin-bloom-rollout-052408547.html"><em>Pikmin Bloom</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>so they can build their own augmented reality and &quot;real-world <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-metaverse-meta-explained-or-not-120032885.html">metaverse</a>&quot; apps. Developers can start using the Niantic Lightship platform today. The company also <a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/lightshiplaunch/?hl=en">announced</a> a $20 million investment fund to back developers that &quot;share our vision for the real-world metaverse and contribute to the global ecosystem we are building.&quot;</p><div id="23afcfbafdbb42a48b45e9decc0cd2c8"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wWHAr_TSDWk?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Developers can use Ninatic&#39;s toolkit to create real-time 3D mesh maps so apps can understand the surfaces and topography of the world surrounding a device. Other APIs will help apps know the difference between different aspects of an environment, such as the ground, sky, water and buildings. The toolkit also enables developers to make apps that allow up to five players to take part in the same AR multiplayer session, keeping all of their content and interactions in sync.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The tools are mostly free. The multiplayer APIs will be available at no cost for the first six months no matter how many users an app has. After that, Niantic will charge a fee if the APIs are used in an app with more than 50,000 monthly active users.</p><div id="be579ca71bb845f989fe353123a505e9"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tzbvhxa4ESY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Several notable brands have taken part in a private beta of the development kit, including Universal Pictures, PGA of America and Warner Music Group. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/coachella/">Coachella</a> has created an AR experience that its festival attendees will be able to check out next year. They&#39;ll be able to see a large version of Coachella&#39;s butterfly landing on the seven-story Spectra rainbow walkway tower.</p><p>Meanwhile, Shueisha is working with developer T&amp;S to bring characters from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/one%20piece/"><em>One Piece</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and other manga into the real world with AR. That app will be available in 2022.</p><p>Niantic&#39;s vision of the metaverse is very much different from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-connect-metaverse-zuckerberg-171507437.html">virtual reality-centered future Facebook&#39;s parent company Meta has in mind</a>. In a <a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/real-world-metaverse/">blog post</a> in August, CEO John Hanke suggested that the &quot;real-world metaverse&quot; is about connecting the physical and digital worlds, rather than existing purely as a virtual experience. With that in mind, his company has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/niantic-ar-headset-teaser-225310953.html">working on AR glasses</a> with Qualcomm over <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-05-qualcomm-teams-up-with-pokemon-go-developer-to-make-ar-glasses.html">the last couple of years</a>.</p><div id="e25ed2291ae342399c1aaca09433cb2c"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XLI-Ka_pmiw?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pokemon-go-niantic-augmented-reality-metaverse-apps-193559416.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3765e3bc-0033-4c87-bd73-2306f8471953</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 19:35:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636411356</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T22:42:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9c429990-40c8-11ec-ae77-1ec2badfb59c" width="2101" height="1034" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9c429990-40c8-11ec-ae77-1ec2badfb59c" width="2101" height="1034" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Niantic]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An illustration depicting Niantic's augmented reality-driven vision of the metaverse.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ninatic's metaverse]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[AMD's first Zen 4 CPUs include a 128-core chip built for the cloud]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AMD has unveiled its first processors based on its new Zen 4 architecture, and they promise a lot of brawn... at least, for some users. <em>AnandTech</em><a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/17055/amd-gives-details-on-epyc-zen4-genoa-and-bergamo-up-to-96-and-128-cores">notes</a> AMD has <a href="https://youtu.be/ECHhuvuiNzs?t=1915">outlined</a> its early Zen 4 roadmap during a virtual data center event, and the first two CPU families are Epyc chips aimed at servers and other heavy-duty computing tasks. The first, nicknamed Genoa, is built for general-purpose computing and packs up to 96 cores (thanks in part to a 5nm process) as well as support for DDR5 memory and PCIe 5.0 peripherals. It arrives sometime in 2022, and partners are sampling chips now.</p><p>The star of the show, however, may be Bergamo. It&#39;s designed for cloud computing and emphasizes core density — AMD is promising up to 128 cores in a single CPU. The design relies on a modified Zen 4c architecture (the C is for &quot;cloud&quot;) that offers similar functionality, but optimizes cache and power consumption to boost the core count and offer as many processing threads as possible. Bergamo doesn&#39;t surface until the first half of 2023, but it may be useful for internet giants juggling many simultaneous users.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you were expecting news on Zen 4-based <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-ryzen-5700g-5600g-apu-radeon-sale-030010401.html">Ryzen processors</a>, you&#39;ll be disappointed. AMD was unsurprisingly focused on corporate customers at its event, and there was no mention of mainstream parts. With that said, it won&#39;t be at all surprising if AMD shares more about next-gen Ryzen hardware in the months ahead.</p><div id="8cd84085ade9405682f25aa66728a31d"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ECHhuvuiNzs?start=1915" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amd-zen-4-genoa-bergamo-cpu-191633260.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0bc86597-d571-4864-9a7c-5b8f7e8b9a7d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 19:16:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636398995</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T19:16:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/6683b230-40c3-11ec-bedf-64be774248ca" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/6683b230-40c3-11ec-bedf-64be774248ca" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AMD, YouTube]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[AMD Bergamo CPU based on Zen 4 architecture]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AMD Bergamo CPU based on Zen 4 architecture]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Paramount+ expands its soccer lineup with Women's Super League matches]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Paramount+" href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/7mnXVr">Paramount+</a> is bolstering <a href="https://www.engadget.com/paramount-plus-afc-soccer-120008376.html">its soccer bonafides</a> with the addition of another notable league. CBS Sports will be the exclusive US rights holder for the Barclays FA Women’s Super League (WSL) in the 2022-23 and 2023-24 seasons, with 57 matches airing across Paramount+ and CBS Sports Network each season. Most matches will stream on Paramount+, but some will air exclusively on CBS Sports Network.&nbsp;</p><p>The WSL, which currently airs on NBC platforms in the US, features 12 teams and it&#39;s the highest level of women&#39;s soccer in England. American soccer fans will surely recognize some players, including current USWNT member Tobin Heath, who plays for Arsenal. Recently retired USWNT legend <a href="https://www.engadget.com/carli-lloyd-iso-cam-fox-sports-222353028.html">Carli Lloyd</a> spent some time on loan at Manchester City a few years back.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The WSL complements the existing plethora of soccer coverage on Paramount+, which includes the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-11-national-womens-soccer-league-games-on-cbs-twitch.html">National Women&#39;s Soccer League</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/paramount-plus-the-womens-cup-streaming-152522543.html">The Women&#39;s Cup</a> and UEFA Women’s World Cup qualifiers. Paramount+ also streams games from the UEFA Champions League, CONCACAF national team competitions, Italy’s Serie A, Scotland&#39;s Premiership and much more.</p><p>Paramount+ now streams more than 2,000 live games a year. Meanwhile, T-Mobile subscribers can currently snag a year of access to the platform <a href="https://www.engadget.com/t-mobile-paramount-plus-free-year-sprint-140923060.html">at no extra cost</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/paramount-plus-soccer-womens-super-league-streaming-184513924.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">260caf93-0133-471d-9d37-ee2420571d91</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 18:45:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636399851</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T19:31:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a59f8970-40bf-11ec-a5ae-7ddb5a14df0f" width="3131" height="2088" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a59f8970-40bf-11ec-a5ae-7ddb5a14df0f" width="3131" height="2088" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Natasha Flint of Leicester City runs past Keira Walsh of Manchester City during the Barclays FA Women's Super League match between Leicester City and Manchester City at the King Power Stadium, Leicester on Sunday 7th November 2021.  (Photo by James Holyoak/MI News/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Leicester City v Manchester City - FA Women's Super League]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[WhatsApp's answer to Discord may be group chat 'communities']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp group chats may soon behave more like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-threads-150018618.html">Discord</a> servers. <a href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-is-working-on-communities/"><em>WABetaInfo</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/6/22767242/whatsapp-working-communities-feature-groups"><em>The Verge</em></a> have learned WhatsApp is developing a Communities feature (initially <a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/whatsapp-new-community-feature-apk-teardown/">spotted</a> at <em>XDA</em>) that lets administrators unite group chats under a larger umbrella. You&#39;d have a top-level Community chat with smaller group chats tied to it — for instance, you could have a Community for a college course with study group chats linked to that parent.</p><p>All of the chats would behave much like they do today, with end-to-end encryption. Admins could invite people to join the community either manually or by sharing an invitation link. Those overseers would also have tools to manage a given community, although details aren&#39;t available at this stage.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>WABetaInfo</em> expected Communities to appear in a future WhatsApp beta for Android and iOS, although it didn&#39;t know when. We&#39;d add that features like this aren&#39;t guaranteed to launch, and might get cut.</p><p>It&#39;s easy to see Communities launching before too long, though. This wouldn&#39;t replace Discord for gamers, but it might fulfill a similar role for classes, fan groups and others that want to tie multiple chats together. It could be particularly important in countries like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-business-directory-test-sao-paulo-161835714.html">Brazil</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-sues-indian-government-traceable-messages-085250264.html">India</a>, where WhatsApp is frequently a mainstay of people&#39;s digital lives.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-communities-leak-182407530.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">457aab37-04b4-4355-893a-01d22d0ef00f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636395849</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T18:24:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/4070a970-40bb-11ec-b7f5-8af70130bf83" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/4070a970-40bb-11ec-b7f5-8af70130bf83" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mika Baumeister on Unsplash]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[WhatsApp Messenger on Android]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Messenger on Android]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wind and solar could meet 85 percent of current US electricity needs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/wind/"><ins>Wind</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/solar%20power/"><ins>solar power</ins></a> could meet around 85 percent of US electricity needs, according to a paper published in <em>Nature Communications</em>. Batteries, capacity overbuilding and other storage options could increase that figure.</p><p>A blend of wind and solar power should be enough to meet most of the current energy needs in &quot;advanced, industrialized nations,&quot; <a href="https://news.uci.edu/2021/11/05/wind-and-solar-could-power-the-worlds-major-countries-most-of-the-time/"><ins>according to the study</ins></a>. Researchers from the University of California, Irvine (UCI), China’s Tsinghua University, the Carnegie Institution for Science and Caltech looked at 39 years of hourly energy demand data from 42 countries to determine whether there&#39;s enough wind and solar resources to meet requirements.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>They found that most reliable systems, in which wind power is most prevalent, can meet energy needs in the countries they studied between 72 and 91 percent of the time, and that&#39;s before any storage considerations. Add the capacity to store up to 12 hours&#39; worth of energy, and these renewable energy sources can meet between 83 and 94 percent of hourly energy needs. However, the researchers noted even when wind and solar sources can power over 90 percent of a region&#39;s energy needs, there would still be hundreds of hours per year where demand isn&#39;t met.</p><p>“Wind and solar could meet more than 80 percent of demand in many places without crazy amounts of storage or excess generating capacity, which is the critical point,” co-author Steven Davis, professor of Earth system science at UCI, said. “But depending on the country, there may be many multi-day periods throughout the year when some demand will need to be met by energy storage and other non-fossil energy sources in a zero-carbon future.”</p><p>There are geophysical challenges at play. The paper suggests it would be easier for larger countries closer to the equator to fully switch to sustainable power sources, since they can more reliably bank on having solar energy all year long. Germany, for instance, might struggle to meet most of its needs through wind and solar, since it&#39;s a relatively smaller country at a higher latitude.</p><p>One solution would be for neighboring countries to pool their resources. &quot;A lot of consistency and reliability could be provided by a system that includes solar resources from Spain, Italy and Greece with bountiful wind available in the Netherlands, Denmark and the Baltic region,&quot; Dan Tong, assistant professor of Earth system science at Tsinghua University and lead author on the paper, said.</p><p>Many countries are cutting back on their reliance on fossil fuels, which is key to mitigating carbon emissions and limiting the impact of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/climate%20change/"><ins>climate change</ins></a>. Europe generated more electricity from renewable sources in 2020 than it did from fossil fuels, according to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/europe-renewables-overtake-fossil-fuels-ember-agora-energiewende-111045685.html"><ins>a report</ins></a> from two green energy-focused think tanks.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/wind-solar-energy-needs-study-172901659.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b69c3463-81f5-4d54-9bd7-95d1a8162be4</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 17:29:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636392543</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T17:29:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Utility Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Renewable Energy & Energy Saving]]></category><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e02920a0-40b6-11ec-9aef-8dab9d724b63" width="3740" height="2153" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e02920a0-40b6-11ec-9aef-8dab9d724b63" width="3740" height="2153" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Denis Balibouse / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A windmill is pictured in front of the Gries lake at SwissWinds farm, Europe's highest wind farm at 2500m, near the Nufenen Pass in Gries, Switzerland, October 25, 2021. Picture taken with a drone. REUTERS/Denis Balibouse]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SWISS-ENVIRONMENT/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing Engadget’s 2021 holiday gift guide!]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re anything like us, the holiday shopping season never really gets easier. It always seems to sneak up when you’re unprepared and making your gift list is often an arduous process. Despite the warm feelings this time of year brings, it can be awash with stress as you try to find the right gifts for the right people, all while trying to stay within budget.</p><p>But hopefully our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/holiday-gift-guide/">annual holiday gift guide</a> can provide some ideas for the tech-loving individuals in your life. We’ve spent time pondering the best (and most fun) gadgets we’ve used this year and came up with more than 200 products worth recommending. You’ll find gifts for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-game-streaming-gear-160012102.html">aspiring game streamers</a>, amateur photographers, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-headphones-speakers-audio-180019755.html">audiophiles</a>, pet parents and more, as well as the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-laptops-and-tablets-130051902.html">best laptops, tablets</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-wearables-130050343.html">wearables</a>. And for those with strict budgets, we have a roundup of all things under $100 in our guide along with additional ideas for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-tech-stocking-stuffers-affordable-gadget-gifts-133012560.html">stocking stuffers</a> that come in under $50.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>And for all you bargain hunters out there, Engadget will continue to cover the best tech deals throughout the holiday season. There have been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/">a ton already</a> as retailers have pushed up the start of the shopping season by an ungodly month (or two). But it’s safe to say that the weeks leading up to Black Friday and Cyber Monday will bring even more discounts. If you haven’t crossed everything off your shopping list yet, be sure to check out our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/">Deals hub</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals">@EngadgetDeals</a> on Twitter to keep up with the latest sales.</p><p>Regardless of how and when you secure those final gifts, we hope our gift guide can make it easier for you to get there. And if you pick up something for yourself along the way, consider that a well- deserved reward for making it through yet another crazy year.</p><div class="inline-emphasis"><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/holiday-gift-guide/">Engadget&#39;s 2021 holiday gift guide</a></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b3e57170-40a6-11ec-8dcd-64d8d74fe75f" alt="Items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="21775f37-96f0-3c7d-bbd6-3310c7b88176"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-laptops-and-tablets-130051902.html">The best laptops and tablets to give as gifts</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-tech-toys-for-kids-190030442.html">The best tech toys for kids</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-tech-charities-to-donate-to-130021399.html">Seven tech charities to support this holiday season</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/home-entertainment-gift-ideas-143038506.html">The home theater gear worth gifting this year (even if the giftee is you)</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-wearables-130050343.html">The best smartwatches, fitness trackers and wearables to gift</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-best-board-games-133002225.html">The best board games to gift this holiday season</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-tech-stocking-stuffers-affordable-gadget-gifts-133012560.html">Small, affordable gadgets that make great stocking stuffers</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-gifts-for-the-aspiring-influencer-in-your-life-143039773.html">The best gifts for the aspiring influencer in your life</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-gifts-for-coffee-lovers-130018731.html">The best gifts for the coffee nerd in your life</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-game-streaming-gear-160012102.html">All the gear you need to game-stream like a pro</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-headphones-speakers-audio-180019755.html">These are the audio gadgets to gift this season</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-digital-and-subscription-gifts-160041638.html">The best digital gifts to send your friends and family</a></p></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/introducing-engadgets-2021-holiday-gift-guide-173010821.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">179df2ab-cde7-4216-8512-ac6b33d24d37</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636394885</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T18:08:15+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Banking & Budgeting]]></category><category><![CDATA[Holidays & Celebrations]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hobbies & Personal Activities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/465122b0-328e-11ec-abbd-fac254f54c38" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/465122b0-328e-11ec-abbd-fac254f54c38" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Main items for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Main - 2021 Holiday Gift Guide]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Konami pulls some Metal Gear Solid games from digital stores]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Konami is <a href="https://www.konami.com/mg/jp/info/874/">removing</a> a couple of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/metal%20gear%20solid/"><ins>Metal Gear Solid</ins></a> titles from digital storefronts and platforms for the time being due to licensing issues. Unless you can find a physical copies of them, <em>Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty </em>and <em>Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</em> are no longer available to buy. The publisher said it&#39;s &quot;working on renewing the licenses for select historical archive footage used in-game.&quot; Along with the individual games, Konami is pulling bundles that include either game.</p><p>The move affects titles on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-ps3-vita-playstation-store-card-shutdown-194942426.html"><ins>PlayStation 3, PlayStation Vita</ins></a>, PlayStation Now, Xbox 360, Nintendo 3DS, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/metal-gear-solid-substance-castlevania-contra-gog-com-141759959.html"><ins>GOG</ins></a> and NVIDIA Shield (not exactly the most current of platforms in most cases). It&#39;s not clear when <em>MGS2 </em>and <em>MGS3 </em>will return to stores, or whether Konami will keep the footage in question.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>It&#39;s hardly the first time licensing issues have affected games long after they were released. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-05-12-alan-wake-delisted-from-steam-sorry-barry.html"><em><ins>Alan Wake</ins></em><ins> disappeared</ins></a> from storefronts <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alan-wake-remaster-4k-ps5-trailer-071047656.html"><ins>for quite some time</ins></a> after Remedy&#39;s rights to certain songs on the soundtrack expired. Rockstar Games, meanwhile, has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-13-gta-iv-vladivostok-fm-music-cut.html"><ins>deleted songs</ins></a> from various Grand Theft Auto titles over the years for the same reason.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/konami-metal-gear-solid-games-removed-digital-stores-155616537.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">94b918ab-d3ba-4d6f-8a1a-7a2a5fe65a11</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 15:56:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636386977</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T15:56:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/72bd9d90-40aa-11ec-97ff-2938552f2032" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/72bd9d90-40aa-11ec-97ff-2938552f2032" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Konami]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Solid Snake in Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Solid Snake in Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The best digital gifts to send your friends and family]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a world where so much of our lives revolve around digital services, giving someone a virtual gift no longer has a stigma attached to it. For gadget-lovers who seemingly have everything, or someone getting an exciting new piece of hardware this holiday, digital gifts can help them get even more out of things they own and love. This year, we’re including time-tested music and TV streaming services, some game subscriptions and practical options like learning services to keep your brain both calm and limber just as the new year gets here.</p><h2>Apple One</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ede1dc70-40a0-11ec-bfc7-ee12a44a9696" alt="Apple One" data-uuid="60d0181a-e53e-3ad7-bfc6-49e32b9ac287"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>If you know someone with multiple Apple devices, chances are good they’re already paying for a little bit of iCloud storage, and maybe a few other Apple services like Music or Arcade as well. If that’s the case, consider gifting them an <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-one/">Apple One subscription</a>. In a single monthly charge, Apple offers a combo of Apple Music, Apple TV+, Apple Arcade and either 50GB, 200GB, or 2TB of iCloud storage. If you spring for the $19.95 Family plan, that 200GB can be shared with five other family members. The $29.95 plan adds subscriptions to Apple News+ and Apple Fitness+ too. At this point, all of Apple’s offerings are pretty good – Arcade has a load of fun games with no ads, TV+ has <em>Ted Lasso</em>, and Music is second only to Spotify in the streaming world.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><a class="athena-button" href="https://www.apple.com/apple-one/" id="645f80b10ff34bdc8377ae38c6499ee5" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Apple;elmt:other;pdid:">Buy Apple One starting at $15</a><h2>Xbox Game Pass</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d6655e0-409d-11ec-aff1-a35f96e25474" alt="Microsoft Xbox Game Pass Ultimate
" data-uuid="d750350f-8c69-34b6-af7b-c64783b6295a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Getting an Xbox Series X or Series S this holiday season is likely going to be difficult. But if you know someone who managed to get their hands on Microsoft&#39;s latest console, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Xbox Game Pass" href="https://fave.co/3v6Xg80">Xbox Game Pass</a> is an outstanding addition to their new console. A $15/month subscription offers more than 100 games that can be played on the Xbox or PC, and they can be streamed to phones and tablets as well.</p><p>Xbox Game Pass Ultimate also includes a number of other perks, including Xbox Live Gold. That&#39;s usually $10 a month on its own, and it&#39;s a requirement if you want to play games online. It also includes EA Play, which opens up access to more games for the Xbox and PC. Perhaps the best part of Xbox Game Pass, though, is that it offers access to first-party Xbox Game Studios titles the day they&#39;re released, so you don&#39;t even have to purchase them. For an Xbox owner, it&#39;s a no-brainer. If the person you’re shopping for is a PlayStation owner, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:PlayStation Now" href="https://amzn.to/3ws4qo9">PlayStation Now</a> offers access to hundreds of streaming games for $60/year (or $10/month), while <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Nintendo&#x002019;s Switch Online" href="https://amzn.to/30d7Tv3">Nintendo’s Switch Online</a> unlocks online play and a large selection of NES, Super NES, Sega Genesis and N64 games for $50/year.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3v6Xg80" id="9100bac04e624a80b78f95273fff9044" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Microsoft;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Xbox Game Pass at Microsoft - $15/month</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3ws4qo9" id="cabae3e9c23d4f45ad336febf51c2f68" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy PS Now (12 months) at Amazon - $60</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/30d7Tv3" id="6d2709de7df34bfd97b96859b2d32c6d" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Switch Online (12 months) at Amazon - $20</a><h2>YouTube Premium</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d643301-409d-11ec-bffe-bb6907afbdd4" alt="YouTube Premium
" data-uuid="7d986ec7-397d-3934-b4bb-f165c1fe8cca"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget / YouTube</div></figure><p>There&#39;s something for everyone on YouTube — and there are also enough ads to make watching it pretty painful. Shrewdly, YouTube offers a solution. A <a href="https://www.youtube.com/premium">$12/month subscription</a> removes the ads, but there are a number of other benefits as well. If you&#39;re watching on a phone or tablet, you can download basically any video and save it for offline playback. Videos also can play in the background, which means you can switch to other apps without stopping. This comes in handy for picture-in-picture, or if you just want to hear the audio while you switch away to send a text message.</p><p>Premium also comes with a subscription to YouTube Music, the company&#39;s competitor to Spotify and Apple Music. It&#39;s a pretty solid service, and it does a few things that Apple and Spotify can&#39;t offer. For example, all of YouTube&#39;s music video content lives alongside its standard streaming catalog, which means users can build playlists that combine videos uploaded to YouTube alongside official artist releases. For $12, the combination of a better YouTube experience and a full-fledged music streaming app is a pretty good deal.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://www.youtube.com/premium" id="12e28dbb30a746c8bf49a735606ceaf9" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:YouTube;elmt:other;pdid:">Buy YouTube Premium - $12/month</a><h2>The Disney Bundle</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d643300-409d-11ec-bffb-2c3b0c0383c4" alt="The Disney Bundle, showing logos and images of popular shows." data-uuid="a12ea77f-afa5-39da-9765-abb796085364"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Disney</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Disney&#39;s $14/month video bundle" href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/mgE321">Disney&#39;s $14/month video bundle</a> that includes Disney+, ESPN+ and Hulu is a great digital gift for basically anyone who likes good entertainment. The appeal of Disney+ is well-known at this point: it includes basically all of Disney and Pixar&#39;s classic animated films, alongside basically everything in the Marvel cinematic universe, the entire<em> Star Wars</em> saga, and new original shows like <em>WandaVision</em>, <em>The Mandalorian</em>, <em>The Bad Batch</em> and more.</p><p>Hulu offers a vast slate of current and classic TV shows, a solid rotating selection of feature films, and a growing roster of originals. Those include <em>The Handmaid&#39;s Tale</em>,<em> Little Fires Everywhere</em>, <em>Veronica Mars</em>, <em>Shrill</em>, <em>Pen15</em> and plenty more. ESPN+, meanwhile, offers a host of live sports, including MLB games every day of the season, a wide variety of soccer leagues, golf, tennis and college games across multiple sports. Add in ESPN&#39;s <em>30 for 30</em> documentary library and a smattering of originals and the Disney bundle ends up being a great option for almost anyone — and it’s only $6 more than Disney+ on its own.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/mgE321" id="094b2a3512824c5aa4bd1ed46b3b5a49" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Disney;elmt:impactRadius;pdid:">Buy Disney Bundle - $14/month</a><h2>HBO Max</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d601450-409d-11ec-bffa-694b94a492f3" alt="HBO Max" data-uuid="489f82eb-f6eb-396c-a4a3-fae990840f4f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">HBO Max</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:HBO Max" href="https://fave.co/3dZW91S">HBO Max</a> might not have the best app we&#39;ve ever used, but it does have one of the biggest and best video libraries you can find. Its collection of original shows and films is still unrivaled in a lot of ways, from classics like <em>The Wire</em> and <em>The Sopranos</em> to newer hits like <em>Mare of Easttown</em> and <em>Succession</em>. The service also has a huge movie library, and lately it’s offered a number of movies at the same time as their theatrical release. For example, <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em> is going to hit HBO Max just a few days before Christmas and will stream there for a month. Speaking of new HBO content, <em>Curb your Enthusiasm</em> is coming back to HBO for an 11th season this fall. And if you&#39;re a DC fan, HBO Max has all of the classic Batman movies (including the Dark Knight Trilogy and Michael Keaton&#39;s two films) as well as more recent films like <em>Aquaman</em>, <em>Wonder Woman</em> and, of course, the infamous Synder Cut of <em>Justice League</em>. Oh yeah, it has <em>Friends</em>, too.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3dZW91S" id="063d01f72d7c4c6ba2fc972bcdb18173" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:HBO Max;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy HBO Max starting at $10/month</a><h2>Headspace</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d6125c0-409d-11ec-b72f-2c6e5c5c58e9" alt="The Headspace app seen on smartphones." data-uuid="ff96a7a9-72cb-3f0c-9def-4c4ab1d6703d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Headspace</div></figure><p>Chances are good that, after the year we&#39;ve all had, you know someone whose mental health could use a little bit of a boost. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Headspace" href="https://fave.co/3mQA8Hp">Headspace</a> app is a great option for adding some peace and quiet to the day. It features a wide variety of guided meditations, including sessions for beginners as well as specific exercises that focus on reducing anxiety, learning breathing techniques, increasing your compassion and so on. It also has sleep tools like soothing music and &quot;sleepcasts,” while other audio programs center on focusing, moving more, and starting your day. For $13/month or $70/year, Headspace can be a great tool to bring someone much-needed peace of mind.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3mQA8Hp" id="ca31fb828d6c4fc8a39da90fe3ca8283" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Headspace;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Headspace - $13/month</a><h2>Endel premium subscription</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d659290-409d-11ec-9f6e-e316884429e3" alt="Endel
" data-uuid="cd82a2df-a7a2-3a86-8e70-f001df245d30"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Endel</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Endel" href="https://fave.co/3oX2tyu">Endel</a> is a unique app in the focus and mental wellness space. In a nutshell, it plays algorithmically-generated soundscapes for a variety of different scenarios. Whether you&#39;re actively on-the-go, want to get some work done, need to relax, or get some sleep, Endel will produce a soundtrack to help you achieve your goal.</p><p>If you give it permission to collect data from your phone (and Apple Watch, if you have one), it can adjust its soundscapes based on things like your heart rate, time of day, location, weather, and so on. Endel is also frequently adding scenarios — recently, the company added study and recovery, and it also has something called an AI Lullaby that was created in partnership with Grimes. At $10 per month or $60 per year, it&#39;s a solid relaxation tool, and I&#39;ve also found it to be particularly useful as a soundtrack when you want to just sit down and focus on a craft, like writing or art.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3oX2tyu" id="a4d76e7e36304567b055f271ceebd287" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Endel;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Endel Premium - $10/month</a><h2>Codecademy</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d65b9a0-409d-11ec-a1ff-707d4e8a01d8" alt="Code Academy for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="4c73db3b-0d48-350f-b47e-83bde237afbe"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget / Code Academy</div></figure><p>If you know someone interested in making a jump into coding, or a coder looking to augment their existing knowledge, a subscription to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Codecademy" href="https://fave.co/3oVF0xF">Codecademy</a> could be a big help. A $240 annual subscription (or $40/month) opens up a huge catalog of courses, including things like a career path for front-end engineering, learning JavaScript or Python, digging into development or data science and many other options. Along with these courses, Codecademy also connects you with a large community for support and feedback, gives you real-world projects to test your skills on and offers completion certificates. It&#39;s a bit of an investment, but helping someone you care about invest in themselves is very much in the spirit of the holidays.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3oVF0xF" id="5fd1d38ce2b946ed93fee6f45f6acab3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Codecademy;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Codecademy - $240/year</a><h2>Skillshare</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d621020-409d-11ec-a999-34d18c8e959b" alt="Skillshare
" data-uuid="6ef9aef5-9f6e-361a-a2b8-3ab0654f03e6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Skillshare</div></figure><p>In the same vein as Code Academy, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Skillshare" href="https://fave.co/3FF0lBh">Skillshare</a> is a great option if you know someone who wants to jumpstart their abilities in a creative field. The service offers thousands of classes in topics like animation, creative writing, graphic design, photography, web development and music, as well as courses to improve skills like leadership and management, marketing or business analytics. A $180 annual subscription (or $32/month, each with a free month included) unlocks ad-free classes with unlimited access to everything Skillshare has to offer. The subscription also includes access to Skillshare&#39;s community and offline courses for your phone or tablet. Finally, a subscription includes some perks of its own, like 20 percent off <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Squarespace " href="https://fave.co/3lyqzNG">Squarespace </a>and 15 percent off <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:Adobe Creative Cloud" href="https://bit.ly/30bwmkz">Adobe Creative Cloud</a>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3FF0lBh" id="d335aef4dcc6416aba9c143243cbdd73" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Skillshare;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Skillshare - $15/month</a><h2>Parallels Toolbox</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d64cf40-409d-11ec-bcfc-8994ae2dbdaa" alt="Parallels Toolbox
" data-uuid="c8da5bb7-59d0-393b-b997-26d385cd6dd3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Parallels</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Parallels Toolbox" href="https://fave.co/3mLkY68">Parallels Toolbox</a> is a great gift for the tinkerer in your life. You know, the kind of person who wants to tweak and optimize everything they can on their computer, so that everything works <em>just right</em>. For $20/year, Parallels Toolbox offers a surprisingly wide variety of utilities for macOS and Windows, including shortcuts to see your clipboard history, capture screens shots, convert video files, download audio from websites, resize images, and and many more. Most of these things can be done using built-in utilities or other apps, but having such a wide variety of quick and useful tools right in one place can be a major productivity boon, especially for the power user in your life.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3mLkY68" id="4d0517a800fc4bdb9545968c74ad5904" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Parallels;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Parallels Toolbox - $20/year</a><h2>1Password</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d606270-409d-11ec-bffa-a5c4776abae5" alt="The 1Password app seen on a laptop screen." data-uuid="2546b90f-afdd-300f-b335-96ccef8d2fe4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">1Password</div></figure><p>If you know someone who doesn&#39;t use a password manager, do them a huge favor and get them set up with <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:1Password" href="https://fave.co/3a7yD22">1Password</a> this holiday season. It&#39;s one of the best options available: it works on unlimited devices and is available on pretty much any platform you can think of. Naturally, it features two-factor authentication for additional security, and gives you 365 days to restore any passwords you may have deleted. It&#39;s $36 a year for an individual, or $60 a year for a family of five. That family membership can be particularly useful if you need to share account passwords between members of a household securely. It&#39;s not the flashiest gift, but I wager that once you get someone on board, they&#39;ll wonder how they went so long without using it.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3a7yD22" id="17701de0e3c14221b522a3b9c1856b1d" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:1Password;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 1Password - $36/year</a><h2>Adobe Creative Cloud Photography plan</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/8d5f9f20-409d-11ec-95bd-71949aee0710" alt="Adobe Photography / Lightroom plans for the Engadget 2021 Holiday Gift Guide.
" data-uuid="94e2ed78-5b10-3ac3-be45-961b1441dff2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget / Adobe</div></figure><p>For the budding photographer in your life, <a href="https://fave.co/3BCCT59">Adobe’s photography plans</a> are a natural fit. Adobe has been in this game for years, and Lightroom remains an excellent tool for managing and editing photos anywhere you are.</p><p>The company offers a few different plans: For $10/month, you can get both Lightroom and Photoshop, along with 20GB of cloud storage to sync images and edits across your devices. For the same price, you can also get Lightroom only, but with a whopping 1TB of storage. If the person you&#39;re gifting this to has been really good, you can spend $20 and get them both Photoshop and Lightroom alongside 1TB of storage, which is ideal for anyone shooting photos in RAW. The plans with Photoshop also include Photoshop for the iPad, so keep that in mind if you&#39;re getting this for someone who loves Apple&#39;s tablet.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://bit.ly/3kgwGFy" id="576658a62dbd47859b49e272d7aa83a8" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Adobe;elmt:viglink;pdid:">Buy Adobe CC Photography plan starting at $10/month</a><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/holiday-gifts-digital-and-subscription-gifts-160041638.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0a7539fe-7e42-38f1-84c0-462b893fa96c</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636385436</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T15:30:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[endel]]></category><category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[thebuyersguide]]></category><category><![CDATA[hgg2020]]></category><category><![CDATA[commerce]]></category><category><![CDATA[ylifegifts]]></category><category><![CDATA[VMHoliday2020]]></category><category><![CDATA[1Password]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masterclass]]></category><category><![CDATA[hbomax]]></category><category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category><category><![CDATA[disneyplus]]></category><category><![CDATA[YouGotThis]]></category><category><![CDATA[digitalgifts]]></category><category><![CDATA[news]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category><category><![CDATA[giftguide20]]></category><category><![CDATA[tunnelbear]]></category><category><![CDATA[playstationnow]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audible]]></category><category><![CDATA[marvelunlimited]]></category><category><![CDATA[DCUniverseInfinite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category><category><![CDATA[holiday20]]></category><category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category><category><![CDATA[xboxgamepassultimate]]></category><category><![CDATA[gear]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c4934c30-40a2-11ec-b5bb-e383263d7e15" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c4934c30-40a2-11ec-b5bb-e383263d7e15" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[FG Trade via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Happy man celebrating good news using laptop at home]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Happy man celebrating good news using laptop at home]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Anova's Sous Vide Precision Cooker Pro is half price at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;re looking for a holiday gift for that budding chef in your life (or if you want another useful tool in your own kitchen), it&#39;s worth taking a look at Anova&#39;s Sous Vide Precision Cooker Pro. The gadget, which aims to make <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-19-sous-vide-guide.html">sous vide cooking</a> a breeze, is currently <a href="https://amzn.to/2YqLTMx">$200</a> on Amazon — $199 off the regular price. It&#39;s not <em>quite</em> the lowest price we&#39;ve ever seen for the gizmo, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/anova-precision-cooker-pro-sous-vide-limited-time-sale-amazon-125318677.html">which was $199</a>, but it&#39;s not far off at all.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2YqLTMx" id="cb601d3515a844a6b59c578104081abd" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Anova Precision Cooker Pro on Amazon - $199</a><p>The sous vide cooking method requires putting food in a sealed bag and placing it in water.  The Precision Cooker Pro, which attaches to your pot, maintains precise temperatures and keeps circulating the water to ensure your food cooks evenly. The idea is that you should have perfectly cooked food every time without having to keep a close eye on it.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You can adjust the settings using Anova&#39;s companion app or the on-device controls. The app has thousands of free recipe suggestions as well, so you&#39;ll always have something new to try.</p><p>The Precision Cooker Pro is Anova&#39;s most powerful sous vide device. It can heat up to 20 gallons of water using 1,200 watts of power. Anova says the device can run for up to 10,000 hours before shutting down. It&#39;s a fairly sturdy machine too. The Precision Cooker Pro is made with stainless steel and should withstand accidental drops. It&#39;s IPX-7 rated as well, so if you dunk it in water by mistake, it should still work.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/anova-sous-vide-precision-cooker-pro-half-price-amazon-good-deal-150721840.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">324afad7-4d7e-44ce-b240-d5b590dfe8ee</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 15:07:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1636383808</ingested><modified>2021-11-08T15:03:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/eaf13e10-ab0b-11ea-bf3f-a50ab0e0075d" width="960" height="631" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/eaf13e10-ab0b-11ea-bf3f-a50ab0e0075d" width="960" height="631" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anova]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Anova Sous Vide]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Anova Sous Vide]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>