<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 21:10:33 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Controversial Iraq War game 'Six Days in Fallujah' delayed until late 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The long and messy development of the controversial <a href="https://www.engadget.com/six-days-in-fallujah-iraq-war-game-revived-181426579.html"><em>Six Days in Fallujah</em></a> is set to last for at least another year. Publisher Victura has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-11-17-six-days-in-fallujah-delayed-to-late-2022">confirmed</a> the first-person shooter will be delayed until the last quarter of 2022. Previously, it targeted a 2021 launch window.</p><p>Victura and Highwire Games, which counts former Destiny and Halo developers among its team, announced in February that they are reviving the game. <em>Six Days in Fallujah</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2009-04-06-konami-announces-six-days-in-fallujah-game-based-on-real-batt.html">first emerged in 2009</a>, but following a backlash, publisher Konami backed out and developer Atomic Games <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2009-08-06-atomic-games-unable-to-secure-funding-for-six-days-in-fallujah.html">wasn&#39;t able to secure funding</a> to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-11-16-atomic-games-still-wants-to-finish-six-days-in-fallujah.html">finish the game</a>. The studio shut down in 2011 and the project, then a third-person shooter, was shelved.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The game features true stories shared by dozens of marines, soldiers and Iraqi civilians who were involved in Second Battle of Fallujah in Iraq in November 2004. Missions take place from the perspective of a person who was there, and they&#39;ll provide narration about what happened, from their point of view.</p><p>As was the case the first time around, critics rallied against <em>Six Days in Fallujah</em>. The Council on American-Islamic Relations, a prominent Muslim advocacy group in the US, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-04-08-playstation-xbox-called-on-to-drop-six-days-in-fallujah">urged</a> Sony, Microsoft and Valve to block it from their gaming platforms.</p><p>Victura CEO Peter Tamte, formerly of Atomic and Destiny studio Bungie, was widely denounced for suggesting the game would not make a political statement regarding why American soldiers were in Fallujah. The publisher later <a href="https://www.sixdays.com/news/a-word-about-politics">clarified</a> that &quot;we understand the events recreated in <em>Six Days in Fallujah </em>are inseparable from politics.&quot;</p><p>Despite the black cloud hanging over the game, Victura and Highwire <a href="https://www.sixdays.com/news/2022">are forging ahead</a>. They plan to almost double the size of the development team. “It became clear that recreating these true stories at a high quality was going to require more people, capital and time than we had,” Tamte said. “Doubling our team is just one of many things we’re doing to make sure <em>Six Days in Fallujah </em>brings new kinds of tactical and emotional depth to military shooters.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/six-days-in-fallujah-delayed-205533283.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cb456f46-f445-4a12-a78d-e947d4c2f3af</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 21:10:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637181707</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:41:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/037dc2f0-47e1-11ec-b6fb-f01e9760a6f4" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/037dc2f0-47e1-11ec-b6fb-f01e9760a6f4" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Victura/Highwire Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Six Days in Fallujah]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Six Days in Fallujah]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fisker will start producing its Ocean electric SUV in 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After building hype for several years, Fisker says it’s nearly ready to bring its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-fisker-ocean-pricing.html"><ins>Ocean</ins></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-fisker-ocean-pricing.html"><ins>SUV</ins></a> to market. At the Los Angeles motor show, the automaker unveiled a <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/cghen8gr8e1n/KY4dEPpu6okyU8EJyXwVF/4e36b5aabdc08e96e31047a0c8b0ccaa/Fisker_Ocean_LAAS_Press_Release_-_FINAL.pdf"><ins>production-intent</ins></a> variant of the all-electric vehicle and said it planned to begin pilot production this week at a Magna-Steyr facility in Austria. According to Fisker, full-scale manufacturing will start a year from now, with deliveries following shortly thereafter.</p><p>As <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-fisker-ocean-pricing.html"><ins>previously announced</ins></a>, the Ocean will start at $37,499 in the US before federal- and state-level subsidies. Fisker will offer the SUV in two additional trims. It will sell the Ocean Ultra for $49,999 and the Ocean Extreme for $68,999. The base-level Sport model features a single 275 horsepower motor capable of accelerating the car from zero to 60 miles per hour in 6.6 seconds. Meanwhile, the dual-motor Ultra model features a total output of 540 horsepower, allowing it to accelerate from zero to 60 miles per hour in 3.9 seconds. The slightly more powerful Extreme can complete that feat in 3.6 seconds thanks to its 550 horsepower powertrain.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Fisker has yet to share the exact battery capacities of each model but estimates the Sport trim will have the ability to go 250 miles on a single charge. On the top end, the Extreme variant will feature a 350-mile range. The Extreme model will also come with a solar roof that Fisker says can add up to 2000 miles of range. Inside the cabin, the Ocean has an all-vegan interior made from recycled fishing nets, old t-shirts and renewed rubber. Another nifty addition is a 17.1-inch touchscreen display that can rotate between portrait and landscape orientations.</p><p>With a year before the Ocean starts making its way to consumers, there’s still a long wait before the SUV arrives. However, once it does arrive, the Ocean will be available for sale globally.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/fisker-ocean-production-22-204310175.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef5060b3-a2a9-4a70-94a8-bf6c1d23d360</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 20:43:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637181795</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:43:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ec3e46f0-47e5-11ec-aedf-ac3eb0d5ef9a" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ec3e46f0-47e5-11ec-aedf-ac3eb0d5ef9a" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Fisker]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Fisker Ocean]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Fisker Ocean]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Headspace gives US teens free access to its mental health app]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After <a href="https://www.engadget.com/headspace-new-york-state-of-mind-website-205305471.html">offering free mental health exercises </a>at the beginning of the pandemic, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Headspace " href="https://fave.co/3mQA8Hp">Headspace </a>has announced that it&#39;s opening up its service for free to a particularly vulnerable group for mental stressors: teens. The company&#39;s new <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211116005910/en/Headspace-Health-Announces-New-Nonprofit-Initiative-to-Provide-Free-Access-to-Headspace-for-All-Teens-Ages-13-18-in-the-United-States">Headspace for Teens</a> initiative is fairly straightforward: Kids between 13 and 18 will be able to access a selection of exercises — including things to help you reduce stress, focus on being mindful and sleep better — at no charge. The only requirement is that they sign up to be members of the youth-focused non-profits <a href="https://bringchange2mind.org/">Bring Change to Mind </a>or <a href="https://www.peerhealthexchange.org/">Peer Health Exchange</a>. Headspace says it also plans to extend the free offering throughout the world as it partners with more non-profits.</p><p>“Through our research, we see that teens today are under a great deal of stress and experience high levels of anxiety due to the demands of school, their jobs, extracurriculars, social life, and a general uncertainty about their futures,” Alice Nathoo, Head of Social Impact at Headspace, said in a statement. “Even though many teens have an awareness of and vocabulary for mental health issues, this doesn&#39;t always translate to action.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Headspace for Teens follows a similar program focused on <a href="https://www.headspace.com/educators">bringing mental health support to educators</a>. To reach a more general audience, the company also created <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-headspace-unwind-your-mind-june-15-170552142.html">three shows for Netflix</a>, including an interactive entry similar to <em>Black Mirror: Bandersnatch. </em></p><p>Given just how anxiety-inducing the world can be these days, it makes sense for Headspace to give people a taste of the benefits from meditation, de-stressing and solid sleep habits. It&#39;s no replacement for a therapist — as we&#39;ve explored in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-24-how-to-find-therapy-therapist-online-teletherapy-coronavirus-quarantine.html">our guide to finding at-home mental health support during the pandemic</a> — but Headspace&#39;s offerings still have the potential to help many people.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/headspace-teen-free-mental-health-mindfulness-201524262.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b0045c5a-ce19-4f34-ae5c-424f61b8cbb6</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 20:25:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637182222</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:50:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Health Care Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/949a0150-47e0-11ec-ad7f-228afb7cee9a" width="5760" height="3840" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/949a0150-47e0-11ec-ad7f-228afb7cee9a" width="5760" height="3840" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[myshkovsky via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[[url=http://www.istockphoto.com/search/lightbox/13849533#16e2cd7a t=_blank]
[img]http://i445.photobucket.com/albums/qq173/myshkovsky/Autumn1_zpseb84cdab.jpg[/img][/url]
[url=http://www.istockphoto.com/file_search.php?action=file&lightboxID=10864542 t=_blank]
[img]http://i445.photobucket.com/albums/qq173/myshkovsky/Woman_zps9b186ea6.jpg[/img][/url]

African descent woman enjoying autumn sunlight.
Camera: Canon EOS 5D Mark III
Lens: Carl Zeiss 50mm macro
post processing.

[url=file_closeup?id=29322174][img]/file_thumbview/29322174/1[/img][/url]]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Young woman enjoying autumn sunlight outdoors]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify's paid podcast subscriptions are now available outside of the US]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You no longer have to live in the US to try <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-podcast-subscriptions-expansion-130049542.html">Spotify&#39;s paid podcast subscriptions</a>. Spotify and Anchor are <a href="https://blog.anchor.fm/updates/podcast-subscriptions-global">rolling out</a> Podcast Subscriptions to 33 new markets over the next week. A total of 29 markets have access as of today (November 17th), including the UK, Australia and Hong Kong. Listeners in Austria, Canada, France and Germany will have to wait until November 22nd.</p><p>The system remains the same. Podcasters can charge extra to unlock special or ad-free episodes, offer early access and otherwise offer perks to listeners willing to pay. Producers keep all the revenue aside from basic transaction fees until 2023, with Spotify taking a five percent cut afterward.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This was arguably overdue. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-podcast-subscriptions-172016084.html">Apple added paid subscriptions</a> to its Podcasts app in May, and made them available in 170 countries and regions. Spotify was effectively handing customers to Apple in those areas where it didn&#39;t have a paid option. While it&#39;s not yet clear that these paid memberships represent a large revenue stream, Spotify might not have wanted to take any chances.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-anchor-paid-subscriptions-expansion-200455419.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9227ee7b-97f2-4a0d-b232-a6df68c5b296</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 20:04:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637179497</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:05:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/5c6ded00-9930-11eb-bfed-a0e05b766f83" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/5c6ded00-9930-11eb-bfed-a0e05b766f83" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Spotify logo is seen displayed on a phone screen in this illustration photo taken in Poland on October 3, 2020. 
 (Photo Illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Spotify Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[PlayStation head Jim Ryan criticizes Activision Blizzard response to sexual harassment scandal]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It turns out Blizzard employees weren’t the only ones to express frustration with their company and CEO Bobby Kotick after <em>The Wall Street Journal</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-call-for-bobby-kotick-resignation-194953539.html">published an explosive report</a> on the ongoing sexual harassment scandal at the publisher. In an email obtained by <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-17/playstation-chief-criticizes-activision-response-to-allegations"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>, Sony Interactive CEO Jim Ryan critiqued Activision’s response to the article. Ryan linked Sony employees to the report, and said he was “disheartened and frankly stunned to read” <em>The Journal’s</em> findings.</p><p>“We outreached to Activision immediately after the article was published to express our deep concern and to ask how they plan to address the claims made in the article,” Ryan says in the message. “We do not believe their statements of response properly address the situation.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As the company that makes the PlayStation 4 and PS5, Sony is one of Activision’s most important partners. Their close relationship is highlighted by the fact Sony has first dibs on some <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-06-15-playstation-is-the-new-home-of-call-of-duty-first-with-beta-a.html"><em>Call of Duty</em> content</a>. The fact Ryan’s email leaked shouldn’t come as a surprise given that it was an all-hands message.</p><p>Broadly,<em> The Wall Street Journal </em>report claims Kotick was not only aware of many of the allegations of sexual misconduct and harassment at the company, but that he may have also intervened to protect some of its worst offenders, and that he mistreated women himself. In a statement to Engadget, a spokesperson for the publisher said the article presents a “misleading view of Activision Blizzard and our CEO.” Shortly after it started circulating widely on social media, Blizzard employees announced they would stage a walkout. Hours later, Activision Blizzard’s board of directors <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211116006294/en/Activision-Blizzard-Board-of-Directors-Issues-Statement-Regarding-Recent-Article">issued a statement</a> expressing its continued support of Kotick’s leadership.&nbsp;</p><p>According to a report published by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/culture/activision-blizzard-doubles-down-on-kotick-defense-in-all-hands-meeting"><em>Game Developer</em></a>, Activision Blizzard also defended Kotick during an all-hands meeting the company hosted after <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> published its report. When asked if its new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-ends-forced-arbitration-151427460.html">zero-tolerance policy</a> would apply to the executive, the company told employees it did not &quot;have evidence&quot; of the claims against Kotick due to the fact they relate to an incident that happened a decade ago.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Update 3:49PM ET</strong>: Added information from <em>Game Developer</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jim-ryan-email-activision-blizzard-195248273.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bbbc4611-f15d-4fa4-a2b4-e00203d93a20</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:52:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637182516</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:55:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/4d66e1f0-47df-11ec-bc7f-b7696bdf337b" width="5000" height="3696" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/4d66e1f0-47df-11ec-bc7f-b7696bdf337b" width="5000" height="3696" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[DAVID MCNEW via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A man carrying a sign accusing Activision Blizzard CEO Robert A. Kotick of pedophilia is ordered by protest organizers to leave the area as employees of the video game holding company, Activision Blizzard, hold a walkout and protest rally to denounce the companys response to a California Department of Fair Employment and Housing lawsuit and to call for changes in conditions for women and other marginalized groups, in Irvine, California, on July 28, 2021.  (Photo by DAVID MCNEW / AFP) (Photo by DAVID MCNEW/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-IT-GAMES-SEXISM-ACTIVISION]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok takes more action against hoaxes and dangerous challenges]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/tiktok/">TikTok</a> has pledged to do more to combat the spread of hoaxes and dangerous challenges. Many TikTok challenges are harmless and fun. Others are riskier, such as this year&#39;s milk crate challenge, which led to a spate of injuries. But well-intentioned parents and other adults who want to warn others about dangerous challenges can inadvertently raise awareness of them — even if those challenges are fake.</p><p>The company <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/helping-our-community-stay-safe-while-having-fun-on-tiktok">commissioned a survey</a> of more than 10,000 teens, parents and teachers in several countries, including the US and UK. It found that 31 percent of teens had taken part in some kind of online challenge.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Teens were asked about the risk level of a challenge they&#39;d seen online recently, not necessarily on TikTok. Around 48 percent said the challenge was safe, 32 percent said it had a little risk and 14 percent described it as risky or dangerous. Respondents said three percent of challenges were &quot;very dangerous,&quot; while 0.3 percent said they&#39;d taken part in a challenge they categorized in that way.</p><p>The study found that 46 percent of teens want more information and help to understand the risks of challenges, while 31 percent said they &quot;felt a negative impact&quot; from hoaxes related to self harm and suicide. Recognizing and dealing with hoaxes isn&#39;t necessarily easy. Thirty-seven percent of the adult respondents say they find it difficult to discuss self-harm and suicide hoaxes without drawing attention to them.</p><p>TikTok says it already removes hoaxes and takes action to limit their spread, but it&#39;s planning to do more. It will take down &quot;alarmist warning&quot; videos about fake self-harm challenges. &quot;The research showed how warnings about self-harm hoaxes — even if shared with the best of intentions — can impact the well-being of teens since they often treat the hoax as real,&quot; TikTok said. &quot;We will continue to allow conversations to take place that seek to dispel panic and promote accurate information.&quot;</p><p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-05-adults-only-ones-fooled-momo-challenge-hoax.html"><ins>Momo Challenge</ins></a>, for instance, was an infamous viral hoax that a lot of people fell for a couple of years ago. Its spread was exacerbated by those sounding the alarm about the &quot;challenge,&quot; which many falsely claimed was urging kids to harm themselves.</p><p>Other safety improvements TikTok has made include expanding &quot;technology that helps alert our safety teams to sudden increases in violating content linked to hashtags.&quot; Whenever a user searches for content linked to a hoax or dangerous challenge, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-will-warn-users-in-search-results-for-distressing-content-120042064.html">they&#39;ll see a warning label</a>.</p><p>The company worked with a clinical child psychiatrist and a behavioral scientist to improve the language of the label. Users who search for hoaxes and harmful challenges will be encouraged to visit TikTok&#39;s Safety Center to learn about <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/en-us/online-challenges/"><ins>how to recognize them</ins></a>. If the search is connected to a hoax linked to suicide or self harm, they&#39;ll see resources such as contact details for the National Suicide Prevention Helpline.</p><p><em>In the US, the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255. Crisis Text Line can be reached by texting HOME to 741741 (US), 686868 (Canada), or 85258 (UK). Wikipedia maintains </em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_suicide_crisis_lines"><em>a list of crisis lines</em></a><em> for people outside of those countries.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-hoax-dangerous-challenge-action-teens-survey-193111320.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">551bb2ad-b208-4532-8d89-f91ed08c1251</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:31:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637177474</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T19:31:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/2adfc360-e6b8-11ea-9f7b-34c49be5c0ed" width="3503" height="2335" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/2adfc360-e6b8-11ea-9f7b-34c49be5c0ed" width="3503" height="2335" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HAIKOU, HAINAN, CHINA - 2020/08/23: In this photo illustration, a TikTok logo seen displayed on a smartphone with a computer in the background.
ByteDance, parent company of popular video-sharing app TikTok on Sunday confirmed it would be filing a lawsuit on Monday local time against the Trump administration over the executive order signed by President Donald Trump banning its service in the United States. (Photo Illustration by Sheldon Cooper/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, a TikTok logo seen displayed on...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify strikes a multi-year deal with J.J. Abrams' new podcast unit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spotify&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-wwe-podcast-network-greenroompodcast-180202849.html">growing podcast ambitions</a> now include a pact with a big studio before it truly gets started. The streaming music service has <a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-11-17/j-abrams-bad-robot-forges-new-audio-division-in-collaboration-with-spotify/">struck</a> a multi-year deal that gives it &quot;first look&quot; access to podcasts from J.J. Abrams&#39; new Bad Robot Audio unit. The move lets Spotify snap up exclusives from Bad Robot&#39;s planned mix of fiction and non-fiction shows.</p><p>Bad Robot Audio hasn&#39;t yet detailed its releases, but it will have an experienced leader. Christina Choi will helm the new outfit after directing content partnerships at Audible, and before that a creative development executive at Spotify. She played an important role in Spotify&#39;s early podcast efforts, and is unsurprisingly eager to collaborate with her former employer in her field of expertise.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The move could be a coup for Spotify if Bad Robot&#39;s podcast group fares as well as its better-known video team. Spotify has numerous major exclusives from narrowly-focused partners like WWE, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-06-spotify-barack-michelle-obama-podcast-higher-ground.html">the Obamas</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/armchair-expert-podcast-spotify-exclusive-dax-shepard-180052195.html">Dax Shepard</a>, but alliances with general studios on this level are decidedly less common. This arrangement might produce top shows in a wider variety of genres, and could include some well-known voices in the bargain.</p><p>For Bad Robot, this is part of a broader expansion into the digital realm. J.J. Abrams&#39; company has been shifting toward <a href="https://www.engadget.com/batman-caped-crusader-jj-abrams-hbo-max-143618065.html">streaming shows</a>, and last year branched out to gaming with Bad Robot Games. There&#39;s a clear effort to create a media empire that reaches well beyond conventional video, and podcasts represent a significant next step.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-bad-robot-audio-jj-abrams-podcasts-182214760.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">43e8b833-d4af-4f88-8a7f-be9a4b191967</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 18:22:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637175311</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T18:55:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c576f110-47d7-11ec-bb5d-214072eb220f" width="3712" height="2474" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c576f110-47d7-11ec-bb5d-214072eb220f" width="3712" height="2474" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[VALERIE MACON/AFP via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[J.J. Abrams in a tux waving to the camera.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[J.J. Abrams]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass cloud gaming arrives on consoles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-xbox-console-cloud-gaming-test-insiders-190628810.html"><ins>limited test</ins></a> in September, Microsoft has <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/11/17/xbox-cloud-gaming-launches-on-console/">begun rolling out</a> cloud gaming support to additional Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S consoles. While the feature is still in beta, it’s now available to select Xbox console owners in <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/regions"><ins>25 markets</ins></a>. Over the coming weeks, the company plans to scale the service to all Xbox systems in those regions. As before, you’ll need a Game Pass Ultimate subscription to use the service, but it’s no longer necessary to take part in the Alpha Skip-Ahead and Alpha Insider programs.</p><p>Microsoft envisions a handful of scenarios where the ability to stream a game will be helpful. To start, it’s a way for people to try a Game Pass title without downloading it first. In much the same way, it also allows you to jump into a multiplayer game with your friends, even if you don’t have that title installed. Lastly, for Xbox One owners, it’s a chance to play Xbox Series X/S titles like <em>The Medium</em> and <em>The Riftbreaker</em>. For the best possible experience, you’ll still want to download your favorite games to your console. You’ll know if you can stream a Game Pass title if it has a cloud icon.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/xbox-cloud-gaming-beta-180329068.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7717a823-0544-40ef-b2b7-dc61b1d6c279</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 18:03:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637172282</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T18:04:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Employment & Career]]></category><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/3916b760-1faf-11eb-ac6f-2e9f202b4a1b" width="2000" height="1344" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/3916b760-1faf-11eb-ac6f-2e9f202b4a1b" width="2000" height="1344" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Jessica Conditt / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Xbox Series S]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Xbox Series S]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft is replacing Windows Media Player with Media Player for Windows 11]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> has built a new media playback app for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">Windows 11</a> to supplant both Windows Media Player, which hasn&#39;t really changed since 2009, and the Groove Music app. Windows Insiders can <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/11/16/new-media-player-for-windows-11-begins-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders/">start testing</a> the creatively named Media Player for Windows 11 now.</p><p>The app is designed for both music and video playback. If you&#39;ve been clinging onto the Groove Music app to manage your library of tracks, even after <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-02-microsoft-drops-groove-music-in-favor-of-spotify.html">Microsoft axed Groove Music services in 2017</a>, you&#39;ll be able to update it to the new Media Player. Your library and playlists will automatically migrate over, as <a href="https://gizmodo.com/microsoft-is-replacing-windows-media-player-with-an-app-1848074365"><em>Gizmodo</em></a> notes.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a58a9a20-47cb-11ec-bef8-39cb40524679" alt="A screenshot showing the music library in the Media Player for Windows 11 app." data-uuid="071709c0-e269-3f03-bbf8-867da3cc310c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Microsoft says users will be able to quickly browse their library to find what they want to listen to, and create and manage playlists. During playback, you&#39;ll see album art and &quot;rich artist imagery&quot; in both full screen and mini-player modes. The app will add files from your PC&#39;s music and video folders too. Through the settings, users can tell Media Player where else to look for things to bring to the library.</p><p>There are accessibility-focused options in the app too. Microsoft says those include &quot;improved keyboard shortcut and access key support for keyboard users and with other assistive technologies.&quot;</p><p>Media Player currently has a couple of issues, Microsoft notes, including ones that affect playback from some network locations, editing album metadata and library content with accented characters. You&#39;ll still be able to access the old version of Windows Media Player through Windows Tools.</p><p>Of course, the Media Player design reflects the clean aesthetic of Windows 11. The app looks nice and it&#39;s the cherry on top of a long, long-awaited overhaul of Windows Media Player. It&#39;s a bit of a shame that Microsoft chose such a boring name for the new app, but at least users shouldn&#39;t be confused about what it does.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/windows-media-player-windows-11-microsoft-music-video-174907728.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bb71a266-93ce-41d5-a7e2-028cd63b3d57</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:49:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637171251</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T17:47:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a1f58c80-47cb-11ec-bcdf-cc672e8cf68f" width="2152" height="1491" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/a1f58c80-47cb-11ec-bcdf-cc672e8cf68f" width="2152" height="1491" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A screenshot showing music playback in the Media Player for Windows 11 app, with including album art.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Media Player for Windows 11]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nissan starts taking reservations for its $46,000 Ariya crossover EV]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nissan is finally ready to offer pricing and other tangible details for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nissan-electric-car-ariya-052306996.html">electric Ariya crossover</a>. The automaker has <a href="https://usa.nissannews.com/en-US/releases/reservations-now-open-for-all-new-2023-nissan-ariya-electric-crossover">started</a> taking <a href="https://www.nissanusa.com/ariya/reserve/venture+">reservations</a> for the Ariya beginning at $45,950 for the Venture+ model. That&#39;s more than the $40,000 ballpark from before, but still brings the price down to $38,450 with a federal tax credit. The Venture+ may be the best model for long drives, too. You&#39;ll have only a 238HP motor with front wheel drive, but you&#39;ll get the longest estimated range at 300 miles. The higher-capacity 87kWh battery is standard on all currently announced models.</p><p>The $48,950 Evolve+ builds on that formula with an &quot;around view&quot; monitor and a powered moonroof, albeit with a shorter 285-mile range. The reservation-only Premiere trim starts at $53,450, but gives you access to the Ariya&#39;s signature &quot;Sunrise Copper&quot; color, hands-off highway driving from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-16-nissan-skyline-propilot-2-driver-assist.html">ProPilot Assist 2.0</a> and ProPilot Park. If you want all-wheel drive, you&#39;ll currently have to splurge on the $58,950 Platinum+ variant with 389HP, a hands-free liftgate, Nappa leather and a reduced 265-mile range.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>All models are due to arrive in fall 2022. You&#39;ll need to place a $500 refundable deposit and choose a preferred dealer, but you can complete the final purchase online and have the Ariya delivered to your home. You won&#39;t have to wade through the usual hassles of in-person dealership sales.</p><p>The price slots the Ariya between the $39,995 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volkswagens-id-4-ev-is-the-basic-people-mover-youve-been-waiting-for-163027836.html">Volkswagen ID.4</a> and Tesla&#39;s Model Y (currently $58,990), with the in-between range and features to match. It may face tough competition as a result. However, that might be the precise appeal — this is a middle-of-the-road EV from a well-known badge. Where the Leaf was aimed at early adopters (and lately <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nissans-entry-level-leaf-is-now-the-cheapest-ev-in-the-us-at-27400-053932185.html">the cost-conscious</a>), the Ariya promises to be a thoroughly mainstream vehicle that reaches more first-time EV owners and helps Nissan electrify the rest of its lineup.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nissan-ariya-ev-price-reservations-171536739.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">52e25066-f688-4efc-b56f-3728da49893a</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:15:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637180395</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T20:19:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/525304d0-47c3-11ec-bbcf-7128c79ae7af" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/525304d0-47c3-11ec-bbcf-7128c79ae7af" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nissan]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Nissan 2023 Ariya electric crossover SUV]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Nissan 2023 Ariya electric crossover SUV]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tascam's Portacapture X8 is a beefy portable recorder with a smartphone-like interface]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most <a href="https://www.engadget.com/advanced-podcast-buyers-guide-part-1-143053492.html"><ins>portable recorders</ins></a> come with an array of physical buttons, switches and toggles. It’s part of what makes them practical and charming to use. But with its new <a href="https://tascam.jp/us/product/portacapture_x8/feature"><ins>Portacapture X8, </ins></a>Tascam wants to make the case for a touchscreen interface.</p><div id="c3cf9d7e2eb0465390c5df16ec4067ba"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NzgMz5m-GHc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The X8 isn’t the first portable recorder to go down the smartphone route. <a href="https://zoomcorp.com/en/jp/handy-recorders/handheld-recorders/H8/"><ins>Zoom’s H8</ins></a> has a touchscreen display too, but it’s smaller and the interface isn’t as modern as the one offered by Tascam. The X8’s software has an emphasis on presets that the company says help to simplify the process of picking the optimal settings for a specific situation. You can also control the device remotely with your smartphone if you purchase Tascam’s AK-BT1 Bluetooth adapter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Portacapture X8 features two 14.6mm condenser microphones that support 32-bit float point recording. Since you can detach the microphones from the device, there’s the possibility Tascam will release optional capsules down the road. It’s possible to reposition the microphones in either an A/B or X/Y orientation. With four XLR/TRS inputs (and two mix tracks), you can use the X8 to record up to eight tracks simultaneously. You’ll also find a dedicated headphone jack on the device, in addition to external in and line-out connections. A built-in USB-C port also allows you to use the device as an audio interface.</p><p>Tascam hasn’t said how much the X8 will cost. But as an H8 competitor, we imagine it will fall somewhere in the $400 range. That’s a lot to spend on a portable recorder, but for prosumers, it comes with a lot of desirable features.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tascam-portacapture-x8-annoucement-170543095.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4eb388cc-0a2d-4e09-b284-80e951da22b9</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:05:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637168747</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T17:05:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/88e166a0-47c7-11ec-9fed-0d52bf99af4f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/88e166a0-47c7-11ec-9fed-0d52bf99af4f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Tascam]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tascam Portacapture X8]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tascam Portacapture X8]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Alien: Isolation' is coming to iOS and Android on December 16th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most memorable survival horror games of recent years is coming to smartphones and tablets. Feral Interactive will bring <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/alien%20isolation/"><em>Alien: Isolation</em></a> to <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/alien-isolation/id1573029040">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.feralinteractive.alienisolation_android">Android</a> on December 16th.</p><p>Feral, which also handled <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-11-alien-isolation-for-switch.html">the Nintendo Switch port</a> of the 2014 game, claims it has replicated the &quot;stunning AAA visuals, arresting narrative and terrifying atmosphere of Creative Assembly’s award-winning sci-fi masterpiece&quot; for mobile devices &quot;without compromise.&quot; It added customizable touchscreen controls, though you can connect an external controller. The game, which costs $15, includes all seven DLC packs.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="c02a92723c02478e95f174aae50067c5"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DboBLkA5WRw?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p><em>Alien: Isolation </em>is set 15 years after Ridley Scott&#39;s classic sci-fi horror film <em>Alien</em>. Players take on the guise of engineer Amanda Ripley, who attempts to get to the bottom of her mother Ellen Ripley&#39;s disappearance.&nbsp;</p><p>Creative Assembly <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-10-03-alien-isolation-review-escape-claws.html">did a great job</a> of replicating the terrifying atmosphere of the original movie. The first-person perspective certainly adds to the feeling of dread as you try to evade a xenomorph. Whether <em>Alien: Isolation</em> feels as immersive on mobile as it does on consoles and PC remains to be seen, though the Switch port was <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/switch/alien-isolation">well-received</a>.</p><p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://twitter.com/XboxGamePass/status/1460653904820006914">as of Tuesday</a>, Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers can play another classic survival horror game on their phone. <em>Dead Space </em>is now part of the cloud gaming library, thanks to Microsoft&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ea-play-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-pc-november-10-december-135548415.html">partnership with EA Play</a>. <em>Alien: Isolation </em>is also available on Game Pass, albeit only on console and PC, not through the cloud.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/alien-isolation-ios-android-release-date-163249099.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8691fb7d-0209-4bab-84b2-98ebe0e208ee</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 16:32:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637168215</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T16:57:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/38833670-47c7-11ec-967f-39221dba23a8" width="1912" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/38833670-47c7-11ec-967f-39221dba23a8" width="1912" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Creative Assembly/Feral Interactive/Sega]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Xenomorph in 'Alien: Isolation'.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Alien: Isolation']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[LA's iconic Staples Center will become the Crypto.com Arena]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/bitcoin-taproot-privacy-security-code-upgrade-212648233.html">Cryptocurrency</a> will soon be inescapable in Los Angeles, at least for a while. AEG has <a href="https://www.aegworldwide.com/press-center/press-releases/aeg-and-cryptocom-lead-future-creative-capital-sports-music-and">signed</a> a 20-year rights agreement that will rename LA&#39;s Staples Center to the Crypto.com Arena. Yes, the Clippers, Lakers, Kings and Sparks will all play in a building named after a crypto platform — more forward-thinking than office supplies, but still a bit strange in 2021. The deal will make Crypto.com the official cryptocurrency partner for the Lakers and Kings, too.</p><p>You&#39;ll see the internal signage and some other branding when the Lakers play the Brooklyn Nets on Christmas Day, although the arena operators won&#39;t fully replace external signs until June 2022. You&#39;ll also see &quot;designations&quot; at other properties, such as LA Live and the Microsoft Theater, and there will be Crypto.com experiences at the entrance, main concourse and LA Live campus.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>AEG chief Dan Beckerman characterized the deal as focusing on &quot;the future,&quot; both for innovation as a whole and the community. That&#39;s somewhat ironic when cryptocurrency has been accused of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-bitcoin-221708146.html">hurting the environment</a>, but Crypto.com has pledged to be carbon negative by late 2022 (if only through offsets).</p><p>The 20-year deal makes clear this isn&#39;t just a temporary marketing stunt. Even so, this is something of a gamble for both AEG and Crypto.com. They&#39;re betting that cryptocurrency is here to stay, and that Crypto.com will play an important role in the long term. Both are distinct possibilities when mainstream companies like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amc-theaters-start-accepting-cryptocurrency-113811626.html">AMC</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-crypto-announcement-192211751.html">Twitter</a> are exploring uses of digital money, but a lot can change in the space of two decades.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/los-angeles-staples-center-renamed-crypto-com-arena-155600573.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">723b5f4c-e634-48ff-aba5-792085d58335</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 15:56:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637164567</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T15:56:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/67d0d7d0-47b7-11ec-bb9e-47e1cb81fbf4" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/67d0d7d0-47b7-11ec-bb9e-47e1cb81fbf4" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AEG Worldwide]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Staples Center renamed as Crypto.com Arena]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Los Angeles Staples Center renamed as Crypto.com Arena]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tidal adds a free tier and brings HiFi audio to its $10 plan]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/tidal/"><ins>Tidal</ins></a> is adding a free, ad-supported tier as it seeks to expand its user base. The option, which is only available in the US for now, <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tidal-launches-their-first-ever-free-music-tier-two-enhanced-hifi-tiers-and-new-ways-to-get-artists-paid-301426774.html"><ins>includes access</ins></a> to Tidal&#39;s entire library of 80 million songs as well as playlists. The service <a href="https://twitter.com/TIDAL/status/1460972114253602824"><ins>noted on Twitter</ins></a> that it&#39;s introducing the free tier to &quot;remain competitive&quot; with its rivals, eight months after Square <a href="https://www.engadget.com/square-buys-control-of-tidal-142318706.html"><ins>bought a majority stake</ins></a> in the company. Tidal says the plan is rolling out on Android and &quot;will be available on all devices in the coming days.&quot;</p><p>There are some trade-offs beyond occasional ads, of course. The audio quality tops out at 160 kbps, there&#39;s no offline listening option and it doesn&#39;t appear that you&#39;ll have unlimited skips. The later feature is mentioned explicitly as part of the revamped $10/month Tidal HiFi plan.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Tidal <a href="https://twitter.com/TIDAL/status/1460972116006903809"><ins>says</ins></a> users on that plan can now listen to music in HiFi quality — up to 1,411 kbps. There are no ads and you&#39;ll gain access to more than 350,000 videos. Users can listen to music in HiFi quality on connected devices through Tidal Connect, and they&#39;ll be able to track and share what they&#39;re listening to via a new activity feed.</p><p>In addition, there&#39;s a $20/month HiFi Plus plan. It includes everything from the HiFi tier, as well as master-quality audio at up to 9,216 kbps. The plan also offers immersive, spatial audio formats, such as Dolby Atmos and Sony 360 Reality Audio, and early access to upcoming features. Both HiFi plans are available in all countries in which Tidal operates.</p><p>What&#39;s more, the HiFi Plus tier has a couple of new features centered around artists. One of those is direct-to-artist payments, which Tidal is rolling out today. Every month, 10 percent of a HiFi Plus user&#39;s subscription fees (i.e. $2) will go to the artist they listen to the most. That&#39;s on top of regular streaming royalties. It&#39;s another way for users to support their favorite artists.</p><div id="d8f055f523eb45c19a8edf32c7e3f56e"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fan-Centered Royalties will not be aggregated.<br><br>Instead, royalties will go to the artists that TIDAL users actually stream, so fans can directly support the artists they love. (What a concept, right?)<br><br>This will start in January 2022 at our HiFi Plus tier. <a href="https://t.co/Q8z4fleYOc">pic.twitter.com/Q8z4fleYOc</a></p>— TIDAL (@TIDAL) <a href="https://twitter.com/TIDAL/status/1460972135212593155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Starting in January, Tidal will roll out a revamped artist payment system called fan-centered royalties. Every time a HiFi Plus user listens to one of their songs, they&#39;ll receive a <a href="https://twitter.com/TIDAL/status/1460972128753307649"><ins>&quot;significantly higher&quot;</ins></a> per-stream payment than other music streaming services&#39; payouts. Apple Music <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-streaming-payment-rate-spotify-162320807.html">pays</a> a penny per stream, while artists have long been <a href="https://pitchfork.com/news/musicians-organize-global-protests-at-spotify-offices/">asking Spotify</a> for a similar rate.</p><p>Tidal says &quot;royalties attributed to HiFi Plus subscribers will not be aggregated.&quot; Payments will be tied to each individual user&#39;s listening activity, but only on that tier. HiFi Plus users will be able to see how those payments are divvied up through their activity feed.</p><p>In addition to revamping the payment model, Tidal is aiming to ensure &quot;quick and seamless&quot; payouts to artists around the world. It&#39;s working with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/square/"><ins>Square</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/cash%20app/"><ins>Cash App</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/paypal/"><ins>PayPal</ins></a> to facilitate those.</p><p>These are bold, but perhaps necessary moves by Tidal as it aims to become more competitive with larger music streaming services. Tidal was one of the first major proponents of lossless audio, but as rivals started offering that option at no extra cost, it more or less had to bring that option to the $10/month plan.</p><p>Apple Music <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-lossless-dolby-atmos-131659010.html"><ins>added</ins></a> lossless and Dolby Atmos spatial audio features in June. Amazon Music Unlimited <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-music-unlimited-plans-hd-streaming-included-135249659.html"><ins>dropped the premium fee</ins></a> for HD and Ultra HD streaming in May. It too offers <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-music-spatial-audio-headphones-ios-android-dolby-atmos-sony-360-reality-audio-142301483.html"><ins>spatial audio</ins></a> as part of the regular plan.</p><p>Meanwhile, many of Tidal&#39;s rivals have long offered ad-supported free streaming options, including Spotify, Amazon Music, Deezer and YouTube Music. At the opposite end of the scale, Spotify <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-hifi-select-markets-premium-cd-quality-audio-2021-165438547.html"><ins>announced plans</ins></a> in February to roll out a CD-quality audio plan, also called HiFi, in select markets at some point this year. It has yet to do so.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tidal-free-streaming-plan-artist-paymetns-royalties-153606001.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4c244d04-d092-4cd0-adf9-b5ef81752451</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 15:36:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637163369</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T15:36:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5e4d34d0-47ba-11ec-bfe9-6cbd4dea05c1" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5e4d34d0-47ba-11ec-bfe9-6cbd4dea05c1" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BARCELONA, CATALONIA, SPAIN - 2021/07/26: In this photo illustration a Tidal app seen displayed on a smartphone and in the background. (Photo Illustration by Thiago Prudêncio/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration a Tidal app seen displayed on a...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mercedes’ EQS sets the bar for luxury EVs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="cd0da4e3bd38470ca48df181788c2e57"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FvQ0MSPDVnM?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The need to electrify its lineup could have resulted in Mercedes tossing an EV powertrain in its S-Class. Instead, it made the correct decision to create an EV-specific vehicle, the EQS.</p><p>With nearly all of the trappings of the S-Class, the EQS sets a new standard in luxury for the EV world. From the Hyperscreen to the comfortable and luxurious interior, the vehicle is almost exactly what the automaker needed to bring to the market as it jumps feet first in the world of electrification. Just don’t expect your tall friends to enjoy the rear seats. Watch the video above for the full story.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mercedes-eqs-ev-review-video-150001883.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b206a66a-8e92-4e9c-8458-9a880653d7e5</guid><dc:creator>Roberto Baldwin</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637159651</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T14:34:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Roberto Baldwin]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/45fa11d0-47b2-11ec-bdbc-0fdd5bad43fb" width="1920" height="1196" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/45fa11d0-47b2-11ec-bdbc-0fdd5bad43fb" width="1920" height="1196" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Mercedes EQS]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Mercedes EQS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's self service program will let you repair iPhones and Macs yourself]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple just became much friendlier to do-it-yourself repairs. The company is <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/11/apple-announces-self-service-repair/">launching</a> a Self Service Repair program that will let you repair products yourself using official Apple parts and tools. The option will be available in the US in early 2022 (later that year for other countries) and will initially give the resources to fix an iPhone 12 or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-and-13-mini-review-130035113.html">iPhone 13</a> (you&#39;re looking at <a href="https://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/iPhone+13+Pro+Teardown/144928">iFixit&#39;s</a> iPhone 13 Pro teardown above), with M1-based Macs eligible soon afterward.</p><p>The first &quot;phase&quot; of Self Service Repair will focus on core components like the battery, camera and display, with other parts eligible later. Apple will ask customers to review a repair manual and then order relevant parts through a Self Service Repair Online Store. The company didn&#39;t say how much parts would cost, but did offer credit to customers who return used parts for recycling.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Not surprisingly, Apple stressed that the program was meant for people with experience repairing electronics. The &quot;vast majority&quot; of people were still better off getting service from professionals, whether at Apple stores or authorized providers.&nbsp;</p><p>The company didn&#39;t say what prompted the openness to self servicing. However, it may be a matter of government pressure. The White House, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-right-to-repair-policy-statement-203721173.html">the Federal Trade Commission</a> and multiple states have backed right-to-repair measures that could force Apple and others to allow customer maintenance. This theoretically heads off some of the major complaints by letting any skilled person fix a device themselves without resorting to unofficial parts.</p><p>There are lingering questions. Will the part pricing be competitive enough to make Self Service Repair a viable alternative to professional help? And will Apple tweak its product designs to make these repairs more practical? While there are signs of these tweaks between a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-face-id-third-party-replacement-215624361.html">relaxed policy</a> on iPhone 13 display repairs and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ifixit-2021-mac-book-pro-teardown-163032306.html">easy-to-remove MacBook Pro batteries</a>, we wouldn&#39;t expect simple fixes in the near future.</p><p><strong>Update 11/17 11AM ET:</strong> iFixit&#39;s Kyle Wiens told Engadget in a statement that Self Service Repair was &quot;exactly the right thing&quot; for Apple to do, and a step back toward &quot;long-lasting&quot; products. The DIY repair shop still had reservations about display swaps requiring Apple part provisioning, but it was so far happy with the move. You can read the full statement below. Also, the Public Interest Research Groups&#39; right to repair director, Nathan Proctor, <a href="https://mailchi.mp/9af21ee3e564/statement-apple-concedes-to-right-to-repair-movement-reverses-ban-on-selling-parts-to-consumers?e=767d7cbbfe">heralded</a> this as a &quot;major milestone&quot; for self-servicing.</p><blockquote><p>Making service manuals available to consumers is exactly the right thing for Apple to be doing. No one should be in the dark on how to swap a battery or fix a cracked screen. Access to service information for products is a fundamental human right. We are proud of Apple for making this change.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>We won&#39;t know details until we can analyze the legal terms and test the program in January. For now, the catch is that the IRP software requires that Apple provision a part that they sell. You can&#39;t swap the screens between two iPhones and then calibrate them with their service software. That&#39;s an issue for recyclers, refurbishers, and anyone else accustomed to harvesting parts to perform repairs.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Apple leads the electronics industry. They pioneered glued-in batteries and proprietary screws, and now they are taking the first steps on a path back to long-lasting, repairable products. iFixit believes that a sustainable, repairable world of technology is possible, and hope that Apple follows up on this commitment to improve their repairability.</p></blockquote>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-self-service-repair-iphone-mac-142122774.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d38a9958-5ce7-4d09-abbb-974b9638708d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637165090</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T16:05:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b44a09d0-47b0-11ec-9567-0b9e9bf6adc8" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/b44a09d0-47b0-11ec-9567-0b9e9bf6adc8" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[iFixit]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 13 Pro teardown by iFixit]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 13 Pro teardown by iFixit]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Streamlabs accused of copying material for its console streaming platform]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Streamlabs is coming under fire for material used to launch <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-streamlabs-studio-xbox-livestreams-160021753.html">Xbox streaming platform</a> — and beyond. As <em>Eurogamer</em><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-11-17-streamlabs-under-fire-from-rival-software-owners-and-streamers-following-release-of-new-product">reports</a>, rivals have accused the company of copying web material, naming schemes and possibly functionality. Lightstream, for instance, <a href="https://twitter.com/Lightstream/status/1460709404609757185">noted</a> that the initial website for Streamlabs Studio was extremely similar to its own, including (as streamer iamBrandon <a href="https://twitter.com/iamBrandonTV/status/1460717382368993286">discovered</a>) the user reviews. Streamlabs said this was an &quot;error&quot; that put placeholder text on a live site, and the planned copy was now in place.</p><p>That&#39;s only the start of the accusations, however. OBS <a href="https://twitter.com/OBSProject/status/1460782968633499651">complained</a> that Streamlabs used OBS as part of its broadcasting software name (Streamlabs OBS, or SLOBS) despite being asked not to. While Streamlabs has technically honored the terms of the GPL license used for OBS, it allegedly &quot;disregarded the spirit&quot; of open source software. Elgato, meanwhile, even <a href="https://twitter.com/elgato/status/1460722403261046789">implied</a> Streamlabs&#39; Stream Deck was borrowing at least the name (if not features) from its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-28-elgato-stream-deck-xl-ios-app-streaming.html">Stream Deck Mobile app</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We&#39;ve asked Streamlabs for comment. However, the plagiarism accusations have already led to a significant backlash.  Top streamers <a href="https://twitter.com/imane/status/1460818399374692355">Pokimane</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hasanthehun/status/1460815355543130116">Hasanabi</a> have both threatened to stop using Streamlabs&#39; products (and in Pokimane&#39;s case, remove her name from the platform) if it didn&#39;t address the situation. Simply put, Streamlabs might lose some of its best-known customers if it doesn&#39;t act quickly.</p><div id="1fccf36319d8481f87f61686d67df70a"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🤡 Hey, can I copy your homework?<br><br>▽   Yeah, just change it up a bit so it’s not obvious you copied.<br><br>🤡 Bet. <a href="https://t.co/xODY5uDZeP">pic.twitter.com/xODY5uDZeP</a></p>— Lightstream (@Lightstream) <a href="https://twitter.com/Lightstream/status/1460709404609757185?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/streamlabs-accused-of-copying-lightstream-obs-140742760.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6167c391-a5d8-4153-bdb1-f8a8e794c72e</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:07:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637158065</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T14:07:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/293a7780-47ab-11ec-9dfd-5e32c288d98d" width="675" height="461" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/293a7780-47ab-11ec-9dfd-5e32c288d98d" width="675" height="461" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Streamlabs]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Streamlabs Studio and OBS]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Streamlabs Studio and OBS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Uber's $10 One subscription gives you VIP access to rides and deliveries]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Uber is taking another shot <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-30-uber-launches-ride-pass-subscription.html">at subscriptions</a>, and this latest attempt might make sense if you&#39;re as interested in deluxe treatment as you are discounts. The service has <a href="https://www.uber.com/us/en/u/uber-one/">launched</a> an Uber One membership that, for $10 per month or $100 per year, showers you with perks for both ridesharing and Uber Eats deliveries. You&#39;ll get 5 percent off &quot;eligible&quot; trips and food orders as well as free delivery for many grocery and restaurant orders. However, that&#39;s really just the start of the plan.</p><p>One subscribers will get &quot;priority service,&quot; with the highest-rated drivers and upgraded support. You&#39;ll also get exclusive promos, offers and invitation-only &quot;experiences.&quot; There&#39;s even an Uber One Promise that gives you $5 in Uber Cash on qualifying deliveries if the courier misses the latest estimated arrival time. You won&#39;t have to settle for the same service as the commoners, in other words.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The new tier is available now, with a one-month free trial and an early bird promo that offers a year for $50 if you sign up before November 29th.</p><p>This is clearly aimed at Uber&#39;s most frequent customers — the ones who rack up enough rides or deliveries that they might save more than they pay for One. Uber can encourage frequent use while collecting a steady stream of revenue. This also gives it an edge over rivals like Lyft and DoorDash that may only focus on one service category. You may be more likely to stick to Uber knowing you&#39;ll get incentives whether or not you leave home.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uber-one-subscription-140045273.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0bbf7717-2438-42a3-9374-ddb993c9ed87</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637093799</ingested><modified>2021-11-16T20:16:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5a8e9580-4712-11ec-beff-c3eb4d00f6ea" width="4000" height="2621" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5a8e9580-4712-11ec-beff-c3eb4d00f6ea" width="4000" height="2621" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Al Seib via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LAX AIRPORT, CA - AUGUST 20:          Passengers connect with drivers at the Rideshare Lot at LAX as Uber and Lyft drivers held a moving rally as part of a statewide day of action to demand that both ride-hailing companies follow California law and grant drivers basic employee rights and to denounce the corporations efforts to avoid their responsibilities to workers. Uber and Lyft threatened to suspend services in California Thursday night but a court granted Uber and Left a stay to a preliminary injunction requiring both rideshare companies to reclassify their drivers as employees, meaning the rideshare companies will not suspend service in California tonight as they threatened.    Los Angeles on Thursday, Aug. 20, 2020 in LAX Airport, CA. (Al Seib / Los Angeles Times]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Uber and Lyft drivers with the Mobile Workers Alliance held a moving rally as part of a statewide day of action to demand that both ride-hailing companies follow California law and grant drivers basic employee rights and to denounce the corporations effort]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 4th-gen August WiFi smart lock returns to a record low of $180]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:August&#39;s WiFi smart lock" href="https://fave.co/2PQ2RzI">August&#39;s WiFi smart lock</a> is on sale again ahead of Black Friday. Wellbots has the smart home gadget for a record low of $180 when you use the code <strong>ENGADLOCKBF</strong> at checkout. We&#39;ve seen the smart lock go on sale a few times in the past couple of months, but now&#39;s another opportunity to get it before Black Friday proper at its best price yet.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/2PQ2RzI" id="8bc5e90b0c9241ee8ecb72cf1ec78212" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Wellbots;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy August WiFi smart lock at Wellbots - $180</a><p>If you&#39;re unfamiliar, August&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/august-wifi-smart-lock-review-174512379.html">4th-generation WiFi smart lock</a> builds upon the solid foundation of the previous model. It&#39;s noticeably smaller and also doesn&#39;t require a bridge like the previous one did since it connects to WiFi. August&#39;s mobile app will walk you through the setup process, and during that you&#39;ll be forced to turn on two-factor authentication. We appreciate that this is an unskippable step as it adds another layer of security to the device. You&#39;re also getting Bluetooth encryption plus AES 128-bit and TLS encryption with this smart lock, too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The setup process is pretty straightforward, and once installed, you&#39;ll be able to use your smartphone to remotely lock or unlock your door. If and when you want to let a friend or family member inside your home when you&#39;re not there, you can do the unlocking yourself or send them secure virtual keys that will let them get inside. The app also shows you an activity feed, so you can see who opened your door and when. We also like the Auto-Lock and DoorSense features for peace of mind: the former automatically secures the lock when you shut the door and the latter tells you if your door is securely closed, so you don&#39;t have to rush back home if you don&#39;t remember shutting it.</p><p>And just because you&#39;ve made the move to a smart lock doesn&#39;t mean your old-school keys are worthless. You can still use your keys to get inside, which will come in handy on the rare occasions when the smart lock&#39;s dual CR123 batteries need replacing. Just remember to check <a href="https://support.august.com/deadbolt-compatibility-list-rkzJDLyR_G">August&#39;s support page</a> before you buy to make sure your deadbolt is compatible with the device.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><em>All products recommended by Engadget are selected by our editorial team, independent of our parent company. Some of our stories include affiliate links. If you buy something through one of these links, we may earn an affiliate commission.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/august-wifi-smart-lock-4th-generation-returns-to-a-record-low-of-180-140020823.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">382196c8-5f3e-4123-ad83-19e91063405d</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637084088</ingested><modified>2021-11-16T17:34:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/e44e9720-bc76-11ea-9eb7-00cc03e3d519" width="960" height="640" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/e44e9720-bc76-11ea-9eb7-00cc03e3d519" width="960" height="640" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[August Smart Lock 4th gen]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[August Smart Lock 4th gen]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Motorola's latest Moto G Power features a 50-megapixel camera]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Motorola is refreshing the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/motorola-moto-g-pure-android-11-142122282.html">Moto G</a> lineup with an updated Power model. Like the phone itself, it’s not the most exciting update. The 2022 Moto G Power once again features a 5,000mAh battery Motorola claims can provide up to three days of continuous use. This time around, the company has gone with a 6.5-inch display that features a panel with 720p resolution and a 90Hz refresh rate.</p><p>New to this latest model is a tweaked triple camera array highlighted by a 50-megapixel main camera. Motorola claims low-light performance is significantly improved. The 2022 Moto G Power trades the ultra-wide camera of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-07-motorola-moto-g-power-moto-g-stylus-hands-on.html">predecessor</a> for a 2-megapixel macro camera and 2-megapixel depth sensor. For selfies, there’s an 8-megapixel with an f/2.0 aperture lens. With Motorola’s dual capture feature, you can record video footage with both the front- and rear-facing cameras.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Internally, the phone features an octa-core MediaTek Helio G37 processor supported by 4GB of RAM. Motorola will sell the phone in two storage configurations, with the 64GB model costing $200 unlocked, while the 128GB variant will set you back $250. A MicroSD slot allows you to add up to 512GB of additional storage.</p><p>Other notable features include IP52 waterproofing and a fingerprint sensor for authentication. One thing the Moto G Power doesn’t include is a NFC chip, so you won’t be able to use it with Google Pay to make mobile payments. One other thing to note is the Moto G Power is limited to 10W charging. That means it will take a while to charge its 5,000mAh battery. The phone will ship with Android 11 out of the box.</p><p>In the US, the Moto G Power will go on sale “in the coming months” at Republic Wireless and T-Mobile’s Metro flanker brand. At a later date, Verizon, Boost Mobile, Xfinity Mobile, AT&amp;T, Cricket, USCellular and Google Fi will also carry the device, with unlocked availability at Best Buy and Amazon to follow sometime in 2022.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/2022-motorola-moto-g-power-140010550.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fc30dbe5-2f34-4263-a3a6-019f81dde411</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637099004</ingested><modified>2021-11-16T21:43:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/51749680-4725-11ec-baff-71d39b11c2de" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/51749680-4725-11ec-baff-71d39b11c2de" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Moto G Power]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Moto G Power]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's colorful new HomePod mini is on sale for the first time ahead of Black Friday]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple expanded its HomePod mini lineup with three new colors back in October, and now we&#39;re seeing the first discount on those new options, plus the classics. B&amp;H Photo has all of the HomePod mini colors, including the new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:orange" href="https://fave.co/3wXmas0">orange</a>, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:blue" href="https://fave.co/3FqCi86">blue</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:yellow" href="https://fave.co/3HuN2V6">yellow</a> configurations, for $95 each. That&#39;s $5 off their normal price and, while a modest discount, it&#39;s one of the best we&#39;ve seen on the tiny smart speaker.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/32bMqDB" id="74cc502239784594b6382330acde7d42" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy HomePod mini at B&amp;H - $95</a><p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-mini-review-140030652.html">HomePod mini</a> is Apple&#39;s main smart speaker now that it discontinued the original HomePod (although the company still supports that speaker with software updates). It&#39;s also the most compact of the $100 smart speakers, its competition being the Amazon Echo and the Google Nest Audio. It&#39;s a capable device and, like other Apple accessories, arguably best for those who have many Apple products and use services like Apple Music. In addition to its cute design, we liked it for its easy setup and Siri&#39;s prowess with music controls. The voice assistant promptly plays Apple Music albums, playlists and tracks when you ask it too, and you can AirPlay audio from almost any other app (like Spotify and Prime Music) to the HomePod mini. So while the speaker is most convenient for Apple Music subscribers, anyone can use it pretty easily.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Despite being the smallest of the $100 smart speakers, the HomePod mini holds its own against the Nest Audio when it comes to sound quality. Mids and highs are clear and the speaker&#39;s passive radiators help deliver forceful bass. Its &quot;computational audio&quot; feature helps out by adjusting sound accordingly based on what type of music you&#39;re playing. You can also pair two HomePod minis together for stereo sound, and they sound even better this way.</p><p>However, if you&#39;re looking for the best sounding device at $100, we recommend going for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon&#39;s Echo" href="https://amzn.to/3DFCe4d">Amazon&#39;s Echo</a> instead. Siri also lags a bit behind Amazon&#39;s Alexa and the Google Assistant when it comes to smart home control — it&#39;s harder to find HomeKit-supported gadgets than it is to find devices that support either Amazon&#39;s or Google&#39;s voice assistants. But those are relatively small cons if you&#39;re looking for a solid, compact smart speaker, particularly one that shines with Apple Music and works well with Apple devices. And if you&#39;ve been holding out for one of the latest colors, we expect B&amp;H&#39;s sale to be one of the better options this holiday shopping season.</p><p><em>Get the latest Black Friday and Cyber Monday offers by visiting </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/buyers-guide/deals/"><em>our deals homepage</em></a><em> and following </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><em>All products recommended by Engadget are selected by our editorial team, independent of our parent company. Some of our stories include affiliate links. If you buy something through one of these links, we may earn an affiliate commission.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apples-colorful-new-homepod-mini-is-on-sale-for-the-first-time-ahead-of-black-friday-135046185.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bc9941b3-dc7a-48eb-96ef-981ef08ed921</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:50:46 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637157168</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T13:53:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Speakers & Headphones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0df6fb60-3036-11ec-afd7-07a954a8ac88" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0df6fb60-3036-11ec-afd7-07a954a8ac88" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple HomePod Mini]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple HomePod Mini]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple Music arrives on LG's smart TVs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now access your Apple Music account on LG smart TVs even if you don&#39;t have an Apple TV. The music streaming service is now available for all the brand&#39;s TVs running webOS version 4.0 and higher, over a year after it made its debut on TV platforms <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-samsung-smart-tv-140023561.html">with Samsung</a>. Since webOS 4.0 only rolled out in 2018, the Apple Music app will most likely be accessible on newer models.</p><p>If your TV can run Apple Music, you&#39;ll find yourself faced with an interface and navigation similar to what you&#39;ll see if you were using an Apple TV. They&#39;re also visually similar to the Apple Music experience on iPads, iPhones, Android devices and PC. The service&#39;s app for LG can access all its songs, playlists, 4K music videos and livestreamed Apple Music Radio. It supports tracks with time-synced lyrics, as well, so you can sing along while reading the lines on a big screen.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The app&#39;s release on LG smart TVs stays true to Apple&#39;s strategy of focusing more attention on its services and making them available on non-Apple hardware. That way, the tech giant can reach more potential customers who aren&#39;t married to Apple devices and can work towards making its services more veritable rivals to competitors like Spotify and Netflix.&nbsp;</p><div id="32ef76e8eb804e8cb717c5b38cc3b935"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Get ready to turn up the volume 🔊 <a href="https://twitter.com/AppleMusic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AppleMusic</a> is now on LG Smart TVs with over 90 million songs streaming ad-free. <a href="https://t.co/bI3BdbLqjr">pic.twitter.com/bI3BdbLqjr</a></p>— LG Electronics (@LGUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/LGUS/status/1460819992329474054?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-arrives-on-lg-smart-t-vs-124801436.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">67d91011-5625-4715-ac43-4d4d7324db22</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:48:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637153341</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T12:49:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Music]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e4af00e0-479b-11ec-99fb-27af30fe4f13" width="1200" height="675" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/e4af00e0-479b-11ec-99fb-27af30fe4f13" width="1200" height="675" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LG]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: The premium toaster maker that's launching a smartphone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been obsessed with Balmuda’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/balmuda-the-toaster-arrives-in-us-035224029.html">fancy toaster</a> for years. As some readers might know, I used to live in Japan while working for Engadget, and I’d browse around electronics superstores like Yodobashi Camera and Yamada Denki, gawping at high-level cameras, weird 3DS games that would never make it to the West and touring floors upon floors of home appliances and gadgets. There are entire shop floors dedicated to rice cookers, water boilers and the rest. And it is amazing.&nbsp;</p><p>Balmuda’s premium toaster oven was the apex, though. Fortunately, the company’s steam-based toaster has made it to the US in recent years and now, for $329, you can have the fluffiest slices of toasted bread you can imagine. But for <a href="https://japanese.engadget.com/balmuda-002031213.html">those in Japan</a>, Balmuda has now announced its first-ever smartphone.&nbsp;</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/japanese-toaster-maker-balmuda-first-smartphone-112521675.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/ae245320-4798-11ec-91cd-6c22f54c71db" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="6cdef641-354f-3a0a-9af6-8b67653f62a5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Balmuda</div></figure></a><p>It&#39;s a petite device with a full-HD 4.9-inch display. The company teamed up with Kyocera to manufacture the Android device, which has 5G and wireless charging. It comes with a 48-megapixel rear camera, an 8-megapixel front-facing camera and a fingerprint sensor. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/japanese-toaster-maker-balmuda-first-smartphone-112521675.html">Balmuda Phone </a>is powered by a Snapdragon 765 processor and, as you might tell, the device packs relatively middleweight specs. The company may be banking on its premium status to convince smartphone shoppers.</p><p>At the moment, the company doesn’t have plans to release the phone outside Japan.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fender-acoustasonic-player-telecaster-guitar-140315674.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Fender&#39;s latest Acoustasonic hybrid guitar is almost affordable</a></h2><h3>The new guitar is for younger musicians.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fender-acoustasonic-player-telecaster-guitar-140315674.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/378b7450-4798-11ec-96fe-c6b9057aa51a" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="873b5867-5e94-3fa4-b3e3-b24925df29fe"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Fender</div></figure></a><h3></h3><p>Fender&#39;s acoustic-electric hybrid guitars are technical marvels — with a price to reflect that. Now, the instrument brand has unveiled its $1,200 Acoustic Player Telecaster with a simpler design with a three-way voice selector (versus five on other models) and one blend knob.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fender-acoustasonic-player-telecaster-guitar-140315674.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><div class="inline-emphasis"><p><strong>Sponsored by Ledger</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.ledger.com/start-your-crypto-journey?utm_source=Engadget&amp;utm_medium=Partnership_NL&amp;utm_campaign=21-11-Ledger_Awareness-ALL-Brand-Paid_Awareness&amp;utm_content=subj_Global__msg_Ledger_Wallet__other_Yahoo">Interested in crypto? The best way to get started is with Ledger.</a></p><a href="https://www.ledger.com/start-your-crypto-journey?utm_source=Engadget&amp;utm_medium=Partnership_NL&amp;utm_campaign=21-11-Ledger_Awareness-ALL-Brand-Paid_Awareness&amp;utm_content=subj_Global__msg_Ledger_Wallet__other_Yahoo"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/09f80670-4310-11ec-bf7d-f28dd27fac5b" alt="TMA - Ledger November Sponsorship " data-uuid="9984635d-4b54-372a-aefd-ee3cd677d251"><figcaption></figcaption></figure></a><p></p></div><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/internet-outage-google-cloud-spotify-snapchat-down-183917361.html">Google Cloud outage took down Spotify, Snapchat, Etsy and more</a></h2><h3>And yet Gmail and Hangouts were working fine, ugh.</h3><h3></h3><p>A Google Cloud networking issue took down a handful of prominent websites late yesterday, including Spotify, Snapchat, Etsy and Discord. As one colleague put it: “Annoyed that my fun stuff is down, but Slack remains miraculously up, as does other work stuff.” Google announced the issue was partially resolved as of 1:17 PM ET but a full fix didn’t occur until around 3:15 PM ET. Google said it “will publish an analysis of this incident, once we have completed our internal investigation.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/internet-outage-google-cloud-spotify-snapchat-down-183917361.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-call-for-bobby-kotick-resignation-194953539.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Activision Blizzard workers walk out and demand CEO Bobby Kotick&#39;s resignation</a></h2><h3>A new report says Kotick knew about the company&#39;s sexual harassment problems for years.</h3><h3></h3><p>Employees at Activision Blizzard are calling for the resignation of CEO Bobby Kotick following new revelations about the role he may have played in creating the toxic workplace culture that has mired the company. A <em>Wall Street Journal</em> report outlined Kotick&#39;s handling of the sexual harassment lawsuit from California&#39;s Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH). The newspaper claimed Kotick not only knew about many of the worst instances of abuse at the company, but in some cases, he may have also acted to protect employees accused of harassment.</p><p>&quot;We have instituted our own Zero Tolerance Policy,&quot; Activision Blizzard employee advocacy group A Better ABK said on Twitter after the report came out. &quot;We will not be silenced until Bobby Kotick has been replaced as CEO and continue to hold our original demand for Third-Party review by an employee-chosen source.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-call-for-bobby-kotick-resignation-194953539.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-rollout-update-180052285.html">Microsoft is speeding up its Windows 11 rollout</a></h2><h3>The update is now more broadly available.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-rollout-update-180052285.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/37726e10-4798-11ec-b1f3-52fa264b7a2e" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="d4cae474-936f-3846-8dc8-9b96c723f154"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>Having slowly rolled out its OS update to the most powerful (and up-to-date) PCs, Microsoft is accelerating the rollout of Windows 11, making it more broadly available. Provided your system is running version 2004 or later of Windows 10 and you recently installed the September 14th, 2021 servicing update Microsoft released, you can now upgrade directly to Windows 11. When Microsoft first released the new OS on October 4th, the company said it expected to offer the upgrade to all eligible devices by mid-2022.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-rollout-update-180052285.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-8k-channel-tcl-nature-191553851.html">Roku now has an 8K channel for TCL TVs</a></h2><h3>It’ll feature a library of ultra-high definition nature documentary videos.</h3><h3></h3><p>Roku&#39;s added its first premium 8K channel to its platform: The Explorers. The only 8K Roku TVs on the market right now are from TCL, in  65- and 75-inch formats. TCL first showed off the TV at CES, and would you know it, the next CES is just around the corner. I’m sure there are more 8K TVs waiting to be revealed in January.</p><p>Ultra-high-definition premium content from The Explorers (which also offers free content through its channel) will typically cost $3/month. A tenth of that fee will be donated to The Explorers Foundation, which aims to preserve biodiversity. The channel will also offer 8K content at a time when it’s still rare. YouTube remains the main place for 8K footage.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-8k-channel-tcl-nature-191553851.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong></strong></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><h3></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-maps-area-busyness-directory-grocery-pickup-updates-110055937.html">Google Maps grocery pickup feature expands to 2,000 US stores</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/firefox-relay-premium-service-140023689.html">Firefox Relay offers unlimited email aliases as part of its new premium plan</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/game-awards-nominees-2021-180501577.html">&#39;Deathloop&#39; and &#39;Ratchet &amp; Clank&#39; top the 2021 Game Awards nominees</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchats-camera-can-scan-food-to-recommend-recipes-150040166.html">Snapchat&#39;s camera can identify food and recommend recipes</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sonos-s2-dts-surround-sound-support-spatial-audio-arc-beam-playbase-163559366.html">Sonos is rolling out DTS surround sound support</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsungs-t7-portable-ssd-in-1tb-is-cheaper-than-ever-right-now-161545035.html">Engadget Deals: Samsung&#39;s T7 portable SSD in 1TB is cheaper than ever right now</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/1-password-8-officially-available-windows-140021850.html">1Password 8 is now officially available for Windows</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-balmuda-toaster-maker-thats-launching-a-smartphone-121527044.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9c4537fd-342b-4bcf-aac6-c906440f1a06</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:15:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637155976</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T13:33:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Finance Trading]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/c758c9e0-47aa-11ec-9b7a-f796f4ef7ca6" width="1300" height="893" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/dba27160-4798-11ec-867f-91ab1452a4df" width="1300" height="975" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget Japanese]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Balmuda Phone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Balmuda Phone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Surprise Pixel 6 update improves fingerprint scanner performance]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has <a href="https://www.verizon.com/support/google-pixel-6-pro-update/">released</a> a surprise mid-month update for the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro smartphones that&#39;s specifically designed to improve the performance of the fingerprint scanner, <a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/pixel-6-november-update-fingerprint-bug-fixed/"><em>XDA</em></a> has reported. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">changed the location</a> of that sensor on the new model, and it&#39;s been a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-slow-fingerprint-sensor-195023475.html">sore point</a> for owners because of slow and finicky performance.&nbsp;</p><p>On top of being slow, the fingerprint scanner occasionally fails to read fingerprints, and has even allowed phones to be unlocked with someone else&#39;s fingers, according to <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/some-google-pixel-6-units-can-apparently-be-unlocked-with-other-peoples-fingerprints/"><em>Android Police</em></a>. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-slow-fingerprint-sensor-195023475.html">defended</a> the problem at the time by saying the reduced performance was due to &quot;enhanced security algorithms&quot; that took longer to verify identities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>According to some Reddit users, the update makes the scanner more consistent with fewer failures, particularly if you&#39;re using a screen protector. However, it&#39;s still slower than some models with similar under-screen fingerprint sensors like the Galaxy S21 Ultra, according to several of those owners.&nbsp;</p><p>Google has issued the update in two builds for Verizon-specific and international models — they should roll out to your device soon, or you can download them directly from Google <a href="https://developers.google.com/android/ota">here</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/googles-surprise-pixel-6-patch-improves-the-fingerprint-scanner-113422282.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2ec8bfa7-5dc9-4594-9301-105c266af540</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:34:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637148865</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T11:34:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0fbd5bd0-4795-11ec-b5fe-6d42dcdd4368" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/0fbd5bd0-4795-11ec-b5fe-6d42dcdd4368" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google's surprise Pixel 6 patch improves fingerprint scanner performance]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google's surprise Pixel 6 patch improves fingerprint scanner performance]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Saints Row’ reboot gets pushed back to August 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/saints-row-reboot-2022-200040315.html"><em>Saints Row</em></a><em>,</em> the reboot of the open-world shooter with an emphasis on gonzo fun and campy excess, has been delayed. Volition’s chief creative officer, Jim Boone, has announced that the title will now land on August 23rd, 2022, back from the original launch date of February 25th.</p><p>In a <a href="https://saintsrow.com/news/saints-update-from-jim-boone">statement</a>, Boone reiterated that the title wasn’t undergoing any wholesale changes and that the team had adapted well to the adversities imposed by the COVID-19 pandemic. But that the original deadline did not offer the team enough time to “do our vision justice,” especially given the “size and scope” of the new game.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Boone added that the extra time will be spent ensuring that the game gets further “fine tuning,” with an emphasis on improving the title’s “overall quality and polish.” He closed the statement by saying that the finished product will have “been worth the wait,” especially given how much is riding on the launch.</p><p><em>Saints Row</em> (2022) is a clean-sheet reboot of the series, which had lain dormant since 2015’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-01-19-saints-row-gat-out-of-hell-review-shout-at-the-devil.html"><em>Gat out of Hell</em></a> (we’re <em>still</em> not counting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agents_of_Mayhem"><em>Agents of Mayhem</em></a>). Earlier this year, Volition’s developers said that while there was a degree of affection for the series, narratively it had run its course — especially since the last title was a rock musical-themed journey into hell.</p><p>Consequently the new title is set in the Four Corners region of the US, with the player character flanked by a trio of new associates. And whereas the previous series spun out into parodying whatever genre was en vogue at the time, this new title is focused more explicitly on the material concerns of its crew. Except, you know, it’s a <em>Saints Row</em> game, so put your tongue in your cheek while you&#39;re doing all of this.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/saints-row-2022-reboot-delayed-until-august-105526445.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">73140461-e381-4447-a3a1-7b33fc625c0e</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 10:55:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637146187</ingested><modified>2021-11-17T10:49:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/89d72630-05b9-11ec-bfb4-fcbcdb6e022e" width="1800" height="1013" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/89d72630-05b9-11ec-bfb4-fcbcdb6e022e" width="1800" height="1013" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Deep Silver / Volition]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Images of the Saints Row cast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Saints Row' cast]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>