<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Google’s updated iOS 15 apps support Focus Mode and iPad widgets]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ios-15-ipados-15-watchos-8-iphone-ipad-watch-release-170601389.html"><ins>iOS 15 now available to download</ins></a>, developers both big and small have started updating their apps to take advantage of the operating system’s marquee features. One of those is Google, which <a href="https://blog.google/products/google-on-ios/google-apps-meet-ios-15/"><ins>detailed today</ins></a> the iOS 15-related enhancements you can expect from its apps.</p><p>The biggest change involves how Gmail, Meet, Tasks, Maps, Home and many of Google&#39;s other applications will handle notifications. Should you have iOS 15’s new Focus Mode enabled, Google says prompts that don’t require your immediate attention will go to the Notifications Center where you can deal with them later. More timely reminders, such as those Google Maps sends you when you’re trying to navigate somewhere, won’t be silenced, and you’ll see them as they’re sent to you. Google says its goal was to make notifications “as relevant and timely as possible.” You&#39;ll see these roll out to the company&#39;s apps in the &quot;coming weeks.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, if you own an iPad you can look forward to new Google Photos and YouTube Music widgets that take advantage of the extra screen space Apple’s tablets offer. The company says it will roll these out in the coming weeks as well. Lastly, Google Drive and YouTube Music feature new Spotlight integrations. You can use the tool to search for specific files and to play a song directly in Google’s music streaming service. Those enhancements are available today — though you&#39;ll probably wish more apps worked with Spotlight in this way.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-ios-15-enhacenments-224214541.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2ee3d8b7-9bff-4ae2-819f-a74053a86005</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632174867</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T21:54:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/cee70c30-1a5a-11ec-b75f-0ab03de35921" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/cee70c30-1a5a-11ec-b75f-0ab03de35921" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google iOS 15 widgets]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google iOS 15 widgets]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[SEC opens investigation into Activision Blizzard's workplace practices]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission has opened a “wide-ranging” investigation into Activision Blizzard, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/sec-is-investigating-activision-blizzard-over-workplace-practices-disclosures-11632165080">per <em>The Wall Street Journal</em></a>. The outlet reports the SEC recently subpoenaed the company and several executives, including CEO Bobby Kotick. The agency has asked the publisher to share a variety of documents, including correspondence Kotick wrote related to complaints of sexual harassment tied to Activision employees and contractors.</p><p>Helaine Klasky, a spokesperson for Activision Blizzard, told <em>The Journal</em> the SEC’s investigation involves disclosures the company made regarding “employment matters and related issues.” The agency reportedly hopes to find out whether Activision properly disclosed those problems, as well as whether those disclosures should have been shared earlier.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>An SEC investigation adds significantly more regulatory pressure on Activision Blizzard. In July, the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH) <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html"><ins>sued the company</ins></a>, accusing its executives of fostering a “frat boy” workplace culture. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html"><ins>According to the initial complaint</ins></a>, only 20 percent of all employees at Activision’s Blizzard Entertainment unit are women, and they’re consistently paid less and overlooked for promotions. One month later, DFEH <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-dfeh-expands-activision-blizzard-lawsuit-215925677.html"><ins>expanded the scope of the lawsuit</ins></a> to include both workers and employees. It also accused the company of using non-disclosure agreements to interfere with its ability to address the workplace violations that had happened at the studio.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sec-activision-blizzard-investigation-212143469.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e85785db-8bc0-40a5-8304-5e190d8c3e78</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 21:21:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632170691</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T20:44:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/eab98e40-eac8-11eb-aefb-94d36d9a725a" width="3792" height="2424" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/eab98e40-eac8-11eb-aefb-94d36d9a725a" width="3792" height="2424" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[UKRAINE - 2021/06/18: In this photo illustration, Activision Blizzard logo of a video game company is seen on a smartphone screen in front of Blizzard Entertainment logo. (Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, Activision Blizzard logo of a...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NASA's VIPER Rover will explore the moon's Relay Crater]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During a teleconference with journalists on Monday, NASA researchers revealed the decided landing and exploration site for its upcoming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasas-first-lunar-rover-will-scour-the-moons-south-pole-for-water-in-2023-160022034-170003713.html">VIPER lunar ice survey</a>. Lori Glaze, director of the Planetary Science Division at NASA Headquarters, announced that the VIPER mission will land along the western edge of &quot;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shackleton_(crater)">Relay crater</a>&quot; at the moon&#39;s south pole.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2c1cdb70-1a4f-11ec-bae7-06e2c813efb2" alt="Lunar South Pole" data-uuid="214556d4-23f3-347a-935f-e312c33bd675"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">NASA</div></figure><p>The decision to select this landing site required balancing a number of competing factors. Mission control &quot;considered critical parameters, such as Earth visibility — for communications from the moon to Earth — sunlight terrain that&#39;s well suited for the rover to navigate through, and most importantly, of course, the expected presence of ice and other resources,&quot; Glaze explained, &quot;while analyzing all these constraints, one study area came out ahead of all the rest, maximizing science return and flexibility to help ensure mission success once Viper is on the moon.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>During its 100-day mission, the VIPER rover <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasas-first-lunar-rover-will-scour-the-moons-south-pole-for-water-in-2023-160022034-170003713.html">is expected to investigate at least six potential sites</a> covering 10 to 15 square-miles of lunar surface through one of the coldest areas in our solar system studied to date. That includes permanently-shadowed craters that have a good probability of potentially containing water ice.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;We really don&#39;t know where that water is so we had to find a place where we could cover significant distances — and by significant distances I mean tens of kilometers — going in and out of thermal regimes that included everything from permanently shadowed craters with literally 50 Kelvin temperatures to areas that transitioned to a balmy 110 Kelvin, and then all the way up to 250 Kelvin,&quot; Anthony Colaprete, Lead Project Scientist at NASA Ames said during the call. &quot;We want to study the entire range of thermal environments.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nas-as-viper-rover-will-explore-the-moons-relay-crater-203503487.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">caffa443-11a1-4358-bf0a-b8854b809d5c</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 20:35:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632172998</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T21:23:28+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2b798c00-1a4e-11ec-bd73-e98d48c87f3c" width="985" height="554" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2b798c00-1a4e-11ec-bd73-e98d48c87f3c" width="985" height="554" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NASA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[VIPER]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[VIPER]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM restarts production of Bolt EV batteries following model-wide recall]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-extends-orion-assembly-plant-shutdown-182244582.html">reports last week</a> that GM might have to extend the shutdown of its Bolt EV production until <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-extends-bolt-ev-production-shutdown-until-mid-october-192020181.html">at least mid-October</a>, the company announced on Monday that it has &quot;outlined a comprehensive action plan to ensure that customers can safely and confidently drive, charge, and park the Chevy Bolt EV and EUV,&quot; according to a <a href="https://media.gm.com/media/us/en/gm/news.detail.html/content/Pages/news/us/en/2021/sep/0920-bolt.html">GM press release</a>. Both LG plants at Holland and Hazel Park, Michigan have resumed production and dealer deliveries are expected to begin by mid-October.&nbsp;</p><p>The battery fault that led to a model-wide recall of the electric vehicles <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-replace-chevy-bolt-battery-modules-fire-risk-100027066.html">beginning in August</a> turned out to be a pair of issues. Manufacturing defects caused both for anodes to tear and cathode-anode separators to fold. Should both of these defects manifest within the same battery cell, it would have a higher chance of catching fire.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;LG has implemented new manufacturing processes and has worked with GM to review and enhance its quality assurance programs to provide confidence in its batteries moving forward,&quot; the GM statement read. &quot;LG will institute these new processes in other facilities that will provide cells to GM in the future.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>GM has established a notification process to inform impacted customers as to when their replacement battery modules will be available. The company has also developed a diagnostic software suite designed to &quot;detect specific abnormalities that might indicate a damaged battery in Bolt EVs and EUVs by monitoring the battery performance,&quot; per the release. The software has to be installed at the dealership but will enable Bolt EV owners to exceed the current GM-enacted 90-percent charge limit should their batteries pass muster.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gm-restarts-production-of-bolt-ev-batteries-following-model-wide-recall-194412215.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1d9fc155-3d37-4014-bdec-e3f5d47468da</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 19:44:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632167061</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T19:44:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/0b7e9570-1a4a-11ec-bfd6-c6baa8041a02" width="4680" height="3207" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/10401520-1a4a-11ec-afff-2b895b3dc883" width="4680" height="3207" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Lucy Nicholson / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Chevrolet Bolt EV is pictured at the 2016 Los Angeles Auto Show in Los Angeles, California, U.S November 16, 2016.  REUTERS/Lucy Nicholson]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[USA-AUTOSHOW/CHEVY]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[US officials can't decide if Honor smartphones are a national security threat]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late last year, Chinese electronics manufacturer Huawei <a href="https://www.engadget.com/huawei-honor-sold-024435704.html">sold its budget mobile brand Honor</a> to “ensure” it would survive the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-15-president-trump-national-emergency-for-telecom-networks.html">sanctions the US</a> had issued against its own business. The move allowed the brand to work with firms like Qualcomm and Intel to source chips and other critical components for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/honor-magic3-flagship-125020517.html">phones, laptops and wearables</a>. But now Honor could be in trouble as well.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/huawei-honor-security-export/2021/09/19/6d49d27c-17ef-11ec-b976-f4a43b740aeb_story.html"><em>The Washington Post</em></a>, officials at four federal agencies voted last week whether to place the company on the Commerce Department’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-19-huawei-ceo-founder-ren-zhengfei-us-ban.html">entity list</a>. Landing there would prevent Honor from working with US companies. The <em>Post</em> reports the vote went evenly down the middle. Officials from the Pentagon and Energy Department were reportedly in favor of putting the company on the list, while their counterparts at the Commerce Department and State Department were not.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>With the deadlock, it’s now up to the political appointees at those agencies to decide what to do. If they can’t make a decision, the issue could eventually make its way to the desk of President Joe Biden.</p><p>The Commerce Department declined to comment on the vote when <em>The Post </em>reached out to the agency about it<em>. </em>Instead, it spoke to the subject of the entity list more broadly, noting it continually reviews the risk of a nominated company illegally sharing US technology. “We remain committed to using a full range of tools, including . . . export controls, to deter efforts by the [People’s Republic of China] and other countries … that seek to leverage technology in ways that risk harming US national security and foreign policy interests,” Brittany Caplin, a spokesperson the agency, told the outlet.</p><p>Ultimately, those making the case that Honor should land on the entity list may have difficulty convincing their counterparts that the company is a national security threat to the US. Unlike its one-time parent, Honor doesn’t sell telecommunications equipment to carriers. That means it’s not involved in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uk-bans-installation-of-huawei-5-g-equipment-starting-september-2021-104019166.html">5G network buildouts</a> that were ostensibly at the center of the decision to place Huawei there. What’s more, its products aren’t even available in the US.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/honor-commerce-department-entity-list-consideration-193403546.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7925da12-8573-4e3a-9518-e437f670d2fd</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 19:34:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632166446</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T19:34:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b03162a0-fb64-11eb-8fdf-721d4a0179c6" width="1423" height="731" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b03162a0-fb64-11eb-8fdf-721d4a0179c6" width="1423" height="731" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Honor]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Honor Magic 3]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Honor Magic3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon will hold a hardware event on September 28th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon will host a hardware event on September 28th at 12PM ET, the company announced today. The retailer promised to share news about its latest “devices, features and services” in an invite it shared with Engadget. Beyond that, the company didn’t provide other details on what to expect from it next week. But if we had to take a guess, we should see many of the same types of products we saw last year.&nbsp;</p><p>In 2020, Amazon announced new Echo speakers, its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-cloud-game-streaming-luna-reveal-173946193.html"><ins>Luna gaming service</ins></a>, WiFi 6-enabled <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-eero-6-mesh-wifi-router-173331388.html"><ins>Eero mesh routers</ins></a> and Fire TV devices. Oh, it also showed off an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ring-always-home-cam-drone-home-patrol-173100325.html"><ins>indoor security drone</ins></a> from Ring that we haven&#39;t seen since that event. Amazon won’t livestream the proceedings, but we’ll have you covered with articles on all of the company’s most notable announcements from that day.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fall-hardware-event-september-28-181440028.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">89ad5a78-557e-4fc0-a79d-c48d0e36895a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632161683</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T18:14:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/386ffa80-1a3e-11ec-ab3c-bd69902e087c" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/386ffa80-1a3e-11ec-ab3c-bd69902e087c" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Echo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Echo]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Balenciaga is now selling Fortnite-themed drip]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Fortnite"><em><ins>Fortnite</ins></em></a> is taking a step closer to creating the broadest metaverse around with its latest crossover. Instead of a partnership with the likes of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-crossover-aloy-horizon-zero-dawn-epic-games-sony-190755915.html"><ins>other games</ins></a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-ariana-grande-concert-date-220749969.html"><ins>Ariana Grande</ins></a>, Epic Games&#39; freshest <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/high-digital-fashion-drops-into-fortnite-with-balenciaga"><ins>collab</ins></a> is with a high-fashion brand.</p><p>Balenciaga is now <a href="https://www.balenciaga.com/en-us/all/discover/fortnite"><ins>selling limited-edition </ins><em><ins>Fortnite</ins></em><ins>-themed clothes</ins></a> at typically high prices. A white Fortnite x Balenciaga hoodie costs $725 while a baseball cap will set you back $395. A t-shirt is $495 while a denim jacket will leave your wallet $1,290 lighter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="77e4c4432c1f4c0b8df753bef4ef5e80"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_gKiVi3tmqI?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>This crossover goes both ways. Four Balenciaga outfits (including a dog wearing the hoodie) are coming to the game. The Balenciaga Fit Set comprises the first high-fashion skins in <em>Fortnite</em>.</p><p>Starting at 8PM ET on Monday, you can unlock Balenciaga backpacks as your back bling, as well as a themed pickaxe shaped like a sneaker, a purse glider, wrap and emote. There are also a pair of free sprays to earn through quests that start on September 21st and run for a week. You can check out a Strange Times Featured Hub that includes a virtual Balenciaga store, as well as a <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/express-yourself-with-strange-times-fortography-be-featured-in-game">themed photography campaign</a>.</p><p>This could open the floodgates for all kinds of <em>Fortnite</em> fashion collaborations in the future. We might see Agent Jones wearing a pair of Air Jordan 1s or the Battle Bus decked out in Gucci logos. Meanwhile, Epic <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/spotlights/balenciaga-blurs-real-with-unreal-in-fortnite?lang=en-US">released</a> a video showing how its team and Balenciaga used Unreal Engine to add the new looks.</p><div id="4bb469dfb25b4a47989cb36e92c3a1f3"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D1AwDbkq-mQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/balenciaga-fortnite-crossover-181216067.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">501285e0-37d5-4410-a374-caf946cff421</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632161538</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T18:12:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7f1d4f70-1a3c-11ec-a6f5-9d46abc8ee82" width="1001" height="563" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7f1d4f70-1a3c-11ec-a6f5-9d46abc8ee82" width="1001" height="563" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Balenciaga Fortnite crossover]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Balenciaga Fortnite crossover]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's 2022 iPhones could feature notch-less designs, but not in-display Touch ID]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple may have only announced its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-event-supercut-201538409.html">iPhone 13 lineup last week</a>, but analyst Ming-Chi Kuo is already looking ahead to the company’s 2022 lineup. According to an investor note <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/20/kuo-iphone-14-pro-hole-punch-48mp-camera/"><ins>seen by </ins><em><ins>MacRumors</ins></em></a>, Kuo claims Apple will release three new iPhones in the second half of the year. The two high-end models will reportedly feature punch-hole display cutouts and a 48-megapixel primary camera. In other words, the expectation is that Apple will start moving away from the notch design that has defined its phones since the release of the iPhone X in 2017.</p><p>Moving to a 48-megapixel camera would also represent a significant change for the company. Recent iPhones have exclusively shipped with 12-megapixel primary cameras. By moving to a denser sensor, the company could use <a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/what-is-pixel-binning-966179/"><ins>pixel binning technology</ins></a> to allow people to take high-resolution shots during the day and less noisy ones when the sun starts to set.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/20/kuo-iphones-with-under-screen-touch-id-now-coming-in-2023-foldable-iphone-in-2024/"><ins>Looking further ahead</ins></a>, Kuo said Apple plans to add an in-display fingerprint sensor to the iPhone in 2023. Previously, the analyst had predicted that would happen next year, but now notes a slower than expected development process has delayed Apple’s rollout of the feature. That’s a significant delay when you consider <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2021-iphone-in-display-fingerprint-sensor-223939578.html"><ins>early reports on the iPhone 13</ins></a> lineup had suggested those phones would include in-display fingerprint sensors. Similarly, he expects the company will release a foldable iPhone in 2024, where he had previously predicted we would see the device sometime in 2023. As always, take these reports with a grain of salt. Kuo has a decent but not flawless track record when predicting Apple releases.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ming-chi-kuo-apple-iphone-14-report-172030312.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">af167258-2611-4429-a100-ab35fca35b5e</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 17:20:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632157777</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T17:09:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a7627a90-13da-11ec-a3ff-c372aa61c8d9" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a7627a90-13da-11ec-a3ff-c372aa61c8d9" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 12 Pro Max back]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 12 Pro Max back]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[iOS 15 is now available]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple is now rolling out <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html"><ins>iOS 15</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html"><ins>iPadOS 15</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watchos-8-beta-hands-on-175457215.html"><ins>watchOS 8</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-airpods-max-spatial-audio-tvos-macos-180128777.html">tvOS 15</a> to iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch and Apple TV devices. You might not see the updates right away, but when they&#39;re available, you&#39;ll have access to a bunch more features.</p><p>Facetime and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-messages-ios-15-shared-with-you-173052730.html"><ins>Messages</ins></a> have been upgraded on both iPhone and iPad. Facetime supports spatial audio and reduces background noise, while people can <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-facetime-wwdc-2021-171840284.html"><ins>join Facetime calls</ins></a> through shareable links on the web and Android. It&#39;ll be easier to keep track of things your friends and family share with you in Messages thanks to dedicated tabs in the News, Music, TV and Podcasts apps.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Notifications have also been overhauled. You&#39;ll have more control over push alerts and you can let only notifications from select apps and people through when you activate one of the new Focus modes. There are profiles for activities including sleeping and working, and the OS can automatically rearrange your home screen apps to bring the ones you&#39;re most likely to use at a certain time to the forefront.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/deb5d810-d95c-11eb-bbcb-b3c3a9983787" style="height:1200;width:1800;" alt="A composite showing three screenshots of Apple&#39;s Live Text feature through the viewfinder in the Camera app in the iOS 15 beta. The left screenshot shows a small yellow frame focused on the middle of a bottle of green moisturizer, the middle screenshot shows the middle part of the bottle highlighted with options above it for " data-uuid="88cace24-b8c1-3780-b2d5-c1e670ea35f6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Screenshots of the iOS 15 beta</div></figure><p>Also new in iOS 15 is the Live Text function, which works in a similar way to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20lens">Google Lens</a>. The feature can extract written text from photos, screenshots and the world around you. You can edit, translate and share the text. The feature can also identify things like art, landmarks, plants and pets.</p><p>Elsewhere, there are new features for the Maps, Photos and Weather apps on iOS. Spotlight searches will have richer results, including your own photos, with Apple using machine learning to figure out what&#39;s in each image.</p><p>On iPad, Quick Notes are now a system-wide feature — just swipe in from the lower right corner to jot down some thoughts using the keyboard or Apple Pencil. Expect some multitasking and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fix-safari-tab-bar-design-third-ios-15-mac-os-monterey-beta-180648751.html"><ins>Safari changes</ins></a> too.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0f51a1c0-db65-11eb-bda3-ff9dd872800f" style="height:1397;width:2000;" alt="iPadOS 15 Quick Notes" data-uuid="a671b167-3284-3130-91da-940de16944ad"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>One thing that iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 don&#39;t have at launch is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-delays-ios-15-shareplay-184450766.html"><ins>the SharePlay feature</ins></a>. It lets you enjoy movies, shows and music together with friends over Facetime, and you can share your screen with them. Apple will release the feature on those operating systems, tvOS 15 and macOS Monterey later. Apple also put the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html"><ins>child safety features</ins></a> it planned to release as part of iOS 15 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-features-csam-delay-132534290.html"><ins>on the back burner</ins></a> while it makes improvements.</p><p>The watchOS 8 update perhaps isn&#39;t quite as extensive. There&#39;s a bigger focus on mindfulness and health, including some new workout categories. Apple Watch now has deeper integration with iPhone, with features including Focus mode support and a Contacts app. You can also expect portrait watch faces and multiple timers.</p><p>Apple TV now has spatial audio support, including for AirPods Pro and AirPods Max, following the tvOS 15 update. You can also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/homepod-15-update-apple-tv-homekit-213444115.html">connect multiple HomePod minis</a> to an Apple TV 4K and use those as the default speakers.</p><p>If you have an iPhone 6s or later, iPhone SE (either generation) or seventh-gen iPod touch, you&#39;ll be able to install iOS 15. Those with Apple tablets can run iPadOS 15 on fifth-gen and later iPads, iPad mini 4 and later, iPad Air 2 and later and all iPad Pro devices. Meanwhile, watchOS 8 is supported by Apple Watch Series 3 and later devices.</p><p>As for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-preview-public-beta-175927010.html"><ins>macOS Monterey</ins></a>, Apple has yet to announce a firm release date for the next version of its Mac operating system. Monterey should be available sometime this fall.</p><p>Apple is rolling out the major annual firmware updates just a few days before the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-pre-order-the-iphone-13-iphone-13-mini-iphone-13-pro-and-iphone-13-pro-max-113024712.html"><ins>iPhone 13 lineup</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-pre-order-the-new-apple-ipad-and-ipad-mini-2021-184818462.html"><ins>new iPads</ins></a> arrive. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-release-date-price-172920553.html"><ins>Apple Watch Series 7</ins></a> will be released later this fall.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-ios-15-ipados-15-watchos-8-iphone-ipad-watch-release-170601389.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">029eb2c9-9bb9-4b32-9625-4125fc8a89d3</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 17:06:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632157697</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T17:08:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f21ed3b0-ff82-11eb-bcf5-db7b17ce6029" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f21ed3b0-ff82-11eb-bcf5-db7b17ce6029" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cherlynn Low/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple iOS 15 beta on iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iOS 15 beta on iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[OnePlus' 2022 flagship will share a unified Android 13 system with Oppo]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-oppo-merging-bbk-electronics-pete-lau-141928142.html">OnePlus&#39; integration into Oppo</a> in June, co-founder Pete Lau — who has been appointed Chief Product Officer for both brands since May 2020 — is ready to share more on what to expect from his expanded team, aka &quot;OnePlus 2.0.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>We already knew about the upcoming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-oppo-oxygenos-coloros-shared-codebase-141211007.html">unified OS</a>, which will apparently bring the best of both worlds — the smoothness and lightness (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-remove-ads-one-ui-apps-123640928.html">no ads!</a>) of OnePlus&#39; OxygenOS, combined with the reliability and smartness of Oppo&#39;s ColorOS. In a recent group interview, Lau added that this yet-to-be-named system will be based on Google&#39;s upcoming Android 13, and it&#39;ll be featured on OnePlus&#39; 2022 flagship device — likely dubbed &quot;OnePlus 10&quot; — due out first half of the year. Some existing devices will also receive this update, though no specific models were mentioned. (Lau said the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-nord-2-5-g-impressions-release-date-price-144511154.html">Nord 2</a> already features an early version of the integrated codebase, so there&#39;s a good chance that it&#39;ll get the full upgrade.)</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Given that the shared OS would reduce differentiation between Lau&#39;s two brands, one might wonder which would more likely produce the &quot;perfect&quot; flagship smartphone? Never one to give a direct answer, Lau implied that he doesn&#39;t believe such a device would ever exist. He referred to an internal demographic map featuring 20 user categories, each of which tied to a combination of different needs — down to the level of product size, specific photography features, charging modes, weight and more.&nbsp;</p><p>Lau&#39;s basic definition of OnePlus users is &quot;tech enthusiasts,&quot; but he added that based on this mapping, it&#39;s still impossible to satisfy everyone&#39;s needs with a single device. As such, the exec thinks the market is big enough for his two brands to avoid friendly fire. For the same reason, OnePlus&#39; Nord line will continue to co-exist with the Oppo Reno series (and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/realme-flash-magdart-android-apple-magsafe-125551887.html">Realme</a>, for that matter), though the similarity of their designs is still questionable. (Lau insisted that each brand has a dedicated design team, even after the merger.)</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/beeb28b0-1a24-11ec-be5f-6929c604d6cc" alt="OnePlus founder Pete Lau" data-uuid="5380acb9-60bf-3d68-96b3-4b4563885a5a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">OnePlus</div></figure><p>Another area which OnePlus may benefit from the integration is photography. Lau pointed out that what used to be a camera team of around 100 people is now some 700, which may allow OnePlus to take better advantage of its relationship with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-9-pro-hasselblad-xpan-film-camera-setting-update-120054895.html">Hasselblad</a>, especially with their ongoing work on color science this year. The exec added that he can&#39;t say OnePlus currently has the best camera performance, but he&#39;s certain that it&#39;s &quot;definitely&quot; among the top in the industry.</p><p>Lau admitted that with his expanded role, even if he had 48-hour days, it&#39;d still be impossible for him to personally pick on every single detail on every product like he did before (let&#39;s just say it&#39;d be unlikely that he&#39;d throw a fit over a minor design issue on a logic board, as he once <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-04-23-oneplus-one-launch-ceo-pete-lau-interview.html">famously</a> did back in his Oppo Blu-ray player days). Instead, Lau had been spending a lot of time teaching his &quot;never settle&quot; philosophy to his new Oppo teammates over the past year or so, in the hopes of changing what used to be a leader-driven mission to true team work. It&#39;ll be a while before we get a real taste of this fruition, but Lau is &quot;confident that this new unified OS won&#39;t disappoint.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-10-oppo-unified-android-operating-system-163038315.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2600f01e-bdd7-47eb-a28d-190056be04d7</guid><dc:creator>Richard Lai</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:30:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632153116</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:52:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Richard Lai]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/78887b40-96a6-11eb-8df5-61842fe56da9" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/78887b40-96a6-11eb-8df5-61842fe56da9" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Eric Chan / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OnePlus 9 Pro 評測]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OnePlus 9 Pro 評測]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Finch' trailer sees man, machine and dog try to flee climate change]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple offered a brief glimpse of the Tom Hanks-led <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tom-hanks-finch-release-date-085915154.html"><em>Finch</em></a> at its recent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-event-supercut-201538409.html">iPhone 13 launch event</a>, and now you can watch the first full trailer for the upcoming sci-fi film. The clip sets the stage for the story that follows. A solar flare knocked out most of the technology on Earth and left much of the US a desolate wasteland. Hanks’ character, the titular Finch, survives in an underground shelter with his only companion, a dog named Goodyear, until he builds a new Android companion. The three of them eventually leave their home when it becomes threatened by the sandstorms that dominate the world of the movie.</p><div id="0e278552eea445e29694dbe80110259b"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-0bYWnP3jH4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-greyhound-tom-hanks-ww-ii-drama-july-10-092506494.html"><em>Greyhound</em></a>, Apple acquired <em>Finch </em>for Apple TV+ when the film got lost in pandemic-related delays. It’s only one part of a strong fall lineup that is surprisingly heavy on sci-fi stories. Before <em>Finch </em>comes out on November 5th, genre fans can look forward to the company’s adaptation of Isaac <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-foundation-isaac-asimov-release-date-152711615.html">Asimov’s<em> Foundation</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>novels on September 24th and then <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-invasion-trailer-222925428.html"><em>Invasion</em></a>, which stars Jurassic Park’s Sam Neill, on October 22nd.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-tom-hanks-finch-trailer-161100270.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c3bf8525-4062-4b0c-ac4a-eddd924ae2f3</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632153013</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:50:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e1b4a890-1a28-11ec-9dff-18517115ff10" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e1b4a890-1a28-11ec-9dff-18517115ff10" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Finch]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Finch]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Meet will automatically adjust webcam brightness in your browser]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20meet"><ins>Google Meet</ins></a> will soon make it easier for you to see all of your co-workers or friends properly on video calls. The web version of the app can detect when someone is underexposed due to bad lighting. Meet will then increase the brightness so it&#39;s easier to see your cohorts and perhaps make your feed clearer if you have a terrible webcam.</p><p>The low-light mode hit the Google Meet iOS and Android mobile apps <a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2020/04/video-conference-anywhere-with-low.html"><ins>last year</ins></a>. It uses AI to examine light levels and tweak the brightness. There&#39;s no admin control for the feature, though users will be able to <a href="https://support.google.com/meet/answer/9302964?ref_topic=7294099"><ins>switch it off</ins></a> — Google says having it enabled might slow down your device.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The feature is coming to all <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20workspace"><ins>Workspace</ins></a> and G Suite basic and business users. Google is rolling it out to Rapid Release domains starting today and Scheduled Release domains on October 4th. The rollout will take up to 15 days in both cases, so by mid-October, bad webcam feeds could be a thing of the past on Meet calls.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-meet-webcam-brightness-web-155518924.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f666fe70-2e12-414b-b72b-8ec98021b5fe</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632152550</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:42:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/19a65d30-1a28-11ec-877d-4d092367a78c" width="721" height="453" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/19a65d30-1a28-11ec-877d-4d092367a78c" width="721" height="453" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Meet automatic brightness adjustment]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Meet automatic brightness adjustment]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[ZTE Axon 30 review: An 'invisible' selfie camera comes at a cost]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="fb16da4db1264fec80086f703e2ea40e"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NlP7YpVJtGc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>ZTE’s family of devices is a little confusing at the moment. The Axon 30 is a direct sequel to the Axon 20, which was the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/zte-axon-20-5g-under-display-front-selfie-camera-140003878.html">first phone to feature an in-screen camera</a>. However, the company has subsequently released the Axon 30 Pro and Ultra in some territories. So, weirdly, the vanilla Axon 30 is the last of the Axon 30 family to appear.</p><p>At $500, it’s also the cheapest — another attempt by ZTE to slide underneath the priciest smartphones around and offer a mixture of compelling features, albeit tempered by some compromises. The Axon 30’s headline feature is a much-improved under-display camera (UDC), which is almost invisible. It’s also a ZTE smartphone that’s launching in the US, which doesn’t always happen.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>But with increasingly strong midrange phone competition from the likes of Samsung, OnePlus and Google, does ZTE’s Axon 30 offer more than just a hidden selfie camera?</p><p>So what’s all the fuss about that camera anyway? Well, the under-screen 16-megapixel selfie shooter on the $500 Axon 30 puts the one on Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 3 to shame. ZTE’s implementation is imperceptible unless you really, really look for it. No punch hole, no notch, no pop-up camera.</p><p>In comparison, the Fold 3’s selfie cam has a pixelated effect that signposts where the camera is and ruins the whole effect. (Yes, in Samsung’s defense, there’s another front-facing camera on the Fold 3 when it’s closed and you’re using the smaller screen.)</p><p>The difference seems to be pixel density, or according to ZTE, the composition of them, with a “special pixel matrix” that ensures the screen appears at 400 PPI — double that found on the Axon 20. If the light catches the unit just right, then yes, you can see it. You’ll probably never notice it again.</p><p>There’s also a dedicated UDC chip that apparently works to keep the camera area looking consistent with the rest of the screen. To get a closer look, I used Oppo’s Find X3 Pro, which has a microscope phone camera — perfect for visually explaining what could otherwise get very technical.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c1e4cce0-1643-11ec-bdff-65a10a81eed6" alt="ZTE Axon 30 review" data-uuid="ecb3519d-46cf-33cf-be2f-dab8e0641e13"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget, Mat Smith</div></figure><p>As you can see, some pixels seem slightly smaller, or dimmer, than those surrounding them. In this close up you can see the outline of the UDC area, but at this magnification, it’s impressive that it doesn’t look more out of place. I’ll touch on the camera’s performance later, but spoiler: While it might look the part, it’s not quite capable enough.</p><p>The hidden sensor also complements the expansive 6.92-inch AMOLED screen, uninterrupted by the presence of any camera notches or holes. With a 2,460 x 1,080 resolution panel and 120Hz refresh rate, the Axon 30 is offering a flagship screen for mid-range prices. You can switch between 120 and 60Hz modes, with an automatic option letting the Axon 30 decide when to increase the frequency. On more expensive phones, like the OnePlus 9 Pro and the recently-announced<a href="https://www.engadget.com/iphone-13-pro-and-pro-max-180857712.html"> iPhone Pro 13</a>, there are more refresh rate options that dip even lower, but at this price, this seems like a fair compromise.</p><p>Leaving it on auto is probably the best fit for most folks, but the manual options are nice — especially as there seems to be a tangible battery life benefit to the lower setting.</p><p>The phone itself is pretty big but feels solid despite its plastic back. ZTE added a translucent reflective effect across the rear of the Axon 30, which I like. I’m less enamored with the giant camera unit, however, which protrudes a few millimeters from the phone, and is likely to be more easily dinged and scratched. Sadly, this design is now everywhere.</p><p>The screen might be comparable to a high-end phone, but there are some features that didn’t make the cut at this price, like wireless charging and certified resistance against dust and water.</p><p><strong>Performance and software</strong></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/1243e550-1571-11ec-a35e-0d3efbfffa54" alt="ZTE Axon 30 review" data-uuid="e6fc0689-11b6-342b-9305-3211a1614f15"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget, Mat Smith</div></figure><p>There are further compromises. The Axon 30 is powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 870 processor — which is a little underpowered compared to the Snapdragon 880 and 880 Plus we’re seeing in flagship Android smartphones now.</p><p>But at $500, phones like the Pixel 5a (and its Snapdragon 765G chip) are a better comparison to make. The Axon 30 has a more powerful chip than Google’s latest device, though it’s hard to notice a difference in performance between the two.</p><p>The Axon 30 handled everything I threw at it, whether that was video streaming, Stadia or playing games on the phone itself. (The Stadia app did flag that the phone wasn’t officially supported, although it worked fine for me.) There was some visible slowdown when recording video at full 4K resolution, and hopping into the gallery, but otherwise, I didn’t have many complaints.</p><p>I also have to mention that the Axon 30 isn’t exactly great for 5G support in the US. It only works on T-Mobile’s midband 5G. If you’re on Verizon or AT&amp;T, you’ll be relegated to 4G.</p><p>ZTE does know what it’s doing with smartphone power, though. The phone has a 4,200mAh battery that, when I turned the 120Hz refresh rate off, lasted a good two days of typical use before I needed to recharge. And when I did need to, it took hardly any time.</p><p>The Axon 30 supports incredibly fast charging speeds of up to 65W with the appropriate charger, which (thankfully) the phone comes with. ZTE estimates it can charge the phone to 100 percent in under an hour, but getting to 50 percent takes proportionately less time — around 20 minutes.</p><p>Software is pretty innocuous, which is generally a good thing. ZTE keeps pretty close to the stock Google experience. Its new MyOS 11 skin, based on Android 11, is pretty close to what you’d find on a Pixel. There are a few gesture quirks (shake the Axon 30 for the flashlight!) and a floating shortcut widget that can be minimized to the edges of the screen. It’s similar to Samsung’s Edge panel on its bigger phones. ZTE’s version is called Z-Pop and you can tweak the four shortcuts for system commands and app switching. That said, it’s not something that makes you think “Mmm what a memorable experience this is.”</p><p></p><h3>Cameras</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/124c97e0-1571-11ec-a75b-f4c08389583e" alt="ZTE Axon 30 review" data-uuid="15b1c40a-7bb5-35cb-b408-cf9ce34ddafd"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget, Mat Smith</div></figure><p>While the front-facing 16-megapixel camera is technically impressive, it doesn’t take great selfies. Don’t get me wrong, it shoots far better pics than the UDC on both Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 3 and the Axon 20. The work done to pixel-bin for low light performance, as well as algorithms to help the camera ‘see’ through the AMOLED panel make this the best UDC so far. But it still offers up middling to poor photos. It’s a bit of a time warp, to be honest, giving me the kind of pictures I used to get on smartphones years ago. Details are fuzzy, and any strong backlighting leads to lens flares and washout.</p><p>There’s also an AI assist mode that doesn’t seem to help much — if anything, modes like brightness seem to wash out skin tones even further, and they’re a little gray to begin with. Even if you turn this off, images seem pretty unnatural.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3d582710-1643-11ec-b766-ba2f99c72f3d" alt="ZTE Axon 30 samples" data-uuid="d27e495c-7fce-3801-bc61-5faf14aae13f"><figcaption>I couldn&#39;t mask how disappointed I was in these selfies.</figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget, Mat Smith</div></figure><p>It does still capture enough detail to offer face unlock functionality if you prefer that method to fingerprint unlock. And yes, there’s also a fingerprint reader built into the screen. Face unlock worked fine for me nine times out of ten, and was plenty fast enough, but I used a combination of the two. Fingerprint unlock seemed more reliable in darker environments.</p><p>But what about the rest of the cameras? On the back, the Axon 30 has a four-camera array, led by a 64-megapixel Sony sensor. While you’ll mostly be taking pictures that fuse a lot of these pixels together for less noise and better performance in low-light, ZTE has kept the ability to take full-resolution stills if you want to. There’s also an 8-megapixel wide-angle camera, a 5-megapixel macro camera and finally, a 2-megapixel depth sensor to aid your bokeh photography efforts and help with focus. You get up to 2x optical zoom, which is what you’d generally expect at this price point.</p><p>While shooting pictures with the Axon 30 during a family event, images of friends and family seemed particularly good. There is a softness to some shots, likely due to the photos being shrunk down from the 64-megapixel original, but the phone was able to handle most things I threw at it.</p><section data-eng-breakout="d271d4f23b974ac682bfd836cdcc2da6" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/9b37a2d0-1642-11ec-bd3f-9ec869f25ab3" alt="ZTE Axon 30 sample images"></section><p>There’s a night mode — of course — but the Axon 30 takes pretty functional shots in low light without having to resort to using it. It did help further reduce noise and improve detail a little, but I’d also advise testing shots with AI mode on and off, as sometimes I found it meddled a little too heavily, especially with people as subjects.</p><p>And the macro camera isn’t worth your time. I suggest using the primary camera with zoom for generally better results in most situations. The problem with the macro camera seems to be that the phone has to be so close to the subject that it blocks a lot of light. That’s not great for detail-oriented photography.</p><p>Video camera modes are generally the same across most mid-range phones in recent years, and the Axon 30 isn’t hugely different. It can handle up to 4K at 60fps and a multi-camera mode lets you record from both the wide-angle and the primary camera at the same time, which is a nice trick we’ve occasionally seen on flagship phones. Due to sluggish autofocus, however, the recording quality isn’t great. If you’ve got a stable subject and good light, videos will generally come out nicely. At other times, you’ll struggle to record anything functional. Just because a phone can record 4K, it doesn’t mean you should.</p><p></p><h3>Summary</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/1224c490-1571-11ec-afcf-825b32632843" alt="ZTE Axon 30 review" data-uuid="6e71016f-7a16-3e39-8320-d41ca3582a07"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget, Mat Smith</div></figure><p>With the Axon 30, ZTE has proved it can successfully camouflage its under-display camera. But that doesn’t mean it’s up to the task. Image quality from the secretive selfie lens really isn’t good enough, even if the implementation is impressive. Aside from that, the Axon 30 has a gorgeous, fluid screen and a decent rear camera setup. The lack of wider 5G support in the US is frustrating in a 2021 phone, but there is still a lot here for $500. The bigger challenge is that competition is tough in the middleweight phone arena. Google’s latest Pixel, the 5a, rings in at $450, and offers better-performing cameras, front and back. If you’re struggling to pick between the two, the decision loosely boils down to a bigger screen or better selfies.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/zte-axon-30-review-153209819.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7b5a2e5b-32ba-4e1e-b89b-825f5a87f0fc</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:32:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632152511</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:42:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/124ce600-1571-11ec-acdc-e652b6376c24" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/124cbef0-1571-11ec-ad7b-052195c49d14" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget, Mat Smith]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ZTE Axon 30 review]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[ZTE Axon 30 review]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's first-generation Echo Show 8 is on sale for $64 right now]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the debut of new Echo Show 8 and Show 5 devices in June, we&#39;ve seen a few good deals on Amazon&#39;s first-generation smart displays since then. A new one has popped up on both Amazon and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Best Buy" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/qnyBqn">Best Buy</a> for the original <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo Show 8" href="https://amzn.to/3nPM3aD">Echo Show 8</a>, dropping it down to a record low of $64. That&#39;s the best price we&#39;ve seen all year on the gadget, and it&#39;s even better than the $70 sale price that we saw during Amazon Prime Day.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3nPM3aD" id="82831fda5d7c4da8a82fe8b75b757127" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Echo Show 8 (1st gen) at Amazon - $64</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/qnyBqn" id="e2d7a316af65496e98cd35ba81de432b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Best Buy;elmt:impactRadius;pdid:">Buy Echo Show 8 (1st gen) at Best Buy - $64</a><p>The Echo Show 8 sits in the middle of Amazon&#39;s smart display lineup with its 8-inch HD screen. While the Echo Show 5 excels as a smart alarm clock, the Echo Show 8 lets you watch videos, view photos and check out security camera feeds with a bit more comfort. The larger display is also better for video chats and it has a physical camera shutter (along with a microphone on/off button) for when you want extra privacy. If the Show 5 is a bit too small for you but the $250 Echo Show 10 is too expensive (or you&#39;re freaked out by its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-echo-show-10-review-130012759.html">swiveling base</a>), the Show 8 will likely hit a sweet spot with its power, screen real estate and price.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:updated Echo Show 8" href="https://amzn.to/3tTqdUo">updated Echo Show 8</a> is only a few months old but it&#39;s much pricer at $130 and it&#39;s not significantly different from the first-generation. It has a faster octa-core processor and a 13-megapixel wide-angle camera with auto-framing, which means it will automatically pan to track your face and keep you in view during video calls. This feature also works with all video chat services that the device supports, including Skype and Zoom, so it will come in handy if you frequently make calls with the Show 8. But you could safely skip the 2021 model if you mostly use your smart displays for weather alerts, calendar appointments, music streaming and other basic tasks.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazons-first-generation-echo-show-8-is-on-sale-for-64-right-now-152439302.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1f25da33-177b-41ef-be12-f9bfb9225bd5</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:24:39 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632151481</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:24:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?resize=2000%2C2000%2Cshrink&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2019-09%2F40dc0430-dfbb-11e9-ae9b-ca5928634a9b&amp;client=a1acac3e1b3290917d92&amp;signature=f96c45df5b3abe419f169fd22a70f0ac82b3af8e" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?resize=2000%2C2000%2Cshrink&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2019-09%2F40dc0430-dfbb-11e9-ae9b-ca5928634a9b&amp;client=a1acac3e1b3290917d92&amp;signature=f96c45df5b3abe419f169fd22a70f0ac82b3af8e" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon&#39;s first-generation Echo Show 8 is on sale for $64 right now]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter will pay over $800 million t​o settle a class action suit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/twitter"><ins>Twitter</ins></a> has <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/0001418091/000119312521276828/d197034d8k.htm"><ins>agreed to pay</ins></a> $809.5 million to settle a class action suit filed by shareholders in 2016. Investors alleged that Twitter masked the company&#39;s slowing growth while executives including former CEO Dick Costolo and co-founders Evan Williams and Jack Dorsey (the current CEO) sold stock “for hundreds of millions of dollars in insider profits.”</p><p>The plaintiffs <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/twitter-investor-lawsuit-settlement-payment-jack-dorsey-1235068982/"><ins>said</ins></a> Twitter was tracking daily active users (DAU) as the key metric for engagement in early 2015, but it was still reporting monthly active user figures. The DAU measurement indicated engagement was dropping or staying flat, according to the lawsuit.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Twitter says the <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/0001418091/000119312521276828/d197034d8k.htm"><ins>proposed settlement</ins></a>, which a court has yet to approve, &quot;resolves all claims asserted against Twitter and the other named defendants without any admission, concession or finding of any fault, liability or wrongdoing by the company or any defendant.&quot; Twitter and all of the individuals named as defendants in the suit have denied any wrongdoing. The lawsuit accused Twitter and executives of violating the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</p><p>The company plans to use cash on hand for the settlement. It&#39;s expected to pay the sum by the end of the year.</p><p>In its Q4 2018 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-02-07-twitter-q4-2018.html"><ins>earnings report</ins></a>, Twitter started reporting average monetizable daily active users (mDAU). It said that was the only engagement metric it would disclose to investors going forward, partly because it&#39;s a more accurate reflection of how it&#39;s making money from users.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-settlement-class-action-suit-151202542.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4a527ee4-8f6d-4265-a1d3-d8e3150a1d46</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:12:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632150724</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T15:12:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/d5a67940-5fd2-11eb-9f5f-bb40263d5a28" width="3024" height="2016" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/d5a67940-5fd2-11eb-9f5f-bb40263d5a28" width="3024" height="2016" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Stephen Lam / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Twitter logo is seen outside the company headquarters, during a purported demonstration by supporters of U.S. President Donald Trump to protest the social media company's permanent suspension of the President's Twitter account, in San Francisco, California, U.S., January 11, 2021. REUTERS/Stephen Lam]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TWITTER-STOCKS/TRUMP]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[DoorDash expands alcohol deliveries to 20 states and DC]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The next time you have friends over and you happen to run out of one guest&#39;s favorite tipple, you&#39;ll have another way to order another bottle quickly — as long as you live in a place where <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/doordash">DoorDash</a> supports alcohol delivery. You can now use the app to <a href="https://ir.doordash.com/news/news-details/2021/DoorDash-Expands-Marketplace-Offering-with-Alcohol-On-Demand/default.aspx"><ins>order booze</ins></a> to your doorstep in 20 states, the District of Columbia, Canada and Australia. The company says more than 100 million people now have access to booze delivery through the app.</p><p>Users in those markets can view a selection of drinks from restaurants, grocery stores, retailers and convenience stores through the Alcohol tab. Depending on where you live, you may be able to bundle alcohol with your restaurant order using the <a href="https://doordash.news/2021/08/05/introducing-doubledash-a-new-way-to-shop-multiple-stores-in-one-order/"><ins>DoubleDash feature</ins></a>, which lets you add items to your order from nearby stores without paying a separate delivery fee.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You&#39;ll need to be of legal drinking age to order alcohol through DoorDash. Couriers will verify your age at dropoff. You can <a href="https://help.doordash.com/consumers/s/article/How-is-my-age-verified-for-alcohol-orders?language=fr_CA"><ins>upload a copy</ins></a> of your ID to the app. Couriers will only be able to see your photo and date of birth on the app — DoorDash says it blurs out all of the other information for security and privacy reasons.</p><p>Over the last few years, DoorDash has enabled merchants to deliver alcohol through DoorDash Drive, its white-label delivery service. DoorDash Drive couriers fulfill orders made via a merchant&#39;s own website, app or third-party platform, not the DoorDash app. The company previously let users in southern California <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-06-29-doordash-service-offers-beer-alongside-food.html">add alcohol</a> to their restaurant orders.</p><p>Alongside the expansion of hooch deliveries, DoorDash announced partnerships with alcohol responsibility organizations. Students Against Destructive Decisions and Responsibility.org focus on drunk driving and underage drinking. DoorDash also teamed up with two organizations Down Under, Drinkwise and Retail Drinks Australia, &quot;to further expand our commitment to responsible service of alcohol in other countries.&quot;</p><p>DoorDash is playing catch up a bit with its rivals when it comes to alcohol. Uber <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-buys-drizly-alcohol-delivery-service-145942834.html"><ins>bought</ins></a> booze delivery service Drizly earlier this year for $1.1 billion. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-14-instacart-pickups-include-alcohol-stores-nearby.html"><ins>Instacart</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-06-28-postmates-alcohol-delivery-comes-to-nyc-and-texas.html"><ins>Postmates</ins></a> both added alcohol delivery options over the last few years.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/doordash-alcohol-us-canada-australia-141544396.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">55145f27-af17-4273-82a6-79c575d2f48e</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 14:15:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632147292</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T14:15:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/58892ea0-1a1a-11ec-9f6f-0fa4a6f86be4" width="5158" height="3439" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/58892ea0-1a1a-11ec-9f6f-0fa4a6f86be4" width="5158" height="3439" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Carlo Allegri / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A DoorDash sign is pictured on a restaurant on the day they hold their IPO in the Manhattan borough of New York City, New York, U.S., December 9, 2020. REUTERS/Carlo Allegri]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[DOORDASH-IPO/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Algoriddim's djay iOS app uses Shazam to recognize and sync with live music]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Algoriddim has been working closely with Apple for years on its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/algoriddim-djay-pro-ai-for-mac-neural-mix-apple-m1-chip-150027988.html">djay apps</a> and regularly appears in the company&#39;s keynotes. Now, it&#39;s integrating another Apple product, Shazam, into its latest <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-12-algoriddim-djay-for-ios-free-pro-dj-software.html">iOS djay app</a> with the release of iOS 15. The new feature lets you can scan your surroundings and identify any song playing, whether at an event, listening to the radio or playing sets with other DJs. Once it picks out the song, djay will instantly load it onto the virtual decks and play it in sync with the external music source.&nbsp;</p><p>Once loaded, you can create a mix with similar tracks, remix the song, apply effects and deconstruct it into components using the company&#39;s Neural Mix tech. It can also save songs into iOS 15&#39;s music recognition history in the control center, &quot;providing users with streamlined access to all of their song discoveries,&quot; the company said.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="a9306fc9ad0d46f49fd10cd12fe623ed"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NvcvaJzRDaQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>While this sounds like cool technology in search of an application, Algoriddim has a few use cases in mind. The main one is that you can identify a track you might hear and get it into your library with the tap of a button, or create an automated mix based on the recognized song. &quot;djay can instantly provide you with similar tracks to the one you just heard, allowing you to quickly immerse yourself in a particular style,&quot; Algoriddim told Engadget.&nbsp;</p><p>Another, more marginal use case is with back-to-back DJing. If you&#39;re playing in tandem with another DJ or in a lineup, you can pick up where the last DJ left off by identifying and syncing with their song before phasing into your own set. This goes a step beyond beat matching, letting you match the last DJ&#39;s song exactly. Mind you, many DJs may not care to replay the last DJ’s song or work with a playlist inspired by it, especially if they weren’t familiar with the tracks</p><p>The Shazam-enhanced version of iOS djay lets you save recognized music to your Tidal (music and video), SoundCloud, Beatport and Beatsource libraries (not Spotify or Apple Music). Other new features include the ability to add effects to the master audio output, enabled by new Audio Unit (extensions) features in iOS 15. That will let you better tailor the sound for broadcast or to match a PA system. Algoriddim&#39;s iOS djay update for iOS is <a href="https://www.algoriddim.com/djay-ios">now available</a> for free, or you can get the Pro version for $6.99 per month or $49.99 per year.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/algoriddims-djay-i-os-app-uses-shazam-to-recognize-and-sync-with-live-music-140001218.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cb021e0a-c118-424b-a769-ffddd4e7dbbf</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632144348</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T13:26:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Music]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/481717a0-1a0e-11ec-9dfb-92bcc8328bb6" width="2000" height="1196" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/481717a0-1a0e-11ec-9dfb-92bcc8328bb6" width="2000" height="1196" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Algoriddim]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Algoriddim's djay iOS app uses Shazam to recognize and sync live music]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Algoriddim's djay iOS app uses Shazam to recognize and sync live music]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roku's new Streaming Stick 4K gets Dolby Vision, HDR10+ and better Wi-Fi]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Roku&#39;s $50 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-02-roku-4k-streaming-stick-players.html">Streaming Stick 4K</a> has been one of our favorite devices for years. It&#39;s cheap, pocketable and has just about every feature you&#39;d want in a streaming gadget. This year, Roku is finally adding a long-awaited feature to its new 4K stick: Dolby Vision HDR. That&#39;s something the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-ultra-dolby-vision-streaming-player-130015662.html">Roku Ultra started supporting last year</a>, and it&#39;s a particularly big deal for home theater fans. Additionally, the new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Streaming Stick 4K" href="https://amzn.to/3AvIn16">Streaming Stick 4K</a> boots up around 30 percent faster than before, and its revamped wireless receiver makes Wi-Fi speeds up to twice as fast, according to Roku.</p><p>Like the HDR10 format, Dolby Vision allows for higher peak brightness levels and more nuanced dark scenes. But it can also do so dynamically, tweaking its contrast and brightness levels for every individual frame in a film or TV show. That&#39;s something HDR10 can&#39;t do, though it&#39;s since been added to the newer HDR10+ format, which the new 4K streaming stick also supports. There&#39;s a lot more Dolby Vision content out there today, though, so I&#39;d wager most people would be more excited for Dolby Vision than HDR10+ support.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/16a0df40-1981-11ec-bafd-7e2bcfaa2c26" alt="Roku Streaming Stick 4K 2021" data-uuid="dec1ca0a-4a07-356b-8dde-ec029fc2626c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roku</div></figure><p>While the 4K streaming stick ships with Roku&#39;s standard voice remote, you can also opt for the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:$70 Streaming Stick 4K+ bundle" href="https://amzn.to/2XtRv7O">$70 Streaming Stick 4K+ bundle</a>, which packs in the company&#39;s new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-express-4k-rechargeable-remote-130031381.html">Voice Remote Pro</a>. Normally a $30 upgrade, that smarter clicker adds hands-free voice searching (instead of hitting a button), as well as a rechargeable battery. And if you&#39;re looking for something a bit more powerful, the $80 Wal-Mart exclusive Roku Ultra LT is also getting Dolby Vision, a faster processor and better Wi-Fi this year.</p><p>For most people, the Roku Streaming Stick 4K is likely all the streaming player you need. You can get faster speeds and more connectivity with the $100 Roku Ultra, or a nicer interface and game ecosystem with the $179 Apple TV 4K. But when it comes to just streaming video in the best possible formats, there&#39;s little need to spend more than $50. You&#39;ll be able to find the new Roku Streaming Stick 4K sometime mid-October in the US, and in the coming months across Canada, Mexico and other Latin American countries.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roku-streaming-stick-4k-dolby-vision-hdr10-130040918.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1e38e48c-8d94-4f23-af98-582c97aad3cd</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632145473</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T13:44:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/16a01bf0-1981-11ec-bb6c-770f56943208" width="2000" height="1249" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/16a01bf0-1981-11ec-bb6c-770f56943208" width="2000" height="1249" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roku]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roku Streaming Stick 4K 2021]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roku Streaming Stick 4K 2021]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roku OS 10.5 adds better voice support, 5.1 Roku speaker configurations]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You won&#39;t need <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-streaming-stick-4k-dolby-vision-hdr10-130040918.html">Roku&#39;s new Streaming Stick 4K </a>to take advantage of its latest software features. The Roku OS 10.5 update, which will roll out to players and TVs in the next few weeks, will be jam-packed with features to make your streaming life easier. There&#39;s expanded Roku Voice support, which will let you ask players (with supported remotes) to start playing content from Netflix, Spotify and most other channels. And the company has added a Live TV Channel Guide to help find free TV content (so far there are more than 200 live channels to sift through).</p><p>But more importantly for the Roku faithful, there are even more configurations for the company&#39;s wireless speakers. Roku OS 10.5 will let you use any of the company&#39;s soundbars — the Streambar, Streambar Pro and Smart Soundbar — as a center channel flanked by Roku wireless speakers. Put that setup together with two more rear speakers and a wireless sub, and voila, you&#39;ve got a full-fledged 5.1 surround solution. Previously, you were only able to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-29-roku-surround-sound-speakers-soundbar.html">use Roku&#39;s soundbars as all of your front channels</a> (left, right and center).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2ddc1150-1983-11ec-beff-a85753283c69" alt="Roku OS 10.5" data-uuid="605257c6-0359-3d4f-87f0-e476883d6bce"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roku</div></figure><p>From what I recall of Roku&#39;s earlier surround solution, it sounded more than adequate for a small room. I haven&#39;t heard the company&#39;s 5.1 setup yet, but generally having more speakers is always better. At the very least, you can expect clearer dialog and better front channel separation. I can&#39;t say if it&#39;s worth shelling out up to  $630 for all of Roku&#39;s speakers ($300 for four wireless speakers, $180 for the StreamBar Pro, and $150 for the wireless subwoofer), but it&#39;s nice to have the flexibility to build out a full system if you&#39;ve already invested in a few of them.</p><p>Roku OS 10.5 will also add some audio improvements for headphones. When you connect a wireless headset to the Roku mobile app, it will adjust your sync settings based on the type of headphone you&#39;re using. You&#39;ll also be able to use your smartphone camera to adjust the audio delay even further. That&#39;s a useful feature for anyone using Bluetooth headphones, where audio delay issues are fairly common.</p><p>To coincide with expanded Spotify voice support, Roku is also adding a new music and podcasts row to its system search. You&#39;ll be able to see results from Spotify&#39;s entire library, but more importantly it opens the door for better audio app support on Roku OS.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roku-os-10-5-update-voice-speakers-130013021.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9b45363a-b4d0-432a-998b-88a8f0b0e8c5</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632082837</ingested><modified>2021-09-19T20:20:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2ddbc330-1983-11ec-9c1f-88e0d0fcc21b" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2ddbc330-1983-11ec-9c1f-88e0d0fcc21b" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roku]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roku OS 10.5]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roku OS 10.5]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: 12 years in jail for unlocking smartphones]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The mastermind behind a seven-year scheme to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/att-phones-unlocked-fraud-prison-sentence-194554103.html"><ins>illegally unlock AT&amp;T handsets has been sentenced to 12 years in jail</ins></a>. Muhammad Fahd unlocked phones for ineligible customers who still had to pay off the cost of their smartphone. AT&amp;T says  1.9 million handsets were unlocked in this manner, and it lost around $201.5 million because of the scheme.</p><p>Fahd contacted and subsequently bribed an AT&amp;T employee to help unlock devices until the company locked down the system. Consequently, Fahd commissioned malware to be installed on AT&amp;T’s internal systems, which captured data on both the company and its employees. Fahd was indicted in 2017, arrested in Hong Kong a year later and extradited to the US in 2019.</p><p>Perhaps the most staggering part of the story is the lengths Fahd went to keep the project going. It’s not clear if Fahd’s malware put any customer data at risk, but that a scheme like this was able to run for so long is troubling.</p><p>— Dan Cooper</p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ultra-white-paint-eliminates-air-conditioning-211150734.html"><strong><ins>Ultra-white paint could reduce the need for air conditioning</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>Someone stop Anish Kapoor from getting hold of this.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ultra-white-paint-eliminates-air-conditioning-211150734.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/75e166a0-19f9-11ec-b7ff-fd8866068460" style="height:380;width:675;" alt="Image of Purdue University&#39;s new White Paint that is designed to reflect solar radiation." data-uuid="ca8d2859-eb45-3255-a768-81a2ad2c2235"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Purdue University / John Underwood</div></figure></a><p>Pretty much everyone knows you can make your house a lot cooler if you paint it white, which is common practice in warmer countries. Now, however, a team of scientists at Purdue University has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ultra-white-paint-eliminates-air-conditioning-211150734.html"><ins>cooked up the ultimate white paint</ins></a>, which, they claim, works so well it could eliminate the need for air conditioning. The covering supposedly reflects 98.1 percent of all solar radiation, theoretically leaving the surface <em>cooler</em> than the surrounding environment. If it works and it’s implemented properly, it could reduce the global energy bill by quite a figure.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ultra-white-paint-eliminates-air-conditioning-211150734.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading. </ins></strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html"><strong><ins>Netflix and Apple TV+ clean up at the Emmys with &#39;The Crown&#39; and &#39;Ted Lasso&#39;</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>HBO is the only ‘traditional’ broadcaster who earned more than streamers.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/92c83c30-19f9-11ec-a157-40daf5b64a76" style="height:482;width:675;" alt="Image of Jason Sudekis as Ted Lasso, supplied by Apple" data-uuid="e1c95001-829a-36c3-88ea-c59c14f9a22f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple TV+, Warner Bros.</div></figure></a><p>In 2020, Apple TV+ was proud to earn just <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-won-its-first-big-emmy-for-billy-crudup-in-the-morning-show-131557453.html"><ins>one</ins></a> primetime Emmy for <em>The Morning Show’s</em> Billy Crudup. A year later and the nascent streamer managed to take home <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html"><ins>11 trophies</ins></a>, with breakout hit <em>Ted Lasso</em> earning seven of those on its own. In fact, while HBO remains the top dog of this particular awards show, Netflix’s<em> The Crown</em> won most of the big drama nods. It’s clear that streaming services are swallowing the world whole, and the challenge of formerly blue-chip broadcasters is to somehow up the ante on their well-heeled rivals.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading.</ins></strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-8-leak-120hz-display-153612043.html"><strong><ins>Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8 might include a 120Hz screen and Thunderbolt ports</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>September 22nd is just a few days away.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-8-leak-120hz-display-153612043.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a9fb69e0-19f9-11ec-aeff-0a9d2a69bfdd" style="height:450;width:675;" alt="Two Thunderbolt ports and a 120Hz display." data-uuid="0f4be605-c4e7-37cc-a5df-3297b79fc7ed"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Shadow Leak, Twitter</div></figure></a><p></p><p>Microsoft has a big event coming September 22nd, and an image, via Twitter user Shadow_Leak, purporting to be a store listing suggests the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-8-leak-120hz-display-153612043.html"><ins>Surface Pro 8</ins></a> might get some big improvements. New features for the slate include a narrow-bezel, 120Hz display, dual Thunderbolt ports and an 11th-generation Intel Core processor. Given how the Surface Pro has become such a mainstay of Microsoft’s hardware lineup, it’s always exciting to see some dramatic changes year on year.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-8-leak-120hz-display-153612043.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading.</ins></strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ntsb-head-on-tesla-full-self-driving-safety-170443851.html"><strong><ins>NTSB head says Tesla must address &#39;basic safety issues&#39; with semi-autonomous features</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>Regulators are not happy with how Tesla operates or markets its technology.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ntsb-head-on-tesla-full-self-driving-safety-170443851.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e8b1cbc0-19f9-11ec-aba8-80484fc3d56c" style="height:386;width:675;" alt="Image of Tesla Model 3 Steering Wheel" data-uuid="ba635080-01fd-3221-9038-38c9a3c54a69"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roberto Baldwin</div></figure></a><p>The new head of the National Transportation Safety Board has advised Tesla to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ntsb-head-on-tesla-full-self-driving-safety-170443851.html"><ins>get its house in order</ins></a>. In an interview, Jennifer Homendy said she took issue with how Tesla tests, operates and markets its self-driving technology. That includes the “misleading and irresponsible” way it sells Full Self Driving, which encourages people to “misuse and abuse” it. In addition, Homendy said the company needed to address “basic safety issues” rather than focus on headline-grabbing new features. Homendy’s words don’t mean much yet in a policy sense, but it might set the tone on how the NTSB chooses to deal with companies like Tesla in future.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ntsb-head-on-tesla-full-self-driving-safety-170443851.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading.</ins></strong></a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-serial-1-mosh-tribute-e-bike-release-date-200253680.html"><strong><ins>Harley-Davidson will sell its retro-inspired e-bike by the end of 2021</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>It’s a beauty but, oh boy, is it expensive.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-serial-1-mosh-tribute-e-bike-release-date-200253680.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/18d20c20-19fa-11ec-aff6-5001e809b503" style="height:450;width:675;" alt="Image of Harley Davidson&#39;s beautiful retro e-Bike" data-uuid="745bda54-5b87-3e43-9365-9d757c8cec85"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Harley Davidson</div></figure></a><p>Were you disappointed when Harley-Davidson <a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-ebike-serial-1-reveal-192548936.html"><ins>showed off</ins></a> a gorgeous, retro-inspired e-bike then didn’t put it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-serial-1-ebikes-pre-order-154027916.html"><ins>on sale?</ins></a> Thankfully, someone at the company heard your sighs of frustration and is going to release a version, called the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-serial-1-mosh-tribute-e-bike-release-date-200253680.html"><ins>MOSH/TRIBUTE, towards the end of this year</ins></a>. Unfortunately, no matter how pretty this thing is, there’ll only be a limited release of 650, and it’ll cost you $5,999 for the privilege of owning one. But, you know, it is <em>pretty</em>.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/harley-davidson-serial-1-mosh-tribute-e-bike-release-date-200253680.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading.</ins></strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-abused-android-dominance-india-antitrust-124019374.html"><strong><ins>India says Google abused Android dominance</ins></strong></a></h2><h3>It’s the conclusion of a two-year antitrust probe</h3><p></p><p>India’s competition authority has found Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-abused-android-dominance-india-antitrust-124019374.html"><ins>abused its dominant position</ins></a> to box out potential rivals. A two-year probe into how the search giant does business on the subcontinent has found the company in violation of the local competition law. Regulators took issue with how Google prevents manufacturers from using forked versions of Android, and the “arbitrary” nature of the Play Store’s policies. India joins an ever-growing list of countries that have probed Google’s business dealings and found something isn’t right. Regulators have yet to decide if Google’s conduct was illegal and if fines need to be handed out, but given what happened in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-177-million-fine-south-korea-antitrust-064455427.html"><ins>South Korea just a few days back</ins></a>, we shouldn’t be surprised.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-abused-android-dominance-india-antitrust-124019374.html"><strong><ins>Continue Reading.</ins></strong></a></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><h3></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-bans-chinese-brands-for-review-fraud-191820086.html"><ins>Amazon has banned over 600 Chinese brands as part of review fraud crackdown</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/israel-remote-control-iran-scientist-assassination-144746205.html"><ins>Israel reportedly used a remote-controlled gun to assassinate an Iranian scientist</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/cadillac-lyriq-debut-edition-ev-sold-out-141406753.html"><ins>Cadillac&#39;s inaugural Lyriq EV sold out of reservations in 10 minutes</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/binance-insider-trading-probe-184903656.html"><ins>US probe into Binance reportedly expands to investigate insider trading</ins></a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-12-years-in-jail-for-unlocking-smartphones-111535951.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">19e45001-77ed-4db7-a5c2-7b7ba49e0d4f</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:15:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632132648</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T10:11:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/53168a60-19f9-11ec-baa3-56e558f3e983" width="2455" height="1661" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/53168a60-19f9-11ec-baa3-56e558f3e983" width="2455" height="1661" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ronald Martinez via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[DALLAS, TEXAS - MARCH 13:  A man walks with an umbrella outside of AT&T corporate headquarters on March 13, 2020 in Dallas, Texas.  AT&T is allowing employees to work remotely from home if they have the ability to do so, as a safety measure due to COVID-19. (Photo by Ronald Martinez/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AT&T Advises Its Over 200,000 Workforce To Work From Home, As Coronavirus Continues To Spread]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon leaks new Kindle Paperwhite models on its own site]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon may be getting set to release a new version of its Paperwhite reader including a high-end &quot;Signature Edition,&quot; according to Amazon listings spotted by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kindle/comments/prk1kq/is_there_gonna_be_a_new_kindle_theres_a_new/">Reddit users</a> and <a href="https://goodereader.com/blog/electronic-readers/amazon-is-going-to-release-kindle-paperwhite-5-signature-edition-soon"><em>GoodEReader</em></a>. A comparison chart on Amazon&#39;s Canadian and Mexican sites, now removed, showed new Kindle Paperwhite and Paperwhite Signature Edition models, with 6.8-inch 300 ppi displays and 17 LEDs. The current Paperwhite, by contrast, has a 6-inch display and just four LEDs.&nbsp;</p><p>Both models are IPX8 waterproof as before, offer a &quot;flush-front design&quot; and appear to have narrower side and top bezels. They also feature an &quot;adjustable warm light,&quot; meaning they likely have both white and amber LEDs — just like Amazon&#39;s high-end <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-19-the-new-kindle-oasis-adjusts-its-screen-color-to-the-time-of-day.html">Kindle Oasis</a>. The Signature Edition offers a storage update over the Paperwhite 5 to 32GB, along with wireless charging and auto-adjusting light sensors that change screen brightness depending on the environment.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Canadian listing shows the Paperwhite and Paperwhite Signature Edition at CAD$150 and CAD$210, (about $117 and $165, respectively), but those could just be placeholders. Currently, the standard 8GB Kindle is $90, the 8GB Kindle Paperwhite $130 and the 8GB Kindle Oasis is $250. If the new prices are accurate you&#39;d be paying more for the Paperwhite, but get some of the features found on the Oasis.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazons-next-kindle-5-may-come-in-a-signature-edition-with-more-storage-101549272.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c22c24e4-9a87-43fc-8c2e-4c75814d2261</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 10:15:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632132952</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T10:16:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Currency]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/b8a60520-19f6-11ec-beff-c0a30d134ac7" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/b8a60520-19f6-11ec-beff-c0a30d134ac7" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon's next Kindle 5 may come in a 'Signature Edition' with more storage]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon's next Kindle 5 may come in a 'Signature Edition' with more storage]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok owner ByteDance limits younger users to 40 minutes a day in China]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-cuts-kids-gaming-time-132539606.html">crackdown on gaming</a> by Chinese authorities, ByteDance is <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/zp43DhzwanDApoPCIgCvJQ">introducing</a> new youth controls for Douyin, its TikTok-equivalent app in China, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-20/bytedance-s-new-tiktok-for-chinese-kids-sets-strict-user-limits"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> has reported. Any users confirmed to be under 14 will enter a new &quot;youth mode&quot; limited to 40 minutes of usage per day. At the same time, it unveiled a new app called Xiao Qu Xing (&quot;Little Fun Star&quot;), a TikTok-style short video app with limited subject materials, a 40 minute time limit and the ability to like, but not upload or share videos.&nbsp;</p><p>On top of the time restriction, kids in China won&#39;t be able to access Douyin between 10PM and 6AM. The new controls only apply to users who supplied their real names and ages, so to that end, Douyin has asked parents to register their kids&#39; real information. ByteDance also added more content to Douyin with educational subjects like science, art history, history and more. The new app, Xiao Qu Xing, appears to offer exclusively educational content.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Gaming limits introduced earlier this month are even more restrictive, with under-14s limited to just three hours per week between 8-9PM on Friday, weekends and public holidays. Previously, kids could game for 90 minutes a day and three hours on holidays. The rule change was put in place to combat gaming addiction, regulators said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The TikTok restrictions won&#39;t affect as many kids, however. According to an article in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3149397/chinese-version-tiktok-limits-kids-under-14-40-minutes-day-adding-fight">South China Morning Post (SCMP)</a>, just 0.34 percent of Douyin users are under 12, with 4.18 percent from 13-19 years old. Those figures are far from certain, though, as Douyin doesn&#39;t publish demographic data.&nbsp;</p><p>It also acknowledged that it might be easy to bypass the new rules. &quot;As the first short video platform to launch minor protection measures, we deeply understand that there will be imperfections,&quot; the company said in a statement. To that end, it has launched a bug-finding campaign seeking &quot;loopholes&quot; in the login process.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tik-tok-china-limits-kids-under-14-to-40-minutes-each-day-091559878.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c190bb0f-05b6-42e1-bd67-2b096a846265</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 09:15:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632129361</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T09:16:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-11/fd8fa760-fd72-11e9-b7f7-3ef3b19b092f" width="3353" height="2236" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-11/fd8fa760-fd72-11e9-b7f7-3ef3b19b092f" width="3353" height="2236" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[China Stringer Network / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A man holding a phone walks past a sign of Chinese company ByteDance's app TikTok, known locally as Douyin, at the International Artificial Products Expo in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, China October 18, 2019. Picture taken October 18, 2019.  REUTERS/Stringer  ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE WAS PROVIDED BY A THIRD PARTY. CHINA OUT.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[USA-CONGRESS/TIKTOK]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[IKEA's new $40 wireless charging pad mounts underneath your desk or table]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;ve ever thought, &quot;hey, it would be great if I could charge my phone or tablet just by laying it on a regular desk,&quot; then IKEA has the gadget for you. It just unveiled the <a href="https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/sjoemaerke-wireless-charger-80512718/">Sjömärke</a>, a $40 wireless charging pad that&#39;s designed to work with nearly any desk or table, as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677980/ikea-sjomarke-wireless-qi-charging-existing-furniture"><em>The Verge</em></a> has reported.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/73b34ff0-19e1-11ec-9f47-e6166b43e89f" style="height:405;width:870;" alt="IKEA&#39;s $40 pad gives your desk wireless charging powers with no clutter" data-uuid="6b7b0a65-8933-320c-87fa-012dc049577a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">IKEA</div></figure><p>The concept is pretty clever. Sjömärke is a Wireless Qi charging pad, but you don&#39;t place it on your desk. Rather, it installs <em>underneath</em> your desk and is held in place either by double-sided tape (included) or 18mm x 6mm screws (not included). Your desktop needs to be made of something like wood or plastic that won&#39;t block the magnetic field, and must have a minimum thickness of 8mm (5/16th of an inch), and a maximum of 22.2mm (7/8th of an inch), according to the <a href="https://www.ikea.com/us/en/manuals/sjoemaerke-wireless-charger__AA-2281316-2_pub.pdf">manual</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Once you install the pad, plug it in with the six-foot power cable and mark the charging point on your table with the included &quot;X&quot; shaped sticker, you&#39;re ready to charge your phone or other device. With Qi 1.2.4 charging, it should supply about 5 watts for decent but not super fast charging. IKEA notes that it also comes with temperature and power monitoring so it won&#39;t overheat — important, since it will be placed against wood surfaces.&nbsp;</p><div id="cf09a4c6fd064735a4087eae0f55ca7e"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K0IvUXG-8wQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>For $40, this might prove to be an attractive option for folks who don&#39;t want to mess up their décor with an unseemly plastic pad. Sjömärke will arrive in <a href="https://bit.ly/3lAbpX8">IKEA&#39;s stores and website</a> in October 2021.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ikeas-pad-can-give-your-desk-wireless-charging-powers-with-no-clutter-072405388.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">32aa471f-8836-4e56-83b3-a01c1ced57e7</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 07:24:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632122648</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T07:24:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Home & Garden]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7cff76f0-19d8-11ec-bff9-c8a2b05142f9" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7cff76f0-19d8-11ec-bff9-c8a2b05142f9" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Fototocam via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Top View of trendy wooden Office Desk with keyboard, white earphones and office supplies]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Top View of trendy wooden Office Desk with keyboard, white earphones and office supplies]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix and Apple TV+ clean up at the Emmys with 'The Crown' and 'Ted Lasso']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix has <a href="https://www.emmys.com/awards/nominees-winners/2021/outstanding-drama-series">nabbed</a> the most Emmys ever for a single platform with 44 including 11 for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-the-crown-win-big-at-the-golden-globe-awards-091701851.html"><em>The Crown</em></a>, more than double its nearest rival, HBO/HBO Max. The 2021 edition of the awards was also a watershed year for Apple TV+, which took home 10 Emmys including seven for its comedy series <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ted-lasso-season-two-july-23-apple-tv-plus-225341867.html"><em>Ted Lasso</em></a>.</p><p>To be sure, a huge chunk of Netflix&#39;s Emmy harvest came from the 34 Creative Arts Emmys it won last week. However, it still took a further 10 primetime Emmys including acting awards for Olivia Colman, Gillian Anderson and Josh O&#39;Connor in <em>The Crown</em>, along with Ewan McGregor in <em>Halston</em>. <em>The Crown</em> also won for writing and directing, while taking the prestigious best drama series prize. Netflix&#39;s The Queen&#39;s Gambit, starring Anya Taylor-Joy, won for best limited series.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/dd1caa80-19d3-11ec-9f73-6a4d4f66f61a" alt="Actors Jeremy Swift, Phil Dunster, Brett Goldstein, Hannah Waddingham, Jason Sudeikis, Juno Temple, Nick Mohammed and Brendan Hunt, cast members of " data-uuid="6ef5be24-efec-3d79-ad07-1cf0ecb0ecee"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Mario Anzuoni / reuters</div></figure><p>Meanwhile, Apple TV+ had its best Emmys yet with 10 total, including seven in primetime. It dominated the comedy series category with seven wins for <em>Ted Lasso</em>, including three in the acting category for Brett Goldstein and Hannah Waddingham (best supporting actors) along with Jason Sudeikis (best actor). <em>Ted Lasso</em> also took the award for best comedy series.&nbsp;</p><p>Thanks in large part to that series, Apple TV+ fared much better than its rivals. Disney+ did beat it with 14 awards total, up from eight in 2020, but only one of those was a primetime Emmy (<em>Hamilton</em> for best pre-recorded variety special). Amazon and Hulu were completely shut out in 2021, after both won Emmys in 2020.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>HBO and HBO Max led all rivals with 130 nominations and took 19 Emmys, including 9 in primetime. The biggest winners last night were Jean Smart for <em>Hacks</em> (best actress in a comedy series) and Kate Winslet for <em>Mare of Easstown</em> (best actress in a limited series). After she was controversially <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-the-crown-win-big-at-the-golden-globe-awards-091701851.html">shut out</a> of the Golden Globes nominations, Michaela Coel took the prize for best writing in a limited series for <em>I May Destroy You</em>.</p><p>It was notable in 2018 when Netflix managed to tie a cable network, HBO (pre-HBO Max), for the most Emmy wins. This year, it beat all rivals by a long way, and streaming platforms overall took the top four spots. Whether that can continue when the pandemic starts to wane — and subscription growth declines — remains to be seen.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1dc37b19-972f-4551-927a-b8254dd8f7d3</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 05:39:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632124659</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T07:57:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Television]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2edd77f0-19d4-11ec-9ee7-411e3abf05e8" width="2471" height="1759" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2edd77f0-19d4-11ec-9ee7-411e3abf05e8" width="2471" height="1759" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Gareth Cattermole via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LONDON, ENGLAND - SEPTEMBER 19:  Gillian Anderson with her Emmy award for 'Outstanding Supporting Actress for a Drama Series', at the "The Crown" 73rd Primetime Emmys Celebration at Soho House on September 19, 2021 in London, England. (Photo by Gareth Cattermole/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA["The Crown" 73rd Primetime Emmys Celebration - Red Carpet Arrivals]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ultra-white paint could reduce the need for air conditioning]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>White houses are often boring, but they might just save the planet. As <em>USA Today</em><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2021/09/17/whitest-paint-created-global-warming/8378579002/">reports</a>, Purdue University researchers have <a href="https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2021/Q3/purdue-record-for-the-whitest-paint-appears-in-latest-edition-of-guinness-world-records.html">developed</a> an ultra-white paint (it just earned a Guinness World Record) that reflects 98.1 percent of solar radiation while outputting infrared heat. As this leaves the surface cooler than the environment (regular paint warms the surface), it could effectively replace air conditioning in some cases — it produces a cooling power of 10kW for a 1,000sq. ft. roof, or more than a typical house AC unit.</p><p>There are existing paints made to reflect heat, but they reflect no more than 90 percent of sunlight and don&#39;t cool surfaces. The team didn&#39;t have much breathing room, either — an even whiter paint might have compromised it.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The trick was to use a high ratio of barium sulfate, a compound you often see in cosmetics and photo paper, in varying particle sizes. The wider range of sizes helps scatter more of the light spectrum and thus reflect more sunlight.</p><p>It&#39;s not clear how close this extremely white paint is to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-29-benjamin-moore-colorreader.html">your local store</a>, but the researchers are fully bent on commercializing their work. They&#39;ve teamed with a company to mass-produce and sell the paint, and have already filed patents. If it lives up to the billing, though, it could play an important role in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/europe-21-years-behind-emissions-goals-enel-study-180121943.html">fighting climate change</a>.  It could reduce or eliminate the need for air conditioning in some homes, particularly in warm regions with ample sunlight. That could reduce emissions and power consumption, and might save you some money on hot summer days.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ultra-white-paint-eliminates-air-conditioning-211150734.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">97a3f35d-e8e2-44a4-9d95-007f498f23ea</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 21:11:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632141146</ingested><modified>2021-09-20T12:32:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c9c1b820-198a-11ec-beff-1a4dfa753af9" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c9c1b820-198a-11ec-beff-1a4dfa753af9" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Purdue University photo/John Underwood]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Ultra-white paint from Purdue University that could eliminate the need for air conditioning in some buildings]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ultra-white paint from Purdue University]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>