<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Photoshop update lets you simply hover over an object to select it]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adobe has unveiled its latest <a href="https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2021/10/26/adobe-unleashes-content-attribution-features-photoshop-beyond-max-2021.html">Photoshop update</a> on desktop and iPad for its Adobe Max 2021 event, and as with the last few versions, the most interesting features are powered by AI. Chief among those is the &quot;Hover Auto-masking Object Selection Tool&quot; that allows you to select a scene object simply by hovering your mouse over it.&nbsp;</p><p>The feature is really as simple as that, as Adobe&#39;s Sensei AI kicks in to determine the edges of an object and select it automatically with a single click. Adobe has promised that selections made either with the hover or other object selection tools &quot;are now more accurate and preserve more details in the edges of a selection,&quot; helping users save time.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7dac82f0-357b-11ec-8757-176a74ecf2b2" style="height:431;width:650;" alt="Adobe photoshop updates max 2021" data-uuid="fae08631-dfe7-3632-bff3-f052d8770654"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>The tool can detect most but not all objects in a scene, and Adobe said it&#39;s constantly improving it to include additional object categories. If an object is not detected or only partially detected, you can drag a marquee over the areas you&#39;d like to select, which is how the tool worked previously.&nbsp;</p><p>Along the same lines is another new feature called &quot;mask all objects.&quot; Also powered by Sensei AI, it simply scans the scene and automatically selects and masks every object in the scene. It can then create masks or objects without the need to do a lick of tedious masking work.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/50df4580-3578-11ec-aefb-dd53b4363a21" style="height:707;width:1432;" alt="Adobe&#39;s latest Photoshop lets you simply hover over an object to select it" data-uuid="b83256c2-7bf0-33bb-86e1-69e5e530e077"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>Last year, Adobe introduced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/photoshop-desktop-ipad-update-artificial-intelligence-130024695.html">Neural Filters</a> that let you do things like smooth skin or make a photo look like a Van Gogh painting. For 2021, it has introduced more of those filters in beta, most notably the Landscape Mixer, Color Transfer and Harmonization. Landscape Mixer can essentially blend multiple landscape to create a new scene with desert elements replacing a seaside coastal scene, for example.&nbsp;</p><p>The most useful one, however, sounds like Color Transfer. It lets you take the colors, contrast and other elements from a photo you like and apply it to another photo, or &quot;make this image look like that,&quot; as Adobe puts it. That would remove a lot of the tedium or trying to match a photographer&#39;s style, or at least give you a starting point toward the look you&#39;re aiming for.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c928a890-357a-11ec-9ffd-027b98e5a5e0" style="height:834;width:2000;" alt="Adobe&#39;s latest Photoshop lets you simply hover over an object to select it" data-uuid="8854cf3f-3e4a-3d11-95eb-c5c5afac9fce"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>The last one, the Harmonization neural filter, makes it easier to composite two images. It overlays a foreground image onto a background, while automatically adjusting the hue and luminosity of the foreground image to match. Adobe also improved the existing neural filters, adding more realistic blurs to Depth Blur, while also improving the Superzoom, Style Transfer and Colorize filters.</p><p>Other new updates improved gradients, color management and HDR capabilities. Finally, Adobe has improved interoperability between Photoshop and Illustrator, letting you copy vector shapes from Illustrator and paste them into Photoshop, &quot;all while maintaining editable attributes in Photoshop like fill, stroke, blend mode and opacity.&quot; And when Photoshop can&#39;t maintain editability from Illustrator because it doesn&#39;t support a feature, &quot;we try to maintain visual fidelity.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/adobes-latest-photoshop-lets-you-simply-hover-over-an-object-to-select-it-130055599.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2531f31e-b64e-46fa-8737-c4e7567af20e</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635156608</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T10:10:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1b884050-3576-11ec-9faf-b6f1e85a08a2" width="2000" height="1143" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1b884050-3576-11ec-9faf-b6f1e85a08a2" width="2000" height="1143" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Adobe's latest Photoshop lets you simply hover over an object to select it]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Adobe's latest Photoshop lets you simply hover over an object to select it]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adobe brings Photoshop and Illustrator to the web]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adobe has <a href="https://xn--mastertheblogadobe-dn9jha.hlx.page/en/drafts/jennie/creative-cloud-canvas-spaces-ps-ai-in-browser.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s taken &quot;a major step forward for collaboration&quot; by bringing its Photoshop and Illustrator apps to the web. The idea is not to do let you do complex work from a web page, but allow collaborators to open and view your work from a browser to provide comments and feedback — much as you can with a Google Doc.&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s currently possible to store your work in Adobe&#39;s Creative Cloud and let anyone open it from anywhere, but they need to have the desktop or iPad app. Now with Photoshop or Illustrator, your colleagues &quot;can review and add comments right in the browser without having to download apps or have a Creative Cloud subscription,&quot; Adobe notes. That means you could show your work directly to ad agency or other clients who don&#39;t need or want Adobe&#39;s products.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4974b610-364d-11ec-be4f-c471395ecefe" style="height:800;width:1280;" alt="Photoshop and Illustrator come to the web for basic edits and collaboration" data-uuid="e6680788-5eb2-3f7c-a407-01b1f3caca5b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>On top of the basic collaboration tools, Adobe is preview some basic browser editing tools that would allow you to make &quot;minor tweaks and quick edits&quot; without having to launch the full Illustrator or Photoshop apps. Those include things like selection, minor color correction and more.&nbsp;</p><p>Taking a page from Microsoft Teams, Klaxoon and similar apps, Adobe is also launching &quot;Creative Cloud Spaces&quot; that allows creative teams to bring &quot;content, context and people together to one place,&quot; according to Adobe. That&#39;s essentially a whiteboard available to project members, showing documents, images and whatever else is required.&nbsp;</p><p>You can start sharing Photoshop and Illustrator work via the web, for the purpose of commenting and feedback, simply by updating the latest versions of the apps dropping today. If you want to try the basic editing capabilities, they&#39;re available via beta for Photoshop (within the Creative Cloud app) or as a private beta for Illustrator. You can request access for the latter <a href="https://pages.adobe.com/creativecloud/en/collaboration/private-beta">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/photoshop-and-illustrator-come-to-the-web-for-comments-basic-edits-and-more-130045329.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6a3f7e2e-3816-4323-bc35-aec0265f4e81</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635247137</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T11:19:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7bddeb20-3644-11ec-adfe-dc94ad154248" width="1280" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7bddeb20-3644-11ec-adfe-dc94ad154248" width="1280" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Photoshop and Illustrator come to the web for basic edits and collaboration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Photoshop and Illustrator come to the web for basic edits and collaboration]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oura’s updated smart ring has continuous heart-rate tracking]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been four years since Oura launched its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-03-13-oura-s-second-generation-ring-is-a-better-fit-for-your-finger.html">second-generation</a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oura-smart-ring-nba-teardown-ifixit-071435908.html">smart ring</a>, but the company hasn’t been out of the spotlight in all of that time. Oura rings found themselves on the fingers of a number of high-profile figures and a number of studies used it to determine if wearable technology <a href="https://www.engadget.com/west-virginia-university-oura-ring-covid-19-symptoms-003239603.html">could predict COVID-19 symptom</a>s. Now, the Finnish company is announcing its third-generation ring with an even greater emphasis on cramming as much hardware into that tiny body as the laws of physics will allow.</p><p>The v3 Oura Ring doesn’t look much different compared to its predecessor, and isn’t — at least on the outside. Inside, however, the company has sweated several new components down to fit inside its chassis, including a new optical heart-rate sensor. That unit alone will let the wearable track your heart rate during the day — something it’s only been able to do at night so far. In addition, you’ll also get heart rate tracking during workouts, and even get blood oxygenation readings.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>With new improved continuous temperature monitoring, Oura’s makers believe that the new model will be far better at predicting when periods will begin. The company added that you can expect more accurate sleep tracking, although the insights related to that won’t be available until at some point early next year. You’ll also get data about how relaxed and rested you are to better enable you to take some time out as, and when, you need it.</p><p>You may have noticed that many wearables companies have pivoted toward getting that sweet, sweet recurring revenue in recent years. Oura is no exception, and for $5.99 a month you can get “daily health insights, personalized recommendations, exclusive audio, educational videos and more.” If you sign up for the membership, you’ll also get a discount on the price of the new ring, which will set you back $299 when it begins shipping at some point in November.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/oura-third-generation-smart-ring-continuous-heart-rate-temperature-tracking-130043398.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3d246aa2-3c7d-47ee-aad5-ea443ce830c1</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635173757</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T14:56:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4a0f6620-35a2-11ec-94df-c23efdef9375" width="1800" height="1012" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4a0f6620-35a2-11ec-94df-c23efdef9375" width="1800" height="1012" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Oura]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Image of the third-generation Oura ring on white background with an emphasis on the new LED sensors.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Oura v3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kindle Paperwhite Signature Edition review: The best e-reader. Period.]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One thing you can definitely say about Amazon’s Kindle: it’s not the kind of device you need to upgrade often, even if you’re an avid reader. I’ve been using the same one since late 2015, and it’s still going strong. But Amazon caught my attention with <a href="https://amzn.to/2XGjv8C">the 5th-generation Paperwhite</a>. For the first time since the original Paperwhite, Amazon <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-kids-signature-edition-130032095.html">increased the display size</a> to 6.8 inches, from six, and it has narrower bezels than ever before. It also now uses 17 LED backlights (up from only five) and an adjustable “warm light” to reduce eye strain at night. Amazon has also finally switched to USB-C for charging.</p><p>Those are some notable new features, but Amazon is also offering a “Signature Edition” (SE) this year, which has 32GB of storage (the standard model only has 8GB), an automatically adjusting backlight, wireless charging and no ads on the lock screen. And it&#39;s still waterproof, can play back Audible audiobooks over Bluetooth and has tremendous battery life. At $190, it’s not cheap; nor, at $140, is the standard Paperwhite. But, if you’ve been using yours for as long (or longer) than me, there’s a lot to like here. It doesn’t radically change the Kindle experience, but does make it a lot nicer.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you’ve used a Kindle at all in the last decade, you’ll be familiar with the new Paperwhite’s design. Like other e-readers, the Paperwhite is dominated by an E Ink touchscreen that has gentle backlights you can turn on or off and adjust to fit your reading conditions. Like earlier Kindles, the rest of the device is soft-touch plastic that picks up fingerprint grease a little too easily.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6298f3e0-35d5-11ec-ae5f-0ec9fa182983" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="d4309305-dd5b-3067-beb8-388063920f2b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>Also, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-13-kindle-paperwhite-review-2018.html">like the 2018 Paperwhite</a>, the screen here is flush with the front of the device, rather than being slightly recessed, like it was on previous models. Coming from an older device, I loved this change. It makes swiping the touchscreen to turn pages much more pleasant, and having the display a little bit closer to your eyes feels better too. It’s simply a higher-quality experience – but if you have a 2018 Paperwhite, or the more expensive Kindle Oasis, you know this already.</p><p>More significant is the larger screen size. Amazon kept the same 300 pixel-per-inch density here, so the display looks as nice as ever. There’s just more room for your books and navigating the Kindle UI. Between the extra screen space and some changes to the interface, using the device is much more comfortable than it used to be. It is worth knowing that the new Paperwhite is ever so slightly wider and taller – so if you have small hands or already found the Kindle to be a little too large, this might be an issue. But, for me, the larger screen is a massive improvement, and isn’t diminished in the least by the slightly bigger body.</p><p>The screen bezels are also significantly smaller, as well. The bottom bezel is on the large side, presumably so you can rest your thumb on it while reading, but the ones on the top, left, and right are all very thin. The smaller bezels, larger display, and lack of a recessed screen all combine to make this hardware feel far more premium than previous Kindle Paperwhite models.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/62999020-35d5-11ec-bfaf-ab80b3314d09" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="cd7a6054-9b0e-3540-aa46-db6a90c6348a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>A less impactful change is the new LED front lighting system. There are 17 individual LEDs that give the Paperwhite its gentle glow that lets you read in poor light, up from five that were in the previous model. That sounds like a big improvement, but I can’t say I notice a major difference. The Old Paperwhite already had a very smooth front lighting system, and it looks great on the new model, too, just not dramatically better.</p><p>These LEDs do have a new trick, though: “adjustable warm lighting.” It’s similar to the Night Shift feature Apple added to its products a few years ago; it adjusts the color temperature of the display lighting to a more amber hue. The Kindle’s blighting system never felt too blue to me, and since we’re not dealing with a glowing LCD, they’ve always been less likely to disrupt sleep. But being able to adjust the screen’s color temperature is still handy.</p><p>Like with other devices, you can set two different color temperatures, one for during the day and a warmer setting for after the sun has gone down. There’s also an automatic schedule that uses location services to automatically and gradually change the color temperature based on sunrise and sunset in your current location.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/629b64e0-35d5-11ec-9ffe-a819228a7896" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="23f7d87f-234b-3ae0-abac-0244eb2813b8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>I appreciate the multiple ways you can customize the warmth of the Paperwhite’s screen, but it’s also a little confusing. When you pull down the settings shade, you’ll see sliders for both brightness and screen warmth. Then, when you dive into the section where you can set a schedule, there’s another slider to set the warmth for the scheduled time. It took me a bit to realize that one slider covered the warmth outside of the scheduled time and another was only in effect during the schedule.I eventually I got everything sorted out, though. And if you don’t care about scheduling the screen’s color temperature, you can just pick a setting that looks best to you and forget about it.</p><p>You’ve been able to set different brightness levels on the Kindle for years now, but the Paperwhite Signature Edition can automatically adjust to the ambient light. Smartphones have had this feature for years, and the more expensive Kindle Oasis has had it for a while, too. Here, it works pretty quickly and reliably. I first manually set the brightness to a comfortable level for the room I was reading in, and then put my trust in the auto brightness feature. I could definitely notice it kicking on in brighter rooms and turning things down in my dimly lit bedroom when I was getting ready to crash for the night. It’s not an essential feature, but it is nice to have.</p><p>Come to think of it, “nice to have” describes most of the difference between the standard Kindle Paperwhite and the Signature Edition. The standard version comes with 8GB of storage, versus 32GB in the SE. The SE also has wireless charging, which works quite well – I dropped the Paperwhite on a few Anker chargers I have around the house, and it charged up quickly and reliably. But given how long the device’s battery lasts, most people will be fine charging it with any old USB-C cable once a month or so. (I haven’t mentioned it yet, but the Paperwhite has a battery that lasts weeks, just like all the other Kindles.)</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/62991af0-35d5-11ec-b1f0-b65b124de4d2" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="11af0585-90a5-39a8-91e2-4424c0426b16"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>The SE also has an ad-free lock screen. The fact that Amazon has long charged a premium to get a device without ads on it that try to sell you more stuff from Amazon is about the most Amazon thing ever. And my desire to not have ads shoved in my face makes the Signature Edition pretty appealing. A $50 price difference is significant – but given the fact that I generally use a Kindle for five years or more, why not get rid of those ads and get a few extra features while I’m at it? Given that the standard Paperwhite without ads is only $30 cheaper than the Signature Edition, this is an upsell that I’d probably go for.</p><p>Things like storage capacity, the number of LEDs, wireless charging and so on only really matter in service of one thing: reading. Fortunately, the new Kindle Paperwhite is the best e-reader I’ve ever used. I’ve never had a big issue with how E Ink screens need to refresh when you turn the page, but the Paperwhite refreshes so quickly and smoothly that this device feels a lot nicer to use than my 2015 model.</p><p>Beyond the refresh rate, the touchscreen is extremely responsive; I rarely had my taps or swipes go unrecognized. When I use the keyboard to search for books, I just plow ahead and don’t get caught up waiting for a key press to register. There are still times where you need to wait for the screen to catch up, though. That’s mostly when you’re navigating more complex layouts, like the Kindle Store.</p><p>In some regards, the new Kindle Paperwhite changes nothing; Amazon has had a stranglehold on the e-reader market for years, and the previous Paperwhite was the device to get. The new Paperwhite is still Amazon’s best e-reader. It’s not as expensive and fancy as the Kindle Oasis, but it offers a far better experience than the basic $90 Kindle. The bigger screen and higher resolution are reasons enough to choose the Paperwhite if you’re anything more than the most casual of reader.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/629aa190-35d5-11ec-9fbf-fa7633b0c4eb" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="1e8592e4-2bf9-353d-a94b-6f43607cd70f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>The other question is whether the $190 “Signature Edition” is worth the $50 premium over the standard model. For most people, the answer is probably no — the two devices are essentially the same in every significant way. Wireless charging is nice to have, but given how infrequently the Paperwhite needs to be charged, it’s not a huge upgrade in convenience. More storage is never a bad thing, but 8GB can still hold literally thousands of books. The extra space is really only important if you use Audible on the Kindle, because audiobooks can quickly eat through your storage.</p><p>The auto-adjusting light is probably my favorite of these Signature Edition features. Almost every other display in your life can do that, And having it here makes sense, especially if you power up your Paperwhite in the middle of the night. Plus, it’s hard to overstate how nice it is to not have to look at an ad every time you pick the device up.</p><p>Ultimately, if I was <a href="https://amzn.to/2XGjv8C">buying the Kindle Paperwhite</a> for someone as a gift, I’d probably get the standard edition. If I was buying for myself, I’d get the Signature. But either way, I’d be buying a Kindle Paperwhite — it remains the best e-reader on the market.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-signature-edition-2021-review-130037090.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">98cd2edf-8342-44f4-bea5-c6cdc981fcc6</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635196304</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T21:11:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/629b3dd0-35d5-11ec-9ffb-68a8f5cf7272" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/629b3dd0-35d5-11ec-9ffb-68a8f5cf7272" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon's latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle Paperwhite Special Edition (2021)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adobe adds automatic sky and subject masking to Lightroom]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At its annual Max conference, Adobe detailed some enhancements that are coming to its <a href="https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2021/10/26/max-2021-photography-releases.html"><ins>Lightroom and Lightroom Classic software suites</ins></a>. To start, the company is introducing a “re-envisioned” set of selective adjustment tools. Set to make their way to all devices where you can access Lightroom and Lightroom Classic, the tools are accessible via a newly added masking button. Much like you can do in Photoshop, they allow you to create multiple masks, including color and luminance ones. In turn, those will allow you to make precise adjustments to specific parts of a photo.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d86594c0-35a3-11ec-b91a-256a0a037adb" style="height:1874;width:2560;" alt="Adobe masking" data-uuid="d7a7168a-055e-30a7-b458-80cbb1490e31"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>Of course, individually masking elements of an image can be time-consuming, and so Adobe is also introducing an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-camera-raw-lightroom-classic-mask-features-ai-160056644.html"><ins>AI-powered tool</ins></a> that can automatically detect the select the subject and sky in your photos. In addition to rolling out to Lightroom Classic and Lightroom on Mac and PC, this is coming to select Android and iOS devices. And that’s where Adobe envisions it being the most useful since it should help with editing on a smaller screen.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you like to start your edits with a preset, a new recommendation engine in Lightroom for Mac, Windows and mobile will suggest ones based on the subject of your photos. The presets will come from the Lightroom community, so you can expect to find “hundreds of thousands,” according to the company. Additionally, Adobe is introducing eight new premium presets, adding to the seven it released previously. Those are available to use in all versions of Lightroom.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ea094460-35a3-11ec-9968-371048b81d9c" style="height:1080;width:1920;" alt="Adobe recommended presets" data-uuid="958514bb-6a75-327f-b861-1bf91f654df8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe</div></figure><p>To make cropping easier on Lightroom for Mac and Windows, Adobe has added the option to select a variety of overlays for different aspect ratios. Some of the options on this front include thirds, golden ratio and diagonal.</p><p>Lastly, the company is introducing a new feature in Lightroom for Mac and Windows called Community Remix. It allows you to upload a photo edit and invite other photographers to take it in a different direction. Adobe says it plans to bring Community Remix to other versions of Lightroom in the future.</p><p>Adobe says it will begin rolling out all of the above updates starting today. They should become available to everyone by the end of the week. At its Adobe Max conference, the company also detailed updates for Fresco, Photoshop and other apps.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lightroom-updates-adobe-max-2021-130009666.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fafe58d3-1e4d-40d4-aa54-e4e721cb750d</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635174225</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T15:03:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/72d8b970-35a3-11ec-9dfb-d59ed253d9c7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/72d8b970-35a3-11ec-9dfb-d59ed253d9c7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lightroom Sky and Subject select]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lightroom Sky and Subject select]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adobe adds motion, reference layers and more to its Fresco painting app]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-24-adobe-fresco-ipad-drawing-painting-app-now-available.html">Adobe Fresco</a> has given artists and designers the ability to draw and paint <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-12-adobe-fresco-preview-live-brushes-oil-watercolor.html">with lifelike digital materials</a> for two years now. Last fall, the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-fresco-drawing-painting-app-iphone-130042001.html">expanded the app to iPhone</a>, but this year the updates are much more robust. With the additions <a href="https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2021/10/26/free-drawing-painting-app-adobe-fresco-adds-motion-tools-more-for-adobe-max-2021.html">announced today</a> at its annual Adobe Max design conference, the company gives its free-to-use drawing and painting app handy tools that expand how and what artists are able to create.&nbsp;</p><p>First, Adobe is adding motion to Fresco. This gives artists and designers the option to add timelines and motion frames to individual layers. The company explains that this allows you to assign specific movement to each element. Adobe says you can also draw paths for objects to follow and the goal is to keep things simple so the concept of motion is approachable for all skill levels.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Next, the company is adding reference layers to Fresco. This should help speed up the process when you need to add color to line art. Once you set the reference layer, you can begin working on a separate layer for fills. Fresco will still recognize the lines on the original layer without applying edits to it. This will work if your reference layer is vector or pixels and keeps your original drawing intact.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5f1e33c0-35cf-11ec-8fdd-39b5b20c6766" style="height:1118;width:1600;" alt="Adobe Fresco" data-uuid="3abc1e1b-a380-3cb7-9106-8a8428c25170"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Adobe/Kyle Webster</div></figure><p>Vector brushes are already available in Fresco, but Adobe is expanding that library to include a new set with &quot;jitter.&quot; Basically, these brushes will help you quickly give drawings texture. Lines are still sharp, but there&#39;s variation in the stroke for a more naturally drawn look. As always, vector brushes are infinitely scalable and can be combined with pixel brushes in the same Fresco file.&nbsp;</p><p>Lastly, Adobe is helping you keep your perspective correct with new guides. Perspective grids will help you keep illustrations looking realistic when it&#39;s time to add depth. You can set vanishing points anywhere, even off the the artboard, and lines will snap to the grids as you work. Adobe says this should allow artists and designers to focus more on art and less on the heavy lifting.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Adobe Fresco is free for anyone to use on iPhone, iPad and Windows without a Creative Cloud subscription. There are more tools available if you do pay for Adobe&#39;s apps, like access to an expanded library of brushes.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/adobe-fresco-update-fall-2021-130004402.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2c90957f-0fa6-4f76-8ba1-7cef6bab94c6</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635193519</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T20:25:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Humanities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/121fe9b0-35ca-11ec-bfbd-7e02bdd0579a" width="1600" height="1147" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/121fe9b0-35ca-11ec-bfbd-7e02bdd0579a" width="1600" height="1147" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe/Bejamin Kohl]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Adobe Fresco]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Adobe Fresco]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Master & Dynamic put its headphone expertise into a $450 gaming headset]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Master &amp; Dynamic" href="https://fave.co/3ekiqIb">Master &amp; Dynamic</a> has staked its name on its mix of refined design, premium materials and crisp, clear audio quality. The company has a number of models under its belt, including wired, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-12-master-and-dynamic-mh40-wireless-headphones-announced.html">wireless</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-22-master-and-dynamic-mw65-review.html">noise-cancelling headphones</a>, in addition to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/master-and-dynamic-mw08-review-true-wireless-earbuds-143027692.html">true wireless earbuds</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-04-18-master-and-dynamic-ma770-wireless-speaker-concrete.html">a concrete speaker</a>. Now M&amp;D is venturing into uncharted sonic territory: gaming headsets. With the MG20, the company has built a set of &quot;wireless gaming headphones&quot; with its trademark design and a range of handy features for a whopping $449 (€449/£429).&nbsp;</p><p>The MG20 has a familiar look to the company&#39;s over-ear headphones, with some simplified design choices. This gaming headset doesn&#39;t have quite as many varying textures as some of M&amp;D&#39;s other products, for example. This time around, the company opted for a combo of aluminum, magnesium, lambskin leather and Alcantara. There&#39;s a detachable boom mic for gaming sessions and the MG20 also has microphones for calls when you&#39;re using them as a set of headphones. The headphones also have a semi-open back design for a wider sound stage and more natural audio quality.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Inside, 50mm drivers power 7.1 surround sound with support for aptX HD for music and aptX Low-Latency for mobile gaming. With the debut of the MG20, M&amp;D has added EQ presets to it&#39;s headphone app for the first time, allowing users to select a sound profile to fit their needs. What&#39;s more, independent volume controls for game audio offer another degree of customization. A low-latency USB adapter is compatible with both PlayStation and PC and offers easy switching between devices. Master &amp; Dynamic says the MG20 will last for up to 22 hours on a charge, and thanks to wear detection, the headphones can save battery life when you&#39;re not wearing them.&nbsp;</p><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:MG20" href="https://fave.co/3ekiqIb">MG20</a> will be available in black and white color options starting November 16th.</p><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="ed2e1dfe-3c69-47ed-a716-6a71de4ce932"/><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/master-and-dynamic-mg20-gaming-headset-announce-specs-price-120045652.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">889a1692-4d29-4a5c-9ca8-54fcb15834b5</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635250413</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T12:13:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/fc2a3ce0-35fc-11ec-bf77-ceb2d4f72363" width="1600" height="908" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/fc2a3ce0-35fc-11ec-bf77-ceb2d4f72363" width="1600" height="908" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Master & Dynamic MG20]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Master & Dynamic MG20]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Palm pivots to audio with $129 ANC true wireless earbuds]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Three years after releasing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-15-palm-is-back-hands-on.html">a teensy phone</a> designed to act as a companion for your primary device, the latest incarnation of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/palm/">Palm</a> is back with a new product: a set of true wireless earbuds. Former designers from Beats by Dre and Samsung created the Palm Buds Pro.</p><p>Palm says it researched which features consumers want most from wireless earbuds, and it seems to have checked off a lot of the right boxes here. Buds Pro has active noise cancellation, bass-heavy audio with 10mm dynamic drivers and an array of six microphones that can tamp down background noise on calls. When the passthrough Ambient Mode is enabled, you&#39;ll be able to hear both audio playback and sounds from the world around you.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/52c33660-3378-11ec-bdcf-fe821ec27a20" alt="An image showing the three microphones in each Palm Buds Pro earbud." data-uuid="83f9ee80-2054-3a93-826f-8c936cd242f8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Palm</div></figure><p>The battery will run for up to 5.5 hours or, if ANC is enabled, 4.5 hours, Palm says. The earbuds should be good for three hours of talk time. The charging case has a 400 mAh battery, which should provide the earbuds with over 24 hours of playback time before you have to recharge the case, according to Palm.&nbsp;</p><p>There&#39;s also fast pairing and syncing with devices, IPX4 sweat and water resistance and support for Siri and Google Assistant. In addition, the earbuds come with three sets of tips to help you find the best fit.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5599d600-3378-11ec-affe-3e4a4c59c70a" alt="A person wearing a Palm Buds Pro earbud." data-uuid="d1daae66-cef7-33d3-bb18-8a5eaecd887f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Palm</div></figure><p>Perhaps the most impressive aspect of the Palm Buds Pro at the outset is how much they cost. The earbuds will be $129 at retail, which is a solid price for a set of ANC earbuds. If you pre-order by November 9th (when general availability starts), you can get a $30 discount.&nbsp;</p><p>Pre-orders are now open in the US, Canada and Mexico <a href="https://palm.com/">on Palm&#39;s website</a>. Palm will ship the earbuds internationally to select markets. There&#39;s also a silicone case accessory in Shadow Black, Rose Pink and Navy Blue. The case is $15 during the pre-order period. It&#39;ll typically cost $25.</p><p>It remains to be seen how good Palm Buds Pro are in practice. Even though we weren&#39;t huge fans of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-21-palm-phone-review.html">the Palm Phone</a>, there&#39;s a strong design pedigree behind the earbuds, so they might very well be worth checking out.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/palm-buds-pro-anc-true-wireless-earbuds-120015174.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0aacb773-a605-42f0-be7a-6774396286dd</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634937250</ingested><modified>2021-10-22T21:14:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4f0c9700-3378-11ec-bfc3-9b8d2a225048" width="3500" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4f0c9700-3378-11ec-bfc3-9b8d2a225048" width="3500" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Palm]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Palm Buds Pro with charging cases that have Shadow Black, Rose Pink and Navy Blue silicon covers.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Palm Buds Pro]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Sony’s Xperia Pro-1 is a camera first, smartphone second]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony’s smartphones have never quite set the world on fire. It’s one of the last storied tech companies still willing to try to sell phones, despite the dominance of Apple and Samsung.</p><p>The company seemed to turn a corner with its Xperia 1 series — phones that leaned into Sony’s camera knowledge, both when it came to sensors it’s made for years and software smarts.</p><p>We’ve got a review incoming for the Xperia 1 III, but that’s now been elbowed aside by the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-pro-i-announcement-031222484.html">Xperia Pro-1</a>, announced last night.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-pro-i-announcement-031222484.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1d0792a0-364d-11ec-a777-48574c19fd57" alt="Xperia Pro-1" data-uuid="c89ba4ac-7876-36ca-920f-94ae8afc5dc7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure></a><p>The big feature of the Xperia Pro-I is a 1-inch sensor last seen from the company&#39;s wonderful <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-25-sonys-mic-ready-rx100-vii-is-a-vloggers-dream.html">RX100 VII</a> point-and-shoot camera. It’s a much larger sensor than you&#39;ll find on most phones (although Sony says the lens only actually covers a portion of the sensor). For comparison, the primary sensor on the just-released Google Pixel 6 Pro features a pixel pitch of 1.2µm. The Pro-I has 2.4µm-sized pixels. The device can capture RAW stills, 4K 120 fps video, and (like the last few Xperia 1 models) shoot images at 20 fps as well.</p><p>Also notably, there’s a 24mm lens made from glass that can switch between f/2.0 and f/4.0 apertures — another rare feature, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-03-08-samsung-galaxy-s9-and-s9-plus-review-video.html">if not the first phone to feature aperture switching.</a></p><p>The phone will also arrive with all kinds of dongles and add-ons, including support for Sony’s “dead-cat” muffler to cut wind noise, a shooting grip and its very own add-on display, for self-recording and vlogging with the primary camera sensor.</p><p>As tradition dictates, Sony is demanding a premium, yet again. In the US, the Xperia Pro-I will cost $1,800.The company reasons that you’re getting a flagship phone and RX100 VII point-and-shoot all in one device, for less.</p><p>I’m not sure most of us will swallow that excuse.</p><p>-Mat Smith</p><p></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">Google Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro review</a></h2><h3>Solid phones, great software, perfect pricing</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ef8a7b40-364b-11ec-b7fb-3eae1d7ac744" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="d8d4b448-cb33-301d-b865-f22bc7f44003"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>While we balk at that Sony phone price, Google’s Pixel phones have landed.  A true blend of premium hardware and tempting prices. Yep, for hundreds less than the competition, the Pixel 6 Pro offers everything you’d expect from a flagship and more. It has a lovely 120Hz screen, excellent cameras and a beautiful UI. Plus, Google’s clever AI touches add some intriguing photography tricks and makes voice typing easier.</p><p>Torn between the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro? Given the similarity of specs (and size) that decision this year boils down to one key factor: price.  Choose the Pixel 6 instead of the Pro and you’ll save $300. You&#39;ll only be missing out on the 120Hz screen and a telephoto camera. And the Pixel 6 has cooler color options anyhow...</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-review-2021-160026883.html">Apple AirPods review (2021)</a></h2><h3>Design, fit and features combine for a better set of earbuds.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-review-2021-160026883.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/92247540-364c-11ec-87c6-48259df673aa" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="56d10019-bdc5-3289-bc4e-a76a80bb9965"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>Apple’s overhauled AirPods bring major changes to design and audio quality. The company expanded availability of key features from the AirPods Pro like spatial audio and Adaptive EQ to a more affordable set of earbuds, all while keeping all of the convenience of AirPods intact.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-review-2021-160026883.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hertz-reportedly-orders-100000-teslas-in-the-single-large-ev-purchase-ever-132633765.html">Hertz reportedly orders a Tesla car fleet</a></h2><h3>100,000 Teslas would be the largest EV purchase ever.</h3><h3></h3><p>Hertz has ordered 100,000 Tesla EVs for its fleet, with plans to rent them out in major US markets and parts of Europe starting in November, according to <em>Bloomberg</em>. That would mark the largest electric vehicle order of all time and represent a major move by Hertz into electric car rentals.</p><p>It would be a pretty sharp turnaround for Hertz, considering that it filed for bankruptcy in 2020.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hertz-reportedly-orders-100000-teslas-in-the-single-large-ev-purchase-ever-132633765.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-group-workout-shareplay-available-now-170031703.html">iOS 15.1 turns on SharePlay for Apple Fitness+</a></h2><h3>And SharePlay for everything else.</h3><h3></h3><p>Apple has announced that Group Workouts are available starting today, so you can get up to 32 friends together to follow along with the company&#39;s exercise or meditation videos.</p><p>To use the new features, you&#39;ll need to update to iOS 15.1 or iPadOS 15.1, as well as watchOS 8.1, all of which are available today. Those who plan on watching the videos on their Apple TV will also need tvOS 15.1. SharePlay <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-delays-ios-15-shareplay-184450766.html">wasn&#39;t available when iOS 15 launched</a> earlier this year, and during <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html">the iOS 15 beta</a> it was buggy and unstable.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-group-workout-shareplay-available-now-170031703.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-trailer-162005655.html">Watch a closer look at Halo Infinite&#39;s single-player campaign</a></h2><h3>It’s been over a year.</h3><h3></h3><p>With Halo Infinite’s release date fast approaching, Microsoft has shared a new six-minute trailer that offers an in-depth look at the game’s single-player component. It’s another attempt after the divisive <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-gameplay-trailer-master-chief-grappling-hook-162432108.html">Xbox showcase appearance from 2020</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-trailer-162005655.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><p></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/orbital-reef-200848765.html">Blue Origin announces plans for a commercial space station</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q3-2021-earnings-young-adults-metaverse-220703590.html">Mark Zuckerberg says Facebook&#39;s future is &#39;young adults&#39; and the metaverse</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/orbital-reef-200848765.html">Blue Origin announces plans for a commercial space station</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-book-pro-14-16-inch-review-2021-apple-mighty-macs-130011975.html">MacBook Pro 14-inch and 16-inch review (2021): Apple&#39;s mighty Macs</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apples-new-air-pods-pro-are-already-seeing-their-first-discount-083108462.html">Apple&#39;s new AirPods Pro with MagSafe charging are already down to $220</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-the-frame-tvs-early-black-friday-sale-up-to-33-percent-off-125551419.html">Samsung&#39;s The Frame TVs are up to 33 percent off in an early Black Friday sale</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-south-korea-dr-brain-hacking-series-191732378.html">Apple&#39;s first Korean TV series is about brain hacking</a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-sonys-xperia-pro-1-is-camera-first-smartphone-second-111526718.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2857f18f-815b-4504-927d-0ed56cf6968d</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 11:15:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635253844</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T13:10:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ddf25d00-364e-11ec-afb7-8d695e7c01f8" width="1286" height="865" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ddf25d00-364e-11ec-afb7-8d695e7c01f8" width="1286" height="865" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony Xperia Pro-1]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony Xperia Pro-1]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[US retailers stop selling security cameras made by some Chinese companies]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Home Depot and Best Buy have pulled the products of Chinese tech surveillance makers linked to human rights abuses from their shelves, according to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/lorex-ezviz-pulled-from-shelves/"><em>TechCrunch</em></a>. Both US retail giants have stopped selling products from Lorex and Ezviz, while Lowe&#39;s no longer carries products by the former. Lorex is a subsidiary of Dahua Technology, whereas Ezviz is a surveillance tech brand owned by Hikvision. As <em>TechCrunch</em> explains, the US government added Dahua and Hikvision to its economic blacklist in 2019 for their role in the <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">mass surveillance</a> of Uighur Muslims in the province of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-02-22-china-xinjiang-surveillance-tech-spread.html">Xinjiang</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/story/2021-02-09/dahua-facial-recognition-china-surveillance-uighur"><em>Los Angeles Times</em></a> published a report detailing how the facial recognition software developed by Lorex owner Dahua was being shopped to law enforcement as a way to identify Uighurs. A user guide for the service apparently touts its capability to identify people passing in front of its cameras by race. Meanwhile, Hikvision&#39;s cameras have been installed at mosques and detention camps in Xinjiang, according to a 2019<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/22/world/asia/china-surveillance-xinjiang.html"><em> New York Times</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>report. Maya Wang, a China researcher for Human Rights Watch, told the publication back then: &quot;These systems are designed for a very explicit purpose — to target Muslims.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In a <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">report</a> on the human rights practices in China, the US Department of State said that the Chinese government &quot;conducted mass arbitrary detention of Uyghurs, ethnic Kazakhs, Kyrgyz, and members of other Muslim and ethnic minority groups in Xinjiang. China Human Rights Defenders alleged these detentions amounted to enforced disappearance, since families were often not provided information about the length or location of the detention.&quot; Human rights groups believe over a million Uighurs are being <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-22278037">detained</a> in internment camps, but China continues to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-22/china-denies-uighur-abuse-claims-as-international-pressure-grows">deny</a> the allegations.&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s unclear why the retail giants have decided to pull Lorex and Ezviz products now, but consumers have freely been able to buy their security cameras over the past couple of years after their parent companies were placed in the US economic blacklist. Home Depot told <em>TechCrunch</em> that it&#39;s &quot;committed to upholding the highest standards of ethical sourcing and [it] immediately stopped selling products from Lorex when this was brought to [the company&#39;s] attention.&quot; Best Buy simply told the publication that it was “discontinuing its relationship&quot; with both Lorex and Ezviz.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/us-retailers-stop-selling-security-cameras-lorex-ezviz-082543444.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">75bcbef3-ed83-4d49-9081-9c1a81a222a5</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 08:25:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635235476</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T08:04:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Human Rights]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0f05fde0-362a-11ec-b27b-1fd8c31db195" width="1000" height="667" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0f05fde0-362a-11ec-b27b-1fd8c31db195" width="1000" height="667" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Lorex]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lorex]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lorex]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Insider update offers easier Twitch streaming on Xbox consoles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Streaming to Twitch on the PS5 is relatively easy, but not so much on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-x-review-microsoft-140045437.html">Xbox Series X</a> or S — you currently need to download the Twitch app and run through a series of steps. However, Microsoft is <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/10/25/xbox-insider-release-notes-alpha-skip-ahead-2111-211022-2000/">introducing</a> &quot;Console Live Streaming&quot; on its latest update Xbox Insider preview, making Twitch access easier and more direct. It also added an Xbox Cloud Gaming beta to Xbox One, giving users of older consoles access to the latest games.&nbsp;</p><p>To use the new Twitch streaming feature, you&#39;ll just need to navigate the &quot;Capture and Share&quot; tab and choose &quot;Live streaming.&quot; Link your Twitch account using a mobile device or console settings, then hit the &quot;Go live now&quot; button to start streaming gameplay. &quot;This feature only streams game play so viewers will see a pause screen if the user navigates to home or another app,&quot; Microsoft notes.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If you&#39;re still on an Xbox One and want to play Xbox Series X/S titles or more hardware intensive games, the Xbox Cloud Gaming beta is also available to Insiders. Want to play an Xbox Series X/S exclusive like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-azure-ai-machine-learning-193545436.html"><em>Microsoft Flight Simulator</em></a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-medium-extended-gameplay-video-154348210.html"><em>The Medium</em></a> on an Xbox One? It&#39;s now feasible if you&#39;re on the Alpha Skip-Ahead ring, launching today at 5PM EST. Both of these features will eventually come to everyone, as well.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-previews-easier-twitch-streaming-on-xbox-one-consoles-073445970.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1cf2846c-1b7b-42e2-840a-18962ad5fcfa</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 07:34:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635233687</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T07:34:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ff006ab0-3625-11ec-9dea-5ac38758e5e4" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ff006ab0-3625-11ec-9dea-5ac38758e5e4" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Microsoft previews easier Twitch streaming on Xbox One consoles]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft previews easier Twitch streaming on Xbox One consoles]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's Xperia Pro-I is a $1,800 phone with a 1-inch camera sensor]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the start of 2021, Sony introduced the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-pro-5g-smartphone-creators-broadcasters-2500-dollars-150052203.html">$2,500 Xperia Pro</a>. It was a phone the company made for video professionals. Now, Sony is back with a second professional-grade smartphone designed to appeal to photography enthusiasts. The headline feature of the Xperia Pro-I is a 1-inch sensor borrowed from the company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-25-sonys-mic-ready-rx100-vii-is-a-vloggers-dream.html">RX100 VII</a> point-and-shoot camera. That&#39;s a much larger sensor than you&#39;ll find on most phones.&nbsp;</p><p>To put things in perspective, the primary sensor on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">Pixel 6 Pro</a> features a pixel pitch of 1.2µm. By contrast, the main sensor on the Pro-I has 2.4µm-sized pixels, making it much better in low light. It can also shoot 12-bit RAW files and native 4K video at 120 frames per second with eye-detection auto-focus. Speaking of auto-focus, it comes with 315 points that cover 90 percent of the frame.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Pro-I also includes one of Sony&#39;s BIONZ X imaging processors, giving it the ability to shoot up to 20 frames per second with both auto-focus and auto-exposure enabled.  The fast readout speed of the sensor allows it to avoid a rolling shutter effect, a feature Sony says helps the Pro-I stand out from other phones with 1-inch sensors like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-price-launch-date-134516642.html">Mi 11 Ultra</a>. Those handsets also don&#39;t have phase-detection autofocus like the Pro-I does.</p><p>Complimenting the 1-inch sensor is a 24mm lens made from glass that can switch between f/2.0 and f/4.0 apertures. Sony went with an aspherical design to make the optics as small as possible. Flanking the primary camera is a 16mm ultrawide camera and a 50mm telephoto camera. Sony says it chose that lens arrangement after consulting with photographers who told the company they wanted a setup that matched their collection of prime lenses.</p><p>Once you get past its camera, the Xperia Pro-I is essentially a souped-up <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii-pro-camera-smartphones-5g-specs-074022474.html">Xperia 1 III</a>. Internally, the phone features a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-5g-gaming-cameras-150046640.html">Snapdragon 888</a> supported by 12GB of RAM and 512GB of internal storage. You can add up to 1TB of additional storage with the help of a microSD card. Powering everything is a 4,500mAh battery Sony claims will allow you to use the Pro-I for a full day on a single charge. Inside the box is a 30W power adapter that can charge the phone to 50 percent in 30 minutes.</p><p>The Pro-I also features the same 6.5-inch OLED that came on the Xperia 1 III. It&#39;s a 4K display with a 120Hz refresh rate and 21:9 aspect ratio. On the audio front, the Pro-I not only comes with a 3.5mm headphone jack, but it also includes Sony&#39;s LDAC and DSEE technologies.</p><p>All of those capabilities come with a hefty price tag. In the US, Sony plans to sell the Xperia Pro-I for the eye-watering price of $1,800. The way the company sees it, you&#39;re effectively getting a flagship phone and RX100 VII for less than the price of buying those devices separately. However, the Xperia Pro-I isn&#39;t a one-to-one replacement for the RX100 VII. Sony&#39;s point-and-camera outputs images at 20.1-megapixel, using the full readout from its sensor. The Pro-I uses a crop because taking advantage of the entire sensor would necessitate a much larger lens than would be feasible to include on a smartphone.&nbsp;</p><p>Pre-orders for the Xperia Pro-I open on October 28th, with general availability to follow in December.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-pro-i-announcement-031222484.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">14d89184-3182-40b0-b597-a10a64b64998</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 03:12:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635217988</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T03:13:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6c67fd50-360a-11ec-b0ff-e4ea7d85e62e" width="1600" height="961" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6c67fd50-360a-11ec-b0ff-e4ea7d85e62e" width="1600" height="961" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony Xperia Pro-I]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony  Xperia Pro-I]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg says Facebook's future is 'young adults' and the metaverse]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amid reports that Facebook <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-25/facebook-files-show-growth-struggles-as-young-users-in-u-s-decline?sref=10lNAhZ9">has misled</a> shareholders about significant <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks">declines</a> in teens and younger users, Mark Zuckerberg said the company was “retooling” in order to make “serving young adults” its top priority. To do that, the company plans to make “significant changes” to its Facebook and Instagram apps, and spend billions of dollars building out its vision for a “metaverse.”</p><p>Citing increased competition from TikTok and iMessage, Zuckerberg said the company would do more to win over “young adult” users between the ages of 18 to 29, even if it came at the expense of older users. Speaking during the company&#39;s third-quarter earnings call, he said the company’s TikTok rival Reels would be “as important for our products as Stories.” “We also expect to make significant changes to Instagram and Facebook in the next year to further lean into video and make Reels a more central part of the experience,” Zuckerberg said.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On top of that, he said the company was “retooling” internally in order to make young people its “North Star.” He added the shift “will take years, not months.” The issue of younger users has been particularly fraught for the company. A whistleblower’s disclosures about Facebook’s internal research on teen mental health prompted a series of Congressional hearings about child safety, and a wave of headlines about how the photo sharing app may be harmful to some of its most vulnerable users. At the same time, other internal documents have indicated Facebook and Instagram have faced significant declines in engagement among teens and young adults for years.</p><p>Zuckerberg said another major priority for the company would be building its vision for a “metaverse.” He didn’t comment on reports that the company would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-reportedly-changing-name-042958266.html">change its name</a> to reflect its new focus on augmented reality and virtual reality, but made clear the company has significant ambitions in the space. “Our goal is to help the metaverse reach a billion people,” he said. He added that a metaverse could enable “hundreds of billions of dollars of digital commerce.”</p><p>The company also said Monday that going forward it will report two sets of financials: one for its “family” of apps, which includes Facebook, Instagram, Messenger and WhatsApp; and one for its Reality Labs division that oversees its augmented and virtual reality work. In <a href="https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2021/Facebook-Reports-Third-Quarter-2021-Results/default.aspx">a statement</a>, Facebook said its 2021 profit will be reduced by $10 billion due to its investment in Reality Labs, and that the company would only increase its AR and VR spending in the next “several years.”</p><p>Zuckerberg also addressed the ongoing revelations stemming from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-papers-release-120713316.html">&quot;Facebook Papers,&quot;</a> a series of articles based on documents provided by former employee turned whistleblower <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html">Frances Haugen</a>. The CEO referred to the work from a consortium of news organizations as &quot;a coordinated effort to selectively use leaked documents to paint a false picture of our company.&quot; The documents, which have been the basis of more than a dozen stories detailing Facebook&#39;s botched efforts to fight hate speech and other harms, have also been provided to members of Congress and the Securities and Exchange Commission.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;Any honest account should be clear that these issues aren&#39;t primarily about social media,&quot; Zuckerberg said. &quot;That means that no matter what Facebook does, we&#39;re never going to solve them on our own.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q3-2021-earnings-young-adults-metaverse-220703590.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4b96a438-3812-49d4-951a-74c93a2b1b57</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 22:07:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635201160</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T22:32:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/59c6ad30-16e4-11ec-95cd-bc79f50b8032" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/59c6ad30-16e4-11ec-95cd-bc79f50b8032" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[GLENN CHAPMAN via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook co-founder and chief executive, Mark Zuckerberg, speaks at an Oculus developers conference while wearing a virtual reality headset in San Jose, California on October 6, 2016. 
Facebook unveiled new hardware for its Oculus division as part of a stepped-up effort to integrate virtual reality with the leading social network. The new offerings aim to get an array of virtual reality gear to consumers in the coming months, including a new "Touch" controller and compatible computer to help spur Facebook's push. / AFP PHOTO / Glenn CHAPMAN        (Photo credit should read GLENN CHAPMAN/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-IT-LIFESTYLE-GAMES-FACEBOOK-OCULUS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blue Origin announces plans for a commercial space station]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blue Origin has more ambitious plans than simply space tourism. Today, the spaceflight company owned by Jeff Bezos announced that it is working on creating its very own space station as well. Called <a href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/orbital-reef-commercial-space-station">Orbital Reef</a>, it promises to be something of an industrial and commercial hub, and is meant to start operating in the second half of this decade.&nbsp;</p><p>It will be developed, owned and operated in partnership with Sierra Space, a subsidiary of the Sierra Nevada corporation. Sierra Space is perhaps better known for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-09-29-sierra-nevada-un-first-space-mission.html">Dream Chaser</a>, a spacecraft that’s set to begin operating in 2022 and carry cargo to the International Space Station. Orbital Reef is also backed by Boeing, Redwire Space, Genesis Engineering Solutions and Arizona State University. The company hopes to use Boeing’s Starliner and Sierra Space’s aforementioned Dream Chaser to ferry both cargo and passengers to Orbital Reef.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Think of Orbital Reef as essentially a “business park,” but in space. In a press release, Blue Origin said that the destination “will offer research, industrial, international, and commercial customers the cost competitive end-to-end services they need including space transportation and logistics, space habitation, equipment accommodation, and operations including onboard crew.” Anyone who wants to “establish their own address in orbit” can do so.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a7b9eb30-35cd-11ec-b384-5d62cac7d874" alt="Concept images of Orbital Reef. " data-uuid="4f26e64e-f1fd-3080-86a9-752cded18dd1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Blue Origin</div></figure><p>Blue Origin said that Orbital Reef would be habitable for up to 10 people, which is almost as much as that of the International Space Station. It will feature “human-centered space architecture” with “world-class services and amenities.” There will be multiple ports for visiting spacecraft and modules. Orbital Reef will apparently feature an open system that will enable any customer or nation to use it. As the market for such facilities grows, Blue Origin promises that Orbital Reef will scale the amenities and utilities to match.</p><p>“Seasoned space agencies, high-tech consortia, sovereign nations without space programs, media and travel companies, funded entrepreneurs and sponsored inventors, and future-minded investors all have a place on Orbital Reef,” said the company in a press release.</p><p>“For over sixty years, NASA and other space agencies have developed orbital space flight and space habitation, setting us up for commercial business to take off in this decade,” said Brent Sherwood, Senior Vice President of Advanced Development Programs for Blue Origin. “We will expand access, lower the cost, and provide all the services and amenities needed to normalize space flight. A vibrant business ecosystem will grow in low Earth orbit, generating new discoveries, new products, new entertainments, and global awareness.”</p><p>Blue Origin’s only successful project is a suborbital tourist program that sends passengers to the edge of space (and back) on the New Shepard. It has already flown eight people, which includes <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-completes-first-crewed-spaceflight-132937714.html">Bezos</a> as well as Star Trek’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/william-shatner-blue-origin-spaceflight-new-shepard-144025171.html">William Shatner</a>. Other projects, such as the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-approves-blue-origin-for-future-uncrewed-missions-105530293.html">New Glenn rocket</a> (which the company hopes to use to launch some of Orbital Reef’s modules) and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-09-blue-origin-blue-moon-lunar-lander.html">Blue Moon lunar lander</a> are still in development.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/orbital-reef-200848765.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7ca5a4a0-4e58-473a-849a-da11ab33ac10</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 20:08:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635196141</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T21:09:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Industrials]]></category><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/197441e0-35cd-11ec-b7cb-b3d9877b4250" width="2748" height="1672" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/197441e0-35cd-11ec-b7cb-b3d9877b4250" width="2748" height="1672" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Orbital Reef]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Orbital Reef]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[YouTube will begin demonetizing 'low-quality' kids videos next month]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has announced a <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/our-responsibility-approach-protecting-kids-and-families-youtube/"><ins>policy change</ins></a> to push YouTube creators to produce and publish higher-quality content for kids. Starting next month, the company will demonetize channels that primarily target young people or market themselves as &quot;made for kids&quot; if the content they upload is of low quality. By YouTube&#39;s definition, that can include overly commercial videos and ones that encourage bad behaviors. Per the new guidelines, YouTube warns those videos may see limited or no ads. Additionally, the company says violating its new content guidelines could lead to removal from the YouTube Partner Program.&nbsp;</p><p>The move is part of a recent push by Google to make YouTube and YouTube Kids a more appropriate destination for children and their families. At the start of the year, the company announced the availability of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-parental-controls-tweens-teens-supervised-accounts-160050870.html"><ins>expanded parental controls for tweens and teens</ins></a>. More recently, it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-unveils-major-safety-changes-for-kids-on-search-you-tube-and-more-130051206.html">implemented new safety measures</a> to protect kids across its various platforms. One of those changes saw the company change the default upload setting for users between the ages of 13 and 17 to the most private option available.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;Our ultimate goal is to foster a safe and enriching environment for families while rewarding trusted creators who are making high-quality kids and family content,&quot; Google said of this latest policy change. It may take some time before the new guidelines elevate the quality of content on YouTube. So it doesn&#39;t hurt to keep an eye out on what your children are watching.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/youtube-low-quality-demonetization-kids-video-194733880.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">182979e2-1891-4611-8fb0-4ebd3498b3b2</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:47:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635191258</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T19:47:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/47d61b50-35cb-11ec-beee-8060929a7efe" width="6048" height="4024" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/47d61b50-35cb-11ec-beee-8060929a7efe" width="6048" height="4024" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[simon2579 via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Image of Happy Young Asian mother applying make-up to her daughter on social media together at home.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Happy Young Asian mother and her daughter recording video blog at home with makeup theme]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's first Korean TV series is about brain hacking]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/apple%20tv%20plus/"><ins>Apple TV+</ins></a> will <a href="https://www.apple.com/tv-pr/news/2021/10/apple-original-series-dr-brain-to-premiere-globally-on-thursday-november-4-to-coincide-with-the-apple-tv-launch-in-south-korea/"><ins>expand</ins></a> into a new territory when it launches in South Korea on November 4th. In a case of perfect timing, the streaming service&#39;s first series from the country will debut worldwide on the same day (or a day earlier if you&#39;re in the US).</p><p>The brilliantly titled <em>Dr. Brain</em> is a sci-fi drama based on a webtoon of the same name. Lee Sun-kyun of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/parasite/"><em><ins>Parasite</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>fame (he played Park Dong-ik, the father of the well-off family) stars as brain scientist Sewon. After Sewon&#39;s family suffers a mysterious accident, he hacks the brains of the deceased to access their memories and learn clues about what happened.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="85119576c7f2403a9c393e59498124e2"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZK2nevD7cWA?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The six-episode series is co-written, directed and executive produced by the highly regarded filmmaker Kim Jee-woon, who&#39;s perhaps best known for <em>The Good, The Bad and The Weird </em>and <em>I Saw the Devil</em>. A new episode of <em>Dr. Brain </em>will hit Apple TV+ each week until the finale on December 10th.&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s a busy fall for sci-fi projects on Apple TV+. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-foundation-trailer-isaac-asimov-154330992.html"><em>Foundation</em></a>, based on Isaac Asimov&#39;s books of the same name, debuted in September, while alien invasion series <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-invasion-trailer-222925428.html"><em>Invasion</em></a> premiered last Friday. A movie called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tom-hanks-finch-release-date-085915154.html"><em>Finch</em></a>, in which Tom Hanks plays a man who takes a road trip across post-apocalyptic America with his dog and robot, will hit Apple TV+ on November 5th.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-south-korea-dr-brain-hacking-series-191732378.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a2dcd620-cb9b-422c-b588-0bd1381d8458</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:17:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635189455</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T19:17:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Television]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/21770e10-35c6-11ec-a9a7-6fd1439f6043" width="2997" height="1583" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/21770e10-35c6-11ec-a9a7-6fd1439f6043" width="2997" height="1583" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple TV+]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A still from Apple TV+ series Dr. Brain in which Sewon (Lee Sun-kyun) lies on a table wearing a headpiece covered in wires.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Dr. Brain]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HomePod mini software update adds support for Apple Music lossless]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#39;s not only <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-group-workout-shareplay-available-now-170031703.html"><ins>iOS</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-macos-monterey-release-facetime-safari-shareplay-171102479.html"><ins>macOS</ins></a> that Apple has updated today. The company has rolled out a firmware update for HomePod as well. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-smart-speaker-014943611.html">discontinued</a> speaker now supports Apple Music lossless playback, as well as Dolby Atmos spatial audio. Apple Music lossless will also be available on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-171521559.html"><ins>HomePod mini</ins></a> after you update it via the HomePod section of the Home app.</p><p>It&#39;s a much-needed update, since Apple Music lossless hit iOS, iPadOS, macOS and Apple TV 4K devices <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-lossless-now-available-on-supported-devices-094540982.html"><ins>in June</ins></a>. Apple only started publicly testing lossless and Dolby Atmos support <a href="https://www.engadget.com/homepod-mini-spatial-audio-apple-music-lossless-support-beta-210300048.html"><ins>on HomePod in August</ins></a>. In any case, it&#39;s good to see that Apple eventually brought a pair of notable audio features to products it designed primarily to, you know, play audio.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-dolby-atmos-apple-music-support-update-182738975.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0f4ba6e2-b030-4967-ac52-2fe995308a2f</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 18:27:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635186461</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T18:27:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/edc755a0-839d-11eb-bbb9-eb8b09cfe071" width="2000" height="1375" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/edc755a0-839d-11eb-bbb9-eb8b09cfe071" width="2000" height="1375" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple HomePod]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple HomePod]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung partners with Best Buy to offer in-store phone repairs across the US]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve ever damaged your phone, you may have run into a situation where you found it difficult to find a place that can repair it. Samsung is trying to help owners of its flagship devices avoid that situation with a newly announced <a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-authorized-care-select-best-buy-locations-nationwide/"><ins>Best Buy partnership</ins></a>. Starting on October 26th, more than 100 Best Buy stores across the US will begin offering <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-camera-samples-screen-specs-160033680.html">Galaxy S</a> and Galaxy Note repairs. Then, early next month, those same locations will start repairing Samsung’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">Galaxy Z foldables</a>.</p><p>If you bring your phone into one of the stores, they’ll be able to help with front and back screen replacements, battery swaps as well as port and camera repairs. Best Buy’s Geek Squad will complete the repairs with parts and training provided by Samsung.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>For the South Korean company, this partnership is all about expanding its repair footprint. The 100 Best Buy stores add to the more than 550 in-person authorized care locations the company already has in place across the US. They won’t help you if you own a more affordable Samsung device like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-hands-on-impressions-review-performance-camera-145018683.html"><ins>Galaxy A52</ins></a> (and you may not like the idea of the Geek Squad handling your device), but it’s still a step in the right direction. Outside of Apple, most tech companies have struggled to make it easy for their customers to find in-person support, and that&#39;s something that can have a significant impact on someone&#39;s relationship with a brand.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-best-buy-repair-partnership-180546057.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4502dc60-cd33-4611-a3a5-01e2326c2a70</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 18:05:46 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635185150</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T18:05:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Smart Phones]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/407adc60-e6ee-11ea-b7bf-0df563e5f3b3" width="3024" height="2016" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/407adc60-e6ee-11ea-b7bf-0df563e5f3b3" width="3024" height="2016" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Xinhua News Agency via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HOUSTON, March 19, 2020 -- A BestBuy store limits its store hours due to the spread of COVID-19 in Frisco, on the outskirts of Dallas, Texas, the United States on March 19, 2020. U.S. state of Texas Governor Greg Abbott on Thursday announced the shutdown of schools, restaurants, gyms and bars statewide to stop the spread of COVID-19. The order will be in effect until April 3, with an extension pending. (Photo by Dan Tian/Xinhua via Getty) (Xinhua/ via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[U.S.-TEXAS-PLANO-PUBLIC SERVICES-SHUTDOWN]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zoom's automatic closed captioning rolls out to all free users]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Zoom’s live transcription feature is now widely <a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-auto-generated-captions/"><ins>available to all free users</ins></a>. Previously it was a feature you had to pay to access, but toward the start of the year, Zoom <a href="https://www.engadget.com/zoom-automatic-closed-captions-all-users-fall-081631869.html"><ins>said</ins></a> it would roll it out to everyone. Now that it&#39;s here, free users don’t need to request access from the company if they need the tool for their meetings. If you’re in a call and want to request the host turn on live transcription, you can do so by using the meeting toolbar.</p><p>At the moment, the feature only works in English, but support for more languages is on the way. In September, Zoom said it would offer automated closed captioning in a total of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/zoom-live-captions-expansion-173233882.html"><ins>30 languages</ins></a> over the next year. The company is also working on adding live translation for 12 languages over that same time frame.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/zoom-automatic-closed-captions-free-users-172250054.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1cb8d38f-9015-441c-81a4-c302aece0970</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:22:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635181981</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T17:13:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9380cd00-35b4-11ec-af29-45e751b9df74" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9380cd00-35b4-11ec-af29-45e751b9df74" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Zoom]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Zoom Meeting]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Zoom Meeting]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[macOS Monterey is out now without SharePlay]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple has at long last released the latest major version of its Mac operating system, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/macos-monterey-release-date-180751313.html"><ins>macOS Monterey</ins></a>. While it&#39;s perhaps a more modest update than in previous years, there are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-preview-public-beta-175927010.html"><ins>some significant changes</ins></a> in some areas of the OS.</p><p>The redesigned Safari might be the most obvious transformation for many users. Apple initially planned to remove the tabs bar before it thankfully saw sense and decided to leave it as is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fix-safari-tab-bar-design-third-ios-15-mac-os-monterey-beta-180648751.html"><ins>in a later developer preview</ins></a>. The bar will match the color of the web page you&#39;re viewing, and there are some new features, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-wwdc-safari-redesign-extensions-mac-ios-ipados-tab-groups-184210596.html"><ins>such as Tab Groups</ins></a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Apple has overhauled FaceTime in macOS Monterey too. It works a little more like other conference calling software, in that you can start a call and then invite other people. This includes folks using Android or Windows devices <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-facetime-wwdc-2021-171840284.html"><ins>through the new FaceTime web app</ins></a>. M1 Macs will also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-airpods-max-spatial-audio-tvos-macos-180128777.html"><ins>support spatial audio</ins></a> for FaceTime and other features through <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-review-2021-160026883.html"><ins>AirPods</ins></a> and AirPods Max.</p><p>Elsewhere, macOS Monterey adds the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-ios-15-enhacenments-224214541.html">Focus Modes</a> seen in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, Quick Notes, Shortcuts and a new-look Maps app. Live Text, Apple&#39;s answer to Google Lens, is another new tool at macOS users&#39; disposal.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-delays-ios-15-shareplay-184450766.html"><ins>SharePlay</ins></a>, the feature that lets people sync streaming videos and music with friends, isn&#39;t available just yet. You&#39;ll also need to wait a little longer for<a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-universal-control-ipad-macbook-imac-184045949.html"> Universal Control</a>, which brings Mac and iPad together. You can move your cursor from one to the other and drag files between devices. SharePlay and Universal Control will arrive on macOS later this fall.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-macos-monterey-release-facetime-safari-shareplay-171102479.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a0b8f1ca-239f-4d58-94c7-5b8a9289755a</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:11:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635182292</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T17:18:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/3d437b60-da9f-11eb-b6d2-c27c02f86e65" width="2000" height="1279" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/3d437b60-da9f-11eb-b6d2-c27c02f86e65" width="2000" height="1279" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Devindra Hardawar/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[macOS Monterey]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[macOS Monterey]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[iOS 15.1 turns on SharePlay for Apple Fitness+]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-plus-adds-group-workouts-so-you-can-exercise-with-friends-via-share-play-174529068.html">said in September</a> that it was launching a feature called Group Workouts on Fitness+ that would use <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-wwdc-2021-facetime-messages-notification-summary-live-text-172526551.html">iOS 15&#39;s SharePlay tool</a> for exercise sessions over FaceTime. The company just <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/fitness-plus-introduces-workouts-and-meditations-with-shareplay/">announced</a> that Group Workouts is available starting today, so you can get up to 32 friends together to follow along with the company&#39;s exercise or meditation videos.&nbsp;</p><p>To use the new features, you&#39;ll need to update to iOS 15.1 or iPadOS 15.1, as well as watchOS 8.1, which are available today. Those who plan on watching the videos on their Apple TV will also need tvOS 15.1. To start a Group Workout, you&#39;ll need to first be on a FaceTime call, go to the Fitness app, then pick the video to follow. As you all sweat it out, Apple will display each person&#39;s metrics on their own screens. When someone moves ahead on the Burn Bar (which appears on specific workouts with more cardio activity) or closes their rings, everyone gets an alert so you can celebrate together.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>SharePlay <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-delays-ios-15-shareplay-184450766.html">wasn&#39;t available when iOS 15 launched</a> earlier this year, and during <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html">our testing of the iOS 15 beta</a> it was buggy and unstable. The company just released iOS 15.1 today, bringing the ability to SharePlay over FaceTime, so you can watch movies and videos with your friends or just show them what&#39;s on your iPhone.</p><p>Fitness+ is also expanding to 15 new countries. From Nov. 3rd, Austria, Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Indonesia, Italy, Malaysia, Mexico, Portugal, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Switzerland and the United Arab Emirates will be able to access the service. In America, those on UnitedHealthcare insurance can get a year of Fitness+ on their plans at no additional cost, starting Nov. 1st.&nbsp;</p><p><strong><em>Update (at 1:15pm ET)</em></strong><em>: This post was edited to add information about iOS 15.1&#39;s availability starting today.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-group-workout-shareplay-available-now-170031703.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">de02b7a0-ef94-4e81-abf1-8885761ebea8</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635235480</ingested><modified>2021-10-26T08:04:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Small Businesses]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2bc8f830-35b0-11ec-bfdf-e9e5a2ffc7dd" width="675" height="405" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2bc8f830-35b0-11ec-bfdf-e9e5a2ffc7dd" width="675" height="405" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An example of someone using Group Workouts on Apple Fitness+ on an iPad on a stationary bicycle.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Fitness+ Group Workouts Shareplay]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xbox consoles can now access NVIDIA GeForce Now via Microsoft Edge]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/xbox/">Xbox</a> owners are waiting for Microsoft to switch on its<a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/xcloud/"> own cloud gaming service</a> on consoles, they have other ways to stream games. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xboxs-latest-update-rolls-out-the-edge-browser-to-all-consoles-114037339.html">An update in September</a> brought the Chromium-based Microsoft Edge browser to Xbox One and Series X/S consoles, allowing players to access <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/stadia/">Google Stadia</a>. Starting today, they can fire up PC games via NVIDIA&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/geforce%20now/">GeForce Now</a> as well.</p><p>GeForce Now is now available in beta on Edge, as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22738056/microsoft-xbox-pc-games-steam-nvidia-geforce-now-streaming"><em>The Verge</em></a> notes, creating a pathway for Xbox users to play hundreds of games they might otherwise miss out on. GeForce Now is free for one-hour sessions though the resolution is limited to 1080p. NVIDIA just unveiled <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-now-introduces-an-rtx-3080-tier-for-up-to-1440-p-120-fps-gaming-130011568.html">a new, more expensive plan</a> that promises &quot;desktop-class latency&quot; and gameplay streaming in 1440p at up to 120 fps on PC and Mac and in 4K HDR at 60 fps on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-shield-xbox-series-x-s-ps5-dualsense-controllers-153040559.html">NVIDIA Shield TV</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Microsoft said it will bring Xbox Game Pass Ultimate&#39;s cloud gaming feature <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-cloud-gaming-game-pass-xbox-series-x-s-xbox-one-173404923.html">to consoles this holiday season</a>. Even so, thanks to GeForce Now, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S players now have a gateway to some major PC exclusives, such as <em>League of Legends </em>and <em>Dota 2,</em> without the need for a gaming rig.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/xbox-one-series-x-s-nvidia-geforce-now-microsoft-edge-pc-games-163558878.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8b145fe7-6c5b-4872-835e-12292db8ffc0</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 16:35:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635178603</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T16:16:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7e00910-35ad-11ec-8cdd-13ffde2fae32" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7e00910-35ad-11ec-8cdd-13ffde2fae32" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Aaron Souppouris/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Xbox Series X and Xbox Wireless Controller]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Xbox Series X and Xbox Wireless Controller]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft shows off Halo Infinite's campaign for the first time in over a year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With <em>Halo Infinite’s</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-december-8th-launch-date-134031534.html"><ins>December 8th</ins></a> release date fast approaching, Microsoft has shared a new six-minute trailer that offers an in-depth look at the game’s single-player component. The last time the company provided an extended preview of <em>Infinite’s </em>campaign was during its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-gameplay-trailer-master-chief-grappling-hook-162432108.html"><ins>Xbox showcase in 2020</ins></a>. That trailer was poorly received, with most fans agreeing the game’s visuals looked dated. In the aftermath of that reveal, developer 343 Industries said they <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-343-industries-visual-art-style-craig-response-102047314.html"><ins>had work to do</ins></a>, and Microsoft subsequently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-delay-2021-193546027.html"><ins>delayed the game to 2021</ins></a>.</p><div id="f44eb90167e74b11a65bb61660f9cf65"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XCbMVbeKlCg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>In this latest preview, you can see the visuals have gotten an update (look at <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744656/microsoft-halo-infinite-craig-brute-improved-graphics">Craig the Brute</a>). But what hasn’t changed too much is the emphasis on sandbox gameplay. During a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-230204570.html"><ins>community Q&amp;A back in March</ins></a>, 343 Industries said they were inspired by levels like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Silent_Cartographer"><ins>The Silent Cartographer</ins></a> from <em>Halo: Combat Evolved </em>to design the game in a way that would allow players to accomplish objectives with creativity.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You see that ethos on display in the second half of the trailer. Master Chief stumbles upon a Banished outpost he has to take out. You can use his grappling hook to move around the facility quickly and pull enemy weapons and explosives to augment your current arsenal. Vehicles play an important part in the overall gameplay loop, as do abilities you can purchase for Master Chief.&nbsp;</p><p>All of the different gameplay elements come together to form something that looks like it will offer a classic but more open Halo experience. It’s just too bad you won’t be able to play the campaign with a friend, at least <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-forge-release-date-343-industries-190153091.html"><ins>not at launch</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-trailer-162005655.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3767d7d8-df73-42cb-a898-792564b84720</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 16:20:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635178274</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T16:11:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/33b83f90-35ad-11ec-b7f3-f86989efc733" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/33b83f90-35ad-11ec-b7f3-f86989efc733" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Halo Infinite]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Halo Infinite]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GoPro addresses Hero 10 overheating issues with new firmware]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p><p>GoPro is issuing a firmware update that includes new &quot;video performance modes.&quot; These aren&#39;t new creative tools, rather they&#39;re designed to prevent cameras shutting down through overheating when recording in certain situations. The company is also unveiling a new &quot;Enduro&quot; battery that should improve performance in cold weather.</p><p>Soon after the launch of the Hero 10, some reviews complained that <a href="https://petapixel.com/2021/09/23/gopro-admits-hero-10-5-3k-mode-overheats-in-20min-under-zero-airflow/">their cameras were overheating</a> and turning off after around 20 minutes of continuous recording. The problem didn&#39;t seem to be universal, in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gopro-hero-10-review-a-big-invisible-upgrade-130041612.html">our review</a> I performed such a test (before hearing of said complaints) and was able to get over an hour of footage. Other <a href="https://www.dcrainmaker.com/2021/09/a-deep-dive-into-gopro-hero-10-overheating.html">detailed tests</a> also didn&#39;t initially bump into the issue. But enough users were having the problem that the company clearly had to take note.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Today, GoPro has confirmed that a new firmware update is coming with the aforementioned Video Performance Modes — Maximum Video Performance, Extended Battery and Tripod/Stationary. The first in that list sounds much like the current mode. Extended Battery, as the name suggests, provides optimal settings for longer battery life. The latter assumes that the camera will not be moving and thus removes things like GPS and HyperSmooth stabilization to, presumably, ease the load on the new processor in situations where there&#39;s no motion or airflow to cool the camera down.</p><p>According to GoPro, with the new firmware, a 5.3K recording at 60fps will run for 47 percent longer (an average of 29 minutes per clip). Alternatively, at 4K/60fps you can enjoy a 154  percent increase to an hour and three minutes total.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0289b260-357f-11ec-b7fd-b9756c5eb80b" alt="GoPro Hero 10 Enduro battery." data-uuid="9530d3e9-dd1d-3a0a-a6a6-7ad0e0bff439"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">GoPro</div></figure><p>As for the new Enduro battery ($24.99) GoPro states it will extend recording times to an average of 56 minutes of 5.3K/60 video at 14F/-10C. When used at moderate temperatures, 5.3K/60 shots should see a boost of 28 percent in duration while 4K/120 videos will enjoy a 40 percent improvement in record time. The new cell will be compatible with both the Hero 9 Black and the Hero 10 Black and thankfully comes in a different color so that you won&#39;t mix it up with your standard batteries.</p><p>GoPro stops short of saying what the new battery is doing beyond using &quot;revolutionary technology.&quot; Either way, whatever your use case for the Hero 10, by the end of the month you&#39;ll be able to update your firmware for the new modes or you can pick up the new battery in late November.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/go-pro-hero-10-overheating-new-firmware-160050913.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a510c7da-c318-4ae3-95db-59b9023a348f</guid><dc:creator>James Trew</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635184116</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T17:48:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|James Trew]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/1cd317f0-164a-11ec-96af-402492a10c43" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/1cd317f0-164a-11ec-96af-402492a10c43" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[James Trew / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[GoPro Hero 10 Black review.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GoPro Hero 10 Black review]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple AirPods review (2021): Better in nearly every way]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you consider 2019’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-03-apple-airpods-review-2019-more-of-the-same.html">second-generation AirPods</a> were a modest update rather than a complete overhaul, Apple was way overdue for an all-new model. With this year’s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:third-gen version" href="https://amzn.to/3nuato2">third-gen version</a>, the company has given us just that. The 2021 AirPods have a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-third-gen-announced-price-specs-availability-171540519.html">new design</a>, complete with handy features from the company’s more expensive earbud and headphone models. The stick-bud look is still with us, and the overall fit will remain polarizing, but Apple has nonetheless massively improved its “regular” AirPods in nearly every way.</p><h2><strong>Design</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f4428f0-359a-11ec-bfde-032bea08da59" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="4bd45c26-58b9-3347-a9d5-dcd393866de3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>Apple completely redesigned AirPods inside and out for this third-generation model. The new look is a blend of the original AirPods design and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-06-apple-airpods-pro-review.html">AirPods Pro</a>, with some modifications. Right off the bat you’ll notice the lack of the silicone eartips found on the Pro. The overall fit of the new model is similar to that of the first two AirPods, which means that there will be a good number of people who won’t care for it. That mixture of designs continues on the stem. Apple reduced the length of the component by a third versus the previous model, adding the force sensor from the AirPods Pro for the on-board controls.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>For its new “contoured design,” Apple says it considered customer feedback on fit and comfort as well as thousands of ear scans, acoustic studies and heat map modeling to create the shape. The company explains that the design reduces weight and its tapered silhouette and angle increase comfort. Not to mention the updated earbud better directs sound into your ear. All of this turned out to be true, as the new model is more comfortable and the design helps deliver massive improvements to audio quality.</p><p>Despite a lot of people using AirPods at the gym or on a run, only the Pro model was sweat and water resistant. Apple has extended that protection to this third-gen unit as well as its charging case. You won’t want to try submerging either one, but the IPX4 rating should be enough to keep the earbuds safe during workouts or from an errant, albeit small, splash.</p><p>AirPods have had automatic pausing before now, but Apple changed in-ear detection for the 2021 edition. Instead of a simple optical sensor, Apple’s new version actually detects skin. Combined with the built-in accelerometer, AirPods can better determine when they’re in your ear, which Apple says makes pausing more accurate and can even extend battery life.</p><h2><strong>Software and features</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f4365a0-359a-11ec-bdaf-31d6f36d5be0" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="e53f8242-32ec-336a-a0c1-8ebe4bdebca1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>Like Apple’s other recent AirPods models, this new set is equipped with the company’s H1 chip. That component enables a lot of features, with the first one being one-touch fast pairing. Simply flip open the case near your iPhone and all you have to do is tap the pop-up to sync the two devices. It’s so quick and easy, and you’ll quickly realize how much time you wasted putting earbuds in pairing mode before swiping over to the Bluetooth menu. Those days are long gone and, quite frankly, good riddance.</p><p>The H1 chip also powers always-on Siri. As before, this allows you to summon the virtual assistant without having to reach for or be near your phone. H1 lends a hand with Adaptive EQ, spatial audio and dynamic head tracking as well, bringing features from the pricier Pro and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/airpods-max-review-143019326.html">Max</a> models to a more affordable version of AirPods.</p><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="73c484d7-4d95-4125-8cf1-301d9ef31fba"/><p>Similar to previous products, AirPods are equipped with automatic switching between Apple devices. When you’re listening to music on your MacBook Pro and get a call, you can automatically switch over. And when the call is finished, you can go back without re-pairing. Thanks to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-features-ios-15-180549807.html">latest version of iOS</a> features like announce notifications with Siri and improved Find My are all available on the third-gen AirPods. The older <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-20-ios-audio-sharing-beats.html">audio sharing</a> tool is back as well.</p><p>With the change to force sensor-driven controls, Apple has given AirPods the same actions as AirPods Pro. On the second-gen model, you had to tap the earbud and the options were very limited. Like the Pro version, you now have the ability to play/pause and accept calls (press once), skip tracks forward (press twice), skip tracks backwards (press three times) and activate Siri (press and hold). Once again, there’s no option for on-board volume control. The press-and-hold input on the AirPods Pro changes noise-cancelling mode, so it seems like Apple could’ve reassigned this action for volume — up on one side, down on the other. As it stands, using this for Siri seems redundant, especially as the hands-free assistant is a staple of its AirPods line.</p><section data-eng-breakout="ce1ab27d8ce14269ab71e02ee7a15df8" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/de643e70-359a-11ec-bff6-8ee274c81d5c" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality."></section><h2><strong>Sound quality</strong></h2><p>I don’t want to mince words here: the new AirPods sound so much better than the previous two versions. Like almost night and day better. Apple didn’t make any significant changes to sound quality from the first model to the 2019 version. But for gen three, Apple paired a custom driver with a high-dynamic-range amplifier to improve the audio chops. The company says that the duo work together to produce “rich consistent bass” and “crisp, clean” highs. From the moment I fired up the first song, this was all immediately evident. I don’t think I’ve ever audibly said “woah” with the first note from a guitar on any review unit, but given how average older AirPods sound, it was involuntary this time.</p><p>Overall, the sound is bigger and more immersive. It’s open and airy, instead of being compressed and downright boring like older AirPods. While greatly improved, the sound quality doesn’t match the absolute best I’ve tested: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-160006474.html">Sony’s WF-1000XM4</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/master-and-dynamic-mw08-review-true-wireless-earbuds-143027692.html">Master &amp; Dynamic’s MW08</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-19-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-2-review.html">Sennheiser’s Momentum True Wireless 2</a>. However, the new AirPods do sound better than the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-150002889.html">Galaxy Buds 2</a> and are comparable to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jabra-elite-85t-review-130035415.html">Jabra’s Elite 75t</a> — both of which offer active noise cancellation and are more in line with Apple’s latest in terms of price.</p><p>Even without spatial audio tracks, music feels dimensional with vocals, instruments and other sounds standing on their own. The performance is consistent across the bluegrass picking of Nickel Creek to the bluesy folk rock of Jason Isbell and the grungy metal of Every Time I Die. Sure, part of this is due to the new driver/amp combo, as the crisp treble and constant, but not overpowering, bass help create these soundscapes. Another reason is the new shape of the earbud that better directs sound into your ears.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f433e90-359a-11ec-8fff-883108614607" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="0fd3d96f-ca46-366f-81b4-caacacb10e53"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>The third aspect is Adaptive EQ, a feature Apple first introduced on the AirPods Max. Using computational audio, the company’s H1 chip and the inward-facing mic, AirPods tune the music for how the earbuds fit in your ear. Adaptive EQ constantly monitors sound and adapts low- and mid-range frequencies in real time. All of these updates make the new AirPods something I actually wanted to listen to music with, rather than something that was just more convenient that other earbuds.</p><p>The new AirPods also support Apple’s spatial audio. This means you can listen to tracks that are available in Dolby Atmos on Apple Music with no issue. I can respect that spatial audio as a concept is divisive: some people like it while others don’t. I don’t care for it with the AirPods Max, but I think it sounds better with these new AirPods. Dolby Atmos seemed a bit too spacious at times with Apple over-ear headphones (Kacey Musgraves’ <em>Golden Hour </em>is a prime example), but that’s not the case with the supported earbuds. I’m not sure it will sway folks who don’t care for spatial audio currently, but that’s why you have the ability to disable it entirely.</p><p>Like the AirPods Pro, spatial audio here is also available with dynamic head tracking, which changes the position of the audio in your earbuds when you turn your head. iOS will allow you to switch between fixed spatial audio and dynamic head tracking via the volume slider in Control Center. There’s also a third option to disable the immersive sound entirely from here. I think head tracking has some benefits when you’re watching a movie or TV show, but when you’re listening to music, it’s not so great. Especially when you momentarily walk away from your computer or phone. For that reason, easy access to these controls is a great thing.</p><p>What you won’t find here is active noise cancellation (ANC) or a transparency mode. Apple has reserved both for the pricier AirPods Pro, and there’s a key reason why. The third-gen AirPods allow some outside sound in by design as they don’t completely seal off your ear canal. This would make an ANC setup difficult and means the AirPods are “transparent” by default. Much like the design, if you consider the features of the new AirPods as the middle ground between the base model and the Pro version, a lot of these decisions make sense.</p><h2><strong>Call quality</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f4190e1-359a-11ec-bdaf-6fc7ea6fcb17" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="0f3b32b8-85be-34b5-9b4d-d1fc3ee074c2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>As ever, Apple is hyping the voice quality on its latest AirPods. The company says new acoustic mesh covers for inset microphones help reduce wind noise. These earbuds also support the AAC-ELD codec, which Apple says enables “full-HD voice quality” to keep you sounding crisp and clear on FaceTime calls. What’s more, the AirPods support spatial audio in Group FaceTime calls to further simulate the feeling of being in the same room. Basically, the sound from the person who is talking comes from the direction they’re positioned on your screen. It’s not like speaking IRL, but it is an improvement. It makes calls more immersive, plus you can get an even better sense of directional audio when your device is in landscape mode.</p><p>Indeed, FaceTime calls are crisp and clear with the new AirPods. Phone calls are improved as well but not to the same degree. Voice quality is here better than most earbuds I’ve tested, but not by a ton. True to Apple’s claims, these AirPods do a decent job blocking background noise and focusing on your voice. It’s great when you’re talking, but the clamor resumes when you’re not speaking. Depending on how loud the noise is, it might be distracting for the person on the other end. There are improvements in regards to voice, but you’ll notice them most in FaceTime.</p><h2><strong>Battery life</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f431780-359a-11ec-adef-de9e3721d288" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="089f3f7b-8f2a-3dbb-af41-2c0f7f0be794"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>To accompany the redesign, Apple also increased battery life on the new AirPods. The company says you can expect up to six hours on the earbuds themselves and up to 30 hours total when you factor in the case. I actually managed just over seven hours during my tests, and that’s with fixed spatial audio on (but without dynamic head tracking). Since the second-gen version was rated at five hours, over seven is a significant upgrade for those who use headphones throughout their work day.</p><p>If you find yourself in a pinch, the new AirPods have the same quick-charge feature as the AirPods Pro: five minutes in the case gives you about an hour of use. Where the original AirPods Pro case supported wireless charging, now both it and the case for AirPods is equipped with MagSafe. The MagSafe case still works with Qi-certified pads, but Apple will sell you a magnetic charger for a better experience. Just remember: the second-gen model that Apple kept around for $129 doesn’t support wireless charging at all.</p><h2><strong>The competition</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f427b40-359a-11ec-bfa7-35c742f43455" alt="Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality." data-uuid="646208d1-3b39-326e-afe7-e992b858cb85"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>There’s never been a doubt that AirPods are built for iPhone, iPad and Mac. Nearly every feature is meant to enhance or extend the tools available on those devices, including giving you the ability to access Siri and other things without reaching for an iPhone. By adding the third-gen AirPods in the middle of its lineup, Apple has replaced the 2019 model with a wireless charging case. That leaves its roster with the original design (second-generation) at $129, this model at $179 and the AirPods Pro at $249. The company now has a trio of options akin to what Samsung has offered for a while now: a range of choices with varied options and prices.</p><p>At this point, the only options that come close to the deep iOS integration AirPods offer are products like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-16-beats-powerbeats-pro-review.html">Powerbeats Pro</a>.  A <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-27-beats-powerbeats-wireless-earbuds-review.html">few models</a> in the Beats lineup offer handy features like fast pairing and hands-free Siri since they’re powered by Apple’s H1 chip. The more affordable <a href="https://www.engadget.com/beats-studio-buds-review-150014566.html">Studio Buds</a> (<a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:$150" href="https://amzn.to/3bf5Nwx">$150</a>) don’t have that component, but they still offer the ability to wake the assistant without reaching for your phone. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/beats-fit-pro-leak-191933131.html">Beats Fit Pro</a> leaked earlier this month and initial reports indicate they too will carry Apple’s powerful earbud tech, but we don’t know about price just yet. There are plenty of options that sound great and have handy features in their own right, but nothing without the H1 chip syncs as well with Apple’s devices.</p><p>If you want active noise cancellation or ambient sound in some tiny earbuds, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Galaxy Buds 2" href="https://amzn.to/3nsZ0Ff">Galaxy Buds 2</a> are a solid bet. Unfortunately, Samsung scaled back its iOS integration a few models ago, but <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-150002889.html">these</a> still work well with iPhone and the like. If ANC, spatial audio or hands-free Siri aren’t things you need, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jabra-elite-3-review-120031350.html">Jabra’s Elite 3</a> earbuds are the best value right now. They’re tiny and comfy, but the sound is impressive and the battery life is good. Plus, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:they&#x002019;re only $80" href="https://amzn.to/3mb0C7a">they’re only $80</a>.</p><h2><strong>Wrap-up</strong></h2><p>No modest update this time around. Apple totally overhauled <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:AirPods" href="https://amzn.to/3nuato2">AirPods</a> for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality. The company also expanded availability of key features like spatial audio and Adaptive EQ to a more affordable set of earbuds while keeping all of the convenience of AirPods intact. These earbuds still aren’t for everyone, but what they offer the Apple faithful can’t be found elsewhere and the company will do well to keep it that way.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-review-2021-160026883.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">19f05692-bf9e-4f9f-9491-632fb52fd3f9</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 16:00:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1635178588</ingested><modified>2021-10-25T16:16:35+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/72e88700-359a-11ec-bfb9-b69664469f60" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/72e88700-359a-11ec-bfb9-b69664469f60" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple totally overhauled AirPods for the third-generation version with the biggest changes coming in the design and audio quality.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple AirPods (2021) review]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>