<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></title><link>Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics</link><description><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[The best dorm room essentials for college students]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Colleges are returning to their pre-pandemic normal this year, which also means a return to dorm room living. Since this is the first time many of you will be away from home, it’s a good idea to stock up on a few items for your new tiny abode. Not all of our recommendations will be strictly tech-related here because, while tech is important in college (of course), we also wanted to cover the other  essentials that will bring you the comforts of home to your dorm and hopefully make student life less stressful.</p><p>Examples include kitchen items like an adjustable-temp electric kettle, a weighted blanket for reducing anxiety, and a mattress topper that will make that dorm bed much more comfortable. At the same time, you might not want to be in your room forever, which is why we’ve also recommended a few items that could improve your social life, such as a portable Bluetooth speaker for parties and a couple of casual board games. Whether you just want to chill out or make a few friends, we hope this list will help you settle into dorm life.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>Linenspa foam pillow</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d56203-df46-11eb-bdef-485d039d449f"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Comfort is key to dorm living, which is why we recommend an oversized reading pillow like <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:this one from Linenspa" href="https://amzn.to/2VgBPUq">this one from Linenspa</a>. It helps change up your seating position so you’re not in your desk chair all the time, plus it’s a lot more comfortable than just piling up bed pillows against the wall. The pillow is filled with shredded memory foam so it won’t put a lot of stress on your back, plus it comes with a soft velour cover. That posture support makes it great for reading, playing games or watching TV. As a bonus, there’s also a handle on the top that makes it easy to carry around.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy LinenSpa pillow at Amazon - $40" href="https://amzn.to/2VgBPUq">Buy LinenSpa pillow at Amazon - $40</a></p><h2>Mind Reader lap desk</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d56202-df46-11eb-9f5d-f9c8c39b9a41"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>If you frequently use your laptop not just for work but also for watching videos and general entertainment, consider getting a portable desk that you can place on your lap. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:This one from Mind Reader" href="https://amzn.to/3ACQwRS">This one from Mind Reader</a> is excellent thanks to its dual-bolster pillow support. All told, it has eight different angle options that you can adjust to your liking. Additionally, you can use it to prop up a book or tablet for easy reading. When you’re done working, it also works well as a tray table for snacks while watching TV.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy lap desk at Amazon - $15" href="https://amzn.to/3ACQwRS">Buy lap desk at Amazon - $15</a></p><h2>Aeropress</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4cf6e92-df46-11eb-bb7b-14073d39c068" alt="Aeropress for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="5ccb66eb-c75d-3ad4-b78c-02a11b8d9443"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Having a reliable way to make coffee every morning is practically a must-have for a lot of college students, especially for those dreaded 8am classes. One of the cheapest and fastest ways to get an excellent brew is to use the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Aeropress" href="https://amzn.to/2Uz4dAU">Aeropress</a>, which has been a favorite among caffeine addicts for years. It can make a strong, full-bodied cup in just a few minutes, and its plunger-driven design is so simple that even a coffee beginner can use it. It’s small and compact enough for travel and it doesn’t require any electricity, which makes it ideal for camping trips. On top of that, there’s minimal cleaning involved. Equally important, it’s quite affordable at around $30.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Aeropress at Amazon - $32" href="https://amzn.to/2Uz4dAU">Buy Aeropress at Amazon - $32</a></p><h2>Black+Decker Dustbuster Pivot Vac</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4cf6e91-df46-11eb-9a56-67435f107a15"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>One of the first lessons you’ll likely learn as a college student is that you’ll have no one to clean up after you. That means doing your own laundry and yes, cleaning your own room. The easiest way to do so is with a handheld vacuum, like the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Black+Decker 20V Max" href="https://amzn.to/3ACJtbT">Black+Decker 20V Max</a>. It only weighs three pounds so it’s lightweight enough for you to clean your whole room without a lot of fuss. It has a pivoting nozzle which makes it ideal for getting around tight corners and hard-to-reach shelves. Its high-performance motor provides plenty of suction and its 15-ounce capacity is large enough for most dorm rooms. The bowl and filter are removable so you can give them a good wash in between uses. It’s also overall easy to use and fairly affordable, two things you can’t often say about fancy, expensive vacuums.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Black + Decker handheld vacuum at Amazon - $90" href="https://amzn.to/3ACJtbT">Buy Black + Decker handheld vacuum at Amazon - $90</a></p><h2><strong>Anyday Medium Deep Dish</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4cf6e90-df46-11eb-bedb-0a4b4cfe01bc" alt="Anyday Medium Deep Dish for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="03230302-0c20-3bc8-bcff-9bd82e3a03af"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>You’re probably not allowed to have an Instant Pot in your dorm room, but one kitchen appliance that almost always gets the thumbs up is a microwave. Sure, you can use it to heat up frozen dinners, but why not try it to cook actual dishes as well? <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Anyday&#x002019;s line of microwave cookware" href="https://fave.co/3wnvQdo">Anyday’s line of microwave cookware</a> lets you do exactly that. Everything is microwave safe, including the stainless steel rim (its smooth and curved shape prevents electrical arcing). Its primary feature is its lid, which has a knob that can vent excess steam when it is lifted. Thanks to this innovation, you can make everything from mac and cheese to a breakfast burrito using only your microwave. For college students, we recommend the medium dish set — they’re sized just right for solo diners.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy Medium cookware set at Anyday - $55" href="https://fave.co/3wnvQdo">Buy Medium cookware set at Anyday - $55</a></p><h2>Bearaby Cotton Napper</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d031e0-df46-11eb-97de-a85a909dd10f" alt="Bearaby Cotton Napper for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="31151283-a735-3388-b362-ed94a5f72e43"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Bearaby</div></figure><p>If you’re like most college students, you’ll probably have your fair share of stress throughout the semester, which can make it harder to get enough sleep. One way to help overcome it is with a weighted blanket, which helps reduce anxiety. Our favorite is the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Bearaby cotton napper" href="https://fave.co/3k5P2dd">Bearaby cotton napper</a>. Unlike other weighted blankets that are filled with tiny glass beads, it’s handmade with a heavy chunky-knit material that feels like a warm hug when wrapped around you. Another bonus is just how gorgeous they look: They come in a variety of luscious colors — from Midnight Blue to Butternut Bliss — and their knit design makes them far more stylish than most weighted blankets on the market. They’ll go well in any decor and are sure to garner plenty of likes on Instagram.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy Cotton Napper at Bearaby - $250" href="https://fave.co/3k5P2dd">Buy Cotton Napper at Bearaby - $250</a></p><h2>Lenovo Smart Clock Essential</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d4ecd0-df46-11eb-aa79-6dac8cc0ac61" alt="Lenovo Smart Clock Essential for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="50018997-cb93-3b29-97d2-52133160a42a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Even though you could use your phone as an alarm clock, it’s still useful to have a dedicated device for the task. It lets you keep your phone away from your bedside for a more restful sleep, plus you can tell time just by glancing at it. One of our favorites is <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Lenovo&#x002019;s Smart Clock Essential" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/yRyZWv">Lenovo’s Smart Clock Essential</a>, which has Google Assistant built in. There are other smart alarm clocks out there — like Amazon’s Echo Show 5, for example — but it retails for close to $85. The Smart Clock Essential, on the other hand, is very affordable at only $50. Sure, it isn’t nearly as advanced as the Echo Show 5, but if all you want are the alarm clock features, then the Essential should more than suffice. The clock’s 4-inch LED screen shows time in bold digits, and you can ask the Assistant to play music, set timers or create reminders. The integrated nightlight is also a nice touch for those who don’t like to sleep in complete darkness.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Smart Clock Essential at Best Buy - $50" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/yRyZWv">Buy Smart Clock Essential at Best Buy - $50</a></p><h2>Lunya Organic Pima sleep mask</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d56201-df46-11eb-bb54-60d47704d019" alt="Lunya Organic Prima sleep mask for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="6a12fa34-c1d0-38ff-b202-ce383e01d915"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Roommate pulling an all-nighter with the lights on? Want to catch some z’s in the afternoon in between classes? Or maybe you’re just particularly sensitive to light? If you can relate to any of this, we recommend getting a sleep mask to make it easier for you to drift off into dreamland. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:This one from Lunya" href="https://fave.co/3yv46ou">This one from Lunya</a> is one of our personal favorites because it completely blocks out light and feels comfortable to boot; it’s like wearing pillows on your eyes. We tend to prefer this model over masks with eye cups because it’s not quite as bulky. The Lunya’s wide elasticized band will fit most people and it even covers the ears, which helps reduce noise. It’s also machine washable, so you can easily keep it clean.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy sleep mask at Lunya - $48" href="https://fave.co/3yv46ou">Buy sleep mask at Lunya - $48</a></p><h2>OXO pour-over kettle</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d5b020-df46-11eb-81ff-801b3c3f78a7" alt="OXO Pour-over kettle for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="e4e1cc2a-6344-3f94-9fc3-4d9b09a5cfaf"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>Most dorms don’t allow appliances with an open heating element, which is why there are no toasters or hot plates on this list. But thankfully for tea and coffee aficionados, many do permit electric kettles. One of our favorite models is the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:OXO Brew Adjustable Temperature Pour-Over Kettle" href="https://amzn.to/3dSmz6s">OXO Brew Adjustable Temperature Pour-Over Kettle</a>. You can adjust the temperature in one-degree increments from 140 to 212 Fahrenheit, which is perfect for those who like to dial in the right temp for a specific brew — most green tea, for example, brews between 160 and 170 Fahrenheit, while you generally want boiling water for black tea. This specific model is especially useful for those who like pour-over coffee due to its gooseneck spout. There’s also a built-in timer to keep track of your brewing process. Of course, you can use boiling water to heat up other concoctions too, like hot cocoa mix or cup noodles.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy OXO kettle at Amazon - $100" href="https://amzn.to/3dSmz6s">Buy OXO kettle at Amazon - $100</a></p><h2>Pure Green latex mattress topper</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d64c61-df46-11eb-9f5f-1b59b2d44bb8" alt="Pure Green Latex mattress topper for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="b103a48f-db92-3351-aaa4-e5eb838586ff"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Pure Green</div></figure><p>Chances are, the bed in your dorm room isn’t very comfortable. It’s also probably not easy (or cost effective) to change the mattress. That’s why we recommend getting a mattress topper because it’s the one way to control how your bed feels without spending a lot of money. We prefer a natural latex option like <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:this one from Pure Green" href="https://amzn.to/3yv3TSe">this one from Pure Green</a> because it delivers comfort and support without the sinking feeling of memory foam. It also won’t absorb much body heat, which helps keep you cool throughout the night. Pure Green sells its mattress topper in three different thicknesses — from 1-inch to 3-inch — to fit your particular needs. Opt for the 1 or 2-inch if you want firm or medium-firm, or spring for the 3-inch model if you prefer things soft.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy mattress topper at Amazon - $110" href="https://amzn.to/3yv3TSe">Buy mattress topper at Amazon - $110</a></p><h2>Rubbermaid food storage containers</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4cfe3c0-df46-11eb-bf1f-f707b2ecf579" alt="Rubbermaid food storage for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="bc0eab77-f5b7-3886-8582-9d73a2ed5b51"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Rubbermaid </div></figure><p>When you’re in college, you’ll no longer have quick access to your family’s pantry, which you could easily raid for late-night munchies. Instead, you’ll have to supply your own, and you’ll want to keep them in airtight storage containers like <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:these ones from Rubbermaid" href="https://amzn.to/3xklfky">these ones from Rubbermaid</a>. The lids snap tight to keep food fresh and they stack on top of each other in order to save space. They’re durable enough to withstand everyday use, whether you use them for crackers, pretzels or cereal. You could also use these containers to grab a hot dinner from the dining hall on your way to a group study session.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Rubbermaid Brilliance container at Amazon - $17" href="https://amzn.to/3xklfky">Buy Rubbermaid Brilliance container at Amazon - $17</a></p><h2>Ultimate Ears Boom 3</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d64c60-df46-11eb-bebf-08880c24587a" alt="Ultimate Ears Boom 3 for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="b0b3c1b6-6413-3eae-ba83-56ea5659ceec"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>College life isn’t all work and stress — sometimes you’ll want to have parties and blast your favorite tunes. The best way to do so is with a Bluetooth speaker like the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Boom 3" href="https://amzn.to/3hNiwJI">Boom 3</a> from Ultimate Ears. Your smartphone just won’t have the same level of volume or audio quality as a dedicated speaker, and your laptop’s speakers likely aren’t to task either (not to mention you probably want to put your laptop away if you’re at a party). The Boom 3 has an attractive cylindrical design, a rechargeable battery that lasts 15 hours on a charge, and it delivers punchy, immersive sound that will easily fill the room. It’s also IP67-rated to be waterproof, which makes it ideal for hanging out by the pool or a trip to the beach.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy UE Boom 3 at Amazon - $150" href="https://amzn.to/3hNiwJI">Buy UE Boom 3 at Amazon - $150</a></p><h2>Codenames</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d031e1-df46-11eb-9ea7-bc9600079cbc"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Playing casual board games is a great way to socialize at gatherings without the need to engage in small talk. A really popular one is called <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Codenames" href="https://amzn.to/3dUsHv3">Codenames</a>, a party game that pits two teams of spies against each other. Each “spymaster” has to get their teammates to guess hidden words (which are plotted out on a grid) using only one-word clues and a number. For example, if you wanted your team to guess the words “costume,” “web,” and “spider,” you might say “Peter, 3” to indicate that there are three clues on the board that match that word. There are also clues you have to avoid, which makes the game a little harder. The game is easy to explain, plus it encourages communication, which helps break the ice.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Codenames at Amazon - $20" href="https://amzn.to/3dUsHv3">Buy Codenames at Amazon - $20</a></p><h2>Monikers</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d56200-df46-11eb-bf71-f12cbe86cc1c"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>For larger groups (up to 20 people in this case) who want to have a bit of silly fun, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Monikers" href="https://amzn.to/2UwzgNG">Monikers</a> is a fantastic party game. Players take turns giving clues to teammates so that they’ll guess what’s on the card, which can be anything from a famous musician (eg. Rick Astley) to a viral meme (e.g., LOLCats). For the first round, they can use as many words as they want to describe the clue. But in the second round, they can only use one. In the third, they can’t use any words at all, which is basically charades. Almost every game of Monikers will result in giggles, laughter and hopefully a memorable evening.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Monikers at Amazon - $30" href="https://amzn.to/2UwzgNG">Buy Monikers at Amazon - $30</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-college-dorm-room-essentials-143052706.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3f3cb6df-16f9-42a1-8c86-5e0d13343d58</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626448194</ingested><modified>2021-07-16T15:10:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Career & Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Home & Garden]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d2c9f0-df46-11eb-bae6-0a62678cf7a8" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b4d2c9f0-df46-11eb-bae6-0a62678cf7a8" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A collection of Dorm Essentials for Engadget's 2021 Back to School guide.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Dorm Essentials (lead)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's latest flagship soundbar offers Dolby Atmos and 360 Reality Audio]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At CES 2020, Sony demoed its 360 Reality Audio (360RA) technology <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-07-sony-360-reality-audio-ces-2020.html">on a home theater setup</a> like you would put in your living room. The in-booth layout included a soundbar, subwoofer and two rear satellite speakers. Today, the company announced the first gear that will allow you to actually create something similar at home. The company&#39;s new <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/tv-video-home-theater-sound-bars/all-home-theater-sound-bars/p/hta7000">HT-A7000 flagship soundbar</a> offers Dolby Atmos in addition to 360RA and the option to tack on sub and/or extra speakers can accommodate any space. If you&#39;re not so much into soundbars but still want the sensation of immersive audio, Sony also introduced <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/tv-video-home-theater-sound-bars/all-home-theater-sound-bars/p/hta9">the HT-A9</a>: a set of four speakers and a control box equipped with new 360 Spatial Sound Mapping tech.&nbsp;</p><p>The HT-A7000 is a 7.1.2-channel soundbar packed with Sony&#39;s X-balanced speakers, side beam tweeters, up-firing drivers for Dolby Atmos and dual subwoofers. Thanks to a Virtual Surround Engine (overhead) and S-Force Pro Front Surround (horizontal), the A7000 can simulate immersive audio on its own so you can take advantage of DTS:X in addition to Atmos. The soundbar is equipped with Sound Field Optimization that uses built-in microphones to calibrate the speaker to a room by detecting the height and width of the space as well as the position of a wireless subwoofer and any rear speakers.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="72f06060-abb4-4ccc-babc-6f7049155e08"/><p>When it comes to music, the A7000 accommodates High-Resolution Audio and 360 Reality Audio. In fact, this is the first Sony soundbar to support 360RA and just the third speaker from the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-360-reality-audio-ces-2021-130027671.html">to do so</a>. The A7000 also has Sony&#39;s DSEE Extreme technology that Sony has leveraged for its headphones. That feature restores some of the compression from streaming services in real time, giving you something akin to lossless audio without the massive file sizes or the need for a wired setup.&nbsp;</p><p>In terms of connectivity, the A7000 has HDMI 2.1 with eARC and both 8K and 4K/120fps passthrough — plus Dolby Vision support. The soundbar works with Chromecast, AirPlay 2 and Spotify Connect, so you have options when it comes to streaming music from your phone or another device. When used with compatible Bravia TVs, the A7000 works with Sony&#39;s Acoustic Center Sync that allows you to employ your television&#39;s speakers as additional center audio for things like speech clarity. The new soundbar can be controlled by a Google Assistant device at launch and Sony plans to add Alexa compatibility in a future update. Lastly, the company says optional wireless subwoofers and rear speakers will connect automatically to the A7000 when you power them on.&nbsp;</p><p>Unlike <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-01-07-sonys-flagship-soundbar-kicks-out-room-filling-audio.html">the HT-ST5000</a> that it&#39;s replacing, the HT-A7000 soundbar doesn&#39;t come with a subwoofer. Sony says it unbundled the pairing based on customer feedback. Some people wanted the company&#39;s top-of-the-line soundbar, but they weren&#39;t necessarily interested in the sub. It&#39;s a beast in terms of both size and sound, so it&#39;s not ideal for apartments on any room where space is limited. Instead, Sony is offering two subwoofer options — <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/tv-video-home-theater-sound-bars/all-home-theater-sound-bars/p/sasw5">the SA-SW5</a> and <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/tv-video-home-theater-sound-bars/all-home-theater-sound-bars/p/sasw3">SA-SW3</a> — along with <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/tv-video/tv-video-home-theater-sound-bars/all-home-theater-sound-bars/p/sars3s">a pair of rear satellite speakers (SA-RS3S)</a> as separate purchases. All of the add-ons connect to the HT-A7000 wirelessly, with the SW5 offering 300 watts of low-end tone via a 7-inch driver and the SW3 packing 200 watts of bass with a 6-inch speaker.&nbsp;</p><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="593796ae-7a85-46f9-bc14-e17b759a666e"/><p>With the A9 &quot;home theater system,&quot; four cylindrical speakers offer what Sony describes as a &quot;flexible layout&quot; option that&#39;s meant to blend in with your living room decor. Thanks to Sound Field Optimization and built-in mics, the A9 can calibrate itself to any space — just like the tech does for the A7000. A key difference here is that the A9 is also equipped with Sony&#39;s new 360 Spatial Sound Mapping Technology. This feature not only lets you place the four units as you see fit, but it also offers a broad soundstage the company says is more immersive than &quot;traditional&quot; soundbars. Sony explains that the A9 gives users the sensation that the audio is &quot;coming from beyond their walls&quot; by creating up to 12 &quot;phantom&quot; speakers with just the four units. Of course, this is something we&#39;ll have to put the test to double-check the claim.&nbsp;</p><p>Each speaker houses X-balanced front and up-firing speakers along with a tweeter and bass duct. The four devices connect wirelessly to a control box that has HDMI in/out (eARC output) with 8K and 4K/120 passthrough alongside Dolby Vision. The A9 is compatible with immersive formats like Dolby Atmos, DTS:X, 360 Reality Audio and High-Resolution Audio. It also works with Chromecast, AirPlay 2 and Spotify Connect and you can leverage voice control by pairing the set of speakers with a Google Assistant (at launch) or Alexa (via future update) device. If you need a boost in the center channel, you can use the A9 with compatible Bravia TVs and Sony&#39;s Acoustic Center Sync to employ the speakers from the display. Lastly, both of Sony&#39;s new subwoofers can be paired with the A9 speakers for fuller sound.</p><p>All of Sony&#39;s new home theater gear is set to arrive in &quot;September/October,&quot; according to the company. The HT-A7000 soundbar is $1,300 while the HT-A9 speaker set is $1,800. The SA-SW5 and SA-SW3 subwoofers are $700 and $400 respectively, while the SA-RS3S satellite speakers are $350. That means if you&#39;re expecting to grab a complete setup with the A7000, a soundbar and rear speakers, you&#39;ll need to hand over at least $2,050.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-ht-a9-home-theater-system-140038379.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eb6bcbd5-02de-43de-b014-ee3965ee3c83</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626783534</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T12:19:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Speakers & Headphones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/16aba220-e904-11eb-8eef-dbf21f9eb5f7" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/16aba220-e904-11eb-8eef-dbf21f9eb5f7" width="1200" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony HT-A7000 soundbar]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony HT-A7000 soundbar]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roku sale on Amazon knocks the Streambar down to $99]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ve been fans of Roku streaming devices for a long time thanks to their power, versatility and support for most major streaming services. Those looking to make an old TV in their homes smarter, or upgrade an aging streaming gadget, can do so for less now that many Roku devices are on sale at Amazon. Of note is the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Streambar for $99" href="https://amzn.to/3kD56Du">Roku Streambar for $99</a> — that&#39;s the best price we&#39;ve seen the compact soundbar that also has built-in 4K streaming capabilities. Also discounted are the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Express" href="https://amzn.to/3eyj0mk">Roku Express</a>, now $25, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Express 4K+" href="https://amzn.to/3wPeBBL">Roku Express 4K+</a>, now $29, and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Streaming Stick+" href="https://amzn.to/3xRZRUd">Roku Streaming Stick+</a>, now $39.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Streambar at Amazon - $99" href="https://amzn.to/3kD56Du">Buy Roku Streambar at Amazon - $99</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Express at Amazon - $25" href="https://amzn.to/3eyj0mk">Buy Roku Express at Amazon - $25</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Express 4K+ at Amazon - $29" href="https://amzn.to/3wPeBBL">Buy Roku Express 4K+ at Amazon - $29</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Streaming Stick+ at Amazon - $39" href="https://amzn.to/3xRZRUd">Buy Roku Streaming Stick+ at Amazon - $39</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-streambar-review-133013675.html">Roku Streambar</a> is one of those multipurpose gadgets that succeeds at everything it&#39;s designed to do. It&#39;s a soundbar that&#39;s roughly the size of a carton of eggs, which should make it easy to fit into most TV setups. And despite its small size, it packs a punch when it comes to sound quality. The Streambar makes for a solid upgrade for anyone relying on built-in TV speakers, plus it supports Dolby Audio and works as a Bluetooth speaker as well.</p><p>While you could invest in the Streambar purely for its audio chops, it also has built-in Roku 4K streaming technology — that means it&#39;ll act as both your soundbar and set-top box. If you&#39;re not happy with your current smart TV or you have an old, &quot;dumb&quot; TV set that you don&#39;t want to replace just yet, the Roku Streambar is a good (and affordable) way to make it feel new again.</p><p>Those on tighter budgets may find something even better suited for their setup in Roku&#39;s other discounted devices. The Streaming Stick+ has been a favorite of ours for many years because it gives you 4K HDR streaming in a sleek, portable package. If you can compromise on things like long-range wireless connectivity and remote capabilities, the Express or the Express 4K+ are both inexpensive ways to add streaming features to your TV.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roku-streambar-99-deal-amazon-roku-streaming-devices-sale-134034742.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6a0454e3-eb5d-4470-8825-83747d7d1493</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 13:40:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626786719</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T13:12:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/9ef272e0-1794-11eb-bffd-21e2290ccd64" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/9ef272e0-1794-11eb-bffd-21e2290ccd64" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roku Streambar soundbar on a white table.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roku Streambar]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blue Origin completes its first crewed spaceflight with Bezos onboard]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blue Origin just joined the ranks of private companies that have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-richard-branson-spaceflight-complete-154012847.html">taken people to space</a>. Jeff Bezos&#39; outfit has successfully <a href="https://twitter.com/blueorigin/status/1417475031597260802">completed</a> its first crewed spaceflight, taking Bezos, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-tourist-flight-123407896.html">his brother</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wally-funk-blue-origin-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-155036734.html">Wally Funk</a> and paying customer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-first-paying-customer-151137093.html">Oliver Daemen</a> beyond the Kárman line (62 miles above Earth) before their capsule returned to the desert.  The New Shepard rocket also touched down in what appeared to be a picture-perfect landing.</p><p>The flight broke multiple records. It included both the oldest-ever astronaut (Funk, 82 years old) and the youngest (Daemen, 18 years old). And while Virgin Galactic did enter space first by NASA&#39;s definition, Blue Origin was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-throws-shade-virgin-galactic-133319071.html">more than a little keen</a> to point out that its flight was the only one of the two to cross the Kárman line.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>SpaceX was the first of these companies to take people to space through its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-crew-1-mission-splashdown-record-144301622.html">Crew-1 mission</a>, although it won&#39;t fly an all-civilian crew until <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-inspiration4-mission-full-crew-143428383.html">later this year</a>. Its space tourism plans so far focus on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-09-18-who-is-yusaku-maezawa-spacexs-first-lunar-tourist.html">trips around the Moon</a>, although those aren&#39;t expected to start until 2023.</p><p>The flight clearly involved a large share of bragging rights — it&#39;s yet another instance of a billionaire paying his way into space and marketing his space tourism business. It did represent an important transition for Blue Origin to commercial service after years of uncrewed test flights, though. More importantly, it showed that private human spaceflight is becoming increasingly common. Blue Origin, Virgin and SpaceX were just the vanguards. It&#39;s now just a question of how quickly the industry grows.</p><div id="9f2608b268f74f95b3cc0803abbe8e6a"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tMHhXzpwupU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-completes-first-crewed-spaceflight-132937714.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">64a8a147-b3a9-47e3-b92c-0592ee8d542f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 13:29:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626789259</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T13:54:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/d3f6a880-e95d-11eb-afef-b43a9f3d264d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/d3f6a880-e95d-11eb-afef-b43a9f3d264d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Blue Origin New Shepard capsule touchdown after first human spaceflight]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Blue Origin New Shepard capsule touchdown after first human spaceflight]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple Arcade's upcoming additions include 'Tetris' and 'Monster Hunter' games]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple Arcade is expanding its game selection, and it once again includes a mix of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/final-fantasy-hironobu-sakaguchi-fantasian-interview-apple-arcade-150022942.html">brand new (if familiar) originals</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-expansion-app-store-greats-131859755.html">well-established classics</a>. The all-you-can-play service will &quot;soon&quot; add <em>Tetris Beat</em>, an Arcade original from N3twork that blends Alexei Pajitnov&#39;s line-clearng puzzles with rhythm game elements. The more you keep to the rhythm, the larger your combos get. The soundtrack includes well-known names like Alison Wonderland and Hannah Diamond, among others, so you might enjoy it just for the music.</p><p>The other upcoming title, <em>Monster Hunter Stories</em> (below), will be more than a little familiar — it&#39;s a years-old adaptation of the turn-based Capcom RPG that made its debut on the 3DS. The game flips the usual premise on its head by making you a &quot;rider&quot; that forms ties with some monsters rather than hunting them down.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5c158be0-e955-11eb-be3e-52cf76d3382b" style="height:887;width:1920;" alt="&#39;Monster Hunter Stories&#39; from Apple Arcade on iPhone" data-uuid="6c61c9df-6450-38b6-8332-7b84d6c7a00c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Capcom</div></figure><p>Two more veteran games will join the mix. Halfbrick&#39;s <em>Jetpack Joyride</em> makes the endless runner (flier?) available without worrying so much about in-app purchases, while <em>Neko Atsume</em> offers serene cat collecting as a foil to the other, more frantic games in the collection.</p><p>As before, Apple isn&#39;t counting on any one game to draw you to Arcade. Like past additions, these latest entries are more about making a stronger overall case for Apple&#39;s $5 per month service — you might be more likely to sign up (or get it as part of an Apple One bundle) if you know titles like <em>Tetris Beat</em> and <em>Monster Hunter Stories</em> are just a quick download away.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-tetris-beat-monster-hunter-stories-132138969.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">724b4b11-b192-4b4c-8719-3587ded03e99</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 13:21:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626787301</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T13:22:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f9737f00-e955-11eb-bdf2-3bd131d11f76" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f9737f00-e955-11eb-bdf2-3bd131d11f76" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[N3twork]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['Tetris Beat' from Apple Arcade on an iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Tetris Beat' from Apple Arcade on an iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's AirPods Max drop to $455 at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-max-sale-100-off-adorama-184943075.html">Adorama&#39;s sale</a> on the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:AirPods Max" href="https://amzn.to/3hRsV8x">AirPods Max</a> wireless headphones may have come and gone, but Amazon&#39;s latest sale is almost as good. Every color of Apple&#39;s high-end headphones except for space gray are down to $455 at Amazon right now, and that&#39;s about $94 off their normal price. It&#39;s also only $5 more than a sale we saw at Adorama at the end of last week, so if you missed that chance to grab a pair, you have another opportunity today.&nbsp;</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy AirPods Max at Amazon - $455" href="https://amzn.to/3hRsV8x">Buy AirPods Max at Amazon - $455</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>One of our biggest gripes with the AirPods Max is their price. Normally $550, these are the best headphones Apple has to offer — but despite how much we liked them, we still thought they were on the steep side. We recommend waiting for a sale before taking the plunge as AirPods Max are a much better buy when discounted like this.</p><p>They earned a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/airpods-max-review-143019326.html">score of 84</a> from us in part due to their excellent sound, solid ANC and reliable touch controls. AirPods Max have more balanced sound than competitors, with bass that comes through nicely but isn&#39;t overpowering. The active noise-cancellation on these cans holds its own against that of Bose and Sony devices, even if we slightly prefer the latter two for that feature. The Max also have Transparency Mode, allowing you to easily hop in and out of conversations when necessary. And you&#39;re getting spatial audio support on iPhones, iPads, Macs and soon, Apple TV as well.</p><p>All of that plus the Max&#39;s unique yet elegant design make them <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-headphones-150030794.html">solid wireless headphones</a>, but features brought by their built-in H1 chip make them even better for those living in the Apple ecosystem. In addition to hands-free Siri, you&#39;ll also get quick pairing and switching between all your Apple devices. While still expensive at this sale price, the AirPods Max are a good option for Apple lovers that want a pair of wireless headphones that both sound great and work seamlessly with their devices.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-max-deal-455-amazon-125146678.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f45377e8-7967-4a42-acae-af260c64868d</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 12:51:46 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626784932</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T12:42:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0d1209b0-e955-11eb-9bf6-9f7105bc098b" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0d1209b0-e955-11eb-9bf6-9f7105bc098b" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple&#39;s AirPods Max drop to $455 at Amazon]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The best budget TVs and streaming gadgets for students]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Listen up, students: You can do better than watching movies on your laptop in bed. If you want to truly be immersed in a film (or game, or TV show), nothing beats a large TV. And it turns out, you don&#39;t have to invest thousands to get started with a decent dorm entertainment system. LCD sets and streaming devices are cheaper than ever. So save that notebook for schoolwork — consider these inexpensive ways to upgrade your movie watching experience.</p><h2>TVs for smaller spaces</h2><h3>43-inch TCL 4 Series Roku TV</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e534c080-df41-11eb-9fbf-33f2a2b1ca95" alt="TCL	4 Series 43" data-uuid="b3cd548f-ec09-332d-8cf7-af7822638522"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography / TCL</div></figure><p>A Roku TV is one of the easiest ways to just start streaming movies and TV, making them ideal for most students. This <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:4-series TCL model" href="https://amzn.to/3A6X3nC">4-series TCL model</a> sports a 4K screen (with upscaling from lower-res sources) and HDR, for better dynamic range. But best of all, you can usually find it for around $300. It&#39;s not the most feature-packed TCL Roku TV (the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:5-series" href="https://amzn.to/3hcXfZU">5-series</a> costs around $100 more and adds Dolby Vision), but it&#39;s one of the best options around for its price. And at 43 inches, it&#39;s small enough to fit in most dorm rooms, while still offering enough screen space to immerse you in a film.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy 42-inch TCL 4 Series Roku TV at Amazon - $348" href="https://amzn.to/3A6X3nC">Buy 42-inch TCL 4 Series Roku TV at Amazon - $348</a></p><h3>32-inch Vizio D-Series</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e5386a00-df41-11eb-bfea-9098a93f13a8" alt="Vizio 32" data-uuid="ac29889e-7e20-3429-be9b-548b72ac4d6e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography / Vizio</div></figure><p>The “D” in Vizio&#39;s D-series sets might as well stand for &quot;dirt cheap.&quot; But this <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:32-inch model" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/LPnyAL">32-inch model</a> is still pretty impressive for the price. It has full-array LED backlighting, Vizio&#39;s streaming channels, and it supports Google Chromecast and Apple AirPlay. Plus, judging from the reviews, it doesn&#39;t look too bad either, even if it is limited to a 1,366 x 768 resolution. It&#39;s a solid option for very small spaces.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy 32-inch Vizio D-series smart TV at Best Buy - $219" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/LPnyAL">Buy 32-inch Vizio D-series smart TV at Best Buy - $219</a></p><h2>Bigger and better TVs</h2><h3>50-inch Vizio M-Series Quantum</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e5347260-df41-11eb-aefe-ecca765b0b37" alt="Vizio 50" data-uuid="29c99f04-f6f6-3e90-861f-066704daa3d2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography / Vizio</div></figure><p>If you want a 50-inch screen that looks fantastic but doesn&#39;t break the bank, it&#39;s hard to do better than <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Vizio&#39;s M-Series Quantum sets" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/jWzGxv">Vizio&#39;s M-Series Quantum sets</a>. They&#39;re infused with quantum dots, for more robust color reproduction; they offer full-array backlighting, for better contrast and black levels; and they&#39;re equipped with AMD&#39;s FreeSync technology to smooth out gameplay. The M-series also features Dolby Vision HDR and support for Chromecast and AirPlay 2, so you can cast video from most smartphones. With slim bezels along three sides, the M-series also looks far more premium than other cheap TVs.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy 50-inch Vizio M-series at Best Buy - $429" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/jWzGxv">Buy 50-inch Vizio M-series at Best Buy - $429</a></p><h3>50-inch Samsung Class Crystal</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e531da50-df41-11eb-b4fb-9cac9efe5a01" alt="Samsung	50" data-uuid="ccdaf3bf-c57c-3fb1-a413-aebcb74d5bc9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>Another solid option for a larger set, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Samsung&#39;s Class Crystal TVs" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/QOJvVP">Samsung&#39;s Class Crystal TVs</a> feature the company&#39;s Crystal 4K processor, which is focused on delivering solid image quality at a budget price. It doesn&#39;t have Dolby Vision or quantum dots, so in general we&#39;d recommend the Vizio M-series over this model. <em>But</em>, Samsung&#39;s hardware does look a bit nicer, so it may be a better option if you value form over function.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy 50-inch Samsung Class Crystal TV at Best Buy - $479" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/QOJvVP">Buy 50-inch Samsung Class Crystal TV at Best Buy - $479</a></p><h2>Must-have streaming accessories</h2><h3>Chromecast with Google TV</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/c7402f00-df42-11eb-9ff7-2ea8b70fb339" alt="The Google Chromecast with Google TV for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="651cc157-32b0-3121-b615-85949dc0d75e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>If you&#39;re a heavy Google user, there&#39;s no better streaming device than the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Chromecast with Google TV" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/EaqBjn">Chromecast with Google TV</a>. Unlike previous versions of Google&#39;s puck, it has an interface of its own, along with a suite of streaming apps to choose from. And yes, you can still cast video from Android devices or the Chrome browser. The Chromecast is a great option if you&#39;re buying a cheaper TV, but be sure to check if your set already has Chromecast streaming built in.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Chromecast with Google TV at Best Buy - $50" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/EaqBjn">Buy Chromecast with Google TV at Best Buy - $50</a></p><h3>Roku Streaming Stick+</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/efb5d980-df42-11eb-befe-31376789f519" alt="The Roku Streaming Stick+ for Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="beaf65f0-c063-31fd-8030-6c4ceacd7e0d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>If you own an older TV, or you just want something a bit zippier than your set&#39;s onboard apps, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku&#39;s Streaming Stick+" href="https://amzn.to/3A4Q7HF">Roku&#39;s Streaming Stick+</a> is worth snapping up. It&#39;s just $50 (and often less), supports 4K/HDR, and it gives you access to Roku&#39;s entire app library. Best of all, though, it&#39;s so tiny you can easily bring it along when you&#39;re traveling. The Streaming Stick+ also supports Apple AirPlay, giving you a way to cast video from iOS devices and Macs. Roku&#39;s bundled voice remote also makes it easy to search for things to watch without pecking away at a keyboard.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Streaming Stick+ at Amazon - $50" href="https://amzn.to/3A4Q7HF">Buy Roku Streaming Stick+ at Amazon - $50</a></p><h3>Roku Streambar</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e5318c30-df41-11eb-9fff-615cf490d3ea" alt="Roku Streambar for the Engadget 2021 Back to School guide." data-uuid="5ae12863-3cbe-3582-b0b4-d0ffae7c316f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Streambar" href="https://amzn.to/3hhrLl8">Streambar</a> is an unusual device. It&#39;s both a decent soundbar <em>and </em>a media streaming box. That&#39;s just so Roku. Honestly, if you&#39;re picking up a TV, you should really consider a soundbar of some kind. (We have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-23-the-best-soundbar-in-2019.html">a whole guide dedicated to that</a>.) But we&#39;re recommending the Streambar here because it&#39;s a relatively simple and inexpensive solution that solves two common pain points: getting streaming apps and better sound. It&#39;s also a nice thing to have around to play a bit of music when you&#39;re not watching anything. For even bigger sound, you might also want to consider the slightly pricier <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Streambar Pro" href="https://amzn.to/3k7ER7E">Streambar Pro</a>.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Roku Streambar at Amazon - $129" href="https://amzn.to/3hhrLl8">Buy Roku Streambar at Amazon - $129</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-budget-home-entertainment-streaming-devices-cheap-tvs-for-students-123020749.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5004b660-2d56-4c79-b4cd-ae44ab3fa94d</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 12:30:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626792135</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T14:42:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Video Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e5386a00-df41-11eb-be5f-e8c6404b1560" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e5386a00-df41-11eb-be5f-e8c6404b1560" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Will Lipman Photography for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A collection of products for the Engadget 2021 Back to School guide home entertainment section.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Home Entertainment gear (lead)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Louis Vuitton's $2,890 light-up speaker looks like a UFO]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Louis Vuitton&#39;s forays into tech-infused luxury gear have taken in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-10-louis-vuitton-flexible-screens-prototype-handbags-lv-cruise-2020.html">handbags with screens</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-04-louis-vuitton-pricey-tracker-for-designer-luggage.html">luggage trackers</a>. A year after the release of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-17-louis-vuitton-true-wireless-earbuds.html">$1,000 earbuds</a>, the French fashion house&#39;s latest stab at audio is as eccentric as they come. The new LV Horizon Light Up Speaker looks like a spaceship sculpted by aliens to resemble a sawn-off spinning top. What&#39;s more, it costs $2,890, but you knew it wouldn&#39;t come cheap.&nbsp;</p><p>Inspired by its Toupie handbag, the speaker lights up to accentuate the brand&#39;s flower insignia and a spelled out Louis Vuitton around the center. There&#39;s also a top ring light with 23 LEDs that puts on a rainbow color show. The neons combined with the black perforated and embossed leather is best described as cyber-chic.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/51d1ca00-e954-11eb-9eee-f35ca07b8f5b" alt="Louis Vuitton" data-uuid="8b659fa7-7d75-3d9f-80b3-5b9115e1e05b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Louis Vuitton</div></figure><p>But, if you&#39;re going to splurge just shy of $3,000 on a speaker, you probably want it to sound good. The Horizon features a 3-inch woofer paired with two 0.75-inch tweeters that LV says combine to offer 360-degree sound. Though, the jury&#39;s out on whether it can match the immersive audio touted by the likes of the $700 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-srs-ra5000-review-150011735.html">Sony SRS-RA5000</a>. If the mid-range Qualcomm QCS 404 chipset inside is anything to go by, it may not offer the big sound you&#39;d associate with its price tag. It also comes with three mics in case you want to take calls on the glowing mothership on your desk.</p><p>The conical shape means the speaker sits on its side, which doesn&#39;t impact the sound as it can apparently &quot;adapt to its orientation.&quot; Just don&#39;t leave it on a sloping surface. To avoid any (expensive) accidents, the Horizon comes with an accompanying dock that you can rest it in. Being wireless, it works with Bluetooth and supports Apple AirPlay to boot. You can purchase the speaker now from Louis Vuitton&#39;s <a href="https://us.louisvuitton.com/eng-us/products/louis-vuitton-horizon-light-up-speaker-nvprod2900129v">online store</a>.</p><div id="2ce558d1430d413c9877d961cd64f5e8"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-79cvOzcuJI?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/louis-vuitton-horizon-speaker-ufo-122944145.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3001f5e3-a88b-4133-9f2a-0c18d5041c93</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626784282</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T12:31:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/38944d60-e954-11eb-afe2-d48656d05ac1" width="1987" height="1269" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/38944d60-e954-11eb-afe2-d48656d05ac1" width="1987" height="1269" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Louis Vuitton]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Louis Vuitton]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Louis Vuitton]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The RadRover 6 Plus is a 'durable' $1,999 e-bike with a 750W motor]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The pandemic proved a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/electric-bicycle-scooter-market-popularity-sales-coronavirus-2020-150041480.html">boon</a> for electric bicycle makers, not least <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/rad%20power%20bikes">Rad Power Bikes</a>. The company claims to be North America&#39;s largest e-bike brand with 350,000 riders on the road. Those figures helped it to secure $150 million in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/rad-power-bikes-raises-150-million-as-electric-bike-sales-boom/">funding</a> from big name investors like Morgan Stanley earlier this year. Naturally, it&#39;s using that cash to do what it does best: Make more e-bikes. Rad&#39;s latest offering is the $1,999 RadRover 6 Plus, an overhauled version of its flagship durable bike.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5127ba40-e947-11eb-8bdd-35e3a72480ef" style="height:2000;width:3000;" alt="RadRover 6 Plus" data-uuid="62da6efa-de10-393d-93bf-6d406b8f15cb"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Rad Power Bikes</div></figure><p>The first thing you&#39;ll probably notice are the fat tires, an attribute carried over from the first iteration in 2015. But, look closer and you should spot several noticeable changes. Firstly, there are the all-new hydraulic disc brakes for more stopping power (a first for a Rad bike). The plus-sized RadRover also features a custom geared hub motor that provides 750W of power, compared to 500W on the $999 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rad-power-launches-a-lightweight-ebike-for-999-140004049.html">RadMission Electric Metro Bike</a> and $1,099 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rad-power-bikes-radmission-electric-bicycle-review-120020625.html">RadMission 1.</a> For off-road enthusiasts, that apparently means the bike can climb hills 25 percent faster than its predecessor.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Here, the battery is also semi-integrated instead of external. That effectively allows you to swap it out with the turn of a key. A new two-part display, meanwhile, shows real-time stats such as battery charge status, power output, trip mileage, time and a headlight indicator.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/86aa9c50-e947-11eb-bc7f-4b3aa88da49f" style="height:2000;width:3000;" alt="RadRover 6 Plus" data-uuid="8677c1d7-9471-38b1-ac4f-219b105857f3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Rad Power Bikes</div></figure><p>Overall, Rad pitches the new RadRover as its everyday bike that&#39;s versatile enough for grocery trips, commutes and trails. Which may explain why it costs more than some of its lightweight alternatives. In keeping with its focus on flexibility, the e-bike has two frame sizes (high-step and step-thru) to cater to a wider range of heights. The RadRover 6 Plus is available to pre-order today in the US and Canada.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/radrover-6-plus-ebike-120056788.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">da495c4c-04a9-4f99-8f08-e1c978dd48ff</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626779052</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T11:04:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/1df69490-e940-11eb-9737-afa020043d52" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/1df69490-e940-11eb-9737-afa020043d52" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rad Power Bikes]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Rad Power Bikes]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Rad Power Bikes]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch Blue Origin’s first crewed spaceflight at 9AM ET]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jeff Bezos is about to go to space, along with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-tourist-flight-123407896.html">his brother</a> Mark and the youngest and oldest people to venture above the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-throws-shade-virgin-galactic-133319071.html">Kármán line</a>. Blue Origin&#39;s first passenger flight <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-first-flight-july-20-174559828.html">takes place today</a>, and you&#39;ll be able to watch New Shepard&#39;s latest trip to space from the Texas desert as it happens.&nbsp;</p><p>Blue Origin owner and former Amazon CEO Bezos <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wally-funk-blue-origin-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-155036734.html">invited Wally Funk</a> to join the mission. Funk is an 82-year-old aviation pioneer who was one of 13 women who trained for space missions as part of a program back in the 1960s. None of the Mercury 13 have ever made it to space until now.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The other passenger seat will be filled by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-first-paying-customer-151137093.html">18-year-old Oliver Daemen</a>, who is New Shepard&#39;s first paying customer. The person who won <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-new-shepherd-seat-auction-winner-182036391.html">the $28 million auction</a> for the fourth spot decided to take a trip on New Shepard at a later date due to &quot;scheduling conflicts.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>You can watch the flight live via the stream below. Liftoff is scheduled for 9AM ET and the flight should last for around 12 minutes.</p><div id="9aaf5387c997427da3c48583588a19e2"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vadX1PSaxF8?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/how-to-watch-blue-origin-first-passenger-flight-jeff-bezos-120008011.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dc36af61-ce2e-412e-b731-c80d60aeb0cf</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626784584</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T12:36:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/169ede90-c79f-11eb-bcfe-5663964c6361" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/169ede90-c79f-11eb-bcfe-5663964c6361" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Isaiah Downing / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A general view of the Blue Origin New Shepard rocket booster at the 33rd Space Symposium in Colorado Springs, Colorado, United States April 5, 2017.  REUTERS/Isaiah J. Downing]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SPACE-BEZOS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Casio made a vintage Pac-Man version of its A100 digital watch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Casio has <a href="https://www.casio-watches.com/sp/a100wepc/ja/">unveiled</a> a new digital watch made in collaboration with Bandai Namco, paying homage to not one but two digital classics from the late &#39;70s and early &#39;80s. The A100WEPC Pac-Man edition has a design based on the Casio&#39;s F-100 digital watch from 1978, and celebrates one of the most famous games of all time: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pac-man-99-nintendo-switch-012341338.html">Pac-Man</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The F-100 was one of the most advanced watches you could buy at the time, offering a stopwatch, digital alarm and calendar features. It was also the first watch with a resin case, as Casio notes in a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pac-man-99-nintendo-switch-012341338.html">press release</a>. It&#39;s perhaps most famous for being the watch worn by Ripley and other characters from the 1979 movie <em>Alien</em>.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="35cc8fcdb0034308b396a46fdf5c2577"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YwNRscWmf2w?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The A100WEPC reprises that with the same four-button layout. At the same time, the watch face features the Pac-Man and ghost characters, with the center illuminator logo rendered with the Pac-Man font. The face replicates the Pac-Man game screen, while the top watch band is laser etched with a Pac-Man character being chased by ghosts, with the reverse on the bottom band. It comes with special packaging featuring the Pac-Man characters and game score screen.&nbsp;</p><p>Casio&#39;s watch isn&#39;t the first with a Pac-Man theme, as the $79 Timex T80 x Pac-Man also fetes the retro title. However, since Casio pairs it with a watch design from the same period, it&#39;s perhaps a bit more desirable for fans of the game.&nbsp;</p><p>The base AW100WE model, which <a href="https://www.g-central.com/all-new-casio-a100-is-a-tribute-to-the-f-100-watch-from-alien/">came out last month</a>, offers water resistance, a 1/10 second stopwatch, daily alarm, hourly time signal, auto-calendar and LED light. It&#39;s scheduled to be released in August in Japan for ¥12,100, or about $110 — a relative bargain for enthusiastic Pac-Man fans.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/casio-unveils-the-pac-man-edition-a-100-digital-watch-113542602.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2055f840-25e3-4448-955b-32fa9c6c019f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:35:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626780746</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T11:32:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/4dfa2b90-e948-11eb-96ff-825c767167ab" width="1840" height="953" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/4dfa2b90-e948-11eb-96ff-825c767167ab" width="1840" height="953" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Casio]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Casio unveils the Pac-Man edition A100 digital watch]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Casio unveils the Pac-Man edition A100 digital watch]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: The best laptops for students going back to school]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s another strange and unusual year for students, but it’s time to start preparing for another one, and our team has been picking out the best PCs and other tech to make academic life a little easier. Our 2021 Back To School guide kicks off with our guide to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-laptops-for-students-130054631.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">best laptops for students</a>, as well as a guide to more humbly priced gadgets and things <a href="https://www.engadget.com/school-tech-under-50-140026676.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">for under $50.</a></p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-laptops-for-students-130054631.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7e73d400-df2b-11eb-8b7d-224d93864217" alt="Three laptops against a bright colorful background." data-uuid="22671198-eba8-36de-afc2-4d717db2c689"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Will Lipman Photography for Engadget</div></figure></a><p>I don’t want to spoil everything, but we’ll cover budget TVs for college students, educational toys for younger learners and even the best student discounts we’ve found for 2021.</p><p></p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/warby-parker-virtual-vision-test-app-150052775.html">Warby Parker&#39;s vision test app can help renew your glasses prescription</a></h2><h3>You might not need to visit a clinic.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/warby-parker-virtual-vision-test-app-150052775.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/44b52200-e647-11eb-a99f-f4b5901a325f" alt="Warby Parker Virtual Vision Test app for iPhone" data-uuid="3874e700-57d1-34b5-bf38-d1e83707a03e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Warby Parker</div></figure></a><p>Warby Parker is turning its Prescription Check app into the Virtual Vision Test, and it’ll offer a way to renew your glasses or contact lens prescription using only an iPhone and your existing eyewear. Prop up your phone, stand 10 feet away and you can walk through a familiar &quot;can you read this&quot; test that will gauge whether or not your glasses or contacts need updating. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/warby-parker-virtual-vision-test-app-150052775.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ps4-farm-fifa-ultimate-team-accounts-cryptocurrency-182654013.html">PS4 &#39;crypto farm&#39; reportedly used bots to grind in-game FIFA currency</a></h2><h3>Instead of crypto, the consoles were mining FIFA Ultimate Team accounts for profit.</h3><p></p><p>You might recall that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/cryptofarm-ps-4-pro-raided-ukraine-045118233.html">crypto farm bust</a> last week in the Ukraine, where thousands of PS4s were rigged to run on stolen electricity. Well, according to local news outlet Delo, it wasn’t crypto but FIFA the machines were churning through. PCs were running bots on the consoles to play FIFA and automatically earn in-game currency. Although buying or selling FIFA coins with real money is against EA policies, that hasn&#39;t stopped a thriving black market for the digital currency. One site offers PS4 FIFA 21 account with 5.1 million coins for $300.</p><p>Illegal third-party sellers aren’t the only ones making bank. Last year, EA made $1.62 billion from the Ultimate Team franchise, which accounted for 29 percent of its net revenue for the fiscal year. &quot;A substantial portion&quot; of that revenue came from FIFA games. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ps4-farm-fifa-ultimate-team-accounts-cryptocurrency-182654013.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-147-magsafe-battery-pack-apple-card-podcasts-homepod-192323154.html">Apple launches iOS 14.7 with support for its new MagSafe Battery Pack</a></h2><h3>And you can merge two Apple Cards into a co-managed account.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-147-magsafe-battery-pack-apple-card-podcasts-homepod-192323154.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/a4f836d0-e402-11eb-b77f-32ac984a1efc" alt="iPhone 12 MagSafe Battery Pack" data-uuid="fdc9145c-55fe-37da-88ea-4674ffa036a8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure></a><p>The latest version of iOS 14 adds a few useful but relatively minor features, such as support for the new MagSafe Battery Pack on iPhone 12. There&#39;s an option to merge two Apple Cards into a co-owned account with a combined credit limit.</p><p>There&#39;s also a new filter in the Podcasts library that allows you to see all shows or only the ones you follow. Oh, and did I mention you can subscribe to this very newsletter in its audio form <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-morning-after/id1476318243?l">right here</a>? <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-147-magsafe-battery-pack-apple-card-podcasts-homepod-192323154.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/cnn-plus-streaming-service-launch-153702038.html https://www.engadget.com/...">CNN+ will offer live and on-demand content in early 2022</a></h2><h3>The new service will include original shows and movies.</h3><h3></h3><p>CNN has unveiled its rumored streaming service and says it will offer a blend of live and on-demand shows that are &quot;separate and distinct&quot; from its existing TV coverage. It will debut sometime in the first quarter of 2022. While CNN hasn&#39;t narrowed down the price, lead executive Andrew Morse told <em>Variety</em> there wouldn&#39;t be an ad-supported tier at launch.<strong>&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.engadget.com/cnn-plus-streaming-service-launch-153702038.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>But wait, there’s more...</h2><h2></h2><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-join-group-calls-in-progress-160026130.html">WhatsApp now lets you join in-progress group calls</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-tv-update-features-from-google-tv-160004195.html">Android TV gets new Google TV features</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/ocado-robot-collision-fire-114027027.html">A robot collision sparked a fire at the UK&#39;s top online grocer</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tencent-sumo-acquisition-091425058.html">Tencent to buy British video game studio Sumo for $1.27 billion</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-shows-wolfenstein-youngblood-running-rtx-ray-tracing-on-arm-130037247.html">NVIDIA shows &#39;Wolfenstein: Youngblood&#39; with RTX ray-tracing on ARM</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-air-amazon-deal-105043941.html">Engadget Deals: Apple&#39;s latest iPad Airs fall to all-time lows at Amazon</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-111537965.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4d5b28e4-99a1-4139-88be-960f5c89cba3</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:15:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626776971</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T10:29:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0bd919b0-e943-11eb-afd9-5a11e0c5fdef" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0bd919b0-e943-11eb-afd9-5a11e0c5fdef" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Morning After: The best laptops for students going back to school]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google's Wear OS update makes apps easier to find and download]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has been giving <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Wear%20OS">Wear OS</a> some much needed attention of late. In the lead up to the launch of its new smartwatch <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-one-ui-watch-wear-os-details-171505347.html">software collab with Samsung</a>, Google has been focusing on apps. First it made <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-youtube-music-app-wear-os-051417768.html">YouTube Music</a> available on Wear OS and now it&#39;s making apps easier to find and download.&nbsp;</p><p>As part of a new Play Store update for Android phones and smartwatches, users will see new search filters and category pages on handsets that highlight &quot;watch&quot; apps or &quot;watch faces.&quot; You&#39;ll also be able to remotely install your chosen software or visuals.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, the Play Store on Wear OS is getting a new look in keeping with Google&#39;s Material You design. The aim is to make navigation more simple in the display&#39;s restricted surface area. As a result, Google is placing important info in cards to make it easier to read and make a selection. If you decide to buy, the Play Store will also prompt you to open a purchase page on your Android phone or the web to complete the purchase.</p><p>Google said the updates will roll out in the coming weeks to Android phones and watches running Wear OS version 2.x and up.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-wear-os-update-apps-103556477.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c96e5077-1ef5-43fa-ab2e-3f26a571860c</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 10:35:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626774490</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T09:48:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/98709010-e93e-11eb-ae64-2a7389d4858c" width="2000" height="1196" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/98709010-e93e-11eb-ae64-2a7389d4858c" width="2000" height="1196" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Wear OS]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Wear OS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's Kindle sale slashes up to 35 percent off its popular e-readers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you weren&#39;t able to snag an e-reader last month during <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-amazon-devices-deals-prime-day-2021-echo-speakers-fire-tablets-fire-tv-kindle-eero-blink-070926873.html">Prime Day</a>, Amazon has a standalone sale on its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-10-amazon-kindle-review-2019.html">base Kindle</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-13-kindle-paperwhite-review-2018.html">Paperwhite models</a> that could get you onboard for almost the same price. The biggest discount is on the Kindle Paperwhite (ad-supported), Amazon&#39;s waterproof e-reader with a better-contrast display. You can now pick up the 8GB model for $85 (35 percent off the regular $130 price), or $105 for the 32GB model, a savings of $55 or 34 percent.&nbsp;</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Kindle Paperwhite 8GB at Amazon - $85" href="https://amzn.to/3BkpXkO">Buy Kindle Paperwhite 8GB at Amazon - $85</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Kindle Paperwhite 32GB at Amazon - $105" href="https://amzn.to/3eDo3lD">Buy Kindle Paperwhite 32GB at Amazon - $105</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The latest Paperwhite is waterproof with an IPX8 rating, so it can tolerate being immersed in up to two meters of water for as long as an hour — making bathtub or beach reading stress free. We also noted in our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-13-kindle-paperwhite-review-2018.html">review</a> that it has a better-contrast display than previous models and offers both Audible and Bluetooth support. The drawbacks are the lack of MP3 and text-to-speech support, along with a high price — but this sale takes some sting off the latter.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/a57b5370-e93a-11eb-8fef-a228ecee935b" style="height:506;width:675;" alt="Amazon is offering up to 35 percent off its Kindle e-readers" data-uuid="f0a9a533-49ec-3c46-82a1-256db864be69"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>If it&#39;s a standard Kindle you&#39;re after (above), we have good news there, too. The regular ad-supported model is on sale for $60, a discount of $30 from the regular $90 price. If you need one for the younger set, you can pick up the Kindle Kids Edition for $70, for a savings of 36 percent or $40.&nbsp;</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Kindle at Amazon - $60" href="https://amzn.to/2UswjxU">Buy Kindle at Amazon - $60</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Kindle Kids Edition at Amazon - $70" href="https://amzn.to/3kFwbWr">Buy Kindle Kids Edition at Amazon - $70</a></p><p>The latest Kindle models offer a lot for that price, including an LED-lit screen, weeks of reading time and a touch interface. The Kids Edition adds some perks, like one of four colorful cases, a two-year worry-free guarantee and a year of complimentary access to the company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-12-05-amazon-kindle-freetime-unlimited.html">FreeTime Unlimited service</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Unlike the Paperwhite, the Kindle isn&#39;t water-resistant and offers a lower-density 167ppi (rather than 300ppi) display. If you&#39;re not fussy about those things, however, you can put the extra money saved toward your library of books.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-is-offering-up-to-35-percent-off-its-kindle-e-readers-100536845.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c8271469-fb6c-47de-9ffd-735f53072783</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626772860</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T09:21:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/d9cc6910-e936-11eb-abf9-db886d4a3866" width="1800" height="1157" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/d9cc6910-e936-11eb-abf9-db886d4a3866" width="1800" height="1157" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon is offering up to 35 percent off its Kindle e-readers]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon is offering up to 35 percent off its Kindle e-readers]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple reportedly delays office return as US COVID-19 cases rise]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple bosses had been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-employees-return-to-the-office-september-060428094.html">pushing</a> for employees to get back into the office in September, but they may have changed their tune due to a resurgence in COVID-19 cases. According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-20/apple-will-postpone-return-to-office-after-covid-19-persists"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>, the company is delaying its return-to-office deadline by about a month and won&#39;t be expecting employees to start working out of its facilities again until October at the earliest. It&#39;s reportedly a response to the recent uptick in coronavirus cases due to the spread of the highly transmissible Delta variant in the US and around the world.</p><p>Apple originally wanted to implement a hybrid workplace arrangement starting in September, wherein most employees will be expected to show up at the office for three days a week at a minimum.  &quot;Video conference calling has narrowed the distance between us, to be sure, but there are things it simply cannot replicate,&quot; Tim Cook reportedly wrote in an internal email.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22584761/apple-return-to-office-delayed-covid-delta-variant"><em>The Verge</em></a> reports, staff members tried to push back and sent the company a letter asking it to rethink its &quot;location-flexible work policy&quot; and to embrace remote work for the sake of inclusion and diversity. However,  Apple execs insisted back then that &quot;in-person collaboration is essential to [the company&#39;s] culture and... future.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p><em>Bloomberg</em> notes that Apple is one of the first tech giants is the US to delay its return to office. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-sundar-pichai-hybrid-work-week-plan-225637951.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s adopting a hybrid work week back in May, but it expects 20 percent of its workforce to continue working from home full time. As for Facebook, CEO Mark Zuckerberg previously said that he expects 50 percent of his employees to work from home within the next five to ten years. While Apple doesn&#39;t have a new data for its hybrid workplace implementation, <em>Bloomberg&#39;s</em> sources said that the company will give employees a month&#39;s notice in advance before they&#39;re expected to go back to work in the office.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-reportedly-delay-employees-return-to-office-093544574.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0faa7486-2de3-42e9-82c7-798777b2f53c</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 09:35:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626785341</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T12:49:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Employment & Career]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/43b5c0b0-e937-11eb-bfef-7247e8383bfc" width="3600" height="2400" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/43b5c0b0-e937-11eb-bfef-7247e8383bfc" width="3600" height="2400" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Emma McIntyre via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[WEST HOLLYWOOD, CALIFORNIA - JULY 15: Apple CEO Tim Cook attends Apple's "Ted Lasso" season two premiere at Pacific Design Center on July 15, 2021 in West Hollywood, California. (Photo by Emma McIntyre/WireImage)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple's "Ted Lasso" Season 2 Premiere - Arrivals]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Peloton launches its first exercise game for connected bike owners]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-18-ring-fit-adventure-nintendo-switch-review-video.html"><em>Ring Fit Adventure</em></a> for the Switch was a reminder that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-is-selling-way-more-switches-than-it-predicted-083640962.html">people like</a> gamified workouts. Now, Peloton is jumping in to the arena with its first fitness game titled &quot;<a href="https://www.onepeloton.com/press/articles/peloton-lanebreak">Lanebreak</a>.&quot; The rhythm-based game is available on the fitness company&#39;s stationary bikes and has a simple setup: Players control a rolling tire on a track by pedalling and switching lanes with the resistance knob in the face of multiple obstacles. This being Peloton, the entire game is synchronized to a music soundtrack. It will all look very familiar to anyone who&#39;s played procedurally-generated music racer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Audiosurf"><em>Audiosurf</em></a>.</p><p><em>Lanebreak</em> is the culmination of months of trials that saw select users playing mini games in two-week pilots. The idea is to export some of the core mechanics of gaming, chiefly rewards and progression, to incentivize Peloton members to exercise more. Music, according to Peloton, acts as the DNA that links its regular exercise classes with its new game in a bid to acclimatize novice players. For now, <em>Lanebreak</em> is still in early access mode with a full launch planned for this winter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The challenge is that there are plenty of fitness gaming rivals in the wild, though few have the brand recognition to match Peloton. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/zwift">Zwift</a>, for instance, offers an app with multiplayer cycling and running in a virtual world that users can interact with using their personal treadmill or bike trainer. While VR workout software<a href="https://www.engadget.com/supernatural-vr-workout-app-beat-saber-chris-milk-130014895.html"> Supernatural</a> transports you to exotic settings for its <em>Beat Saber</em>-style routines.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/peloton-exercise-game-bike-090808077.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3ee3f588-0626-4350-88ad-4baa92c059aa</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 09:08:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626772091</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T09:08:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/ff4ea7b0-e937-11eb-b3fb-ec1d260da945" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/ff4ea7b0-e937-11eb-b3fb-ec1d260da945" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Peloton]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Peloton]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Peloton]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deezer's 360 degree audio comes to Sony Reality Audio speakers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-28-deezer-app-360-reality-audio.html">360 by Deezer</a> app, Deezer decided to adopt <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-15-sony-360-reality-audio-launch.html">Sony&#39;s 360 Reality</a> audio format rather than Dolby Atmos. That format delivers surround sound not just on headphones but Chromecast-enabled speakers like, say, Sony&#39;s 360-enabled SRS-RA5000 and RA3000 models. Now, Deezer has announced that it is supporting those two very models with its new casting feature.&nbsp;</p><p>If you subscribe to Deezer&#39;s premium HiFi tier and own either the Sony RA5000 or RA3000, you&#39;ll just need to get the latest 360 by Deezer app, pick a track and select the &quot;cast&quot; button in the top right hand corner. Though it&#39;s just a single speaker, you&#39;ll here different parts of the song as different independent sound &quot;objects,&quot; Deezer said, with vocals and instruments &quot;placed in positions in a virtual auditorium to create a truly immersive experience for the listener.&quot;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Deezer originally launched the app in 2019 with 1,000 tracks, and said that library is growing with new albums from David Bowie, Doja Cat and Alicia Keyes. You can now find dedicated 360 editorial playlists in the app&#39;s recommendation page, including Deezer&#39;s &quot;360 Sessions&quot; playlist with live performances from Dua Lipa, Anne-Marie, Circa Waves and others.&nbsp;</p><p>Sony&#39;s 360 Reality Audio was already available on the RA5000 and RA3000 speakers via Chromecast on Amazon Music and Tidal. Now that it&#39;s on Deezer as well, Sony has a pretty solid base of streaming services using its surround sound tech.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/deezers-360-degree-audio-comes-to-sony-reality-audio-speakers-via-chromecast-080059236.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a9b4558e-845d-488f-8152-4871bac3237b</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626768257</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T08:04:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2d942b10-e92c-11eb-bf7b-f2c7e95c9892" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2d942b10-e92c-11eb-bf7b-f2c7e95c9892" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Deezer's 360 degree audio comes to Sony Reality Audio speakers via Chromecast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Deezer's 360 degree audio comes to Sony Reality Audio speakers via Chromecast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google extends Pixel 4 XL's repair warranty for a year in some regions]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google will fix your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-21-google-pixel-4-and-4-xl-review-motion-sense-cameras.html">Pixel 4 XL</a> phone for free for up to a year after your warranty expires, provided you live in the US, Singapore, Canada, Japan and Taiwan. The tech giant has <a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/10169830">launched</a> an extended repair program for the larger version of its 2019 flagship device, which features motion gesture support and built-in radar. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-4-xl-flagship-phones-discontinued-store-130357276.html">stopped selling</a> the Pixel 4 and the Pixel 4 XL from its own store in August 2020, but they&#39;re still available from retail partners until supplies last. While this program can get you free repairs if you&#39;re in one of the eligible regions, it only covers specific power-related issues.</p><p>In particular, the issues must be related to not being able to switch on your phone  and to having trouble charging with an adapter or a wireless charger. If your phone keeps restarting or shutting down without you doing it or if your battery drains significantly faster than before, you could get free repair under the program, as well. In Canada, Japan and Taiwan, you could even get a free replacement. That said, you can&#39;t get a free repair or replacement if you purchased your device from Australia, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy Spain or the UK, even if you&#39;re in one of the eligible locations.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Make sure to check Google&#39;s <a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/10169830">FAQ page</a> for more information on how you can take advantage of the program in your location. In the US, you&#39;d have to bring your device to a uBreakiFix location or access Google&#39;s <a href="https://store.google.com/us/repaircenter">repair center website</a> to start the process.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-4-x-ls-repair-warranty-extension-063237385.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">619e62f5-227f-423d-a432-980b38bd7e66</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 06:32:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626764511</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T07:02:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/93493ac0-e91f-11eb-ae26-dc1868059fb8" width="2400" height="1342" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/93493ac0-e91f-11eb-ae26-dc1868059fb8" width="2400" height="1342" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM announces third electric pickup after the Hummer and Silverado EVs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>GM is working on another electric pickup truck in addition to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gmcs-newly-unveiled-hummer-ev-suv-is-830-hp-of-electric-supertruck-220323684.html">GMC&#39;s Hummer EV</a> and the electrified <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chevrolet-electric-silverado-043134066.html">Chevrolet Silverado</a> it confirmed back in April. The automotive giant has made the announcement at a media event, according to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/19/gm-confirms-third-electric-pickup-truck-ahead-of-hummer-ev-production.html"><em>CNBC</em></a> and <a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/gmc-electric-pickup/"><em>CNET Roadshow</em></a>. It didn&#39;t reveal a lot of details about the project and only showed a shadowy image of a tarp-covered truck during the presentation, but it did say that it would be a full-size GMC pickup.</p><p>Also, <em>CNBC</em> says it&#39;s expected to be a more &quot;traditional&quot; pickup than the Hummer EV, which is a &quot;lifestyle&quot; vehicle. That could mean that it&#39;s something priced within the reach of more people than the Hummer is, though GMC global head Duncan Aldred reportedly refused to admit whether it&#39;s the electrified version of the Sierra pickup.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>General Motors has been pledging more and more money into efforts to go electric and driverless. The automaker originally planned to pour $20 billion into the endeavor, but it announced that it would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-self-driving-ev-investment-35-billion-035316455.html">raise</a> its 2020-to-2025 investment to $35 billion just this April. GM plans to offer 30 EVs on the market by the end of 2025 and to exclusively sell electric vehicles starting in 2035.&nbsp;</p><p>The Hummer EV is slated to go into production this fall and would be one of first electric pickups people can buy. With prices that begin at around $80,000, though, it&#39;s not exactly a direct competitor to other upcoming electric trucks. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-cybertruck-2022-004217965.html">Tesla&#39;s Cybertruck</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/f-150-lightning-electric-truck-013038952.html">Ford&#39;s F-150 Lightning</a> will cost about half that, and this mysterious third electric truck might be more of competition for them.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gm-third-electric-pickup-032356371.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1e3bad6c-0aca-4197-aeb0-1f02eac21e45</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 03:23:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626751498</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T03:25:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/62e751c0-e904-11eb-bfbd-8c02fa90cc39" width="1600" height="1018" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/62e751c0-e904-11eb-bfbd-8c02fa90cc39" width="1600" height="1018" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[GMC]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The GMC HUMMER EV is driven by next-generation EV propulsion technology that enables unprecedented off-road capability, extraordinary on-road performance and an immersive driving experience.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GMC]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tom Clancy’s XDefiant is a free-to-play, team-based FPS]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ubisoft is delving deeper into the Clancyverse with <em>Tom Clancy’s XDefiant</em>, a free-to-play game <a href="https://www.engadget.com/watch-ubisoft-tom-clancy-game-reveal-173008218.html">it revealed on Monday</a>. The first-person multiplayer shooter will pit teams of six characters (or Defiants) against each other across several game modes. There’s a focus on gunplay, though you’ll also be able to harness traits, abilities and “ultras” — which seem similar to ultimates in other games — based on the faction you’re using.</p><div id="629855497ccb413e8fa9ad3cc76d53c9"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IB0f39NgAkg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p><em>XDefiant</em> is a bit of a crossover between Ubisoft’s various Clancy franchises. The initial set of factions include the Wolves (inspired by Tom Clancy’s Ghost Recon), Echelon (Splinter Cell) and the Outcasts and Cleaners (The Division). More Defiants will be added to the game later, and will draw from a variety of characters and abilities “from the Tom Clancy universe … and beyond,” Ubisoft said.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Ubisoft San Francisco is developing <em>XDefant</em>, which the creative leads said features “fast-paced firefights meet punk rock moshpits.” You can customize your Defiant’s loadout (including a primary and secondary weapons, attachments and device). You’ll be able to modify your setup when you respawn to help you adjust to what’s happening in a match. It sounds like there will be ways for both casual and competitive players to get the most out of the game too.</p><div id="6a825db2aade4282ac12a3c2a3e16603"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fpM6cLrCs8I?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>There are clear echoes of <em>Overwatch</em> and <em>Valorant</em> here, with plenty Clancyverse flavor thrown in. Executive producer Mark Rubin previously worked on Infinity Ward’s Call of Duty games, and there’s some obvious DNA from that franchise in <em>XDefiant</em> as well.</p><p><em>XDefiant</em> is coming to Xbox One, PlayStation, Xbox Series X/S, PS5, PC, Google Stadia, Amazon Luna and Ubisoft Connect with full cross-play expected at the outset. The game’s still fairly early in development, but Ubisoft’s already inviting the public to try it. The first public PC test starts on August 5th, and you can sign up through the <a href="http://www.playxdefiant.com"><em>XDefiant </em>website</a> for a chance to take part.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-tom-clancys-xdefiant-first-person-shooter-free-205135328.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8817d9ea-61b4-4254-9a1c-0b716b629254</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 20:51:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626727898</ingested><modified>2021-07-19T20:52:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/95a80430-e8d0-11eb-bbbd-44701f3e697d" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/95a80430-e8d0-11eb-bbbd-44701f3e697d" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ubisoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tom Clancy's XDefiant]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tom Clancy's XDefiant]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple rolls out iOS 14.7 with MagSafe Battery Pack support for iPhone 12]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting today, everyone with a compatible iPhone can update their device to iOS 14.7. The latest public release of the firmware adds a few useful but relatively minor features, such as support for the new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-battery-pack-175601349.html"><ins>MagSafe Battery Pack</ins></a> on iPhone 12. There&#39;s an option to merge two Apple Cards into a co-owned account with a combined credit limit.</p><p>The Home app now has a way to manage HomePod timers, while users in Canada, France, Italy, Netherlands, South Korea and Spain will now see air quality info in Weather and Maps. On the audio front, there&#39;s a filter in the Podcasts library that allows you to see all shows or only the ones you follow. You can update your iPhone to iOS 14.7 by opening the Settings app, tapping General and then Software Update.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Apple will likely <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html"><ins>release iOS 15</ins></a> in a couple of months. It&#39;s saving big upcoming features such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-facetime-wwdc-2021-171840284.html"><ins>FaceTime on PC and Android</ins></a>, revamped <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-wwdc-2021-facetime-messages-notification-summary-live-text-172526551.html"><ins>notifications</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-wallet-drivers-license-ios-15-tsa-174600256.html"><ins>driver&#39;s license storage in Apple Wallet</ins></a> for that update.</p><p>Elsewhere, tvOS 14.7 is now available, bringing general performance and stability boosts to Apple TV. Apple Watch users in <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/19/apple-releases-watchos-7-6/"><ins>30 more countries</ins></a> can now use the ECG app after Apple released watchOS 7.6.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ios-147-magsafe-battery-pack-apple-card-podcasts-homepod-192323154.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">50359834-5d11-4ee5-8ee8-344517ff5df0</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 19:23:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626722606</ingested><modified>2021-07-19T19:23:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/a4f836d0-e402-11eb-b77f-32ac984a1efc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/a4f836d0-e402-11eb-b77f-32ac984a1efc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[iPhone 12 MagSafe Battery Pack]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[iPhone 12 MagSafe Battery Pack]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[PS4 'cryptofarm' reportedly used bots to grind in-game FIFA currency]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, officials in the Ukraine busted what appeared to be a cryptocurrency mining operation that used <a href="https://www.engadget.com/cryptofarm-ps-4-pro-raided-ukraine-045118233.html">thousands of PS4 consoles to mine crypto</a>. That doesn&#39;t quite seem to be the case. According to a new report, the consoles (and allegedly stolen electricity) were actually being used to farm and sell digital currency and accounts for EA&#39;s FIFA games.</p><p>Ukranian news outlet <a href="https://delo.ua/econonomyandpoliticsinukraine/kriptovaljuta-vinnica-fifa-384126/"><em>Delo</em></a> reported that PCs were running bots on the consoles to play FIFA and automatically earn an in-game currency. Players can use FIFA coins in the Ultimate Team (FUT) mode to either scoop up sought-after players on an open market or open <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fifa-21-ultimate-team-loot-boxes-love-hate-153036039.html">controversial FUT packs</a> in the hopes of unlocking killer additions for their squads. FUT packs can also be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ea-fifa-loot-box-ultimate-team-151637620.html">opened with real money</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Although buying or selling FIFA coins with real money is against EA policies, that hasn&#39;t stopped a thriving black market for the digital currency. People sell coins or game accounts loaded with the currency to players who are desperate to build a dream FUT roster. One site I checked listed a PS4 <em>FIFA 21</em> account with 5.1 million coins for $300.</p><p>Ultimate Team modes across EA&#39;s sports games are enormously important for the developer&#39;s bottom line. Last year, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ea-fifa-ultimate-team-net-revenue-2021-loot-boxes-143258804.html">EA made $1.62 billion</a> from Ultimate Team, which accounted for 29 percent of its net revenue for the fiscal year. &quot;A substantial portion&quot; of that revenue came from FIFA games.</p><p>Meanwhile, FUT packs and other loot boxes have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-08-ftc-loot-boxes-investigation-public-workshop.html">drawn scrutiny</a> from regulators in recent years. Since gamers can&#39;t see which soccer players they&#39;ll unlock when they buy a pack, some authorities have described the packs as a form of gambling. Belgium <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-25-loot-crates-illegal-in-belgium.html">banned</a> that type of game mechanic in 2018. This summer, perhaps in an attempt to stave off the criticism, EA started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fifa-ultimate-preview-packs-202923317.html">testing</a> a type of FUT pack that allows players to preview the contents.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ps4-farm-fifa-ultimate-team-accounts-cryptocurrency-182654013.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f0218ef8-4ba5-44e9-95a5-3779e1eb6d65</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:26:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626766060</ingested><modified>2021-07-20T07:27:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/40709db0-e8bc-11eb-b7bf-7148bfba141e" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/40709db0-e8bc-11eb-b7bf-7148bfba141e" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Security Service of Ukraine]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[PS4 FIFA account farm]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[PS4 FIFA account farm]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch Ubisoft reveal a new Tom Clancy game at 2PM ET]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ubisoft isn&#39;t pinning all its Tom Clancy game strategy on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-delays-rainbow-six-extraction-riders-republic-172418599.html"><em>Rainbow Six Extraction</em></a>. The company is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oyizdujFcXo">revealing</a> a new Tom Clancy game at 2PM Eastern, and you can watch the premiere here through the video below. The company didn&#39;t say much in advance beyond calling it a &quot;wild&quot; experience, but a brief clip (also below) has already spoke volumes about what to expect.</p><div id="f7ddbd02214e4d0daeb24bdf49390fb5"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Get a quick taste of a brand-new Ubisoft game right here, right now!<br><br>We had a chance to see what it looks like up close, and we can’t wait to tell you more. Keep an eye out on <a href="https://twitter.com/Ubisoft?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Ubisoft</a> tomorrow, July 19 at 11:15am PT for the full reveal. <a href="https://t.co/nZkZB8kKNf">pic.twitter.com/nZkZB8kKNf</a></p>— IGN (@IGN) <a href="https://twitter.com/IGN/status/1416790212815081472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>For a start, this doesn&#39;t appear to be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tom-clancys-the-division-heartland-204549029.html"><em>The Division Heartland</em></a>. Instead, this would be a competitive team multiplayer shooter that looks like it&#39;s set in <em>The Division</em>&#39;s take on New York City, complete with killstreaks and an escort objective. It&#39;s not necessarily piggybacking on existing hot games like <em>Valorant</em>, but we also wouldn&#39;t count on a completely original take. This is the company that belatedly hopped on the battle royale bandwagon with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyper-scape-season-two-atrax-memorial-floor-lava-battle-pass-110128670.html"><em>Hyper Scape</em></a>, after all.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Ubisoft had hinted that multiple <em>The Division</em>-related games were in the pipeline. In that regard, this mystery title is just one part of a much larger planned wave. It&#39;s just a question of whether or not these early projects will be popular enough to justify the rest.</p><div id="d4c91afbe9454b4cb41470a3cb763dd6"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oyizdujFcXo?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/watch-ubisoft-tom-clancy-game-reveal-173008218.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cccd6f47-c240-417c-bd92-be3bbed7f4ee</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626711565</ingested><modified>2021-07-19T16:19:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/edcc5340-e8a9-11eb-9fc3-f8b5cdaa1a18" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/edcc5340-e8a9-11eb-9fc3-f8b5cdaa1a18" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ubisoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Untitled Ubisoft 'Tom Clancy' multiplayer shooter game]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Untitled Ubisoft 'Tom Clancy' multiplayer shooter game]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Uber expands its grocery delivery service to more than 400 US cities and towns]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/uber">Uber</a> has <a href="https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2021/Uber-Accelerates-National-Grocery-Availability-Across-the-U.S/default.aspx">announced</a> the first major expansion of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-cornershop-grocery-delivery-143454216.html">grocery delivery service</a> in the US. The company is more than doubling the number of service areas this week to north of 400 cities and towns. It now serves several major markets through the Uber and Uber Eats apps, including San Francisco, New York City and Washington DC.</p><p>The rapid expansion was partly fueled by a partnership with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-search-maps-covid-19-vaccines-pharmacies-160024114.html">Albertsons Companies</a> and its 1,200 grocery stores across the country. Albertsons owns brands including Safeway, Jewel-Osco, Acme, Tom Thumb and Randalls. Uber also offers delivery from regional chains such as Southeastern Grocers and New York’s Red Apple Group. Uber Pass and Eats Pass subscribers don&#39;t need to pay delivery fees on grocery orders over $30.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Grocery delivery became an important component of Uber&#39;s business during the toughest parts of the COVID-19 pandemic, because the number of rides people were taking dropped significantly. The company is also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-lyft-surge-pricing-lack-of-drivers-035835230.html">dealing with a driver shortage</a> that led to higher prices for rides. Uber bought several delivery startups over the last couple of years to fuel its growth in that sector, such as Cornershop, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-owns-postmates-144950595.html">Postmates</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-buys-drizly-alcohol-delivery-service-145942834.html">Drizly</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uber-grocery-delivery-expansion-us-cities-new-york-san-francisco-162657661.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1b66df3d-7bd6-4c5c-b4e6-4a9084c9b045</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:26:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626715466</ingested><modified>2021-07-19T17:24:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fde91e50-e8b5-11eb-adff-b3d8b52ae756" width="2362" height="1575" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fde91e50-e8b5-11eb-adff-b3d8b52ae756" width="2362" height="1575" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An Uber Eats bike delivery worker pedals away to their next delivery.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[1232204732 Uber Eats]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[WhatsApp now lets you join in-progress group calls]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-05-01-group-video-calling-in-whatsapp.html">WhatsApp group calls</a> are about to behave more like Zoom calls and other more free-form chats. <a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/">The company</a> has started rolling out the ability to join group calls in progress, rather than having to be there (and stay) when the call starts. You can drop in and out at will as long as you were invited at the beginning.</p><p>There&#39;s also a call information screen to show who&#39;s participating in and invited to a chat. Also, don&#39;t worry  if you have to hit &quot;ignore&quot; for a call — the door will still be open if you want to join later.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The addition is a recognition that Zoom and other more flexible video chat services are still popular even as the pandemic (hopefully) winds down. WhatsApp is also acknowledging that some people have always had different video chat habits — this could make the service more appealing if you&#39;ve always left a video chat running so that friends could pop in when they have a moment.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-join-group-calls-in-progress-160026130.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8e044fe0-9e0f-40e9-9b08-1f4f8451747d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:00:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626703888</ingested><modified>2021-07-19T14:11:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f93eddb0-e895-11eb-bbb2-b14c0c119994" width="1920" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f93eddb0-e895-11eb-bbb2-b14c0c119994" width="1920" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Joining a WhatsApp group call in progress]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Joining a WhatsApp group call in progress]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>