<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Hydrasynth Explorer review: Possibly the most synth you can get under $600]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ashun Sound Machines, or ASM, came virtually out of nowhere to deliver one of the most hyped synths of 2020. The <a href="https://www.ashunsoundmachines.com/">Hydrasynth</a> is an unabashedly digital instrument with an impressive collection of sound design tools and a proprietary keyboard that has polyphonic aftertouch. For those looking to leave behind the warm but staid world of analog for the complex frontiers of digital, it’s pretty alluring. But, while its $1,299 list price isn’t absurd given the feature set, it’s also out range for many hobbyists. Even the desktop model, which ditches the keyboard in favor of 24 pads, is slightly pricey at $799.</p><p>The new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/asm-hydrasynth-explorer-superbooth-wavemorphing-portable-191358134.html">Hydrasynth Explorer</a>, however, is expressly designed to get ASM’s keyboard and synth engine in the hands of as many people as possible. And it’s “portable” to boot. (Although, as I’ll get to later, the company’s definition of portable is highly questionable.) Of course to reach the more attainable price of $599, some things had to be sacrificed. But the good news is, most of what’s missing amounts to minor conveniences.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Before we go any further, let’s set some expectations: I cannot possibly cover every feature of the Hydrasynth Explorer in detail. Even the 88-page manual feels like it’s just skimming the surface. If you’re looking for an exhaustive walkthrough, I highly recommend Loopop’s nearly hour-long tutorial on the original <a href="https://youtu.be/-rJd_j9_Ixs">Hydrasynths</a> and its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfuTU1hdMV4">half-hour long follow-up</a> looking at what’s different on the Explorer and Deluxe.</p><p>The most important thing you need to know is that the core of the Hydrasynth — its wavemorphing engine — remains unchanged and it&#39;s running on the same hardware. So the Explorer still has eight-note polyphony, with three oscillators per voice, and over 200 waveforms to choose from. The first two oscillators can be static or in “wavescan” mode, which simply means you can choose up to eight waveforms at a time to morph between. While you can’t import your own custom wavetables, you can essentially build your own from the pre-approved ingredients.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882eb493-5782-11ec-a4fe-eb5d1ebaf4f6" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer" data-uuid="2f77867c-9d36-385a-b11e-c33b0c77d2d2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>Those oscillators can be combined and manipulated using what ASM calls Mutators — two each for oscillators one and two. There are eight different Mutators to choose from, ranging from classic FM (frequency modulation) and hard sync, to the slightly more exotic PhazDiff, and even three different flavors of pulse width modulation.</p><p>The third oscillator is a much simpler affair. It’s a static wave and it can’t be sent through a Mutator, but it can still add depth to a sound. The most obvious use is as a sub-oscillator to add a little bass, but it can also be fed through the ring modulator. Which, by the way: Yes, there is a ring modulator and a noise source as well.</p><p>There are also two filters, which can be in series or parallel, and you can control how much of each oscillator goes to which filter. The first filter has 16 different modes, ranging from classic 12db low pass to a speech-like vowel filter, while the second sweep from low pass, through bandpass or notch, and into high pass.</p><div id="undefined"><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1173556741%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-2DxwFFku5Fu&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/hydrasynth-explorer-sound-samples/s-2DxwFFku5Fu" title="Hydrasynth Explorer sound samples" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Hydrasynth Explorer sound samples</a></div></div><p>To control all these various parts, you’ve got five six-stage envelopes and five LFOs that all feed into a 32-slot modulation matrix. In total there are 29 modulation sources and 155 destinations. It’s a lot of variables to contend with. Frankly, it can feel overwhelming, and that’s even before you start digging into the effects and voice options like “density.”</p><p>The good news is, to get started with the Hydrasynth you don’t need to master its sound design tools, you can just dig into the presets. The stock sounds are pretty solid and cover a wide range of styles, though it does especially excel at icy ambience, strings and plucky keys. But even navigating those can be daunting, especially as some of them start to sound indistinguishable. There’s a grand total of 640 presets spread over five banks of 128 patches. Scrolling through them one by one with the large patch knob can get tedious. But if you turn your attention to the small OLED to the right of the “Main Systems” section, you can use the encoders there to filter presets by category, such as brass, ambient or e-piano. There’s also a favorites menu, where you bookmark 32 of your most used patches.</p><section data-eng-breakout="23555ad0c11b45bb82127fd3a9d71424" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/88301420-5782-11ec-af5e-e23f58862d8b" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer"></section><p><em>(I do want to briefly pause here, to nitpick about the layout of the Hydrasynth Explorer, especially because this isn’t an issue on other models. The Keyboard, Desktop and Deluxe versions all have their displays in a single line. But the Explorer has them staggered, with the navigation display being below and to the left of the parameter display on the right. The right display is significantly smaller and more cramped on the Explorer, but that’s less of an issue than the alignment, which means your eyes have to move much further when going back and forth. It’s doubly frustrating since the solution is simple: move the large patch knob from above the left display, to below it. This would have the added benefit of making it easier to see the left OLED when browsing patches since your hand wouldn’t be blocking it.)</em></p><p>Now, while there’s absolutely nothing wrong with playing presets (I am mostly a tweak-a-preset guy myself), you would be underutilizing the Hydrasynth if you didn’t explore its depths. And while it’s an incredibly complex instrument no matter how you slice it, ASM deserves credit for making the interface as clear and intuitive as possible. The Hydrasynth is far from being knob-per-function, but a lot of work was done to minimize menu diving.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/88303b30-5782-11ec-bf91-76292281c3d5" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer" data-uuid="df47fffa-25b5-33fc-af4d-19a330d7d7bb"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>The front panel is divided up into neatly labeled sections: arpeggiator, filer controls, main systems, master controls and module select. In each of these sections are easy-to-read buttons, often with just one function, plus some knobs. And, by the way, all of those buttons and knobs are a delight to use. This is an incredibly well made instrument and while some sacrifices were made to reach the $599 price, build quality was not one of them.</p><p>You’ll spend most of your time at the bottom of the Master Control and Module Select section where there are 26 buttons for the various parts of the signal chain. The leftmost buttons are where you select which oscillator to modify. When you press the OSC 1 button, the right screen brings up the options for that module and you change the parameters with the endless encoders at the four corners of the display. The up and down arrows to the right scroll through the pages of settings.</p><p>For the oscillators, there are only two pages and you’ll only really need to venture to the second one in Wavescan mode. That’s where you’ll find the “wavelist edit” option. Press that and you’ll open the menu to select the sounds for your wavetable. All you do is turn the knobs next to each parameter for Wav 1, Wav 2, etcetera until you’re happy with your selection. You can pick up to eight, but you’re not required to. What makes the Hydrasynth somewhat unique is that you’re not just picking a set of static wave shapes to switch between, but as you change the position of the Wavescan it will morph from to the other seamlessly.  Which means if you move through those eight shapes slowly, you can get a lot of movement out of just a single oscillator.</p><p>To set the sound for the second and third oscillators, the process is the same.</p><section data-eng-breakout="c6a77f9b15684354a8afb6470785ab8a" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882e3f60-5782-11ec-b7d7-fa52d1ff5116" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer"></section><p>As you move from left to right in the signal chain you’ll next encounter the Mutant 1-4 buttons. Press one and the OLED on the right brings up the parameters. (Noticing a trend?) Depending on what Mutator you select using the top left encoder you’ll see different options here to control. But at its most basic, you just turn one knob to choose, say PWM, then another set the wet/dry value you want.</p><p>There are eight different Mutators to choose from, but I want to focus briefly on PW-ASM, or Pulse Width ASM. There are two things that make pulse width modulation special on the Hydrasynth. One, you can use it on any waveshape — usually PWM is associated with square waves. And two: in ASM mode you can create your own custom pulse width patterns. PW-ASM breaks a wave into eight distinct sections and you dial in the amount of modulation around each of the slice points. It’s not exactly the easiest thing to explain, but suffice to say I don’t know of any other synths out there with this feature. (If you do, please tell me in the comments.)</p><p>Under the Mutants is the button to bring up the ring modulation and noise parameters, and then as you follow the line illustrating the signal chain to the right, you see they all feed into the mixer. Here you can dial in the volume of each oscillator, the ring mod and noise section, as well as panning for each. And this is also where you’ll decide how much of each to send to which filter and whether the filters are in series or parallel. This is one of the sections with the most pages of options to scroll through, but it’s still straightforward. Just press the up and down buttons next to the display until you see the parameter you want, then turn the knob next to it.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882f02b0-5782-11ec-affb-9ac63e93fb92" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer" data-uuid="da117142-d6b9-3f9a-8050-f8af73880a2c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>After the mixer, you’ll see the signal chain branches off again with your envelopes (ENV) along the top, LFOs along the bottom and down the middle your audio signal, including filters, amp and effects.</p><p>By default ENV 1 and LFO 1 are connected to the filters, while ENV 2 and LFO 2 are connected to the amp. There’s no way to break the connection between ENV 2 and the amp, it will <em>always</em> define the total volume of your sound. That doesn’t mean you can’t control the volume of the oscillators separately; it just means you have to get creative.</p><p>So if you wanted OSC 2 to come in slightly after OSC 1 you could use ENV 3 to control it, just with a slightly longer attack time than ENV 2. To make the connection you could press the mod matrix button at the top and scroll through all the options. But the easier way is to hold the ENV 3 button, then press the mixer button. Then those two modules will be automatically connected and all you have to do is pick the parameter you want (OSC2CVol in this case) and dial in the depth. It’s also worth mentioning that the Hydrasynth’s envelopes have six stages — delay, attack, hold, decay, sustain and release — as opposed to the more common ADSR. That means you can actually delay the start of the envelope for a certain amount of time after a key press.</p><p>Even more interesting are the LFOs. While you can use them to create whooshing filter sounds and gentle pitch warbles, you can also use them as a sequencer. Step mode lets you create a customized modulation pattern of up to 64 steps.</p><p>On the fourth page of the LFO settings, though, you’ll find the SemiLock option — this is where the magic happens. See, Hydrasynth doesn’t have a proper sequencer, but you can use the LFOs locked to semitones thanks to the latest firmware. So, with fairly minimal work, OSC 2 could come in behind OSC 1 and play melody over a pad. This is just one example of how to use this power. You can sequence anything from filter cutoff to the wet/dry mix on the reverb to the detune or glide time, or even the parameters of the Mutators. This level of control opens a whole world of possibilities.</p><p>At the end of the signal chain you have four effects slots to work with: one pre-fx, one post-fx and sandwiched between them are dedicated delay and reverb modules. There are a few different varieties of the latter two. The reverse delay is excellent, and while the plate and hall reverbs are solid, cloud is my favorite setting.</p><p>The post- and pre-fx sections have the same options to choose from, including phaser, distortion, compression, rotary, tremolo and more. But my favorite to stick at the end of almost every patch is Lo-Fi. You can turn down the sample rate to get some crushed digital sounds and there are various filter types to choose from that give you the quality of something being played through a phone or over a radio. It’s just a nice touch to keep everything from getting too crisp and clean.</p><p>Here’s the thing: This is only just scratching the surface of what the Hydrasynth is capable of. There are a number of options in the Voice menu for adding depth and warmth, like the sort of vague Analog Feel. There’s an incredibly capable arpeggiator with eight different modes. There’s a macro section where you can assign multiple parameters to a single knob to dramatically transform sounds in a performance-friendly way. And I barely even mentioned the keyboard which has polyphonic aftertouch — something basically unheard of at this price point.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882eb494-5782-11ec-a6fd-aecd6921d416" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer" data-uuid="01513a55-07dc-3a1a-8045-8becf659a74a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>The Hydrasynth Explorer, at least under the hood, is virtually indistinguishable from it’s larger counterpart the Hydrasynth Keys, which costs almost twice as much. So what are you giving up here? Well, one the Explorer has mini keys instead of full-sized ones, but that might not be a con for some people like myself with small hands and limited piano skills. There’s also no proper pitch and mod wheels, instead you get touchstrips; they’re fine, but not nearly as accurate. The biggest loss is the reduced number of controls. The filter knobs have been reduced from five to three, and there’s only four macro / parameter knobs, versus eight on the larger models. But honestly, these are minor sacrifices to reach this price.</p><p>The one last thing to address is that ASM calls the Hydrasynth Explorer “portable,” but that’s only true in the most technical of senses. In addition to the included AC adapter you can power it with eight AA batteries — which is not a trivial amount — for three to four hours. Plus, the Explorer weighs 7.5 pounds and it’s nearly 22 inches long. Sure, that’s petite compared to the 22 pounds and 32 inches of the Hydrasynth Keys, but this is not something that you’re gonna toss in a backpack and bring to the park on a whim. While it’s easy enough to toss in the trunk and bring to a jam session, that ASM doesn’t include or sell a travel case for it, kind of undermines the portability pitch.</p><section data-eng-breakout="c0c7110991a54cc19f0c9b64be0d4a8f" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882eb491-5782-11ec-bcec-2c91fbe5922b" alt="Hydrasynth Explorer"></section><p>So no, the Explorer isn’t really what I’d call “portable,” but that doesn’t matter. Even if this thing never left your studio it would be worth the money. It sounds great (as long as you can accept that it sounds obviously digital), it’s solidly built, and it has an almost bottomless set of sound design tools to explore. It’s possible to just get lost building patches on the Hydrasynth — and not in an annoying menu-diving way. If you’ve got the money, the larger Keys with more hands-on controls will almost certainly save you some headaches, but the Hydrasynth Explorer might be the most synth you can get for under $600.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hydrasynth-explorer-review-wavetable-synthesis-183026724.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">286605bb-3572-434a-b39e-f31ce64fc430</guid><dc:creator>Terrence O&amp;#39;Brien</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638901059</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T18:20:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Terrence O&#39;Brien]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/882eb491-5782-11ec-bcec-2c91fbe5922b" width="2000" height="1126" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/88308951-5782-11ec-abf4-d18bc8813c29" width="2000" height="1126" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Terrence O'Brien / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Hydrasynth Explorer]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Hydrasynth Explorer]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard workers stage walkout over Call of Duty studio layoffs]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Employees and contractors at Activision Blizzard are walking out of work today in support of their colleagues at Raven Software. The protest, the third such <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-employees-call-ceo-bobby-kotick-resign-194513764.html"><ins>work stoppage</ins></a> to hit the company since it was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html"><ins>sued by California</ins></a> over sexual harassment allegations in July, comes after Raven, one of the studios that supports Activision’s incredibly popular Call of Duty franchise, laid off 12 quality assurance contractors. The action started on Monday when 60 workers at Raven Software, including both full-time employees and contractors, left work to protest the surprise terminations.</p><p>The protest has no planned end date, a first for the walkouts at Activision Blizzard. Those involved in the action are demanding the publisher hire all QA contractors, including those who lost their jobs on Friday, as full-time employees. “Those participating in this demonstration do so with the continued success of the studio at the forefront of their mind,” said Blizzard Activision worker advocacy group A Better ABK on Twitter. “The Raven QA department is essential to the day-to-day functioning of the studio as a whole. Terminating the contracts of high performing testers in a time of consistent work and profit puts the health of the studio at risk.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="2b6dcddf15914b69aff8cab3ccce27a7"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">To our leadership, we hope you&#39;ll abide by our policy to lead responsibly. To our community, we hope you&#39;ll join us today in demanding better working conditions for QA in the industry. Let&#39;s raise our <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/VoicesForChange?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#VoicesForChange</a></p>— ABetterABK 💙 ABK Workers Alliance (@ABetterABK) <a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK/status/1467880086665895940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Management at Raven told QA staff at the end of last week it would hold one-on-one meetings with everyone to decide if they would get the chance to stay at the studio as a full-time staff member. The developer told approximately 30 percent of the team their contracts would end on January 28th, with more still waiting to find if they’ll have a job beyond the start of the year. According to A Better ABK, every worker Raven decided not to keep was in “good standing,” which is to say they had not underperformed in their job or committed a fireable offense.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/12/06/raven-software-walkout/"><em><ins>The Washington Post</ins></em></a>, Raven studio head Brian Raffel said during an all-hands meeting on Monday he didn’t consider the terminations as layoffs. Instead, he said the studio had merely decided not to renew the contracts of those who were let go. Raffel reportedly later apologized for his comments.</p><p>“We are converting approximately 500 temporary workers to full-time employees in the coming months,” an Activision Blizzard spokesperson <a href="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1467892585637167108?s=20"><ins>told </ins><em><ins>Bloomberg’s</ins></em><ins> Jason Schreier</ins></a> in response to the layoffs. “Unfortunately, as part of this change, we also have notified 20 temporary workers across studios that their contracts would not be extended.” The move comes after the publisher posted a <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-11-02-king-blizzard-push-activision-blizzard-to-q3-growth"><ins>net income of $639</ins></a> million during its most recent fiscal quarter.</p><p>We’ve reached out to Activision Blizzard for additional comment.</p><p>This latest action isn’t directly related to the misconduct claims that have left Activision Blizzard in turmoil for months — though it’s likely safe to say frustrations across the company are at a boiling point. The first walkout occurred in July shortly after the company issued an “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-employee-open-letter-221223475.html"><ins>abhorrent and insulting</ins></a>”  response to the harassment lawsuit from California&#39;s fair employment regulator. More recently, employees <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-call-for-bobby-kotick-resignation-194953539.html"><ins>staged a second action</ins></a> after <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/activision-videogames-bobby-kotick-sexual-misconduct-allegations-11637075680"><em><ins>The Wall Street Journal</ins></em></a> published a bombshell report on Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick’s handling of the crisis. That article implicated Kotick in the mistreatment that has characterized the company’s work culture for years. As part of that protest, thousands of Activision Blizzard employees <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-employees-call-ceo-bobby-kotick-resign-194513764.html"><ins>called for Kotick’s resignation</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/raven-software-walkout-activision-blizzard-181557930.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c785229c-fb96-428a-836a-a3d39933ea43</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:15:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638900961</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T18:16:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/9f43b450-8bb4-11ea-b7ff-a5c651570d90" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/9f43b450-8bb4-11ea-b7ff-a5c651570d90" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Infinity Ward]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Warzone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Warzone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services went down and took a bunch of the internet with it]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Users are reporting a widespread outage at Amazon Web Services, bringing down websites and backend services for organizations including the Associated Press, Disney+ and Vice. Details about the outage are scarce.</p><p>The <a href="https://status.aws.amazon.com/">AWS status page</a> reported increased error rates for its Management Console on Tuesday morning.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;We are experiencing API and console issues in the US-EAST-1 Region,&quot; the page said. &quot;We have identified root cause and we are actively working towards recovery. This issue is affecting the global console landing page, which is also hosted in US-EAST-1.&quot;</p><div id="cdbc504a5858420d81bfbe738034c144"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BREAKING: Users say Amazon Web Services is suffering a major outage. The company provides cloud computing services to individuals, universities, governments and companies including The Associated Press. <br><br>Amazon has yet to comment on the outage and few details are available.</p>— The Associated Press (@AP) <a href="https://twitter.com/AP/status/1468265411540094976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>AWS <a href="https://www.engadget.com/a-huge-outage-is-affecting-large-swaths-of-the-internet-102354305.html">went down in June</a>, taking out sites like Twitch, Reddit, Twitter, Hulu, HBO Max, Shopify and Amazon itself. That outage was resolved the same day. AWS has suffered outages <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-web-services-aws-outage-180852407.html">prior to this year, too</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-web-services-outage-dec-2021-173157290.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">91e1d879-bb22-4a5c-b84c-aa7ffe275307</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:31:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638898755</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T17:39:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b10db2c0-5783-11ec-bbf7-2a7ecc505896" width="1540" height="764" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b10db2c0-5783-11ec-bbf7-2a7ecc505896" width="1540" height="764" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Downdetector]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Uncharted 4' and 'Lost Legacy' remasters hit PS5 on January 28th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You won&#39;t have to wait too much longer to play (or replay) the last two Uncharted games on your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-review-130048353.html">PlayStation 5</a>. Naughty Dog and Sony have <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/12/07/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-details-on-the-remastered-bundle/">confirmed</a> that <em>Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection</em> will be available for PS5 on January 28th <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection/">for $50</a>, or $10 if you&#39;ve bought the PS4 versions of either included game.  The companies have also revealed just what audiovisual upgrades you can expect. These aren&#39;t complete overhauls (they&#39;re both mid-cycle PS4 releases, after all), but they might be worthwhile if you missed out on <em>Uncharted 4</em> or <em>Lost Legacy</em>, or just want to make the most of a new TV.</p><p>As with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spider-man-miles-morales-performance-rt-mode-ray-tracing-60-frames-second-133034897.html">some PS5 titles</a>, you can prioritize the graphics for either resolution or speed. A &quot;Fidelity Mode&quot; jumps to native 4K while preserving a target frame rate of 30FPS. You can alternately use a &quot;Performance Mode&quot; if 60FPS matters more than crisp graphics, and there&#39;s even a &quot;Performance+&quot; option that caps the resolution at 1080p in return for an extra-smooth 120FPS.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Both games promise &quot;near instant&quot; load times thanks to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-ps5-ssd-expansion-upgrade-150052315.html">PS5&#39;s SSD</a>, and Naughty Dog is taking advantage of improved DualSense haptic feedback as well as spatial audio for built-in TV speakers and headphones. It should be a more immersive experience, then, even if you can&#39;t justify an elaborate audio setup.</p><p>You&#39;ll have to be patient if you&#39;re jonesing for the PC version. You can add the <em>Uncharted</em> bundle to your wish lists on the <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection">Epic Games Store</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1659420/UNCHARTED_Legacy_of_Thieves_Collection/">Steam</a>, but the developers haven&#39;t narrowed down the release date beyond a generic &quot;2022.&quot; The system requirements aren&#39;t yet available, either. While that&#39;s not surprising given the extra challenges of porting a PS4 game to PCs, it could leave you waiting a bit longer than you might like.</p><div id="6cb96f8c0457408f92c1c24fd171ef0e"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QyJ7sRru7LM?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-4-lost-legacy-ps5-release-date-172821857.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3d101a21-6359-4493-80bb-3b40837f6bee</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638898105</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T17:28:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/73e2b000-577c-11ec-bf4f-b28dff737d78" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/73e2b000-577c-11ec-bf4f-b28dff737d78" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Naughty Dog]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['Uncharted 4' in the 'Legacy of Thieves Collection' for PS5]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Uncharted 4' in the 'Legacy of Thieves Collection' for PS5]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla’s in-dash video games can be played even while driving]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/tesla/"><ins>Tesla</ins></a> vehicles allow drivers to play a selection of games on the infotainment system while the car is in motion, according to a report by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/07/business/tesla-video-game-driving.html"><em><ins>The New York Times</ins></em></a>. The company rolled out an update in the summer that reportedly let drivers play <em>Solitaire</em>, jet fighter game <em>Sky Force Reloaded</em> and strategy title <em>The Battle of Polytopia: Moonrise</em> while on the road.</p><p>The touchscreen is said to display a warning before a game of <em>Solitaire </em>starts. “<em>Solitaire </em>is a game for everyone, but playing while the car is in motion is only for passengers,&quot; the message reads, according to the <em>Times</em>. That indicates Tesla knows the game is playable while the car&#39;s moving.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Although players have to acknowledge that they&#39;re a passenger, the driver can tap that button and play the game. Even if a passenger is playing something, it&#39;s possible that a driver will divert their attention to the screen to see what&#39;s happening anyway.</p><p>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/risky-driving/distracted-driving"><ins>says</ins></a> 3,142 people died in crashes involving distracted drivers in the US in 2019. A 2017 study suggested that many infotainment features absorbed drivers&#39; attention too long for them to be safe. Researchers at the University of Utah <a href="https://unews.utah.edu/caution-ahead-the-growing-challenge-for-drivers-attention/"><ins>found that</ins></a>, when drivers used voice-based and touchscreen systems, they &quot;took their hands, eyes and mind off the road for more than 24 seconds to complete tasks.&quot;</p><p>Drivers are supposed to keep their hands on the steering wheel when Tesla&#39;s Autopilot is engaged, but a recent study suggested <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-drivers-become-inattentive-when-using-autopilot-study-finds-072247148.html"><ins>drivers become less attentive</ins></a> when the mode is active. In August, the NHTSA said it was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-autopilot-investigation-nhtsa-141310451.html">investigating Autopilot</a> following a number of crashes with parked first responder vehicles. Those resulted in one death and 17 injuries.</p><p>Other automakers lock many touchscreen and infotainment features when the car is in motion. Stellantis (fka Fiat Chrysler), for instance, lets drivers and passengers watch a DVD on the dashboard screen in some vehicles, though only when the car&#39;s parked. NHTSA <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/staticfiles/nti/distracted_driving/pdf/distracted_guidelines-FR_04232013.pdf"><ins>guidelines</ins></a> urge automakers to ensure that cars with infotainment devices prevent drivers from carrying out &quot;inherently distracting secondary tasks while driving.”</p><p>Tesla has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-08-01-tesla-adds-atari-games-to-cars.html"><ins>added</ins></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fallout-shelter-tesla-230607712.html"><ins>a number</ins></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-02-cuphead-in-tesla-cars.html"><ins>of games</ins></a> to its infotainment system over the last few years. Until a few months ago, they were only playable while the car was parked. The <em>Times </em>says Tesla and CEO Elon Musk didn&#39;t respond to requests for comment — the company no longer has a PR department. Engadget has contacted the NHTSA for comment.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-touchscreen-video-games-driving-165327545.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3424cd1d-fda4-4a6d-994b-565d19b283d1</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:53:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638897972</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T17:26:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/419bbf10-577c-11ec-bef9-0708644f870f" width="1843" height="1003" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/419bbf10-577c-11ec-bef9-0708644f870f" width="1843" height="1003" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Tesla]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tesla Model S touchscreen showing a selection of games.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tesla Model S touchscreen showing a selection of games.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nick Offerman will play Bill in 'The Last of Us' on HBO]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ron Swanson is coming to the world of <em>The Last of Us.</em> Yesterday, Murray Bartlett, a cast member on the upcoming HBO show based on the video game, said that he recently shot scenes with Nick Offerman, a person who hadn&#39;t yet been linked to the production. Now, Naughty Dog has confirmed a report from Variety that Offerman is playing the loner Bill in <em>The Last of Us. </em>Bill had a small but crucial role in the original game that was played by W. Earl Brown, who said earlier this year he wouldn&#39;t be reprising the role in the HBO show.</p><p>Offerman is not the first person to be cast as Bill. The role was originally offered to Con O’Neil, who previously had worked with show runner Craig Manzin on his <em>Chernobyl </em>series (also on HBO). According to <em>Variety, </em>O&#39;Neil had to back out of the role due to scheduling conflicts.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="1d57e456db64474d92468099bdcf38c9"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Welcome to The Last of Us, <a href="https://twitter.com/Nick_Offerman?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Nick_Offerman</a>! We&#39;re so stoked to see you bring Bill to our TV screens!<a href="https://t.co/oxluGsllMU">https://t.co/oxluGsllMU</a></p>— Naughty Dog (@Naughty_Dog) <a href="https://twitter.com/Naughty_Dog/status/1468250782625501187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>In addition to filming scenes with Bartlett, Offerman should get plenty of screen time with series leads Pedro Pascal, who is playing Joel, and Bella Ramsey, who plays Ellie. While there have been plenty of leaks from location shooting around Canada that shows this production is well underway, there&#39;s no word yet on when <em>The Last of Us </em>will arrive on HBO. It&#39;s expected sometime in 2022, though.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nick-offerman-the-last-of-us-hbo-164105965.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">06b4d6da-ab56-4621-9343-9a3b49e0ba28</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:41:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638895269</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T16:41:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Television]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6fb80e90-577b-11ec-bfbe-88dd6ed81fe7" width="3500" height="2109" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6fb80e90-577b-11ec-bfbe-88dd6ed81fe7" width="3500" height="2109" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mario Anzuoni / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Cast member Nick Offerman poses at an event for the 10th anniversary of the television series "Parks and Recreation" during PaleyFest LA in Los Angeles, California, U.S., March 21, 2019. REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TELEVISION-PARKSRECREATION/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat is hoping lens creators can make augmented reality useful]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While Facebook is still <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-metaverse-meta-explained-or-not-120032885.html">trying</a> to explain what a metaverse is, Snap has been working toward a very different vision for an AR-enabled future. Over the last four years, the company has recruited a small army of artists, developers and other AR enthusiasts to help build out its massive library of in-app AR effects.</p><p>Now Snap is tapping lens creators — it has more than 250,000 — to help it make AR more useful. The company is releasing new tools that allow artists and developers to essentially make mini apps inside of their lenses. And it’s working on getting its latest AR innovation into more of  their hands: its next-generation Spectacles, which have AR displays.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The goal, according to Sophia Dominguez, Snap’s head of AR platform partnerships, is to expand the ways AR can be used, while keeping those experiences firmly rooted in the real world — not the metaverse.  “You don&#39;t want to escape into another world,” she says of Snap’s philosophy. “To us, the world around us is magical, and there&#39;s things to learn from it.” Instead, she says, the company is looking to enable experiences that can “bridge” digital spaces and physical ones, and create “more useful applications” for AR.</p><p>For now, Snap is leaving it up to creators to figure out exactly what a “useful” augmented reality lens is, but the company is introducing a number of new tools to help them build it. At its annual Lens Fest event, Snap is also introducing a new version of Lens Studio, the software that allows developers to create and publish lenses inside of Snapchat.</p><p>The latest version includes new APIs that allow AR creators to connect their effects to real-time information. The resulting lenses are almost like mini apps inside Snapchat lenses. For example, creators can build lenses with real-time translation capabilities via iTranslate. Or check on their preferred cryptocurrency with a lens powered by crypto platform FTX. Weather data (via Accuweather) and stock market info (from Alpaca) will also be available, and the company is planning to add more partners in the near future.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b2e57340-5773-11ec-befa-b40598f20f21" alt="New APIs available in Snapchat&#39;s Lens Studio software." data-uuid="e751a452-c4cc-3a6e-a732-09ab27d99635"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Snap</div></figure><p>These kinds of lenses are even more intriguing in the context of Snapchat’s augmented reality glasses, its “next-gen” Spectacles. Snap first showed off the glasses earlier this year, saying that the device would only be available to a small number of AR creators and developers. Since then, the company has handed out its latest Specs to hundreds of creators, who have been helping Snap figure out how far they can push the tech, and what kinds of new experiences AR glasses can enable.</p><p>That’s because with Spectacles, a “lens” doesn’t just have to be something that goes on top of a selfie — it can add contextual information to the world around you. For example, one creator experimenting with Spectacles recently showed off a concept where staring out a train window can surface details about where you are and what the weather is.</p><div id="c970f5f5e80c488d95484e8b8356fc30"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">On a train trip today, I wanted to know what cities I&#39;m passing by, so I created an <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AR</a> lens for <a href="https://twitter.com/Spectacles?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Spectacles</a> to tell me where I am. <a href="https://t.co/98Wud3i7K3">pic.twitter.com/98Wud3i7K3</a></p>— Vova Kurbatov (@V_Kurbatov) <a href="https://twitter.com/V_Kurbatov/status/1465311637771071490?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Nike created a Spectacles lens that allows runners to follow an AR pigeon along their route, and view different animations along the way.</p><div id="83a8f5bdc478401e89428db830f8a420"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Nike + <a href="https://twitter.com/Snapchat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@snapchat</a> AR = no more boring runs. <br><br>What do you think <a href="https://twitter.com/EliudKipchoge?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@EliudKipchoge</a>? 🏃‍♀️🏃 <a href="https://t.co/dB0Ik91DZB">pic.twitter.com/dB0Ik91DZB</a></p>— Nike.com (@nikestore) <a href="https://twitter.com/nikestore/status/1456614947056717826?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Creator Brielle Garcia, who has also been experimenting with Spectacles, recently previewed a concept for an AR menu that allows users to view 3D models of meals on a restaurant menu. Other creators are experimenting with interactive shopping and gaming lenses.</p><p>“When you think about what&#39;s gonna get people to put glasses on their face every single day, those are the things today you’re checking your apps for,” Dominguez said. “We’re really excited to see the different UIs that people can create in augmented reality with this kind of utility.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/93ea5920-5772-11ec-9cff-3072947a321e" alt="A concept for a 3D interactive menu with Snapchat&#39;s AR Spectacles." data-uuid="a6aa6007-ac62-324f-acd7-373c96090bf2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Snap</div></figure><p>All that comes with an important caveat: the reason why the AR Spectacles aren’t for sale and likely won’t be anytime soon is due to some pretty significant hardware limitations. Battery life is extremely limited (the charging case provides four extra charges) and the glasses themselves are, well, ugly.</p><p>While previous iterations of Spectacles look and feel like sunglasses, the next-gen Specs are comically large. Every time I see them, all I can think of is the chunky black frames worn by Roddy Piper <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/they-live-sunglasses">in They Live</a>. And, after spending some time wearing them, I can confirm that they are even more ridiculous looking when you put them on your face.</p><p>That said, Snap has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-spectacles-augmented-reality-180101040.html">been clear</a> from the get-go that this version isn’t intended to look good, or even like something people will want to buy. Rather, the goal is to enable new types of AR development.&nbsp;</p><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="2617f188-3ea0-4e6b-8bad-020f5daf3215"/><p>And, despite the looks, their capabilities are impressive.The frames are equipped with “3D waveguides,” which power the AR displays; as well as dual cameras, speakers and microphones. On the left side is a capture button, so you can snap a photo or video of your surroundings, and on the right is a “scan” button. Much like the feature of the same name in the Snapchat app, scanning can help you find lenses based on your surroundings.</p><p>I only got to experiment with a handful of AR lenses while wearing the Specs, but the process was strikingly similar to using lenses in Snapchat’s app. I was able to scroll through a selection of lenses by swiping along a touchpad on the outside of the frames. Then, you can place the lens into your surroundings to see the AR effects around you. Like other AR headsets, the field of view is  narrow enough that it’s not fully immersive, but I was impressed by the resolution and brightness of what I saw.</p><p>“&#39;I’ve worked on each generation of Spectacles and this one is by far the most fun,” says David Meisenholder, a senior product designer at Snap, pointing to the company’s close collaboration with its creator community. “We&#39;re also learning how much we need to go to make those perfect for the consumer glasses of the future.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-is-hoping-lens-creators-can-make-augmented-reality-useful-163817246.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">30cd12db-f21a-419b-8d2c-2b66a758e85e</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:38:17 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638895099</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T16:38:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b5758540-5779-11ec-a9fd-9b3108f5e6b8" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b5758540-5779-11ec-a9fd-9b3108f5e6b8" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Snap]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Snapchat wants creators to build more 'useful' augmented reality.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Snap useful AR ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[BMW will help recreate 'Rocket League' in real life for charity]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You probably won&#39;t see <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rocket-league-ford-mustang-mach-e-ev-shelby-gt-350-r-180040475.html"><em>Rocket League&#39;s</em></a> flying cars in the real world any time soon, but BMW and esports brand LVL might offer the next best thing. They&#39;re teaming on <a href="https://www.dasrace.com/">Das Race Goal</a>, a <em>Rocket League</em>-style esports platform that has remote-controlled cars play soccer for charity. Players worldwide will steer the vehicles in a real arena while grabbing virtual powerups and activating &quot;special effects.&quot;</p><p>The initial event takes place December 12th at 1PM Eastern and will be streamed live on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/lvlglobal">LVL&#39;s Twitch channel</a>. This inaugural competition will have six three-player teams compete in Munich&#39;s BMW Welt stadium to raise awareness and funds for the United Nations Population Fund&#39;s <a href="https://lac.unfpa.org/es/topics/skills-life">Skills for Life</a> programs, which aim to improve education and healthcare for youth in the Caribbean and Latin America. Each team will have an esports player (including members from Cloud9, Fnatic, G2 Esports and OG), a social media influencer and a young gamer involved in the UN&#39;s efforts.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Thomas Fellger, chief of Das Race Goal partner Icon Group, stressed this wasn&#39;t just a one-off tourney — it was part of a &quot;long-term partnership&quot; that could help the UN&#39;s long-term rights initiatives. At the least, this could add the thrill of real-world elements to a video game format that already has a loyal following.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bmw-das-race-goal-rocket-league-real-life-161508734.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b1806c68-3c62-4d52-8397-db8f4c441305</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:15:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638893461</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T16:11:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6f7544c0-5771-11ec-9ffb-8ecf4bcc9d17" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6f7544c0-5771-11ec-9ffb-8ecf4bcc9d17" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[BMW/LVL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BMW and LVL Das Race Goal remote-controlled car soccer]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW and LVL Das Race Goal remote-controlled car soccer]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Discord gives server owners the tools to put channels behind a paywall]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Discord has started testing a feature called <a href="https://discord.com/blog/building-sustainable-creator-communities-on-discord">Premium Memberships</a> with a small group of users. The tool allows community owners to gate access to part or all of their server behind a monthly subscription fee. It’s something the company’s growing number of users, particularly admins and mods, have been asking it to implement for a while. Before today, those individuals had to turn to third-party services like Patreon to monetize access to their servers.</p><p>By contrast, the Premium Memberships tool creates a streamlined interface for that same purpose. A new tab under the “Community” heading in the app’s setting’s menu allows server owners to do things like set price tiers and view related analytics. The feature similarly streamlines the process of signing up for paid channels for users. If you want to support a community, you don’t need to leave Discord to do so. When you tap on a premium channel, indicated by the new “sparkle” icon in the sidebar, the client will tell how much you need to pay for access, as well as what perks you’ll gain for doing so.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/da1e5800-5773-11ec-ab3e-50db057e408c" style="height:1133;width:1600;" alt="Discord Premium Memberships" data-uuid="69fd8975-211c-3632-8118-edd522bbfee1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Discord</div></figure><p>As for pricing, Discord says it will encourage server owners to experiment. As a baseline, the company will recommend a monthly fee of $2.99 as a minimum and $99.99 as a maximum. When it comes to most of the channels you visit, you probably won’t pay more than $5 or $10 a month for access. The top end of the price range is a reflection of how much Discord has changed since the start of the pandemic to accommodate a more diverse group of communities. Discord <a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-rebranding-151953314.html">isn’t exclusively a place for gaming anymore</a>.</p><p>“Access to a channel can seem simplistic, but it’s a foundational piece that someone can build a lot of flexibility on top of,” said Jesse Wofford, group product marketing manager at Discord, in an interview with Engadget. One of the server owners the company is working with on this week’s soft launch is someone who runs gaming bootcamps. According to Wofford, they’ve built an entire business around private lessons. The company wants to give those people the opportunity to create a sustainable business on its platform.&nbsp;</p><p>Whatever someone decides to charge for access to their channels, the company plans to take a 10 percent cut of the subscription. “It&#39;s an important stake in the ground for us that this product, like a lot of other ones, is built around creator success,” Wofford said. Additionally, for people who want to continue to use services like Patreon to monetize their channels, Discord won’t stop them from doing so. “One of the important things here is that we’re still investing in those relationships,” said Wofford. “We want to create an ecosystem that gives creators as many options to succeed as possible.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b268f040-5773-11ec-bfd5-9432ce0d0309" style="height:1138;width:1600;" alt="Discord Premium Memberships" data-uuid="eea2733d-9fa0-3310-99fc-35f59a4d21b2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Discord</div></figure><p>Premium Memberships is something Discord has been working on for a while. “There’s probably a world where we could have released this a while ago,” Wofford told me. “We wanted to make sure we took in the right feedback from a diverse set of creators and built it in a way that we felt confident would deliver value.” To that end, the company plans to take its time testing the feature before it rolls it out more widely.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/discord-premium-memberships-announcement-160019679.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">68dfd6f5-36b7-401a-ab75-e0daa1ea0c87</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:00:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638892636</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:57:28+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/93e42220-5773-11ec-bdbd-d574ba91490d" width="1600" height="1138" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/93e42220-5773-11ec-bdbd-d574ba91490d" width="1600" height="1138" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Discord]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Discord Premium Memberships]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Discord Premium Memberships]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Hubble telescope is fully operational again after a month-long nap]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NASA&#39;s Hubble telescope has been in a &quot;coma&quot; since <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hubble-telescope-recovering-from-system-failure-151249317.html">going into system failure</a> in late October — but today, the agency <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2021/nasa-returns-hubble-to-full-science-operations">announced</a> that it is waking Hubble up. After multiple instrument sync failures that required putting Hubble into safe mode, NASA says the telescope is now functioning as normal, with all four active instruments collecting data.&nbsp;</p><p>On October 23rd, NASA first noticed that Hubble&#39;s instruments weren&#39;t receiving sync messages from the telescope&#39;s control unit. Communications issues continued for several days, which led NASA to put the telescope into a sort of safe mode — something that takes a long time to come out of because of the sensitivity of Hubble&#39;s hardware. Rapid power or temperature changes aren&#39;t good for its lifespan, so NASA took its time here.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This shutdown was the second that was required in 2021, with another month-long &quot;coma&quot; taking place in July to deal with an unrelated issue. Given the 31-year-old telescope&#39;s age, it&#39;s entirely possible that Hubble is nearing the end of its useful life in space, but for now NASA expects Hubble to work in tandem with the Webb telescope &quot;well into this decade.&quot; After numerous delays, the Webb telescope is expected to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/james-webb-space-telescope-launch-delay-215323872.html">finally launch on December 22nd</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nasa-hubble-telescope-is-operational-again-155710162.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">748c1972-bf40-4d5f-8623-9c5ab0c05f2e</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:57:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638892633</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:57:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/faf2bb70-5773-11ec-bdf5-071d24c531ce" width="2048" height="1361" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/faf2bb70-5773-11ec-bdf5-071d24c531ce" width="2048" height="1361" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Hubble telescope is fully operational again after a month-long nap]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter buys would-be Slack competitor Quill]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may not have heard of messaging service Quill, but it was positioned as a Discord- or Slack-style app for team communications that tried to be less noisy and more structured. The platform only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-new-new-slack-quill/">launched this past February</a>, but today Twitter has announce it is purchasing Quill and shutting it down this weekend. Twitter&#39;s tech GM Nick Caldwell announced the move this morning, and Quill <a href="https://quill.chat/updates/2021-12-07-quill-twitter/">confirmed the news</a> in a blog post on its own site.</p><div id="48148a1901454c398c93e18fdd2bc6b1"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Excited to share that today we’re welcoming <a href="https://twitter.com/QuillChat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@QuillChat</a> to Twitter! 👋🏿👋🏿🪶🪶</p>— Nick Caldwell🔪🧼 (@nickcald) <a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1468221427354517504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The fact that it&#39;s shutting down this weekend is a stunningly fast turn-around; Quill is offering details on how to export data, which any team using it will probably want to do ASAP. (They&#39;ll also want to go and find a new messaging service to use post-haste.)&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The app had billed itself as &quot;messaging for people that focus,&quot; and it&#39;s not clear how that mission will continue as part of Twitter. Caldwell said that the goal was to have the Quill team help &quot;make messaging tools like DMs a more useful &amp; expressive way people can have conversations.&quot; Chances are good this is more of an acqui-hire situation, in which Twitter wanted to have the Quill team working on Twitter&#39;s existing products. Given how fast Quill is shutting down, it&#39;s pretty clear Twitter doesn&#39;t have any interest in spending resources on that existing product.</p><p>It&#39;s the second major acquisition Twitter has made in the last month or so — in mid-November, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-buys-threader-194631446.html">Twitter purchased Threader</a>, a popular tool that pulled threads of tweets together into an easier to read format. Just like the Quill purchase, Twitter didn&#39;t waste much time shutting down Threader — the app is set to disappear on December 15th. (At least it got a longer lease on life than Quill.) Threader is expected to be rolled into the Twitter Blue subscription service; we&#39;ll have to see if some of Quill&#39;s legacy ends up there, as well.</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-purchases-quill-messaging-service-153151449.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">80911ee2-4a6d-4730-be9d-fb157ecea0eb</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638890160</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:16:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c9788d30-576f-11ec-b377-eb768af176e8" width="1426" height="846" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c9788d30-576f-11ec-b377-eb768af176e8" width="1426" height="846" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Quill]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Quill messaging service]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Quill messaging service]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A hacker named Bowser agrees to pay Nintendo $10 million to settle a civil piracy suit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A Canadian hacker named Gary Bowser (yes, like Mario&#39;s nemesis) has agreed to pay the company $10 million to settle <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-bowser-lawsuit-switch-hacks-205618404.html"><ins>a civil piracy lawsuit</ins></a>. Bowser, who was part of Switch hacking group Team Xecuter, was accused of being part of a &quot;cybercriminal enterprise that hacked leading gaming consoles,&quot; as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-12-07-nintendo-hacker-gary-bowser-agrees-to-pay-usd10m-fine"><em><ins>Eurogamer</ins></em></a> notes. Nintendo argued Bowser violated the company&#39;s copyright and it seems the hacks were not in another castle.</p><div id="cd4a6e34ad644d568d0df277b6891d23"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">NEW: Gary Bowser agrees to pay Nintendo $10 million in video game piracy civil lawsuit. This follows Bowser&#39;s guilty plea in October in the federal criminal case against him (where he agreed pay Nintendo $4.5 million in restitution.) <a href="https://t.co/zohn0SPHnH">https://t.co/zohn0SPHnH</a><a href="https://t.co/KMJro3l8Zw">pic.twitter.com/KMJro3l8Zw</a></p>— Rob Romano (@2Aupdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/2Aupdates/status/1467989403876352009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>News of the settlement emerged several weeks after Bowser pleaded guilty to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/team-xecuter-arrests-214400208.html"><ins>multiple federal hacking charges</ins></a>. He was fined $4.5 million in that case and faces up to 10 years in prison. Bowser, who was arrested in the Dominican Republic in October 2020 and deported to the US, admitted to having &quot;developed, manufactured, marketed, and sold a variety of circumvention devices&quot; that let people play ROMs on consoles.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bowser-nintendo-civil-piracy-lawsuit-settlement-152050856.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dc737d88-61b3-4876-919f-526db85092b1</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:20:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638890160</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:16:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Crime & Justice]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/b59fd5b0-32e6-11eb-af4f-fcdb72a28cfd" width="3968" height="2674" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/b59fd5b0-32e6-11eb-af4f-fcdb72a28cfd" width="3968" height="2674" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[KYODO Kyodo / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A statue of Bowser or King Koopa is displayed inside Bowser's Catsle at Super Nintendo World, a new attraction area featuring the popular video game character Mario where set to open in the spring of 2021, at the Universal Studios Japan theme park in Osaka, western Japan, November 30, 2020, in this photo taken by Kyodo.  Mandatory credit Kyodo/via REUTERS ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE WAS PROVIDED BY A THIRD PARTY. MANDATORY CREDIT. JAPAN OUT.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NINTENDO-UNIVERSAL STUDIOS JAPAN/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rohingya refugees sue Facebook for $150 billion over Myanmar genocide]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-09-20-facebook-accused-of-supporting-ethnic-cleansing-in-myanmar.html">repeatedly accused</a> of enabling Myanmar&#39;s genocide against the country&#39;s Rohingya minority, and now it will deal with those accusations in court. A Rohingya woman has filed a class-action lawsuit on behalf of refugees against Facebook parent company Meta, alleging the company both amplified anti-Rohingya hate speech through its algorithms and failed to remove content fostering violence. The refugees ask for over $150 billion in damages.</p><p>The plaintiffs argued that Facebook only took meaningful action against pro-genocide factions after it was pushed. The Myanmar military launched its purge of Rohingya in 2017, with officials and nationalist monks spreading slurs and misinformation on Facebook to either justify or cover up atrocities. Facebook only started cracking down in August 2018 following a UN report linking unchecked behavior on the social network to real-world violence. The company requested an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-06-facebook-myanmar-bsr-report.html">independent audit</a> at the same time that reached a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-06-facebook-myanmar-bsr-report.html">similar conclusion</a>. This was too little too late, according to the refugees — the company admitted it &quot;should and could have done more&quot; only after mass displacements and deaths.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meta has already declined to comment on the lawsuit. A similar complaint is expected in the UK in 2022.</p><p>The firm was quick to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-limiting-myanmar-military-reach-065458912.html">clamp down on the Myanmar military</a> following its February 2021 coup, and went so far as to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-takes-down-myanmar-military-page-160843607.html">pull the military&#39;s main page</a>. However,  that swifter response won&#39;t help much with a lawsuit over past actions. While it&#39;s too soon to say whether or not the lawsuit will succeed, let alone obtain the hoped-for damages, the company may have a difficult time defending itself.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rohingya-lawsuit-facebook-meta-genocide-150644112.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4ce3889f-ac31-417d-b5ae-35a8eabcf6a1</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638889608</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:06:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9483db00-5767-11ec-abcb-58e872336e1a" width="3856" height="2560" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9483db00-5767-11ec-abcb-58e872336e1a" width="3856" height="2560" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Beawiharta Beawiharta / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A protester holds a placard during protest against Myanmar's treatment of its Rohingya Muslim minority in front of Myanmar's embassy in Jakarta, Indonesia, December 5, 2018. REUTERS/Beawiharta]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[MYANMAR-ROHINGYA/INDONESIA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's Alexa Together caregiver service is available today]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alexa-together-service-171909617.html">Alexa Together</a> to help take care of aging family members. Amazon has <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alexa-Together/b?ie=UTF8&amp;node=21390531011">launched</a> the $20 per month ($199 per year) service, with a six-month free trial available for a &quot;limited time.&quot; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-2020-alexa-breathing-teach-voice-profiles-for-kids-172918631.html">Care Hub</a> users get a full free year from now until December 7th, 2022. Your loved one will need an Alexa-capable device, but after that it&#39;s relatively hands-off — they ideally get more independence while you get some peace of mind.</p><p>The elderly relative can reach an emergency helpline if they ask Alexa to &quot;call for help,&quot; but Together is mainly useful for notifications. You&#39;ll get alerts if your family member calls that line, or simply for their first Alexa interaction of the day. Use a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-24-walabot-home-fall-detection.html">fall detection sensor</a> from ATS or Vayyar (more device support is coming) and you&#39;ll also get word if there&#39;s an incident.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Amazon stressed that seniors would still have their privacy. They have to grant permission for you to remotely assist them by adding contacts, reminders and services. Any Alexa interaction alerts are also generic. You&#39;ll know your loved one made an entertainment request, for instance, but you won&#39;t know what was playing.</p><p>The service is still relatively limited. Amazon doesn&#39;t expect to support multiple caregivers until early 2022, for instance, so this won&#39;t help if your siblings also want to pitch in. It might still be useful if you want that safety net, though. If nothing else, it&#39;s clear between this and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-halo-fitness-nutrition-164816502.html">Halo services</a> that Amazon wants to be a part of your daily wellness checks — whether they&#39;re your own or someone else&#39;s.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alexa-together-service-release-date-140003827.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">527694f2-b792-4509-a97c-658834d1c27b</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638885192</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:53:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a3909040-5760-11ec-affb-38da2f528fab" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a3909040-5760-11ec-affb-38da2f528fab" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Alexa Together 'start my day' routine]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Alexa Together 'start my day' routine]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's second-generation AirPods are back on sale for $100]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite the addition of the third-generation AirPods to Apple&#39;s earbud lineup, the second-gen versions remain a decent option for those that liked the fit of the company&#39;s old-school EarPods. They&#39;ve also become a budget-friendly option this holiday shopping season as we&#39;ve seen the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:second-gen AirPods" href="https://amzn.to/3Ewo4Th">second-gen AirPods</a> go on sale a few times. Now you can pick them up for only $100, which is roughly $60 off their normal price. While they were on sale for $89 last month for a brief period of time, this remains one of the best prices we&#39;ve seen.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3Ewo4Th" id="9b0ac9ea2c774ad89561c147e40f05e8" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy AirPods (2nd gen) at Amazon - $100</a><p>You probably know the drill about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-03-apple-airpods-review-2019-more-of-the-same.html">AirPods</a> by now, but we&#39;ll provide a refresher. These are the &quot;classic&quot; style AirPods that made Apple&#39;s earbuds some of the most popular in the wireless audio space. Their kicker is the H1 chipset inside that allows them to quickly pair and switch between Apple devices. Not only do they connect to your iPhone in seconds, but they can also switch to, say, your MacBook while you watch a YouTube video pretty seamlessly.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The EarPods-like design of these buds will be great for some, but a bit cumbersome for others. That&#39;s one of the improvements Apple made with its <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:third-gen earbuds" href="https://amzn.to/3GrWx69">third-gen earbuds</a>, but those come in at $179. The second-gen models have decent sound quality and a good battery life, too — you&#39;ll get around five hours of use before they need more power, and you can get more than 24 hours of total listening time after a few recharges with the included case. Overall, they may not have some of the newer bells and whistles you&#39;ll find on the latest AirPods, but these make a good pair of wireless earbuds for Apple users on a budget.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apples-second-generation-airpods-are-back-on-sale-for-100-133533441.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7f510e1b-76bb-4eb6-8ef5-969cbeca9807</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:35:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638884135</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:35:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/9b12fa70-e79f-11ea-bebd-5d587fda2efa" width="2000" height="1350" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/9b12fa70-e79f-11ea-bebd-5d587fda2efa" width="2000" height="1350" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple AirPods]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple AirPods]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony stops producing its new ZV-E10 camera due to chip shortages]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony only just launched its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-expands-its-vlogging-lineup-with-the-zv-e-10-mirrorless-camera-142731045.html">ZV-E10</a> mirrorless vlogging camera in July, but as of December 3rd, it has suspended orders and ceased production due to the ongoing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/chip%20shortage/">chip shortage</a>, Sony Japan <a href="https://www.sony.jp/ichigan/info2/20211203.html">announced</a>. The company added that a resumption of production and sales will depend upon &quot;the status of parts supply,&quot; and that interested buyers should keep an eye on the camera&#39;s <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/imaging/interchangeable-lens-cameras/aps-c/p/ilczve10l-b">product page</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The ZV-E10 was released as a more capable follow-up to the popular, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-zv-1-vlogging-camera-review-162822651.html">compact ZV-1</a> vlogging camera, thanks to the option to change lenses. It&#39;s essentially a reworked A6100 model with a flip-out display, no electronic viewfinder (EVF), a high-quality built-in three-capsule microphone and a button that makes it easy to switch from video to still photography.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Sony has also paused production of the A7 II, A6400 and A6100 cameras. The latter two are fairly recent models, but the A7 II originally launched in 2014 — so it&#39;s hard to see a particular pattern.&nbsp;</p><p>Cameras aren&#39;t the only Sony products affected by semiconductor shortages. Sony also reportedly reduced PS5 production, something that might put its delivery target of 14.8 million consoles by March 2022 in jeopardy. Sony and TSMC recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-tsmc-confirm-japan-factory-chip-shortage-153515725.html">announced</a> that they&#39;d team up on a chip factory in Japan for specialized chips used in cars, cameras and other gadgets. However, the plant won&#39;t come online until 2024 at the earliest, so it&#39;ll do nothing to help Sony or anyone else, anytime soon.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-suspends-orders-for-the-new-zv-e-10-because-of-shortages-132051883.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ac8e72b5-8706-46e6-8aaf-739e8eaf1e60</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638882962</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:16:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d2e798c0-5756-11ec-beff-c160986f0d69" width="2500" height="1579" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d2e798c0-5756-11ec-beff-c160986f0d69" width="2500" height="1579" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony suspends orders for the new ZV-E10 because of chip shortages]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony suspends orders for the new ZV-E10 because of chip shortages]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's smart thermostat falls to $48 in first ever discount]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in November, Amazon <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-60-dollar-alexa-powered-thermostat-161738943.html">started selling</a> its own smart thermostat for a price that&#39;s less than half what a Google Nest thermostat costs. Now, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat" href="https://amzn.to/3lDS0Fp">Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat</a> has gotten its first price drop and is currently on sale for $48, or 20 percent off its original retail price. It&#39;s not as feature-rich as its much expensive rivals — it doesn&#39;t have motion activation, for instance — but it&#39;s a solid option for a fraction of the price.&nbsp;</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3lDS0Fp" id="60a0f326fa61417c806d5d04a2a9ba1b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Amazon Smart Thermostat at Amazon - $48</a><p>The device is Energy Star-certified, which means it was designed to save you an average of $50 on electric bills per year. It works with Alexa voice control, as you would expect from an Amazon product, but it doesn&#39;t have speakers or a microphone. You&#39;ll have to issue voice commands through a compatible Alexa-enabled device, such as an Echo or the Alexa app.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Once set up, Alexa can take over for you. It can set the temperature if you want it to and update it throughout the day for maximum savings potential. Through the thermostat&#39;s learning feature called Hunches, Alexa will be able to automatically adjust the temperature based on its observations. For example, it can turn down the heat if it believes that nobody&#39;s home.&nbsp;</p><p>Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat also has a simple, modern design that doesn&#39;t make it look cheap despite being a budget option. The $48 device doesn&#39;t come with a C-wire power adapter. If you need the adapter, you can also get the bundle with one for $63 or 25 percent lower than its usual price, though it&#39;s currently not in stock.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p><p><em>All products recommended by Engadget are selected by our editorial team, independent of our parent company. Some of our stories include affiliate links. If you buy something through one of these links, we may earn an affiliate commission.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-smart-thermostat-first-price-drop-131009736.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3d3da35d-0211-4810-b092-7bd4c2521dfc</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638882827</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:13:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa71aab0-5757-11ec-affd-13cf53c2fc44" width="1600" height="1036" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa71aab0-5757-11ec-affd-13cf53c2fc44" width="1600" height="1036" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon smart thermostat]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon smart thermostat]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: The latest Unreal Engine demo is ‘The Matrix Awakens’]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That’s a digital Keanu and, yes, Epic Games’ interactive demo ties into <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em> feature film landing later this month. On December 9th,<em>&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-awakens-unreal-engine-5-interactive-demo-165501226.html"><em>The Matrix Awakens</em></a> will be available on your PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X/S console ahead of its debut at The Game Awards.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-awakens-unreal-engine-5-interactive-demo-165501226.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/e9754dc0-574d-11ec-bbf6-850d168c676c" style="height:422;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="145e743b-88e0-3151-9856-64d332bf233d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Epic Games</div></figure></a><p>It appears to be a slick technical demo of Unreal Engine 5, showing what the next-generation engine is capable of, with some help from Neo et al. For most, this will be the first chance to see UE5 in action. Epic previewed the engine partway through last year with a stunning PS5 demo, but has been largely quiet since. The Game Awards, this Thursday, sounds like a good time to show off.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Samsung’s major shake-up</a></h2><h3>It’s replaced all its CEOs.</h3><h3></h3><p>Samsung has merged its mobile business, the company&#39;s biggest moneymaker, with its consumer electronics division in a major restructuring meant to &quot;strengthen its business competitiveness.&quot; The tech giant has also replaced all of its CEOs and shuffled many around.</p><p>Jong-Hee Han, head of its TV business, has been named as Vice Chairman and co-CEO of the newly merged mobile and consumer electronics divisions. Han won&#39;t be leaving his duties as Head of Visual Display, though, and will instead lead both businesses. Han reportedly has no experience in mobile, but Samsung credits him with playing a key role in the company dominating global TV sales over the past 15 years.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html https://www.engadget.com/...">The SEC is investigating Tesla over defective solar panels</a></h2><h3>The probe stems from a 2019 whistleblower complaint.</h3><h3></h3><p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission is investigating Tesla after a whistleblower complaint alleging the company failed to disclose a variety of safety risks associated with its rooftop solar panels. According to a <em>Reuters </em>report, the agency acknowledged the probe in a Freedom of Information Act request made by Steven Henkes (pictured above), a former Tesla employee.</p><p>The investigation follows several years of reports of safety concerns with Tesla’s solar panels. In 2019, Walmart sued the company after its solar panels led to seven store fires. While the two companies eventually settled, the retailer claimed at the time that Tesla regularly sent inspectors who “lacked basic solar training and knowledge.&quot; That same year, Tesla solar panels at an Amazon warehouse in California reportedly caught fire as well.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Concept hydrogen-powered plane could fly halfway around the world without refueling</a></h2><h3>But the main word is concept, for now.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/cb1ca340-574e-11ec-bdef-c39d7251a0c9" style="height:370;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="0fa1513f-741f-3c7d-962e-bf7d591467e1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Aerospace Technology Institute</div></figure></a><p>Electric planes won&#39;t be feasible until batteries become more powerful and lightweight, but hydrogen-powered flight is another possible way to reduce the flight industry’s carbon emissions.</p><p>The FlyZero project, led by the Aerospace Technology Institute and funded by the UK government, came up with a concept for a liquid hydrogen-powered midsize aircraft. It said the plane would be able to fly 279 passengers non-stop from London to San Francisco or from London to Auckland, New Zealand, with one stop for refueling.</p><p>We&#39;re years away from commercial hydrogen aircrafts, with refueling infrastructure non-existent and hydrogen more expensive and difficult to store than standard kerosene fuel. The FlyZero project plans to publish more detailed findings early next year.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html">Instagram launches Take a Break and other safety features for teens</a></h2><h3>Just in time for Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony.</h3><h3></h3><p>Instagram has launched a number of new and experimental features meant to make its app a safer place for teens ahead of Instagram head <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-adam-mosseri-congress-testify-184609082.html"><ins>Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony</ins></a>. The previously announced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-teen-take-a-break-205617444.html"><ins>Take a Break</ins></a> feature has now launched in the US, UK, Canada and Australia. Now, when a user — teens, in particular — scolls through Instagram for a long while, the app will ask them to take a break and to set reminders for the future.</p><p>In March, Instagram will be launching tools for parents and guardians to give them a way to view how much time their kids are spending on the app and to set time limits.</p><p>Adam Mosseri is set to testify this week as part of a series of hearings about protecting kids online. Instagram and Facebook have come under fire in recent months after whistleblower Frances Haugen told Congress about the social networks&#39; effect on teens based on Meta&#39;s own research. Haugen revealed that &quot;engagement-based ranking on Instagram can lead children from very innocuous topics like healthy recipes… to anorexia-promoting content over a very short period of time.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><p></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/shatner-in-space-documents-the-90-year-olds-blue-origin-voyage-134555889.html"><ins>William Shatner&#39;s space voyage is becoming an Amazon documentary</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/toshibas-flagship-amazon-fire-hands-free-alexa-140014641.html"><ins>Toshiba&#39;s flagship Fire TV set has hands-free Alexa</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-firefox-95-rlbox-190712215.html"><ins>Firefox 95 enhances the browser&#39;s protection against malicious code</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/doordash-15-minute-grocery-delivery-nyc-ultra-fast-200711153.html"><ins>DoorDash tests 15-minute grocery deliveries in New York City</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/googles-pixel-6-can-now-be-used-to-unlock-bmw-vehicles-180000062.html"><ins>Google Pixel update delivers time-saving improvements on new and older models</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-copyright-transparency-report-184854080.html"><ins>YouTube says most disputed copyright claims are resolved in the uploader&#39;s favor</ins></a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-the-latest-unreal-engine-demo-is-the-matrix-awakens-121518809.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">284ea041-2290-4172-9af3-b3e121bcabe0</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 12:15:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638876159</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T11:22:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/beb9a050-574c-11ec-bfcf-4012fd9e8060" width="1432" height="792" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/beb9a050-574c-11ec-bfcf-4012fd9e8060" width="1432" height="792" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Matrix Awakens]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Matrix Awakens]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla is reportedly replacing some faulty Autopilot cameras for free]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tesla will replace the Autopilot cameras in the front fenders of some its electric vehicles for free, according to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/06/tesla-is-replacing-faulty-autpilot-cameras-in-some-model-s-x-3-cars.html"><em>CNBC</em></a>. While Tesla has yet to issue a recall, the news organization has seen internal documents distributed to authorized service providers in late November, asking them to replace faulty repeater cameras at no cost to owners. Apparently, the cameras on some Model S, X and 3 vehicles manufactured by the company at its Fremont, California plant have faulty printed circuit boards.&nbsp;</p><p>Those cameras capture the car&#39;s blind spots, and Autopilot wouldn&#39;t work without them. If they&#39;re not working as intended, drivers typically only see a block box on their main display and may get alerts that their Autopilot has limited function. <em>CNBC</em> says Tesla may have to replace cameras for at least several hundred vehicles as a result of the faulty PCBs it used.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A Tesla sales manager told the publication that internal service notices are sometimes followed by voluntary recalls, but the automaker has yet to issue a statement. Tesla recalled vehicles several times in the past over various issues. In October, it recalled nearly 3,000 Model 3 and Y vehicles, because their front suspension lateral link fasteners <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-recall-suspension-model-y-3-191031712.html">may loosen</a>. The company also recalled 11,704 Tesla EVs from 2017 and later in November after they became prone to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-braking-recall-software-glitch-132442476.html">false-positive braking</a> following a buggy Full Self-Driving beta update.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-replacing-faulty-autopilot-cameras-115552280.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eb766432-e3ad-4f8e-97d9-b054a694e0f7</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:55:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638876404</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T11:26:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-12/0099abe0-1605-11ea-99e7-1a2853920ae2" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-12/0099abe0-1605-11ea-99e7-1a2853920ae2" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[jetcityimage via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Indianapolis, US - March 29, 2016: Tesla Motors Store in Indianapolis Selling Electric Cars III]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Indianapolis - March 2016: Tesla Motors Store III]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[BMW says it hit its goal of delivering one million 'electrified' vehicles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, BMW <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-19-bmw-now-has-500-000-evs-on-the-road.html">delivered</a> its 500,000th electrified vehicle (including EVs and hybrids), promising to deliver one million units in two years. Now, the company has <a href="https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0362353EN/delivered-as-promised:-bmw-group-hands-over-one-millionth-electrified-vehicle-and-achieves-next-milestone-in-transformation">announced</a> that it&#39;s met that goal by delivering its one millionth electrified vehicle, an iX xDrive40 SUV (shown above), to a customer in Europe. It&#39;s also promising to double that tally to two million by next year, while delivering two million fully electric EVs by 2025.&nbsp;</p><p>BMW was a pioneer in the pure electric category with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-07-29-bmw-unveils-i3-electric-car-in-the-carbon-fiber-flesh-video.html">i3</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-09-10-bmw-i8-plug-in-hybrid-pricing.html">i8 EVs</a>, but has been slow to ramp up its offerings since then. As such, the majority of its electrified sales have been hybrid, rather than pure EVs. (The term &quot;electrified&quot; generally encompasses both PHEVs, mild hybrids and EVs.) Between January and September of 2021, BMW reportedly sold 59,688 EVs and 171,887 plug-in hybrid vehicles worldwide, according to <a href="https://cleantechnica.com/2021/11/05/bmws-ev-sales-double-in-2021-but-still-cant-catch-tesla/"><em>CleanTechnica</em></a>. In 2020, it sold 192,646 plug-in vehicles, including PHEVs and EVs, <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/465907/bmw-group-plugin-electric-car-sales-2020/"><em>InsideEVs</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>reported.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This year, the company launched the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bmw-i4-m50-first-drive-video-163055887.html">i4 sedan</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bmw-ix-ev-first-drive-video-193002612.html">iX SUV</a> pure electric models into the US market, but they only went on sale last month. It also offers <a href="https://www.bmwusa.com/vehicles/plug-in-hybrid-electric.html">four PHEVs</a>, including versions of the 7, X5, 3 and 5 models. Over the next year, BMW will add the fully electric BMW 7 series and X1, plus the high-volume BMW 5 series by 2023. It plans to have &quot;about ten million fully-electric vehicles on the road&quot; by 2031 or so.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bmw-says-it-hit-its-goal-of-delivering-a-million-electrified-vehicles-by-2021-112235105.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">37e4e0b5-e42c-4f93-b1b6-14358aca884f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:22:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638883601</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:26:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/44ee2690-5749-11ec-b7d7-8bf1242f770a" width="2560" height="1624" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/44ee2690-5749-11ec-b7d7-8bf1242f770a" width="2560" height="1624" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Uwe Fischer / BMW]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BMW one millionth electrified vehicle sale]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW one millionth electrified vehicle sale]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[ESPN+ will offer 4,300 hours of PGA Tour Live golf streaming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Golf has been <a href="https://www.golfdigest.com/story/national-golf-foundation-reports-numbers-for-2020-were-record-se">booming</a> during the pandemic as folks look for socially distanced outdoor activities, and that has extended to <a href="https://golf.com/news/5-takeaways-golf-tv-ratings-2021-hot-mic/">interest</a> in televised golf. There&#39;s going to be a lot more to watch in 2022, as ESPN+ has announced that it will offer 4,300 hours of golf coverage across 35 tournaments as part of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-09-pga-tour-live-espn-plus-in-2022.html">PGA Tour Live streaming deal</a>. US viewers will also pay less to access the service.</p><p>In the past, we&#39;ve seen &quot;Featured Groups&quot; and &quot;Featured Holes&quot; on PGA Tour Live. Next year, however, ESPN+ will offer four concurrent feeds, adding a &quot;Marquee Group&quot; with the most interesting players. It&#39;s also introducing a &quot;Main Feed&quot; that will resemble a traditional broadcast with the best content from all its cameras around the course.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>ESPN+ said the PGA Tour Live production crew will increase from 85 to 210 people as part of its new commitment to the tour. Each feed will have hosts and on-course analysts including Stuart Appleby, Christina Kim, Chantel McCabe and Mark Immelman.&nbsp;</p><p>PGA Tour Live first launched as a free service on pgatour.com, and has recently been available for free <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-01-05-twitter-will-livestream-portions-of-pga-golf-tournaments.html">on Twitter</a> during select broadcasts. Now, you&#39;ll need to pay $6.99 per month for ESPN+, or pick it up in the Disney Bundle that includes Disney+, Hulu and ESPN+ for $13.99 per month (ESPN+ is only available in the US). That&#39;s a significant sum, but PGA Tour Live currently costs $9.99 per month on NBC Sports Gold, and ESPN+ offers other live sports coverage (soccer, MLB baseball, NHL hockey, MMA, etc.) on top of golf.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/espn-is-the-new-home-for-pga-tour-lives-extended-golf-coverage-094741252.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2b75045e-27b8-48d3-973d-2e624bc4c6bd</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 09:47:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638870463</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T09:47:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Golf]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/384528b0-5741-11ec-bbf3-7acd75beedaa" width="5985" height="3982" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/384528b0-5741-11ec-bbf3-7acd75beedaa" width="5985" height="3982" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Keyur Khamar via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OWINGS MILLS, MD - AUGUST 28:  Bryson DeChambeau at the top of his swing as he plays his shot from the 13th hole drop zone after hitting his tee shot in the water during the third round of the BMW Championship, the second event of the FedExCup Playoffs, at Caves Valley Golf Club on August 28, 2021 in Owings Mills, Maryland. (Photo by Keyur Khamar/PGA TOUR via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW Championship - Round Three]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instagram adds more teen safety features ahead of parental control rollout next year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Instagram has launched a number of new and experimental features meant to make its app a safer place for teens ahead of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-adam-mosseri-congress-testify-184609082.html">Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony</a>. To start with, it&#39;s launching the previously announced &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-teen-take-a-break-205617444.html">Take a Break</a>&quot; feature in the US, UK, Canada and Australia today. Now, when a user has been scrolling Instagram for quite some time, the app will ask them to take a break and to set reminders for the future. Teens, in particular, will get notifications to set those reminders on to make sure they&#39;re aware of the feature. They&#39;ll also see expert-backed tips to help them &quot;reflect and reset.&quot;</p><p>In March, Instagram will be launching tools for parents and guardians that will give them a way to view how much time their kids are spending on the app and to set time limits. Teens will get the option to notify their parents if they report someone, as well, serving as a way to signal the adults in their life that they may need to talk about it.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>One of the experimental features Instagram is testing will come in handy for teens and young adults who want to remove their activity on the app from when they were a lot younger. It will allow users to bulk delete the photos and videos they posted, as well as all their likes and comments. The feature will be available to everyone in January.&nbsp;</p><p>Another test feature will expand what Instagram started earlier this year when it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-restricts-adult-dms-to-teens-140416475.html">prohibited</a> adults from DMing teens who don&#39;t follow them. Early next year, it will also switch off the ability to tag or mention teens by adults who don&#39;t follow them, or to include their content in Reels Remixes or Guides. Finally, it&#39;s exploring the possibility of limiting the sensitive content teens see even more and is currently building an experience that would nudge users towards another topic if they&#39;ve been scrolling one topic for a while.&nbsp;</p><p>Instagram head Adam Mosseri is set to testify this week as part of a series of hearings about protecting kids online. Instagram and Facebook have come under fire in recent months after whistleblower Frances Haugen <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-said-should-change-143051354.html">told Congress</a> about the social networks&#39; effect on teens based on Meta&#39;s own research. Haugen made a lot of disclosures about Facebook&#39;s algorithms and other internal systems, and one of the things she revealed was that &quot;engagement-based ranking on Instagram can lead children from very innocuous topics like healthy recipes… to anorexia-promoting content over a very short period of time.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">581eaf03-0510-4b11-996e-4c539f3fe800</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638886739</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T14:19:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/12a07320-572e-11ec-9fff-3363a7aecdf6" width="3000" height="1996" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/12a07320-572e-11ec-9fff-3363a7aecdf6" width="3000" height="1996" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Steve Jennings via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SAN FRANCISCO, CA - SEPTEMBER 14:  Vice President of Product Management at Facebook Adam Mosseri speaks onstage during TechCrunch Disrupt SF 2016 at Pier 48 on September 14, 2016 in San Francisco, California.  (Photo by Steve Jennings/Getty Images for TechCrunch)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt SF 2016 - Day 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung merges mobile and consumer electronics divisions in major shakeup]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung has <a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-electronics-announces-new-leadership-2">merged</a> its mobile business, the company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-q3-earnings-chip-mobile-record-high-030342880.html">biggest moneymaker</a>, with its consumer electronics division in a major restructuring meant to &quot;strengthen its business competitiveness.&quot; In addition, to combining divisions, the tech giant has also replaced all of its CEOs.&nbsp;</p><p>Jong-Hee Han, the head of its TV business, has been named as Vice-Chairman and co-CEO of the newly merged mobile and consumer electronics divisions. Han won&#39;t be leaving his duties as head of visual display, though, and will instead lead both businesses. According to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/samsung-elec-says-it-will-reorganise-company-structure-2021-12-07/"><em>Reuters</em></a>, Han has no experience in mobile, but Samsung credits him for playing a key role in the company achieving top position in global TV sales over the past 15 years.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, Samsung President Kyehyun Kyung has also been named co-CEO and will now lead its chip and components division. Kyung is a semiconductor design expert and used to leading the company&#39;s flash product and technology team. He&#39;s expected to &quot;help maintain&quot; Samsung&#39;s semiconductor leadership and conjure innovative ideas at the same time.&nbsp;</p><p>While mobile generated the biggest revenue (US$24.2 billion) for Samsung in the third quarter of 2021, its chip business isn&#39;t that far behind. Its semiconductor business posted US$22.6 billion in revenue due to the heightened demand for server DRAMs and for computers in general during the pandemic. Samsung is aiming to become the number 1 chip contract manufacturer within the next decade and has poured hundreds of billions into the business. Just this November, it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-17-billion-chip-factory-texas-054150875.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s building a $17 billion semiconductor factory in Texas to manufacture high-end and advanced chips for smartphones, 5G and artificial intelligence.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef90d74e-3eab-4aa9-a19b-6d86dd504ce1</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 05:54:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638856512</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T05:55:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/59faabe0-5716-11ec-bdff-18a1bf083db7" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/59faabe0-5716-11ec-bdff-18a1bf083db7" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chung Sung-Jun via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SEOUL, SOUTH KOREA - AUGUST 25:  A Samsung flag flies outside the Samsung office on August 25, 2017 in Seoul, South Korea. Prosecutors are seeking a 12-year jail sentence. Lee, de facto chief of South Korean conglomerate, faces five charges connecting the bribery scandal involving ousted former President Park Geun-hye and her confidant Choi Soon-sil. The verdict affects the business of Samsung, which has launched new Galaxy Note 8 smartphone to wipe out the misery of exploding Note 7 last year.  (Photo by Chung Sung-Jun/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Group Heir Lee Delivered Ruling Over Bribery Scandal Involving Former President Park]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[EV startup Arrival is building a $11.5 million battery plant in North Carolina]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>British-American vehicle manufacturer Arrival today <a href="https://arrival.com/us/en/news/arrival-announces-high-voltage-battery-module-assembly-plant-in-charlotte-nc">announced</a> it plans to establish an $11.5 million battery plant in Charlotte, North Carolina. The factory will be the company’s third overall facility in the city. It will be located just steps away from its soon-to-be-complete North American headquarters. Once the plant is operational, it will supply batteries to the company’s Van “Microfactory,” creating approximately 150 additional jobs.&nbsp;</p><p>“By bringing the assembly of our proprietary High Voltage Battery Modules in-house, we’re striving to be as vertically integrated as possible,” Arrival CEO Mike Ableson said. “This will enable us to have even greater control over the functionality and cost of our products and pass those cost savings on to the customer while also working toward our goal of zero waste production.” The company told <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/ev-maker-arrival-to-build-high-voltage-battery-module-assembly-plant-in-north-carolina/"><em>TechCrunch</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>the facility should have a production capacity of up to 350,000 battery modules per year.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Arrival has a lot riding on the success of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/arrival-ups-delivery-van-beta-trials-us-uk-090059767.html">Van EV</a>. In 2020, UPS <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-29-ups-arrival-electric-trucks-order-investment.html">ordered 10,000</a> electric trucks from the automaker, with the option to buy an additional 10,000 vehicles if everything goes well. The announcement comes on the same day Toyota said it would build a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/toyota-greensboro-randolph-megasite-ev-annoucement-202448241.html">$1.29 billion battery plant</a> in central North Carolina.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/arrival-north-carolina-221732120.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">95ecf494-821d-42c0-8f15-5be87c02f91f</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 22:17:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638883625</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:27:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0e497c10-56e1-11ec-a6f5-a1fb94e2fc33" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0e497c10-56e1-11ec-a6f5-a1fb94e2fc33" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Arrival]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Arrival battery]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Arrival battery]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The SEC is investigating Tesla over defective solar panels]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission is investigating Tesla following a whistleblower complaint alleging the company failed to disclose a variety of safety risks associated with rooftop solar panels from its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-11-21-tesla-solarcity-acquisition.html"><ins>SolarCity division</ins></a>. Per <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/exclusive-sec-probes-tesla-over-whistleblower-claims-solar-panel-defects-2021-12-06/"><em><ins>Reuters</ins></em></a>, the agency acknowledged the probe in a Freedom of Information Act request made by Steven Henkes (pictured above), a former Tesla employee.&nbsp;</p><p>He contacted the SEC in 2019 after the automaker allegedly ignored his pleas to notify consumers and regulators about the safety issues with its solar panels. One of those involved defective electrical connectors that could cause fires.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In 2020, Henkes later sued Tesla, alleging the company had dismissed him in retaliation for his actions. &quot;The top lawyer cautioned any communication of this issue to the public as a detriment to the Tesla reputation,” Henkes said in his complaint. According to the lawsuit, more than 60,000 residential customers were affected by the issues Henkes documented in his complaint.</p><p>The investigation follows several years of reports of safety concerns with Tesla’s solar panels. In 2019, Walmart <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-20-walmart-sues-tesla-over-solar-panel-fires.html"><ins>sued the company</ins></a> after its solar panels led to seven store fires. While the two companies eventually settled, Walmart claimed at the time Tesla regularly sent inspectors who “lacked basic solar training and knowledge.&quot; It also asserted the company’s panels were plagued by visible defects. That same year, the Tesla solar panels at an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-24-bloomberg-tesla-solar-panel-amazon-fire.html"><ins>Amazon warehouse</ins></a> in California reportedly caught fire as well.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4cac06e1-671b-4455-8d57-ae42838023ac</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 21:14:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638825246</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T21:14:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/24bc07f0-56d8-11ec-a1ff-d55e983b28b8" width="4032" height="2268" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/24bc07f0-56d8-11ec-a1ff-d55e983b28b8" width="4032" height="2268" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Frandino / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Steven Henkes, a former Tesla and Toyota employee who complained to the SEC in 2019 that Tesla failed to properly notify shareholders and consumers of fire risks of its solar panel systems, is seen during an interview in San Francisco, California, U.S. on December 1, 2021. Picture taken December 1, 2021. REUTERS/Nathan Frandino]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TESLA-SOLAR/SEC]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>