<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></title><link>Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics</link><description><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Alphabet's latest moonshot aims to make industrial robots more practical]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet has launched another company in its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-30-chronicle-cybersecurity-alphabet-moonshot-x.html">X moonshot factory</a>, and this one may be its most ambitious <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-x-mineral-223517153.html">robotics project</a> to date. The <a href="https://blog.x.company/introducing-intrinsic-1cf35b87651">just-opened</a> firm, Intrinsic, plans to make <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-11-adidas-abandons-robot-speedfactories-in-germany-and-the-us.html">industrial robots</a> more accessible to people and businesses that couldn&#39;t otherwise justify the effort involved to teach the machines. You could see robotic manufacturing in more countries, for example, or small businesses that can automate production that previously required manual labor.</p><p>Intrinsic will focus on software tools that make these robots easier to use, more flexible and more affordable. To that end, the company has been testing a mix of software tools that include AI techniques like automated perception, motion planning and reinforcement learning. Company chief Wendy Tan-White has relevant experience, too. She started the &quot;world&#39;s first&quot; software-as-a-service site builder to make web development more accessible, launched early online banking and lending services, and helped nurture startups as a VP at X.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The technology is still early, but there are already promising results. During its development time at X, the team trained a robot to make a USB connection in two hours (instead of programming it over hundreds of hours) and had robotic arms build simple furniture (shown below). Automation wouldn&#39;t be &quot;realistic or affordable&quot; for efforts like these using existing technology, Intrinsic said.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fc9c3ea0-ebb8-11eb-bcfe-b0c7bc6d40eb" style="height:288;width:512;" alt="Intrinsic industrial robots use perception, force control and planning to assemble furniture" data-uuid="62c3587c-7651-3591-80ba-ea6eaaf1d93c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Intrinsic/X</div></figure><p>The new company still has much work to do. It&#39;s now focused more on creating a practical product and &quot;validating&quot; its tech. It&#39;s also hunting for partners in car manufacturing, electronics and healthcare that currently use industrial robots. If Intrinsic succeeds, though, it could make robotics more equitable and fill gaps in production. The company even suggests that its work could help the environment — the closer robotic factories are to people, the lower the emissions needed to transport goods to customers.</p><p>This might prove challenging. Rethink Robotics spent years developing collaborative robots that learn through simple human guidance, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-04-rethink-robotics-shuts-down.html">only to shut down</a> as sales fell short. X moonshot companies also aren&#39;t guaranteed to succeed — look at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/loon-shutdown-014334705.html">Loon&#39;s fate</a> as an example. Alphabet&#39;s money could help where companies like Rethink struggled, however, and Intrinsic is focused more on solving overall robotics problems rather than specific scenarios. This effort might stand a better chance than most.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-x-intrinsic-industrial-robot-moonshot-140057232.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4eb581f6-049c-4f48-8b00-c8bad8d26785</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627046831</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T13:27:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/9097a1c0-ebb0-11eb-bbed-4c2bfbfd69dd" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/9097a1c0-ebb0-11eb-bbed-4c2bfbfd69dd" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Intrinsic/Alphabet]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Intrinsic logo for Alphabet X moonshot covering industrial robots]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Intrinsic logo for Alphabet X moonshot covering industrial robots]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HTC Vive Pro 2 review: An excellent 5K headset for the VR faithful]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="88c991e8eae740c89c33f4761ce96090"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kATHHeP4Wfo" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>The HTC Vive Pro 2 is a VR enthusiast&#39;s dream. Its 5K 120Hz display delivers the sharpest desktop VR experience I&#39;ve ever seen. And while its design hasn&#39;t changed from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-03-htc-vive-pro-review.html">2018 model</a>, it&#39;s still very comfortable to wear for extended sessions. But its high price and reliance on old controllers make it a tough sell. And let&#39;s be honest, it&#39;ll take a lot to dethrone the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oculus-quest-2-review-vr-facebook-headset-173026291.html">$299 Oculus Quest 2 </a>as the ideal VR headset for mainstream users.</p><p>That&#39;s not who HTC Vive is really targeted at, though. Like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/htc-vive-focus-3-review-standalone-vr-headset-163044765.html">standalone Vive Focus 3</a>, this headset is clearly geared towards professionals. But unlike that device, it also has plenty to offer gamers. For them, spending $1,399 on the entire Vive Pro 2 package would be worth it to play <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-23-half-life-alyx-review-valve-vr.html"><em>Half Life: Alyx</em></a> in the best quality possible. And if you&#39;ve already invested in the previous <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-03-htc-vive-pro-review.html">Vive Pro </a>or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-28-valve-index-review-vr.html">Valve Index</a>, you can nab the new headset on its own for $749.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="96cb55eb-ae39-425c-b5f5-a7064c3f8924"/><p>Just be sure to keep track of which Vive Pro is which, because they look practically identical. The Pro 2 features a black and purple color scheme, but its front facia, strap and headphones all look the same as before. The difference becomes clear once you put on the Vive Pro 2, though: Its 5K screen offers 2,448 by 2,448 pixels per eye, a huge leap ahead of the 1,440 by 1,600 pixels from the Pro. Plus the Pro 2&#39;s LCDs have RGB sub-pixels, which helps make everything look sharper still. The screen can also refresh at up to a 120Hz, which is noticeably smoother than the previous 90Hz panel, and I appreciated the wider 120-degree field of view, which makes virtual worlds feel all the more immersive.</p><p>These specs may sound familiar, because the Vive Focus 3 also has the same 5K screen, it just happens to have a slower 90Hz refresh rate. But I came away far more impressed with the Pro 2, because it can easily run any PC VR game or app. The Focus 3, meanwhile, has a limited selection of mobile titles, and I was never able to successfully stream higher-end VR from my gaming PC. And, honestly, even if I got that to work, streaming is still a clear step down from running natively.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e35896d1-eb10-11eb-b7ff-c8fd80773144" alt="HTC Vive Pro 2" data-uuid="31169255-820a-32dc-9309-a7c6c02fe00e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>I revisited old and newer games on the Pro 2, and everything just looked fantastic. I kept getting distracted by the detailed environments in <em>Half Life Alyx</em> — a game that looked great on the Index, but has an extra level of polish with the Pro 2&#39;s resolution bump. It&#39;s sort of like the jump from 1080p video to 4K. You might not notice the difference  at first glance, but once you start inspecting the finer details like grass and wood grain you can tell you&#39;re working with more pixels.</p><p>Hopping back into <em>Superhot</em> almost felt like I was playing <em>Superhot 2</em>. I could make out plenty more detail in the game&#39;s cyberpunk introductory room. And even though its aesthetic is relatively simple, the game&#39;s enemies, weapons and environments all looked more detailed than I remembered. I also spent more time than I expected gawking at just about everything in the VR version of <em>Hellblade: Senua&#39;s Sacrifice</em>. That game already looked impressive on a normal monitor, but in 5K VR I could appreciate Senua&#39;s intricate character model even more.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e3556280-eb10-11eb-b21f-bf58f5bd8c30" alt="HTC Vive Pro 2" data-uuid="2f9c6e5f-6b10-3211-abeb-510c51cbfae4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>As impressive as everything looked, though, I really wish HTC had upgraded the Pro 2&#39;s controllers. Its full kit includes the same enormous wands that came with the original Vive in 2016. They work decently enough, but they&#39;re not nearly as ergonomic as Oculus&#39;s touch controllers, or even the Focus 3&#39;s gamepads. They&#39;re particularly archaic after experiencing Valve&#39;s hand-tracking Steam VR controllers, which are bundled with the Index. Since it&#39;s a SteamVR headset as well, you could always use the Index gamepads with the Pro 2, but that&#39;s another $280 on top of an already expensive headset.</p><p>It also would have been nice to see HTC Vive upgrade the Pro 2&#39;s design a bit. It&#39;s still very comfortable, thanks to its plush cushioning along the front and back, as well as its balanced weight distribution. But the company could have taken a few cues from the Valve Index. Near-field speakers would have been a solid upgrade from on-ear headphones, especially since the Pro 2&#39;s cans tended to make my head feel warm. The headset&#39;s displays also generate a decent amount of heat as well, which led to some sweaty play sessions.</p><section data-eng-breakout="b0517a70dc3e47d6b435c5e237d35897" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e35848b0-eb10-11eb-af55-098a6d678d74" alt="HTC Vive Pro 2"></section><p>Setting up the Vive Pro 2 also takes a bit of work, but that shouldn&#39;t be a surprise to VR heads. It requires having two SteamVR base stations set up in opposite corners of your room, as well as USB 3.0 and DisplayPort cables running to a breakout box. If you&#39;ve already got base stations from the original Vive Pro or Valve Index, they&#39;ll still work. And if you don&#39;t, be sure to pick up the full Pro 2 kit, which includes the base stations and VR wands.</p><p>To get the most out of the Vive Pro 2, you&#39;ll also need to make sure you&#39;ve got some serious graphics power. I tested it on a system running an NVIDIA RTX 3080 Ti, AMD Ryzen 7 5800X and 32GB of RAM. That was enough to get smooth performance at the headset&#39;s full resolution, though I couldn&#39;t tell if I was always reaching 120fps to fill its refresh rate. I didn&#39;t notice any stuttering or slowdown, though. True VR aficionados typically stuff even more absurdly powerful hardware in their systems, so I&#39;d wager they&#39;d have a similar experience. But you can probably forget about getting anything truly usable out of the Vive Pro 2 using its minimum system requirements (a GTX 1060 and 4th-gen Intel CPU).</p><p>If you&#39;re stuck with slower hardware, and you don&#39;t want to fight to the death for a new GPU, you&#39;ll be better off with a less demanding VR headset. The Oculus Quest 2 remains my main recommendation for most people, since it offers excellent standalone virtual reality, as well as a simple way to connect it to your PC to stream high-end experiences. HP&#39;s Reverb G2 is another solid option based on its resolution alone, though I&#39;m not the biggest fan of its controllers.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e3556282-eb10-11eb-abf7-28cf22db9b3a" alt="HTC Vive Pro 2" data-uuid="1ce0d5ea-8817-3bdd-8b97-47ad3bf256ae"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>I’ll admit, the Vive Pro 2 doesn’t sound like a great deal if you compare it to practically any other VR headset on the market, especially at its full $1,399 price. It’s in many ways an example of the greatest issue facing VR today: To get the best experiences, you’ll have to shell out a ridiculous amount of money, not to mention deal with a clunky setup process and annoying cables. That’s not stopping true virtual enthusiasts though — for them, and for businesses who need the highest quality VR around, the Vive Pro 2 is the new benchmark.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/htc-vive-pro-2-review-5k-vr-headset-133100685.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">062c2ddb-bc72-46b9-9a2a-cc4813619420</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627045675</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T13:11:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e3553b70-eb10-11eb-adbb-58d3a3230e93" width="2000" height="1045" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e3553b70-eb10-11eb-adbb-58d3a3230e93" width="2000" height="1045" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Devindra Hardawar/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HTC Vive Pro 2]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[HTC Vive Pro 2]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics' opening ceremony featured an orchestrated video game soundtrack]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Tokyo Olympics opening kicked off early this morning, and the parade of nations, where athletes walk through Japan&#39;s Olympic stadium, had a Japanese twist. A medley of videogame music, orchestrated, formed the soundtrack for the parade.&nbsp;</p><p>It all kicked off with the main theme from <em>Dragon Quest </em>— which sounds pretty Olympian outright — followed by hits from <em>Final Fantasy, Monster Hunter, Nier, Sonic, Chrono Trigger </em>and, er,<em> eFootball</em>. (That&#39;s the<a href="https://www.engadget.com/pro-evolution-soccer-efootball-104633019.html"> new name for Pro Evolution Soccer</a><em>,</em> in case you missed it.)</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There are some notable omissions — no Nintendo songs (Pokemon? Mario? Zelda?) being the biggest one — but some<em> Street Fighter II </em>songs might have fitted well into the competitive theme. Maybe the latter was too violent?&nbsp;</p><p>The march hasn&#39;t quite finished, and we&#39;ll try to embed a video here when we can. The USA will be the third-to-last country to march, as it&#39;s hosting the Olympics soon in LA — you might be able to catch the final parts of the march on the <a href="https://stream.nbcolympics.com/nbc-opening-ceremony">NBC live stream</a>.</p><p>With some help from <a href="https://www.nikkansports.com/olympic/tokyo2020/news/202107230000867.html"><em>Nikkan Sports</em></a>, here&#39;s the full tracklist.&nbsp;</p><p></p><p>- Dragon Quest “Overture: Roto’s Theme”</p><p>- Final Fantasy “Victory Fanfare”</p><p>- Tales of series  “Sorey’s Theme - The Shepherd”</p><p>- Monster Hunter “Proof of a Hero”</p><p>- Kingdom Hearts “Olympus Coliseum”</p><p>- Chrono Trigger, “Frog’s Theme”</p><p>- Ace Combat “First Flight”&nbsp;</p><p>- Tales of series “Pomp and Majesty”&nbsp;</p><p>- Monster Hunter “Wind of Departure”&nbsp;</p><p>- Chrono Trigger “Robo’s Theme”&nbsp;</p><p>- Sonic the Hedgehog “Star Light Zone”&nbsp;</p><p>- Winning Eleven (Pro Evolution Soccer) “eFootball walk-on theme”</p><p>- Final Fantasy “MAIN THEME” -&nbsp;</p><p>- Phantasy Star Universe “Guardians”&nbsp;</p><p>- Kingdom Hearts “Hero&#39;s Fanfare”&nbsp;</p><p>- Gradius (Nemesis) “01 ACT I-1”&nbsp;</p><p>- NieR “Song of the Ancients”</p><p>- SaGa series “The Orchestral SaGa - Legend of Music”</p><p>- Soul Calibur “The Brave New Stage of History”</p><p></p><p>Hopefully, a kind soul will make a Spotify playlist for us. Please?</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tokyo-olympics-parade-of-nations-video-game-music-125715215.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e95a444d-69f3-4ecd-8013-50a70e6740e4</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 12:57:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627046308</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T13:18:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b2584480-ebb1-11eb-9f7b-9db0e2dac741" width="4700" height="3133" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b2584480-ebb1-11eb-9f7b-9db0e2dac741" width="4700" height="3133" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Pilar Olivares / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tokyo 2020 Olympics - The Tokyo 2020 Olympics Opening Ceremony - Olympic Stadium, Tokyo, Japan - July 23, 2021.  Cecilia Carranza of Argentina and Santiago Lange of Argentina lead their contingent in the athletes parade during the opening ceremony REUTERS/Pilar Olivares]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OLYMPICS-2020-CEREMONY/OPENING]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The best Chromebooks you can buy]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="83597d012c314266be5298c49dceea4b"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ferZFNwzSE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Chromebooks have earned a reputation for being cheap and limited, but that hasn’t been true for a while now. The combination of years worth of software updates and laptop manufacturers  making more powerful and better-built  Chromebooks means there are a ton of good Chrome OS machines that work well as everyday drivers. Of course, there are an unnecessary number of Chromebooks on the market, so choosing the right one is easier said than done. Fortunately, I’ve tried enough of them at this point to know what to look for and what to avoid.</p><h2>What is Chrome OS, and why would I use it over Windows?</h2><p>That’s probably the number one question about Chromebooks. There are plenty of inexpensive Windows laptops on the market, so why bother with Chrome OS? Glad you asked. For me, the simple and clean nature of Chrome OS is a big selling point. If you didn’t know, it’s based on Google’s Chrome browser, which means most of the programs you can run are web based. There’s no bloatware or unwanted apps to uninstall like you often get on Windows laptops, it boots up in seconds, and you can completely reset to factory settings almost as quickly.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Of course, the simplicity is also a major drawback for some users. Not being able to install native software can be a dealbreaker if you’re, say, a video editor or software developer. But there are also plenty of people who do the vast majority of their work in a browser. Unless I need to edit photos for a review, I can do my entire job on a Chromebook.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/28c4bed0-cd37-11eb-a7ff-de290c52cdf7" alt="Acer Chromebook Spin 713" data-uuid="7bb7452a-b7d0-3f5e-b839-e8ce1a54bb00"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>Google has also added support for Android apps on Chromebooks, which greatly expands the amount of software available. The quality varies widely, but it means you can do more with a Chromebook beyond just web-based apps. For example, you can install the Netflix app and save videos for offline watching; other Android apps like Microsoft’s Office suite and Adobe Lightroom are surprisingly capable. Between Android apps and a general improvement in web apps, Chromebooks are more than just a browser.</p><h2>What do Chromebooks do well, and when should you avoid them?</h2><p>Put simply, anything web based. Browsing, streaming music and video and using various social media sites are among the most common things people do on Chromebooks. As you might expect, they also work well with Google services like Photos, Docs, Gmail, Drive, Keep and so on. Yes, any computer that can run Chrome can do that too, but the lightweight nature of Chrome OS makes it a responsive and stable platform.</p><p>As I mentioned before, Chrome OS can run Android apps, so if you’re an Android user you’ll find some nice ties between the platforms. You can get most of the same apps that are on your phone on a Chromebook and keep info in sync between them. You can also use some Android phones as a security key for your Chromebook or instantly tether your laptop to use mobile data.</p><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/358e6910-bb98-11ea-ab7d-e1659e861e4b" alt="Google Pixelbook" data-uuid=""><figcaption>Nathan Ingraham / Engadget </figcaption></figure><p>Google continues to tout security as a major differentiator for Chromebooks, and I think it’s definitely a factor worth considering. The first line of defense is auto-updates. Chrome OS updates download quickly in the background and a fast reboot is all it takes to install the latest version. Google says that each webpage and app on a Chromebook runs in its own sandbox, as well, so any security threats are contained to that individual app. Finally, Chrome OS has a self-check called Verified Boot that runs every time a device starts up. Beyond all this, the simple fact that you generally can’t install traditional apps on a Chromebook means there are a lot fewer ways for bad actors to access the system.</p><p>As for when to avoid them, the answer is simple: If you rely heavily on a specific native application for Windows or a Mac, chances are good you won’t find the exact same option on a Chromebook. That’s most true in fields like photo and video editing, but it can also be the case in fields like law or finance. Plenty of businesses run on Google’s G suite software, but more still have specific requirements that a Chromebook might not match. If you’re an iPhone user, you’ll also miss out on the way the iPhone easily integrates with an iPad or Mac, as well. For me, the big downside is not being able to access iMessage on a Chromebook.</p><p>Finally, gaming is almost entirely a non-starter, as there are no native Chrome OS games of note. You can install Android games from the Google Play Store, but that’s not what most people are thinking of when they want to game on a laptop. That said, Google’s game-streaming service Stadia has changed that long-standing problem. The service isn’t perfect, but it remains the only way to play recent, high-profile games on a Chromebook. It’s not as good as running local games on a Windows computer, but the lag issues that can crop up reflect mostly on Stadia itself and not Chrome OS.</p><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/4c76dcb0-bb99-11ea-9feb-9247a5659ee6" alt="Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook" data-uuid=""><figcaption></figcaption></figure><h2><br>What are the most important specs for a Chromebook?</h2><p>Chrome OS is lightweight and usually runs well on fairly modest hardware, so the most important thing to look for might not be processor power or storage space. That said, I’d still recommend you get a Chromebook with a relatively recent Intel processor, ideally an eighth-generation or newer M3 or i3. Most non-Intel Chromebooks I’ve tried haven’t had terribly good performance, though Lenovo’s Chromebook Duet 2-in-1 runs surprisingly well on its MediaTek processor.</p><p>As for RAM, 4GB is enough for most people, though 8GB is a better target if you have the cash, want to future-proof your investment or if you’re a serious tab junkie. Storage space is another place where you don’t need to spend <em>too</em> much; 64GB should be fine for almost anyone. If you plan on storing a lot of local files or loading up your Chromebook with Linux or Android apps, get 128GB. But for what it’s worth, I’ve never felt like I might run out of local storage when using Chrome OS.</p><p>Things like the keyboard and display quality are arguably more important than sheer specs. The good news is that you can find less expensive Chromebooks that still have pretty good screens and keyboards that you won’t mind typing on all day. Many cheap Chromebooks still come with tiny, low-resolution displays, but at this point there’s no reason to settle for anything less than 1080p. (If you’re looking for an extremely portable, 11-inch Chromebook, though, you’ll probably have to settle for less.) Obviously, keyboard quality is a bit more subjective, but you shouldn’t settle for a mushy piece of garbage.</p><p>Google has an Auto Update policy for Chromebooks, and while that’s not a spec, per se, it’s worth checking before you buy. Basically, Chromebooks get regular software updates automatically for about six years from their release date (though that can vary from device to device). <a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/a/answer/6220366?hl=en">This support page</a> lists the Auto Update expiration date for virtually every Chromebook ever, but a good rule of thumb is to buy the newest machine you can to maximize your support.</p><h2>How much should I spend?</h2><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/6b2e7aa0-bb99-11ea-bffe-c33913c3f803" alt="Samsung Galaxy Chromebook" data-uuid=""><figcaption>Nathan Ingraham / Engadget </figcaption></figure><p>Chromebooks started out notoriously cheap, with list prices often coming in under $300. But as they’ve gone more mainstream, they’ve transitioned from being essentially modern netbooks to the kind of laptop you’ll want to use all day. As such, prices have increased a bit over the last few years. At this point, you should expect to spend at least $400 if you want a solid daily driver. There are still many budget options out there that may be suitable as couch machines or secondary devices, but if you want a Chromebook that can be your all-day-every-day laptop, $400 is the least you can expect to spend.</p><p>There are also plenty of premium Chromebooks that approach or even exceed $1,000, but I don’t recommend spending that much. Generally, that’ll get you better design quality with more premium materials, as well as more powerful internals and extra storage space. Of course, you also sometimes pay for the brand name. But, the specs I outlined earlier are usually enough.</p><p>Right now, there actually aren’t too many Chromebooks that even cost that much. Google’s Pixelbook Go comes in $999 and $1,399 configurations, but the more affordable $650 and $850 options will be just as good for nearly everyone. Samsung released the $1,000 Galaxy Chromebook in 2020; this luxury device does almost everything right but has terrible battery life. Samsung quickly learned from that mistake and is now offering the Galaxy Chromebook 2 with more modest specs, but vastly better battery life at a much more affordable price (more on that laptop later). For the most part, you don’t need to spend more than $850 to get a premium Chromebook that’ll last you years.</p><h2>Engadget picks</h2><h3>Best overall: Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook</h3><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/f654d800-bb98-11ea-b7dd-2fd5be9d3296" alt="Google Pixelbook Go" data-uuid=""><figcaption>Nathan Ingraham / Engadget </figcaption></figure><p>Look beyond the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-flex-5-chromebook-review-170023587.html">awkward name</a> and you’ll find a Chromebook that does just about everything right that’s also a tremendous value. It gets all the basics right: The 13-inch 1080p touchscreen is bright, though it’s a little hard to see because of reflections in direct sunlight. It runs on a 10th-generation Intel Core i3 processor, the eight-hour battery life is solid, and the backlit keyboard is one of the best I’ve used on any laptop lately, Chromebook or otherwise. The Flex 5 is now a little over a year old, but it still holds up well and is even cheaper than it was when it first launched. It can now regularly be found for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:well under $400 on Amazon" href="https://amzn.to/36PVEEG">well under $400 on Amazon</a>. (As of this writing, it’s priced at $329.) That’s an outstanding value for a Chromebook this capable.</p><p>Naturally, Lenovo cut a few corners to hit that price. Most significantly, it only has 4GB of RAM and 64GB of storage. Normally, I wouldn’t recommend anyone buy a computer with those specs — but Chrome OS is far less dependent on local storage. Unless you were planning to store a ton of movies or install a huge variety of Android apps, 64GB is enough for moderately advanced use. I was concerned about the non-upgradeable 4GB of RAM, but my testing showed that the IdeaPad Flex 5 can run plenty of tabs and other apps without many hiccups. If you push things hard, you’ll occasionally have to wait for tabs to refresh if you haven’t viewed them recently, but other than that this is a solid performer, particularly for the price.</p><p>Other things in the IdeaPad Flex 5’s favor include that it has both USB-C and USB-A ports and a 360-degree convertible hinge. I personally don’t find myself flipping laptops around to tablet or stand mode very often, but it’s there if you like working in those formats. At three pounds and 0.66 inches thick, it’s not the lightest or slimmest option out there, but those specs are also totally reasonable considering the price.</p><p>Ultimately, the Ideapad Flex 5 hits the sweet spot for a large majority of potential Chromebook buyers out there, providing a level of quality and performance that’s pretty rare to find at this price point. That said, given this laptop has been out for over a year now, we’re keeping an eye out for any potential replacements Lenovo offers, as well as comparable options other manufacturers release.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook on Amazon - $430" href="https://amzn.to/36PVEEG">Buy Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook on Amazon - $430</a></p><h3>Upgrade picks: Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2, Acer Chromebook Spin 713</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/ab871810-96d5-11eb-b5fe-41c2db4984ea" alt="Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 laptop with its lid open sitting on a wooden table." data-uuid="7ab2a381-4ce9-3e15-8d3d-497f2294540d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Premium Chromebooks with more power, better design and higher prices have become common in recent years. If you want to step up over the excellent but basic Lenovo Flex 5, there are two recent options worth considering: <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Samsung&#x002019;s Galaxy Chromebook 2" href="https://fave.co/3mRQrTV">Samsung’s Galaxy Chromebook 2</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Acer&#x002019;s Chromebook Spin 713" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/9WA6Vj">Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713</a>.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-review-140021243.html">Galaxy Chromebook 2</a> is infinitely more stylish than most other Chromebooks, with a bright metallic red finish and a design that looks far better than the utilitarian Flex 5 and Chromebook Spin 713. As I mentioned earlier, Samsung’s Galaxy Chromebook 2 fixes some of the serious flaws we identified in the original. Specifically, the 2020 Galaxy Chromebook had terrible battery life and cost $999; this year’s model starts at $549 and can actually last seven hours off the charger. That’s not great, but it’s far better than the lousy four hours the original offered.</p><p>Samsung cut a few corners to lower the Galaxy Chromebook 2’s price. Most noticeable is the 1080p 13.3-inch touchscreen, down from the 4K panel on the older model. The good news is that the display is among the best 1080p laptop screens I’ve seen in a long time, and the lower resolution helps the battery life, too. The Galaxy Chromebook 2 is also a bit thicker and heavier than its predecessor, but it’s still reasonably compact.</p><p>Finally, the Galaxy Chromebook 2 has a 10th-generation Intel Core i3 processor rather than the Core i5 Samsung included last year. All these changes add up to a laptop that isn’t as ambitious, but is ultimately much easier to recommend. Instead of pushing to have the best screen in the thinnest and lightest body with a faster processor, Samsung pulled everything back a bit to make a better-priced but still premium laptop.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/28c53400-cd37-11eb-bd93-ef3c5be3c6e5" alt="Acer Chromebook Spin 713" data-uuid="5663ca34-693a-318a-96f6-e8e722956c82"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review-183025946.html">Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713</a>, by comparison, doesn’t look like much from the outside — it’s a chunky gray slab with little to distinguish it from many other basic laptops. While it doesn’t seem exciting, the Spin 713 is just as well-made as the Galaxy Chromebook 2, with a sturdy hinge and body. But what’s most interesting is the display, a 13.5-inch touchscreen with a 3:2 aspect ratio. That makes it a much better option than 1080p displays when you’re scrolling vertically through documents and webpages. It has a somewhat unusual resolution of 2,256 x 1,504, thanks to the taller aspect ratio, but it makes for a more pixel-dense display than you’ll find on your standard 13.3-inch, 1080p laptop. Long story short: The screen is great.</p><p>As for the rest of the hardware, the 11th-generation Intel Core i5 processor is more than enough power for most tasks, and the keyboard and trackpad are solid, if not the best I’ve used before. The same can be said for battery life: I got about the same six to seven hours using the Spin 713 as I did using the Galaxy Chromebook 2. I wish it were better in both cases, but it’s in line with other premium Chromebooks I’ve used lately.</p><p>The Spin 713 configuration that I tested costs $699, the same as the Galaxy Chromebook 2. Because I’m such a fan of the 3:2 display, I prefer the Spin 713 (which also has a more powerful processor), but the Galaxy Chromebook 2 is worth a look if you want a laptop that has a little more style and a better keyboard.</p><p>Last year, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Google&#x002019;s Pixelbook Go" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/ZdXGVg">Google’s Pixelbook Go</a> was our pick for the best premium model. It’s still an excellent choice and one of my favorite Chromebooks to use, but it’s almost two years old. Its age coupled with its aging 8th-generation Intel processor make it tougher to recommend. That said, it’s still one of the thinnest and lightest Chromebooks around, and it still handles everything I can throw at it. It also has the best keyboard I’ve used on any recent Chromebook. There’s still a lot to like, but it’s harder to justify spending $650 or more on it. Hopefully Google will release an updated version this fall.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 starting at $549" href="https://fave.co/3mRQrTV">Buy Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 starting at $549</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Acer Chromebook Spin 713 at Best Buy - $629" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/9WA6Vj">Buy Acer Chromebook Spin 713 at Best Buy - $629</a></p><h3>A good option for kids: Acer Chromebook 512</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/4f7ab540-ebb2-11eb-abfb-1eaab65915ef" alt="Acer Chromebook 512" data-uuid="e86216a4-72b6-31ce-b39b-1cd4c2fe1414"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Acer</div></figure><p>While Lenovo’s Flex 5 is inexpensive enough that you could get one for your kid, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Acer&#x002019;s Chromebook 512" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/Ea960Q">Acer’s Chromebook 512</a> might be a better option for young ones in your life. First off, it’s specifically built to take abuse. In addition to the military-rated (MIL-STD 810G) impact-resistant body, you can spill up to 330mL of liquid on the keyboard. A drainage system will flush it out and keep the insides working. (Note that I haven’t actually tried that.) The keyboard features “mechanically anchored” keys that should be harder for kids to pick off, too. Regardless of exactly how much water you can pour onto that keyboard, the Chromebook 512 should handle a child’s abuse better than your average laptop.</p><p>This computer isn’t a speed demon, but the Intel Celeron N4000 chip coupled with 4GB of RAM and 32GB of storage should be fine for basic tasks. The 12-inch screen isn’t a standout either, but it has the same taller 3:2 aspect ratio as Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713. That means you’ll get more vertical screen real estate than you would on the 16:9, 11-inch panels typically found in laptops of this class. (The Chromebook 512’s screen resolution is 1,366 x 912, whereas most 11-inch Chromebooks use a 1,366 x 768 panel.)</p><p>All in all, it’s a fairly modest computer, but grade-school kids, a computer that can take some abuse and runs an easy-to-use OS that’s well supported in education should fit the bill well. The Chromebook 512 is priced at $249.99 direct from Acer, but it&#39;s going for $219.99 as of this writing at other retailers.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Acer Chromebook 512 at Best Buy - $220" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/Ea960Q">Buy Acer Chromebook 512 at Best Buy - $220</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-chromebooks-160054646.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">71ca355e-be06-3ba2-a84a-3e55a19dbc84</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 12:45:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627045777</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T13:10:15+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[chromeos]]></category><category><![CDATA[chromebook]]></category><category><![CDATA[hp]]></category><category><![CDATA[thebuyersguide]]></category><category><![CDATA[google]]></category><category><![CDATA[commerce]]></category><category><![CDATA[samsung]]></category><category><![CDATA[feature]]></category><category><![CDATA[asus]]></category><category><![CDATA[bts2020]]></category><category><![CDATA[lenovo]]></category><category><![CDATA[laptops]]></category><category><![CDATA[gear]]></category><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/d8c18b40-bb97-11ea-a5fe-af97d6f8bf2f" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/d8c18b40-bb97-11ea-a5fe-af97d6f8bf2f" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixelbook Go]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixelbook Go]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Today's Google doodle is an anime-infused sports game]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has gone all-out on today&#39;s doodle to mark the start of the Tokyo Olympics. Select the modified logo and you can play &#39;Doodle Champion Island Games,&#39; an anime-infused title featuring sports mini-games. Google <a href="https://www.google.com/doodles/doodle-champion-island-games-july-24">says</a> it&#39;s the largest interactive doodle it&#39;s ever made.&nbsp;</p><p>You control Lucky the cat in a pixel-art landscape dotted with Japanese landmarks. Once you join one of several color-coded teams, you can take part in mini-games including table tennis and skateboarding. The controls are relatively straightforward, relying on various combinations of the arrow keys and spacebar. We won gold in the table tennis and pulled off kick-flips and fakies while skateboarding with ease. The doodle will stick around for the coming weeks, adding new games along the way.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The cut scenes are pretty lush, too. According to Google, the interactive doodle was made in collaboration with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/studio4c">STUDIO4°C</a>, the Tokyo-based animation house behind feature films like <em>Tekkonkinkreet. </em>It also worked on action-adventure puzzle game<strong>&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/catherine"><em>Catherine</em></a>. You can find out more about Doodle Champion Island Games in the behind-the-scenes video below.</p><div id="58ddfb0e1952447089123b4d4c5c13e9"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hy7tHQUR3TM?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-doodle-olympics-sports-game-115650463.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6a8e2572-d55f-408c-88df-d996c68d093c</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:56:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627042057</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T12:07:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/64622cf0-ebac-11eb-ba3f-e5dc35ddeee2" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/64622cf0-ebac-11eb-ba3f-e5dc35ddeee2" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's WH-1000XM3 ANC headphones fall to a new low of $170]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You no longer have to spend upwards of $200 on a quality pair of active noise-canceling (ANC) headphones. If you don&#39;t mind settling for a slightly older model, we highly recommend the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-09-18-sony-1000xm3-review.html">Sony WH-1000XM3</a>. Weeks after they dropped to $190, the wireless headphones are down another $20 at <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Best Buy;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Best Buy" href="http://bestbuy.7tiv.net/kjzYKx">Best Buy</a> to a new low of $170.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Best Buy;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Sony WH-1000XM3 at Best Buy - $170" href="http://bestbuy.7tiv.net/kjzYKx">Buy Sony WH-1000XM3 at Best Buy - $170</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We gave the XM3 a review score of 94 in September 2018 due to their excellent sound and comfort. Inside is a dedicated noise-canceling chip, the QN1, which does the heavy-lifting in terms of blocking background noise and boosting audio. For those unaccustomed to ANC, you may even notice new sounds on the tracks you love.  Audiophiles will also take to the customization offered through Sony&#39;s app that lets you fine-tune audio.</p><p>We&#39;d be remiss if we didn&#39;t mention the XM3&#39;s successors, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wh-1000xm4-headphones-review-150050779.html">XM4</a>. The newer headphones feature two major additions: Auto-pause and seamless multi-device listening. Hardly a deal-breaker when you consider they currently cost $348.&nbsp;</p><p>The XM3&#39;s design is also a crowdpleaser. The over-ear headphones come in black with bronze accents on the Sony logo and USB-C<strong>&nbsp;</strong>port. In our tests, we found the plush cushioning around the pads and headband to be significantly more comfortable than some of the alternatives. You can also fold them up when you&#39;re not using them, making them great for travel. The XM3 offer around 30 hours of battery life, more than enough for regular commuters. A well-powered USB-C connection also provides five hours of charge after just 10 minutes.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-wh1000xm3-headphones-deal-114006907.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">758b2f5a-4487-4ae3-aa49-e136859977d6</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:40:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627038081</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T11:01:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5deb7cd0-eba4-11eb-a7d5-56ab875a21dd" width="675" height="402" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5deb7cd0-eba4-11eb-a7d5-56ab875a21dd" width="675" height="402" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: LG adds a mic and speaker to its high-tech air-purifying mask]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember the high-tech face masks teased during the relatively early days of the COVID-19  pandemic? Not many have made it into stores (or on to our faces) just yet, but that’s given companies even more time to build in upgrades. Like LG, which has used the Tokyo Olympics (and the Team Thailand) to showcase its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-wearable-air-purifier-mic-114651832.html">improved wearable air-purifying mask</a>.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-wearable-air-purifier-mic-114651832.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/6a8a1eb0-eae1-11eb-afff-f5479425980c" style="height:666;width:1000;" alt="LG mask" data-uuid="e5eb4dab-810b-389a-a828-d50748f5cbed"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">LG</div></figure></a><p>Still packing three fans and a pair of HEPA-style filters, it now also features a smaller, lighter motor and a built-in mic, speaker and voice amplifier. LG says its VoiceOn tech will detect when you&#39;re talking and boost the sound so others can hear you — a common issue when you’re trying to communicate while wearing any kind of mask. This new version will arrive in Thailand in August.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/playstation-network-down-161951186.html">DNS issue pulls PSN, Steam, LastPass and more offline</a></h2><h3>Fortunately, a fix came a few hours later.</h3><p></p><p>Starting at approximately 11:20 AM ET yesterday, Downdetector began logging a spike in outage reports across a variety of online services and websites. Some of the more notable platforms people couldn’t connect to included, PSN, LastPass, TikTok, Steam and UPS. Visiting the PlayStation Store and other affected websites would return a DNS error. Akamai said it implemented a fix for the issue it was having with its Edge DNS service, and most sites and services returned to normal. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/playstation-network-down-161951186.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-protect-mark-zuckerberg-130242571.html">Facebook spent $23.4 million on Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s personal security</a></h2><h3>The CEO&#39;s protection costs far eclipsed those of other tech execs.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-protect-mark-zuckerberg-130242571.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f5b58420-eaeb-11eb-bb2f-1723f3b29589" alt="Facebook Inc. CEO Mark Zuckerberg is escorted by security guards as he departs New York City&#39;s Sheraton Hotel May 7, 2012. Facebook Inc kicked off its IPO roadshow in New York on Monday, attracting hundreds of investors to the Sheraton as the world&#39;s largest social network aims to raise about $10.6 billion, dwarfing the coming-out parties of tech companies like Google Inc and granting it a market value close to Amazon.com Inc&#39;s.   REUTERS/Eduardo Munoz    (UNITED STATES - Tags: BUSINESS SCIENCE TECHNOLOGY)" data-uuid="505e77c1-209d-3f13-8d75-3440133ef8f8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Eduardo Munoz / reuters</div></figure></a><p>A new analysis of the security expenses racked up by Silicon Valley giants shows they collectively spent $46 million to safeguard their top brass last year. Of that, $23.4 million alone was spent on Facebook chief Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s personal security, up from $20.4 million in 2019, according to a report by <em>Protocol</em>. In comparison, Jeff Bezos paid $1.6 million in personal security costs. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-protect-mark-zuckerberg-130242571.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html">Activision Blizzard sued by California over alleged sexist culture</a></h2><h3>Female employees deal with constant sexual harassment, the complaint said.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/eab98e40-eac8-11eb-aefb-94d36d9a725a" alt="UKRAINE - 2021/06/18: In this photo illustration, Activision Blizzard logo of a video game company is seen on a smartphone screen in front of Blizzard Entertainment logo. (Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)" data-uuid="f1aca9ce-2890-3515-acf4-3632e2cd7d9d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">SOPA Images via Getty Images</div></figure></a><p>Activision Blizzard is facing a lawsuit filed by the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing for fostering what the agency describes as a &quot;frat boy&quot; workplace. The DFEH sued the company that owns the Call of Duty series and <em>Overwatch</em> after a two-year investigation. It said at the company, in addition to receiving smaller salaries than their male counterparts, female employees were allegedly subjected to constant sexual harassment. Activision Blizzard, denies DEFH&#39;s allegations, adding that the lawsuit &quot;includes distorted, and in many cases false, descriptions of Blizzard&#39;s past.&quot; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/slack-salesforce-acquisition-complete-060457876.html">Slack is now officially part of Salesforce</a></h2><h3>The messaging app cost $27.7 billion.</h3><p></p><p>Messaging app Slack is now officially a part of Salesforce after completing a deal worth $27.7 billion. The IRC-style client, which cost 27.7 times as much as Instagram when bought by Facebook, will now operate as a standalone unit inside the computing giant. Salesforce intends to use the $27.7 billion Slack as the new interface of Customer 360, its tool for managing its many apps. It also puts Salesforce, which paid, I repeat, $27.7 billion for Slack, into an antitrust war with Microsoft, after the Windows maker bundled Microsoft Teams with its Office suite. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/slack-salesforce-acquisition-complete-060457876.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/framework-laptop-review-150001399.html">Framework’s modular laptop is uncontroversial on purpose</a></h2><h3>It’s a laptop designed for the right to repair movement.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/framework-laptop-review-150001399.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e1867930-e93f-11eb-8de5-0d0581187a5b" alt="Framework Laptop Hero Image" data-uuid="d5a7ef23-e2fe-38d2-bd6b-eb1e66dce77a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Daniel Cooper</div></figure></a><p>The right to repair movement is all about giving users the right to make basic repairs to their devices without too much fuss. But many companies make it very difficult to get your smartphone or laptop screen replaced after a bump. Framework is a company that has designed its first laptop to be entirely user-serviceable, and easy enough that anyone can do so. Dan Cooper put the machine through its paces, and what it lacks in battery life and sound, it more than makes up for in repairability. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/framework-laptop-review-150001399.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-nord-2-5-g-impressions-release-date-price-144511154.html">The OnePlus Nord 2 5G makes another good argument for ignoring expensive smartphones</a></h2><h3>But if you&#39;re in the US, you won&#39;t see it.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-nord-2-5-g-impressions-release-date-price-144511154.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b6f2c730-eae0-11eb-bfe3-c73cce194ce4" alt="OnePlus Nord 2 5G hands-on" data-uuid="4d8987f9-5ea2-3e42-8d1c-4b123fa9e7d1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Mat Smith, Engadget</div></figure></a><p>OnePlus has an unusual problem. It’s making very good flagship smartphones these days, but at the same time, it’s still chasing status as a flagship phone killer. That’s where its Nord series comes in, offering premium-looking (and feeling) smartphones at the fraction of a price of flagship devices. The Nord 2 5G is a similar proposition to the original Nord, with some camera improvements and a new processor rounding out the biggest changes. The £399 (roughly $458 before tax) Nord 2 has a slightly more premium style similar to its expensive relatives, like the $729 OnePlus 9. But while it might look the part, is it as good? Mat Smith tested the phone out for a few days. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oneplus-nord-2-5-g-impressions-release-date-price-144511154.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/jack-dorsey-bitcoin-world-peace-171030828.html">Jack Dorsey hopes bitcoin can bring about world peace</a></h2><h3>He said issues with the current monetary system distract &#39;from the bigger problems.’</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/jack-dorsey-bitcoin-world-peace-171030828.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/8a042e00-8e36-11eb-9b3b-ed25a3476562" alt="Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey testifies during a remote video hearing held by subcommittees of the U.S. House of Representatives Energy and Commerce Committee on " data-uuid="e3c42753-d64c-3c6b-927f-83e29e35de24"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Handout . / reuters</div></figure></a><p>Twitter and Square CEO Jack Dorsey has long been a bitcoin enthusiast. In fact, he&#39;s so optimistic about the cryptocurrency, he reckons it could bring about a more peaceful planet.  During a video discussion on cryptocurrency with Elon Musk, another vocal cryptocurrency figure, and Cathie Wood, chief executive of Square stakeholder ARK Invest, he said:</p><p>“My hope is that it creates world peace or helps create world peace. We have all these monopolies off balance, and the individual doesn’t have power, and the amount of cost and distraction that comes from our monetary system today is real and it takes away attention from the bigger problems.” <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jack-dorsey-bitcoin-world-peace-171030828.html"><strong>Continue Reading</strong></a>.</p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><strong>But wait, there’s more...</strong></h2><p></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/playstation-5-apple-tv-plus-six-months-free-trial-152055045.html">PlayStation 5 owners now get six free months of Apple TV+</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/introducing-engadgets-2021-back-to-school-gift-guide-160004263.html">Introducing Engadget&#39;s 2021 Back to School gift guide!</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/battlefield-2042-portal-mode-customs-180008313.html">Battlefield 2042&#39;s secret third mode is &#39;Portal&#39;</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-second-factory-capacity-battery-cells-193825530.html">Rivian is planning to build a second EV factory in the US</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-4k-2021-new-siri-remote-deal-amazon-181228166.html">Engadget Deals: The Apple TV 4K (64GB) is on sale for $180 right now</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-lg-high-tech-air-purifying-mask-111534812.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bc40cb67-9e29-4f13-9f66-f105acdc5270</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627036548</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T10:36:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/27330850-eba1-11eb-b7fa-b997a919e594" width="1440" height="959" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/27330850-eba1-11eb-b7fa-b997a919e594" width="1440" height="959" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LG]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG Puricare Mask]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG Puricare Mask]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Astronomers spot possible moon-forming region for the first time]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While scientists have found plenty of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-tess-2200-exoplanets-184133840.html">exoplanets</a> over the years, they&#39;ve yet to spot to moons orbiting those worlds outside our solar system. Now, a group of astronomers has <a href="https://www.eso.org/public/archives/releases/sciencepapers/eso2111/eso2111a.pdf">discovered</a> (PDF) what&#39;s believed to be a region with exomoons-in-the-making for the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/science/moon-forming-region-seen-around-planet-another-solar-system-2021-07-22/">first time</a>. Myriam Benisty and team from the University of Grenoble found the disk of dust — the moon-forming region — around a young exoplanet in a star system dubbed PDS 70 located 370 light years from Earth.&nbsp;</p><p>The team found the first protoplanet (PDS 70b) in the system back in 2018 using European Southern Observatory&#39;s Very Large Telescope in Chile. A year later, they found another young gas giant (PDS 70c) using the same equipment. The astronomers believe based on the data they have that the star system is only 10 million years old and that both gas giants are several times bigger than Jupiter. To know more about the system, they focused all other possible instruments on it, including the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-03-14-earths-largest-telescope-supercomputer.html">Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array</a>. ALMA is made up of 66 short-wavelength radio dishes, and its observations made it possible to spot the dust around PDS 70c.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The disk of dust spans a distance slightly wider than that between Earth and the Sun, and there&#39;s enough mass in there for three moons the same size as ours. Benisty says the moons may have already formed, but  there&#39;s no conclusive proof yet because they can&#39;t be seen with ALMA. According to <a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2021/07/astronomers-spy-possible-moons-making-distant-star-system"><em>Science</em></a>, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-05-27-extremely-large-telescope-construction-begins.html">Extremely Large Telescope</a>, which will be the world&#39;s largest optical telescope when it&#39;s built, may have the power to see if the moons have already formed around the protoplanet. The telescope is still under construction, though, and scientific operations won&#39;t start <a href="https://www.eso.org/public/announcements/ann21008/">until 2027</a> at the earliest.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/astronomers-spot-moon-forming-region-102240266.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c77923d2-fd82-421f-ac74-e2e37eed105b</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:22:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627035828</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T10:24:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7ede8240-eb98-11eb-bfeb-255b791d5cb0" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7ede8240-eb98-11eb-bfeb-255b791d5cb0" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ALMA (ESO/NAOJ/NRAO)/Benisty et al]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[This image, taken with the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA), in which ESO is a partner, shows wide (left) and close-up (right) views of the moon-forming disc surrounding PDS 70c, a young Jupiter-like planet nearly 400 light-years away. The close-up view shows PDS 70c and its circumplanetary disc centre-front, with the larger circumstellar ring-like disc taking up most of the right-hand side of the image. The star PDS 70 is at the centre of the wide-view image on the left. Two planets have been found in the system, PDS 70c and PDS 70b, the latter not being visible in this image. They have carved a cavity in the circumstellar disc as they gobbled up material from the disc itself, growing in size. In this process, PDS 70c acquired its own circumplanetary disc, which contributes to the growth of the planet and where moons can form. This circumplanetary disc is as large as the Sun-Earth distance and has enough mass to form up to three satellites the size of the Moon.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Wide and close-up views of a moon-forming disc as seen with ALMA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Corning's new Gorilla Glass protects smartphone cameras while letting in more light]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having conquered phone displays, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/corning">Corning</a> is bringing Gorilla Glass to handset cameras. The company&#39;s DX and DX+ range of damage-resistant glass will next be <a href="https://www.corning.com/gorillaglass/worldwide/en/news/news-releases/2021/07/corning-expands-corning-gorilla-glass-composite-products-to-optimize-performance-of-mobile-device-cameras.html">available</a> for mobile camera lens covers, starting with Samsung devices. Alongside the added protection, Corning claims its tech can improve the optical performance of smartphone cameras.&nbsp;</p><p>According to the company, DX glass essentially results in less light being reflected by the camera cover lens. Currently, even with the use of an anti-reflective coating, around 92 percent of transmitted light enters a smartphone camera. Corning says that with DX/DX+ on the outside a camera lens can capture 98 percent of light, helping to reduce optical issues like ghosting. These reflections are usually caused by a bright light source during daylight or in low-light conditions. Lens hoods and coatings applied to lens surfaces can help to suppress ghosting, also known as ghost reflections.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Some smartphone makers are already working with specialist suppliers to address the problem. Both <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-xperia-1-ii-review-4k-camera-pro-best-phone-in-years-150049871.html">Sony</a> and <a href="https://cn.engadget.com/vivo-x60-pro-plus-123326888.html">Vivo</a> use a Zeiss coating to boost light transmission while reducing flares, ghosting and reflections on their high-end phones.</p><p>But, Corning also offers the added benefit of durability and has strong ties with the biggest smartphone makers in the field. The company says its DX glass is scratch resistant and that DX+ approaches the resistance of Sapphire, which is used in high-end watches thanks to its Grade 9 on the Mohs scale — a system for rating the hardness of various minerals. It could even allow you to finally ditch that smartphone case.</p><p>Gorilla Glass is now featured on 8 billion devices by more than 45 major brands, according to Corning. While Gorilla Glass DX is also available on more than 30 million wearables. Recognizing its integral role as a supplier, Apple poured $450 million into the company as part of two separate investments in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-05-12-apple-corning-advanced-manufacturing-fund.html">2017</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-17-apple-investment-250-million-corning-glass.html">2019</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/corning-gorilla-glass-smartphone-cameras-091722946.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3b4e0d1d-7349-41e2-8619-b45434906ac4</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 09:17:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627031846</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T09:17:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Smart Phones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5b909ab0-eb95-11eb-a93e-359652a3312c" width="2866" height="1604" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5b909ab0-eb95-11eb-a93e-359652a3312c" width="2866" height="1604" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Corning]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Corning]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Corning]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kaseya deploys a master decryption key to unlock systems hit by REvil attack]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back on July 2nd, Russia-linked ransomware group REvil <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kaseya-ransomware-cyberattack-155719139.html">staged</a> what ended up as a massive attack on IT management software giant Kaseya, as well as its clients and their customers. The group took advantage of vulnerabilities in the Kaseya software companies use to send out updates to computer networks, allowing it to distribute ransomware to as many as 1,500 businesses and organizations worldwide. Most of them are just small businesses, and some of the victims in New Zealand are schools, which aren&#39;t your typical ransomware targets. Now, Kaseya has <a href="https://www.kaseya.com/potential-attack-on-kaseya-vsa/">announced</a> that it has obtained a universal decryptor and will help those &quot;impacted by the incident.&quot;</p><p>REvil originally demanded a payment of $70 million for a universal decryptor that will unlock the data owned by victims of the July 2nd attack. In mid-July, however, the group suddenly fell off the face of the internet. The critical sites it uses to communicate with victims vanished shortly after President Biden revealed that he talked to Russian President Vladimir Putin about ransomware attacks originating from his country. It&#39;s still unclear if the group disappeared from the internet as a result of that talk, of an offensive cyber operation conducted by US authorities or of something else entirely.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In its announcement, Kaseya said it &quot;obtained the tool from a third party&quot; and that it worked with software company Emsisoft to confirm that it can unlock victims&#39; data. It also said that it formed teams to actively help &quot;customers affected by the ransomware to restore their environments&quot; and that its representatives will contact clients who haven&#39;t heard from the company yet.</p><p>When <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/kaseya-obtains-universal-decryptor-for-revil-ransomware-victims/"><em>BleepingComputer</em></a> asked Kaseya if it paid the ransom to obtain the key, the company replied that it &quot;can&#39;t confirm or deny that.&quot; The publication also asked the FBI if it was involved in obtaining the decryption key, but the agency refused to comment on an ongoing investigation. That means that key&#39;s origin is still a mystery, though we doubt its source matters for the victims that just want to access their locked data.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/kaseya-master-decryption-key-revil-attack-081230168.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c2a1a08e-521e-477f-9cc0-b8abacc3a64e</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 08:12:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627028018</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T08:13:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/ec8e6300-447c-11eb-9afd-751a15e105d0" width="8660" height="5773" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/ec8e6300-447c-11eb-9afd-751a15e105d0" width="8814" height="5876" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AndreyPopov via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Worried Businessman Looking At Laptop With Ransomware Word On The Screen At The Workplace]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Person Looking At Laptop Screen]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NASA's InSight probe reveals the first detailed look at the interior of Mars]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NASA&#39;s InSight lander <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-26-nasa-insight-lander-arrived-on-mars.html">arrived on Mars</a> in 2018 to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-20-nasa-insight-lander-seismometer-positioned.html">learn about its interior</a> by monitoring &quot;marsquakes,&quot; and now the project is starting to really pay off. NASA has <a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/news/8996/nasas-insight-reveals-the-deep-interior-of-mars/">announced</a> that researchers have mapped the red planet&#39;s interior and discovered some big surprises and major differences with Earth.&nbsp;</p><p>The map is the first ever of the interior of another planet. Compared to Earth, Mars has a thicker crust, thinner mantle layer and a bigger, less dense and more liquid core than expected. That in turn suggests that Mars may have formed millions of years before our planet, when the sun itself was still not fully formed.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;It gives us our first sample of the inside of another rocky planet like Earth, built out of the same materials but very, very different,&quot; University of Cambridge seismologist Sanne Cottaar (who wasn&#39;t involved in the project) told the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/nasas-insight-lander-gives-first-look-at-mars-interior-yielding-a-big-surprise-11626976810"><em>Wall Street Journal</em></a>. “It is impressive.”</p><p>Constructing a map from the limited data provided by InSight was no easy feat. The probe only recorded quakes from one location and has just a single seismometer, for one thing. And Mars — while seismically active — <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-25-nasa-insight-marsquakes.html">didn&#39;t have</a> any quakes larger than around 4 on the Richter scale.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/c5fa7980-eb80-11eb-b0da-6344cbeeb430" alt="NASA&#39;s Insight reveals the first detailed look at the interior of Mars" data-uuid="5b205496-3f87-30ea-bd61-b086e4323c7f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Science</div></figure><p>Still, taking that data, along with planet&#39;s magnetism and orbital wobbles, scientists were able to create a detailed map. The planet&#39;s innermost core was found to have a diameter of around 2,275 miles, larger than previously thought. Given the mass of the planet as a whole, that implies that the iron/nickel core likely contains lighter elements like sulfur, oxygen and carbon.&nbsp;</p><p>The crust, meanwhile, was found to be very old. It was also thicker in Mars&#39; southern highlands and thinner in the northern lowlands, which may have hosted oceans long ago. On average, it&#39;s between 15 and 45 miles thick and split into several layers of volcanic rock.</p><p>The mantle between the crust and core extends roughly 970 miles below the surface. It&#39;s thinner than Earth&#39;s and has a different composition which suggests the two planets arose from different materials when they formed. This “might be the simple explanation why we don’t see plate tectonics on Mars,” ETH Zurich geophysicist and study co-author Amir Khan told the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/22/science/mars-nasa-insight.html?smid=tw-nytimesscience&amp;smtyp=cur"><em>New York Times</em></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The results has given scientists new insight into not just the inside of Mars, but how rocky planets form in general. That will help them develop new theories about planet formation that could become particularly valuable in the near future, when new instruments like the James Webb Space Telescope will allow astronomers to scan exoplanets around the galaxy. NASA will reveal more about its findings in a live event <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/nasa-s-insight-reveals-the-deep-interior-of-mars">later today</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nasas-insight-reveals-the-first-detailed-look-at-the-interior-of-mars-071812860.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">97363ad9-9af4-4317-9845-ab64a7ec69d3</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 07:18:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627043153</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T12:26:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fb021040-ebb0-11eb-bcbf-7831f70ace54" width="976" height="654" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fb021040-ebb0-11eb-bcbf-7831f70ace54" width="976" height="654" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NASA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A photograph of Mars' surface from the InSight lander probe]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Mars InSight]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla Powerwall owners can sign up to help balance California's energy grid]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tesla has launched a new program that will allow Powerwall owners to kick power back to the grid in times of high usage. The &quot;Tesla Virtual Power Plant&quot;  is now entering a beta phase, letting customers sign up, albeit without any compensation for the time being.&nbsp;</p><p>When it first announced the program last week, Tesla noted that &quot;the California grid operator forecasts a continued need for Californians to support the grid through 2021.&quot; That could be a big understatement, as the grid is expected to be heavily stressed over the rest of the summer because of record high temperatures boosting demand, along with a severe drought that could reduce output from hydroelectric plants.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Enrollment is now open for &quot;PG&amp;E, SDG&amp;E and SCE customers who own Powerwall and solar,&quot; Tesla said in a news release. &quot;Enrolling requires the <a href="https://www.tesla.com/support/tesla-app">Tesla app</a> 3.10.14 and a new Powerwall firmware version which will be released soon.&quot;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e0230fe0-eb74-11eb-b65d-aca15bed2882" style="height:324;width:815;" alt="Tesla Powerwall virtual power plant event notification" data-uuid="6f354170-0c7e-396e-ab17-238d288d98d5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Tesla</div></figure><p>So how will it work? Tesla gave an example showing that the app will give you a push notification warning a few hours ahead of any grid stress events. It will also show the time period that the event will impact your Powerwall usage, as shown above.</p><p>&quot;Depending on the forecasted severity of the event, your Powerwall may prioritize charging from your solar system in advance of the event to help shift your home’s grid use to earlier in the day,&quot; Tesla explained. &quot;If Powerwall fully charges before an event, your solar system will resume powering your home and export any excess power to the grid.&quot;</p><p>Tesla noted that customers will not be compensated for contributing to the Virtual Power Plant, though it encouraged users to join up for what it called a &quot;public good.&quot; However, customers already on net metering programs will be compensated for any power sent back to the grid as usual, <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/07/22/tesla-releases-details-virtual-power-plant-public-good-without-compensation/"><em>Electrek</em></a> noted.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-powerwall-owners-can-now-help-balance-the-grid-in-california-052917432.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0bfa0f75-4de9-4a0d-8822-5fe000d60826</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 05:29:17 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627018160</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T05:29:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/87de6b90-eb6f-11eb-9fdf-380227eb1d69" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/87de6b90-eb6f-11eb-9fdf-380227eb1d69" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Tesla]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tesla Powerwall owners can now help balance the grid in California]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tesla Powerwall owners can now help balance the grid in California]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM's hands-free Super Cruise is coming to six more Cadillacs in 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Beginning the first quarter of next year, GM will make its advanced semi-autonomous driving assistant, Super Cruise, available on six more Cadillac models including the Escalade, CT4,CT5, Silverado, Hummer EV, and Sierra.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;We’re excited to expand Super Cruise to even more new models with additional capabilities to provide our customers with even more opportunities to go hands-free,” Mario Maiorana, Super Cruise chief engineer, said in a prepared statement. “The additional Super Cruise-enabled vehicles and new features are an important step toward our goal of enabling hands-free driving 95 percent of time and getting people more comfortable with letting go of the wheel.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>These vehicles will also enjoy a number of additional features that the current generation of Super Cruise users do. These include Trailering capability which enables drivers to engage the system even if they&#39;re towing a load behind them, Automatic lane change, and Enhanced navigation display, which will highlight Super Cruise-compatible routes and roads along the way to your driving destination. Now, if you already own a Super Cruise enabled vehicle and want to upgrade to the more advanced system, you are in luck assuming you bought your GM SUV in 2021 as that is the only model year getting an upgrade. If you bought between 1997, when Super Cruise was first introduced, and 2020, sorry but no dice, you&#39;ll have to change your own lanes like a schmuck.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gms-hands-free-super-cruise-is-coming-to-six-more-cadillacs-in-2022-040101614.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">334503d2-f9bd-421e-ae9a-b2c0bcb1dbcd</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 04:01:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626987074</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T20:51:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Travel & Tourism]]></category><category><![CDATA[Travel Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b6744160-eb2d-11eb-b5dd-2e74e6ec1172" width="5700" height="3800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b6744160-eb2d-11eb-b5dd-2e74e6ec1172" width="5700" height="3800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[GM]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The CT4-V Blackwing]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The CT4-V Blackwing]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple Music's lossless and spatial audio streaming arrive on Android devices]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple has recently updated its Music app for Android, but it left out a couple of new features you may have been waiting for: support for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-lossless-now-available-on-supported-devices-094540982.html">lossless streaming</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-dolby-atmos-spatial-audio-now-available-174616634.html">spatial audio</a>. <em>Engadget</em> has confirmed that the tech giant has started rolling out the new high-quality streaming options, even though they aren&#39;t specifically mentioned in the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apple.android.music&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US">Android app&#39;s</a> release notes.&nbsp;</p><p>The company first <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-lossless-dolby-atmos-131659010.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s making the streaming options available to subscribers at no extra charge back in May, promising immersive experiences similar to what Tidal HiFi and Amazon Music HD offer. Both options arrived for Apple users back in June, but they&#39;re limited to certain albums. Apple promised to make Dolby Atmos content easy to find with curated playlists and special badges, though, and it said lossless streaming will eventually come to its entire catalog with 75 million tracks.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You will need to use compatible speakers or headphones to be able to enjoy these new immersive listening experiences, though. Apple previously said that AirPods and Beats earbuds and headphones with an H1 or W1 chip, as well as the speakers on the latest iPhones, iPads and Macs will work with Dolby&#39;s spatial audio. You&#39;d have to look up your device&#39;s features to make sure it can also access spatial audio streaming. Meanwhile, lossless audio requires a wired connection and won&#39;t work with wireless audio devices.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-streaming-android-034510410.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bf10b0f1-6050-4e84-9791-0054161d95a3</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 03:45:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627011977</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T03:46:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/634f0ee0-eb62-11eb-ae57-34551c2d1e28" width="1306" height="873" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/634f0ee0-eb62-11eb-ae57-34551c2d1e28" width="1306" height="873" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instagram tests Limits feature to curb targeted harassment]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Instagram is testing a new feature called “Limits” that allows users to lock their accounts and limit any potential interactions when they feel they’re the target of harassment. In introducing the tool, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-no-longer-a-photo-sharing-153127352.html">Adam Mosseri</a>, the head of Instagram, referenced the recent Euro 2020 final, which saw <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/12/football/england-racist-abuse-bukayo-saka-jadon-sancho-marcus-rashford-euro-2020-final-spt-intl/index.html"><ins>three Black players</ins></a> on the English National team face a flood of harassment after England lost to Italy when the match went to a penalty shootout.</p><p>“Racism and hate speech have no place on Instagram,” Mosseri said in a video he <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CRot2ucpUoA/"><ins>shared on Thursday</ins></a>. “It is not only honestly fucked up to see people treated that way, but it breaks how Instagram works.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In trying to curb harassment on the platform, Mosseri said Instagram plans to try to reduce hate speech to “as close to zero as we possibly can.” However, knowing that it will likely be impossible to completely eradicate all forms of racism from the app, the company also plans to give people new tools that will allow them “to take some power back.” That’s where Limits fits in. “We know that people sometimes are in temporary moments of real risk and pain, and we need to give them tools to protect,” Mosseri said of the feature.</p><p>Ahead of wide rollout, Instagram is currently testing Limits in select countries across the world. In the meantime, Mosseri promised the company would have more to share on how it plans to tackle racism on Instagram in the coming months.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/instagram-limits-feature-test-223844994.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">601f9280-6972-45e3-b31e-ecd9caa7bc93</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:38:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626991495</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T22:05:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/30e23da0-e979-11eb-bbaf-60938b4d69ff" width="4109" height="2560" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/30e23da0-e979-11eb-bbaf-60938b4d69ff" width="4109" height="2560" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Instagram app is seen on a smartphone in this illustration taken, July 13, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TECH-INSTAGRAM/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here's everything EA announced at its Play Live 2021 event]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="291f998f3a5c4fabac3bf664c1083511"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZggqHAnv3tY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>Electronic Arts held its EA Play Live 2021 event today. During the approximately 40-minute presentation, we got a first look at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/grid-legends-codemasters-ea-play-live-story-mode-175059123.html"><em>Grid Legends</em></a><em>, </em>a new entry in Codemasters&#39; ongoing racing franchise that will feature a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/grid-legends-codemasters-ea-play-live-story-mode-175059123.html">single-player story with live-action performances</a>. <em>Lost in Random</em>, the upcoming Tim Burton-inspired action-adventure game from <em>Fe</em> developer Zoink Games, also got a release date. It&#39;s coming out on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lost-in-random-september-10th-180420302.html">September 10th</a> on current and last-generation consoles, as well as PC. For Battlefield fans, EA offered a look at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/battlefield-2042-video-details-151958457.html"><em>2042</em></a>&#39;s new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/battlefield-2042-portal-mode-customs-180008313.html">Portal mode</a> that will allow fans to create their own custom match types that they can share with the game&#39;s community.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>But EA saved the best news for last. In a short teaser, the publisher confirmed Motive Studios is working on a remake of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/dead-space-ps5-xbox-series-x-pc-180518562.html"><em>Dead Space</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S. In addition to more modern graphics courtesy of Dice&#39;s Frostbite engine, EA promised gameplay improvements, as well as new story and character elements.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ea-play-live-2021-supercut-214303925.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">88e98a0b-8129-4e2b-9b07-557d0b0b9dc9</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 21:43:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626988334</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T02:19:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e0188700-eb10-11eb-8fff-1c3463e43aca" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e0188700-eb10-11eb-8fff-1c3463e43aca" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[EA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat just announced its largest user growth in years]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snapchat is enjoying its highest user growth in years, according to its <a href="https://investor.snap.com/events-and-presentations/events/event-details/2021/Snap-Inc-Q2-2021-Earnings/default.aspx">latest earnings report</a>. Daily active users have increased to 293 million, which is a 23 percent growth from this time last year. That’s the best Snap Inc has seen in a while; it tops the company’s prior best of 22 percent, which happened four years ago. The number even tops Twitter’s, which recently reported 206 million daily users in the second quarter.</p><p>Overall revenue also increased by a very impressive 116 percent to $982 million, which is its strongest growth rate yet. That’s faster than even that of Twitter and Facebook, at least right now.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The company also said that Spotlight, its TikTok-like feature that pays users for clips, has grown in popularity. Daily active users of Spotlight grew by 49 percent, and average daily content submissions have more than tripled.</p><p>Much of this growth can be attributed to pandemic lockdowns ending, as well as a much-improved Android app. In a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snap-q1-2021-earnings-224943122.html">prior earnings statement</a>, CEO Evan Spiegel said that  “as things began to open up in the United States in late February, we saw inflection points in key behaviors like Story posting and engagement with the Snap Map.” However, the recent surge of COVID-19 cases point toward an uncertain third quarter.&nbsp;</p><p>The company said it so far has not seen too much of a negative effect from Apple&#39;s rollout of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-14-5-users-reject-app-tracking-165309407.html">iOS 14</a>, which forces developers to ask users permission to track their data (often used for ad-targeting). Snap&#39;s business officer, Jeremi Gorman, said that the company actually saw relatively high opt-in rates compared to the rest of the industry.&nbsp;</p><p>Additionally, Spiegel is hopeful that the development of the app’s augmented reality platform will drive engagement even further. Users, for example, can now &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-shopping-creators-175728100.html">try on</a>&quot; clothes and accessories using the app, and the company also unveiled a new pair of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-spectacles-augmented-reality-180101040.html">Spectacles</a> that have AR built-in.</p><p>“We are pleased by the progress our team is making with the development of our augmented reality platform, and we are energized by the many opportunities to grow our community and business around the world,” he said. &quot;More than 200 million Snapchatters engage with AR every day on average, and over 200,000 creators use Lens Studio to build AR Lenses for our community.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-earnings-210932638.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fa85241e-05c8-4a1e-be59-1f80ed9e93a2</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 21:09:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626995260</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T23:07:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-09/b709e300-d8a6-11e9-b06f-00312702d819" width="5400" height="3600" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-09/b709e300-d8a6-11e9-b06f-00312702d819" width="5400" height="3600" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ASSOCIATED PRESS]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A banner for Snap Inc. hangs from the front of the New York Stock Exchange, Thursday, March 2, 2017, in New York. The company behind the popular messaging app Snapchat is expected to start trading Thursday after a better-than-expected stock offering. (AP Photo/Mark Lennihan)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Financial Markets Snap IPO]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Senate bill would create exception to Section 230 to limit health misinformation]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A week after Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy declared health misinformation an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-surgeon-general-health-misinformation-advisory-191241209.html">&quot;urgent threat&quot; to the US public</a>, Senators Amy Klobuchar of Minnesota and Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico have introduced new legislation that would modify <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-31-s230-repeal.html">Section 230</a> of the 1996 Communications Decency Act to strip liability protections from technology companies if their platforms help spread misinformation during a health crisis.</p><p>If passed, the Health Misinformation Act of 2021 would create an exception to Section 230 that would see social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter &quot;treated as the publisher or speaker of health misinformation&quot; when their platforms algorithmically amplify misleading health content. What falls under the definition of health-related misinformation would be decided by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. The exception would only apply during a public health crisis, which the HMS Secretary would have to declare beforehand.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In establishing a rationale for the change, the bill cites a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/anti-vaccine-misinformation-report-12-accounts-212245856.html">joint report</a> from the Center for Countering Digital Hate and Anti-Vax Watch that found that as much 73 percent of vaccine misinformation on Facebook can be linked to a group of 12 individuals known as the &quot;disinformation dozen.&quot; White House Press Secretary <a href="https://twitter.com/Acyn/status/1415725645875740672">Jen Psaki</a> recently referenced that same report, saying that many of those individuals are still active on the social network.</p><p>&quot;For far too long, online platforms have not done enough to protect the health of Americans. These are some of the biggest, richest companies in the world and they must do more to prevent the spread of deadly vaccine misinformation,&quot; Senator Klobuchar said in a statement. &quot;The coronavirus pandemic has shown us how lethal misinformation can be and it is our responsibility to take action.&quot;</p><p>The bill&#39;s introduction also follows a recent statement made by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/joe-biden-facebook-killing-people-vaccine-misinformation-195433641.html">President Joe Biden</a>. He said platforms like Facebook were &quot;killing people&quot; by not doing more to stop vaccine- and health-related misinformation. &quot;We will not be distracted by accusations which aren&#39;t supported by facts,&quot; a spokesperson for Facebook told Engadget after Biden made his comments. &quot;The facts show that Facebook is helping save lives. Period.&quot; The president later walked back his statement, noting the people using the platform to spread their misinformation were the ones doing harm but reiterated his belief that Facebook could do more to combat what was happening.</p><p>&quot;We have long supported common industry standards and section 230 reform,&quot; Kevin Martin, vice-president of public policy at Facebook said after the news broke. &quot;We believe clarification on the difficult and urgent questions about health-related misinformation would be helpful and look forward to working with Congress and the industry as we consider options for reform.&quot;</p><p><strong>Update 10:54PM ET</strong>: Added comment from Facebook.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/health-misinformation-act-2021-204010072.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5a8e606a-5d37-4d27-bd1a-cc778881cdc1</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:40:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627008985</ingested><modified>2021-07-23T02:56:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/64488f10-eb2b-11eb-9ff3-ff8d606cc1bf" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/64488f10-eb2b-11eb-9ff3-ff8d606cc1bf" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Elijah Nouvelage via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ATLANTA, GA - JULY 19: U.S. Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) attends a U.S. Senate Rules Committee Georgia Field Hearing on the right to vote at the National Center for Civil and Human Rights on July 19, 2021 in Atlanta, Georgia. Senate Democrats are trying to keep a focus on voting rights in an ongoing effort to pass the "For the People Act". (Photo by Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Senate Rules Committee Holds Field Heating In Atlanta On Georgia Voting Laws]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rivian is planning to build a second EV factory in the US]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Electric vehicle manufacturer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/rivian"><ins>Rivian</ins></a> is planning to build a second factory. The company may make battery cells as well as EVs at the plant, should it come to fruition. Rivian might make an announcement within the next couple of months and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/exclusive-amazon-backed-rivian-confirms-plan-second-us-assembly-plant-2021-07-22"><em><ins>Reuters</ins></em></a> reports construction could start next year.</p><p>Rivian spokesperson Amy Mast confirmed to the organization that the company is &quot;exploring locations for a second US manufacturing facility.&quot; Mast noted it&#39;s early in the process and didn&#39;t share additional details.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The company&#39;s first factory is in Normal, Illinois. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-rivian-electric-delivery-vans-san-francisco-141525649.html"><ins>Rivian</ins></a> employs around 7,000 people and a second plant would likely create hundreds of new jobs, which seems to be the reason why several states have reportedly made bids.</p><p>An additional factory would enable Rivian to increase capacity and have a 50 gigawatt-hour battery cell production line, according to the report. The location may also feature a product and technology center, and construction is likely to take place in phases. Meanwhile, Rivian reportedly has a goal of achieving net-zero carbon emissions at the plant as swiftly as possible.</p><p>Last week, Rivian <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-electric-r1t-pickup-r1s-suv-delay-180542789.html"><ins>delayed initial shipments</ins></a> of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-cold-weather-testing-171527674.html"><ins>R1T</ins></a> pickup by a couple of months to September and the R1S SUV to the fall. It blamed the effects of COVID-19 as a major factor. The pandemic also resulted in a shift in the timeline for the second factory, according to <em>Reuters</em>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rivian-second-factory-capacity-battery-cells-193825530.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">809cecad-293e-4250-b273-9dda0769133e</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:38:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626982707</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T19:38:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/f1b6edf0-93c5-11eb-bdfe-12c256795ebe" width="6415" height="4277" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/f1b6edf0-93c5-11eb-bdfe-12c256795ebe" width="6415" height="4277" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[REUTERS/Mike Blake]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Rivian EV pickup truck on display at an auto show, on stage by itself.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AUTOSHOW-LA/ELECTRICPICKUP]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google expands Android Auto's beta testing program]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has long run an Android Auto beta program, but joining it was almost impossible before today. Those who tried to take part often got an error message that said the program was maxed out. Thankfully, that&#39;s no longer the case. Google is expanding the program, giving anyone with an Android device and a willingness to put up with bugs the opportunity to test the platform&#39;s latest features before they&#39;re available to the public.</p><p>&quot;As a beta tester, you can help us build a better version of Android Auto. You can test how well new features work with your specific phone and vehicle in your part of the world,&quot; Google says of the initiative on a <a href="https://support.google.com/androidauto/answer/10961485">support page</a>. &quot;When you share your feedback, we&#39;ll use it to help plan improvements for future releases.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You can join the program by visiting the <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.google.android.projection.gearhead/">beta opt-in page</a> Google has set up. Click the &quot;Become a tester&quot; button, and then download the beta version of Android Auto from the Play Store. If you eventually decide using unstable software isn&#39;t all it&#39;s made out to be, you can <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.google.android.projection.gearhead/join">leave the program</a>.</p><p>With Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-12-beta-3-update-available-today-scrolling-screenshot-170040876.html">inching closer</a> to the official release of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-12-beta-hands-on-181528378.html">Android 12</a>, the company likely wants to avoid a repeat of last year&#39;s Android 11 release. While the operating system was buggy as a whole at release, Android Auto suffered from some <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-auto-problems-in-android-11-211241058.html">particularly rough bugs</a>. There were numerous audio issues and missing apps. In some instances, the software was also known to &#39;soft-brick&#39; devices like the Pixel 3 XL. So it&#39;s no surprise Google wants more help testing the software.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/android-auto-beta-test-program-190704773.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef326f30-af0f-481b-9b57-b28550c1ad11</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626980829</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T19:07:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Small Businesses]]></category><category><![CDATA[Utility Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/b3c07d80-9632-11eb-af69-9c2b71cc5c5e" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/b3c07d80-9632-11eb-af69-9c2b71cc5c5e" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Android Auto]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Android Auto]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Apple TV 4K (64GB) is on sale for $180 right now]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple gave its TV 4K set-top box some love this year by upgrading the internals and revamping its accompanying Siri remote. But it didn&#39;t change the price, which means you&#39;ll still pay at least $179 for it. However, Amazon has a new deal that knocks nearly $20 off the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:64GB Apple TV 4K" href="https://amzn.to/3kMMnFA">64GB Apple TV 4K</a>, bringing it down to $180. The base, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:32GB model" href="https://amzn.to/3x4yx3W">32GB model</a> has been on sale for $169 for a few weeks at this point, but this new deal essentially lets you get the extra-storage model at the base&#39;s original price.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Apple TV 4K (64GB) at Amazon - $180" href="https://amzn.to/3kMMnFA">Buy Apple TV 4K (64GB) at Amazon - $180</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We consider the 2021 Apple TV 4K to be the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-streaming-devices-media-players-123021395.html">best high-end streaming box</a> you can get, and it&#39;s even more attractive if you live in the Apple ecosystem. It runs on an A12 Bionic processor and it supports Dolby Vision and HDR video at 60fps, plus features like AirPlay 3 and screen mirroring. While navigating the interface of tvOS is a zippy experience, most people probably won&#39;t notice a huge performance difference between the old and new models.</p><p>What&#39;s really key to the new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-4k-review-2021-new-siri-remote-150054255.html">Apple TV 4K</a> is the redesigned Siri remote. Now, we&#39;re not saying the new remote is reason enough to upgrade if you&#39;re happy with your current Apple TV, but it does fix a lot of previous complaints we had. The new Siri remote is larger and easier to use, thanks in part to a revamped directional pad that makes controlling the gadget much smoother. The pad is also touch sensitive, so you can swipe between TV show and movie options more easily. We also found Siri to be even more useful on a device like the Apple TV, since queries tend to be more direct (&quot;Play <em>The Mandalorian</em>&quot; or &quot;Show me some new horror movies&quot;) than they are when calling upon the assistant from an iPhone or iPad.</p><p>Speaking of Siri commands, you can also ask the assistant on the Apple TV 4K to show you video feeds from your security cameras. The set-top box has a HomeKit hub built in, so you can connect various smart lights, locks and cameras to it. Video feeds from cameras, for example, will show up on your TV in picture-in-picture mode, so it won&#39;t totally interrupt the show you&#39;re watching.</p><p>The Apple TV 4K will be a tough sell for some since it&#39;s more expensive that competing streaming boxes (the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Roku Ultra" href="https://amzn.to/2UvT18w">Roku Ultra</a> is only $100, and often on sale for less), but those who spend most of their time with Apple products will find its conveniences and integrations worthwhile. Plus, Apple&#39;s rolling out <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-airpods-max-spatial-audio-tvos-macos-180128777.html">spatial audio to tvOS</a> later this year, which means you&#39;ll be able to get full Dolby Atmos sound from the Apple TV 4K when listening with AirPods Pro or AirPods Max.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-4k-2021-new-siri-remote-deal-amazon-181228166.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5a2bf95a-d817-47e6-90d7-a54cdbf81ef5</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:12:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626977550</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T18:12:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/e5549830-bfbe-11eb-bd29-331b18490ec1" width="2000" height="1189" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/e5549830-bfbe-11eb-bd29-331b18490ec1" width="2000" height="1189" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Devindra Hardawar/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple TV 4K (2021)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple TV 4K (2021)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Dead Space' is being remade for PS5, Xbox Series X/S and PC]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Dead Space</em> is getting a new chance at life. EA revealed a teaser trailer for a remastered version of the original <em>Dead Space</em>, showing off a terrifying necromorph-infested environment and not much else. Motive Studios is developing the game, and it&#39;s heading to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC.&nbsp;</p><div id="f32a5ca8ec454de99ae2f4a145d9eecb"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l5WeBNfX-og?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Here&#39;s how EA describes the new endeavor on YouTube: &quot;The sci-fi survival horror classic <em>Dead Space </em>returns, completely rebuilt from the ground up by Motive Studios to offer a deeper and more immersive experience. Harnessing the power of the Frostbite game engine and next generation consoles, this remake brings jaw-dropping visual fidelity and improvements to gameplay while staying true to the original.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Electronic-Arts-Announces-the-Return-of-Dead-Space-a-Remake-of-the-Sci-Fi-Classic-Survival-Horror-Game/default.aspx">EA says</a> the new version of <em>Dead Space</em> will include improved story, characters and gameplay mechanics.</p><p>The original <em>Dead Space</em> came out in 2008 for the Xbox 360, PS3 and PC, and it became an instant classic. The series taps into a space-based brand of horror, with terrifying alien creatures around every corner, creative weaponry, and the constant threat of crushing isolation. All of this should be even spookier on current hardware.</p><p>There&#39;s no word on a release window for the remastered <em>Dead Space</em> just yet.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/dead-space-ps5-xbox-series-x-pc-180518562.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">19a05949-5e47-432b-b86f-3d142a18a06c</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:05:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626978173</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T18:23:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/0fcb65f0-eb19-11eb-acff-36ff3c23093b" width="2540" height="1410" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/983d0e20-eb19-11eb-a773-b1722e7457d1" width="2540" height="1410" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[EA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Dead Space remake]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Dead Space remake]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tim Burton-inspired 'Lost in Random' comes to consoles and PC on September 10th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Electronic Arts will release <em>Lost in Random, </em>the latest entry in its ongoing Originals lineup, on September 10th, the publisher announced today during its EA Play Live event. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ea-lost-in-random-005438834.html">First announced last year</a>, the Tim Burton-inspired adventure game is the latest project from <em>Fe</em> developer Zoink. In <em>Lost in Random</em>, your character Even is on a mission to save her sister. A die named Dicey will join your quest, and their abilities are essential to your success. In its moment-to-moment gameplay, <em>Lost in Random </em>is a mix of a third-person adventure title and deck-building games like <em>Slay the Spire </em>and<em> Griftlands. </em>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><div id="cda4e27a3e524db08ac1def25d6dbb8e"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/diilMn5gSAg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>EA will release <em>Lost in Random </em>on Nintendo Switch, PC, Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S. On PC, it will be available on both Steam and Origin.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lost-in-random-september-10th-180420302.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3301cea1-bc06-42b0-a491-8b79f2fd4f7a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626977200</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T18:07:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/551b9150-eb16-11eb-9e3f-5ab1f6229ee8" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/551b9150-eb16-11eb-9e3f-5ab1f6229ee8" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[EA / Zoink]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lost in Random]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lost in Random]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042's secret third mode is 'Portal']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When EA and DICE revealed <a href="https://www.engadget.com/battlefield-2042-video-details-151958457.html"><em>Battlefield 2042</em></a> in June, they had to contend with a wave of leaks and spoiled surprises, but they were able to keep details about the game&#39;s third and final mode under wraps. Today, the secret&#39;s out. Battlefield Portal is the third mode in <em>Battlefield 2042</em>, and it&#39;s all about community interaction and user-created levels.</p><p>Battlefield Portal includes all seven maps from <em>2042</em>&#39;s All-Out Warfare mode, plus six classic environments from previous Battlefield titles. The classic maps are Battle of the Bulge and El Alamein from <em>Battlefield 1942</em>, Arica Harbor and Valparaiso from <em>Battlefield: Bad Company 2</em>, and Caspian Border and Noshahr Canals from <em>Battlefield 3</em>.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e0188700-eb10-11eb-8fff-1c3463e43aca" alt="Battlefield 2042" data-uuid="36173e80-41e3-33ae-9128-0690a77f542d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">EA</div></figure><p>The mode features pre-programmed, reimagined experiences from these past titles, including conquest, rush and team deathmatch. All of the maps, including the classic ones, will support matches of up to 128 players on PC, Xbox Series consoles and PlayStation 5. As with <em>Battlefield 2042</em>&#39;s main All-Out Warfare mode, matches on older-gen hardware will be capped at 64 players.</p><p>Here&#39;s where it gets <em>custom</em>. Along with the updated, old-school playgrounds, Battlefield Portal includes more than 40 weapons, more than 40 vehicles, and more than 30 gadgets from three theaters of war, plus all of the related content from <em>Battlefield 2042</em>. This means the M1 Garand, Panzerschreck, B17 Bomber, Spitfire, defibrillator and other fan-favorite tools are back.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e01cccc0-eb10-11eb-afed-28891fa33b79" alt="Battlefield 2042" data-uuid="5499ac24-f8f0-3f08-9d71-0ac3fe99e007"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">EA</div></figure><p>Factions are also returning to Battlefield Portal. On top of the specialists from <em>Battlefield 2042</em>, the mode features seven armies from the classic games, including the UK, US and Germany out of <em>1942</em>, and the US and Russia from <em>Bad Company 2</em>. Battlefield Portal also supports classic soldier archetypes like <em>Battlefield 3</em>&#39;s assault, recon, support and engineer roles.</p><p>All of this culminates in the Builder tool in Battlefield Portal. In Builder, players can design their own matches and share them with the community, adjusting a range of settings including the game logic itself. Players will have control over the maps and modes in their custom games, including traits like available factions, weapons and gear; the ability to toggle down sights or go prone; the size of the battle and conditions for victory.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e0144140-eb10-11eb-bbb4-5de70f586e77" alt="Battlefield 2042" data-uuid="7ff3a026-e81b-3847-ba21-bf4d04d6dd20"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">EA</div></figure><p>Players won&#39;t be able to edit any of the actual maps, but overall, Portal has an extremely rich customization mode. All progress in Battlefield Portal is shared across consoles, just like stats in the main game.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Battlefield 2042</em> — including Battlefield Portal — is due out on October 22nd, for $60 on PC, Xbox One and PS4, and $70 on Xbox Series X/S and PS5. There&#39;s still one more game mode yet to be revealed, Hazard Zone. We know it&#39;s a &quot;high-stakes squad-based game type never seen before in the Battlefield franchise,&quot; and it&#39;s not a battle royale mode, but that&#39;s about it.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/battlefield-2042-portal-mode-customs-180008313.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1a907da5-9322-49ad-8e5b-71cf2c11dce6</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626976424</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T17:53:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/52c0e730-eb10-11eb-baae-76bbf060524b" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/52c0e730-eb10-11eb-baae-76bbf060524b" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[EA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 - Battlefield Portal]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The next Grid game uses the same virtual set tech as 'The Mandalorian']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://engadget.com/tag/codemasters"><ins>Codemasters</ins></a> offered the first look at the next Grid game during <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ea-play-live-spotlight-series-223554077.html"><ins>EA Play Live</ins></a>. <em>Grid Legends</em> features a story mode that mashes together live-action performances and in-game action. Senior gameplay designer Becky Crossdale said Codemasters harnessed the same extended reality tech that was used to create the world of <em>The Mandalorian</em>.</p><p>In the story mode, you&#39;ll be &quot;front and center in a fly-on-the-wall documentary that captures every moment on and off the track&quot; during the Grid World Series, according to <a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Become-a-Racing-Legend---A-Thrilling-Next-generation-Motorsport-Story-From-Codemasters-Launching-In-2022/default.aspx"><ins>EA</ins></a>. The cast includes Ncuti Gatwa (Netflix&#39;s <em>Sex Education</em>).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="e9a4873a04b147e1acaa53c701cc3fef"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F3-BJfhnlWY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>You&#39;ll be able to race in and upgrade more than 100 vehicles, including touring cars, big rigs, single seaters and stadium trucks. With the race creator, you can set up a showdown between a variety of mixed-class rides. There will also be more than 130 tracks to race on including real-life locations like Brands Hatch and Indianapolis and street routes in the likes of San Francisco, Paris, London and Moscow.</p><p><a href="https://www.ea.com/games/grid/grid-legends"><em><ins>Grid Legends</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>is coming to PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S and PC in 2022. Codemasters plans to reveal more details in the coming months.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/grid-legends-codemasters-ea-play-live-story-mode-175059123.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d130e5be-3285-4121-a356-2e13c7c4a1ff</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 17:50:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1626976261</ingested><modified>2021-07-22T17:51:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7dd4e670-eb14-11eb-9edf-690332efd99a" width="1454" height="818" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7dd4e670-eb14-11eb-9edf-690332efd99a" width="1454" height="818" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[EA/Codemasters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Grid Legends]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Grid Legends]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>