<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 04:00:50 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Former Sennheiser engineer Axel Grell made a $200 pair of ANC true wireless earbuds]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2019, Axel Grell, the designer of Sennheiser’s legendary HD580 and HD800 headphones, left the company to found Grell Audio. Two years later, the startup is coming out with a pair of true wireless headphones known as the TWS/1. Set to cost $200 when they go on sale next month, they feature components individually sourced and designed by Grell. Highlights include custom 10mm drivers, support for ANC and a proprietary feature called Noise Annoyance Reduction (NAR) that the company claims cancels out high-end noises.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/dd5a7c30-261b-11ec-bbbf-cc443bc9fe65" style="height:1000;width:1600;" alt="Grell Audio TWS/1" data-uuid="03cba28d-3358-3f03-a03c-f88350db282b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Grell Audio</div></figure><p>Codec support is also extensive. In addition to mainstays like SBC and AAC, the earbuds can connect to your device over LHDC, aptX, aptX HD and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-08-31-aptx-adaptive-bluetooth-qualcomm.html">aptX adaptive</a>. Outside of a handful of proprietary Sony formats, all that’s missing here is Qualcomm’s recently announced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/qualcomm-aptx-lossless-codec-announcement-161851075.html">aptX Lossless</a> codec. You can get up to 28 hours of battery life from the headphones with the included charging case.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Grell plans to employ a direct-to-consumer model that will see the company sell the TWS/1 earbuds exclusively through its <a href="https://grellaudio.com/">website</a> and <a href="https://drop.com/">Drop</a>. Pre-orders open today, with general availability to follow in November. The Drop version of the headphones will be known as the tws.01 and feature an all-black finish and come with an additional set of blue wingtips.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/grell-audio-tws-1-earbuds-annoucement-040050084.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3764c3ca-6869-4980-a58b-bc8dc0cdc706</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 04:00:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633466882</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T20:48:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b6c614d0-261b-11ec-bbf7-babcb6c01bca" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b6c614d0-261b-11ec-bbf7-babcb6c01bca" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Grell Audio]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Grell Audio TWS/1]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Grell Audio TWS/1]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg denies Facebook puts profit over users' safety]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg didn&#39;t testify at today&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-senate-hearing-161557412.html">whistleblower hearing</a>, but he has <a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10113961365418581">posted</a> a lengthy reply to the accusations being lobbed at the company. He said the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html">Frances Haugen&#39;s</a> claims don&#39;t make sense and that they paint a &quot;false picture&quot; of the social network. &quot;At the heart of these accusations is this idea that we prioritize profit over safety and well-being. That&#39;s just not true,&quot; he wrote in his post. The Facebook chief cited the Meaningful Social Interactions (MSI) update to News Feed, which was designed to show fewer viral videos and more content from friends and family.&nbsp;</p><p>He said the company went through with the change knowing that it would make people spend less time on the website, because research suggested it was the right thing thing to do for people&#39;s well-being. In Haugen&#39;s testimony, she painted MSI in a less flattering light. She said Zuckerberg chose to apply &quot;metrics defined by Facebook&quot; like MSI &quot;over changes that would have significantly decreased misinformation and other inciting content.&quot; The whistleblower said the CEO was presented with solutions to make Facebook &quot;less viral, less twitchy,&quot; but he decided not to use them because they had a negative impact on the MSI metric.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In the SEC complaint she filed, Haugen claimed that Facebook allowed &quot;hateful&quot; and &quot;divisive&quot; content, because it is &quot;easier to inspire people to anger than it is to other emotions.&quot; Zuckerberg addressed that in his post, as well, calling it &quot;deeply illogical.&quot; Facebook makes money from ads, he said, and advertisers apparently tell the company that they don&#39;t want their ads next to harmful or angry content.&nbsp;</p><p>In addition, Zuckerberg said the research into how Instagram affects young people was mischaracterized. He didn&#39;t explicitly mention it, but <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739?mod=article_inline"><em>The Wall Street Journal</em></a> published an article in mid-September about how it knows Instagram is toxic for teen girls based on internal documents detailing Facebook&#39;s own research. The social network eventually <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-senate-hearing-161557412.html">published</a> a couple of documents from that research, but Haugen <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-research-instagram-teen-mental-health-slides-003452675.html">provided</a> Congress with four more. Zuckerberg defended the platform, writing that many teens the company heard from actually &quot;feel that using Instagram helps them when they are struggling with the kinds of hard moments and issues teenagers have always faced.&quot;</p><p>Haugen, who joined Facebook in 2019, worked on democracy and misinformation issues when she was with the company. She brought &quot;tens of thousands&quot; of pages of internal Facebook documents to Whistleblower Aid founder John Tye in addition to filing a whistleblower complaint with the SEC. There were several reports that came out based on those documents, including the existence of a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-vip-cross-check-xcheck-181720267.html">VIP program</a> that enabled high-profile users to skirt Facebook&#39;s rules. Haugen also accused Facebook of contributing to election misinformation and the January 6th US Capitol riots.</p><p>As for Zuckerberg, part of his post reads:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;If we wanted to ignore research, why would we create an industry-leading research program to understand these important issues in the first place? If we didn&#39;t care about fighting harmful content, then why would we employ so many more people dedicated to this than any other company in our space — even ones larger than us? If we wanted to hide our results, why would we have established an industry-leading standard for transparency and reporting on what we&#39;re doing? And if social media were as responsible for polarizing society as some people claim, then why are we seeing polarization increase in the US while it stays flat or declines in many countries with just as heavy use of social media around the world?&quot;</p></blockquote>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mark-zuckerberg-denies-facebook-profit-over-safety-033717690.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ed50340a-0baf-4f7c-a907-b0a4c4ef3cd8</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 03:37:17 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633491486</ingested><modified>2021-10-06T03:38:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-10/01193280-fbe2-11e9-b3df-18f615b92db2" width="6219" height="4146" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-10/01193280-fbe2-11e9-b3df-18f615b92db2" width="6219" height="4146" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Drew Angerer via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NEW YORK, NY - OCTOBER 25: Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg speaks about the new Facebook News feature at the Paley Center For Media on October 25, 2019 in New York City. Facebook News, which will appear in a new dedicated section on the Facebook app, will offer stories from a mix of publications, including The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal and The Washington Post, as well as other digital-only outlets.(Photo by Drew Angerer/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg And News Corp CEO Robert Thomson Debut Facebook News]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rode's PSA1+ boom arm works with small mics and cameras too]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a favorite streamer, chances are you&#39;ve seen <a href="https://www.amazon.es/Rode-PSA1-Accesorio-para-micr%C3%B3fono/dp/B001D7UYBO">Rode&#39;s PSA1</a> hanging out in the corner of the frame. Or perhaps you <em>are</em> that streamer? Rode&#39;s boom arm has become a go-to for YouTubers, Twitch channels and podcasters alike. As handy as the PSA1 is, it isn&#39;t so good for lighter cameras and microphones —  at least not without some <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cM_Cl-hHZtQ">DIY adjustments</a>.</p><p>Enter the PSA1+ ($129). Unveiled today, it&#39;s a revised version of the ubiquitous mic arm that will handle devices as light as 94g / 3.3oz. That might not sound like much, but the original needed a lot more weight to keep its balance, effectively ruling out any microphone or camera under 700g / 24.7 oz. That excludes most webcams, all GoPros (which can now <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gopro-hero-8-black-webcam-update-130050315.html">work as webcams</a>) and a bevy of other more affordable mics. Sure, you can tighten the screws or meddle with counterweights, but that isn&#39;t always ideal or guaranteed to work.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Functionally, the PSA1+ feels a lot closer to something like <a href="https://www.bluedesigns.com/products/compass/">Blue&#39;s Compass</a> which holds itself in place even without weight thanks to a combination of hand-tightened friction hinges and its internal spring mechanism. Blue&#39;s offering might be better for lighter microphones and cameras but it doesn&#39;t adjust its position as accurately or smoothly as the PSA1 (although its cable management is better).</p><p>The extended device support on the PSA1+ isn&#39;t the only new feature. Rode claims the new arm is completely silent so you won&#39;t suffer errant squeaks or spring noises during your stream or recording. The company also states that part of this is thanks to a revised spring design along with the jazzy new neoprene cover (that kinda makes the PSA1+ look like it&#39;s headed to the gym). The cover makes for a more appealing design over the original&#39;s standard &quot;desk lamp&quot; aesthetic though. That said, there&#39;s some pretty strong branding printed on the side that&#39;ll likely catch your eye during videos. Sadly it doesn&#39;t seem like you can do much about that as the neoprene appears to be physically connected to the cable clips.</p><p>Those clips are a good thing though. As mentioned, cable management, which was functional but not pretty on the PSA1 (essentially it was velcro cable ties) now uses neater, sturdier plastic clasps which should be more reassuring. Now at least either your USB or XLR lead will mostly be out of sight.</p><p>The PSA1+ goes on sale tomorrow for $129.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rodes-psa-1-podcasting-boom-arm-230009046.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">aae2d66d-dfd8-4766-9c60-a9f96550e114</guid><dc:creator>James Trew</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 23:00:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633429754</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T10:29:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|James Trew]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2424b320-25c6-11ec-9f7d-db3c1e68053e" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2424b320-25c6-11ec-9f7d-db3c1e68053e" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rode]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Rode PSA1+ Boom arm.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Rode PSA1+ Boom arm]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony is making it harder to buy PS3 and Vita games]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony may be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-ps3-vita-store-reversal-psp-174551086.html">keeping the PS3 and Vita stores alive</a>, but that doesn&#39;t mean it will be easy to shop. <em>Kotaku</em><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-planning-to-make-ps3-vita-stores-nearly-unusable-1847801952">noticed</a> that Sony is <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/important-notice/">shutting down</a> credit card, debit card and PayPal store payments for its older consoles on October 27th. From then on, you&#39;ll have to either load your virtual wallet (through the web or another console) or rely on gift cards — you can&#39;t just buy games directly.</p><p>The company didn&#39;t explain the decision in a notice to customers. We&#39;ve asked Sony for comment.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Whatever the reasoning, the reduced payment options send a not-so-subtle signal: Sony would really, really like you to stop buying games for older consoles and move on to a PS4 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-review-130048353.html">or PS5</a>. That&#39;s unsurprising when the PS3 is 15 years old and has the aging store infrastructure to match, but it&#39;s not very reassuring if you&#39;re hanging on to a PS3 or Vita to play classic games.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-ps3-vita-playstation-store-card-shutdown-194942426.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dbfc1499-d348-462b-8bf1-0aa8637e85db</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:49:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633463385</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T19:49:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/436d2a50-2611-11ec-befc-386f88a73301" width="3000" height="2182" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/436d2a50-2611-11ec-befc-386f88a73301" width="3000" height="2182" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JIL Studio via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony Playstation 3 at the Makuhari Messe in Makuhari, Japan. (Photo by JIL Studio/WireImage)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tokyo Game Show 2006]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook explains how its October 4th outage started]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following Monday’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-down-161653706.html">massive service outage</a> that took out all of its services, Facebook has published a <a href="https://engineering.fb.com/2021/10/05/networking-traffic/outage-details/">blog post</a> detailing what happened yesterday. According to Santosh Janardhan, the company&#39;s vice president of infrastructure, the outage started with what should have been routine maintenance. At some point yesterday, a command was issued that was supposed to assess the availability of the backbone network that connects all of Facebook’s disparate computing facilities. Instead, the order unintentionally took those connections down. Janardhan says a bug in the company’s internal audit system did not properly prevent the command from executing.</p><p>That issue caused a secondary problem that ultimately made yesterday’s outage into the international incident that it became. When Facebook’s DNS servers couldn’t connect to the company’s primary data centers, they stopped advertising the border gateway protocol (BGP) routing information that every device on the internet needs to connect to a server.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>“The end result was that our DNS servers became unreachable even though they were still operational,” said Janardhan. “This made it impossible for the rest of the internet to find our servers.”</p><p>As we <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-coming-back-online-after-outage-220412330.html">learned partway yesterday</a>, what made an already difficult situation worse was that the outage made it impossible for Facebook engineers to connect to the servers they needed to fix. Moreover, the loss of DNS functionality meant they couldn’t use many of the internal tools they depend on to investigate and resolve networking issues in normal circumstances. That meant the company had to physically send personnel to its data centers, a task that was complicated by the physical safeguards it had in place at those locations.</p><p>“They’re hard to get into, and once you’re inside, the hardware and routers are designed to be difficult to modify even when you have physical access to them,” according to Janardhan. Once it could restore its backbone network, Facebook was cautious not to turn everything back on all at once since the surging power and computing demands may have led to more crashes.</p><p>“Every failure like this is an opportunity to learn and get better, and there’s plenty for us to learn from this one,” said Janardhan.  “After every issue, small and large, we do an extensive review process to understand how we can make our systems more resilient. That process is already underway.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-outage-explainer-193155776.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2ffcd19b-c3ab-4d9e-8a2d-0246b051ba72</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:31:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633462319</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T19:32:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Internet & Networking Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/edc78c20-2611-11ec-bde6-5fb47d3ad17d" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/edc78c20-2611-11ec-bde6-5fb47d3ad17d" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook data center]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Russian crew is shooting the first feature film on the ISS]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Filming is underway on the first feature-length movie to be shot in space after Russian actor Yulia Sherepild and director Klim Shipenko docked at the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/iss">International Space Station</a>. Their movie, <em>The Challenge</em>, will feature around 35-40 minutes of scenes filmed on the space station, according to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/05/science/russia-space-launch.html"><em>The New York Times</em></a>. The film is about a surgeon (Sherepild) who goes on an emergency ISS mission to save the life of a cosmonaut (Shipenko).</p><div id="5746cb7ad2524858a614aab34850006b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Docking! <br><br>Welcome to the International <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Anton_Astrey?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Anton_Astrey</a>, Yulia and Klim! We have already prepared dinner for you)) <a href="https://t.co/YBRf8dqtuM">pic.twitter.com/YBRf8dqtuM</a></p>— Oleg Novitskiy (@novitskiy_iss) <a href="https://twitter.com/novitskiy_iss/status/1445389464130531329?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The two cosmonauts who were already on the ISS captured a shot as Peresild (or her character) emerged from the capsule and entered the station. Sherepild and Shipenko will film scenes over the next couple of weeks before returning to Earth on October 17th.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Other projects have been filmed on the ISS, including<em>&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/capturing-life-aboard-the-iss-in-a-four-part-vr-documentary-series-190037617.html">documentaries</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacewalk-virtual-reality-123303570.html">virtual reality projects</a> and a short called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BKOK0VzTix4&amp;ab_channel=RichardGarriottdeCayeux"><em>Apogee of Fear</em></a><em>. </em>Tom Cruise hoped to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tom-cruise-movie-in-space-220746768.html">make the first feature film in space</a> with the help of NASA and SpaceX, but the Russian team beat him to the punch. Russia&#39;s Roscosmos agency announced a plan to send an actor to the ISS soon after word emerged about Cruise&#39;s movie in May 2020.</p><p>Time will tell whether <em>The Challenge </em>is any good. Regardless, the creatives behind the project have carved out their own little slice of history.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/international-space-station-russia-movie-the-challenge-183808670.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">716b664b-a0b3-4a07-b138-61d2c35c7e2b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 18:38:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633480213</ingested><modified>2021-10-06T00:30:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e0448950-2606-11ec-bdf7-eecbd7982bf7" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e0448950-2606-11ec-bdf7-eecbd7982bf7" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Handout . / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The International Space Station (ISS) crew members Russian cosmonaut Anton Shkaplerov, film director Klim Shipenko and actor Yulia Peresild pose after donning space suits shortly before the launch at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, Kazakhstan October 5, 2021.  Andrey Shelepin/GCTC/Roscosmos/Handout via REUTERS ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE HAS BEEN SUPPLIED BY A THIRD PARTY. MANDATORY CREDIT.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SPACE-EXPLORATION/RUSSIA-MOVIE-LAUNCH]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[With 'Ghost Recon Frontline,' Ubisoft tries to cash in on the battle royale fad (again)]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyper-scape-season-two-atrax-memorial-floor-lava-battle-pass-110128670.html"><em>Hyper Scape</em></a>? No? Well, apparently neither does Ubisoft. The publisher is working on a new battle royale that will take players to the Tom Clancy universe. On Tuesday, the company announced <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-ca/game/ghost-recon/frontline#5Mrm0eiZlIpv4joTt4MPy7"><em>Ghost Recon Frontline</em></a><em>. </em>Like many of its contemporaries, the free-to-play title will pit you and two other teammates against more than one hundred other players.&nbsp;</p><div id="a8b1040d6607468da30b2e3becea8d6a"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7NewkthNMDE?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>If the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-09-call-of-duty-warzone-available-march-10.html"><em>Call of Duty: Warzone</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>comparisons<em>&nbsp;</em>weren&#39;t inevitable already, <em>Frontline</em> moves the series away from its traditional third-person perspective to a first-person one. However, where Ubisoft&#39;s Bucharest studio hopes to differentiate the game is with a tweak to the battle royale formula. In <em>Frontline&#39;s</em> signature Expedition mode, you and your team will need to find three pieces of intel scattered across an island map. The twist is that you later need to extract that information by calling in an airlift. Other teams can ambush you during this crucial moment and steal the data you fought so hard to obtain. The playspace also won&#39;t get smaller as a match progresses.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The franchise’s most recent outing, 2019’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-12-ghost-recon-breakpoint-jon-bernthal-ubisoft.html"><em><ins>Ghost Recon Breakpoint</ins></em></a>, was, to put it mildly, a disastrous release for Ubisoft. Thanks to its unfinished state, the game performed so poorly in its first week of availability that the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-24-ubisoft-watch-dogs-legion-delay-gods-and-monsters-rainbow-six-quarantine.html"><ins>delayed</ins></a> all of its biggest 2020 releases. It then went on to spend months patching <em>Breakpoint</em>, but the game never quite recovered from the reputation it earned at launch. Ubisoft said it plans to continue to support <em>Breakpoint </em>while working on <em>Frontline</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Ubisoft didn&#39;t share a release date for <em>Ghost Recon Frontline, </em>but it said it would hold a closed PC test starting on October 14th that people in select countries across Europe can sign up to take part in by visiting the game&#39;s <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-ca/game/ghost-recon/frontline#3K0BCfawqA7ByWsOZJCC48">website</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ghost-recon-frontline-battle-royale-180404978.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0f417f5a-d54c-486d-9f22-bbbf7b41d6c2</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 18:04:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633457048</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T18:04:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8db33ec0-2601-11ec-abfe-a3dc49a81388" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8db33ec0-2601-11ec-abfe-a3dc49a81388" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ubisoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Ghost Recon Frontline]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ghost Recon Frontline]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Razer Book laptop gets a price cut to $1,000]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Razer is joining many PC makers by <a href="https://press.razer.com/uncategorized/razer-is-ready-for-windows-11-with-new-razer-book-offers-free-upgrade-for-eligible-razer-laptops/">unveiling</a> new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">Windows 11</a> systems, although the biggest news may have more to do with prices than the computers themselves. To begin with, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-book-13-specs-price-availability-pre-order-160026252.html">Razer Book</a> now has a regular starting price of $1,000 as a company store exclusive. You&#39;ll still get the familiar 11th-gen Core i5, 8GB of RAM and 256GB of SSD storage, but you no longer have to wait for the 13.4-inch machine to go on sale if $1,200 is too extravagant.</p><p>Higher-spec Razer Book models are also better values than their outgoing models, at least at official prices. A jump to $1,500 gives you a touchscreen, a Core i7, 16GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD (previously $1,600), while it now takes &#39;just&#39; $1,800 to buy a 4K touch variant that now includes 1TB of storage on top of the existing Core i7 and 16GB of RAM.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There&#39;s also a slight update for heavy-duty gamers. The Blade 15 Advanced now comes in new configurations that mate a 240Hz QHD screen and a 11th-gen Core i7 with faster GeForce RTX 3070 and 3080 graphics choices. They won&#39;t be cheap, of course. The &#39;base&#39; starts at $2,700 with the RTX 3070, 16GB of RAM and a 1TB SSD, while the all-out $3,100 model leaps to the RTX 3080 and 32GB of RAM.</p><p>All the new Windows 11 PCs are <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:available to order" href="https://fave.co/3ab9JxT">available to order</a> today. Existing Razer systems (including those still on sale) can upgrade to Windows 11 as well, although you&#39;ll want to check the <a href="https://www.razer.com/gaming-laptops/windows-11">compatibility list</a> before you pick up an older model.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/razer-book-blade-15-advanced-windows-11-171416082.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4486d081-9eaf-4dd9-b62c-24ff0e61038b</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:14:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633454059</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T17:14:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ec4c4ab0-25f9-11ec-aaa3-2d237047d8fd" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ec4c4ab0-25f9-11ec-aaa3-2d237047d8fd" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Razer Book (2021) with Windows 11]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Book (2021) with Windows 11]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook Gaming creators can now stream together]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you turn to Facebook Gaming to watch other people play your favorite games, you’ll now see creators collaborate on joint streams. Facebook is introducing support for co-streaming. The feature allows up to four accounts to stream together concurrently. With today’s rollout, co-streaming is available to all content creators, not just those enrolled in Facebook’s partner program. You can access the functionality search for and tag other creators through the Live Producer left rail, in addition to the Gaming Tab and Stream Dashboard of the edit stream module.</p><p>“With co-streaming, we aim to increase discoverability for creators, encourage collaboration between creators and elevate the overall viewing experience for everyone,” the company said in a blog post. The addition of co-streaming support is a case of Facebook playing catch up. Twitch has offered similar functionality through its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-27-twitch-squad-stream.html">Squad Stream</a> feature since 2019. It’s also worth pointing out the idea itself isn’t new. While it’s no longer around, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-06-05-onlive-coming-to-browsers-smart-tvs-with-more-viewing-capabilit.html">OnLive</a> introduced a multi-view feature back in 2012. All the same, it’s a significant addition for Facebook Gaming, particularly as it continues to try to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/streamlabs-twitch-viewership-doubled-in-one-year-150003530.html">compete with Twitch</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-gaming-co-streaming-announcement-170034516.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cffbf449-0fae-4b8a-923f-a84783b3319c</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633446048</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T15:00:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f24bb480-25ec-11ec-bfdb-a8d3e3da2348" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f24bb480-25ec-11ec-bfdb-a8d3e3da2348" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook co-streaming]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook co-streaming]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[James Bond's latest Aston Martin is coming to 'Rocket League']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It wouldn&#39;t be a new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-mgm-james-bond-movies-theaters-170051364.html">James Bond movie</a> without a few tie-ins, and <em>No Time to Die</em> is clearly sticking to that rule. Psyonix and Epic Games have <a href="https://www.rocketleague.com/news/aston-martin-valhalla-rushes-into-rocket-league/">revealed</a> that Bond&#39;s Aston Martin Valhalla, the first hybrid car in the game, will be available in <em>Rocket League</em> (complete with matching audio, decal and wheels) for 1100 Credits starting October 7th. You&#39;ll also find three in-game challenges to unlock a Bond-themed avatar border, banner and player title.</p><p>Completists will have the option of buying a Bond 007 Collection between October 7th and October 13th that includes both the Valhalla and the classic DB5 for 2,000 Credits. The DB5 was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/james-bond-rocket-league-aston-martin-db5-170030428.html">released in July</a>, but this could represent a better deal for Bond aficionados.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The expansion isn&#39;t a surprise when Epic has lots of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-lebron-james-193107259.html">money to throw at promotional deals</a>. This could boost interest in <em>Rocket League</em> among either diehard Bond fans or newcomers looking for more real-world cars. If nothing else, it should be amusing to watch 007 score a flying, upside-down goal or two.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/james-bond-007-aston-martin-valhalla-rocket-league-170014713.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">08d1f044-bc1b-4311-b651-03becf080d19</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633464002</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T20:00:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Bonds]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7985cf70-25df-11ec-9f52-99e73191db46" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7985cf70-25df-11ec-9f52-99e73191db46" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Psyonix/Epic Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[James Bond Aston Martin Valhalla and DB5 in &#39;Rocket League&#39;]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[James Bond Aston Martin Valhalla and DB5 in &#39;Rocket League&#39;]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google will hold its Pixel 6 event on October 19th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has revealed the date for its big fall hardware event. It will discuss the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/pixel%206">Pixel 6</a> lineup in more detail on October 19th at 1PM ET.</p><p>The company has already spilled some info on the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro, including what the phones look like. In August, Google said Tensor, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-faq-specs-ai-ml-160021397.html">the first system-on-chip it designed</a>, will debut on these devices. The SoC will power the Pixel 6&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-first-look-tensor-processor-better-cameras-160005582.html">AI-heavy features</a>, such as speech recognition and on-device live captions and translation.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="8e9ebfcd40a54fa486e32e874f8a3570"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Pixel6</a>, the new Google Phone. <br><br>Tune in October 19th at 10 am PT: <a href="https://t.co/zmp5byVq1y">https://t.co/zmp5byVq1y</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Launch?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Pixel6Launch</a><a href="https://t.co/v3wwySE5gs">pic.twitter.com/v3wwySE5gs</a></p>— Made By Google (@madebygoogle) <a href="https://twitter.com/madebygoogle/status/1445426131297976321?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The phones will have camera upgrades, of course. The Pixel 6&#39;s main camera will allow approximately 150 percent more light in than previous models, while the Pro will have 4x optical zoom and an additional telephoto option. The company claims Tensor will improve the photo processing capabilities too.</p><p>You can expect up to a day&#39;s worth of battery life from a single charge, Google told us, though it&#39;s unclear exactly how many hours of use that translates to. The devices are 5G compatible and they&#39;ll be able to take advantage of all the new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/android%2012">Android 12</a> features.</p><div id="340867dca03244b3afb028f993f54190"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d1aDjlGNdiQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Google is keeping some of the Pixel 6 specs under wraps for now, such as how many CPU and GPU cores there are and how much RAM the devices boast. In any case, we only have to wait another couple of weeks to find out.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-event-smartphone-163852069.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4193e4ab-0b93-420d-beea-249dc14c6863</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633453165</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T16:59:28+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5bcfa7b0-25fa-11ec-b879-1fae03efeed3" width="4096" height="2150" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5bcfa7b0-25fa-11ec-b879-1fae03efeed3" width="4096" height="2150" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 event]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 event]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon is reportedly working on a smart fridge that tracks what's inside]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon is reportedly aiming to bring some of the tech it uses at cashierless <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/amazon%20go">Amazon Go</a> stores to your kitchen. According to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-is-building-smart-fridge-that-monitors-your-buying-patterns-2021-10"><em>Insider</em></a>, the company has been working on a smart fridge that can monitor items and help you order replacements if you&#39;re running low on something.</p><p>The team behind the Amazon Go systems is said to be heading the charge on the project, which has been in the works for at least two years. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazons-just-walk-out-tech-comes-to-two-whole-foods-stores-101036042.html">Just Walk Out tech</a> used at Go stores tracks what shoppers put in their carts and automatically charges them when they leave. Members of the Amazon Fresh and Lab126 hardware teams are reportedly involved with the fridge project too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The fridge would monitor the items inside and keep tabs on your purchasing habits, according to the report. If you run low on something you buy frequently, the fridge would notify you and make it easier to order more from Whole Foods or Amazon Fresh, which could give the company&#39;s grocery division a boost. The fridge could offer recipe suggestions too, which may prove useful if you forget about an item that&#39;s about to expire.</p><p>Amazon wouldn&#39;t make the fridges itself, <em>Insider</em>&#39;s sources said. It&#39;s looking to team up with an appliance manufacturer. There&#39;s a possibility that Alexa voice control could be included. That&#39;s said to not be a major concern, but given Amazon&#39;s propensity for stuffing Alexa into nearly every other type of product, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-astro-robot-165934602.html">home robots</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fire-tv-2021-update-omni-fire-tv-4-series-130041393.html">its own TVs</a>, it wouldn&#39;t be a surprise if the fridge has voice assistant support.</p><p>The company has reportedly spent upwards of $50 million per year on the project so far. Even so, there&#39;s no guarantee that the fridge will come to market as it&#39;s possible Amazon will shelve the plans. If the fridge does come to market, it likely won&#39;t come cheap. An Amazon spokesperson told Engadget the company doesn&#39;t comment “on rumors or speculation.”</p><p>The concept isn&#39;t entirely new. In 2016, Samsung <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-01-04-samsung-family-hub-smart-fridge.html">revealed a fridge</a> that can help you keep track of what&#39;s inside without having to open the door. You can even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-01-08-samsung-family-hub-smart-fridge-hands-on.html">order groceries</a> using <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-07-samsung-updates-family-hub-smart-fridge-new-ui.html">the built-in touchscreen</a>. Amazon&#39;s fridge would take the idea a little further, though, since it would flag items that you&#39;re about to run out of and help you order more through the company&#39;s own grocery ecosystem.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-smart-fridge-report-162623916.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">95259e8d-f483-43ec-bbdf-2a3887778d12</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633451332</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T16:28:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f4f0710-25f8-11ec-b9fb-08066930ce5e" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6f4f0710-25f8-11ec-b9fb-08066930ce5e" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BRAZIL - 2021/09/01: In this photo illustration, an Amazon logo seen displayed on a smartphone along with a shopping cart. (Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, an Amazon logo seen displayed on...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook whistleblower hearing: ‘Facebook and big tech are facing a big tobacco moment’]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Facebook whistleblower who has provided a trove of internal documents to Congress and the Securities and Exchange Commission is testifying about research she says proves the social network has repeatedly lied about its platform. The documents were the basis for <em>The Wall Street Journal&#39;s</em> reporting on Facebook&#39;s controversial rules <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-vip-cross-check-xcheck-181720267.html">for celebrities</a>, and the disastrous effect of Instagram on some teens&#39; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-research-instagram-teen-mental-health-slides-003452675.html">mental health</a>.</p><p>“Facebook and big tech are facing their big tobacco moment,” committee chairman Sen. Richard Blumenthal said at the start of the hearing. “Facebook knows its products can be addictive and toxic to children. They value their profit more than the pain that they cause to children and their families.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In her opening statement, Frances Haugen, the former Facebook product manager <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html"><ins>turned whistleblower</ins></a>, said that the company has ignored much of its own research and is “buying its profits with our safety.” She urged Congress to adopt new regulations to limit the company&#39;s power. “The choices being made inside of Facebook are disastrous for our children, our public safety, our privacy and for our democracy,” Haugen said. “And that is why we must demand Facebook make changes.”</p><div id="c5f917fba662460996f6dbb6ba22561d"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">WATCH: Facebook Whistleblower Frances Haugen complete opening statement. <a href="https://t.co/F81Ci03cjp">pic.twitter.com/F81Ci03cjp</a></p>— CSPAN (@cspan) <a href="https://twitter.com/cspan/status/1445402571435384833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>She highlighted Facebook’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transparency-researchers-170021370.html"><ins>unwillingness</ins></a> to make data available outside of its own research teams has helped the company mislead the public. “The company intentionally hides vital information from the public, from the US government, and from governments around the world,” Haugen said. “The documents I have provided to Congress prove that Facebook has repeatedly misled the public about what its own research reveals about the safety of children, the efficacy of its artificial intelligence systems, and its role in spreading divisive and extreme messages.”</p><p>She also said that Congress should not be swayed by Facebook’s insistence on “false choices,” and that simply reforming privacy laws or Section 230 would not go far enough. “We can afford nothing less than full transparency,” Haugen said. “Facebook wants you to believe that the problems we&#39;re talking about are unsolvable... Facebook can change, but it&#39;s clearly not going to do so on its own.&quot;</p><p>Haugen’s appearance comes days after Facebook sent its head of safety, Antigone Davis, to testify in front of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-mental-health-senate-hearing-210317155.html"><ins>same committee</ins></a>. She and other executives have repeatedly tried to downplay the company&#39;s research, with Davis saying that the documents &quot;were not bombshell research.&quot; In Tuesday’s hearing, some senators called out Mark Zuckerberg, saying that they should be hearing from him instead. “Rather than taking personal responsibility, showing leadership, Mark Zuckerberg is going sailing,” Blumenthal said, in an apparent reference to a recent Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10113955029116581"><ins>post</ins></a> from the CEO.</p><p>Even though he wasn’t in attendance, Zuckerberg’s decisions came up throughout the hearing. Haugen said that several documents she uncovered showed that the Facebook founder “chose metrics defined by Facebook like meaningful social interactions over changes that would have significantly decreased misinformation and other inciting content.”</p><p>She said that last April, Zuckerberg was “directly presented with a list of soft interventions” Facebook could take that would make it “less viral, less twitchy” and that he opted not to make the changes because it had a negative impact on the platform’s “meaningful social interactions” metric. She added that even when Facebook does opt to take interventions and slow down its platform, the company’s AI has problems detecting content.</p><p>“When rioting began in the United States in the summer of last year, they turned off downstream MSI [meaningful social interactions] only when they detected content was health content, which is probably COVID, and civic content,” Haugen said. “But Facebook’s own algorithms are bad at finding this content.”</p><p>In a statement following the hearing, Facebook’s Director of Policy Communications, Lena Pietsch, tried to downplay Haugen’s knowledge of the company, writing that she “worked for the company for less than two years, had no direct reports, never attended a decision-point meeting with C-level executives — and testified more than six times to not working on the subject matter in question.”</p><p>“We don’t agree with her characterization of the many issues she testified about. Despite all this, we agree on one thing: it’s time to begin to create standard rules for the internet. It’s been 25 years since the rules for the internet have been updated, and instead of expecting the industry to make societal decisions that belong to legislators, it’s time for Congress to act.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-senate-hearing-161557412.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8bc4512c-1947-477a-a083-a6e7d53ee43c</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:15:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633456549</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T17:55:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/cd47aaf0-fea0-11ea-8add-97a3fe3113dc" width="2200" height="1467" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/cd47aaf0-fea0-11ea-8add-97a3fe3113dc" width="2200" height="1467" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Elijah Nouvelage / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The entrance sign to Facebook headquarters is seen in Menlo Park, California, on Wednesday, October 10, 2018. REUTERS/Elijah Nouvelage]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FACEBOOK-RESULTS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instagram brings IGTV videos out of their silo and into your regular feed]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Instagram may have been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-down-161653706.html">down for hours</a>, but it&#39;s back with an arguably overdue change to how the social network handles videos. The Facebook brand is merging its long-form IGTV format with the regular videos from your feed, leaving just one format for all Instagram footage — you won&#39;t have to distinguish between the two. We&#39;ve asked Instagram if this will lead to longer videos playing directly in your feed, but there will always be a Video tab in profiles to explore more content.</p><p>The move might help <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-expands-badges-and-commercials-130020878.html">Instagram-based creators</a>, too. While they&#39;ll still have to produce long-form video to qualify for ads (now called Instagram In-Stream video ads), they should have an easier time reaching viewers who would have glossed over IGTV in the past. Instagram is also merging post and video insights into a single metric.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You may have an easier time polishing that video, too. Instagram is bringing a few common editing features to its videos, including trimming, filters, location tags and people tags. Still images have had filters and tags for a while, of course, but this theoretically puts moving pictures more on par. You may have an easier time finding videos linked to a friend or a memorable concert.</p><p>The merger could boost uptake for Instagram video. IGTV demand <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-18-instagram-removes-igtv-button.html">wasn&#39;t what Instagram expected</a>, and this update makes the longer video format more accessible, not to mention less confusing. Creators might be more inclined to share videos on Instagram as a result — and that might help the social media giant better compete <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-three-minute-videos-now-available-182016623.html">against TikTok</a>, YouTube and other video-focused heavyweights.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/instagram-merges-igtv-feed-video-160057187.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1d2709e3-8257-441d-9f2d-f52cb6909029</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633449660</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T16:01:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/41db8da0-25ec-11ec-bff5-0cb49ecb968c" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/41db8da0-25ec-11ec-bff5-0cb49ecb968c" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Instagram]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Instagram video trimming on iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Instagram video trimming on iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat's newest in-app tool encourages young people to run for office]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snap is <a href="https://newsroom.snap.com/run-for-office">introducing a new tool</a> to help more young Americans get involved in politics. Dubbed “Run for Office,” the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-mini-apps-174530579.html">Mini</a> adds a curated database of more than 75,000 local and state elected positions Snapchat users can browse directly through the app.</p><p>Before you see a list of opportunities, the tool will ask you to share some of the issues you’re passionate about in your daily life. Those can include things like the environment, the economy, education and more. Additionally, Snapchat users can also use the tool to nominate their friends.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The company built Run for Office with help from <a href="https://newamericanleaders.org/">New American Leaders</a> and nine other candidate recruitment organizations. Once someone indicates they’re interested in pursuing an opportunity, the Mini will connect them with those groups to provide them with candidate training.</p><p>“Running for office shouldn’t be just for those who are white and wealthy. If we want a democracy that works for and represents all of us, then we need leaders who reflect our increasingly diverse, multicultural communities” said Ghida Dagher, president of New American Leaders.&nbsp;</p><p>By Snap’s estimation, it’s ideally positioned to help get more young people involved in politics since it reaches approximately 90 percent of 13 to 24-year-olds in the US. This isn’t the company’s first foray into politics. Ahead of the 2018 midterms and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-voting-resources-2020-193216455.html">2020 presidential election</a>, the company added voting resources to help drive higher voter turnout in those contests.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-run-for-office-mini-155958298.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e6c056a3-c2f1-4df5-b1c6-b0df4a42e602</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 15:59:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633449602</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T16:00:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Career & Education]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1ed3a430-25f3-11ec-bbed-19d45d44ed50" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1ed3a430-25f3-11ec-bbed-19d45d44ed50" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Snap]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Snapchat Run for Office]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Snapchat Run for Office]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Kingdom Hearts trilogy is coming to Nintendo Switch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The three main Kingdom Hearts games are coming to Nintendo Switch. You&#39;ll be able to play <em>Kingdom Hearts - HD 1.5 + 2.5 ReMix</em>, <em>Kingdom Hearts HD 2.8 Final Chapter Prologue </em>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Kingdom%20Hearts%20III"><em><ins>Kingdom Hearts III</ins></em></a>. They&#39;re all cloud streaming games on Switch, so you&#39;ll need a good internet connection to play them. The release dates and other details will be announced later.</p><div id="099073a3521e4efbb46435ff0178ea3c"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This just in – the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KingdomHearts?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KingdomHearts</a> games are coming to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitch?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NintendoSwitch</a>! <br><br>✨ KINGDOM HEARTS - HD 1.5 + 2.5 ReMix -<br>✨ KINGDOM HEARTS HD 2.8 Final Chapter Prologue <br>✨ KINGDOM HEARTS III<br><br>All three titles will be playable as cloud versions. Look forward to more information soon! <a href="https://t.co/VtoiCJzxKp">pic.twitter.com/VtoiCJzxKp</a></p>— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1445397581215973384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The announcement was made during the last <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kingdom-hearts-sora-super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-140938432.html"><em><ins>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</ins></em><ins> presentation</ins></a>. That game&#39;s director Masahiro Sakurai revealed that Sora from Kingdom Hearts is <em>SSBU</em>&#39;s final DLC fighter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The first Kingdom Hearts title to land on Switch was the rhythm game <em>Kingdom Hearts: Melody of Memory </em>in 2020. The Square Enix series also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kingdom-hearts-epic-games-store-021731745.html"><ins>arrived on PC</ins></a> earlier this year.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/kingdom-hearts-nintendo-switch-152943282.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">af7e47c8-e24e-4bcf-a397-34c9a6d78242</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 15:29:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633447820</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T15:30:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1d8d1740-25ef-11ec-977d-21751a252888" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1d8d1740-25ef-11ec-977d-21751a252888" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Square Enix/Disney]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts III]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts III]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts' Sora is the final 'Super Smash Bros. Ultimate' fighter]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nintendo has finalized the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/super%20smash%20bros%20ultimate"><em>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>roster with the reveal of one last DLC fighter. Director Masahiro Sakurai revealed that Sora from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/kingdom%20hearts">Kingdom Hearts</a> is joining the ranks. Sora is nimble and a skilled airborne fighter, but he&#39;s very light, so it&#39;s easy to launch him. His special abilities include fire, lightning and ice magic attacks and a vertical spiral move that&#39;s a bit like Link&#39;s spin attack.</p><p>Before the stream, Sakurai <a href="https://twitter.com/Sora_Sakurai/status/1444895523995930625">noted on Twitter</a> (per Google Translate) that the &quot;new fighter may be a character you don&#39;t know.&quot; That dashed many fans&#39; hopes that the addition would be Waluigi or, as was previously rumored, Master Chief from Halo. But Sora isn&#39;t exactly an unknown quantity. In fact, Sakurai said he was fans&#39; most-requested <em>SSBU </em>character.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="94f131bde6de4d2fb3ad837b8d39acf2"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L-q6Gz_4Yqc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Sora is the 89th playable character (depending on how you count them) to join the lineup since <em>SSBU </em>arrived <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-06-super-smash-bros-ultimate-review-switch.html">in December 2018</a>. The other members of the $30 Fighters Pass Vol. 2 bundle are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/super-smash-bros-ultimate-arms-fighter-dlc-fallout-153230938.html"><em>Arms&#39; </em>Min Min</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/minecraft-super-smash-bros-ultimate-release-october-13-181150543.html">Steve and Alex from <em>Minecraft</em></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/super-smash-bros-ultimate-dlc-001917366.html">Sephiroth of <em>Final Fantasy 7 </em>fame</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/super-smash-bros-ultimate-roster-pyra-mythra-release-date-164004324.html">Pyra and Mythra</a> from <em>Xenoblade Chronicles 2 </em>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/super-smash-bros-ultimate-kazuya-tekken-161843369.html">Kazuya Mishima</a>, a staple of the Tekken series.&nbsp;</p><p>Nintendo has brought together characters from a vast number of franchises in <em>SSBU</em>, including Mario, The Legend of Zelda, Metroid, Pokémon, Bayonetta, Persona and Street Fighter. Including spirits and Mii Costumes, there are connections to more than 450 games.</p><p>The new <em>SSBU </em>stage that will arrive alongside Sora is Hollow Bastion, in which you can see Maleficent&#39;s castle from the first <em>Kingdom Hearts </em>in the background. Rather than including music with close ties to certain worlds in Kingdom Hearts, the <em>SSBU </em>team decided to pick central themes from the series for the nine song list additions. In addition, if you have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kingdom-hearts-epic-games-store-021731745.html"><em>Kingdom Hearts Melody of Memory</em></a> save data on your Nintendo Switch, you&#39;ll get &quot;Dearly Beloved - Swing Version&quot; as a bonus song.</p><p>Sora, Hollow Bastion and the song list will be available on October 18th. The content is part of the Fighters Pass Vol. 2, but you can buy it separately for $6. Meanwhile, the final Mii Costumes, which will also be available on October 18th, are Doom Slayer (from Doom, naturally) and Octoling and Judd from Splatoon.</p><div id="714d1f3bec864ea8a4709988289c10ab"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_axByU7FaZ4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/kingdom-hearts-sora-super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-140938432.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5d4ad744-1e09-4c25-ac49-ef8b2c91c132</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 14:09:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633445180</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T14:46:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8d509610-25e5-11ec-9fb7-06bd88a7d162" width="1207" height="680" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8d509610-25e5-11ec-9fb7-06bd88a7d162" width="1207" height="680" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts' Sora in Super Smash Bros. Ultiamte]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts' Sora in Super Smash Bros. Ultiamte]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's Kindle is on sale for $60 right now]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon announced a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-kids-signature-edition-130032095.html">revamped Kindle Paperwhite family</a> last month, but the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:standard Kindle" href="https://amzn.to/3Bdw5Lf">standard Kindle</a> remains one of the best options if you&#39;re looking for a reliable and relatively affordable e-reader. It&#39;s normally priced at $90, but you can get it for $60 right now in a limited-time sale. The only time we&#39;ve seen the e-reader drop to a lower price was during Prime Day back in June when it was $55.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3Bdw5Lf" id="93fbe7903dd6486d88c0191f870e9327" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Kindle at Amazon - $60</a><p>We gave this model of the Kindle a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-10-amazon-kindle-review-2019.html">score of 91</a> when it came out in 2019 — while it doesn&#39;t have as many bells and whistles as the Paperwhite has, it will be exactly what some need in an e-reader. Key upgrades include a higher contrast display and four LED front lights that make it easier to read in dark environments. Amazon also refined the design to be sleeker, although this Kindle is not waterproof like the Paperwhite is.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Kindle excels at being a basic e-reader and it will be an upgrade if you&#39;re used to reading books and articles on your smartphone&#39;s screen. The anti-glare display is much easier on the eyes, the built-in 8GB of storage can thousands of titles and the battery will last weeks on a single charge. The only major downside to the Kindle is one that all other Kindles have, too: you&#39;ll have to deal with Amazon&#39;s lockscreen ads, unless you pay extra to remove them.</p><p>If you are interested in the extras that come with the Paperwhite, Amazon seems to be trying to get rid of the previous version as it anticipates the arrival of the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:2021 e-reader" href="https://amzn.to/2YlJx16">2021 e-reader</a>, which will ship at the end of this month. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:2018 Kindle Paperwhite" href="https://amzn.to/3lbyBMe">2018 Kindle Paperwhite</a> in twilight blue is currently on sale for $75, which is a record low. This <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-13-kindle-paperwhite-review-2018.html">model</a> gives you a higher density display, a waterproof design and Audible support, so you can listen to audiobooks saved on the device when you connect a pair of wireless headphones. Both e-readers are good choices, so it ultimately comes down to which features are necessary to you and how much you&#39;re willing to spend.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3lbyBMe" id="387123e1207740bf85513b9ea086eef0" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Paperwhite (2018) at Amazon - $75</a><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazons-regular-kindle-is-on-sale-for-60-right-now-135012068.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f783c1a4-96d6-4fa9-87b6-12f8a1dda833</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:50:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633441815</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T13:50:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/9d4f5640-b233-11ea-bfe7-2b4eac12b399" width="1800" height="1127" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/9d4f5640-b233-11ea-bfe7-2b4eac12b399" width="1800" height="1127" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lenovo's excellent Flex 5 Chromebook is $300 on Amazon today only]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While Chromebooks are meant to be an affordable alternative to standard laptops, you could easily drop hundreds on a fancy Chrome OS devices. Out of all of the Chromebooks we&#39;ve tried, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Lenovo&#39;s Flex 5" href="https://amzn.to/3De3Dt6">Lenovo&#39;s Flex 5</a> hits a sweet spot that most people will appreciate thanks to its solid performance, convertible design and attractive price tag. But today you can get the machine for even less thanks to a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:one-day sale" href="https://amzn.to/3AdvdF8">one-day sale</a> on Amazon — the online retailer has the laptop for $300, or $130 off its normal price and a new record-low.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3De3Dt6" id="10250a74092f441db319058894d3f1f0" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook at Amazon - $300</a><p>The specs on the Flex 5 are good even at its normal $430 price tag, but they&#39;re made even better by this sale price. The laptop has a 13-inch 1080p touchscreen along with a 10th-gen Core i3 processor, 4GB of RAM and 64GB of storage. Getting a Core i3 Chromebook for $300 is a great deal, and the memory and storage numbers are pretty standard for midrange Chrome OS devices. We&#39;d never recommend a standard laptop with 4GB of RAM, but Chrome OS does more with less. One of the reasons why we named the Flex 5 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-chromebooks-160054646.html">our favorite Chromebook</a> is that it performed well even with just 4GB of RAM. As far as storage goes, as long as you&#39;re not installing a bunch of Android apps or downloading your entire Netflix library, 64GB should serve you well.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We also appreciate the Flex 5&#39;s convertible design, allowing you to use it as a tablet if you wish. The laptop isn&#39;t the slimmest, measuring 0.66-inches thick and weighing about three pounds, but it does include two USB-C ports and a USB-A port, which is a more modern selection compared to those on other affordable Chromebooks. Lenovo did a good job packing a lot of value into the Flex 5 Chromebook — it&#39;s rare to find this combination of features at such a reasonable price point, and now that it&#39;s $130 less then usual, it&#39;s a no-brainer for anyone looking for a new Chrome OS laptop.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-flex-5-chromebook-record-low-price-300-amazon-daily-deal-131242705.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d5a9af19-175a-45a5-8044-f3864bce9381</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:12:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633439277</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T13:08:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/81be5090-bae2-11ea-9fff-2a17206d93cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-06/81be5090-bae2-11ea-9fff-2a17206d93cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firefox Focus revamp gives you more control over privacy and tracking]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mozilla likes to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-firefox-redesign-2021-203637892.html">cut distractions</a> and speed up browsing, and its latest browser reflects that priority. The developer has <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/browsers/mobile/focus/">revamped</a> Firefox Focus for Android and iOS to give it a &quot;fresh new look&quot; (including a dark theme), more privacy and quicker access. There&#39;s now a shield icon to quickly turn trackers on or off, not to mention a global counter for every blocked tracker. You&#39;ll find a shortcut feature, too, to help you visit favorite sites that much sooner.</p><p>Firefox is receiving improvements on other platforms. On top of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/firefox-on-android-lets-you-log-in-using-your-face-or-fingerprints-130044590.html">easier password autofill</a>, Firefox users on Android (iOS is coming later this year) can easily create new passwords for apps or unlock accounts using only biometric data like fingerprints and facial recognition.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>And yes, Mozilla is taking advantage of Microsoft&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-windows-11-store-open-to-third-party-stores-175600113.html">loosened Windows 11 store rules</a> for third-party browsers. The company has promised that Firefox will be available through Microsoft&#39;s app portal &quot;later this year.&quot; While that doesn&#39;t provide a firm date, it&#39;s a welcome addition for users who want to quickly grab an alternative to Edge.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-firefox-focus-mobile-updates-130514586.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d88407f7-f0d2-41c5-9f3c-f8dddd06d274</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:05:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633439117</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T13:05:28+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/859d0080-25da-11ec-addd-1d595eff234b" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/859d0080-25da-11ec-addd-1d595eff234b" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Firefox Focus web browser on iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Firefox Focus web browser on iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Pro 8 review: A better but pricier hybrid]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When a device reaches its eighth generation, it can be easy to assume you’re getting more of the same: faster chips, a thinner, lighter design and some aesthetic tweaks. But, in the case of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-hands-on-surface-pro-8-pro-x-go-3-adaptive-kit-price-specs-160005455.html"><ins>Microsoft’s Surface Pro 8</ins></a>, which arrives today alongside Windows 11, you’re getting the biggest redesign the tablet has seen in years. And actually, it’s heavier than <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-21-microsoft-surface-pro-7-review-usb-c-price-specs.html"><ins>the Pro 7</ins></a>.</p><p>In exchange for a 15 percent weight gain, you get up to 52 percent better battery life and Thunderbolt 4 support, plus a larger display with skinnier bezels and a 120Hz refresh rate — something rarely seen outside gaming machines. It looks different, too, taking style cues from the ARM-based <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-05-microsoft-surface-pro-x-review-price-specs-availability-windows-arm-lte.html"><ins>Surface Pro X</ins></a>. Other upgrades include newer 11th-gen Core i5 and i7 processors and a slightly higher-resolution rear camera.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On paper, it addresses two of our three main complaints about the Pro 7 (the detachable keyboard is still sold separately, though). But before we declare the Pro 8 a slam dunk, it’s worth noting that the starting price <a href="https://fave.co/3BbBGS3"><ins>is now $1,100</ins></a>, up significantly from $749 on the Surface Pro 7. (Microsoft both eliminated its lowest-end sku for non-business customers and raised the price for its remaining configurations.) Given that, it’s worth considering whether the improvements are worth the price hike — and how the Pro 8 compares to traditional laptops now that it costs just as much.</p><h2>Hardware</h2><h3>The display</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7bdfe2c0-2534-11ec-9ffb-87ed1a9ee5b8" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="A close-up of a Windows 11 settings menu on the Microsoft Surface Pro 8." data-uuid="c157734d-8b27-3856-ae47-7d0109c81a5a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>Microsoft has always offered lovely displays on its Surface devices. Even with the original Surface, which debuted in 2012, the bright, high-res, low-glare panel was a standout on an  otherwise confused seeming device. The Surface Pro 8 is no exception. The touchscreen here is 11 percent larger than before — 13 inches, up from 12.3 — with a 2,880 x 1,920 resolution that’s nearly 11 percent sharper than the Pro 7. It’s also 12.5 percent brighter, according to Microsoft. (OK, that’s the last time I’ll use the word “percent” for a while.)</p><p>In short, it’s bright, colorful and I never struggled with the viewing angles, regardless of where I was sitting in the house or how much sun was streaming in from outside. On a roof deck, however, the 450-nit screen didn’t feel quite bright enough at max settings — something to keep in mind if you intend to use this on the go.</p><p>Most important is the 120Hz refresh rate. This is a relatively new addition to the world of notebooks. Even so, it’s already something of a meme for reviewers like us to say something like “you don’t know what you’re missing until you experience it.” I’m annoyed to say that is 100 percent true. So, here’s me repeating a tired cliche: You will likely be happy with the 60Hz mode that’s enabled by default, but once you switch to 120Hz in the settings, you won’t want to revert back.</p><p>I noticed the difference immediately, even with the sort of mundane tasks I do hundreds of times a day: launching apps and minimizing windows. It all happens faster. It’s worth noting, however, you’re unlikely to notice much of a difference in movie playback, as Microsoft did some software work specifically to lower the refresh rate for that use case.</p><h3>Everything else</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0cf654c0-2534-11ec-bf69-994730056c65" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="A close-up of the webcam on Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8." data-uuid="0f180712-44f7-382d-bae6-6f4b10dbd403"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>That bigger display comes at the expense of the surrounding bezels, which: good riddance. This is, of course, not a new design tactic. For years, laptop makers have been trimming the fat around their screens. Microsoft did this with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-05-microsoft-surface-pro-x-review-price-specs-availability-windows-arm-lte.html"><ins>ARM-based Surface Pro X</ins></a> and, sure enough, the Surface Pro 8 looks a lot like the X. Its enclosure is aluminum, while the Pro 7’s was a magnesium alloy, but the effect is similar. This is a good thing, considering the dated design was one of only a few complaints in our Surface Pro 7 review.</p><p>In addition to having a larger screen, the Pro 8 is also heavier: 1.96 pounds without the keyboard, up from 1.7. (The keyboard adds 0.62 pounds.) Of course, “heavy” is a relative term. I would be less inclined than ever to use the detached tablet the way I would my smartphone. But my shoulder bag feels appreciably lighter now that I’ve swapped in the roughly two-pound Pro 8 for my three-pound MacBook Pro. Even the power brick is lighter.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5f555e00-2534-11ec-b393-3b84e07860a3" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="A close-up of the vents on Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8." data-uuid="d815df58-6955-308b-92ef-b210877f9e71"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>Besides — and I can’t emphasize this enough — the Surface Pro 8 isn’t a mobile device. It looks and acts like a laptop, even if the keyboard folio isn’t included. It has a thin railroad track of vents along the top and sides, a necessity given the Core i5/i7 processor inside.</p><p>Meanwhile, the two USB-C ports now support Thunderbolt 4. Users have been requesting this for a while, and it means that people can now plug in high-speed drives, multiple 4K displays and eGPUs.</p><p>The built-in kickstand also suggests Microsoft knows people are going to spend more time docking the device than holding it. The kickstand in this year’s model is at once gorgeous and slightly annoying. The weighty aluminum helps the Pro 8 feel like the high-end device it is. Even the “snap” it makes when you pop it into place somehow <em>sounds</em> premium. On the other hand, even after using the Pro 8 for a few days, I still find the kickstand awkward to pull out; the narrow divots make it tough to grab onto.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/48ad27b0-2533-11ec-bf8d-9ea5dda4a116" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8, photographed from behind on a roof deck." data-uuid="c6be54e9-b8c1-3ece-a234-1acb453c3ae8"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>Once you get it open, though, you’ll enjoy flexible viewing angles and a sturdy design that makes it comfortable to use the Pro 8 in your lap. I even used it on my outstretched legs while propped up in bed, though I don’t necessarily recommend that for extended use.</p><p>Finishing up our hardware tour, the rear camera now shoots at 10 megapixels, up from 8MP, and can record in 4K. The images are… fine. But certainly not worth the embarrassment of shooting photos in public with a 13-inch tablet, nor the inconvenience of having to hold a two-pound device steady. Just use your smartphone.</p><p>I’m more impressed by the webcam, the same 5-megapixel/1080p sensor used in the Pro 7+ and Pro X. It’s just so much more capable in mixed lighting than my MacBook Pro. A coworker who I regularly see on video calls remarked on the “night and day” difference from my normal setup. Not only was the image sharper, but it did a better job lighting my face.</p><h2>In use</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e2c71360-2533-11ec-b63c-358db3241849" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="A close-up of Microsoft&#39;s Signature Pro Keyboard." data-uuid="872af7e9-0439-3a1b-85c4-04a531f2e9af"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>To test the Surface Pro is also to test its accessories. And this year, it also meant getting acquainted with Windows 11, which is available for everyone <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-release-date-132605467.html"><ins>starting today</ins></a>.</p><p>As part of its reviewer package, Microsoft included the Surface Pro Signature Keyboard (<a href="https://fave.co/2ZWOpdR"><ins>$180</ins></a>) and the new <a href="https://fave.co/3Fk8b3g"><ins>$130 Slim Pen 2</ins></a>, which <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-151216222.html"><ins>uses a haptic motor</ins></a>, and promises lower latency, a sharper tip and improved precision. That pen docks inside a charging cradle on the Signature Keyboard, which was also designed to be used with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-x-wifi-only-899-usd-151558748.html"><ins>the Surface Pro X</ins></a>.</p><p>Like earlier Surface keyboards, the Signature is covered in Microsoft’s soft Alcantara material, which feels like either suede or felt, depending on how I touch it. All told, there are two ways to use the keyboard: you can allow it to lie flat on your desk, with the pen cradle exposed above the Function row. Or, you can fold up the pen-dock piece so that it magnetically attaches to the tablet’s lower bezel. This lifts the keyboard at a more ergonomic angle.</p><p>There are pros and cons to each method: I find the ergonomic lift more comfortable, but felt distracted by the flimsiness of the panel under my furious typing. On the other hand, as insubstantial as the panel feels, the buttons themselves are spacious and springy. The wobble might sometimes annoy me, but I rarely miss when touch-typing on this.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7555cd80-2533-11ec-b5fb-53da1ba593d3" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="Close-up of the touchpad on the Microsoft Surface Signature Pro Keyboard." data-uuid="8ad70129-e3c9-352d-b583-098e9589ec37"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>The trackpad, meanwhile, is decently sized. Two-finger scrolling feels smooth. (And thanks to the screen’s relatively tall 3:2 aspect ratio, I do slightly less of that on webpages.) For extended use, I preferred using a Bluetooth mouse (in this case, the $30 <a href="https://fave.co/3nYXGvF"><ins>Ocean Plastic Mouse</ins></a> that Microsoft included with my Surface Pro 8 loaner). But you don’t <em>need</em> a standalone mouse, especially if you’re on the go.</p><p>For whatever quibbles I have about the keyboard (including the fact that it’s sold separately), I love the Slim Pen 2. The haptic motor is a small but delightful touch, vibrating when you flip over the pen to erase something. I used the pen to write in Windows 11 text entry fields and Windows mostly recognized my sloppy handwriting. In the Microsoft Store I had to try twice to get it to decipher “Evernote”; it initially thought I typed “everyone.” But other than that it generally understood what I was trying to write.</p><p>Aside from Evernote, I tried the pen in other apps including OneNote and the <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/welcome-to-the-new-whiteboard/ba-p/2779824"><ins>recently redesigned Whiteboard</ins></a>, the latter of which I found particularly enjoyable. (What can I say? I’m a sucker for rainbow and glitter pens.) I also sometimes found myself just scrolling with the pen, even though it’s just as easy to use my fingers. By the end of my testing period, I felt about the Slim Pen 2 the way I did in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-air-2020-review-130044886.html"><ins>my iPad Air review last year</ins></a>: Most people don’t <em>need </em>a stylus, but they’re more fun to use than you might think.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b347f500-2533-11ec-b73f-b313d619b12e" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="Microsoft&#39;s Surface Signature Pro Keyboard with the Slim Pen 2 docked inside." data-uuid="20ece21a-901b-34bf-9d98-b4be08659f79"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>In both laptop and tablet mode, I felt charmed by Windows 11. The OS makes a good first impression with a fast and efficient setup, including the Windows Hello facial recognition enrollment process, which only took a few seconds. I admittedly felt disoriented seeing the center-aligned Taskbar, but you can move it back to its proper place on the left.</p><p>Additionally, I appreciated the redesigned Microsoft Store, where it was easy for me to quickly find and download all of my favorites. And in tablet mode, the elements get subtly larger when you unplug the keyboard, making it easier to select what you want using a combination of finger taps and the large on-screen keyboard.</p><p>Perhaps most impressive of all is the feature that allows you to hover over a window’s maximize icon to see different layout options, including half-and-half, a two-to-one ratio and a couple types of quadrants. It’s just so much more convenient than dragging a window toward the side of the screen, hoping it snaps into place and then tinkering (using a possibly finicky touchpad) to get the window sized the way you want. Frankly, I always found the split-view experience kludgy across Windows, macOS and iPadOS, but with this change I think Microsoft clearly has the more elegant solution.</p><h2>Performance and battery life</h2><table><tbody><tr><td></td><td><p>PCMark 10</p></td><td><p>3DMark Night Raid</p></td><td><p>ATTO disk speeds (top read/write)</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Microsoft Surface Pro 8 (Intel Core i7-1185G7, Intel Iris Xe graphics)</p></td><td><p>4,542</p></td><td><p>16,092</p></td><td><p>2.25 GB/s / 1.47 GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Microsoft Surface Pro 7 (Intel i5-1035G4, Intel Iris Pro graphics)</p></td><td><p>3,324</p></td><td><p>N/A</p></td><td><p>1.79 GB/s / 750.71 MB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Samsung Galaxy Book Pro 360, 15-inch (Intel Core i7-1165G7, Intel Iris Xe graphics)</p></td><td><p>4,648</p></td><td><p>N/A</p></td><td><p>2.33 GB/s / 1.85 GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Nano (Intel Core i7-1160G7, Intel Iris Xe graphics)</p></td><td><p>3,154</p></td><td><p>13,967</p></td><td><p>2.32 GB/s / 1.56 GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Dell XPS 13 2020 (Intel Core i7-1065G7, Intel Iris Plus graphics)</p></td><td><p>4,005</p></td><td><p>10,047</p></td><td><p>2.7 GB/s / 1GB/s</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>For the record, I did not test the entry-level $1,100 model but rather, a more expensive $1,900 configuration with a quad-core 3GHz Intel Core i7-1185G7 processor, 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage.</p><p>Though the benchmarks indicate a laptop whose performance equals or slightly trails other Core i5/i7 machines with integrated Intel Iris Xe graphics, for all intents and purposes it felt like a fast machine in everyday use. As I said, too, all of this mundane stuff feels that much zippier when you switch to 120Hz mode.</p><p>As for battery life, Microsoft claims the Surface Pro 8 can last up to 16 hours on a charge, up from 10.5 on the last generation. Battery performance was one of my colleague Cherlynn Low’s main complaints about the Pro 7; it actually performed worse than the model that preceded it. I’m happy to report that the battery life here is much improved: I logged 13 hours and six minutes in our standard test, up from seven hours and 50 minutes on the Pro 7. That was with the default 60Hz screen refresh rate, of course; with the 120Hz option enabled, the machine lasted seven hours and 36 minutes under the same conditions.</p><p>It’s worth noting that, while Engadget has tested laptops this year that lasted even longer in the same battery test (think: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/surface-laptop-4-review-2021-bigger-better-ultraportable-133047360.html"><ins>15</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-flex-5g-review-windows-on-arm-snapdragon-pc-140042969.html"><ins>almost 17 hours</ins></a>), those systems either packed a less-powerful ARM processor or were significantly larger and heavier. Considering the Surface Pro 8’s chip and relatively light weight, the battery life is pretty good.</p><h2>Configuration options</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b73b59d0-2534-11ec-af7f-ca6e539ad25e" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8, photographed on a roof deck." data-uuid="afe645b7-9340-3a24-9b83-3d48955ce506"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>The Surface Pro 8 starts at $1,100 with a quad-core Core i5-1135G7 processor, 8GB of RAM and a 128GB SSD. The base-model Surface Pro 7 cost $749, but that was with a Core i3 chip and half the RAM, just four gigs. (If you don’t mind aging, lower-powered hardware and would rather save money, Microsoft sells the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-lte-143814278.html"><ins>Surface Pro 7+</ins></a> for <a href="https://fave.co/2ZKsqGL"><ins>$800</ins></a> with a Core i3 CPU.)</p><p>Even with that caveat about the discontinued Core i3 sku, if you wanted a Core i5 machine last year with 8GB of memory and 128 gigs of storage, the price was $900 then, not $1,100. So, while calling it a $350 price hike feels imprecise, it’s definitely a $200 increase even if you stick to direct comparisons.</p><p>But I digress. If you’re happy with the Core i5 CPU and 8GB of RAM on this year’s base model but want more storage, you can buy an otherwise identical machine with a 256GB or 512GB SSD for $1,200 or $1,400, respectively. A Core i5 machine with 16GB of RAM costs $1,400 with 256GB of storage.</p><p>Meanwhile, the least expensive Core i7 model costs $1,600. (That, too, has 16GB of RAM and a 256GB drive.) From there, you can step up to Core i7 with 512GB of storage ($1,900) or a terabyte ($2,200). If you really wanted, you could have Core i7, a 1TB SSD and 32GB of RAM, all for a cool $2,600. Oh, and you’d still have to pay extra if you wanted the keyboard and pen.</p><p>There’s also an LTE-equipped model. Just know that that variant maxes out at 512GB of storage and won’t be available until “a later date.” They will start at $1,100 with a Core i3 processor.</p><h2>The competition</h2><p>To recap, the <a href="https://fave.co/3BbBGS3"><ins>base $1,100 configuration</ins></a> with the $180 keyboard costs $1,280, and let’s be real: You definitely want the keyboard. That puts it squarely in ultraportable-laptop territory.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a147bb90-2535-11ec-bf7d-dfe56615e1be" style="height:1067;width:1600;" alt="The Dell XPS 13, as photographed for Engadget&#39;s review of the 2020 edition." data-uuid="42253f4e-ee99-35a4-be68-a0655d12b604"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>Perhaps its most obvious competitor is the <a href="https://bit.ly/2Y3TakZ"><ins>Dell XPS 13</ins></a>, a longtime <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-04-01-dell-xps-13-review-best-ultraportable.html"><ins>Engadget favorite</ins></a> that we described as “tweaked to near perfection” in our most recent review. It currently starts at $967 on Dell’s website with a Core i3 processor. You can get a Core i5 machine with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for $1,170, whereas the Surface Pro 8 costs $1,100 with 128GB of storage and no keyboard. However, a touchscreen brings the XPS 13 to $1,269, which is similar to what the Surface Pro 8 costs with the keyboard. At that point, it depends on your priorities: You get a more optimal typing experience with the XPS 13, but pen support and more flexibility with the Surface Pro 8.</p><p>Another easy comparison: <a href="https://fave.co/2ZQ0wsZ"><ins>HP’s Spectre 13 x360</ins></a>. It’s a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-27-hp-spectre-x360-13-inch-review.html"><ins>convertible laptop</ins></a> with a Core i5 CPU, Iris Xe graphics, 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for $900. In our review we awarded it a high score of 94 and listed barely any cons, one of which was the webcam.</p><p>It’s also worth comparing the Surface Pro 8 to the most similarly specced Apple products, though my thesis about the Pro 8 is that the likeliest shoppers are already committed Windows users. If you want a proper laptop, the best comparison is the 2.8-pound <a href="https://amzn.to/3FjWVUy"><ins>MacBook Air</ins></a> with Apple’s M1 chip, which costs $1,000 with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. (Versus $1,380 for the Surface Pro 8 and keyboard with the same amount of memory and storage.) Obviously, there’s no touchscreen, though.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d196d420-2535-11ec-a5f7-d67217a07be1" style="height:1542;width:3000;" alt="Apple&#39;s 2021 iPad Pro." data-uuid="0757fb75-02e8-329a-8259-2daa26a4d531"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Chris Velazco/Engadget</div></figure><p>Perhaps the better comparison is the <a href="https://amzn.to/2WCGPUg"><ins>iPad Pro</ins></a>, which starts at $799 with 128GB of storage and a smaller 11-inch screen. (The 12.9-inch model starts at $1,099). Like the Surface Pro, it doesn’t come with a keyboard or stylus (in this case, the similarly priced $129 Apple Pencil). Apple’s first-party <a href="https://amzn.to/3Bbg1tt"><ins>Magic Keyboard</ins></a> costs $299, but you can pay less if you choose a third-party brand. Brydge, for instance, lists its <a href="https://amzn.to/3BdGy9p"><ins>keyboards</ins></a> between $150 and $170 depending on the size of the iPad Pro.</p><p>All of this is to say that if you opted for the smaller 11-inch model and went with Apple’s own keyboard, you’d be paying a similar total price as you would for the Surface Pro 8 and keyboard. The 12.9-inch iPad Pro is more similar in size to the Pro 8 but is more expensive once you factor in the keyboard.</p><p>More than hardware, the choice there comes down to the user experience. iPadOS will feel more familiar to iOS and macOS users, and it has a better selection of touch-specific apps, but it just isn’t as good at multitasking as Windows 11.</p><h2>Wrap-up</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/088f94b0-2533-11ec-b9a3-0ab15069c542" style="height:1300;width:2000;" alt="Microsoft&#39;s Surface Pro 8 and Signature Pro Keyboard accessory." data-uuid="27319964-9d1e-3c8f-8e95-daa497cb8401"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dana Wollman/Engadget</div></figure><p>The Surface Pro is incrementally better in its eighth generation, with a fast-refreshing screen, much-requested Thunderbolt 4 support and a return to long battery life. But it’s also more expensive than ever, with a $350 higher starting price that effectively wipes out any price advantage it once had over premium ultraportable laptops. The pricier the Surface Pro gets, the more caveats I have to append to my recommendation.</p><p>The pen-on-tablet experience is lovely, but the most persuasive reason for me to recommend the Surface Pro is the 120Hz display. It truly makes a difference in everyday use. Microsoft needs to do a better job communicating the benefits to would-be buyers, though. I understand why it’s disabled out of the box (battery life, duh), but how will average users find it if they’re not in the know? And as of this writing, the 120Hz refresh rate doesn’t get a prominent mention on Microsoft’s product page.</p><p>Meanwhile, as good as the typing experience and battery life are, they’re not necessarily superior to a comparably priced notebook. If you only have money for one high-end laptop-like device, then, the bar seems higher for choosing the Surface Pro over an ultraportable.</p><p><em>Special thanks to senior editor Devindra Hardawar and reviews editor Cherlynn Low.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-pro-8-review-130044641.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">37185bb9-0f5c-4cde-9e5c-bd6b626cf09f</guid><dc:creator>Dana Wollman</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633369167</ingested><modified>2021-10-04T17:39:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Dana Wollman]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/08a498c0-2532-11ec-bbeb-89489df6e407" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/08a498c0-2532-11ec-bbeb-89489df6e407" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dana Wollman/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Microsoft Surface Pro 8, photographed on a roof deck with the keyboard folio attached.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Pro 8]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yubico's new security keys have fingerprint readers for added protection]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yubico&#39;s latest <a href="https://www.engadget.com/yubicos-latest-security-key-uses-nfc-or-usbc-for-authentication-121635229.html">physical security keys</a> have another layer of security: fingerprint readers. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:YubiKey Bio Series" href="https://fave.co/3lb3ccQ">YubiKey Bio Series</a> is the company&#39;s first lineup with built-in biometric authentication for passwordless and second-factor logins.</p><p>You can use the keys on desktop platforms that support WebAuthn, including Windows, macOS, Chrome OS and Linux operating systems and Chromium-based browsers including Edge and Chrome. With the Yubico Authenticator for Desktop app, users can add and remove fingerprints. If, for some reason, you can&#39;t use the fingerprint reader, you can enter a PIN instead.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/39b0fe20-2543-11ec-adef-388289383b94" alt="YubiKey Bio" data-uuid="70f70229-9248-348a-ad0e-36ea1ac38131"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Yubico</div></figure><p>YubiKey Bio devices support FIDO2/WebAuthn and U2F protocols, as well as the YubiEnterprise subscription service. You&#39;ll be able to use the same key for a variety of operating systems and desktop devices. It&#39;ll work with any app or service that supports FIDO protocols, including Citrix Workspace, GitHub, IBM Security Verify and Microsoft 365.&nbsp;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/yubico">Yubico</a> opted for a three-chip architecture, which allows it to store fingerprint data separately on a secure element. The company says that provides &quot;enhanced protection from physical attacks.&quot;</p><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:YubiKey Bio" href="https://fave.co/3lb3ccQ">YubiKey Bio</a> keys are available from Yubico&#39;s website in either USB-A or USB-C formats. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:USB-A model costs $80" href="https://fave.co/3ozCehp">USB-A model costs $80</a> and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:USB-C is $85" href="https://fave.co/2YdRBkl">USB-C is $85</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/yubico-yubikey-bio-fingerprint-reader-130034276.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f07dc279-ba06-4a51-bfd5-4ca9c2fac051</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:00:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633445260</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T14:47:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/34c44fc0-2543-11ec-babf-956a118b48b7" width="2500" height="1843" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/34c44fc0-2543-11ec-babf-956a118b48b7" width="2500" height="1843" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Yubico]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[YubiKey Bio]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[YubiKey Bio]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Go 3 review: Third time isn't quite the charm]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has been trying to straddle two different worlds with the Surface Go. When it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-08-02-surface-go-review.html">launched in late 2018</a>, Microsoft positioned it as an inexpensive way to get the 2-in-1 Surface experience. Three years later, that’s still true: The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Surface Go 3" href="https://fave.co/2YrJdOv">Surface Go 3</a>, which Microsoft unveiled in late September, is an exceedingly well-built tablet, with a lovely screen and strong kickstand. For a device that starts at $400, it feels great.</p><p>But the full truth of the Surface Go 3 is a little more complicated. You need to shell out at least another $100 for a keyboard. And, seeing as Windows still doesn’t offer a great tablet experience you <em>need</em> the keyboard. Not to mention the basic $400 Surface Go 3 is underpowered – so by the time you’re buying a keyboard and bumping up the processor, storage and RAM, you’re spending as much money as you might on a full-fledged laptop with a larger display and more powerful internals.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Our review unit came with a 10th-generation Intel Core i3-10100Y processor, 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage. But that configuration costs $630, not including the $130 Alcantara-clad Type Cover and $100 Surface pen Microsoft sent along as well. It’s a fairly capable machine despite its tiny size, making it a potentially great travel companion. But if you’re going to spend $860 for the kit that I’m testing, you should know exactly what you want to do with it that you can’t do with a standard laptop.</p><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="0ed786b7-ff08-45b5-9447-fc82095fc270"/><p>When we <a href="https://www.engadget.com/surface-go-2-review-microsoft-tablet-pc-180000917.html">reviewed the Surface Go 2 </a>last spring, we noted that it was nearly identical to the first version, with the notable exception of a larger screen. This time out, I’m pretty sure the external hardware is completely identical. The Surface Go 3 is the exact same size and weight as its predecessor, and the display is the same 10.5-inch, 1,920 x 1,280 touchscreen as before.</p><p>That’s not a knock on the hardware, though, as the Surface Go 3 is a wonderfully designed and constructed device. I haven’t used previous Surface devices extensively, but Microsoft’s reputation for thoughtful hardware is well deserved. The screen is bright, sharp and colorful, with great viewing angles. I also very much appreciate the taller 3:2 aspect ratio – a 16:9 panel here would feel very cramped for vertical space.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fcd6410-2549-11ec-b7ef-79edc6b2a4d1" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="1e8613a7-dec1-3a5e-8bc1-a51fe83e9510"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>I’m also a big fan of the infinitely adjustable kickstand. I’m no visual artist, but the way you can push it nearly all the way around to prop up the tablet for drawing is a brilliant design decision, and the way the Surface Pen magnetically snaps to the side for easy access is very handy. It really makes me wish I could draw, but alas.</p><p>As before, the Surface Go 3 only has a few ports and buttons. There’s a USB-C port on one side as well as a headphone jack and Microsoft’s proprietary charging port. The good news is you can use the USB-C port for faster charging (as well as any other peripherals you have) and use the cables you probably already have instead of the slower charger. Up top, there’s a power button and volume rocker; an 8-megapixel camera stares out from the back of the tablet. Two stereo speakers flank the display, and there’s a 5-megapixel front-facing camera with a 1080p resolution for video calls. It also works with Windows Hello for face unlock. Finally, under the kickstand you’ll find a Micro SDXC card reader, but you really have to go searching for it.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc0e0f1-2549-11ec-be7f-6ff48a435d99" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="afcf1ecd-f33f-3912-9511-492e7717e5e6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>Every time Microsoft releases new Surface tablets, questions follow about whether Windows is actually a viable platform for touchscreen use. With Windows 11, the answer is still “not really.” But purely on the strength of its hardware, the Surface Go 3 is a lovely tablet. The 3:2 aspect ratio makes it work well when holding it in either portrait or landscape mode. And at 1.2 pounds it’s a little heavier than an iPad, but not so much so that you’ll get tired of holding it.</p><p>We typically recommend Surface buyers use the device with some kind of keyboard, so nearly all my time testing the Go 3 was with Microsoft’s Type Cover attached. It’s unchanged from last year’s version, but that’s OK because Microsoft’s Surface keyboards are surprisingly good. Given the Go’s small size, it felt a bit cramped at first, but after giving my hands a little time to adjust it wasn’t an issue.&nbsp;</p><p>The keys have decent travel and feel very solid, despite the Type Cover’s extremely thin design, and the magnets that attach it to the Go are very strong. The touchpad is fine given its rather small size, but – like the keyboard – it&#39;s not something I want to use for hours on end. When I was using the Go 3 at my desk for extended work sessions, I preferred using a Bluetooth mouse.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc1cb51-2549-11ec-afff-407bb988cc79" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="0b00e871-91f4-36ec-a045-5512c08e5738"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>The Type Cover weighs just over half a pound, so the tablet plus its keyboard cover is a good bit less than two pounds total. While the overall design hasn’t changed, the Surface Go 3 and its keyboard cover are still a very compact and well-designed set. There aren’t many devices that can provide the full Windows experience in such a portable package.</p><p>Unfortunately, as with the prior Surface Go models, you’re trading portability for performance. The Core i3 powering the $630 Go 3 that I’ve been testing is enough for basic tasks, but if you try and push things too much you’re going to be disappointed. My workflow is fairly modest: I mostly live in a browser (I used Edge for this review), and I also run apps including Trello, Slack, Todoist and Spotify. I also wrote this review in Word, to get the full Windows experience. Usually, the Surface Go 3 kept up with these tasks, but I had occasional music stutters and tabs often had to be reloaded if I navigated away from them for more than a minute or two.</p><p>Occasionally, things got worse. The Surface Go 3 mostly ran Adobe Lightroom fine, but moving through the interface definitely required patience as UI elements and photos took a while to load. And if I had it open along with any other programs, things slowed down significantly. Browser tabs were more likely to reload, and opening or switching between other apps took a lot longer. Lightroom performance itself was not terrible, though exporting an edited RAW file to a JPG took long enough that I did most of my photo editing and exporting for this review on my MacBook Pro. Exporting a single image probably took about 10 seconds, compared to a second or two on my Mac.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc21970-2549-11ec-9df0-edf1fd4e1131" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="15e0e7f2-6f97-3a51-8aeb-bf9056333144"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>I’m sure you’ll be shocked to know that being on a video call also led to serious performance issues. When I was on a Google Meet call with some co-workers, switching that and Slack was painfully slow, and Slack had to refresh entirely as if I just opened it. While we’re at it, Slack performance was mediocre on this machine; jumping between different channels and conversations led to noticeable delays. (I’m willing to put some of the blame on Google and particularly Slack, because Slack&#39;s Windows app is not good. But not all of it.) That sums up the Surface Go 3 experience pretty well — I often just had to wait a lot for things to catch up.</p><p>Running our usual suite of Windows benchmarks confirmed my impressions – indeed, according to Geekbench 5 and PCMark10, the new Core i3 processor is nearly identical to the m3 that it replaces. This just highlights that Intel still doesn’t have a great solution for smaller devices. Apple’s $330 iPad, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-9th-generation-review-143045685.html">which I just reviewed</a>, hit 1,336 (single-core) / 3,349 (multi-core) on Geekbench 5, compared to the 859/1,450 I got running it on the Surface Go 3.</p><table><tbody><tr><td></td><td><p>GeekBench 5 CPU</p></td><td><p>PC Mark 10</p></td><td><p>3DMark (Night Raid)</p></td><td><p>ATTO (Top reads/writes)</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Microsoft Surface Go 3 (Core i3-10100Y, Intel UHD)</p></td><td><p>859 / 1,450</p></td><td><p>2,601</p></td><td><p>2,637</p></td><td><p>1.65 GB/s / 808 MB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Microsoft Surface Go 2 (Core m3-8100Y, Intel UHD)</p></td><td><p>800 / 1,590</p></td><td><p>2,737</p></td><td><p>3,848</p></td><td><p>1.6 GB/s / 265 MB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Acer Aspire 5 (Intel Core i3-1115G4, Intel UHD)</p></td><td><p>1,316 / 2,583</p></td><td><p>3,790</p></td><td><p>6,723</p></td><td><p>2.26 GB/s / 893 MB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Lenovo Flex 5 14 (AMD Ryzen 3 4300U, AMD Radeon)</p></td><td><p>730 / 1,879</p></td><td><p>4,186</p></td><td><p>6,271</p></td><td><p>1.40 GB/s / 925 MB/s</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>The battery situation also leaves something to be desired. I got about five hours using the Surface Go 3 during normal use doing my normal work routine — not awful, but given how low-powered the processor is, I expected more. It also makes the Go’s portability less useful, because if you can’t be away from a charger for a full work day, what’s the point of having such a small device? The device did last quite a long time in a lower-power test. The Go 3 lasted almost 11 hours while playing back HD video, which matches up with Microsoft&#39;s estimates for 11 hours.&nbsp;</p><p>The Surface Go 3 isn&#39;t the fastest to charge, either. I had the device plugged in while running some benchmarks, and it took a whopping three hours to charge from 50 percent to 100 percent using the included charger. I was pushing the system pretty hard during that time, but even when I was doing less intense work, it took a good long while to charge. When the Go 3 was asleep, it still took about two hours to fully charge it up from 20 percent.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc1f260-2549-11ec-b7db-3efc946044a1" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="741472d1-d529-3bc6-8a4a-5215880f1d2a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>Benchmarks don’t tell the entire story, but they should give you a good idea of what to expect with the Surface Go 3. I could see the Go 3 making sense as a second computer, a companion to a more powerful Windows desktop for travel. If I was still commuting, I’d be happy to use the Go 3 on my hour-long train ride to go through email, do a little writing and manage all my to-dos. I could also see it being a good companion for running around at events like CES or E3. But I’d probably get tired of writing on that tiny screen.</p><p>But $630 plus another $100 minimum for the Type Cover is a lot of money for a device that feels rather slow and rather cramped. For that kind of money you could certainly get a more capable Windows laptop. Apple’s iPad is also a great option for a secondary computing device, and has the benefit of an OS that was built with tablets in mind; it’s also far more responsive than the Surface Go 3, and there are plenty of keyboard covers out there for getting real work done.</p><p>The value calculus does change if you’re a visual artist, I think. I have zero drawing ability, so the Surface Pen isn’t terribly useful for me. But it’s a very good stylus, and I could see artists who like to use Windows appreciating the Go 3 as a portable drawing tool that can also be a full-fledged computer when you need it. But once again, an iPad probably has better app support for artists who prefer a stylus.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc0e0f0-2549-11ec-b65f-07bb09638b29" alt="Microsoft Surface Go 3" data-uuid="b66d07f3-d8d3-396b-8520-7b2192b829c0"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>Probably the biggest issue with the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Surface Go 3" href="https://fave.co/2YrJdOv">Surface Go 3</a> is that nothing has significantly changed since Microsoft released the Go 2 almost a year and a half ago. The design is still good, but performance and battery life are essentially unchanged, despite the new chip. I can’t recommend that anyone get a Surface Go 3 with the Pentium Gold processor; it feels like the low-end model exists only so Microsoft can say it sells a $400 tablet.</p><p>Just like its predecessors, the Surface Go 3 can be a pretty useful tiny Windows device, though you’re paying a premium for the portability. And the price for performance ration is seriously out of whack. If you’re a  Windows fan, it&#39;a decent option as a secondary device for casual work and for when you want something extremely portable. There aren’t a lot of comparable Windows devices out there, and the hardware’s design and built quality remains outstanding. Just make sure you buy the Type Cover, don’t expect much from tablet mode and be patient if you’re running a lot of apps.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-go-3-review-130025822.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">15dae855-0777-4455-9f84-58f27ada017b</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633438934</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T13:02:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc1cb52-2549-11ec-bffa-35d34a8a41a6" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fc1cb52-2549-11ec-bffa-35d34a8a41a6" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Go 3]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Go 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Surface Laptop Studio review: A better Surface Book, a missed opportunity]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Surface Laptop Studio proves that Microsoft has learned from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/surface-book-3-review-140031292.html">mistakes of the Surface Book </a>— well, most of them. Instead of over-engineering a way to have a detachable screen on a powerful notebook, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Laptop Studio&#39;s " href="https://fave.co/3FhRGVg">Laptop Studio&#39;s </a>display simply tilts forward. Press it down even further, and it turns into an angled digital easel, similar to its larger sibling, the Surface Studio. That <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-easel-hinge-153618416.html">hinged screen</a> isn&#39;t entirely unique — we&#39;ve also seen similar implementations on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-29-hp-spectre-folio-review.html">HP Spectre Folio </a>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-acer-conceptd-7-ezel-pro-hands-on-price-specs-availability-conceptd-700.html">Acer&#39;s ConceptD 7</a>— but it&#39;s still distinctive enough to justify a spot in the Surface family.</p><p>After reviewing the Surface Book 3 last year, it was clear that Microsoft needed a new strategy. All of the Surface Books were actually tablets that docked into a keyboard base, which housed an additional battery and an optional discrete graphics card. The PC guts were placed entirely behind the Book&#39;s screen. That was an ingenious way to make a detachable slate that could take advantage of powerful GPUs, but the tight size constraints severely limited CPU power. It was a design that simply couldn&#39;t keep up against other laptops, which could fit much more powerful hardware.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Enter the Surface Laptop Studio, one of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">first Windows 11 PCs</a>. At first glance, it looks like a direct MacBook Pro competitor. Even before you see its moving screen, it&#39;s evident this isn&#39;t your typical notebook. Its bottom half looks like two slightly different-sized tablets stacked together. That gives you thin edges to hold, but a bit more height to fit in beefy specs. At 3.8 to 4 pounds (depending on the chip you get), it&#39;s over a half-pound heavier than the 15-inch Surface Laptop 4. It’s clearly not trying to be an ultraportable, but Microsoft is also trying to keep it from feeling like a hefty gaming laptop.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8cc17e1-2574-11ec-9deb-e92802e50499" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="25448fca-f360-3ca2-8a1e-66fc464ed6e6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p><strong>Microsoft’s most intriguing display yet</strong></p><p>The Surface Laptop Studio’s 14.4-inch screen is a bit sharper than 1,440p, with a 2,400 by 1,600 resolution. Notably, it&#39;s one of the first productivity PC screens with a fast 120Hz refresh rate. That&#39;s something Microsoft also brought to the new Surface Pro 8, and it simply makes everything on the display look smoother, no matter if you&#39;re scrolling through web pages or jotting down notes with the Surface Slim Pen 2. Typically, high refresh rates have been reserved for gaming laptops (faster action means better headshots, of course), though it&#39;s also a marquee feature of Apple&#39;s iPad Pro.</p><p>In its standard notebook orientation, the Laptop Studio&#39;s display fits right alongside the rest of the Surface family, which historically have had some of the best screens on the market. It also features Dolby Vision support, allowing you to enjoy the higher brightness and contrast from HDR videos and games. I&#39;ve seen countless laptop screens over the years, and while the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/dell-xps-15-oled-review-practically-perfect-15-inch-screen-laptop-120033751.html">XPS 15&#39;s OLED </a>is still the high bar for me, the Laptop Studio comes very close. Everything looks fantastic, and that high refresh rate leads to less eye strain after hours of web browsing (and working on this review). It makes sense: If the screen can scroll more naturally, your eyes don&#39;t have to work extra hard to keep track of everything.</p><section data-eng-breakout="68c6205547864e06923b3d1cfb8ccaed" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8dc4481-2574-11ec-be9c-83722fafc1a4" alt="Surface Laptop Studio"></section><p>Even though it&#39;s surrounded by some chunky bezels — something Microsoft avoided with the Surface Pro 8 — the Laptop Studio&#39;s display entranced me. And that&#39;s before I started spending time with its flexible modes. You can pull it forward with just two fingers, and it magnetically rests between the keyboard and trackpad. That&#39;s useful for binging video, especially if you prefer using the touchpad instead of dirtying your screen. Another plus for the Surface Studio: It has surprisingly powerful speakers, including two subwoofers spitting sound out the sides of the laptop, and two tweeters blasting through the keyboard. They also support Dolby Atmos for (very basic) simulated surround sound.</p><p>You can get into easel mode by pulling the Laptop Studio&#39;s screen completely forward, where it&#39;s angled up slightly for sketching and writing. And while Microsoft hasn&#39;t advertised this too much, you can also push the screen backwards so that the keyboard is completely behind it. That could be helpful for stepping through presentations without turning your entire computer around.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8cb2d80-2574-11ec-bdd6-4aa08dcba3fc" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="6679dc10-c465-3aae-a0de-eaa058214eb7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>That last orientation also gives you a clear view of the Surface Laptop Studio&#39;s unique hinge. The area directly underneath the display is covered in a smooth cloth, which also keeps the hinge from making direct contact with the screen. The hinge mechanism feels a bit flimsy at first, until you figure out where the display is supposed to rest for each mode. Microsoft reps tell us that they typically put their hinges through years of testing, so they should last for the lifetime of the laptop. Still, I&#39;d certainly be anxious about putting this laptop in front of a small child. My parental spidey sense can foresee disaster if a kid starts pulling the screen.</p><p><strong>A solid Surface Book successor… mostly</strong></p><p>The big takeaway after living with the Laptop Studio for around a week: It&#39;s so much easier to use than the Surface Book. I don&#39;t have to worry about hitting the eject button to release the screen, and placing it in the exact right spot when I want to lock it back in. There&#39;s no obscene hinge curve, which always made it difficult to fit the Surface Book into slim bags. And finally, Microsoft can throw more power into a high-end Surface!</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8dc6b92-2574-11ec-abef-b598fb8165be" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="348dd929-60bc-3684-a62b-1d6b48cfa8d6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>Well, sort of. The Laptop Studio is powered by quad-core 11th-gen Intel chips, either the i5-11300H or the i7-11370H. Both are a big step up from the 10th-gen hardware in the Book 3, but it&#39;s curious that Microsoft didn&#39;t push for six or eight-core CPUs. If Dell can <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-26-dell-xps-13-10th-gen-intel-core-alienware-oled-availability.html">squeeze a six-core chip into the XPS 13</a>, why can&#39;t Microsoft make that happen in its flagship Surface notebook? When asked about the power limitation, Microsoft representatives said their research showed a quad-core CPU with discrete graphics (the Laptop Studio can also be equipped with NVIDIA&#39;s RTX 3050 Ti) was the best option for their users. But as someone who knows plenty of media professionals and other would-be Laptop Studio customers, I find that hard to believe.</p><p>Even if that&#39;s the case, it&#39;s hard to recommend a system with a quad-core chip when there are so many competitors sporting more power. At least Microsoft is using Intel&#39;s beefier H35 chips, which are meant for ultraportable gaming laptops. Our benchmarks show the Laptop Studio is a significant step up from the Book 3 in every benchmark. But it doesn&#39;t have a chance against the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-blade-14-review-amd-ryzen-173003809.html">Razer Blade 14</a>, which can be equipped with an eight-core AMD CPU and NVIDIA RTX 3080 GPU. That&#39;s particularly damning when the Blade 14 tops out at $2,800, whereas the comparable Laptop Studio model is $2,700. The only downside for Razer is that its machine comes with 16GB of RAM, instead of the Surface&#39;s 32GB.</p><table><tbody><tr><td></td><td><p>PCMark 10</p></td><td><p>Geekbench 5</p></td><td><p>3DMark Night Raid</p></td><td><p>ATTO disk speeds (top read/write)</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Surface Laptop Studio (Intel Core i7-11350H, NVIDIA RTX 3050 Ti)</p></td><td><p>5,397</p></td><td><p>1,445/5,430</p></td><td><p>26,566</p></td><td><p>3.2 GB/s / 3 GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Razer Blade 14 (AMD Ryzen 9 5900HX, NVIDIA RTX 3080)</p></td><td><p>6,551</p></td><td><p>1,443/7,226</p></td><td><p>35,812</p></td><td><p>3 GB/s / 2GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Surface Pro 8 (Intel Core i7-1185G7, Xe graphics)</p></td><td><p>4,542</p></td><td><p>1,289/5,217</p></td><td><p>16,092</p></td><td><p>2.25 GB/s / 1.47 GB/s</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Surface Laptop 4 15&quot; (AMD Ryzen 7 4980U Surface Edition, Radeon)</p></td><td><p>4,620</p></td><td><p>1,048/6,551</p></td><td><p>15,517</p></td><td><p>1.9 GB/s / 985 MB/s</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>It could just be that Microsoft is setting itself up for an even bigger Laptop Studio down the line. The Book 3 came in 13.5- and 15-inch variations, so I wouldn&#39;t be surprised to see a future 16-inch studio with even beefier hardware eventually. Perhaps Microsoft is just waiting to see what Apple&#39;s next hardware refresh means for the 16-inch MacBook Pro.</p><p>Ignoring how it competes on a hardware level, the Laptop Studio is a solid performer for everyday computing tasks. It&#39;s also fast enough to reach between 90 and 100fps in <em>Overwatch </em>at the Studio&#39;s native resolution and ultra graphics settings. That&#39;s better than what I saw with<a href="https://www.engadget.com/dell-xps-15-oled-review-practically-perfect-15-inch-screen-laptop-120033751.html"> the XPS 15 OLED</a>, which could only reach around 70fps in 1,440p with a slightly slower RTX 3050 Ti. For most people, it&#39;ll be very capable for media work with some light gaming on the side. Still, I can&#39;t help but sigh at some of the benchmarks: how is it only slightly faster than the Surface Pro 8 — <em>a tablet </em>— in Geekbench 5?</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8dc6b90-2574-11ec-bbab-557f252f88c2" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="c3daeab1-ed10-3eb7-ae7e-8fb3f5b4e672"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>I was similarly annoyed by the Surface Laptop Studio&#39;s anemic port situation. It only has two USB-C ports alongside the proprietary Surface Connect slot. Thankfully, those USB-C connections also support ThunderBolt 4, so they&#39;ll work with high-bandwidth storage devices, external GPUs and let you string together multiple 4K external monitors. Still, it&#39;s a shame to see the Book 3&#39;s SD card slot go. I suppose Microsoft is just following in Apple&#39;s footsteps here with the 13-inch MacBook Pro, but it sure seems like a missed opportunity to outdo their competitor. Also, strangely, while the Surface Pro 8 has an easily accessible NVMe SSD slot for additional storage, there&#39;s no secondary SSD slot for the Studio. (Though you could unscrew the bottom of its case and replace its SSD eventually.)</p><p>So that&#39;s a few big strikes against the Surface Laptop Studio, at least as a machine meant for creative professionals. Thankfully, Microsoft brought over one of the best aspects of the Book 3: that fabulous keyboard. It&#39;s wide, responsive and has some of the most satisfying key travel I&#39;ve ever felt in a laptop. It&#39;s also accompanied by a Precision Haptic touchpad, which has no moving parts, but does a great job of mimicking that click you feel when pressing on a trackpad. That tech isn&#39;t new, exactly: Apple has<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-03-13-ifixit-new-macbook-force-touch-trackpad.html"> offered it on MacBooks since 2015</a>, but we&#39;re only now  beginning to see it on PCs, like<a href="https://www.engadget.com/sensel-force-sensing-tech-lenovo-laptop-130004184.html"> Lenovo&#39;s ThinkPad X1 Titanium Yoga</a>.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8cc17e2-2574-11ec-8fd9-4dbe040594ed" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="c9890f90-69ee-3bea-acd9-54bd97d19bc2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>The new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Surface Slim Pen 2" href="https://fave.co/3Fk8b3g">Surface Slim Pen 2</a> — which unfortunately costs an additional $130 — is also the perfect companion to the Laptop Studio&#39;s excellent keyboard and trackpad. It&#39;s easy to hold and it has a haptic motor of its own, which helps to mimic the feeling of putting pen to paper. That&#39;s a thoughtful addition, as the feeling of a stylus nub against glass always felt unnatural to me. The Slim Pen 2, meanwhile, makes me feel like I&#39;m actually writing in a notebook. And unlike the Surface Book, there&#39;s a secure spot to store the new stylus right underneath the keyboard. It also wirelessly charges off of the Surface, which is much more convenient than carrying around tiny spare batteries.</p><p>Speaking of batteries, the Laptop Studio lasted an admirable 12 hours and 25 minutes with a 120Hz refresh rate during our battery benchmark. When I knocked that down to 60Hz, a must if you ever need to save some energy, it went for 17 hours and 15 minutes. But really, save your eyes whenever possible — just keep 120Hz on.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8cc17e0-2574-11ec-b8d9-49ba4d00f250" alt="Surface Laptop Studio" data-uuid="1647bbdd-636a-3f1b-b6e3-8565cf4875a9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p><strong>Wrap-up</strong></p><p>Here’s the thing: I genuinely like using the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Surface Laptop Studio" href="https://fave.co/3FhRGVg">Surface Laptop Studio</a>. Its flexible screen is far less frustrating than the Surface Book’s, it has an excellent keyboard and it’s powerful enough to play a few games. But I can’t help but want more, especially after seeing how much the Surface Book line struggled since its inception.</p><p>With a starting price of $1,600, the Surface Laptop Studio directly competes with Dell’s XPS 15, the MacBook Pro 16-inch, and the Razer Blade. You’d have to shell out at least $2,100 to get the NVIDIA GPU, which puts it up against far more powerful gaming laptops. So here’s the question: How much is a tilting screen worth to you? If it’s more important than having the best CPU and GPU power around, the Surface Laptop Studio will suit you well. But if you want genuine power for a similar price, just get the Razer Blade 14 already.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/surface-laptop-studio-review-better-surface-book-130019425.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6ea34ed0-480b-4d2b-bbc1-bd754af19c47</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633436830</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T12:27:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8dc6b91-2574-11ec-999f-a8492d5df877" width="2000" height="1293" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b8dc6b91-2574-11ec-999f-a8492d5df877" width="2000" height="1293" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Devindra Hardawar/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Surface Laptop Studio]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Surface Laptop Studio]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Facebook's empire goes offline]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I locked myself out of my apartment yesterday. It’s a rare occurrence, but when it does happen, I usually text my building’s WhatsApp group, begging someone to buzz me in. So it was not a great time for Facebook’s entire network, including WhatsApp, Instagram (oh and Oculus), <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-down-161653706.html https://www.engadget.com/...">to collapse for six hours.</a></p><p>While it’s unclear exactly what happened, during the downtime, the company’s outgoing Chief Technology Officer, Michael Schroepfer, said it was due to “networking issues.”</p><p>Even within Facebook, the issues reportedly led to employees being unable to access emails, Workplace and other tools. <em>The New York Times</em> reported that employees were also physically locked out of offices as workers’ badges stopped working. Poor Facebook.</p><p>By <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-coming-back-online-after-outage-220412330.html">6 PM ET yesterday</a>, most of the services were back, though Facebook for Business Status page still showed &quot;major disruptions&quot; to core services. On Facebook — when it was back online — CEO Mark Zuckerberg <a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10113957526871061"><ins>apologized</ins></a> for the services going down.</p><p>That didn’t help me with my low-priority problem. Fortunately, I gleaned some of my neighbor’s phone numbers from WhatsApp, and sent a few SMS SOSes, ‘00s style. Twenty minutes later, I was finally back in my home.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">Engadget reviews Windows 11</a></h2><h3>Microsoft’s most pleasant OS — until it isn&#39;t.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0d796f90-25c5-11ec-a6af-6538f2311820" style="height:450;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="b9e48a0f-b26f-3ad5-83b0-42755576d162"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>Windows 11 is almost here, and it is (generally) a solid step forward aesthetically from Windows 10. According to Devindra Hardawar, some of the changes may annoy long-time users. It’s a more secure OS as well, but that also means it’s more restrictive, hardware-wise, and potentially harder to upgrade. For those considering their options, we have a guide to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-get-windows-11-download-upgrade-microsoft-200010838.html"><ins>exactly that.</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html">Facebook whistleblower reveals their identity</a></h2><h3>She says company &#39;chooses profits over safety&#39;.</h3><h3></h3><p>Internal documents published by <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> recently revealed that Facebook allowed VIPs to break its rules, and it was aware Instagram affected the mental health of teens. Now, the whistleblower who brought that information to light has revealed herself as Frances Haugen in an interview with <em>60 Minutes</em>.</p><p>&quot;I’ve seen a bunch of social networks, and it was substantially worse at Facebook than what I had seen before,&quot; Haugen told the show. &quot;Facebook, over and over again, has shown it chooses profit over safety.&quot;</p><p>Haugen joined Facebook in 2019, working on democracy and misinformation issues, while also handling counter-espionage, according to a personal website and Twitter account she and her team set up. She worked as a Facebook product manager and left the company in May.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/william-shatner-blue-origin-spaceflight-new-shepard-144025171.html">Blue Origin will fly William Shatner to the edge of space on October 12th</a></h2><h3>Going where Bezos has gone before.</h3><h3></h3><p>After decades of pretending to explore the universe in TV shows and movies, William Shatner is actually going to space. Blue Origin&#39;s second tourist spaceflight is scheduled for October 12th.  Shatner, 90, is to become the oldest person to fly to space. He&#39;ll take the record from 82-year-old aviation pioneer, Wally Funk, who was a passenger on New Shepard&#39;s first crewed flight in July.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/william-shatner-blue-origin-spaceflight-new-shepard-144025171.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-release-date-132657501.html">Apple Watch Series 7 pre-orders open on October 8th</a></h2><h3>Ready to wear on October 15th.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-release-date-132657501.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0d5d5c10-25c5-11ec-bd37-cc333014867c" style="height:380;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="bc2d249b-a9db-347e-bdf0-963913db1446"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure></a><p>Apple has announced when you&#39;ll be able to snag an Apple Watch Series 7. Pre-orders start this Friday, October 8th, at 8 AM ET. The device, which starts at $399, will be available one week later on October 15th.</p><p>The biggest change this year is a larger, always-on display. Apple has bumped up the case size options to 41mm and 45mm while reducing the bezel to 1.7mm, meaning it should feel pretty similar to last-generation Watches, but with more screen. The user interface takes advantage of the larger screen, with a full, swipe-based QWERTY keyboard and two additional watch faces.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-preorder-release-date-132657501.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/following-criticism-apple-now-allows-users-to-report-app-store-scams-094849581.html"><ins>Apple makes it easier to report bad apps and scams</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-now-lets-you-send-gifts-to-friends-with-just-their-email-or-phone-number-082124197.html"><ins>Amazon lets Prime members send gifts with only an email address or phone number</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/crucial-pny-and-lexar-storage-is-up-to-32-percent-off-on-amazon-today-only-125403349.html"><ins>Crucial, PNY and Lexar storage is up to 32 percent off on Amazon today only</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-neckband-speaker-dolby-atmos-bravia-tv-175408900.html"><ins>Sony&#39;s latest neckband speaker supports Dolby Atmos</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-12-android-open-source-project-173339442.html"><ins>Android 12 has been released to the Android Open Source Project</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/you-tube-on-the-web-now-lets-you-resume-watching-a-smartphone-video-114001447.html"><ins>YouTube makes it easy to resume watching a mobile video on desktop</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-asks-for-ftc-antitrust-charges-dismissed-again-180704263.html"><ins>Facebook asks judge to dismiss FTC antitrust charges... again</ins></a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-facebooks-empire-goes-offline-111542675.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f575cfef-fcac-4885-94b8-eed332a32f54</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 11:15:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633429857</ingested><modified>2021-10-05T10:31:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a3928f90-252d-11ec-9eb7-d7e722c7c04e" width="1261" height="772" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a3928f90-252d-11ec-9eb7-d7e722c7c04e" width="1261" height="772" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Igor Bonifiacic / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>