<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 19:15:35 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Instagram's 'Practice Mode' lets users check if they're ready to go live]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Instagram is adding two new enhancements to its livestreaming toolset. Starting today, creators can schedule their Live broadcasts up to 90 days in advance, and share the fact they’re doing so in both posts and Stories. Viewers can use those to set a reminder for themselves not to miss the broadcast.</p><div id="80422c68817243279cff8d8e571e81e5"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Going Live hits different when your followers come through 🙌<br><br>Live Scheduling lets you schedule your stream up to 90 days in advance and followers can set reminders to tune in ❤️🔔 <a href="https://t.co/8t7BWmjEL7">pic.twitter.com/8t7BWmjEL7</a></p>— Instagram (@instagram) <a href="https://twitter.com/instagram/status/1448351873488998400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Instagram also plans to roll out a “Practice Mode” soon. The tool allows creators to connect with guests before they start a broadcast so that they can do things like check audio levels and lighting, and go over any content they plan to cover.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The new features follow the introduction of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-live-mute-audio-disable-video-174622681.html"><ins>audio-only livestreams</ins></a> in April. If you’re someone who merely watches Live sessions, Live Scheduling and Practice Mode won’t change your experience dramatically, but they may help your favorite creators get more organized.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/instagram-live-scheduling-191535112.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">398ed7b0-8337-42ef-8409-78449e677115</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 19:15:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634151349</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T18:55:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4b2b9600-2c56-11ec-93d5-916709a43cb7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4b2b9600-2c56-11ec-93d5-916709a43cb7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Instagram]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Instagram Practice Mode]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Instagram Practice Mode]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok gives livestreamers more ways to mute annoying people]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-live-stream-kindness-discovery-tools-133912505.html">promised in July</a>, TikTok is rolling out more ways for livestreams to wrangle their unruly audiences. Now, streamers and their trusted helper will be able to <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/our-continued-fight-against-hate-and-harassment">temporarily mute people for minutes</a>, hours or the length of an entire livestream. According to Eric Han, head of Tiktok&#39;s US Safety team, muting a person will remove their entire comment history from the stream. And of course, you could also just turn off comments entirely or filter out specific keywords. Together with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-live-stream-kindness-discovery-tools-133912505.html">Tiktok&#39;s last batch of &quot;kindness&quot; updates </a>for livestreamers, the platform is aiming to create a safer environment for creators.</p><p>Han says the prompts TikTok added in July — which pop up to make you think twice about posting an &quot;unkind or harmful&quot; comment — have led almost 40 percent of people editing or withdrawing their comment entirely. That&#39;s not too surprising, as Twitter found a similar feature also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-anti-bullying-prompts-expansion-173049219.html">led to reduced bullying</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Given Tiktok&#39;s meteoric rise as a relatively young social network, it&#39;s apparently learned quite a bit from the struggles of older outfits like Facebook and Twitter. Based on its Q2 <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/resources/tiktok-transparency-report-2021-q-2?lang=en">Community Guidelines Enforcement Report</a>, the company says it&#39;s also getting better at weeding out improper videos. Han says 73.3 percent of harassment videos were removed before there were any user reports, whereas that figure was 66.2 percent in the previous quarter. Similarly, 72.9 percent of videos showing hateful behavior were removed in the second quarter, compared to 67.3 percent previously.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-livestream-mute-temporary-harassment-184929315.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cf7fb092-eeb9-4f03-bb59-4c505749554d</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634150384</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T18:39:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-02/2f6fe710-4ddf-11ea-b3ff-ca9d067be64b" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2020-02/2f6fe710-4ddf-11ea-b3ff-ca9d067be64b" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anatoliy Sizov via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tyumen, Russia - January 21, 2020: TikTok and Facebook application  on screen Apple iPhone XR]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TikTok and Facebook application  on screen Apple iPhone XR]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A live-action 'System Shock' TV series is on the way]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nightdive Studios’ immersive sim franchise <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/system%20shock"><ins>System Shock</ins></a> franchise is being turned into a live-action TV show. You&#39;ll be able to watch it on the upcoming streaming service Binge, which is also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-driver-live-action-tv-show-155250265.html"><ins>working on a show</ins></a> based on Ubisoft&#39;s <em>Driver</em>.</p><p>More details about the <em>System Shock </em>TV show will be revealed in due course. It will tell &quot;a harrowing story of Citadel Station and its rogue AI that subjects the crew to unimaginable horror,&quot; Binge said. The service, which is set to launch next year, didn&#39;t reveal when the series will premiere.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, Nightdive is working on a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/system-shock-remake-summer-release-date-194824409.html"><em><ins>System Shock </ins></em><ins>remake</ins></a>. The game was supposed to arrive this past summer, but it&#39;s now scheduled to debut by the end of 2021.</p><p><em>System Shock </em>joins a long list of shows and movies based on games that are in the pipeline. Among them are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/anthony-mackie-sony-twisted-metal-172027414.html"><em><ins>Twisted Metal</ins></em></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/firewatch-movie-snoot-entertainment-210556286.html"><em><ins>Firewatch</ins></em></a><em>, </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/disco-elysium-tv-series-184111590.html"><em><ins>Disco Elysium</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and a ton of Netflix projects, like <em>League of Legends </em>series <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-trailer-185418635.html"><em><ins>Arcane</ins></em></a>. Rumors are also floating around that Epic Games might be making <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-10-11-epic-mulls-fortnite-movie-as-it-launches-entertainment-division"><ins>a </ins><em><ins>Fortnite </ins></em><ins>movie</ins></a>.</p><p>Elsewhere, Sony is supposed to release the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-movie-delayed-again-again-024721336.html"><em><ins>Uncharted </ins></em><ins>film</ins></a> in February at long, long last. Has, uh, anyone happened to see a trailer lying around somewhere?</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/system-shock-live-action-tv-series-streaming-binge-182014160.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5aa60315-306c-4ecc-a725-6fc51095166f</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 18:20:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634149219</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T18:20:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/614ef3a0-2c51-11ec-9fbf-a544d5b0feb3" width="623" height="311" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/614ef3a0-2c51-11ec-9fbf-a544d5b0feb3" width="623" height="311" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Binge/Nightdive Studios]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A promotional image for the System Shock live-action TV series.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[System Shock]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon India allegedly copied products and promoted its own versions in searches]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/amazon"><ins>Amazon</ins></a> allegedly &quot;ran a systematic campaign&quot; of copying other companies&#39; products in India and gamed search results to promote its own versions. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/amazon-india-rigging/"><em><ins>Reuters</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>obtained thousands of pages of internal documents including emails and business plans that detail the practices.</p><p>A private brands team in India (which works on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-2021-hardware-event-roundup-195702185.html"><ins>the company&#39;s own products</ins></a>) used data from Amazon&#39;s marketplace in the country to find and target goods and create knockoff versions, the agency reported. The goal was to find “reference” or “benchmark” wares and copy them. A document from 2016 detailed a plan for an Amazon brand called Solimo, which is tailored toward the Indian market. The aim was to “use information from Amazon.in to develop products and then leverage the Amazon.in platform to market these products to our customers.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The document indicated that the private brands group aimed to form partnerships with the manufacturers of the benchmark items, because those companies use “unique processes which impact the end quality of the product.” The team sought to gain insights from the manufacturers and use the so-called &quot;Tribal Knowledge&quot; in its own versions to &quot;fully match quality with our reference product.&quot;</p><p>After it made the knockoffs, the company manipulated search results with a method called “search seeding” so that AmazonBasics and Solimo items would pop up near the top of the page, according to the document. The company also &quot;aggressively&quot; used a technique called “search sparkles on PC, Mobile and App to specifically promote Solimo products on relevant customer searches from ‘All Product Search’ and Category search,” per the document. Sparkles are the banners placed above search results.</p><p>&quot;As <em>Reuters </em>hasn&#39;t shared the documents or their provenance with us, we are unable to confirm the veracity or otherwise of the information and claims as stated,&quot; an Amazon spokesperson told Engadget in a statement. &quot;We believe these claims are factually incorrect and unsubstantiated.&quot;</p><p>&quot;Amazon identifies selection gaps based on customer preferences at an aggregate level only and shares this information with all sellers,&quot; the spokesperson added. &quot;Amazon’s policy strictly prohibits the use or sharing of non-public, seller-specific data for the benefit of any seller, including sellers of private brands. This policy applies uniformly across our company to all employees — our internal teams receive regular trainings on its application and we thoroughly investigate any reports of employees acting contrary to this policy.&quot;</p><p>This is far from the first time we&#39;ve heard reports of Amazon allegedly copying other companies&#39; products. Over the years, the company has been accused of cloning the Instant Pot, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-20-allbirds-amazon-copycat.html"><ins>Allbirds sneakers</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peak-design-amazon-video-175235085.html"><ins>a camera bag from Peak Design</ins></a> to name a few. A <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-used-seller-data-for-competing-products-180533964.html"><ins>2020 </ins><em><ins>Wall Street Journal</ins></em><ins> investigation</ins></a> also indicated that Amazon studied sales data of third-party products on its platform to inform the design and pricing of its own goods.</p><p>Regulators in India, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-antitrust-lawsui-washington-dc-attorney-general-155235736.html">the US</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/eu-amazon-antitrust-third-party-data-114513778.html"><ins>Europe</ins></a> have targeted Amazon over alleged anti-competitive practices. <em>Reuters </em>points out that an investigation in India is looking into whether the company unfairly promoted its own branded goods.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-india-products-copy-search-results-manipulation-174030250.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">18c542a4-3c7c-49e7-939d-dfbe4dba7409</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:40:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634146835</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T17:40:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/5d134100-d8e7-11eb-8ffd-a1658ea76643" width="5315" height="3543" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/5d134100-d8e7-11eb-8ffd-a1658ea76643" width="5315" height="3543" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ivan Romano via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NAPLES, ITALY - MARCH 22: A worker inside the Ariete 1 warehouse, during the first Amazon workers strike on March 22, 2021 in Arzano, Italy. The first strike of Amazon workers organized by the CGIL, Cisl and Uil unions at the Arzano headquarters was totally deserted by the workers who did not join the presidium to which, in addition to the unions, some formations of the extra-parliamentary left joined. The unions had called the strike day to ask for a review of many aspects of staff contracts: workloads, shifts, meal vouchers, bonuses, travel allowances and reduced working hours, and a general stabilization of drivers, the logistics sector and the administered employees. For some trade unionists, the absence of workers from the garrison should be read as "fear that their contracts will not be renewed". (Photo by Ivan Romano/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Workers Strike In Naples]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook introduces new policies to protect public figures from targeted harassment]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook is introducing new policies to safeguard users from online bullying and harassment. In a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/advancing-online-bullying-harassment-policies/">post</a> attributed to Head of Safety Antigone Davis, the company said it will take down mass coordinated harassment campaigns targeted at individuals at heightened risk of offline harm. It will do so even if the content people post wouldn’t normally violate its safety guidelines. Additionally, Facebook says it will remove objectionable content in whatever form it takes, be that direct messages, comments or posts. As part of the same policy, the company will remove state-linked networks that work together to silence and harass people.</p><p>Had the above policy been in place in the past, one situation where Facebook may have enforced it was when Taylor Swift’s Instagram account was bombarded with snake emoji following a <a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/columns/pop/7934297/taylor-swift-the-snake-history-kim-kanye-instagram">dramatic breakup with electronic producer Calvin Harris</a>. Speaking of celebrities, the company has also put in place new protections to safeguard public figures from sexual harassment and appearance shaming. To that end, it plans to remove profiles, pages and groups dedicated to sexualizing those individuals. It will also target “severe sexualizing content,” including photoshopped images and drawings.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>“We made these changes because attacks like these can weaponize a public figure’s appearance, which is unnecessary and often not related to the work these public figures represent,” the company said.  Facebook will also provide additional protections for individuals who become famous involuntarily. Those may include individuals like journalists and human rights activists.&nbsp;</p><p>Facebook has repeatedly faced pressure to do more to prevent bullying and harassment across all of its apps, but particularly on Instagram. In the aftermath of the Euro 2020 final, which saw <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/12/football/england-racist-abuse-bukayo-saka-jadon-sancho-marcus-rashford-euro-2020-final-spt-intl/index.html">three Black players</a> on the English national team face a flood of harassment after England lost to Italy, Instagram Head Adam Mosseri promised the company would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-limits-feature-test-223844994.html">introduce new feature</a>s to protect users. “Racism and hate speech have no place on Instagram,” he said at the time. “It is not only honestly fucked up to see people treated that way, but it breaks how Instagram works.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-targeted-harassment-policy-172858497.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">10775835-5fcc-4413-9e16-a618775a6c8b</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:28:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634146144</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T17:29:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2c111270-26c2-11ec-afe7-9bdea293e11a" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/2c111270-26c2-11ec-afe7-9bdea293e11a" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chesnot via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[PARIS, FRANCE - OCTOBER 06: In this photo illustration, the Facebook logo is displayed on the screen of an iPhone on October 06, 2021 in Paris, France. Frances Haugen, a former employee of the Facebook social network created by Mark Zuckerberg, told the US Senate on October 05 that Facebook was prioritizing its profits at the expense of security and the impact of the social network on young users. To support her claims, Frances Haugen draws on her two-year experience as a product manager at Facebook and on the thousands of documents she took with her last spring, grouped together under the name of "Facebook Files ". (Photo illustration by Chesnot/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook : Illustration]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Call of Duty: Warzone' and 'Vanguard' anti-cheat updates include a kernel-level driver]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Activision has unveiled its big, new approach to squashing hackers in <em>Call of Duty: Warzone</em> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-november-5-174533819.html"><em>Vanguard</em></a>, and it&#39;s a two-pronged system called <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2021/10/ricochet-anti-cheat-initiative-for-call-of-duty">RICOCHET Anti-Cheat</a>. The first stage is a series of server-side enhancements that will better identify and remove cheaters from games, and this is scheduled to hit <em>Warzone</em> with the Pacific update later this year. These new server tools will be live in <em>Vanguard </em>when it comes out on November 5th.</p><p>The second prong is a PC kernel-level driver designed to monitor the deepest level of every player&#39;s rig while they&#39;re in-game, in an effort to stop outside software from sneaking in through this back door. The kernel, or ring 0, is the most privileged level of any PC, granting access to every layer of hardware, and generally reserved for things like graphics card drivers and trusted bits of the operating system. The RICOCHET Anti-Cheat kernel-level driver will only turn on when <em>Warzone</em> or <em>Vanguard</em> is active; it&#39;s not an always-on situation.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>While operating in the kernel isn&#39;t uncommon for anti-cheat software, this is likely the most concerning part of Activision&#39;s new plans for many players. Riot Games faced scrutiny in 2020 for implementing a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/valorant-vanguard-riot-games-security-interview-video-170025435.html">similar kernel-level driver in <em>Valorant</em></a>, though the main issue was that it was always on, operating even when the game wasn&#39;t active. (Confusingly, the <em>Valorant</em> anti-cheat system is called Vanguard).</p><div id="c7840546fbe84c279e58bf5f1b31e757"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4W_1zA6j9FU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>This isn&#39;t a new worry, either — in 2013, the always-on ring 0 anti-cheat system employed by <a href="https://play.esea.net/news/12692">ESEA</a> was commandeered to turn unsuspecting players&#39; PCs into a secret bitcoin mining farm.</p><p>With these lessons in mind, Activision has stressed that RICOCHET will only be active when the associated game is live, saying specifically, &quot;the driver shuts down when you exit the game and turns on when you start a new game.&quot;</p><p>The kernel-level driver will hit <em>Warzone</em> alongside the Pacific update this year, and it&#39;ll come to <em>Vanguard</em> at a later date.</p><p>Cheating has been a significant problem in <em>Call of Duty: Warzone</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-warzone-bans-60000-confirmed-cheaters-071107304.html">for a long while now</a>. Activision has banned more than 500,000 accounts since the game&#39;s launch, though it&#39;s not uncommon for matches to be riddled with aimbots and cheap hacks to this day. Players have been screaming for a robust anti-cheat system in <em>Warzone</em> and other Call of Duty titles, and RICOCHET is Activision&#39;s kernel-level, not-always-on answer.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/call-duty-warzone-vanguard-anti-cheat-ricochet-kernel-driver-170043541.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">86578928-da61-49ae-82ca-1e10204557d4</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Conditt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634144204</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T16:56:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jessica Conditt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/07fa1c00-2c45-11ec-a8d7-6b86cb0c143c" width="1920" height="1193" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/07fa1c00-2c45-11ec-a8d7-6b86cb0c143c" width="1920" height="1193" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Activision]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Call of Duty Warzone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Warzone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[DoorDash establishes $1M relief fund for restaurants hit by natural disasters]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the next year, DoorDash has earmarked <a href="https://ir.doordash.com/news/news-details/2021/DoorDash-Establishes-1000000-Restaurant-Disaster-Relief-Fund/default.aspx"><ins>$1,000,000</ins></a> to support local restaurants affected by state or federally declared natural disasters. With help from <a href="https://helloalice.com/"><ins>Hello Alice</ins></a>, it will distribute $10,000 grants to businesses that can use the funds to pay for essential expenses like rent, supplies and payroll in times of need. <a href="https://c212.net/c/link/?t=0&amp;l=en&amp;o=3321314-1&amp;h=3268589323&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fdoordash.helloalice.com%2F&amp;a=doordash.helloalice.com"><ins>Starting on November 1st</ins></a>, the companies will process applications every three months, with funding to follow shortly thereafter.</p><p>Currently, the program is only available to restaurants in the US. Other eligibility requirements include that a business owner operate three restaurants or less. None of those locations may have generated more than $3 million in revenue over the last 12 months. Notably, a partnership with DoorDash or Caviar isn’t required to apply for the program.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The relief fund comes as food delivery apps face increasing scrutiny from local governments. The City of Chicago recently launched separate lawsuits against <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chicago-sues-doordash-grubhub-210424254.html"><ins>DoorDash and GrubHub</ins></a>, accusing the two companies of using bait-and-switch tactics to mislead consumers. New York City also recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/new-york-city-food-delivery-workers-laws-234217000.html"><ins>passed sweeping legislation</ins></a> aimed at protecting workers of app-based delivery services.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/doordash-disaster-relief-fund-162009764.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b22b7de3-026c-4cf6-93c6-f35d586ab806</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:20:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634141062</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T16:04:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/c5c583f0-3a51-11eb-aed7-134ab4b0fc57" width="5124" height="3416" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/c5c583f0-3a51-11eb-aed7-134ab4b0fc57" width="5124" height="3416" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Carlo Allegri / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A DoorDash delivery person is pictured on the day they hold their IPO in the Manhattan borough of New York City, New York, U.S., December 9, 2020. REUTERS/Carlo Allegri]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[DOORDASH-IPO/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bose’s new rugged Bluetooth speaker floats in water]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just in time for the holiday season, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/bose">Bose</a> has released a new portable Bluetooth speaker designed for both strong audio performance and durability. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:SoundLink Flex" href="https://fave.co/3iZbqmR">SoundLink Flex</a> has an IP67 rating, meaning it&#39;s water, dust and dirt resistant, and the company even claims that the speaker will float to the surface if you drop it in water (but you should probably fish it out quickly if it drops into a bathtub or the ocean).</p><p>The silicone rear and powder-coated steel grille should protect the speaker from drops and bumps, according to Bose. The company also claims the device is resistant to UV light and corrosion and it won&#39;t peel or flake.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>But it&#39;s not just the speaker&#39;s apparent toughness that makes it interesting. Bose says it packed the SoundLink Flex with features &quot;to deliver astonishing audio performance.&quot; It claims that the custom transducer provides maximum audio clarity and &quot;bass that you can feel in your chest.” The SoundLink Flex also has dual-opposing passive radiators, as well as Bose&#39;s digital signal processing tech, which should minimize distortion.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/67d190d0-2c3c-11ec-bde7-c031a012c437" alt="A Bose SoundLink Flex portable Bluetooth speaker in some mud." data-uuid="cb2ba729-b153-3e91-a5de-b30f13eca84d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Bose</div></figure><p>The speaker can detect its orientation and adjust the audio output accordingly. So, whether it&#39;s horizontal, vertical or hanging from the utility loop, the sound will be optimized. It&#39;s the company&#39;s first Bluetooth speaker that uses this Bose PositionIQ tech.</p><p>SoundLink Flex can remember up to eight Bluetooth connections to make it easy to switch from one device to another. You can adjust the settings using the Bose Connect app and control your phone&#39;s voice assistant and take calls using the speaker&#39;s microphone.</p><p>You can pair a second Bose Bluetooth speaker for stereo or simultaneous playback. The SoundLink Flex can connect to other Bose speakers and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bose-smart-soundbar-900-dolby-atmos-spatial-audio-144433233.html">soundbars</a> as part of a home audio system. Bose says you&#39;ll get up to 12 hours of playback on a single charge and you can recharge the lithium-ion battery with a USB-C cable.</p><p>The SoundLink Flex is just under eight inches wide, 2.1 inches deep and 3.6 inches tall. It weighs just over a pound and is available in black, white smoke or stone blue. The speaker costs <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:$149" href="https://fave.co/3iZbqmR">$149</a> and you can pick it up from Bose&#39;s website starting today.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bose-soundlink-flex-portable-bluetooth-speaker-rugged-160442384.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7f795460-119b-4595-bb0e-1865f716ea24</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:04:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634149581</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T18:26:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Speakers & Headphones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/650b6bf0-2c3c-11ec-b6d1-5212858bfa79" width="1919" height="1391" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/650b6bf0-2c3c-11ec-b6d1-5212858bfa79" width="1919" height="1391" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bose]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A person holding a Bose SoundLink Flex portable Bluetooth speaker that has water on it.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bose SoundLink Flex portable Bluetooth speaker]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Anker's audio glasses pair swappable frames with 'surround' sound for $200]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Anker is jumping into the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jlab-audio-jbuds-frames-true-wireless-open-ear-speakers-eyewear-152928580.html">increasingly crowded</a> world of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-04-bose-frames-audio-ar-sunglasses-available-january.html">audio eyewear</a>. The company&#39;s Soundcore brand has <a href="https://us.soundcore.com/pages/soundcore_frames_bonus?ref=new_banner">introduced</a> Soundcore Frames glasses that promise stealthy music playback and calls. The hook, in this case, is style — Soundcore is offering your pick of ten reasonably fashionable frames you can swap in and out depending on your mood or lens needs, including prescription, polarized and blue light filtering lenses.</p><p>You&#39;ll also get &quot;surround&quot; sound with speakers in front of and behind the ears, noise reduction (including an anti-leak private listening mode) and a mix of touch and voice-based controls. You won&#39;t use these all day with 5.5 hours of music listening, although a 10-minute charge is enough to provide another 1.5 hours. They&#39;re IPX4 water-resistant, so you at least won&#39;t have to worry about a the rain.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Soundcore Frames will be available in November for $200. Extra frames will cost another $50 each. That&#39;s not a spectacular price for audio glasses, but the style is sharp enough that you might not mind the outlay — especially if you aren&#39;t looking for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-hands-on-160048150.html">smart glasses</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/anker-soundcore-frames-audio-glasses-154554875.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3a4d0043-bb35-431f-a719-e5c1ea86bf6a</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634139957</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T15:45:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/82e37190-2c37-11ec-bbee-acf8b1aa5ba5" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/82e37190-2c37-11ec-bbee-acf8b1aa5ba5" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Soundcore]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Anker Soundcore Frames audio glasses]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Anker Soundcore Frames audio glasses]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reddit's new 'predictions' feature turns polls into a game]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reddit has launched a new feature called Predictions, which can make <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-24-reddit-polls-new-post-type.html">polls</a> more fun by giving you tokens to bet with. The website has been testing the feature for a year, and now that it&#39;s widely available, community mods and mod-approved users will be able to create Predictions Tournaments with a series of questions that challenges you to predict the outcome of an event or conversation.&nbsp;</p><p>You&#39;ll get 1,000 tokens for free when you join a tournament, which can consist of as many questions as a moderator wants — they can add more even after the tournament has started. When you vote for the prediction you want, you&#39;ll have to bet some of the tokens you get after you joined. How to distribute those tokens is totally up to you, and you will win more on top of the ones you used for every correct prediction. The larger the number of tokens you put in, the more you can win. However, you&#39;ll have to make your tokens last throughout the tournament, and there&#39;s no way to get more if it turns out that your prediction game is weak. It&#39;s a totally user-driven experience, since the tournament&#39;s creator will also be in charge of resolving the outcome and making sure you get your winnings.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>So, what do you get for correct predictions aside from winning tokens? Mostly, recognition in the form of a leaderboard. Tokens are only for use in the Prediction experience, so you can&#39;t really do anything with them on the website. Reddit will start rolling out the feature today, and it will be available for all communities with at least 10,000 members.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4f01d7b0-2c1c-11ec-bef2-80c96a2637bc" style="height:647;width:669;" alt="Reddit" data-uuid="e5336946-1b23-3e31-b9a7-7f8237c988a9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Reddit</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/reddit-predictions-150040687.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0b16da11-17c8-4cf1-a92b-d4020805bf7c</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634126677</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T12:04:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/95f87310-06a9-11ec-bf66-80c6a3820096" width="3301" height="2156" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/95f87310-06a9-11ec-bf66-80c6a3820096" width="3301" height="2156" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Reddit app is seen on a smartphone in this illustration taken, July 13, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TECH-REDDIT/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[William Shatner becomes the oldest person to reach space]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#39;s official: after <a href="https://www.engadget.com/william-shatner-blue-origin-spaceflight-new-shepard-144025171.html">plenty of hype</a> and a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-shatner-flight-delay-171339388.html">slight delay</a>, William Shatner has <a href="https://twitter.com/blueorigin/status/1448302595261468677">become</a> the oldest person to fly to space. The 90-year-old Star Trek icon was one of four crew members aboard Blue Origin&#39;s NS-18 mission as it flew to an altitude of 66 miles. He edged out 82-year-old aviation pioneer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wally-funk-blue-origin-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-155036734.html">Wally Funk</a>, who <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-completes-first-crewed-spaceflight-132937714.html">set the previous age record</a> just a few months earlier.</p><p>The New Shepard flight also included Blue Origin VP Audrey Powers, Planet Labs co-founder Dr. Chris Boshuizen and Medidata co-creator Glen de Vries. This is the second of three crewed missions Blue Origin has planned for 2021.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This is an important moment for spaceflight, not to mention sci-fi fans. It shows that age isn&#39;t much of a restriction for brief trips to space, and fulfills the dreams of anyone who wanted to see Captain Kirk visit the final frontier in real life — even if he wasn&#39;t helming a starship.</p><p>With that said, it&#39;s also a timely public relations boost for Blue Origin. Jeff Bezos&#39; private spaceflight outfit is currently grappling with accusations of a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-toxic-workplace-employee-letter-181051514.html">toxic work environment</a>, not to mention the fallout of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-on-blue-origin-lawsuit-151130133.html">legal tussle with SpaceX</a> over NASA&#39;s Moon mission contract. Shatner&#39;s successful trip won&#39;t completely distract from those issues, but it might give Blue Origin a chance to highlight some achievements at a time when many are focused on its shortcomings.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/william-shatner-blue-origin-spaceflight-successful-145444763.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2b220452-01e4-4f4a-a3f8-7f37eeadfaa4</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:54:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634137672</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T15:08:04+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d424de30-2c29-11ec-b72d-6f2c98df9ce1" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d424de30-2c29-11ec-b72d-6f2c98df9ce1" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[William Shatner and the Blue Origin NS-18 crew]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[William Shatner and the Blue Origin NS-18 crew]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat is back online after outage (updated)]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/snapchat">Snapchat</a> is back online after some users had problems with the app this morning, with several noting on Twitter that they were <a href="https://twitter.com/lilliana_romero/status/1448255535489355780">unable</a> to <a href="https://twitter.com/MariahRain11/status/1448289817469595655">send snaps</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/snapchatsupport/status/1448254521914937349">In a tweet posted at</a> 7:29AM ET, Snap said it it was looking into the problem and, at 10:31AM ET, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/snapchatsupport/status/1448295237978365954">said</a> the issue was fixed. All systems should now be back online.</p><div id="6fc0c989440b4d61ba2ce96996864b9c"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re aware that some Snapchatters are having issues using the app right now - hang tight, we’re looking into it!</p>— Snapchat Support (@snapchatsupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/snapchatsupport/status/1448254521914937349?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><div id="1fdc8db49e2e4b7383387a3c40b8c0a5"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The issue has been fixed! If you&#39;re still having trouble, please let us know. Happy Snapping!</p>— Snapchat Support (@snapchatsupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/snapchatsupport/status/1448295237978365954?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Outage reports from users skyrocketed on <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/snapchat/">Down Detector</a> just before 7AM ET before tapering off somewhat at around 9:30AM. A <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/snapchat/map/">heat map</a> indicated that reports were coming in from across the US. A Snap spokesperson told Engadget that not all users were affected.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This is the latest big outage to affect a major social media service over the last week or so. Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp were <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-messenger-down-161653706.html">down for more than six hours</a> on October 4th. Facebook <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-outage-explainer-193155776.html">blamed the outage</a> on a &quot;faulty configuration change&quot; that caused havoc with the DNS servers. Facebook&#39;s apps <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-and-instagram-are-down-for-the-second-time-this-week-193257623.html">went down yet again</a> for a couple of hours last Friday. Twitter, meanwhile, briefly had issues of its own on Tuesday evening, with tweets not loading for some users for a spell.</p><p><strong>Update 10/13 10:45AM ET:</strong> Snapchat is up and running again.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-down-error-outage-snaps-142107269.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">62767bc8-aa5d-4274-837e-970b4c42338d</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:21:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634137132</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T14:58:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-06/1be1c810-982e-11e9-bdd0-b68b2199f048" width="3500" height="2179" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-06/1be1c810-982e-11e9-bdd0-b68b2199f048" width="3500" height="2179" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A 3D printed Snapchat logo is seen through broken glass in this illustration taken November 7, 2017. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BOSNIA-SNAPCHAT/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['NBA 2K22 Arcade Edition' hits Apple Arcade on October 19th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>NBA 2K22 Arcade Edition</em> is one of several games that&#39;s bound for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/apple%20arcade"><ins>Apple Arcade</ins></a> in the coming weeks. The follow-up to <em>NBA 2K21</em>, which is also available on Apple&#39;s game subscription service, includes a new mode called The Association. You can become the general manager or head coach of an NBA franchise and put together your own team by scouting rookies, making trades and scooping up free agents while managing the budget.</p><div id="9f8535b38f644f8393d5972b297fae86"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6aJo9ziVwKA?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The game features current NBA rosters and modes including quick match, online multiplayer and Blacktop, a 3v3 street basketball option. In MyCAREER mode, you can create your own player with a custom look, position, jersey number and play style. You can run drills on a custom court to practice and level up your player in the MyCOURT mode. <em>NBA 2K22 Arcade Edition</em> will debut on the same date as the NBA&#39;s 75th season tips off: October 19th.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Elsewhere, a classic iPhone title is coming to Apple Arcade this Friday. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-12-01-tiny-wings-update-apple-tv-app.html"><em><ins>Tiny Wings</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>first made waves back in 2011 as a one-button game in which you control a bird that slides down hills and launches into the air. It&#39;s one of those simple-in-concept, great-in-execution games that works so well on a mobile device. It&#39;ll be a solid addition to Apple Arcade.</p><p>Looking further ahead, Apple has announced the sequel to tower defense game <em>Kingdom Rush</em> is on the way to the service too. You&#39;ll protect your domain from dragons, human-snaffling plants and other deadly enemies in <em>Kingdom Rush Frontiers TD</em>, which <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-05-28-kingdom-rush-frontiers-coming-to-ios-next-week.html"><ins>first hit iOS back in 2013</ins></a>. It&#39;s coming to Apple Arcade soon.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-nba-2-k-22-arcade-edition-tiny-wings-141053090.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">084b1141-871a-4c32-b86e-41c7f5b0926b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634133664</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T16:49:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8ccde650-2c2c-11ec-bbfb-cd4d34b6f843" width="1729" height="973" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8ccde650-2c2c-11ec-bbfb-cd4d34b6f843" width="1729" height="973" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[2K Games/Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A screenshot of gameplay from NBA 2K22 Arcade Edition.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NBA 2K22 Arcade Edition]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's lightweight 70-200mm zoom has features designed for video creators]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony has <a href="https://www.sony.ca/en/electronics/camera-lenses/sel70200gm2">unveiled</a> the FE 70-200mm F2.8 GM OSS II zoom lens that looks to be an interesting option for hybrid video and photo shooters. Designed for the company&#39;s full-frame <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-a7s-iii-mirrorless-camera-review-140041536.html">Alpha-series</a> mirrorless cameras, it&#39;s the lightest 70-200mm F2.8 lens on the market at 1,045 grams, Sony said. It also offers a number of features aimed at movie creators not usually seen in a lens like this.&nbsp;</p><p>While large zoom lenses tend to focus slowly, Sony said the new model uses four XD linear motors to deliver reliable focus that&#39;s up to three times faster than rival models, and four times faster than the previous model on Sony&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-a1-review-8k-mirrorless-camera-video-143023884.html">Alpha 1 camera</a>. Tracking with continuous autofocus while zooming has improved by 30 percent compared first-gen model, too. It also focuses quietly, so the motor sound is less likely to be picked up by a camera&#39;s microphone.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="d9198c7feeb44655a87fc5859b5bda13"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hsZnBaumeF0?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Video shooters often need to pull focus between subjects, but lenses designed for photography usually exhibit &quot;breathing,&quot; or zooming in and out while changing focus. Sony said it designed the FE 70-200 F2.8 GM OSS II to curtail that, while also reducing focus shift while zooming. Such features are usually only found in cinema lenses that cost considerably more.</p><p>The lens should deliver nice bokeh thanks to the wide, continuous F2.8 aperture, while offering good handling with dual lens elements that move internally. It also offers three separate rings for focus, aperture and zoom, making it easier to rig for cinema use. Other features include high resolution, extra-low dispersion, aspherical glass to suppress chromatic aberrations, Sony&#39;s Nano AR Coating II to reduce flares and ghosting and a new 11-blade aperture that produces softer, more circular bokeh.&nbsp;</p><p>Sony also offers <a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1222777-REG/sony_sel14tc_fe_1_4x_teleconverter.html?sts=pi&amp;pim=Y">FE 1.4x</a> and <a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1222778-REG/sony_sel20tc_fe_2x_teleconverter.html?sts=pi&amp;pim=Y">FE 2.0x</a> teleconverters ($548 for each) that extend the lens&#39;s focal length up to 400mm at F5.6. The FE 70-200mm F2.8 GM OSS II zoom lens will go on sale in December for $2,800, or $3,500 CAD in Canada.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sonys-lightweight-70-200-mm-zoom-has-features-designed-for-video-creators-140542959.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0af587ce-efd6-40be-b5b8-6e59aa843daf</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:05:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634136489</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T14:48:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b73ec7c0-2c30-11ec-bfff-7f9439160618" width="2000" height="1275" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b73ec7c0-2c30-11ec-bfff-7f9439160618" width="2000" height="1275" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony's lightweight 70-200mm zoom has features designed for video creators]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony's lightweight 70-200mm zoom has features designed for video creators]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Acer's new Chromebook Spin 514 features a fanless design and improved webcam]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of its usual autumn laptop refresh, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Acer" href="https://fave.co/2YInpi1">Acer</a> is announcing a host of new Chromebook today that&#39;ll roll out in the coming months. There are four models being refreshed today: the Chromebook Spin 514, Chromebook 515, Chromebook 514, and Chromebook Spin 314. That&#39;s a lot of product names, but Spin devices can flip around with a 360-degree hinge, and the last two digits denote the screen size. That should hopefully ground you as we go through these new models.</p><p>Most interesting is probably the Spin 514 (pictured above), which combines a 14-inch 1080p touchscreen that has minimal bezels with Intel&#39;s 11th-generation Core i3, i5 or i7 processors. This laptop has no fans, which means these probably aren&#39;t the highest-powered versions of Intel&#39;s chips, but they should still provide solid performance for Chrome OS. Acer also put some focus on the webcam, a wise choice given how we&#39;re all still stuck on videos calls for the foreseeable future. It&#39;s a 1080p camera with a blue glass filter and new noise-reduction technology to remove things like light flares. We&#39;ll have to see how this works in practice, but given how many laptops have entirely mediocre webcams, any improvements here will be welcome.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="2ed702dc-e239-43be-a58c-8a43c95d2c4a"/><p>Other specs include up to 16GB of RAM, up to 512GB of storage, Intel Iris X graphics and 10 hours of battery life. The Spin 514 weighs in at 3 pounds, so it&#39;s not going to be the lightest thing to use in tablet mode, but otherwise it sounds like it&#39;ll be a very good Chromebook — it also simply looks nice and well-built, at least as far as I can tell from these images. And Acer has a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review-183025946.html">solid track record</a> of making very good Chromebooks, so hopefully that&#39;ll continue here. The Spin 514 is expected to arrive in the US in January and starts at $700.</p><p>Acer&#39;s Chromebook 515 (which comes in consumer and enterprise editions) has similar specs to the Spin 514, though it has a larger 15.6-inch display. Given the large size, this laptop isn&#39;t a convertible, which is probably a smart move. For a 15-inch laptop, though, it&#39;s pretty light — only 3.75 pounds. It comes with the same 11th-generation processor options as the Spin 514, though it also has a budget Pentium Gold option (paired with Intel&#39;s UHD graphics rather than the Iris X). The Chromebook 515 will initially be available in Europe this month for €499; the Enterprise version will come to the US in January 2022 starting at $640.</p><p>Acer has a few less expensive Chromebooks coming out, as well. The Chromebook Spin 314 starts at $500 and arrives in the US in November. For that price, you&#39;ll get a 14-inch screen with an unfortunate 1,366 x 768 resolution, which is pretty unacceptable in the year 2021. It also features budget processors in the form of Intel&#39;s Pentium Gold or two Celeron options and has a 360-degree hinge, as the name implies. More intriguing is the Chromebook 514, which pairs a 14-inch, 1080p display with MediaTek&#39;s 8-core Kompanio 828 processor and 8GB of RAM. We haven&#39;t tested a MediaTek Chromebook in a while, so we can&#39;t say for sure how it&#39;ll perform yet. But Acer is promising 15 hours of battery life, and the laptop weighs less than 3 pounds, so it does have some potential as a budget Chromebook (the 514 will cost $400 when it is released in December).&nbsp;</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/acer-chromebook-spin-514-fall-2021-updates-134548903.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d54e340a-68fb-48c3-b5fd-075c26a8617c</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:45:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634134207</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T14:10:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/eb40bab0-2c26-11ec-aff8-1394753ed502" width="3000" height="2377" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/eb40bab0-2c26-11ec-aff8-1394753ed502" width="3000" height="2377" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Acer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Spin 514 (2021)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Spin 514 (2021)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Acer's glasses-free 3D SpatialLabs laptop arrives this winter]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-conceptd-7-7-pro-laptop-update-300-mid-tower-134558886.html">usual</a> raft of hardware updates, Acer is adding new ConceptD machines with new displays and different chassis options. But the most notable product on the docket for late-2021 is the new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:ConceptD 7 SpatialLabs Edition" href="https://fave.co/2YInpi1">ConceptD 7 SpatialLabs Edition</a>, which packs a stereoscopic display. It’s the first time that such a product is available for everyone to buy after <a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-spatiallabs-stereoscopic-view-134520222.html">the company first teased the project earlier this year</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/acer-spatiallabs-stereoscopic-view-134520222.html">Back then</a>, Acer and SpatialLabs teamed up to put one of the latter’s stereoscopic displays on the former’s machines. The idea is to enable 3D artists to preview their work in a form closer to the finished article long before it had reached the lengthy rendering pipeline. But while that initial concept was only available to developers who applied (and promised to share their work with Acer), this is a retail product.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The ConceptD 7 SpatialLabs Edition is packing an 11th-generation Core i7, with the option of a GeForce RTX 3080, up to 64GB RAM and up to a 2TB SSD. And users are going to be staring into a Pantone-validated 4K display with a Delta E&lt;2 color accuracy for those who need it. Of course, this is only a sideshow to the eye-tracking cameras sited on the top bezel to match the 3D images to your gaze.</p><p>Acer added that, on the software side, it has updated the AI underpinning the system that enables users to view 3D content from any 2D image (or video) shown on screen. The company has also launched a new developer site to allow users to download all of the various plugins and tools (including a hand-tracking app and add-ons for Unreal Engine) to make everything work.</p><p>Of course, it’s not simply designers who may find the D 7 (don’t make me type it all out again) a useful proposition. The company says that it already has examples of companies using this as a car configurator for showroom use, architects using this to show off home designs and researchers examining high-resolution images from satellites.</p><p>If you want one of these, bear in mind that you’ll need to wait until December (if you’re in EMEA) or 2022 (if you’re in the US). Plus, you know, it’s going to cost: The starting price on that side of the pond will be €3,599 (roughly $4,158).</p><p>At the same time, the company is launching a new 16-inch ConceptD 3 model with a 16:10-ratio display and a 15.6-inch convertible edition. These, too, will be reaching the US at some point early next year, with base prices running from $1,700 through to $2,000, depending on your size preferences.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/acer-fall-2021-conceptd-7-spatiallabs-edition-134507031.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">082eb81b-ab5c-436f-bf0d-7548dabaae6d</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:45:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634134171</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T14:09:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/fbead7e0-2b51-11ec-ab7f-be692b31021c" width="1800" height="1013" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/fbead7e0-2b51-11ec-ab7f-be692b31021c" width="1800" height="1013" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Acer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Image of the ConceptD 7 SpatialLabs edition]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Acer ConceptD 7 SpatialLabs edition]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple is reportedly exploring ways to use AirPods as health devices]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple&#39;s health ambitions for AirPods might extend beyond using them to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-conversation-boost-feature-175701382.html">boost conversations</a>. <em>Wall Street Journal</em><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-studying-potential-of-airpods-as-health-device-11634122800?mod=djemalertNEWS">sources</a> claim Apple is exploring multiple ways it can use AirPods as health devices. It might use the buds as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/eargos-latest-smart-hearing-aids-bring-a-much-needed-hearing-test-160001810.html">hearing aids</a>, but it could also use the motion sensors to correct your posture. A prototype would even include a thermometer to check your core body temperature, according to leaked documents.</p><p>The features wouldn&#39;t show up in 2022 and might not be available at all, the sources said. Apple declined to comment.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Apple would face numerous hurdles to marketing AirPods as health gadgets. The company would likely require regulatory clearance for at least some features. A US Food and Drug Administration ruleset due in 2022 might make that possible, but it could still take months to approve the earbuds. Even Bose had to wait a long time before it could sell its FDA-cleared <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bose-soundcontrol-hearing-aids-152746656.html">SoundControl hearing aids</a>.</p><p>There are technical challenges, too. Right now, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-06-apple-airpods-pro-review.html">AirPods Pro</a> won&#39;t last longer than 4.5 hours for listening (with noise cancelling on), and 3.5 hours for calls — that just wouldn&#39;t be practical for health wearables that might need to sit in your ears all day. They&#39;d also need to be comfortable for long periods and adapt to varying types of hearing loss.</p><p>It&#39;s easy to see why Apple might expand the AirPods&#39; usefulness, though. As with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-review-all-about-the-screen-130036181.html">the Apple Watch</a>, health could be a selling point that grow the audience beyond the enthusiast core. It might also court a relatively underserved market of people who may have mild or moderate hearing loss, but either can&#39;t afford most hearing aids or don&#39;t like the limited functionality and drab designs that often define the category.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-health-device-leak-132037664.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">066803f7-d9d7-4501-b5dd-e0b0ebdef386</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:20:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634131150</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T13:19:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Health Care Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/989a1f60-12da-11eb-a5ff-730eaab52657" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/989a1f60-12da-11eb-a5ff-730eaab52657" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget                                    ]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple AirPods Pro in ears]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple AirPods Pro in ears]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple Watch Series 7 review: It’s all about the screen]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="aeb9b088196a4fa4b92deb78f14e315f"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3F54aFTMhLU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>The main difference between Apple’s Watch Series 7 and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-6-review-153047133.html">the Series 6</a> is just a larger display, but it makes an outsized impact on a device as small as a watch. Apple also generally enlarged the UI, making things easier to read and navigate. To make better use of the bigger canvas, the company also added some new watch faces and a full QWERTY keyboard for replying to messages.</p><p>The other changes to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:the Series 7" href="https://amzn.to/3iXCNxT">the Series 7</a> are less obvious, like a new SiP (system-in-package), faster charging and overnight respiratory tracking. For those coming from the last generation, this might not feel like a significant upgrade. But the larger display does make a meaningful impact for anyone that’s upgrading from a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-se-review-watchos-7-price-specs-comparison-172542713.html">Watch SE</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-24-apple-watch-series-5-review.html">Series 5</a> or older.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>Design and hardware</h2><p>Even though its screen is bigger, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-release-date-price-172920553.html">the Series 7</a> still manages to retain basically the same footprint as its predecessor. It’s a hair heavier than the Watch SE and Series 6, which makes sense since its case is slightly larger. Unlike previous generations, which came in 40 and 44mm sizes, this year you can choose between 41mm and 45mm. The difference is barely noticeable at first.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9761caa0-2b96-11ec-bffd-fddd7431d5dc" alt="An off-angle view of the Apple Watch Series 7 on a person&#39;s wrist, showing the screen&#39;s refracted edge and the watch&#39;s dial and button." data-uuid="bbaa17ff-6cb2-39cc-a85d-29dc0859f8b3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>Once I turned the screen on, though, I was struck by its roominess. This was when this main design change became obvious. Apple used a refractive edge here to make it seem like the display curves slightly along the sides and it helps the face feel even more expansive. The bezels have been whittled down to just 1.7mm (0.07 inch) compared to last gen’s 3mm.</p><p>Oh, and a quick shout here to its durability: It’s the first Apple Watch to be certified IP6X for dust resistance. Since I’m in reviewer mode, I&#39;ve been very careful to avoid situations where I might damage the device. But I’ll admit I’ve already dropped the Series 7 once and it survived without a scratch, thanks to Apple’s crystal covering that the company says is more crack resistant than on the Series 6.</p><p>Now, you’re probably not comparing an Apple Watch to Android or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-samsung-new-wear-os-rip-tizen-183031381.html">Wear OS</a>, but in case you were curious, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-body-fat-scan-wear-os-120026149.html">Samsung’s Galaxy Watch 4</a> is noticeably lighter than the Series 7. It also has a round face and thinner body. But really, if you’re an iPhone user, you’ve probably never even thought about a Galaxy watch.</p><h2>A big screen difference</h2><p>Depending on which Apple Watch you’d been using before, the jump in screen size may be less obvious. It’s increased more than 50 percent from the SE and 20 percent from the Series 6. Either way, the more spacious UI is helpful. Buttons for entering my passcode stretched out over the edges, and I didn&#39;t need to aim as carefully to strike the right keys. It&#39;s easier to hit the right settings in the control center, too, and I can see more of my friends’ messages at once. My heart rate and time passed during workouts are more readable as well. Those with visual impairments will also appreciate that there are new larger font size settings available.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ed648510-2c26-11ec-9fdf-6858672c9558" style="height:1112;width:1639;" alt="Apple Watch Series 7" data-uuid="3230d43e-c6c7-3d6c-a561-ba7d52b65502"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Though most buttons are between 12 and 27 percent larger, app icons are still squished together. That’s a problem for those of us who use the grid view for all apps, but not so much if you’re in list view.</p><p>The extra space also means Apple was able to introduce a full QWERTY keyboard for replying to messages by typing or swiping on the screen. Compared to handwriting, dictating or emojis, a keyboard offers a bit more flexibility, especially when the system correctly picks up your swipes. But because it’s so cramped, the accuracy rate is <em>maybe</em> 60 percent, and I still preferred using dictation. Plus, the new screen may be big, but it’s definitely not big enough to make tap typing possible. Still, it’s a good option to have.</p><p>In addition to enlarging most of the elements across the UI, Apple also added new faces that can display more information at once, like the Modular Duo. There’s also a Contour style that pushes the clock’s digits all the way to the edge where they warp and “melt” over the sides like in Salvador Dali’s <em>The Persistence of Memory</em>. The remaining two are a Portrait face that we already saw in the watchOS 8 beta, and World Time, which is helpful for interacting with people in other countries. I used Modular Duo the most, though it’s not very attractive, and when I wanted something prettier I just switched to one with my face as the wallpaper instead. (Just kidding: I use the “Artist” design or a cute animal background.)</p><section data-eng-breakout="2b903d05d74b4e6b8d04e467648d0717" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ed648510-2c26-11ec-af5f-1b44504099ed" alt="Apple Watch Series 7" data-uuid="9a8809c7-0765-3935-a87b-005d625b5f40"></section><p>The new Modular Duo screen is the most useful. It lets you place two expanded complications on top of each other, while still showing the time and an additional small complication at the top. You can choose to show the world clock with a timer or your favorite stock’s performance with Apple Music, for example. I went with a Spotify controller and the Weather forecast. Though the latter worked well, showing me hourly temperature and sunlight data on the screen, the Spotify complication was, in a word, trash. It just shows the words “Tap to play music,” and I’d have to waste a tap and a second to pull up playback controls.</p><p>A second doesn’t sound like much, but when I’m out running or juggling my groceries, I don’t want to waste that time holding up my arm and watching my screen for more than a fraction of a second. I’m not going to harp on this because this is more of a Spotify problem than an Apple Watch issue, but given how many people use the music app, it would do both companies good to make this complication work better. I’d love to see more useful complications from other apps too.</p><p>One last note on the Series 7’s screen: Though its actual peak brightness hasn’t changed, Apple has tweaked the system so that the Always On display is up to 70 percent brighter when you’re indoors. This way, it’s easier to read if you have your hand hidden below a table while you’re at a meeting.</p><h2>Battery life, charging and performance</h2><p>That pretty much sums up all the screen-related updates on the Series 7. But there are a few other noteworthy upgrades. The most significant of these is that it charges faster, and in about 10 minutes, I got close to 10 percent capacity. It reached almost 100 percent in under an hour with the new cable that Apple includes in the box. Meanwhile, the Apple Watch SE only got to about 60 percent in an hour.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f7478130-2b96-11ec-a1fb-7ab26f0589b0" alt="The new QWERTY keyboard on the Apple Watch Series 7." data-uuid="e57f1f38-3af0-34ef-a52d-80d4e446db6b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>You’ll need both the new charger and the Series 7 to get these faster charging speeds, by the way. It’s the coils on both the watch and the wireless disc that enable the higher rate, so this isn’t something you can get just by running out and buying a new accessory. As someone who’s constantly forgetting to charge my watch until I&#39;m about to run out the door, I appreciate the faster speeds. That said, I still wish smartwatches in general lasted longer and took less time to charge.</p><p>Speaking of the battery, the Series 7 promises the same runtime as its predecessor, which is to say, about 18 hours. I generally found myself getting about half a day more from the new watch than the SE, despite the lack of an Always On display on the SE. The Series 7 usually stuck around for a day and a half, almost two, with the screen set to Always On, and tracking between three and five workouts. I also used the device to send plenty of messages and map my walks while I ran errands with the GPS on. That endurance is impressive given the larger screen, but it’s worth noting that I haven’t used the watch for sleep tracking yet.</p><p>The battery efficiency can be partly attributed to Apple’s new S7 system-in-package (SIP), which is based on the same processor as the S6. In general, I didn’t feel much of a difference between the Series 7 and the SE when launching workouts or getting Siri to text my friends. The Apple Watch has been and continues to be a responsive device that feels as fast as, if not faster than, its Android counterparts.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/18adc460-2b97-11ec-88fb-058d5a0b0624" alt="The battery page on the Apple Watch Series 7." data-uuid="adae6ef5-c9d1-303b-a7c9-285d3100dd7d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p></p><h2>Sleep tracking, watchOS 8 and other updates</h2><p>One area where Apple continues to lag the competition is sleep tracking. While companies like Fitbit and Samsung can use their wearables’ heart rate monitors to detect what sleep zone you’re in, Apple still doesn’t offer that. And you’ll need to make sure you have the Sleep Focus mode on (either manually or by setting a schedule) before the Watch will log your slumber. The others are all able to automatically tell when you’ve gone to sleep and don’t need you to set a schedule. In fact, Fitbit has been doing it since 2015.</p><p>The Series 7 does usher in a new feature that logs your respiration rate while you sleep, and then tells you your breath-per-minute rate the next morning. Cool. Respiratory tracking is something that’s coming via watchOS 8 and isn’t exclusive to the Series 7, and the same is true of features like the new Mindfulness app, guided meditation sessions, redesigned Photos app, SharePlaying Fitness+ workouts and more. This means they’re less likely to sway your decision on whether to get the Series 7 if you already have an Apple Watch. The main things exclusive to the Series 7 are the Modular Duo and Contour watch faces, larger font sizes and buttons, and the QWERTY keyboard.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/5b370030-2b97-11ec-b7f3-7e614289c1b4" alt="The all apps page in grid view on the Apple Watch Series 7." data-uuid="8da67b38-07aa-3973-a561-f883c426c7b6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p></p><h2>Wrap-up</h2><p>Though the differences between the Series 6 and 7 seem minor, it&#39;s worth a reminder that most people who own last year’s model likely aren’t looking to upgrade yet anyway. For anyone else who’s looking for a new smartwatch, the Series 7 will be a satisfying purchase, especially if you’ve never used one before. WatchOS is a capable and comprehensive system that can help you track your workouts, automatically log your sessions, prompt you to be more active and mindful of your mental health all while being a great extension of your smartphone. It’s not the best at sleep-tracking, though, so if that’s a priority you might prefer a Fitbit. Despite its relatively high starting price <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:of $400" href="https://amzn.to/3iXCNxT">of $400</a>, what Apple offers is currently the best in the market, especially for the iOS ecosystem.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-review-all-about-the-screen-130036181.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">61cd880b-921f-4f77-b6e6-955ff0f333d9</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634130711</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T13:11:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/76dc4a80-2b96-11ec-a6a6-1afca201cc47" width="1900" height="1267" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ed61c5f0-2c26-11ec-bfff-fc22ded728bb" width="1861" height="1090" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple Watch Series 7]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Watch Series 7]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[AMD's Radeon RX 6600 is a $329 GPU for 1080p gaming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of July, AMD announced the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-unveils-the-radeon-rx-6600-xt-gpu-designed-for-1080-p-gaming-033049778.html">Radeon RX 6600XT</a>, a video card the company billed as its 1080p flagship. For its final GPU release of 2021, it has unveiled the Radeon RX 6600. It&#39;s a video card that offers 28 compute units, a 2,044MHz game clock and up to 8GB of GDDR6 memory. On paper, that makes it only slightly less powerful than the RX 6600XT, which comes with 32 compute units, a 2,359MHz game clock and 8GB of GDDR6 RAM.</p><p>On average, AMD claims the RX 6600 is 23 percent faster than NVIDIA’s last generation RTX 2060 and about on par with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-release-date-185849067.html">RTX 3060</a> while delivering better per watt performance. In <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, the company says players can expect an average of 70 frames per second at max settings in 1080p. In less visually demanding titles like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/resident-evil-village-release-date-may-7-2021-224214298.html"><em>Resident Evil Village</em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hitman-3-epic-games-store-exclusive-150053170.html"><em>Hitman 3</em></a><em>,</em> you can expect on average more than 100 frames per second, according to AMD.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Notably, AMD didn’t say how the RX 6600 performs in esports titles like <em>Valorant </em>and <em>Overwatch</em>. Presumably, it should be able to put up the kind of frame rates you need to drive a single Full HD monitor at 240Hz or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-nvidia-360hz-esports-display-gsync-asus-rog-swift-360.html">360Hz</a>. The more interesting tidbit about the RX 6600 is that it can play some games at 1440p. In <a href="https://www.engadget.com/far-cry-6-release-date-gameplay-trailer-182030303.html"><em>Far Cry 6</em></a>, for example, AMD says it’s possible to get a very playable 62 frames per second at the higher resolution.</p><p>The RX 6600 will also ship with ray-tracing support out of the box. Here the company claims you can get more than 60 frames per second while playing <em>Far Cry 6</em> at both 1080p and 1440p, provided you also take advantage of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/unity-nvidia-dlss-support-game-engine-164535941.html">DLSS-like</a> FidelityFX Super Resolution upscaling technology. Ray-tracing performance has consistently been a weak point among AMD’s RDNA 2 GPUs, so we’ll have to see if the RX 6600 lives up to the claims.</p><p>One other point AMD was eager to get across is that RX 6600 only needs 132 watts of board power. So you’ll only need a power supply unit with about 450 watts of total power to run the GPU, making it an upgrade that should be easy to add to most computers.</p><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Radeon RX 6600" href="https://amzn.to/3awKI0n">Radeon RX 6600</a> is available today from AMD board partners like ASUS, Gigabyte and XFX, with pricing for the GPU starting at $329. AMD CEO Lisa Su recently said she expects the current global chip shortage to continue through into the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/27/amd-ceo-lisa-su-says-chip-shortage-likely-to-end-next-year.html">second half of 2022</a>, so we anticipate supply of the RX 6600 will be hard to come by.</p><p>In the meantime, if you’re still using a Radeon 5000 series GPU, the good news is that AMD is expanding support for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-smart-access-memory-zen-2-cpus-161011253.html">Smart Access Memory</a> feature to cards in that family. You’ll need a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-zen-3-ryzen-5000-cpu-162431364.html">Ryzen 5000</a> or 3000 series CPU and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-3rd-gen-ryzen-3-3100-and-b550-184902399.html">B550</a> or X570 motherboard to take advantage, but if you have the necessary components, you can expect up to a 16 percent performance uplift in some games.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amd-radeon-rx-6600-annoucement-130016539.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">56595b38-d89e-4955-9455-84103b374e52</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634131314</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T13:22:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d732cd00-2bd2-11ec-bfbf-af5eedb7f36b" width="2000" height="1176" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d732cd00-2bd2-11ec-bfbf-af5eedb7f36b" width="2000" height="1176" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ASUS]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ASUS AMD Radeon RX6600]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[ASUS AMD Radeon RX6600]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 512GB Mac Mini M1 is down to $750 on Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While it&#39;s very likely we&#39;ll hear about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-unleashed-macbook-pro-event-date-161136786.html">new Apple computers</a> next week, Amazon&#39;s having a sale now on the Mac Mini M1. The base <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:256GB model" href="https://amzn.to/3aB4MyN">256GB model</a> is down to $600 thanks to an automatically applied coupon, but the upgraded model has an even rarer discount. Normally, we&#39;ve seen it drop to $800 in the past — but now another automatically applied coupon has knocked the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:512GB Mac Mini M1" href="https://amzn.to/3AwIhWc">512GB Mac Mini M1</a> down to $750.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3aB4MyN" id="d7a79592901448729afe26bceb822b97" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Mac Mini M1 (256GB) at Amazon - $600</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3AwIhWc" id="07c9d5cd6b194912b11c9e9c7ce85871" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Mac Mini M1 (512GB) at Amazon - $750</a><p>As with other M1 machines, this Mac Mini doesn&#39;t look different from its Intel counterpart but Apple upgraded the internals significantly with its M1 chipset. We haven&#39;t tested the machine ourselves, but we have tried out the M1 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-140031323.html">MacBook Air</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/macbook-pro-m1-review-163011742.html">MacBook Pro</a>, and both laptops impressed us with their powerful performance and speed. The Mac Mini M1 has an eight-core CPU and an eight-core GPU, plus a 16-core Neural Engine that handles machine learning tasks. Both the 256GB and 512GB models have 8GB of RAM and that should be enough for most people, but remember that you&#39;re basically stuck with that because you can&#39;t upgrade it yourself.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Those who prefer a desktop setup will gravitate to the Mac Mini for its sleek, compact profile. There&#39;s not much to the small box aside from an array of ports, which includes two Thunderbolt ports, two USB-A connectors, an HDMI port, an Ethernet port and a 3.5mm headphone jack.</p><p>But we&#39;d be remiss if we didn&#39;t mention Apple&#39;s event coming up next week where we could see new Mac laptops, desktops and even a new pair of AirPods. Nothing is confirmed yet, but rumors have been swirling for a while about a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-mac-mini-m-1-x-rumor-194549101.html">redesigned Mac Mini</a>. But if you need a new desktop sooner rather than later, or you want to get one while you can save a bit of money, Amazon&#39;s latest sale on the Mac Mini M1 isn&#39;t one to overlook.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-mac-mini-m1-512gb-sale-750-with-coupon-on-amazon-123155378.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">272ca639-4b58-4c8f-91fe-7d0d9aa86a15</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 12:31:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634129044</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T12:44:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/dcba6960-f38b-11eb-bc7f-bf7d76504fdd" width="2880" height="1620" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/dcba6960-f38b-11eb-bc7f-bf7d76504fdd" width="2880" height="1620" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple Mac Mini]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Mac Mini]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Someone made a USB-C iPhone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Years ago, I wrote this piece about how <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-10-iphone-11-pro-usb-c-fastcharge.html">I really wanted the iPhone to adopt USB-C</a> and retire its Lightning connector. This was just after the advent of the company’s first iPhone Pro models with pro level features, like surgical-grade stainless steel and, er, three cameras. Fast-forward to now, just after the launch of the iPhone 13 series, and I still don’t have my USB-C iPhone. Fortunately, there are engineers that like a challenge.&nbsp;</p><p>On his YouTube channel, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology student Ken Pillonel teased an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-usb-c-i-phone-becomes-a-reality-thanks-to-a-robotics-engineer-113556672.html">iPhone X with a USB-C port</a>, promising a full video later on how it was done. In an earlier video, he also explained how he reverse-engineered the Lightning connector, pulling out an integrated circuit from a third-party cable and hooking it all up to a USB-C connector. Yes, this is not something most of us should attempt.&nbsp;</p><p>It’s certainly possible for Apple to do the same, given the iPad Pro and new mini have USB-C ports. Europe recently proposed USB-C charging as standard for all phones and electronic devices — which may speed up Apple’s adoption.&nbsp;</p><p></p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-countersues-epic-for-sidestepping-fees-on-in-game-purchases-084602622.html">Google countersues Epic Games for sidestepping fees on in-app purchases</a></h2><h3>It said the company ‘willfully breached’ its Play Store developer agreement.</h3><p></p><p>Google has countersued Epic Games over in-app purchases on Fortnite, saying it &quot;willfully breached&quot; its Play Store developer agreement. Epic originally sued Google in August, shortly after it filed a complaint against, and was countersued by, Apple. &quot;Epic has alternatively been unjustly enriched at Google&#39;s expense,&quot; the company said in its complaint.&nbsp;</p><p>In case you forgot, Epic sued Google when it removed Fortnite from its Play Store after a Mega Drop update gave players a way to bypass Play and get discounted items.</p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-countersues-epic-for-sidestepping-fees-on-in-game-purchases-084602622.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><div class="inline-emphasis"><p><strong>Sponsored by CISCO</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/smb-security-outcomes-study.html?ccid=cc001540&amp;oid=rptsc025200&amp;dtid=pdidgd000002">Your work-from-anywhere solution</a></p><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/smb-security-outcomes-study.html?ccid=cc001540&amp;oid=rptsc025200&amp;dtid=pdidgd000002"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6d880620-22ec-11ec-bffe-a23f265a294d" style="height:370;width:640;" alt="CISCO Image 3" data-uuid="04680a05-57a2-3816-8844-d1f15d73ffcf"><figcaption></figcaption></figure></a><p></p></div><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-unleashed-macbook-pro-event-date-161136786.html">Apple is holding its next event on October 18th</a></h2><h3>Didn’t we just have an Apple event?</h3><a href=" https://www.engadget.com/apple-unleashed-macbook-pro-event-date-161136786.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e1492230-2c13-11ec-bedf-c8884351faf9" style="height:422;width:675;" alt="Apple Unleashed event invite" data-uuid="a699aaab-b6c0-39e6-a91f-90a66bd7d8bf"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure></a><p>Apple will hold a second fall product event on October 18th at 1 PM ET. The invitation for the virtual Unleashed presentation doesn&#39;t provide many clues, but we’re expecting to see 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros, powered by souped-up M1X processors.</p><p>Apple might also introduce third-generation &#39;basic&#39; AirPods — headphones we thought we’d see at the iPhone just months ago.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-unleashed-macbook-pro-event-date-161136786.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2>Motorola Edge (2021) review</h2><h3>Improvements where they were needed most.</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1ea57250-2c14-11ec-97fb-3d20b2087329" style="height:451;width:675;" alt="Motorola Edge stood in puddle." data-uuid="98d8c548-6de8-3766-8929-853a07c2bf3b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Motorola’s Edge, updated for 2021, still makes compromises but in adding a fast 144Hz display, a more consistent fingerprint sensor and better software support, it addresses many of the shortcomings of its predecessor. If you can forgive the middling camera and its missing wireless charging, there’s a lot to like about this phone. For now, the unlocked 256GB model is $600, but it will eventually cost $700. Another strong midrange phone is here.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/motorola-edge-2021-review-130059627.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tile-pro-ultra-wideband-tracker-new-devices-100025451.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Tile teases its first ultra-wideband tracker to go up against Apple’s AirTags</a></h2><h3>The company has also upgraded its existing lineup.</h3><h3></h3><p>Tile is making a tracker that uses both ultra-wideband (UWB) and Bluetooth and will work across both Android and iOS. UWB devices can transmit directional and spatial data to narrow down their location more accurately than over Bluetooth alone.</p><p>The Tile Ultra tracker&#39;s Point and Locate feature lets you use augmented reality to find the item with turn-by-turn directions and a visual indicator of where the tracker is. Tile&#39;s working with Google to refine the feature for Android 12 and UWB-capable phones. It’s set to arrive in early 2022.</p><p>Until then, the company has announced the new Tile Pro, as well as revamped versions of Sticker, Slim and Mate trackers. The Pro is the company&#39;s most powerful tag to date, with a finding range of 400 feet.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tile-pro-ultra-wideband-tracker-new-devices-100025451.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-orbi-wifi-6e-quad-band-mesh-router-142948379.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Netgear&#39;s new quad-band WiFi 6E mesh router costs $1,500</a></h2><h3>For that premium router feel.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-orbi-wifi-6e-quad-band-mesh-router-142948379.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/545f42e0-2c14-11ec-ba6d-e92a50ff9a76" style="height:450;width:675;" alt="Netgear routers" data-uuid="f8f7b6be-f6ef-395c-ab77-ead9104367bc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Netgear</div></figure></a><p>How much would you pay for the fastest home wireless networks possible? At least it’s a three-pack.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netgear-orbi-wifi-6e-quad-band-mesh-router-142948379.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-v-e-bike-hyperbike-fastest-150015459.html https://www.engadget.com/...">VanMoof&#39;s fastest e-bike yet tops out at 31MPH</a></h2><h3>The company plans to start shipping its first hyperbike in late 2022.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-v-e-bike-hyperbike-fastest-150015459.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/82a2acf0-2c14-11ec-97df-a593979196bf" style="height:380;width:675;" alt="VanMoof V hyperbike" data-uuid="7bbade55-fcae-3ca4-90fe-13a4a2d52654"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">VanMoof</div></figure></a><p>E-bike maker VanMoof wants to get riders from A to B more swiftly with its first high-speed model. The VanMoof V is the company’s first hyperbike, which will be able to hit a top speed of 31MPH (50KMH).</p><p>VanMoof is pitching this as a car replacement for city life and longer commutes, but as speed limits for e-bikes vary across cities and counties, the e-bike will have matching integrated speed settings. As it develops the VanMoof V, the company plans to work with lawmakers and governments on e-bike rules, including geofencing and speed regulations.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-v-e-bike-hyperbike-fastest-150015459.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><h3></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-hybrid-scan-watch-is-set-to-arrive-in-the-us-next-month-135842112.html"><ins>Withings&#39; ScanWatch is finally coming to the US after FDA clearance</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-lg-chevy-bolt-ev-euv-recall-agreement-131047763.html"><ins>LG will cover nearly the entire cost of GM&#39;s Chevy Bolt EV recall</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/1-passwords-new-feature-will-let-you-securely-share-logins-with-anyone-130044719.html"><ins>1Password&#39;s new feature lets you safely share passwords using just a link</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-material-design-uikit-171651054.html"><ins>Google will stop trying to make its iOS apps look like Android apps</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-dreamdrive-semi-autonomous-features-160026944.html"><ins>Lucid details the Air&#39;s semi-autonomous driving features</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/g4-g4tv-comcast-philo-twitch-xfinity-cox-verizon-fios-141608050.html"><ins>G4 will return to TV on November 16th</ins></a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-someone-made-a-usb-c-i-phone-111525796.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5c37566f-27b4-4d36-9781-b6c947dfb880</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 11:15:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634123135</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T11:05:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/52ab9c50-2b4c-11ec-9b95-b31298297f21" width="1822" height="1147" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/52ab9c50-2b4c-11ec-9b95-b31298297f21" width="1822" height="1147" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ken Pillonel]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The iPhone finally got a USB-C port thanks to a robotics engineer]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The iPhone finally got a USB-C port thanks to a robotics engineer]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['EVE Online' finally runs natively on the Mac]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After years of waiting and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/eve-online-native-mac-app-150543699.html">nearly a year of teasing</a>, <em>EVE Online</em> can play &#39;properly&#39; on a Mac. CCP Games has <a href="https://www.eveonline.com/download">released</a> its first truly native <em>EVE</em> client for both Intel- and Apple Silicon-based Macs — no more using a compatibility layer to play the spaceship-focused MMO. That should improve performance and reduce memory demands, as you might expect, but it also enables Mac-native keyboard and mouse commands you&#39;ve had to forego until now.</p><p>The game remains free-to-play, although CCP clearly hopes you&#39;ll be sufficiently engrossed to spend real money. Mac users will share the same game universe as their Windows counterparts.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This isn&#39;t about to up-end the market for gaming computers. There are only so many people who both prefer Macs and are determined to play <em>EVE Online</em>. This could significantly expand the number of Macs that can play <em>EVE</em> in the first place, though, and might make the game an easy pick if you&#39;re looking for Mac-friendly online titles beyond obvious choices like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/world-of-warcraft-burning-crusade-classic-release-date-141750216.html"><em>World of Warcraft</em></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/eve-online-native-mac-app-110047741.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">aa2f8edf-142d-4d79-b6f1-b07b9fbde1c6</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634073479</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T21:18:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ecf5bcf0-2b92-11ec-aefc-db5ee63d0e60" width="1920" height="1081" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ecf5bcf0-2b92-11ec-aefc-db5ee63d0e60" width="1920" height="1081" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[CCP Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['EVE Online' art for Mac native release]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['EVE Online' art for Mac native release]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Riot Games disables /all chat in ‘League of Legends’]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Online games are rife with toxic behavior that can ruin the experience for players who just want to have fun. In an effort to curb verbal abuse in <em>League of Legends</em>, Riot Games has decided to disable /all chats for publicly matchmade games — temporarily, at least. The feature gives players a way to communicate with the opposing team and can be a source of fun banter. Game director Andrei Van Roon and lead game producer Jeremy Lee wrote in their <a href="https://www.leagueoflegends.com/en-us/news/game-updates/disabling-all-chat/">announcement</a>, though, that at the moment, negative interactions outweigh the positives due to the rise of in-game verbal abuse this year.</p><p>Teams will still see the other&#39;s emotes and CTRL+1-2-3-4 spam, and the change doesn&#39;t affect the chat function between allies at all. Riot knows there&#39;s still verbal abuse going on within team chats, and that the move won&#39;t eliminate the behavior from the game completely. The developer deems team chats too important to disable, however, since that&#39;s what people use to strategize and coordinate their actions.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>According to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22722747/league-of-legends-all-chat-removed-patch-riot-games"><em>Polygon</em></a>, the reaction to the change has mostly been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/leagueoflegends/comments/q6oi8k/riot_is_disabling_all_chat_in_all_matchmaking/">negative</a>, with people mentioning the fun experiences they&#39;ve had bonding with players from opposing teams. Some even claim that most toxic behavior happens within team chats instead. van Roon has since clarified on Twitter that the plan is to test the change for a couple of patches, starting with patch 11.21, and then ask players for feedback. Riot could choose to keep or reverse the change based on the feedback it gets, though it could also keep it in some regions where the response to it is largely positive</p><div id="42e00b0745464fc590f599ad1d946567"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A few more all chat test details:<br>- Plan is to test for a couple of patches, then survey player opinion<br>- Potential responses then include keeping the change, reverting it entirely, keeping it in regions positive on it and reverting elsewhere, changing which queues it applies to</p>— Andrei van Roon (@RiotMeddler) <a href="https://twitter.com/RiotMeddler/status/1447963125060276225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/riot-games-disables-cross-team-chat-league-of-legends-103543917.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">57f223fc-7939-4f64-85ce-b883d9cc1dfd</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:35:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634120391</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T10:20:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/bf2706e0-2c04-11ec-992f-5f3f1d0ade89" width="1600" height="935" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/bf2706e0-2c04-11ec-992f-5f3f1d0ade89" width="1600" height="935" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Riot Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[League of Legends]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[League of Legends]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Security flaws at NFT marketplace OpenSea left users' crypto wallets open to attack]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After finding itself embroiled in a controversy over <a href="https://www.engadget.com/opensea-nate-chastain-nft-buying-incident-163044364.html">insider trading</a>, NFT marketplace OpenSea is getting some more bad press. The site had a critical security vulnerability that could have allowed hackers to steal users&#39; entire crypto wallets, according to security research firm Check Point Software.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Check Point said it first noticed reports of stolen crypto wallets triggered by airdropped NFTs, prompting the firm to investigate OpenSea. That revealed critical security discoveries &quot;that, if exploited, could have led hackers to hijack user accounts and steal entire crypto wallets of users, by sending malicious NFTs,&quot; the company said.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The attack relied on user inattention and the fact that OpenSea already generates a lot of pop-ups. If the victim received and viewed a malicious NFT sent by a hacker, it triggered a pop-up from OpenSea&#39;s storage domain, requesting a connection to the victim&#39;s cryptocurrency wallet. Clicking on the popup gave the hacker access to the wallet and allowed them to generate another popup. If the user also clicked on that without noticing a note describing the transaction, the attacker could theoretically steal all their money.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>It seemed that a lot of things needed to go wrong for the attack to work, and it&#39;s not clear if it was actively exploited. Check Point said it disclosed the vulnerability as soon as it found it, and OpenSea said it implemented a fix &quot;within an hour of it being brought to our attention.&quot; The company said it&#39;s &quot;doubling down on community education around security,&quot; by adding a blog series and taking other measures.&nbsp;</p><p>The security research firm said that given the rapid pace of innovation, &quot;there is an inherent challenge in securely integrating software applications and crypto markets.&quot; Bad actors are also drawn to crypto like wasps to <em>pain au chocolat</em>, so it&#39;s likely we&#39;ll hear about similar attacks in the near future.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/open-sea-vulnerability-exposed-crypto-wallets-to-attack-security-researchers-say-100028216.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">462e6101-7c8c-4890-bc68-0745484c031d</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634118971</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T09:56:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2d0bd7f0-124f-11ec-9d5b-406f59cf7dbc" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2d0bd7f0-124f-11ec-9d5b-406f59cf7dbc" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OpenSea logo displayed on a phone screen and representation of cryptocurrencies are seen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on August 26, 2021. (Photo by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OpenSea Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bird will test sensors that prevent riding on sidewalks]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you live in a city where rideshare scooters are available, chances are you’ve had someone zip by on one while you were walking on the sidewalk. It’s an issue that local governments around the world have pushed mobility companies to address since day one. And after working on the problem since 2019, Bird thinks it has a solution.</p><p>Collaborating with a firm called <a href="https://www.u-blox.com/en"><ins>U-blox</ins></a>, the company has developed a custom multi-sensor and GPS module it says is far more accurate than other solutions at detecting when someone drives a scooter onto a sidewalk. When you drive a Bird scooter that’s equipped with the module onto a sidewalk, it will produce an audible sound and send a notification to your smartphone. The vehicle will also slowly and smoothly come to a stop.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Bird is testing the technology in Milwaukee and San Diego and plans to bring it to Madrid and other cities in the future.</p><p>For Bird, coming to this point has been a long journey. At one point, the company tried using AI-assisted cameras for sidewalk detection but found they presented two problems. One, they would have added a fragile component to a vehicle that’s already frequently <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2018/12/electric-scooter-bird-lime-lakes-rivers-environment-vandalism.html"><ins>vandalized</ins></a>. Two, training the machine learning software that would power those cameras would have proven difficult due to the ways road infrastructure in different countries can look. According to Bird, the advantage of its latest solution is that it’s a solution it can implement at scale without worrying about the weather or vandalism.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bird-u-blox-sidewalk-detection-module-100016730.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9e974cf8-bb2c-4056-8c5d-ae2e5dcf55d2</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634078502</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T22:41:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/853a4a60-2ba9-11ec-acff-fa76b34af919" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/853a4a60-2ba9-11ec-acff-fa76b34af919" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bird]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bird sidewalk detection]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bird sidewalk detection]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>