<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:41:43 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Square Enix opens a new studio dedicated to mobile games]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Square Enix is ramping up its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-19-final-fantasy-viii-remastered-release-date.html">mobile game efforts</a> by opening a studio devoted to phone titles. The publisher has <a href="https://www.square-enix-london-mobile.com/">launched</a> a Square Enix London Mobile location that will focus on free-to-play games. It&#39;s relying on both Square Enix&#39;s own brands as well as other big-name licenses.</p><p>The first projects reflect that strategy. The already-announced <em>Tomb Raider Reloaded</em> is a top-down puzzle solver coming to Android and iOS in 2022. A new, as-yet untitled game based on <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> is also in the works from Canada-based Navigator games.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This won&#39;t be thrilling if you were hoping for more console and PC games, but it&#39;s expected given the shifting gaming landscape. While console and PC titles are still important, the mobile market is huge. Titles like <em>Honor of Kings</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tencent-limits-honor-of-kings-play-time-122045915.html">dominate China</a>, and Square Enix itself has been interested enough to port &#39;full-size&#39; games like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-19-final-fantasy-viii-remastered-release-date.html"><em>Final Fantasy VIII Remastered</em></a> to phones. The London Mobile studio lets Square Enix tap into that burgeoning market without drawing resources away from its other development teams.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/square-enix-london-mobile-game-studio-144143411.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b186d068-a269-4b57-a407-bf8f73c7ad6f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:41:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634740904</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T14:41:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7aca150-31ad-11ec-8ad7-7806e02156af" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7aca150-31ad-11ec-8ad7-7806e02156af" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Square Enix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A still image from the Tomb Raider mobile game.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider mobile game]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Razer reveals new mics for pro and casual streamers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://engadget.com/tag/razer">Razer</a> has refreshed its lineup of microphones aimed at streamers with new versions of two Seiren models. The Seiren V2 Pro and Seiren V2 X are both plug and play mics with a high pass filter to mitigate unwanted low frequencies and an analog gain limiter to tackle voice distortion.</p><p>The mics each have a gain dial and mute button as well as a headphone jack, while the V2 Pro also has a volume dial. They’re both said to be fully customizable for mixing and sound profiles, and there’s integration with audio mixing software via Razer Synapse.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The V2 Pro is a dynamic microphone with 20 Hz frequency response to pick up a full range of audio, according to Razer. The company says it’s an improvement on its Elite offering and it delivers “rich and powerful vocals” with “superior clarity and noise dampening.”</p><p>Meanwhile, the V2 X is a new version of the Seiren X, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-20-razer-webcam-microphone-made-for-streamers.html">which emerged in 2017</a>. It&#39;s a 25mm condenser mic with a supercaridoid pickup pattern, which Razer suggests bolsters the device’s voice isolation capabilities. The company is promising “crisp and natural vocals” with the V2 X as well.</p><p>Razer recently introduced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-budget-webcam-capture-card-streaming-newbies-kiyo-x-ripsaw-x-162956687.html">a webcam and capture card</a> for streaming newbies and an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-kaira-x-headset-xbox-playstation-164416154.html">entry-level headset</a> for console gamers. However, the latest mics are aimed at professional and casual streamers who might want to improve the sound quality of their streams. The V2 Pro costs <a href="https://fave.co/3aX95V8">$150</a>, while the V2 X is <a href="https://fave.co/3pm5ng7">$100</a>. Both are available now, as is the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-seiren-mini-microphone-172118633.html">Seiren Mini</a>, which Razer debuted a year ago.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/razer-seiren-v2-pro-x-microphone-streaming-142521356.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">019047ce-eb6f-456f-91ed-57e7d42a56b8</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:25:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634739922</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T14:25:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1a2f5f00-31b0-11ec-8fed-4f057cc6997b" width="1193" height="895" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1a2f5f00-31b0-11ec-8fed-4f057cc6997b" width="1193" height="895" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Razer Seiren V2 Pro and Seiren V2 X microphones positioned as part of a a PC game streaming setup, with a monitor, keyboard, laptop, headphones and ring light.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Seiren V2 Pro and Seiren V2 X]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung's Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition offers 49 possible color combinations]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Wednesday, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Samsung" href="https://fave.co/31Ygak3">Samsung</a> held its last Unpacked presentation of the year. The company headlined the event with the announcement of the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition" href="https://fave.co/3vuNblx">Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition</a>, a version of its clamshell foldable you can customize in a variety of colors. Specifically, you can choose between two frame tones (black or silver) and five front and back panel hues (blue, yellow, pink, white or black), for a total of 49 possible combinations. Each Bespoke Edition Galaxy Z Flip 3 also comes with matching wallpaper and cover screen.</p><p>If you ever want to update the look of your phone, Samsung will offer an Upgrade Care service where you can send it in for a palette swap. That should come in handy if you ever feel like you went overboard on your first design attempt and made something completely garish. Outside of the additional customization options, the Bespoke Edition Galaxy Z Flip 3 is identical to the model Samsung released in August. So expect the company’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">best foldable yet</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/84176ba0-3143-11ec-bbfb-857672afb1b6" alt="Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition" data-uuid="09588bb3-00aa-3f31-825c-f3d58476e5b7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>The Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition is available to order today from Samsung’s website in the US, Australia, Canada, France, Germany, Korea and UK. It starts at $1,100 and comes with 12 months of Samsung Care+ protection. As each device is made to order, delivery times will vary.</p><p>Alongside the Bespoke Edition Galaxy Z Flip 3, Samsung announced a software update for the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-body-fat-scan-wear-os-120026149.html">Galaxy Watch 4</a>. Available to download today, it comes with four new watch faces, including one called Info Brick that you can customize to display the fitness and health stats you want to see most. If you’re a fan of the existing Animals watch face, it’s now possible to add up to four complications to the interface.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0abf6cd0-3143-11ec-badf-bbb839a55e1d" alt="Galaxy Watch 4 update" data-uuid="3bfe31da-a2da-36a5-adcc-254e61f3e38a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>As part of the My Photo+ watch face, you can now choose to use a GIF instead of a still image. In the same vein, Samsung has redone the animations that are part of the step challenge to make them more playful. There’s now a cute bear there to encourage you to walk your 10,000 steps.</p><p>The update also adds a new knock-knock gesture you can assign to launch your favorite app or feature. For instance, you can bind the gesture to create a new reminder or open a list of workouts. Lastly, you can tweak the sensitivity of the fall detection feature to trigger even if you fall after standing still. With the update, Watch 4 owners can also get a free 60-day subscription to Strava.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a19ef890-3144-11ec-8ffd-218b6025808b" alt="Maison Kitsune Galaxy Watch 4 " data-uuid="a82361ad-9a7d-3b6e-9bf9-76da37dba3a2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>Rounding out the event, Samsung announced <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:two Maison Kitsun&#xe9; special edition" href="https://fave.co/2XuLfgx">two Maison Kitsuné special edition</a> Galaxy Buds 2 and Galaxy Watch 4 models. Set to cost $250 and $400 when they go on sale later today, the devices come in a new “Moonrock Biege” color and feature the usual design flourishes that the fashion house is known for.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/bf007c60-3144-11ec-beee-0377230d2e97" alt="Maison Kitsune Galaxy Buds 2" data-uuid="1ebff89a-ee82-3e3d-b9dc-07964395883a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Samsung</div></figure><p>The watch comes with two straps. One in the aforementioned Moonrock Beige color and the other in a tone called “Stardust Gray.” The leather case the earbuds come is made from that same color.  If you buy one of the wearables, you’ll get access to a playlist curated by the Kitsuné Musique music label. Both devices will be available in limited quantities in select markets across the world.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-bespoke-edition-140040550.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5669d62c-5162-4361-aa89-ea69bf2459ef</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634740240</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T14:30:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e4c61780-3143-11ec-bcc9-3bf507f35176" width="3840" height="2400" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e4c61780-3143-11ec-bcc9-3bf507f35176" width="3840" height="2400" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 3 Bespoke Edition]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is Apple’s M1 Max really the fastest laptop chip ever?]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After months of rumors, Apple has revealed not one but two new processors, along with a pair of new Macbook Pro laptops. The original M1 processor paired four high-performance and four low-power cores with a 7- or 8-core GPU, and with that set up it delivered impressive results. The M1-powered 13-inch MacBook Pro bested a 16-inch MacBook Pro with an 8-core Intel i9 CPU and dedicated GPU <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yLVcRkFtEcA">when we tested it last year</a>, and did so while staying impressively cool and quiet.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The new M1 Pro and M1 Max bump the core count to eight high-performance and two low-power cores, and add 16, 24, or 32 GPU cores. With twice the high-performance CPUs, and up to four times the GPU cores as the original M1, these chips should be incredibly fast, but expect it to come at the cost of more heat and noise.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="def1a7f33bce42809bb77e04abf49a9d"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9QvfmV_DgbU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Despite a shortage of compatible games, the original M1 proved to be a remarkably adept processor for gaming, and these new chips should be even better, outpacing most Intel CPUs and maybe even besting a mobile NVIDIA RTX 3080 GPU&#39;s performance. The new 14-inch and 16-inch MacBooks also come with a 120Hz display with HDR, and improved speakers. Add that all together, and suddenly the new MacBook Pro looks like a pretty capable gaming machine, compatibility issues aside. If only Apple still supported Bootcamp.</p><p>For all the details on these new chips, check out the video above.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/m-1-max-pro-announced-upscaled-131531800.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c1f63b6f-c4dd-43c3-a9fd-9cde8404189b</guid><dc:creator>Christopher Schodt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 13:15:31 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634739848</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T14:24:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Christopher Schodt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/57257310-318b-11ec-bfbe-31c8821196b4" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c83f9250-31af-11ec-bffa-8d2b42b4ce7c" width="2000" height="1300" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An artist rendering of the Apple M1 Max chip, or at least a square with the Apple logo and the product title.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple M1 Max ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The new Assassin's Creed educational tour lets you explore the Viking Age]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-02-13-assassins-creed-origins-discovery-tour.html">Assassin&#39;s Creed Discovery Tours</a> can offer valuable educational insights into historical periods, and that may be particularly true for the latest instalment. Ubisoft has <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-ca/article/6WpV6SBWGb59fcnYhT2KBb/assassins-creed-discovery-tour-viking-age-out-now">released</a> a <em>Discovery Tour: Viking Age</em> update for <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-ca/article/6WpV6SBWGb59fcnYhT2KBb/assassins-creed-discovery-tour-viking-age-out-now"><em>Assassin&#39;s Creed Valhalla</em></a> that gives you the chance to explore Viking-era England and Norway without the usual conflicts. There&#39;s a new format, however. Rather than go on guided tours and visit exhibits, you assume the roles of four Anglo-Saxon and Viking characters (such as Anglo-Saxon king Alfred the Great and a Viking merchant) as they undertake eight quests that illustrate their daily lives.</p><p>You can also study period artifacts from museums in the UK, France and Denmark. And yes, there are rewards to unlock in the main <em>Valhalla</em> game for Eivor and his longship.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The <em>Discovery Tour</em> update is free for <em>Valhalla</em> players on all platforms, and you can buy the $20 stand-alone version for PCs through either <a href="https://store.ubi.com/us/game/?lang=en_US&amp;pid=613f1bcb5cdf9a076026d090&amp;dwvar_613f1bcb5cdf9a076026d090_Platform=pcdl&amp;edition=Viking%20Age&amp;source=detail">Ubisoft&#39;s store</a> or the <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/discovery-tour-viking-age">Epic Games Store</a>. Console and streaming players will have to wait until 2022 for a stand-alone release. However you get a copy, it could be a worthwhile experience if you&#39;ve wanted to dispel the myths surrounding Vikings and their conquests.</p><div id="1143ed71f96745b19cd07bd82d8dee5a"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2A8vES0EwOY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/assassins-creed-valhalla-discovery-tour-viking-age-131501270.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">16f91c41-ed10-4c98-8930-c35ad45b56f5</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 13:15:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634735418</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T13:10:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4b831eb0-31a2-11ec-be77-d3736c542785" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4b831eb0-31a2-11ec-be77-d3736c542785" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ubisoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Discovery Tour of England in 'Assassin's Creed Valhalla']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Discovery Tour of England in 'Assassin's Creed Valhalla']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[WhatsApp users can now shop for items by category using 'Collections']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook, ever on the search for ways to monetize its apps, recently introduced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whatsapp-shopping-185948786.html">Catalogs</a> and a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-shopping-cart-business-catalog-messaging-120011660.html">basic cart</a> to WhatsApp so users could shop directly from their chats. Now, the company is refining that process with the addition of Collections, essentially categorized lists that make it easier for WhatsApp users to find products.&nbsp;</p><p>With the new feature, businesses can now &quot;organize items in their catalogs by category so customers no longer have to scroll through long lists of items to find what they’re looking for,&quot; WhatsApp said. From a user perspective, you&#39;ll now see categories for &quot;men’s clothes, women’s clothes, shirts, pants&quot; and more rather than just a list of products. As before, you can access a company&#39;s catalog through a sent link or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-shopping-button-152011215.html">shopping button</a> in their header.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="3d722876be84490bbee6cd6856272a6f"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ssYQkqPsmo?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>WhatsApp noted that the app has become more popular for shopping in Brazil and India since COVID-19 started. Facebook and WhatsApp have a mixed record in developing countries, however — Brazil, for example, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-payments-suspended-in-brazil-104007806.html">suspended</a> WhatsApp&#39;s fledgling mobile payment system late last year.</p><p>The new feature is now live in time for the holiday season. Businesses interested in using it can learn how to do it using the video supplied by WhatsApp, above.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/whats-app-users-can-now-shop-for-items-by-category-130047604.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2e034d1f-2e8c-49b1-93a2-b9e0619f2a3a</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634734392</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T12:53:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3252ddf0-31a1-11ec-bba5-abc07b9cde67" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3252ddf0-31a1-11ec-bba5-abc07b9cde67" width="2000" height="1125" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[WhatsApp users can now shop for items by category with 'Collections']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[WhatsApp users can now shop for items by category with 'Collections']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Talli Baby tracker is a one-touch system for logging kids activities]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Never in my life did I think it would be important for me to know when someone else had pooped, but then I became a mom and here we are. The amount of stuff that mom’s need to keep track of is, in a word, immense. Since I brought my twins home from the hospital, I’ve used <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/baby-tracker-newborn-log/id779656557">an app</a> to note every bottle, diaper change, nap, medication, bath time and more. That’s worked well so far, but now that my kids are older, I’ve had a harder time immediately logging their events. That’s partially because our routines were interrupted with a recent move and partially because they <em>really </em>want to play with my phone every time they see it. Regardless, I’m trying to get us all back into an established pattern of meals and nap times so I’ve been wanting to re-establish my habit of logging all their details.</p><p>Talli sells a $99 physical gadget for this purpose: a single-touch tracking device that lets busy, sleep-deprived parents push a button to log activities like bottle feeds and bedtimes. The <a href="https://fave.co/3iXtgGW">Talli Baby one-touch tracker</a> includes seven pre-assigned buttons and a miscellaneous eighth, and it pairs with an app to provide you the best of both worlds. A single-function device to track kids’ care may not sound like a big deal, but if you’ve ever tried to operate a touchscreen with diaper cream all over your hands, you may be able to see the utility here.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>Hardware</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/72e24170-30e4-11ec-bfdf-b49595c6e30b" alt="Talli Baby One Touch Tracker" data-uuid="83b7e639-7cb8-3382-b129-b295cdaaa487"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Amber Bouman/Engadget</div></figure><p>The Talli is a white and faux-woodgrain box with rounded edges, roughly the size of a small but stuffed wallet. It has two rows of four activity buttons with icons to indicate which action the button is assigned to: bottle feeding, solid food, wet diaper, dirty diaper, sleeping, nursing, pumping or “miscellaneous,” which can be customized within the app. Events that happen at the same time — say, a wet and dirty diaper — require simultaneous button presses. There’s also a small WiFi button on the lower right that’s used during setup, and the company says that WiFi is only used when the device is transmitting an event. The rear contains slots to wall-mount the Talli using the included hardware.</p><p>Setting up the Talli is fairly uncomplicated and follows the same steps as many other app-connected devices: download the app, create an account, add a device, connect to a WiFi network and you’re done. When I first set up the device, it kept flashing an error message, which the included start-up pamphlet instructed me was a WiFi connection issue likely due to an incorrect network name or password.</p><p>Only I hadn’t gotten to that step yet, I was only trying to sync the device. I contacted Talli support and tried again and was able to connect and set up the device without any further issue. It’s worked normally since then so I’m not certain what the issue was, but it did make me realize that adding a hardware device to my tracking process meant there would be another potential point of failure. Since Talli pairs with an app that can be used independently to track what you’re doing with your kids, it wouldn’t be the end of the world if the hardware wasn’t working. However, it would detract from the main advantage of the system: the convenience of pressing a button on the tracker and continuing with your day.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b021e1d0-30e4-11ec-be57-12f1f9232edd" alt="Talli Baby One Touch Tracker" data-uuid="bf0d407d-da47-3d0c-9aba-2cfee0d3782d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Amber Bouman/Engadget</div></figure><p>Taking out my smartphone, opening an app and typing in an entry isn’t exactly heavy lifting, but doing that while two toddlers wind themselves between my legs, grab at my phone, whine, harass the cat, throw everything out of the kitchen drawers and try to climb over child gates is another story. Being able to press a button and be done was an unexpected relief: My kid’s data was logged, so I knew when they were last changed and I could always flesh out the entries with more detail in the app later (though I’ll admit that rarely happened). It was extremely easy to use the Talli instead of my previous app, and it was oddly satisfying, too — not unlike crossing something off a to-do list.</p><p>Because Talli runs on four AA batteries, it has a portable design allowing it to be moved anywhere or handed off to any caretakers or babysitters. It can also be mounted on a wall, which has advantages and disadvantages depending on how you’ll use it. I kept my Talli untethered because my changing table area doesn’t have the best WiFi coverage, so I kept it on a nearby shelf where I could touch the buttons on my way in and out of the room.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0a0dd510-310c-11ec-997f-532cdf7aaeb7" alt="Talli Baby" data-uuid="f34f71b1-0e49-31c5-b4f5-42bdc28e5a0e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Talli</div></figure><p>Frankly, I would have preferred to mount the thing; when grabbing for the device, I would often accidentally hit a button and register an incorrect event, which I would then have to remember to delete later. But I also often had to move the Talli out of sight, because my son is particularly enamored with pushing buttons and things that light up, so the Talli was like forbidden candy to him. It was hard to find the perfect location where the device was connected to my WiFi network, easily accessible to me and didn’t draw his attention.</p><p>Each Talli device gets assigned to one child, that is to say you’ll need one Talli per child. But you can assign multiple devices to the same child if you end up getting more than one for different areas of your home. And Talli works with Alexa, so you can have the assistant log events for you if you say “Alexa tell Talli Baby that Sam had a dirty diaper.” You can also request that Alexa read you the most recent activity reports. I don’t currently have an Alexa-enabled device, so I wasn’t able to test this out yet. The company says Google Home compatibility is coming soon, too.</p><h2>Software</h2><p>Much like the device itself, the Talli app is  simply designed and straightforward to use. The home screen contains the same icons as the device; when a button is active — it turns green for a pumping session or a nap time, for example. Near each button is a date and time stamp for the last logged event and tapping on the icon brings up an entry page to edit and add details. I sometimes had to tap commands a few times — say, to pause or start a sleep timer — but this otherwise worked fine.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9c220070-30e9-11ec-bfe9-e479f059f977" alt="Talli Baby app" data-uuid="5998f4f5-111e-3e61-9ffe-b356f4f46f35"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>The rest of the app is organized into a Daily List, which is exactly what it sounds like: a list of your child’s daily events. There’s also a Details view which provides an hour-by-hour graph of events and can be toggled to show any of your child’s metrics over a time period. My favorites were the Averages view, which shows totals for each event, and the More tab, which has selections for account sharing, reminders and children’s profiles. I’m trying to switch the twins over to all solid foods and being able to track what they’ve eaten, how much and when has helped me establish routines and menus. And because it was easy to press a button on the way in or out of the room, Talli made it possible for me to log how often my son woke in the middle of the night and how long before he went back to sleep.</p><p>However, the app frequently (albeit briefly) flashed a “Refreshing your data” screen when I navigated around the options. I had to wait an extra beat or two for the data to refresh when I did almost anything in the app: changed screens, edited data, deleted an event and the like. I’m hoping this is due to my satellite internet connection, because it was one of my biggest pain points with the Talli system. I will say I appreciated that there was no subscription component: Talli offers all its information and your data without any additional fees, whether you purchase the tracker or simply use the free app.</p><h2>Wrap-up</h2><p>The Talli device offers something that isn’t otherwise available: a hardware device dedicated to tracking everything you do with your child on a daily basis. It’s nicely designed, easy to use and has an app that charts and graphs the data for you. I liked using it a lot more than I expected to, given that tracking all my kids’ various activities through an app had become a bit of a chore. But using the Talli tracker wasn’t a chore — and having a physical device (even more, a single button) that I could tap and walk away from did indeed help me stay more consistent with tracking habits.</p><p>I only wish that I had found a better location for the device in my kids’ room — and I wish that the app didn’t lag so much — but otherwise I was pleasantly surprised at how well the Talli Tracker fit into my lifestyle. I can see it being particularly useful for those who have family or multiple caretakers tending to children or for people who prefer physical logging methods like calendars or notebooks. But it’s also a $99 gadget — and when a free app just requires more work but will ultimately do the job, it makes the Talli a bit of a luxury.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-talli-baby-tracker-is-a-one-touch-system-for-logging-kids-activities-130022927.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f9663317-90f0-4e03-8700-9f538035edce</guid><dc:creator>Amber Bouman</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634735278</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T13:08:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Amber Bouman]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/99b2b240-31a6-11ec-b9fe-84293a39baae" width="4032" height="2634" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/99b2b240-31a6-11ec-b9fe-84293a39baae" width="4032" height="2634" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Talli]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An overhead view of the Talli Baby tracker and a cup of coffee on a small round table.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Talli Baby tracker]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['LEGO Star Wars: Castaways' arrives November 19th on Apple Arcade]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lego-star-wars-the-skywalker-saga-trailer-release-window-192234269.html"><em>LEGO Star Wars</em></a> game is heading to Apple Arcade, and it&#39;s the first social, action-adventure title in the franchise. The upcoming game, entitled <a href="https://www.starwars.com/games-apps/lego-star-wars-castaways"><em>LEGO Star Wars: Castaways</em></a>, will have you building and customizing your own in-game LEGO minifigure character. Once you&#39;re done designing your own blocky hero, you&#39;ll head to a new planet where you can team up with friends to battle enemies and solve puzzles. Along the way, you can unlock collectibles to solve a mystery and save your merry band of LEGO minifigures.</p><p>When you&#39;re not out on adventures — of if you really just want to hang out in a virtual world with friends — you can stay in the game&#39;s Social Hub or race Microfighters. <em>LEGO Star Wars: Castaways</em> is an Apple Arcade exclusive, just like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-lego-star-wars-battles-exclusive-rts-180046178.html"><em>LEGO Star Wars Battles</em></a>. The latter is a real-time strategy game that will let you collect upgradable characters, troops and vehicles and then pit you against other players in one-on-one showdowns. In <em>Star Wars Battles, </em>you&#39;ll also have to build and defend your own LEGO towers, as well as attack your opponent&#39;s.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>LEGO Star Wars: Castaways </em>will be playable across iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple TV, so long as you have an Arcade subscription. You can now sign up to be notified when the game becomes available for download from the Mac Store and the iOS App Store, but the game won&#39;t be available to play until November 19th.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lego-star-wars-castaways-apple-arcade-121058221.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4d286b76-94f4-4475-85e1-fa2f72a0da24</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 12:10:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634731046</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T11:57:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/367164b0-3192-11ec-bfae-5feb36b12de1" width="1536" height="864" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/367164b0-3192-11ec-bfae-5feb36b12de1" width="1536" height="864" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LEGO Star Wars: Castaways]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LEGO Star Wars: Castaways]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LEGO Star Wars: Castaways]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard says over 20 employees have 'exited' following harassment cases]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Activision Blizzard has confirmed that more than 20 employees have &quot;exited&quot; the company as part of its efforts to change its internal culture following allegations of fostering a &quot;frat boy&quot; workplace. The video game company has <a href="https://activisionblizzard.com/content/atvi/activisionblizzard/ab-touchui/ab/web/en/newsroom/2021/10/creating-a-more-accountable-workplace.html">published</a> the letter Executive VP for Corporate Affairs Fran Townsend sent to employees revealing the move, in which she also said that more than 20 other individuals faced different types of disciplinary action. Back in July, the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html">filed a lawsuit</a> against the developer for allowing a work environment wherein female employees were allegedly subjected to constant sexual harassment.</p><p>The agency, which sued the company after a two-year investigation, detailed several of its findings in the lawsuit. It said female employees constantly have to fend off unwanted sexual comments, and that they have to endure being groped by male colleagues. They&#39;re also not paid as much as their male counterparts,  are typically promoted more slowly and fired more quickly. At the time, Townsend told employees that the lawsuit &quot;presented a distorted&quot; picture of the company and that it included &quot;factually incorrect, old and out of context stories.&quot; Hundreds of employees walked out in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-employee-open-letter-221223475.html">protest</a> over the company&#39;s response.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Now, in her letter, Townsend said that there&#39;s a team dedicated to investigating harassment claims, &quot;working tirelessly to ensure that, moving forward, [the company] is a place where people are not only heard, but empowered.&quot; The team received an increasing number of reports in recent months, including concerns from years ago, and it was the members&#39; investigation that led to the exit of more than 20 employees. Townsend declined to name those individuals, but she told <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7cb805b9-4d14-40ee-a1f2-72bc3c3e1ea6"><em>Financial Times</em></a> that they include several game developers and a few supervisors. None of them came from senior management or from the board.&nbsp;</p><p>A <a href="https://kotaku.com/jesse-mcree-diablo-4-director-no-longer-at-activision-1847469113"><em>Kotaku</em></a> report from August <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-loses-designers-121905544.html">named</a> three senior designers who abruptly exited the company. Two of them — <em>Diablo 4</em> lead designer Jesse McCree and <em>World of Warcraft</em> designer Jonathan LeCraft — were previously pictured inside the Cosby Suite. In its lawsuit, DEFH said the Cosby Suite is a room with a photo of Bill Cosby where male employees allegedly harassed women during company events.</p><p>To be able to handle more complaints, Activision Blizzard hired three full-time employees to join the investigation team. It&#39;s also adding 19 more full-time roles to its overall Ethics &amp; Compliance Team, two of which will be dedicated to overseeing investigations for the EMEA and APAC regions. Townsend admitted that the team can&#39;t always share the details of an investigation, but she also promised more transparency &quot;We know there’s a desire to know about the outcome when misconduct is reported. Sometimes, there are privacy reasons we can’t share. But where we can, we will be sharing more information with you. We will also be providing you regular aggregate data about investigative outcomes,&quot; she wrote in her letter.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-fired-20-employees-harassment-cases-112540361.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">786bf980-e5bb-41d0-871c-cfb464a03e11</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:35:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634728107</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T11:08:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f0ef7ae0-f54f-11eb-bf39-1896212cf0e2" width="5000" height="3263" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f0ef7ae0-f54f-11eb-bf39-1896212cf0e2" width="5000" height="3263" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[DAVID MCNEW via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Employees of the video game company, Activision Blizzard, hold a walkout and protest rally to denounce the companys response to a California Department of Fair Employment and Housing lawsuit and to call for changes in conditions for women and other marginalized groups, in , in Irvine, California, on July 28, 2021.  (Photo by DAVID MCNEW / AFP) (Photo by DAVID MCNEW/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-IT-GAMES-SEXISM-ACTIVISION]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Google Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro first impressions]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google’s Pixel 6 family is officially priced and will launch on October 28th, available to pre-order today. While not cheap, both the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-price-specs-release-date-170039729-170024290.html">Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro</a>, costing $599 and $899 respectively, land at tempting price points.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-price-specs-release-date-170039729-170024290.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/42e94c00-3190-11ec-a5fb-3e0d2959f7e0" alt="Pixel 6" data-uuid="1e6194be-f5e6-343a-a253-1bf89c627be0"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>These phones are going toe-to-toe with the iPhone and Galaxy S series. Again. But will Google finally be able to get its phones in people’s hands? The company glimpsed success with its very competitively priced Pixel 3a, briefly edging out OnePlus in phone sales for a hot second. Then the Pixel 4 and Pixel 5 failed to repeat the success at tougher prices. Notably, the $600 Pixel 6 is $100 cheaper than last year&#39;s Pixel 5, but it looks to be a far better phone.</p><p>Each phone has a thick camera bar stretching across the back. The Pixel 6 has a dual-camera system, with wide and ultrawide lenses, while the Pixel 6 Pro adds a telephoto option. On both devices, the primary camera is a 50-megapixel sensor with a quad-bayer filter, which puts four pixels behind each standard color block — you’re not going to get 50-megapixel photos here, but something more in the realm of 12.5 megapixels. The Pixel 6 Pro’s telephoto camera is a 48-megapixel sensor with 4x optical zoom. There are no invisible front-facing cameras — or notches — but a pin-hole camera on both Pixels. There is also an under-screen thumbprint sensor for the first time in a Pixel phone. You can find the rest of the specs <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-price-specs-release-date-170039729-170024290.html">right here</a>.</p><div id="f01e87e4efc3462c9bbf33b97c149292"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/erVIyrv3PE0?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Reviews Editor Cherlynn Low spent time with both Pixels. We’ll dive deeper into her impressions below.</p><p></p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h3>All the biggest news from Google’s Pixel event</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-soc-pixel-6-chip-170059466.html">Google details the Pixel 6&#39;s unique Tensor chip</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-camera-will-feature-larger-image-sensors-and-smarter-photo-editing-ai-171159356.html">The Pixel 6&#39;s camera will feature larger image sensors and smarter photo editing AI</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-assistant-call-hold-181236423.html">Google turns those annoying call center menus into easy-to-navigate screens</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-quick-tap-to-snap-snapchat-180058754.html">Quick Tap to Snap is a Pixel 6-first camera shortcut for Snapchat</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-live-translate-ai-google-tensor-chip-174938971.html">Google&#39;s Pixel 6 can translate text as you type</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-camera-skin-tone-inclusive-pixel-google-170212102.html">Real Tone is Google&#39;s attempt at a more inclusive Android camera</a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-hands-on-tensor-features-camera-specs-available-price-170038272.html">Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on</a></h2><h3>A return to premium?</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-hands-on-tensor-features-camera-specs-available-price-170038272.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a085aed0-3190-11ec-abcf-6106e9916937" alt="Pixel 6" data-uuid="83e1282b-6d46-359b-8d73-34f7d71785e0"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>Spoiler alert: The best thing about the new Pixel phones is the reasonable pricing. But there are a lot of new things to tackle with the Pixel 6 series. This series has the company’s first “pro” phone, some Android 12-exclusive tricks and significant voice recognition enhancements — if you’re in the US.</p><p>The two phones differ slightly in design, which marks a departure from previous years. Instead of the matte soft-touch texture of older Pixels, both Pixel 6 phones have glass-covered sides,   creating a premium feel. According to Cherlynn Low, they’re a little blockier and feel more like a Samsung device — which may not be a bad thing.</p><p>Both phones are also much larger than the Pixel 5, and though their screen sizes differ, they have almost the same footprint. But the main feature improvement in the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro is their cameras, and this is what Cherlynn (and I) are most excited about. For now, she could only gather some impressions while under the supervision of Google reps, but expect her own review to put all the cameras through their paces. As Cherlynn will admit herself, she loves a selfie camera opp.</p><h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-hands-on-tensor-features-camera-specs-available-price-170038272.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></h3><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pass-subscription-170056831.html">The Pixel Pass bundles a Pixel 6 with Google services for $45 per month</a></h2><h3>All the Google you’d ever need.</h3><h3></h3><p>Google has an answer to the Apple One bundle, and it includes a new phone. The Pixel Pass is a subscription service that includes a Pixel 6 or 6 Pro phone (with an upgrade in two years), an extended warranty, 200GB of Google One storage, Google Play Pass, YouTube Premium and YouTube Music Premium. The Pass starts at $45 per month for the regular Pixel 6, while it’s $55 for the Pixel 6 Pro.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pass-subscription-170056831.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-tech-deals-best-buy-early-black-friday-sale-october-2021-121526669.html">The best tech deals in Best Buy&#39;s early Black Friday sale</a></h2><h3>Headphones, robot vacuums, OLED TVs, laptops and more.</h3><h3></h3><p>No, it’s never too early to grab a Black Friday deal, OK? Especially if it doesn’t involve a store rush.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-tech-deals-best-buy-early-black-friday-sale-october-2021-121526669.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-is-announcing-a-new-camera-on-october-21st-likely-the-a-7-iv-085021205.html">Sony may announce its new A7 IV mirrorless camera on October 21st</a></h2><h3>A YouTube data leak has spoiled some of the surprises, however.</h3><p></p><p>Sony has teased the launch of a new Alpha camera on October 21st at 10 AM ET, and judging by the YouTube metadata, it appears to be the long-awaited full-frame A7 IV mirrorless model. A list of now-stripped tags, if accurate, would make the A7 IV a formidable hybrid full-frame camera, on par with Canon&#39;s R6 (but hopefully without the overheating issues). Expect a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video with 10-bit All-I XAVC recording. And that’s probably just the start.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-is-announcing-a-new-camera-on-october-21st-likely-the-a-7-iv-085021205.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-portal-go-review-140033819.html">Facebook Portal Go review</a></h2><h3>Tablet or smart display?</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-portal-go-review-140033819.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/eb84bfc0-3190-11ec-afff-19bde7218d71" alt="Facebook Portal Go" data-uuid="fb200d41-15ed-3bc6-8003-2455ff802bfa"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure></a><p>Facebook’s new Portal Go adds portability to the company’s video-chat-focused smart display. Like with previous Portals, it has an AI-powered camera that keeps you in frame during video calls, except this time you can carry it around the house. The Go has other improvements, too, such as a more personalized home screen and a new Household Mode that makes it more family-friendly. However, it lacks a lot of features that other smart displays have, and Facebook’s poor reputation precedes it.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-portal-go-review-140033819.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-event-2021-highlights-192245034.html">Here&#39;s everything Google announced at its Pixel 6 event</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pro-vs-the-apple-iphone-12-samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-oneplus-9-pro-172019652.html">The Pixel 6 Pro vs. the competition: Telephoto, Tensor and more</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-vs-the-competition-iphone-12-galaxy-s21-171553646.html">The Pixel 6 vs. the competition: The Tensor chip goes up to bat</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-pre-order-google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-smartphones-173051481.html">How to pre-order the Google Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/dbrand-darkplates-2-0-162306317.html">Dbrand says its latest PS5 faceplates will survive Sony&#39;s legal wrath</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/raspberry-pi-build-hat-lego-robots-123039227.html">Raspberry Pi&#39;s Build HAT helps students build LEGO robots</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/donald-trump-campaign-website-defaced-072039009.html">Donald Trump&#39;s campaign website was defaced by a hacker</a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-first-impressions-111515992.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5802919e-45a9-403e-ad4a-5b65f1994427</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:15:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634737828</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T13:50:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e2055830-30f3-11ec-8ff7-c6914738a341" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e2055830-30f3-11ec-8ff7-c6914738a341" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook fined $69.6 million in the UK for breaking rules related to its Giphy takeover]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Facebook acquired the popular GIF repository Giphy (reportedly for $400 million), the UK&#39;s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) launched an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uk-investigates-facebook-giphy-acquisition-141604075.html">investigation</a> to determine if the merger would lessen competition. As part of that probe, it said Facebook couldn&#39;t continue with activities related to the merger (integrating products, merging teams and so on) without prior approval from the CMA.&nbsp;</p><p>Now, the CMA has <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-fines-facebook-over-enforcement-order-breach">announced</a> that it has fined Facebook £50.5 million ($70 million) for breaching those enforcement orders. &quot;This is the first time a company has been found by the CMA to have breached an [order] by consciously refusing to report all the required information,&quot; the CMA said in a press release.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The authority said that Facebook &quot;significantly limited the scope of&quot; updates required by the CMA, despite repeated warnings. Citing criticism by the Competition Appeal Tribunal and Court of Appeal, it noted that Facebook engaged in &quot;what might be regarded as a high-risk strategy&quot; around a &quot;lack of cooperation&quot; with the CMA.</p><p>In response to the fine, a Facebook spokesperson gave the following statement: &quot;We strongly disagree with the CMA’s unfair decision to punish Facebook for a best effort compliance approach, which the CMA itself ultimately approved. We will review the CMA’s decision and consider our options.&quot;</p><p>The CMA said it also fined the company £500,000 ($700,000) for changing its Chief Compliance Officers twice without seeking consent. Facebook saw net revenue of $29.4 billion in 2020, so the fines are relative pocket change. However, its issues with the CMA aren&#39;t over yet, as the authority has yet to make a decision on the merger itself. In the meantime, it promised to &quot;work constructively with the companies as things progress further.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Update 10/20/2021 7:58 AM ET</strong>: Facebook gave Engadget a statement on the ruling, which has been added to the article.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uk-fines-facebook-70-million-for-breaking-rules-related-to-its-giphy-purchase-110227187.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0dd26a38-8894-43e0-bf4e-d2dc6861206a</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:02:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634731148</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T11:59:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/30fca520-3193-11ec-bd9f-c96f357afb8b" width="5524" height="3712" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/30fca520-3193-11ec-bd9f-c96f357afb8b" width="5524" height="3712" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Toby Melville / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A giant logo is seen at Facebook's headquarters in London, Britain, December 4, 2017. REUTERS/Toby Melville]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BRITAIN-FACEBOOK/HQ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[New union pact means better pay and conditions for streaming production crews]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The union representing film production crews has avoided a strike with an agreement that will see its members paid up to 30 percent more on streaming productions, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735892/iatses-tentative-basic-agreement-streaming-pay"><em>The Verge</em></a> has reported. The deal represents a win for International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) workers, who have typically been <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/07/iatse-hard-line-film-tv-contract-talks-amptp-1234800346/">paid less</a> for streaming shows than theatrical film productions and broadcast TV series in the US.</p><p>In an informational brief, IATSE tweeted that wages will increase for long-form, episodic and mini-series at up to 30 percent, depending on the classification. Those boosts depend on the size of the streaming company, with rates higher for services with 20 million or more subscribers. Longform productions between $20 and $32 million used to get discounts if they were headed to streaming services, but that will no longer be the case.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="42b43d8fd4f44a069cac9b788fe5b5ea"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">NEW: We are releasing our first three one page documents explaining how the new tentative Basic Agreement addresses the priorities members identified early in the bargaining process.<br><br>This is a non-exhaustive set of member priorities, more soon.<br><br>1. STREAMING IMPROVEMENTS <a href="https://t.co/ACLP5cbLiv">pic.twitter.com/ACLP5cbLiv</a></p>— IATSE // #IASolidarity (@IATSE) <a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450646990279282689?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>On top of higher wages, members will also see <a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450646995790598146">improved workplace conditions</a>. That includes employer funding of health and pension plans, along with revised terms for producers that tend rely a lot on overtime. In addition, &quot;workers under the IATSE Basic Agreement across the US will be entitled to the same sick leave benefits as California members,&quot; the union stated.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>IATSE had warned that it would be taking a hard line with streaming services. &quot;The most profitable companies on the planet do not need cut rates that were negotiated to address a once emerging distribution method. Apple, Amazon, Netflix, Facebook should all pay industry standard wages to the professionals who crew their productions,&quot; the union told <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/07/iatse-hard-line-film-tv-contract-talks-amptp-1234800346/"><em>Deadline</em></a> in July.&nbsp;</p><p>IATSE members unanimously voted to strike this week if contract negotiations stalled, but that was narrowly avoided by a tentative agreement between the union and AMPTP group representing producers. However, it still needs to be ratified by union members, who could vote against it and send the parties back to the table.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/union-deal-means-better-pay-and-conditions-for-streaming-production-crews-103537294.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3c48937f-0eef-4d7f-9b47-14ab6f437b3d</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:35:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634723635</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T09:54:08+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Unions]]></category><category><![CDATA[Labor Issues]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4368aba0-3184-11ec-b7ef-a5f72926134d" width="1024" height="683" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4368aba0-3184-11ec-b7ef-a5f72926134d" width="1024" height="683" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ken Woroner/Netflix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Netflix strike averted]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netflix strike averted]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pinterest is redesigning its home feed to look more like TikTok]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pinterest is stepping up its efforts to lure creators to its platform, and making its app a little more like TIkTok in the process. The company showed off a number of new creator-focused features Wednesday to mark its annual “Creator Festival” event.</p><p>The changes include a redesigned home feed that separates the app into two tabs: “Browse,” which features a familiar grid of Pins, and “Watch” a new feed of full-screen vertical video that looks a lot like TikTok.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>But instead of viral dances and catchy music, Pinterest’s Watch section is an endless feed of “Idea Pins,” the Stories-like <a href="https://newsroom.pinterest.com/en/post/pinterest-introduces-idea-pins-globally-and-launches-new-creator-discovery-features"><ins>feature</ins></a> the company launched earlier this year. Idea Pins allow creators to publish the kind of first-person video with narration or text overlays that you might find on platforms like TikTok. The feature has been central to the company’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pinterest-shopping-idea-pins-affiliate-links-155149992.html"><ins>creator-focused</ins></a> initiatives, though the company has been slower to embrace influencers than some competing platforms.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/36c40740-313f-11ec-bede-843ec642c8fd" style="height:2160;width:2160;" alt="Pinterest will enable users to create " data-uuid="8f25e138-0a71-3b48-b4b7-b4eb35b3c572"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Pinterest</div></figure><p>But with the new “Watch” feed, Idea Pins are moving front and center within the app, and will be served up to users in a swipeable, TikTok-like format. And, after initially limiting the format to a small group of vetted creators, Pinterest is adding features it hopes will spur more users to create Idea Pins of their own. A new “Takes” feature will allow users to riff off of other creators&#39; Idea Pins, similar to the way creators may remix or respond to each other’s TikToks.</p><p>While TikTok may not be the platform most associated with creators, the company has been steadily ramping up its efforts to engage with more influential users. In addition to creator profiles and Idea Pins, the company also launched a $500,000 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pinterest-creator-fund-creator-code-150013929.html">creator fund</a> to provide direct financial support to creators from underrepresented backgrounds. And the company introduced dedicated <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pinterest-shopping-idea-pins-affiliate-links-155149992.html">monetization features</a> to help creators make money via brand partnerships.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pinterest-is-redesigning-its-home-feed-to-look-more-like-tik-tok-100013969.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">79aaaf2c-eca8-499d-b19c-4f2b6e1ea354</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634691086</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T00:51:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/edd13350-3139-11ec-bbdd-ab72c256cb30" width="2348" height="1570" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/edd13350-3139-11ec-bbdd-ab72c256cb30" width="2348" height="1570" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Pinterest's new Watch tab looks like TikTok.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Pinterest watch tab]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix co-CEO says he 'screwed up' communication over Dave Chappelle special]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix co-CEO Ted Sarandos has said he &quot;screwed up&quot; communication with employees following a backlash over Dave Chappelle&#39;s <em>The Closer</em>, according to <a href="https://variety.com/2021/film/news/dave-chappelle-netflix-ted-sarandos-i-screwed-up-1235093098/"><em>Variety</em></a>. At the same time, he stood by the show, saying the company heavily values &quot;artistic expression.&quot; His comments come just ahead of a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/19/business/media/netflix-dave-chappelle-employee-walkout.html">planned walkout</a> organized by LGBTQ+ staffers, creatives and allies.&nbsp;</p><p>After debuting earlier this month, <em>The Closer</em> was met by a storm of criticism from the LGBTQ+ community, who called it transphobic. At the time, he told employees that Netflix would never allow titles &quot;that are designed to incite hate or violence, and we don’t believe <em>The Closer</em> crosses that line.&quot;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Now, Sarandos has said he regrets the way he handled the situation with employees. &quot;Obviously, I screwed up that internal communication,&quot; he said in an interview with <em>Variety</em>. &quot;First and foremost, I should have led with a lot more humanity. Meaning, I had a group of employees who were definitely feeling pain and hurt from a decision we made. And I think that needs to be acknowledged up front before you get into the nuts and bolts of anything.&quot;</p><blockquote><p>Obviously, I screwed up that internal communication. First and foremost, I should have led with a lot more humanity. Meaning, I had a group of employees who were definitely feeling pain and hurt from a decision we made. And I think that needs to be acknowledged up front before you get into the nuts and bolts of anything.</p></blockquote><p>At the same time, Sarandos said in a separate interview that &quot;my stance hasn&#39;t changed&quot; regarding to the decision to stream the special. &quot;We do tell our employees upfront that we are trying to entertain our members, and that some of the content on Netflix you’re not going to like,&quot; he told <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/netflix-ted-sarandos-dave-chappelle-walkout-1235033910/"><em>The Hollywood Reporter</em></a><em>.</em> &quot;The inclusion of the special on Netflix is consistent with our comedy offering [and is]… one of those times when there’s something on Netflix that you’re not going to like.&quot;</p><p>As part of the walkout, employees will reportedly have a list of demands for Netflix, and Sarandos has been meeting them to hear their views. He said that while the company is &quot;deeply committed to inclusion,&quot; it&#39;s equally committed to &quot;supporting artistic freedom with the creators who work at Netflix.&quot; He added that Netflix would not add a disclaimer in front of the special as employees requested, reasoning that Chappelle himself gives a warning at the beginning.&nbsp;</p><p>Sarandos also addressed the issue of transparency in the company after an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-fires-employee-trans-leader-dave-chapelle-leak-204706894.html">employee was fired</a> for leaking internal company documents showing viewer figures for Netflix shows, including Chappelle&#39;s previous special. &quot;We’re deeply committed to the culture of transparency,&quot; he told <em>THR</em>. &quot;And it also depends upon a great deal of trust with our employees that we continue to secure, but we don’t plan on changing any of our internal operations around that.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-ceo-says-he-screwed-up-internal-communication-over-dave-chappelle-special-080412118.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">38d5c08d-dcec-4a4f-9808-cb98e96bc373</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 08:04:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634717054</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T08:04:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/13476990-3173-11ec-af4f-56e641bd9a60" width="4000" height="2665" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/13476990-3173-11ec-af4f-56e641bd9a60" width="4000" height="2665" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ROBYN BECK via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Netflix logo is seen on the Netflix, Inc. building on Sunset Boulevard in Los Angeles, California on October 19, 2021. - Netflix reported billion-dollar profits and booming subscriber growth on October 19 that beat forecasts as global hits like Squid Game drew viewers in droves. (Photo by Robyn Beck / AFP) (Photo by ROBYN BECK/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-NETFLIX-INTERNET-TELEVISION-EARNINGS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix says 142 million households watched Korean series 'Squid Game']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-19/netflix-says-142-million-households-watched-squid-game?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>, Netflix&#39;s pre-recorded call to shareholders announcing its third-quarter results gives us another glimpse at how successful <a href="https://www.engadget.com/squid-game-documents-reveal-how-netflix-considers-a-show-successful-081058871.html"><em>Squid Game</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>was. Around 142 million households worldwide watched the Korean-language show about debt—ridden individuals playing a deadly game for a cash prize worth tens of millions of dollars. That makes it the most-viewed new show in Netflix history, the publication said.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Squid Game</em> captured the &quot;cultural zeitgeist&quot; and claimed the number 1 spot in the streaming giant&#39;s rankings in 94 countries, including the US, Netflix has revealed. Since there&#39;s a huge demand for all things <em>Squid Game</em>, Netflix has also announced that consumer products based on the show are now on their way to retail.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A few days ago, <em>Bloomberg</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/squid-game-documents-reveal-how-netflix-considers-a-show-successful-081058871.html">obtained</a> documents detailing the company&#39;s scores for &quot;impact value&quot; and &quot;efficiency.&quot; Netflix has been pretty secretive on the metrics that make a title successful or not, and the documents showed how it measures series&#39; and movies&#39; success. <em>Squid Game</em> was a standout, generating $891.1 million in impact value, which is around 41.7 times — that&#39;s its efficiency score — its budget of $21.4 million.</p><p>Thanks in part to <em>Squid Game&#39;s</em> massive viewership, Netflix said it <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-19/netflix-tops-third-quarter-subscriber-views-sees-upbeat-fourth?sref=10lNAhZ9">posted</a> its best subscriber growth of the year. &quot;As the quarter continued, we saw an acceleration in our growth,&quot; Chief Financial Officer Spencer Neumann said on the call. It welcomed 4.38 million subscribers in the third quarter, mostly from Asia and Europe, and it expects to get 8.5 million more customers in the final quarter of 2021.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-142-million-households-squid-game-070044407.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8cf88ebe-4265-412f-b99d-ba25e9306c3d</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634713262</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T07:01:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/56f23ba0-316b-11ec-bcbd-9019801c1a29" width="1600" height="987" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/56f23ba0-316b-11ec-bcbd-9019801c1a29" width="1600" height="987" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Squid Game (Netflix)]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook is reportedly changing its name]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook is rebranding and changing its company name as soon as next week, according to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"><em>The Verge</em></a>. Apparently, the social media giant will have a new name that will reflect its focus on creating a metaverse. It&#39;s also possibly connected to its unreleased social virtual reality world called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-25-oculus-social-vr-world-facebook-horizon.html">Horizon Worlds</a>. The social network itself will likely retain the Facebook branding and will be under a new parent company, along with Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus. That would be similar to what <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-10-02-google-alphabet-restructuring.html">Google did in 2015</a> when it put its various projects and divisions, along with itself, under its parent company Alphabet.</p><p><em>The Verge</em> says the name change is a closely guarded secret at the moment and not even all senior leaders have knowledge about it. Mark Zuckerberg has long talked about wanting to make Facebook a metaverse company and has been taking steps towards that goal. Earlier this year, Facebook <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q2-2021-earnings-214311750.html">formed</a> a team dedicated to building a metaverse, and just a few days ago, it talked about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-europe-jobs-metaverse-220103694.html">adding</a> 10,000 &quot;high-skilled&quot; jobs across the European Union over the next five years to build its virtual and augmented reality experiences. It also released the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-smart-glasses-ar-160006477.html">Ray-Ban Stories</a> augmented reality smart glasses in September.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>We reached out to Facebook for a statement, and company spokesperson Joe Osborne said: &quot;We don’t comment on rumor or speculation.&quot;</p><p>It&#39;s unclear how long Facebook been has planning on changing its name, but it&#39;s almost certainly hoping it&#39;ll serve as a distraction from the investigations it&#39;s facing and the recent flood of bad press. Former executive-turned-whisleblower Frances Haugen provided the Congress and the Securities and Exchange Commission with a treasure trove of internal documents, dropped several revelations about the company and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html">accused</a> it of choosing &quot;profit over safety&quot; — something Zuckerberg adamantly <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mark-zuckerberg-denies-facebook-profit-over-safety-033717690.html">denied</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>In early October, she <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-senate-hearing-161557412.html">testified</a> at a Senate hearing about research she says proves that the social network repeatedly lied about its platform, including the &quot;efficacy of its artificial intelligence systems, and its role in spreading divisive and extreme messages.&quot; Haugen has several ideas on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-said-should-change-143051354.html">what Facebook should change</a>, but none of them has anything to do with changing its name. They include going back to chronological feeds from algorithmic ranking, adding some features that would prevent the spread of misinformation and opening Facebook research to people outside the company.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-reportedly-changing-name-042958266.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">25673060-7e38-46cf-b319-0593ca45c581</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 04:29:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634737720</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T13:48:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-06/4d5a7330-a5d2-11ea-a75e-1683395fdf3b" width="3132" height="2310" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2020-06/4d5a7330-a5d2-11ea-a75e-1683395fdf3b" width="3132" height="2310" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anadolu Agency via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[MUNICH, GERMANY - FEBRUARY 15: Founder and CEO of Facebook Mark Zuckerberg makes a speech as he attends the 56th Munich Security Conference at Bayerischer Hof Hotel in Munich, Germany on February 15, 2020. (Photo by Abdulhamid Hosbas/Anadolu Agency via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[56th Munich Security Conference]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roland's free mobile studio app helps you record fresh ideas]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The inspiration for a song can surface whether or not your full studio is available, and Roland has a solution for those spur-of-the-moment sessions. The music pioneer has <a href="https://www.roland.com/global/products/rc_zentracker/">introduced</a> a free Zentracker app for Android and iOS that serves as a multitrack recorder for impromptu performances. You can add unlimited tracks (it defaults to four in the name of simplicity), draw on 200 audio loops and wield 16 audio effects while using familiar features like beat matching and looping.</p><p>You can save tracks to OneDrive, and Google Drive is &quot;coming soon.&quot; The app is free as long as you have a Roland account, although Roland nudges you toward a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roland-slashes-the-starting-price-of-its-cloud-synth-subscriptions-070036849.html">Cloud subscription</a> by limiting some effects, loop bundles, stem exports and other features to paying customers. You&#39;ll likely want a mixer like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rolands-go-mixer-pro-x-studio-in-your-pocket-160021589.html">Go: Mixer Pro-X</a> to make the most of Zentracker, too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There&#39;s an app for more formal productions. Roland is releasing a TR-Editor desktop app (below) that serves as a companion for machines like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roland-tr-6-s-review-classic-drum-machines-808-909-portable-143001780.html">TR-6S</a> and TR-8S. You can browse sounds, program beats and tweak parameters from the comfort of your computer screen. While we&#39;re waiting on launch details as we write this, the software could be handy if you find the TR-series&#39; on-device interface too cumbersome.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f4658f50-311a-11ec-935f-2c91b75a41b1" style="height:1280;width:1920;" alt="Roland TR-Editor app on a Mac" data-uuid="3511e449-aadd-3efe-a32a-8ba3bece3589"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Roland</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roland-zentracker-app-tr-editor-000059079.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a08d3359-37a8-4399-897d-17a6038385b8</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634675561</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T20:32:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4544a190-3116-11ec-8ff8-991efc607628" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/4544a190-3116-11ec-8ff8-991efc607628" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roland]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roland Zentracker music recording app for iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roland Zentracker music recording app for iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Flight Simulator: GOTY Edition' adds new aircraft and locations on November 18th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft is spicing up <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-azure-ai-machine-learning-193545436.html"><em>Flight Simulator</em></a> with an expanded re-release, although this one may be more ambitious than some. It&#39;s <a href="https://www.flightsimulator.com/coming-soon-microsoft-flight-simulator-game-of-the-year-edition/">releasing</a><em>Flight Simulator: Game of the Year Edition</em> on November 18th with both a heaping of new content as well as some meaningful feature upgrades. To start, there are five new stand-out aircraft, including the F/A-18 Super Hornet — you won&#39;t have to wait until the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-top-gun-maverick-expansion-delayed-173042478.html">Top Gun expansion</a> to buzz the tower in a fighter jet. You&#39;ll also get to fly the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volocopter-reservations-first-electric-air-taxi-flights-183426570.html">VoloCity air taxi</a>, PC-6 Porter short-takeoff aircraft, the bush flying-oriented NX Cub and the single-seat Aviat Pitts Special S1S.</p><p>The GOTY upgrade adds eight airports, including Marine Corps Air Station Miramar and Patrick Space Force Base. Eight cities will get photogrammetry detail upgrades, such as Helsinki, Nottinghm and Utrecht. There are accordingly new tutorials (such as bush flying and IFR) and Discovery Flights.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The update adds useful features, too. You&#39;ll have early access to DirectX 12 features, an improved weather system and a developer mode replay system, among other improvements.</p><p>Most notably, you won&#39;t have to pay for any of this as a veteran player— existing <em>Flight Simulator</em> owners will receive a free update on both Windows PCs and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-x-review-microsoft-140045437.html">Xbox Series X</a>/<a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-s-review-140027758.html">S</a>. The paid GOTY release exists chiefly to entice first-timers. For everyone else, this is billed as a &quot;thank you&quot; upgrade that could keep them coming back.</p><div id="e1936386a92e41f1ba29a84c26fc2c31"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x2C3d4pMo40?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-game-of-the-year-edition-release-date-221249927.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4b92a3e9-b007-42bd-b0bb-c4ac3557fc1f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 22:12:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634732703</ingested><modified>2021-10-20T12:25:15+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ebd8f680-311d-11ec-bd7e-2a1982013ee3" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ebd8f680-311d-11ec-bd7e-2a1982013ee3" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Aviat Pitts S1S in Microsoft 'Flight Simulator: Game of the Year Edition']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Aviat Pitts S1S in Microsoft 'Flight Simulator: Game of the Year Edition']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook announces ‘small pilot’ to test cryptocurrency wallet Novi]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook is finally testing Novi, the digital wallet it’s been teasing for more than <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-18-facebook-calibra-libra-cryptocurrency-digital-wallet.html">two years</a>. Facebook’s payments chief David Marcus <a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1450447439341580293">announced</a> that the company is <a href="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t39.2365-6/245645778_229514682497390_5814575696636412345_n.pdf?_nc_cat=102&amp;ccb=1-5&amp;_nc_sid=ad8a9d&amp;_nc_ohc=vMfQUa02-cIAX9uoMQW&amp;_nc_ht=scontent.xx&amp;oh=6f6a46ed0214fe4d18fc02ff0c03b44f&amp;oe=61744796">launching</a> “a small pilot” of Novi in the United States and Guatemala with the goal of enabling family members to send remittances across borders.</p><p>“We’re doing a pilot to test core feature functions, and our operational capabilities in customer care and compliance,” Marcus wrote. “We’re also hopeful this will demonstrate a new stablecoin use case (as a payments instrument) beyond how they are typically used today.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The fact that Novi is finally launching, even in a limited way, would seem like significant step forward for Facebook’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-libra-changes-190011623.html">long-troubled</a> crypto plans. However, the company is launching the wallet without Diem, its planned cryptocurrency (previously called Libra) that’s faced a wave <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-diem-association-us-111008891.html">of pushback</a> from lawmakers and regulators around the world.</p><div id="97216150c5414c92983d9f98a21767d4"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re doing a pilot to test core feature functions, and our operational capabilities in customer care and compliance. We’re also hopeful this will demonstrate a new stablecoin use case (as a payments instrument) beyond how they are typically used today. 2/8</p>— David Marcus (@davidmarcus) <a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1450447440339877889?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 19, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Instead, the initial pilot will use the Pax Dollar (USDP), a stablecoin that Marcus said has “been operating successfully for over three years and has important regulatory and consumer protection attributes.” He added that Facebook has partnered with Coinbase during the pilot.</p><p>News of the pilot has already sparked renewed criticism from lawmakers. On Tuesday, hours after Marcus’ initial announcement, a group of five Democratic senators <a href="https://www.schatz.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/schatz_et_al_letter_to_facebook_on_diem.pdf">sent a letter</a> to Facebook asking the company “to immediately discontinue your Novi pilot and to commit that you will not bring Diem to market.” The letter cited the recent disclosures from a Facebook <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-senate-hearing-161557412.html">whistleblower</a>, and the company’s “relentless pursuit of profits at the expense of its users.”</p><p>“Given the scope of the scandals surrounding your company, we write to voice our strongest opposition to Facebook’s revived effort to launch a cryptocurrency and digital wallet, now branded ‘Diem’ and ‘Novi,’ respectively,” the senators wrote. “Facebook cannot be trusted to manage a payment system or digital currency when its existing ability to manage risks and keep consumers safe has proven wholly insufficient.”</p><div id="d5dd5ac1bf124e9da6dc60b3ea360db6"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Beyond the pilot, our business model is clear. We’re a challenger in payments. We’ll offer free person-to-person payments using Novi. Once we have a solid customer base, we’ll offer cheaper merchant payments and make a profit on merchant services. 6/8</p>— David Marcus (@davidmarcus) <a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1450447444379013122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 19, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>A spokesperson for Novi said that “we look forward to responding to the Committee’s letter,” but didn&#39;t elaborate. In his initial announcement, Marcus said the company remains committed to launching Diem. “I do want to be clear that our support for Diem hasn’t changed and we intend to launch Novi with Diem once it receives regulatory approval and goes live,” he wrote.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-will-test-cryptocurrency-wallet-novi-in-small-pilot-210320677.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">070d03e6-f53c-426b-9f37-f1394b5b157d</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 21:03:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634677309</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T21:02:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c74516e0-3119-11ec-8d7d-1d2026e14e74" width="4909" height="3102" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c74516e0-3119-11ec-8d7d-1d2026e14e74" width="4909" height="3102" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anadolu Agency via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ANKARA, TURKEY -  MAY 27: In this illustration photo, the logo of "Novi" is displayed on a smartphone as "Facebook" logo is seen behind, in Ankara, Turkey on May 27, 2020. (Photo by Hakan Nural/Anadolu Agency via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook and Novi]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook settles with Justice Department over H-1B hiring practices]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook has reached <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-labor-departments-reach-settlements-facebook-resolving-claims-discrimination-against">separate settlements</a> with the Department of Justice and Department of Labor over its hiring practices related to foreign workers. The settlements <a href="https://www.engadget.com/justice-department-sues-facebook-h1b-visas-205126525.html">stem from allegations</a> the Trump administration brought against Facebook in late 2020. At the time, the DoJ said the company had “inadequately advertised” at least 2,600 positions between 2018 and 2019 that were eventually filled by workers on H-1B visas.</p><p>The company allegedly employed a recruitment process that was intentionally designed to dissuade US workers from applying for positions it had set aside for temporary visa holders. Under the DoJ settlement, Facebook will pay $4.75 million to the federal government and up to $9.5 million to eligible victims.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>​​“While we strongly believe we met the federal government’s standards in our permanent labor certification (PERM) practices, we’ve reached agreements to end the ongoing litigation and move forward with our PERM program, which is an important part of our overall immigration program,&quot; a spokesperson for Facebook said. &quot;These resolutions will enable us to continue our focus on hiring the best builders from both the US and around the world, and supporting our internal community of highly skilled visa holders who are seeking permanent residence.”</p><p>The fines, while a drop in the ocean for a company like Facebook, represent the largest such penalties the Department of Justice has enforced as part of the Immigration and Nationality Act. More significantly, they&#39;re another piece of bad news for a company that has been mired in it in recent weeks. At the start of October, whistleblower<a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-said-should-change-143051354.html"> Frances Haugen</a> testified before Congress how Facebook’s algorithms have hampered its efforts to slow misinformation on its platforms. The company has also faced increasing scrutiny over its efforts to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-mental-health-senate-hearing-210317155.html">downplay internal research</a> that shows its platforms can be harmful to some young users.</p><p><strong>Update 5:03PM ET</strong>: Added comment from Facebook.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-doj-worker-settlement-201346028.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ba781b46-9293-431f-878e-c26c961f02b7</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 20:13:46 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634677509</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T21:05:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/bce6bd90-3117-11ec-ae5e-8ce4372ae293" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/bce6bd90-3117-11ec-ae5e-8ce4372ae293" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[s-cphoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Istanbul, Turkey - October 5, 2021: Social media applications icons on the mobile device screen. Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Social Media Applications]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Volvo’s new in-car app squeezes every last mile out of your EV’s battery]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many electric car drivers are aware of tricks to wring every last drop of range from their cars, but Volvo thinks it can take that load off people&#39;s shoulders. It&#39;s <a href="https://www.media.volvocars.com/us/en-us/media/pressreleases/289321/optimise-the-range-of-your-fully-electric-volvo-with-new-range-assistant-app-in-latest-over-the-air">updating</a> Volvo <a href="https://about.polestar.com/news/being-outdated-is-outdated-new-ota-updates-for-polestar-2">and Polestar</a> EVs with a Range Assistant app that both helps you make smart choices and, in one case, makes the decisions itself. The app can automatically tweak the climate control system to extend your range at the (slight) expense of comfort.</p><p>The update is rolling out now to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-16-volvo-xc40-ev-unveil.html">XC40 Recharge</a>, and will be coming to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/for-polestar-the-twos-are-anything-but-terrible-130059155.html">Polestar 2</a>. All compatible EVs should have the update by the end of October. And don&#39;t worry if you&#39;re eyeing a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volvos-c-40-recharge-knocks-the-ass-off-its-xc-40-predecessor-and-we-love-them-for-it-163057786.html">C40 Recharge</a> — that coupe-like SUV will include the Range Assistant from the start. Future updates should add driver coaching on driving habits and speed, among other tweaks.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You probably won&#39;t need this app if you&#39;re a seasoned EV driver. You&#39;ll know enough to turn the AC off, stick to speed limits and avoid mashing the throttle. However, this could be vital as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/new-york-law-ban-gas-powered-car-sales-2035-053554406.html">EVs enter the mainstream</a>. Newcomers might not need to spend as much time learning the ropes (and charging their cars)  as their predecessors.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/volvo-polestar-range-assistant-optimizer-194501187.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d9f6589e-2b79-481a-9bdc-23bdb4f39c3f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634672169</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T19:36:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/df8e9790-310e-11ec-bbfb-e011332d0466" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/df8e9790-310e-11ec-bbfb-e011332d0466" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Volvo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Volvo Range Assistant app to optimize EV range]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Volvo Range Assistant app to optimize EV range]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here's everything Google announced at its Pixel 6 event]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="81795052da55438891637de2341f8f75"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4GM-Almtdos" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>Google may have announced the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-first-look-tensor-processor-better-cameras-160005582.html">August</a>, but we had to wait more than three months to get the full story on its latest phones. On Tuesday, the company did just that, detailing nearly every aspect of their design and software.&nbsp;</p><h2>Pixel 6 and 6 Pro</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8b6bac20-30eb-11ec-b8bb-a9b6d0525232" style="height:942;width:1600;" alt="Google Pixe 6 and Pixel 6 Pro" data-uuid="6510550a-c367-3e9d-84b2-8a465d15216f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Unsurprisingly, Google spent a lot of time talking about the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-price-specs-release-date-170039729-170024290.html">Pixel 6 and 6 Pro’s hardware</a>. There’s a lot to unpack between the two phones, but the most important thing you need to know about them is that they’ll start at $599 and $899. In the case of the Pixel 6, that means it’s $100 cheaper than last year’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5-review-camera-performance-battery-price-150051832.html">Pixel 5</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Headline features shared by both phones include Google’s eight-core <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-soc-pixel-6-chip-170059466.html"><ins>Tensor processor</ins></a>, a fresh new design, a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-camera-will-feature-larger-image-sensors-and-smarter-photo-editing-ai-171159356.html"><ins>rear camera array</ins></a> that includes a 50-megapixel main sensor and new security features courtesy of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-android-12-pixel-3-rollout-170031989.html"><ins>Android 12</ins></a> and the company’s Titan M2 chip. To that package the Pixel 6 Pro adds a 6.7-inch “waterfall” display with a dynamic 120Hz refresh rate, 12GB of RAM and a 48-megapixel telephoto camera with 4x optical zoom. With both phones, Google says you can expect more than 24 hours of usage on a single charge.</p><p>Both the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro are available to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-pre-order-google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-smartphones-173051481.html"><ins>pre-order today</ins></a>, with general availability to follow on October 28th. For more information on the phones, make sure to check out our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-hands-on-tensor-features-camera-specs-available-price-170038272.html"><ins>hands-on</ins></a>.</p><h2>Pixel Pass</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0e78bb60-2c4d-11ec-bcfc-ce631a8414bc" style="height:1083;width:1920;" alt="Google Pixel 6 in peach at an angle" data-uuid="0fcfa6ee-54cb-3102-8d66-d37a9dd1b865"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Alongside the new phones, Google will offer <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pass-subscription-170056831.html"><ins>Pixel Pass</ins></a>. The subscription includes a Pixel 6 or 6 Pro, an extended warranty, 200GB of Google One storage, Google Play Pass, YouTube Premium and YouTube Music Premium. It also comes with a device upgrade after two years. If you want a Pixel 6, the Pass costs $45 per month. It increases to $55 per month with the 6 Pro.</p><h2>AI and other features</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e90490e0-3109-11ec-bfff-a4ed6a61e937" style="height:1000;width:1600;" alt="Live Translate feature on Google Pixel 6" data-uuid="161d65a8-efa8-35bb-b9ea-c679d6792477"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Of course, hardware was only part of the story on Tuesday, and Google had just as much, if not more, to say about all the new software it’s built for its latest phones. One such feature is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-live-translate-ai-google-tensor-chip-174938971.html"><ins>Live Translate</ins></a>. With the help of its Tensor chip, the Pixel 6 can translate text as you type. It can do so almost instantaneously and without help from the cloud.</p><p>Google’s Tensor chip will also make Assistant more capable. If you need to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-assistant-call-hold-181236423.html"><ins>contact a call center</ins></a>, it will generate an automated on-screen menu so you don’t have to listen to the assistant on the other side.</p><p>On the security front, the Pixel 6 comes with a new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-security-hub-privacy-dashboard-180603530.html"><ins>dashboard</ins></a> that provides an at-a-glance overview of any issues you may need to address. For instance, it will identify potentially “harmful” apps, and prompt you to set a fingerprint or PIN to unlock your device.</p><p>Looking to other software feature, Snap is creating a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-quick-tap-to-snap-snapchat-180058754.html"><ins>Pixel 6-first shortcut</ins></a> that affords quick access to Snapchat’s camera mode. When taking photos, the Pixel 6 should also do a better job of capturing darker skin tones thanks to a feature called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-camera-skin-tone-inclusive-pixel-google-170212102.html"><ins>Real Tone</ins></a>. Google worked with a variety of experts to fine-tune its camera algorithms to ensure its cameras “work for everyone.”</p><p><em>Catch up on all the latest news from </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Pixel%206%20event"><em>Google&#39;s Pixel 6 event</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-event-2021-highlights-192245034.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8627302e-e37a-45ed-b003-d86b46504016</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:22:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634671367</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T19:23:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/91a42bf0-305d-11ec-9f9f-636d29742095" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/91a42bf0-305d-11ec-9f9f-636d29742095" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cherlynn Low / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Close up of the Pixel 6 Pro's camera bump.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Pixel 6 Pro camera]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[FDA proposes rule for over-the-counter hearing aids]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/fda/">Food and Drug Administration</a> is moving closer to making more affordable over-the-counter (OTC) hearing aids a reality for millions of Americans with mild or moderate hearing loss. The agency issued a <a href="https://public-inspection.federalregister.gov/2021-22473.pdf">proposal</a> to create a category of approved devices that people would be able to buy without a prescription, hearing exam or having to arrange a fitting with an audiologist.</p><p>&quot;The proposed rule is designed to help increase competition in the market while also ensuring the safety and effectiveness of OTC and prescription hearing aids,&quot; <a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-issues-landmark-proposal-improve-access-hearing-aid-technology-millions-americans">the FDA said</a>. Around 15 percent of adult Americans (some 37.5 million) have hearing difficulties, according to the agency.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The FDA&#39;s goal is to make it easier for those who could benefit from hearing aids to actually get one — it says only a fifth of people who fall into that category use such a device. The agency is hoping to tackle some of the barriers people might encounter, including cost, ease of access, social stigma and state and federal regulations.</p><p>In 2017, the federal government passed the Over-the-Counter Hearing Aid Act with the aim of improving access to more affordable hearing aids. Hearing aids have only available with a prescription as the FDA classed them as Class I or II medical devices. President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/09/executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">signed an executive order</a> in July that, in part, instructed the Secretary of Health and Human Services to publish a proposed rule for OTC hearing aids within 120 days.</p><p>The proposal is now open to a 90-day public comment period. If and when the rule is finalized, it will come into effect 60 days after it&#39;s published in the federal register.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-15-upgrade-your-hearing-with-technology.html">Several companies</a> have already made moves to gain a foothold in the OTC hearing aid market. Earlier this year, Bose <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bose-soundcontrol-hearing-aids-152746656.html">started selling</a> its SoundControl hearing aids after gaining approval from the FDA, while Jabra unveiled its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jabra-enhance-plus-earbuds-130001782.html">Enhance Plus earbuds</a> a couple of months ago. Other companies are blending hardware and tech in hearing aids, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-01-08-bragi-project-ears-hearing-aids-tinnitus.html">Bragi</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-05-olive-union-smart-ear-hands-on.html">Olive Union</a>.</p><p>Apple, meanwhile, recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-pro-conversation-boost-feature-175701382.html">updated AirPods Pro</a> with a feature that amplifies the volume of other people&#39;s voices in conversation while reducing ambient noise. The company is also said to be looking into ways of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-health-device-leak-132037664.html">using AirPods as health devices</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/fda-over-the-counter-hearing-aids-proposed-rule-190444627.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3e8a311e-ef0e-4a50-a3a4-83ecc6d70536</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:04:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634670287</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T19:04:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Government Agencies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Disease & Medical Conditions]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/796a7690-fb5e-11eb-bf57-dac88e198d8b" width="6048" height="4032" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/796a7690-fb5e-11eb-bf57-dac88e198d8b" width="6048" height="4032" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AlexRaths via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Doctor inserting hearing aid in man's ear]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Hearing Aid]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google turns those annoying call center menus into easy-to-navigate screens]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-6-pro-hands-on-tensor-features-camera-specs-available-price-170038272.html">Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro</a>, Google also released more details about new capabilities that its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-soc-pixel-6-chip-170059466.html">Tensor chip</a> enables. One of them is a much more intelligent way of handling those calls to businesses that sometimes have you waiting hours on end just to speak to a representative. Now, the Pixel will show you the current and projected wait times before you even place a call so you can call when it works for you.&nbsp;</p><p>Additionally, when you do call and encounter an endless list of options (like, &quot;Press 1 for branch location and hours&quot; if you&#39;re calling a bank), you don&#39;t need to remember all of them carefully. Instead, Google will listen to them for you and show the automated menu options on the screen for you to tap.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This is in addition to a &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/hold-for-me-duplex-pixel-5-4a-030330679.html">Hold For Me</a>&quot; feature Google introduced last year. Instead of having to stay on the line, Google Assistant will remain on the call for you. It understands the difference between a recorded message and an actual representative on the line. When a real life person is finally on, it&#39;ll alert you to take the call.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Catch up on all the latest news from </em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Pixel%206%20event"><em>Google&#39;s Pixel 6 event</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-assistant-call-hold-181236423.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">be6bea36-c869-4813-b118-30166c22dd12</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 18:12:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634668265</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T18:31:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/55089280-3107-11ec-bebf-87f16614f44d" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/55089280-3107-11ec-bebf-87f16614f44d" width="2000" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 event]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 event]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google shows off new security hub and privacy dashboard for Pixel 6]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google is ramping up its security and privacy features with the Pixel 6. The company showed off new security hub and privacy dashboard features that will make it easier to control important settings.</p><p>The security hub provides an at-a-glance overview of security settings, such as whether or not your phone has the latest security updates installed or if you’ve set a fingerprint or PIN to unlock your device. Importantly, it can also keep tabs on the apps you’ve installed and can identify ones that are potentially “harmful.” At the top of the security hub is an indicator that will alert users if any settings need attention. A green checkmark indicates all is well, while a yellow exclamation mark will appear if something needs to be addressed.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Google also showed off new indicators to make it easier to tell when an app is using the phone’s camera or microphone feeds. Much like the notifications in iOS, an indicator will light up at the top right corner of the display when the phone’s mic or camera feeds are in use, and users will have the ability to kill access for specific apps.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9896fec0-3106-11ec-bee7-ae7e0964532b" style="height:964;width:822;" alt="pixel 6 privacy dashboard" data-uuid="38a688f6-5f22-34f3-b054-6395e6a5215a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Likewise, the new privacy dashboard makes it easier to track which data apps have access to and how each app is using its permissions to access information like location data. As with the security hub, Google has previously made much of this information available within Android already, but it was often buried several layers into the settings menu, so having it all in a single dashboard should make it easier for most users to find.</p><p>Google also said it’s beefed up its anti-spam and phishing protection features, and Pixel 6 will be able to provide warnings when it detects potential shady phone calls, texts, emails and links.</p><p>It’s not yet clear if or when the company plans to bring these features to more devices than just its Pixel lineup. The company said during its event that the privacy dashboard and security hub would be “coming first” to Pixel, so the features could eventually make their way to more Android devices in the future.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pixel-6-security-hub-privacy-dashboard-180603530.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">76298033-6311-46d0-bbc1-096552b91d78</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 18:06:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634666764</ingested><modified>2021-10-19T18:06:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a20a1c70-3102-11ec-9dff-6025448e758a" width="1746" height="1002" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a20a1c70-3102-11ec-9dff-6025448e758a" width="1746" height="1002" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Pixel 6 Security Hub.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[pixel 6 security hub]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>