<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Security flaws at NFT marketplace OpenSea left users' crypto wallets open to attack]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After finding itself embroiled in a controversy over <a href="https://www.engadget.com/opensea-nate-chastain-nft-buying-incident-163044364.html">insider trading</a>, NFT marketplace OpenSea is getting some more bad press. The site had a critical security vulnerability that could have allowed hackers to steal users&#39; entire crypto wallets, according to security research firm Check Point Software.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Check Point said it first noticed reports of stolen crypto wallets triggered by airdropped NFTs, prompting the firm to investigate OpenSea. That revealed critical security discoveries &quot;that, if exploited, could have led hackers to hijack user accounts and steal entire crypto wallets of users, by sending malicious NFTs,&quot; the company said.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The attack relied on user inattention and the fact that OpenSea already generates a lot of pop-ups. If the victim received and viewed a malicious NFT sent by a hacker, it triggered a pop-up from OpenSea&#39;s storage domain, requesting a connection to the victim&#39;s cryptocurrency wallet. Clicking on the popup gave the hacker access to the wallet and allowed them to generate another popup. If the user also clicked on that without noticing a note describing the transaction, the attacker could theoretically steal all their money.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>It seemed that a lot of things needed to go wrong for the attack to work, and it&#39;s not clear if it was actively exploited. Check Point said it disclosed the vulnerability as soon as it found it, and OpenSea said it implemented a fix &quot;within an hour of it being brought to our attention.&quot; The company said it&#39;s &quot;doubling down on community education around security,&quot; by adding a blog series and taking other measures.&nbsp;</p><p>The security research firm said that given the rapid pace of innovation, &quot;there is an inherent challenge in securely integrating software applications and crypto markets.&quot; Bad actors are also drawn to crypto like wasps to <em>pain au chocolat</em>, so it&#39;s likely we&#39;ll hear about similar attacks in the near future.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/open-sea-vulnerability-exposed-crypto-wallets-to-attack-security-researchers-say-100028216.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">462e6101-7c8c-4890-bc68-0745484c031d</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634118971</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T09:56:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2d0bd7f0-124f-11ec-9d5b-406f59cf7dbc" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2d0bd7f0-124f-11ec-9d5b-406f59cf7dbc" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OpenSea logo displayed on a phone screen and representation of cryptocurrencies are seen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on August 26, 2021. (Photo by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[OpenSea Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bird will test sensors that prevent riding on sidewalks]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you live in a city where rideshare scooters are available, chances are you’ve had someone zip by on one while you were walking on the sidewalk. It’s an issue that local governments around the world have pushed mobility companies to address since day one. And after working on the problem since 2019, Bird thinks it has a solution.</p><p>Collaborating with a firm called <a href="https://www.u-blox.com/en"><ins>U-blox</ins></a>, the company has developed a custom multi-sensor and GPS module it says is far more accurate than other solutions at detecting when someone drives a scooter onto a sidewalk. When you drive a Bird scooter that’s equipped with the module onto a sidewalk, it will produce an audible sound and send a notification to your smartphone. The vehicle will also slowly and smoothly come to a stop.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Bird is testing the technology in Milwaukee and San Diego and plans to bring it to Madrid and other cities in the future.</p><p>For Bird, coming to this point has been a long journey. At one point, the company tried using AI-assisted cameras for sidewalk detection but found they presented two problems. One, they would have added a fragile component to a vehicle that’s already frequently <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2018/12/electric-scooter-bird-lime-lakes-rivers-environment-vandalism.html"><ins>vandalized</ins></a>. Two, training the machine learning software that would power those cameras would have proven difficult due to the ways road infrastructure in different countries can look. According to Bird, the advantage of its latest solution is that it’s a solution it can implement at scale without worrying about the weather or vandalism.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bird-u-blox-sidewalk-detection-module-100016730.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9e974cf8-bb2c-4056-8c5d-ae2e5dcf55d2</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634078502</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T22:41:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/853a4a60-2ba9-11ec-acff-fa76b34af919" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/853a4a60-2ba9-11ec-acff-fa76b34af919" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bird]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bird sidewalk detection]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bird sidewalk detection]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fujifilm launches its first wide-format Instax Link smartphone printer]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fujifilm has revealed a new Instax printer that supports its wider, more Polaroid-like film. The Instax Link Wide Smartphone printer is designed to connect to your smartphone over Bluetooth and print out camera roll photos that are twice as wide as the credit card-sized images from the original <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fujifilm-nintendo-switch-themed-instax-printer-121526585.html">Instax mini Link printer</a>. It also allows you to directly transfer and print images from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fujifilm-x-s10-hybrid-aps-c-mirrorless-camera-vloggers-filmmakers-photographers-140041562.html">Fujifilm&#39;s X-S10</a> mirrorless camera, with no need for a smartphone.&nbsp;</p><div id="14f70edbd2db4fe9ad21dddee27c30f4"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gOfpw50Oums?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>As before, the new printer runs on batteries and can do about 100 Instax prints on a charge. You can choose from two printing modes, &quot;Instax Rich, accentuating deep, warm colors, and Instax Natural, which emphasizes the inherent tones of the image,&quot; according to Fujifilm. You can also use the Instax Link app, which offers around 30 filters, collages, text, digital stickers and frame templates, while letting you import and add handwritten text and sketches to a photo.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Instax Link Wide Smartphone printer supports Fujifilm&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:wide-format film" href="https://amzn.to/3v5Xrk9">wide-format film</a>, which costs $20 for a pack of 10 — also used by its <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Instax 300 Wide" href="https://amzn.to/3lArAVC">Instax 300 Wide</a> camera. In addition, Fujifilm introduced a new black-bordered version of Instax Wide film, available at $22 for a ten-pack. The Instax Link Wide Smartphone Printer arrives later this month for $149.95</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/fujifilms-latest-instax-printer-can-handle-wider-photos-085523243.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5edc27d6-0982-4848-a2f7-fddd73dcb44e</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 08:55:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634114673</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T08:44:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/660b8760-2bfb-11ec-8ef5-6175896dc41d" width="1320" height="860" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/660b8760-2bfb-11ec-8ef5-6175896dc41d" width="1320" height="860" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Fujifilm's latest Instax Link printer outputs wide-format photos]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Fujifilm's latest Instax Link printer outputs wide-format photos]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix to start streaming 'Cowboy Bebop' anime on October 21st]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you want to re-watch the original <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> show before Netflix&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-cowboy-bebop-release-date-photos-152038789.html">live adaptation drops</a>, you don&#39;t  have to go to another streaming service. Netflix has acquired the global streaming rights for all 26 episodes of the anime, and they&#39;ll be available for streaming starting on October 21st, just a few weeks before the November 19th debut of the live series&#39; first season. The <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> anime first premiered in Japan in 1998 before making its way to the US via Adult Swim three years later. While it won&#39;t be available on Netflix until the 21st, it&#39;s currently streamable on Hulu.&nbsp;</p><div id="99b2582b99d64863b31b75a4e0cad915"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bang… COWBOY BEBOP, the original anime series, is coming to Netflix worldwide on October 21 <a href="https://t.co/BN3LF2XVSl">pic.twitter.com/BN3LF2XVSl</a></p>— Netflix Geeked (@NetflixGeeked) <a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1448060919595126787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>One might say that adding the anime to its catalogue before the live adaptation&#39;s debut is bold on Netflix&#39;s part, as it would make it easier to compare the two — especially since live anime adaptations haven&#39;t been typically well received. There&#39;s a way to merge the two shows if you think you&#39;d enjoy it that way a lot more, though.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>According to <a href="https://ew.com/tv/cowboy-bebop-anime-comes-to-netflix/"><em>Entertainment Weekly</em></a>, the anime&#39;s original voice actors are reprising their roles for the Japanese dub of the live action series. They include Koichi Yamadera as Spike, Taiten Kusunoki as Jet and Megumi Hayashibara as Faye. It&#39;s also worth noting that original composer Yoko Kanno and original director Shinichirō Watanabe are both involved in the Netflix show. The live action adaptation stars John Cho as Spike, Mustafa Shakir as Jet Black and Daniella Pineda as Faye Valentine. And, of course, an adorable corgi as Ein.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-cowboy-bebop-anime-october-21st-074528313.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a419663b-469e-4b22-90a4-57de71dc0b71</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 07:45:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634109157</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T07:12:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/61da4980-2bea-11ec-bd7e-86040e409257" width="1600" height="1065" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/61da4980-2bea-11ec-bd7e-86040e409257" width="1600" height="1065" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cowboy Bebop]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Cowboy Bebop]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Cowboy Bebop]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roland SP-404MKII hands-on: Dragging an iconic sampler into the modern age]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<div id="0b00a59068564a11b0a71049c8c6f067"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/elUwYqp8crA" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>The Boss and Roland line of SP samplers (specifically the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-07-koala-sampler.html">SP-303</a> and SP-404) are some of the most important instruments in hip hop history. Right up there with the MPC and the Technics SL-1200. They’ve been used by the likes of MF Doom, Madlib and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-07-21-hip-hop-producer-j-dillas-beat-making-gear-headed-to-smithsonia.html">J Dilla</a>, and are a favorite among lo-fi hip hop artists everywhere. They’ve also been used by plenty of other musicians like Panda Bear, Four Tet, Oneohtrix Point Never and even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/radiohead-and-epic-games-team-up-for-the-kid-a-mnesia-exhibit-215738766.html">Radiohead</a>. But, the original SP-404 was released in 2005. And even though it was succeeded by the 404SX and the 404A, those were extremely minor updates that did things like switch from the aging and slow CF Card format to SD. The new SP-404MKII, though, finally updates the classic sampler for the modern age without sacrificing what made the OG so alluring.</p><p>Physically, the 404MKII is very similar to past versions of the 404. There are four knobs across the top; a circular window below them, flanked by six effects buttons; and pads on the bottom for triggering samples. The MKII does look better than the A, at least. The 404A was designed to fit in with the rest of Roland’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-11-08-roland-system-8-review.html">AIRA</a> line — that means stark black accented with garish red and green. It’s… a look. But not one that everyone (myself included) can get behind. The new version is a much more subdued gray and black, with white and muted orange accents.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e655dc22-2b99-11ec-bd2e-300f8eed39bb" style="height:1126;width:2000;" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="297f989a-8c44-35bc-af54-931097124bc6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>Beyond pure aesthetics, though, there are some huge upgrades in the MKII. The two most obvious differences are the detailed OLED screen that has replaced the old-school seven-segment LEDs, and the move from a 12-pad layout to a 16-pad one.</p><p>The screen represents the biggest change to the SP experience. Editing samples on an OG 404 could be painful. The three-digit LEDs gave you only generic start and end points, and because of the high resolution needed to create perfect loops, the range was very small. That would lead to having to crop a sample multiple times to take off all the excess. The OLED on the SP-404MKII is high enough resolution to show the actual waveform as it’s being edited. You can zoom in and out as needed to crop as little or as much as you want. I would go as far as to say that recording and editing samples on the MKII is not only easier, but actually kinda fun.</p><p>The 16 pads give you access to more samples and patterns to construct your beats out of. Also, the four-by-four grid has become something of a standard. It’s the layout used by Akai on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/akai-mpc-live-ii-review-153032772.html">MPC</a>, on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-01-serato-pioneer-ddj-xp2.html">Pioneer’s DJ gear</a>, on the Native Instruments <a href="https://www.engadget.com/maschine-plus-native-instruments-virtual-instruments-groovebox-155725975.html">Maschine</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ableton-live-11-daw-hands-on-review-upgrades-explained-160047192.html">Ableton’s</a> Drum Rack and even some of the larger members of the SP family like the 808 and the 606.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6381af1-2b99-11ec-aef9-bb59674b367a" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="d7915590-1719-3af6-80e1-0e4a1b635278"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>There are other more subtle changes as well. For one, those 16 pads on the front are all velocity sensitive, a first for the SP line. That said, it’s almost impossible to get full velocity out of them without just turning on fixed velocity. Some finger drummers especially may prefer to turn fixed velocity on to keep melodic and percussion elements consistently mixed, but it can also leave things sounding a bit robotic and unnatural. Just something to keep in mind.</p><p>Roland added MIDI out to the back of the SP-404MKII as well. The previous versions had MIDI IN only. Now the 404 can be used to sequence external gear, or even be hooked up to a PC to control your DAW via USB-C. That makes the 16-pad layout even more important, because it’ll map better to whatever you’re connecting it to most likely. Oh. and that USB port can also be used to stream audio to your PC.</p><p>This also marks the first time that Roland has ditched RCA in favor of ¼-inch jacks for the audio ins and outs on an SP. Now, this is a net positive but there is a down side. Often an SP is being used to sample directly from vinyl and most turntables use RCA. That means there will be an intermediary step to getting loops from a record to the 404. But, it does make it easier to sample directly from an instrument. Synths, drum machines, guitars and basses all generally use ¼-inch plugs. And, since the ins and outs on the MKII are balanced, it should be less susceptible to noise and interference.</p><section data-eng-breakout="0ff984f5f11048709b8c78139a78d03f" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e655dc24-2b99-11ec-bfcb-c7d1b2efe790" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="938f5c57-bcf6-3c80-a222-160f15355e8e"></section><p>In addition to the ins and outs around back, there’s a pair of headphone jacks on the front (one ⅛-inch, and one ¼-inch) and a ¼-inch audio input. That jack is switchable from mic to “guitar” or instrument level signals. You can feed audio through the SP-404MKII live so you can use it as a submixer and jam or sing along to your creations. And there are a host of input effects tailored specifically for that application. There’s a pretty decent guitar amp sim that covers everything from clean funk to thrash metal, an auto pitch correction effect, and a vocoder. For the latter, you can connect a MIDI keyboard to play chords and melodies.</p><p>In general, the MKII offers a lot more in the effects department than past models. In addition to the input effects, there’s a pair of bus effects. You can apply one, both or neither to each pad. Put a compressor on your drums, EQ on your bass and both on your rhodes if you want. And there are a pair of background effects, too.</p><p>If you dive into the settings you’ll find Bus 3 and 4 where you can apply master effects. In that same menu is where you can also customize the “direct” effects that are assigned to the six buttons around the display. So, for example, if you don’t like or use the resonator, you can swap in the new cassette simulator, which is what I did. (Though the button will continue to be labeled “resonator” no matter what you do.)</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6320071-2b99-11ec-8a36-5ec440d23b13" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="1e39058d-425f-382f-83e1-4889248b8032"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>The selection of effects is pretty large, too, and it definitely leans into the lo-fi vibe that SP users are generally looking for. In addition to the new cassette simulator (which has a cute, but questionably useful catch feature that simulates the tape getting stuck momentarily), there’s also a lo-fi effect, a bit crusher and the vinyl simulator from both the 303 and the 404. Many SP users swear by the 303 simulator, and I can’t say I blame them. The 404 version is just a bit too extreme and the noise is too constant and frankly kind of annoying even at low levels. The 303 version, however, is amazing.</p><p>If there’s one complaint I have about the effects, it’s that none of them are really subtle. The filter + drive, for example, is great and one of the many things people make heavy use of on the 404, but the drive is <em>intense</em>. Even on one it makes a huge difference in the sound of a loop. And by 10 it’s already introducing ringing feedback. By 100 it’s just noise. (Not that that’s necessarily a bad thing.)</p><p>One of the things that people really like to use those effects for is resampling beats and even mixing down full tracks to individual pads. (That’s how strong the appeal of the 303 vinyl sim and compressor are.) You can even use the MKII’s new DJ mode to blend between two beats while applying those effects. That said, I haven’t really put this through its paces.</p><section data-eng-breakout="55f5fb9fff58424db54b4aaae31f4da3" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6320074-2b99-11ec-b4fa-1fd82d97c78c" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="535464b7-beeb-325b-932f-bb1ac3fd4729"></section><p>Resampling is also incredibly easy. For one, there’s a clearly labeled resample button, which the original 404 had as well, so it was never particularly unintuitive. But there’s also now a Skip Back feature (though, you have to assign the subpad to in the utility menu), which recalls the last 25 seconds of audio performed either on the device or from the inputs and saves it to a pad. This is great for capturing live performance and moments of inadvertent genius.</p><p>And you can capture those moments anywhere you want basically. While the 404 isn’t exactly the smallest device in the world, it fits in a bag easily enough. And you can still power it with six AA batteries like previous models. And just like the previous versions the SP-404MKII is affordable. In fact, Roland cut the price by $50 so a brand new SP will only set you back $500 when it goes on sale in November.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6486ea0-2b99-11ec-be2f-b91eba36b642" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="2d6a757f-bbb8-3e29-965d-25fb8387630a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Terrence O&#39;Brien / Engadget</div></figure><p>That makes it a perfectly reasonable purchase for a first-time producer or someone  looking to dabble in sampling. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/circuit-rhythm-review-a-solid-and-affordable-sampler-groovebox-130026004.html">Novation Circuit Rhythm</a> is $100 cheaper, but I think the effects on the SP are better and the screen makes for a much more pleasant chopping experience. Honestly, the screen alone is probably worth the extra hundred bucks.</p><p>There are even more affordable options like the Elektron Model:Samples, but you can’t actually record and edit samples on that, only play them back. And there are no standalone MPCs in this price range. The $799 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-15-akai-mpc-one-sampler-beat-production-namm.html">MPC One</a> is the cheapest member of the family, but it’s also a lot more complex than all these other devices; it’s closer to a DAW in a box than a sampler.</p><p>One thing those all have over the SP, though, is a step sequencer. That probably isn’t a huge deal to most people already eyeing a 404. But it’s something to keep in mind if rhythm isn’t your strong suit.</p><section data-eng-breakout="1580557368ae4106afa33d05aa3e6f07" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6381af3-2b99-11ec-a96b-1b6753d883d8" alt="Roland SP-404MKII" data-uuid="98823b59-5c90-3622-960e-f3b2e72ae3db"></section><p>Considering that I’ve had it for less than a week and this is my first time using an SP device, I’m hesitant to call this a proper review and slap a score on it. But the SP-404MKII is undeniably fun to use and it’s quickly becoming my favorite entry-level sampler.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roland-sp-404-mkii-hands-on-dragging-an-iconic-sampler-into-the-modern-age-070043439.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f792e4e5-926b-463d-8c7e-ebda70f98844</guid><dc:creator>Terrence O&amp;#39;Brien</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 07:00:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634100151</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T04:42:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Terrence O&#39;Brien]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6475d32-2b99-11ec-bff9-2850785fbfaf" width="2000" height="1126" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e655dc21-2b99-11ec-bffb-83a8c34ddafd" width="2000" height="1126" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Terrence O'Brien / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Roland SP-404MKII]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Roland SP-404MKII]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bowers & Wilkins' new Zeppelin speaker was built for streaming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bowers &amp; Wilkins has launched a new version of its iconic <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-10-08-bowers-and-wilkins-zeppelin-wireless.html">Zeppelin speaker</a>, and the company says it was re-imagined for the streaming age. The audio device manufacturer describes the <a href="https://www.bowerswilkins.com/new-zeppelin">new Zeppelin</a> as &quot;smarter and more flexible&quot; than its predecessors, with built-in support for Amazon&#39;s Alexa voice assistant, so users can simply ask it to play whatever they want instead of using its physical buttons. In addition, B&amp;W plans to give it multi-room capability in early 2022 through a software update. Once that arrives, users will be able to link several Zeppelins together or link a Zeppelin with other B&amp;W speakers in a multi-room environment.&nbsp;</p><p>For now, the new model supports AirPlay 2 and aptX Adaptive Bluetooth to give both iOS and Android users an easy way to stream audio from their devices. Like the previous version, it features Spotify Connect and can be controlled using the Bowers &amp; Wilkins app, which gives it access to more streaming services like Deezer, Soundcloud and TIDAL.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The new Zeppelin comes with two Decoupled Double-Dome tweeters mounted at the far edges for &quot;a wide, spacious and highly accurate sound.&quot; Plus, it has a new 150mm subwoofer for a deep, detailed bass. The 2021 model will be available starting today in Midnight Grey or Pearl Grey from retailers or from the <a href="https://www.bowerswilkins.com/new-zeppelin">company&#39;s website</a>. As potential buyers probably already expect, the high-end speaker won&#39;t come cheap: It&#39;ll set them back $799, which is $100 more than the previous version&#39;s debut price.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bowers-wilkins-new-zeppelin-speaker-070023824.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5f96f808-e039-49a5-b81c-efa8a080708a</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 07:00:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634108369</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T06:59:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f4c23870-2bef-11ec-ae9a-8ccab49ca5e7" width="1600" height="959" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f4c23870-2bef-11ec-ae9a-8ccab49ca5e7" width="1600" height="959" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bowers and Wilkins]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bowers and Wilkins Zeppelin]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bowers and Wilkins Zeppelin]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HTC Vive Flow headset images leak days before reported launch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>HTC is expected to launch a new VR headset within the week, but you don&#39;t have to wait till then to see what it looks like. A collection of Vive Flow images has made its way online, courtesy of <a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1448050993158033412">evleaks</a>, before the launch event. According to <a href="https://www.protocol.com/htc-flow-hue-viveport-verse"><em>Protocol</em></a>, the Vive Flow is a lightweight headset developed for consumers under the internal name &quot;Hue.&quot; The Bluetooth SIG consortium previously <a href="https://launchstudio.bluetooth.com/ListingDetails/137357">published</a> documents describing Hue as a VR AIO (all-in-one) product, which means the device could be a standalone headset that doesn&#39;t need a phone or doesn&#39;t have to be tethered to a PC to work.&nbsp;</p><div id="867a62f427d642a1933ebad1ded24cff"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/OPfdwSQTYt">pic.twitter.com/OPfdwSQTYt</a></p>— E (@evleaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1448058069779423233?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The company reportedly wants to position the Vive Flow primarily as a way to consume media, with some access to gaming. Its chip is less powerful than the Oculus Quest 2&#39;s, <em>Protocol</em> says, but it will have six degrees of freedom tracking. The images leaked online also show more information about the device, including a dual-hinge system to make sure it fits most people, snap-on face cushion, immersive spatial audio, adjustable lenses and active cooling system. After you pair your phone with it via Bluetooth, you can use your mobile device as a VR controller and to stream content to VR using Miracast tech.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="a250fc79f7e84928a7b1d2cd69a1e842"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/NutC8vPZhc">pic.twitter.com/NutC8vPZhc</a></p>— E (@evleaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1448090419452121097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>In addition, the images show that the Vive Flow will be available for pre-order starting on October 15th, with shipments going out in early November. The headset will set you back US$499, which is $200 more than the Quest 2&#39;s launch price, and you&#39;ll get seven free virtual reality content  and a carrying case if you pre-order.</p><div id="f4be8927fd6e43c59b97dd2e65e6f379"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/T0m1YpM8iJ">pic.twitter.com/T0m1YpM8iJ</a></p>— E (@evleaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1448090431401693191?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/htc-vive-flow-headset-images-leak-050326367.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">67a74ffb-0b8e-4e1f-b421-9aa5e5450ab4</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 05:03:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634100876</ingested><modified>2021-10-13T04:54:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/353df300-2bda-11ec-9eee-235c6870125d" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/353df300-2bda-11ec-9eee-235c6870125d" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[HTC (via evleaks)]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HTC  Vive Flow]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[HTC  Vive Flow]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adobe is bringing Camera Raw editing to Photoshop on the iPad]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of its <a href="https://max.adobe.com/?gclid=Cj0KCQjwnoqLBhD4ARIsAL5JedKfdZW1vrGzuRWR-_jjyPQaLKLpKUVlI3pZJdJUR8_qQ66bCbIC5iYaAq9dEALw_wcB&amp;sdid=6S3T79DF&amp;mv=search&amp;ef_id=Cj0KCQjwnoqLBhD4ARIsAL5JedKfdZW1vrGzuRWR-_jjyPQaLKLpKUVlI3pZJdJUR8_qQ66bCbIC5iYaAq9dEALw_wcB:G:s&amp;s_kwcid=AL!3085!3!460768917051!e!!g!!adobe%20max!11001311421!107529819269"><ins>Max conference</ins></a> on October 26th, Adobe has shared a preview of a feature that’s coming to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-04-photoshop-on-ipad-now-available.html">Photoshop on the iPad</a>, and it’s a big one. You&#39;ll soon be able to use its Camera Raw tool to import RAW files from your camera to the iPad.&nbsp;</p><div id="8227014f5a6d4fd18d8d008699d68786"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mvpN-8Ve3TU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>You can use the tool to import any file format Camera Raw currently supports. That includes the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-12-pro-hdr-video-and-proraw-181421701.html">ProRAW</a> files that Apple iPhone 12 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro can output. Once you’ve loaded an image, you have access to all the usual adjustments you’ll find on the desktop version of Camera Raw, allowing you to tweaks things like the exposure and color of your photo.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>One nifty new feature is that it’s possible to import your RAW file as a Smart Object into Photoshop. That means you can add your image to a PSD, open the resulting file in Photoshop desktop and still have access to the embedded file and adjustments. Adobe says Camera Raw is coming to Photoshop on the iPad soon. In the meantime, we’ll likely see the company preview more upcoming features for its various apps at Adobe Max later this month.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/camera-raw-photoshop-ipad-035052237.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">288a011c-8fe1-4c5c-8c1c-2ce3a3615243</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 03:50:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634053978</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T15:53:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ec4be0d0-2b70-11ec-bfff-6d68302d6fa2" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/ec4be0d0-2b70-11ec-bfff-6d68302d6fa2" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[iPad Photoshop]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[iPad Photoshop]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung will hold another Unpacked event on October 20th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, Samsung has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-august-11-supercut-170007617.html">yet another Unpacked event</a> in store. The tech behemoth has announced that an Unpacked Part 2 presentation will take place on October 20th at 10AM Eastern. Samsung didn&#39;t offer many clues as to what it would unveil, but promised to show how the company was offering more chances at &quot;self-expression through technology.&quot; The teaser accordingly shows Samsung app icons (such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-health-qled-tv-smart-trainer-hands-on-160027517.html">Health</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-smartthings-energy-103514042.html">SmartThings</a>) being packaged in pastel-colored boxes.</p><p>Rumors haven&#39;t been much help. Leaks have suggested Samsung might introduce a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-leak-181207022.html">Galaxy S21 FE</a> that would bring <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-camera-samples-screen-specs-160033680.html">S21 features</a> to a more affordable phone, but it&#39;s not certain if that device will surface in 2021 — if it does at all. Samsung is increasingly reliant on mid-range handsets like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-hands-on-impressions-review-performance-camera-145018683.html">Galaxy A52</a>, and might not feel as much pressure to release an S21 FE when the A series offers a close-enough feature set.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As it stands, Samsung might focus its attention on software and services. The company has been eager to expand platforms like Health, and this might represent an opportunity to show where those ecosystems are headed next. This could also be Samsung&#39;s chance to preview One UI changes. The tech firm recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-removes-ads-pay-health-weather-203218433.html">scrapped ads in its One UI apps</a>, and we wouldn&#39;t be surprised if there were more substantial OS changes Samsung wanted to show before the year is over.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-unpacked-part-2-event-fall-2021-000033755.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bd2d56dc-f3f7-4ca3-9634-41993f96b888</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634071167</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T20:39:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f9a29d50-2b98-11ec-bb2d-1a70aa3156c9" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f9a29d50-2b98-11ec-bb2d-1a70aa3156c9" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked Part 2 event teaser]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked Part 2 event teaser]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fandango's Vudu streaming service is now available on Oculus Quest VR headsets]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vudu is now available on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-30-oculus-quest-review-wireless-vr.html"><ins>Oculus Quest</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/oculus-quest-2-review-vr-facebook-headset-173026291.html"><ins>Quest 2</ins></a> headsets. Fandango’s free streaming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/vudu-fandangonow-merge-111549415.html"><ins>service</ins></a> includes both paid and ad-supported content. With today’s launch, you can rent and buy more than 200,000 titles through the storefront, including recent releases like <em>Black Widow</em> and <em>Jungle Cruise</em>. Additionally, there are “hundreds” of 3D movies you can watch on an Oculus Quest 2 headset. Notable inclusions on that front include <em>Venom</em>, <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em> and <em>Mad Max: Fury Road</em>, among others.</p><p>Following a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/quest-2-foam-facial-interface-recall-163432642.html"><ins>voluntary recall</ins></a>, Facebook restarted Oculus Quest 2 sales on August 24th. The $299 base model now features 128GB of internal storage, up from the 64GB it came with at launch. At the time, Facebook said the update was about allowing players to store more of their favorite games and apps on a single device. Clearly, it also had movies in mind.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/vudu-streaming-service-oculus-quest-221553537.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4c14795c-938d-47ae-96b6-5332932b5e1a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 22:15:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634076483</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T22:08:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/381b0e60-2446-11eb-b5fe-a84cf288dbf8" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/381b0e60-2446-11eb-b5fe-a84cf288dbf8" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Oculus Quest 2]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Oculus Quest 2]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch Blue Origin fly William Shatner to space at 8:30AM ET on October 13th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Provided there aren’t any <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-shatner-flight-delay-171339388.html">last-minute delays</a>, Star Trek actor William Shatner will fly to the edge of space on October 13th. You can watch the entire flight right here and on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SiOM-yVILxU&amp;ab_channel=Engadget">Engadget’s YouTube channel</a>. Tune in at around 9:30 to see NS-18 lift off from Blue Origin’s Launch Site One facility near Van Horn, Texas. The mission was originally scheduled to blast off on October 12th but was pushed back due to unfavorable weather conditions.</p><div id="c207bf245f9742608243eb4a04a9b296"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SiOM-yVILxU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>The upcoming launch comes some three months after Blue Origin successfully completed its first crewed flight on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-completes-first-crewed-spaceflight-132937714.html">July 20th</a>. If this latest flight is successful, Shatner, at 90, will become the oldest person to have made such a journey. The current record is held by aviation legend <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wally-funk-blue-origin-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-155036734.html">Wally Funk</a>, who joined Blue Origin founder <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bezos-space-flight-blue-origin-quotes-204210894.html">Jeff Bezos</a> on the company’s inaugural flight.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/how-to-watch-blue-origin-william-shatner-flight-213042866.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9def0f40-f3ff-429e-86d6-a926a1cfbdcf</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 21:30:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634073832</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T21:23:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e89f5a20-2b9d-11ec-b3de-cf3af1991d82" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e89f5a20-2b9d-11ec-b3de-cf3af1991d82" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Blue Origin NS-18]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Blue Origin NS-18]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chrome finally gets an Adobe Acrobat PDF editor]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PDFs aren’t the headache they once were, but they can still be a hassle sometimes, especially if all you need to do is make a quick edit. Not everyone wants to download dedicated desktop software for signing the occasional document and their web apps can present their own jank. In a <a href="https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2021/10/12/work-with-pdf-files-right-in-your-browser.html#gs.d0et1v">move</a> that feels long overdue, Adobe is releasing <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/adobe-acrobat/efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj?hl=en"><ins>Acrobat Chrome</ins></a> and Edge extensions that allow you to access its PDF tools directly through your browser.</p><p>If you mostly need something that allows you to sign documents, the good news is you don’t need an Acrobat Pro DC subscription to access that functionality within the extension. Free access also allows you to add comments to PDFs, in addition to allowing you to download and print them. It’s when you get to things like trying to convert a PDF into a Microsoft Word document that you’ll need to pony up.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>To be clear, the extensions are separate from Acrobat web, which Adobe <a href="https://www.engadget.com/adobe-acrobat-web-update-005609376.html"><ins>recently updated</ins></a> to bring to clear feature parity with its desktop client. If your work involves editing PDFs frequently, you’ll probably continue using Adobe’s dedicated app. For everyone else, the extensions should do just fine in a pinch.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/adobe-acrobat-chrome-extension-193444731.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ff086d3f-b101-4f20-bb52-f83c6a1bad9e</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:34:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634067289</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T19:34:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d1e3c3e0-2b91-11ec-919f-a72a6436e2f2" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/d1e3c3e0-2b91-11ec-919f-a72a6436e2f2" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Adobe Acrobat extension]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Adobe Acrobat extension]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter tests swiping between Home and Latest Tweets on iPhone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/twitter">Twitter&#39;s</a> latest test is all about how you view tweets in the app. Some users on iOS will <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1447971179185295364">be able to swipe</a> between the Home feed, which shows the top tweets in your timeline, and a chronological look at the latest tweets (the proper way to use Twitter, but you do you).</p><p>It&#39;s a fairly small user interface change, but a handy one for those who dart between the two views. The current method of switching between the views is through <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-18-twitter-chronological-timeline-feature-latest-tweets.html">the button on the top right of the screen</a>, but a swipe is quicker than a couple of taps.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The update could make the app&#39;s home screen a little messier if you have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-23-twitter-pin-lists-home-timeline-ios.html">pinned lists</a> that you swipe through. Still, it could be a welcome quality of life change for some folks while making the two options more prominent.</p><div id="7dc3be28fd8d485ebf342dfb6325d910"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Top Tweets first or latest Tweets first? We’re making it easier to switch between the two timelines and know which one you’re scrolling.<br><br>Now testing with some of you on iOS: swipe between &quot;Home&quot; and &quot;Latest&quot; on the Home tab to choose which Tweets you see first. <a href="https://t.co/LoyAN4cONu">pic.twitter.com/LoyAN4cONu</a></p>— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1447971179185295364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-test-home-feed-latest-tweets-ios-swipe-192133089.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0d19a961-1fae-446f-a4f7-980b0778ce4b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634070168</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T20:22:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f6242f80-2b99-11ec-abff-1f62787326f3" width="5000" height="3332" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f6242f80-2b99-11ec-abff-1f62787326f3" width="5000" height="3332" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[POLAND - 2020/11/20: In this photo illustration a Twitter social media app logo seen displayed on a smartphone with blue world data stats in the background. (Photo Illustration by Filip Radwanski/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration a Twitter social media app logo...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix's 'League of Legends' show is getting an immersive IRL event]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The animated <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/league%20of%20legends"><em><ins>League of Legends</ins></em></a> series <em>Arcane </em>will <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-trailer-185418635.html"><ins>hit Netflix on November 6th</ins></a> and Riot Games is marking the launch with an in-person immersive experience connected to the series. The publisher teamed up with Secret Cinema to host the <a href="https://tickets.secretcinema.org/arcane/"><em>Arcane </em>experience</a>, which will only be available in Los Angeles.</p><p>You&#39;ll get to explore the Undercity, where you&#39;ll delve into the origins of two <em>LoL </em>champions. You&#39;ll take on missions, find secret hideouts, form alliances and evade enforcers. The ending of the story will be different depending on the choices you make, so <em>Arcane</em> might encourage repeat visits.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Riot is pushing into another realm of entertainment here. “For the launch of <em>Arcane</em>, we really wanted to find the right partner who shared our vision for bringing such a rich IP and to life in an interactive, immersive way,&quot; Brandon Miao, cross-product experiences and partnerships lead for Riot Experience, said. &quot;Bringing players new, authentic out-of-game experiences that tie back to the narrative of the show is a first for us, and something we are incredibly excited to share with players as we expand to entertainment.”</p><p>The <em>Arcane </em>experience will debut on November 21st and tickets cost $70. You&#39;ll get your first chance at snagging a ticket through a presale that starts on October 13th at 3PM ET. You can sign up for ticket alerts <a href="https://www.secretcinema.org/mailing-list-form-us?utm_source=huntgather&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=hex2021&amp;utm_content=mastercardreleaseannouncement"><ins>through Secret Cinema</ins></a>. General admission starts 24 hours later.</p><p>Secret Cinema has built a reputation for creating immersive experiences based on movies and, more recently with its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/stranger-things-drive-into-experiencce-054937764.html"><em>Stranger Things </em>adaptation</a>, TV shows. This is the first time it has taken on a project with roots in gaming.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-immersive-experience-riot-games-secret-cinema-184323741.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d6a5a54f-6b52-4d67-bb8b-bf5d681394b5</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:43:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634064208</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T18:43:40+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f34bb8f0-2b8a-11ec-97ff-8d05da27084f" width="1500" height="1089" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f34bb8f0-2b8a-11ec-97ff-8d05da27084f" width="1500" height="1089" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Riot Games/Secret Cinema]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Key art for an immersive experience based on League of Legends animated series Arcane.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Poster for Secret Cinema's League of Legends Arcane experience ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google will stop trying to make its iOS apps look like Android apps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google says it will phase out its use of Material Design interface elements within its iOS apps in favor of Apple’s own UIKit. Jeff Verkoeyen, the company&#39;s iOS design chief, announced the change in a <a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1446151509549387781%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fappleinsider.com%2Farticles%2F21%2F10%2F12%2Fgoogle-dropping-material-design-in-ios-to-make-iphone-apps-look-more-like-they-should">Twitter thread</a> spotted by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722130/google-ios-app-material-design-components-uikit"><em>The Verge</em></a>.</p><div id="91c6f22389c549e896a0be7f519178e7"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This year my team shifted the open source Material components libraries for iOS into maintenance mode. Why?<br><br>A 🧵...</p>— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) <a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Introduced in 2014, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-material-you-android-personalized-redesign-182501466.html">Material Design</a> is Google’s in-house design language. The company has used it to unify the look and feel of its apps and services across various platforms. According to Verkoeyen, Google shifted its open source iOS Material component libraries into maintenance mode earlier this year after it conducted a “deep evaluation” of what it means to build a “hallmark” Google experience on iOS. What it found was that many of the custom elements it started building nearly a decade ago to fill gaps in UIKit’s design language are no longer necessary.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>“With the introduction of SwiftUI and significant UIKit improvements in iOS 14+, it’s never been easier to build a great branded experience with a tiny amount of code,” Verkoeyen said.&nbsp;</p><p>With the shift to UIKit, Verkoeyen expects his team will spend less time building custom code, which should hopefully lead to faster and more frequent releases. Additionally, the use of UIKit should allow the company to more tightly integrate its software into iOS. However, those benefits may pale in comparison to the fact the company’s apps may end up looking more at home on Apple devices.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-material-design-uikit-171651054.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">42af7c33-97f5-4c1c-9a7b-d3b998ec27ca</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:16:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634059015</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T17:16:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-05/4b726be0-9aa6-11ea-b7ef-c6c327e6cecf" width="3704" height="2469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2020-05/4b726be0-9aa6-11ea-b7ef-c6c327e6cecf" width="3704" height="2469" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Thomas Trutschel via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BERLIN, GERMANY - APRIL 22: The logo of the online map service Goolge Maps is shown on the display of a smartphone on April 22, 2020 in Berlin, Germany. (Photo by Thomas Trutschel/Photothek via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Maps]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roland's V-Moda reveals its first true wireless earbuds]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-08-08-roland-buys-majority-stake-v-moda-headphones.html"><ins>Roland&#39;s V-Moda brand</ins></a> is moving into the true wireless earbuds market. The initial Hexamove lineup includes two models: Lite and Pro. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/v-moda"><ins>V-Moda</ins></a> says you&#39;ll get up to six hours of use on a single charge. The included charging case will bump up the playback time by 18 hours in total. The hexagonal earbuds have 6mm drivers that deliver what V-Moda describes as &quot;powerful bass, vibrant mids and pristine highs,&quot; though there&#39;s no <a href="https://www.engadget.com/v-moda-m-200-anc-headphones-announced-price-specs-shipping-080007207.html"><ins>active noise cancellation</ins></a>.</p><p>The Hexamove Lite buds are available in three colors: red, white and black. There are three fitting options as well. As for Hexamove Pro, there are six custom fitting options (though it&#39;s only available in black or white). V-Moda says you&#39;ll be able to mix and match fins, ear-hooks and three in-ear fittings to discover the right combo for your ears. You can also attach the earbuds to a neck strap and stabilizer to prevent you from losing them. In addition, you&#39;ll be able to customize audio on the Pro earbuds using the equalizer tool in the V-Moda app.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The brand says both models are IPX5-rated for sweat, water and dust resistance. The Hexamove earbuds are available now from the V-Moda website and Amazon. Hexamove Lite costs <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09HFCWSMQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US"><ins>$130</ins></a> and a pair of Hexamove Pro earbuds will run you <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09BTKNWGS/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US"><ins>$170</ins></a>.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3934a2e0-2b7d-11ec-bff7-b1c6764fc064" style="height:2000;width:3000;" alt="A model wearing a white version of V-Moda&#39;s Hexamove Lite earbuds" data-uuid="3c5984b0-863d-33ff-a917-77542b37164a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">V-Moda</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roland-v-moda-hexamove-true-wireless-earbuds-170022919.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">79781ead-713e-4838-b74d-f3f455767033</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634058002</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T17:00:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1d8514d0-2b7d-11ec-bbc5-fc69657a74d7" width="3000" height="1688" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1d8514d0-2b7d-11ec-bbc5-fc69657a74d7" width="3000" height="1688" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[V-Moda]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[V-Moda Hexamove Lite earbuds in red, black and white]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[V-Moda Hexamove Lite earbuds]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Cloud will show users their gross carbon emissions]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20cloud"><ins>Google Cloud</ins></a> has <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/sustainability/new-tools-to-measure-and-reduce-your-environmental-impact"><ins>added tools</ins></a> to help users gain a better understanding of their environmental impact as part of the company&#39;s broader efforts to combat climate change. The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/carbon-footprint"><ins>Carbon Footprint feature</ins></a> shows the gross carbon emissions linked to the electricity consumption of someone&#39;s Cloud Platform use. It displays emissions over time and can break down the data by project, product and region.</p><p>Companies will be able to roll this information into their own emissions data for internal audits and making carbon disclosures (they can export the data to Salesforce Sustainability Cloud, for instance). Google stressed that the figures relate to a user&#39;s gross carbon emissions, since the company has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-eliminates-carbon-legacy-161544433.html"><ins>carbon neutral for over a decade</ins></a>. It plans to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-carbon-free-energy-2030-190100260.html"><ins>run entirely on carbon-free energy</ins></a> by 2030.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Google Cloud will also flag applications that are not in use, as well as their carbon emissions. Google suggests that deleting apps identified by the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/identity-security/google-cloud-launches-unattended-project-recommender"><ins>Unattended Project Recommender</ins></a> will help companies mitigate security risks, lower costs and reduce their carbon footprint.</p><div id="22f4bafe93a74ee8a4a26b0cb635ac0e"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EarthEngine?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#EarthEngine</a> is now available in preview to commercial customers via Google Cloud Platform. We&#39;re building on our long track record on environmental impact to enable companies and governments that want to make progress on climate action. <a href="https://t.co/j2EXcalf4h">https://t.co/j2EXcalf4h</a></p>— Google Earth (@googleearth) <a href="https://twitter.com/googleearth/status/1447941386892939272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>In addition, Google is bringing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-maps-california-colorado-wildfire-tracking-hourly-142455609.html"><ins>Earth Engine</ins></a> to the Cloud Platform for <a href="https://blog.google/products/earth/earth-engine-preview-google-cloud/"><ins>select users</ins></a>. Using satellite imagery, data sets and other tools, companies can harness Earth Engine to &quot;track, monitor and predict changes in the Earth’s surface&quot; caused by extreme weather events or human activity. That, Google says, will enable businesses to reduce and mitigate risks, &quot;become more resilient to climate change threats&quot; and save money. Companies can <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfC3GlMqj5yaDF4lejrde3sNNfoZVUJQlZ9SMmFYnYYZej4WQ/viewform?resourcekey=0-RDa_Kq6jp6H3QxGrwrYc7g"><ins>apply</ins></a> for access to Earth Engine through Google Cloud.</p><p>Last week, Google unveiled a string of features that highlight the environmental impact of consumer choices. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-search-sustainability-travel-shopping-070110212.html"><ins>Shopping results can promote greener options</ins></a>, while Google Flights started showing carbon emission estimates for almost all trips. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-renew-clean-energy-program-070131398.html"><ins>The Nest Renew program</ins></a>, meanwhile, can switch your thermostat on or off depending on the availability of clean energy. In addition, Google is hoping to use AI to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-ai-traffic-lights-research-environment-pollution-070132356.html"><ins>improve the efficiency of traffic lights</ins></a> and reduce pollution from idle cars.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-cloud-platform-carbon-footprint-emissions-environment-163339146.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2657542c-1cdb-47f6-b989-ad3869ee153c</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:33:39 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634056188</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T16:29:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Internet & Networking Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Climate Change]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9fcbed80-2b76-11ec-b7bf-fa207c31e7b5" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9fcbed80-2b76-11ec-b7bf-fa207c31e7b5" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Thamrongpat Theerathammakorn / EyeEm via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Photo taken in Chon Buri, Thailand]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Close-Up Of Earth Against Blue Sky At Night]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple is holding its next event on October 18th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The murmurs were true: Apple will hold a second fall product event on October 18th at 1PM Eastern. The invitation for the virtual &quot;Unleashed&#39; presentation doesn&#39;t provide many clues, although many unofficially expect Apple to introduce <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-new-macbook-pro-2021-m-1-x-152614042.html">14- and 16-inch MacBook Pro</a> based on souped-up M1X processors.</p><p>The new portables are rumored to be significant redesigns that also harken back to the &quot;good old days&quot; of Apple&#39;s pre-2016 models. While they&#39;d have cutting-edge designs, they&#39;d also bring back <a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-2021-macbook-pro-may-mark-the-return-of-the-mag-safe-connector-091548032.html">MagSafe-like charging</a> and legacy ports like an SD card slot. To no one&#39;s surprise, the M1X would also be far more powerful than the M1 with 10 CPU cores (eight performance and two efficiency) and either 16 or 32 graphics cores. There&#39;s a chance Apple might drop the Touch Bar, too, and it&#39;s safe to presume you&#39;ll hear about a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-preview-public-beta-175927010.html">macOS Monterey</a> release date.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>These might not be the only introductions, either. Apple might introduce <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airpods-third-generation-leak-205121774.html">third-generation &#39;basic&#39; AirPods</a>, and we wouldn&#39;t rule out other M1X-based products (like a high-end Mac mini) or new and expanded services. Unlike last year, Apple might not spread announcements across three events — this may be the company&#39;s last chance to make a big splash before 2021 is over.</p><div id="e2dfc40330904dc3ab795ed4718c2e18"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Unleashed! These next six days are going to speed by. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AppleEvent?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AppleEvent</a><a href="https://t.co/0ops2bVPvl">pic.twitter.com/0ops2bVPvl</a></p>— Greg Joswiak (@gregjoz) <a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1447956519132151810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-unleashed-macbook-pro-event-date-161136786.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">71b09f2b-2e39-48b0-b1b1-7097537e36dc</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:11:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634056285</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T16:31:35+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/cf9f4660-2b76-11ec-adcd-11263c8a2e5f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/cf9f4660-2b76-11ec-adcd-11263c8a2e5f" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple 'Unleashed' event invitation]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple 'Unleashed' event invitation]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lucid details the Air's semi-autonomous driving features]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-ev-delivery-date-214305594.html">Lucid Air is finally in production</a>, its creator is eager to tout the EV&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-lidar-dream-drive-130003018.html">semi-autonomous driving assistance</a> — although it may be as much about what&#39;s missing as what&#39;s here. The new brand has provided further details of its DreamDrive system, now split into regular and Pro versions. Both variants will include 14 regular cameras, four surround cameras, five radar sensors and a string of ultrasonic sensors, but you&#39;ll need the Air in Dream Edition or Grand Touring trim to get DreamDrive Pro&#39;s LiDAR and the advanced features that will come with it.</p><p>Every Air buyer will get core features like Highway Assist (adaptive cruise control with lane centering), Traffic Jam Assist (lane centering at low speeds), cross-traffic protection and Auto Park (for both parallel and perpendicular parking). The combination of an infrared driver camera and hands-off detection will make sure your head, eyes and (of course) hands are focused on the road. If you&#39;re incapacitated or simply ignore the warnings, DreamDrive will ultimately bring the car to a complete stop, switch on hazard lights and unlock the doors. These will sound familiar on a basic level if you&#39;ve ever used Tesla&#39;s Autopilot.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You&#39;ll need DreamDrive Pro to get the most out of Lucid&#39;s platform, however. The Pro tier will include <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-ev-user-interface-170054004.html">21-speaker directional alerts</a> as well as the upcoming Highway Pilot system and its &quot;conditional&quot; hands-free driving. Cars with Pro will also get more Highway Assist features through software updates, although Lucid didn&#39;t say when those upgrades might arrive.</p><p>The technology as described won&#39;t yet match all the features from its most advanced rivals, such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-full-self-driving-10-beta-145035031.html">Tesla&#39;s Full Self-Driving</a> or GM&#39;s upcoming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-unveils-a-hands-free-driving-system-that-works-in-nearly-all-of-the-us-and-canada-161752431.html">Ultra Cruise</a>. LiDAR could give Lucid an edge, but it could take a long while before the sensor reaches its full potential. Instead, Lucid&#39;s greatest advantage might simply be its more realistic (if still fluffy) marketing. Where <a href="https://www.engadget.com/senators-ftc-tesla-autopilot-full-self-driving-192943873.html">Tesla is in trouble</a> for implying its cars are autonomous, Lucid is careful to position DreamDrive as a driver assistance system and not much more.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lucid-air-dreamdrive-semi-autonomous-features-160026944.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4d1f9920-977a-4760-830e-0586d5e05b50</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:00:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634056505</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T16:35:08+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3495fd30-2b6c-11ec-a5bf-15ff8b5bb26d" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3495fd30-2b6c-11ec-a5bf-15ff8b5bb26d" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Lucid Motors]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lucid Air DreamDrive semi-autonomous driving assistance sensors]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lucid Air DreamDrive semi-autonomous driving assistance sensors]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[VanMoof's fastest e-bike yet tops out at 31 MPH]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>E-bike maker <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/vanmoof"><ins>VanMoof</ins></a> is looking to help riders get from A to B more swiftly with its first high-speed model. The VanMoof V is the company’s first hyperbike, which will be able to hit a top speed of 31 MPH (50 km/h).</p><p>VanMoof is pitching this as a car replacement for city life and longer commutes. The VanMoof V will have two-wheel drive, thicker tires, a new frame design and front and rear suspension, which could make lengthier trips more comfortable. Other features include intelligent motor control, VanMoof&#39;s Turbo Boost, a Kick Lock for keyless locking, automatic gear shifting and measures to combat theft.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Details about the e-bike&#39;s range haven&#39;t been revealed, but VanMoof noted the battery has a 700 wH capacity. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-s3-electric-bicycle-review-123059628.html"><ins>VanMoof S3</ins></a> has a 504 Wh battery capacity and a promised range of 60-150 km (37-93 miles). The company sells <a href="https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-powerbank-62-miles-range-boost-121026751.html"><ins>a PowerBank accessory</ins></a> that can increase the range, but it&#39;s unclear whether that device will be compatible with the VanMoof V.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/14473600-2862-11ec-bfe7-b1568a56a246" style="height:844;width:1500;" alt="Render of the VanMoof V e-bike" data-uuid="4dd7ac40-2a17-3e22-b1e0-c023bfc6d2a7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">VanMoof</div></figure><p>Speed limits vary across cities and counties, and the e-bike will have matching integrated speed settings. As it develops the VanMoof V, the company plans to work with lawmakers and local governments on e-bike rules, including geofencing and speed regulations.</p><p>VanMoof plans to start deliveries of the hyperbike in late 2022. The VanMoof V costs $3,498/£3,498/€3,498. The company is offering invite-only reservations for $20/£20/€20 starting today, with its current customers getting first dibs. Alternatively, you can join a waitlist on the <a href="http://vanmoof.com/"><ins>VanMoof website</ins></a>. Reservation codes will be sent out periodically.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/vanmoof-v-e-bike-hyperbike-fastest-150015459.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0d17535f-4c2b-40cd-aeca-b1d65a63af5b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1633717522</ingested><modified>2021-10-08T18:25:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0f7ed880-2862-11ec-bfdb-fa03b00aeb42" width="2500" height="1408" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0f7ed880-2862-11ec-bfdb-fa03b00aeb42" width="2500" height="1408" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[VanMoof]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Render of the VanMoof V e-bike]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Render of the VanMoof V e-bike]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Waze and Headspace team up to make driving less stressful]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/waze">Waze</a> has <a href="https://medium.com/waze/welcome-a-new-era-of-happier-driving-with-headspace-90f539103d09">partnered</a> with Mindspace in the hopes of making your commutes a little more pleasant. The Drive with Headspace experience includes <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-design-brand-refresh-moods-130054677.html">five additional moods</a> —  Aware, Bright, Hopeful, Joyful and Open — and the option to change the in-app car icon to a relaxing hot air balloon. You can also listen to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5kzu984CXB3iTmshDvj8He">a dedicated Spotify playlist</a>, which features music and content from Headspace, through the Waze Audio Player.</p><p>If you use the Headspace theme, the company&#39;s mindfulness teacher and director of meditation Eve Lewis Prieto will read the driving directions. Waze&#39;s Headspace features are available for a limited time starting today in English, French, Spanish and Portuguese. You can switch on the experience by tapping the Drive with Headspace banner in My Waze. It might prove a bit more relaxing than the recent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-halo-experience-130042208.html"><em>Halo</em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-paw-patrol-navigation-164613580.html"><em>PAW Patrol</em></a> experiences.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/waze-headspace-mindfulness-driving-spotify-playlist-145652085.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">131c668d-5b9f-4bf1-a6f6-f7dbe75d3503</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634050726</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T14:58:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/87bbce50-2b6b-11ec-bffd-82e9187d724b" width="1400" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/87bbce50-2b6b-11ec-bffd-82e9187d724b" width="1400" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Waze]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A graphic depicting the Headspace mindfulness experience in the Waze driving app.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Waze's Headspace experience]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netgear's quad-band WiFi 6E mesh router will set you back $1,500]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How much would you pay for one of the fastest home wireless networks possible? More than you paid for your computer or phone? If so, Netgear has your solution. The company has <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211012005318/en/NETGEAR-Adds-the-World%E2%80%99s-First-Quad-Band-WiFi-6E-Mesh-System-to-the-Orbi-Family/">introduced</a> what it says is the first quad-band WiFi 6E mesh networking system, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Orbi Quad-band Mesh WiFi 6E" href="https://fave.co/2YDJNbO">Orbi Quad-band Mesh WiFi 6E</a>. Pay a staggering $1,500 for a three-pack and you&#39;ll get 10.8Gbps of total bandwidth across the 2.4GHz, 5GHz and now 6GHz bands, plus the backhaul band (at &#39;just&#39; WiFi 6 speeds) to keep the main frequencies clear. Your home network could easily outpace your internet connection, even if you have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-07-13-comcast-2gbps-internet-pricing.html">multi-gigabit service</a>.</p><p>There are some improvements beyond pure speed. The three-unit bundle offers about 9,000 square feet of maximum coverage (up from 7,500sq. ft. for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-06-netgear-wifi-6-mesh-router-expensive-700.html">WiFi 6 models</a>), and the WAN Ethernet port now supports up to 10Gbps. Accordingly, there are more 2.5Gbps Ethernet ports on the router and satellites to improve bandwidth for wired devices. You can create up to four distinct WiFi networks, including a 6E-only network to ensure newer devices run at full speed.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Orbi Quad-band router is available for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:pre-order now" href="https://fave.co/2YDJNbO">pre-order now</a>, with shipping expected &quot;in time for the holidays&quot; (Netgear&#39;s store quotes an October 29th ship date). You can also buy additional satellites for $599 each. That&#39;s a massive amount to spend on your home network, but Netgear is clearly counting on at least some customers who&#39;ll pay whatever it takes to get no-compromise WiFi. Just know there are some good-enough alternatives. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/linksys-wifi-6e-mesh-system-axe8400-networking-180021339.html">Linksys&#39; AXE8400</a> doesn&#39;t have the backhaul band, but its one- and two-node options (plus lower overall pricing) could make it a better pick if you&#39;re more interested in WiFi 6E compatibility than raw throughput.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netgear-orbi-wifi-6e-quad-band-mesh-router-142948379.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">40c3d62b-0e14-4623-a7f2-6776404c10e3</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:29:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634049663</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T14:41:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e54f9c10-2b5f-11ec-b9f2-e912c763cbb3" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e54f9c10-2b5f-11ec-b9f2-e912c763cbb3" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netgear]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Netgear Orbi Quad-band WiFi 6E mesh router]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netgear Orbi Quad-band WiFi 6E mesh router]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[G4 will return to TV on November 16th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seven years after it disappeared, G4 has a return date. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/g4tv-teaser-222059630.html"><ins>gaming and fandom TV network</ins></a> will be revived on November 16th on Xfinity TV, Cox and Verizon Fios (Verizon is Engadget&#39;s former parent company). You&#39;ll be able to stream the network on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/philo"><ins>Philo</ins></a> too.</p><p>G4 also has a multi-year promotional and commercial deal with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/twitch"><ins>Twitch</ins></a>. The network will keep making dedicated content for social media channels, including YouTube, as well. G4 announced the return date in typically offbeat fashion, with gags about the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-xbox-mini-fridge-release-date-191211916.html">Xbox Mini Fridge</a> and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-switch-oled-review-130025998.html">Nintendo Switch OLED</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="b77c1c44bb0e4d2badb4932e73434cab"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr">11.16.2021 <a href="https://t.co/6OvQPJNsO6">pic.twitter.com/6OvQPJNsO6</a></p>— G4TV (@G4TV) <a href="https://twitter.com/G4TV/status/1447910146248781824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Classic G4 series <a href="https://www.engadget.com/g4-attack-of-the-show-x-play-211601352.html"><em><ins>Attack of the Show! </ins></em><ins>and </ins><em><ins>Xplay</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>are returning with their respective former hosts, Kevin Pereira and Adam Sessler. A weekly show called <em>Boosted </em>will focus on esports coverage, and you&#39;ll be able to watch <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/esl"><ins>ESL</ins></a> esports events such as IEM Katowice 2022. Also on the docket are a series in which G4 talent and guests play <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Dungeons%20&amp;%20Dragons"><em><ins>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</ins></em></a><em><ins>,</ins></em><em>&nbsp;</em>along with all 167 episodes of <em>Ninja Warrior </em>(aka <em>Sasuke</em>).</p><p>As well as Pereira and Sessler, the G4 talent roster includes esports figures Alex “Goldenboy” Mendez, Ovilee May and Indiana “Froskurinn” Black; YouTube creators Kassem G, Jirard “The Completionist” Khalil and Gina Darling; Twitch streamers Fiona Nova and Will Neff; and WWE wrestler and gaming personality Xavier Woods (aka Austin Creed).</p><p>Carriers <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-02-11-nbcuniversal-g4tv-esquire-network.html"><ins>started dropping</ins></a> the original incarnation of G4 in September 2013. The network&#39;s gradual decline came to a head on November 30th, 2014, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-11-17-g4-channel-shutting-down-for-good-this-month.html"><ins>its final day on the air</ins></a> until now. Comcast announced plans to revive the brand in July 2020. Earlier this year, G4 started streaming shows on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/g4-b4g4-youtube-twitch-220048337.html"><ins>Twitch, YouTube</ins></a> and Twitter in the leadup to the relaunch.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/g4-g4tv-comcast-philo-twitch-xfinity-cox-verizon-fios-141608050.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">83ddff16-4d77-40f3-898d-1420dc25be51</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:16:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634048171</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T14:16:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/c75b4660-cdf9-11ea-9ffb-8588715cf0d6" width="1200" height="680" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/c75b4660-cdf9-11ea-9ffb-8588715cf0d6" width="1200" height="680" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NBCUniversal]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[G4 logo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[G4 logo]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Withings' ScanWatch is finally coming to the US after FDA clearance]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Withings&#39; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-scanwatch-hands-on-ifa-2020-070001875.html">ScanWatch</a> has received FDA clearance, paving the way for it to be sold in the US starting in November, the company announced. The watches, available in regular and diver-style <a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-scanwatch-horizon-divers-watch-070020840.html">Horizon</a> versions, have simultaneously been cleared to take <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-06-withings-move-ecg.html">electrocardiogram (ECG)</a> and SpO2 (oxygen saturation) readings, in health and medical settings.</p><p>The original <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:ScanWatch" href="https://fave.co/3iWqXEd">ScanWatch</a> has been available in Europe since it came out a year ago, but FDA clearance has taken much longer. Both models use ECG readings to check for atrial fibrillation (heartbeat irregularities), and you can even download the results and mail them to your doctor as a PDF. If it notices any irregular heartbeats, it will advise you to take an ECG test.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b74642e0-2b61-11ec-8ffe-e1d265bf9096" alt="Withings&#39; hybrid ScanWatch is set to arrive in the US next month" data-uuid="ea95c562-9a80-3015-9ace-ada421c3b187"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>We found the ScanWatch to be the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/withings-scanwatch-hands-on-ifa-2020-070001875.html">best hybrid smartwatch</a> out there, offering a traditional analog watch look and a small PMOLED display to display activities, heartrate, ECG, SpO2 and more. As with Withings&#39; scales and other health devices, it works with the company&#39;s Health Mate app.&nbsp;</p><p>Sales will commence in early November 2021, with <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:prices starting at $279" href="https://fave.co/3iWqXEd">prices starting at $279</a> for the original ScanWatch 38mm model. The Rose Gold and Horizon versions will will be available in early 2022 priced from $299 and $499 respectively.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/withings-hybrid-scan-watch-is-set-to-arrive-in-the-us-next-month-135842112.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">627aee9a-430b-408b-8eb0-4d7c50e41a7b</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 13:58:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634049736</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T14:42:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Health Care Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7ccdf60-2b5e-11ec-9fbf-d98a46f7ca95" width="1774" height="1052" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b7ccdf60-2b5e-11ec-9fbf-d98a46f7ca95" width="1774" height="1052" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Withings' hybrid ScanWatch is set to arrive in the US next month]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Withings' hybrid ScanWatch is set to arrive in the US next month]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[LG will cover nearly the entire cost of GM's Chevy Bolt EV recall]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>GM may be replacing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-chevy-bolt-ev-recall-battery-replacement-155343570.html">tens of thousands of Bolt EV batteries</a>, but it won&#39;t have to pick up the tab for most of them. The automaker has <a href="https://investor.gm.com/news-releases/news-release-details/general-motors-lg-electronics-reach-agreement-bolt-ev-recall">reached a deal</a> that will have LG pay nearly all the costs associated with recalling the Chevy Bolt EV and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chevys-2022-bolt-ev-redesign-comes-with-an-entirely-new-model-210004893.html">EUV</a>, with GM estimating that LG will &quot;offset&quot; $1.9 billion of the $2 billion in expenses. GM will recognize that financial recovery in its third-quarter earnings.</p><p>The brand said it was happy to land an agreement with a &quot;valued and respected supplier.&quot; With that said, there&#39;s little doubt GM is using the deal to redirect blame — it stressed that the recall was prompted by &quot;manufacturing defects&quot; in LG batteries. LG spotted anode and cathode-anode separator issues that, combined, could increase the chance of battery fires.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>LG has since addressed the battery issues and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-restarts-production-of-bolt-ev-batteries-following-model-wide-recall-194412215.html">restarted production</a>. The immediate costs of the recall may be secondary, however. Both companies have taken a hit to their relatively fragile reputations in the electric vehicle space — it doesn&#39;t look good for GM in particular when its two main EVs have to be taken off the road, if only briefly. GM&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-third-electric-pickup-032356371.html">Hummer EV and electric pickups</a> could mend that image, but that won&#39;t help much in the short term.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gm-lg-chevy-bolt-ev-euv-recall-agreement-131047763.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">810befe1-52d0-4de6-b656-c992f75049c3</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 13:10:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634044250</ingested><modified>2021-10-12T13:11:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2019-08/638ec9f0-c4f3-11e9-bdbb-d242bea88b77" width="1400" height="800" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2019-08/638ec9f0-c4f3-11e9-bdbb-d242bea88b77" width="1400" height="800" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Chevy Bolt EV near Golden Gate Bridge]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Chevy Bolt EV near Golden Gate Bridge]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>