<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 21:50:52 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook restores policy it 'lost' three years ago]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, Facebook’s Oversight Board chastised the company for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-oversight-board-lost-rule-193222133.html">losing an important policy</a> for three years. At the center of the ruling was an Instagram post about Abdullah Öcalan, which encouraged people to talk about his political imprisonment. Öcalan is one of the founding members of the Kurdistan Workers’ Party. The PKK is a Kurdish militia Facebook classifies as a “dangerous organization.”</p><p>The company had initially removed the post because of a rule that prohibits Facebook users from expressing support for groups and individuals that fall under that category. At the same time, Facebook also had “internal guidance” in place — which came out in part around discussions the company had about Öcalan’s imprisonment — that carved out an exception to that policy to allow people to discuss “conditions of confinement for individuals designated as dangerous.” However, Facebook did not apply that rule to Öcalan’s case due to an oversight that occurred when it moved to a new review system in 2018.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In examining what happened, the Oversight Board issued 12 recommendations to Facebook, which the company <a href="https://transparency.fb.com/oversight/oversight-board-cases/support-of-abdullah-ocalan-founder-of-the-pkk/">responded to today</a>. To start, it will “immediately” re-implement the misplaced policy at the center of the case. Facebook says it has begun training its content reviewers on implementing the rule and expects the guidance to be fully in place within the next two weeks.&nbsp;</p><p>By the end of the year, it also plans to clarify the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/dangerous_individuals_organizations">Dangerous Individuals and Organizations policy</a>. Out of the 12 recommendations put forward by the Oversight Board, Facebook plans to fully or partially implement most of them. However, one it’s not sure on would involve the company sharing more comprehensive information on its enforcement of those policies. The company says it’s still examining the feasibility of creating a system that provides a country-by-country breakdown of enforcement and error data. It says it will share an update on that work in one of its upcoming quarterly updates.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-responds-oversight-board-lost-rule-215052348.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cd4c8b02-cf4d-4d50-bb30-8bf11ef667c9</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 21:50:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628286773</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T21:53:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d59d1620-f6fe-11eb-9ffb-457fbfad9173" width="5542" height="3352" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d59d1620-f6fe-11eb-9ffb-457fbfad9173" width="5542" height="3352" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anadolu Agency via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ANKARA, TURKEY - MAY 07: Oversight Board logo is seen on a smart phone in Ankara, Turkey on May 07, 2020. (Photo by Hakan Nural/Anadolu Agency via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Oversight Board...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[WhatsApp head says Apple's child safety update is a 'surveillance system']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One day after Apple <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-scan-iphones-child-abuse-neuralmatch-185009882.html">confirmed plans</a> for new software that will allow it to detect images of child abuse on users’ iCloud photos, Facebook’s head of WhatsApp says he is “concerned” by the plans.</p><p>In <a href="https://twitter.com/wcathcart/status/1423701473624395784">a thread </a>on Twitter, Will Cathcart called it an “Apple built and operated surveillance system that could very easily be used to scan private content for anything they or a government decides it wants to control.” He also raised questions about how such a system may be exploited in China or other countries, or abused by spyware companies.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A spokesperson for Apple disputed Cathcart&#39;s characterization of the software, noting that users can choose to disable iCloud Photos. Apple has also said that the system is only trained on a database of <a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/">“known” images</a> provided by the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) and other organizations, and that it wouldn’t be possible to make it work in a regionally-specific way since it’s baked into iOS.</p><div id="515a335c801a4783866a6e6f1110b90a"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is an Apple built and operated surveillance system that could very easily be used to scan private content for anything they or a government decides it wants to control. Countries where iPhones are sold will have different definitions on what is acceptable.</p>— Will Cathcart (@wcathcart) <a href="https://twitter.com/wcathcart/status/1423701479613894657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><div id="f66bebfcfe8e4d85b759c8844b271ab2"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Can this scanning software running on your phone be error proof? Researchers have not been allowed to find out. Why not? How will we know how often mistakes are violating people’s privacy?</p>— Will Cathcart (@wcathcart) <a href="https://twitter.com/wcathcart/status/1423701481559973890?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>It’s not surprising that Facebook would take issue with Apple’s plans. Apple has spent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-03-28-apple-ceo-tim-cook-criticizes-facebook-privacy-standards.html">years</a> bashing Facebook over its record <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tim-cook-privacy-cpdp-2021-slams-facebook-184333398.html">on privacy,</a> even as the social network has embraced end-to-end encryption. More recently, the companies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-apple-ios-14-privacy-change-full-page-newspaper-ads-131145356.html">have clashed</a> over privacy updates that have hindered Facebook’s ability to track its users, an update the company has said <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q2-2021-earnings-214311750.html">will hurt</a> its advertising revenue.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-head-apple-child-safety-surveillance-system-201956787.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">35cf89b1-aa5f-4ca4-ba19-52bf512c935b</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:19:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628281434</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T20:24:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/a2ab5000-576d-11eb-bff9-f3b9b7d7f8a7" width="3543" height="2160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/a2ab5000-576d-11eb-bff9-f3b9b7d7f8a7" width="3543" height="2160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[WhatsApp logo on the App Store displayed on a phone screen and WhatsApp logo in the background are seen in this illustration photo taken in Poland on January 14, 2021. Signal and Telegram messenger apps gained popularity due to the new WhatsApp's privacy policy. (Photo illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Signal And Telegram Messenger Apps Gained Popularity]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Razer's Project Hazel face mask has a new name and beta test you can sign up for]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Razer’s Project Hazel is one step closer to becoming a product you can buy. On Friday, the company announced a final name for the face mask. It’s now known as Razer Zephyr, and you can sign up to <a href="https://www.razer.com/campaigns/road-to-zephyr#signup">test the device</a> ahead of its planned release date <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-project-hazel-shipping-early-q4-2021-070156937.html">later this year</a>.</p><div id="323ddf15cbe24bb5945cbdff1990567c"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Project Hazel is now officially Razer Zephyr – the latest evolution of our wearable air purifier. Designed to be safe, social and sustainable, Razer Zephyr sports 99% BFE, a secure silicon face seal and anti-fog coating. Join our community beta test: <a href="https://t.co/mlex2YSMpi">https://t.co/mlex2YSMpi</a><a href="https://t.co/yLUj0lO2oJ">pic.twitter.com/yLUj0lO2oJ</a></p>— R Λ Z Ξ R (@Razer) <a href="https://twitter.com/Razer/status/1423660327762374662?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Even among Razer products, Zephyr has had a highly visible development cycle. The company first announced Project Hazel at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-smart-mask-oled-gaming-chair-193027315.html">CES 2021</a>, promising a high-tech face mask with built-in RGB lighting and an active air filtration system Razer claimed was as effective as an N95 mask. In March, Razer CEO Min-Liang Tan revealed the accessory-maker was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-manufacture-project-hazel-rgb-mask-120020874.html">moving forward with plans to manufacture the mask</a>, noting that he believed there would still be a market for Project Hazel even as countries started to vaccinate their people against COVID-19.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Since we first saw the mask at CES 2021, Razer has added internal lighting and a silicon face seal. The company also says the latest iteration of Zephyr is 99 percent effective at filtering out bacteria. The only detail Razer has yet to reveal is how much the mask will cost.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/project-hazel-razer-zephyr-201208975.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bda445fb-4c87-4f8c-8a18-f393c172d98c</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:12:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628280731</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T20:12:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c14703a0-f6f1-11eb-af85-2cdee0b36f40" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c14703a0-f6f1-11eb-af85-2cdee0b36f40" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Razer Zephyr]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Zephyr]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify's iOS app won't get AirPlay 2 support anytime soon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/spotify">Spotify</a> has shelved plans to add <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/airplay%202">AirPlay 2</a> support to its iOS app for the time being. &quot;We&#39;ve discussed this Idea internally and while we are working on supporting AirPlay2 in a proper way, we have decided to close it for now,&quot; a Spotify representative <a href="https://community.spotify.com/t5/Closed-Ideas/iOS-Airplay-2-Support-for-iOS/idc-p/5244350/highlight/true#M235171">wrote on the community forums</a>, as reported by <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/08/06/spotify-pauses-airplay-2-support-for-ios-app/"><em>MacRumors</em></a>.</p><p>The company has pinned the blame on audio driver compatibility issues. Because of those, &quot;this seems like a bigger project that we won&#39;t be able to complete in the foreseeable future.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Apple rolled out AirPlay 2 three years ago <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-05-29-ios-11-4-add-multi-room-stereo-audio-homepod.html">as part of iOS 11.4</a>. The company also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-mini-review-140030652.html">enabled support</a> for third-party music services on HomePod and HomePod mini last year. In 2019, Spotify <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-13-spotify-apple-complaint-eu-app-store.html">filed a complaint</a> with the European Commission that accused Apple of locking it and other companies Apple competes with out of the likes of Siri, HomePod, and Apple Watch. Spotify still doesn&#39;t offer native support for HomePod speakers, though you can play music from the app <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-07-apple-siri-spotify-integration-ios-13.html">through Siri</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-apple-watch-music-download-141809536.html">download Spotify tracks</a> on Apple Watch.</p><p>You can still connect Spotify to speakers and smart TVs over AirPlay or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-07-spotify-connect-streaming-free.html">Spotify Connect</a>. Spotify users won&#39;t officially be able to harness AirPlay 2 capabilities like reduced latency, multi-room audio and Siri control anytime soon. However, because AirPlay is fully integrated with iOS, it should still work with any audio app as long as you use the OS-level playback controls, rather than the Spotify app.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-ios-airplay-2-support-plans-ditched-184633525.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e486239c-57a6-4dac-a5d2-d27e19328a20</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 18:46:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628277950</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T19:25:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5b507cf0-f6e4-11eb-bd3b-9ace8521416a" width="6319" height="4213" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5b507cf0-f6e4-11eb-bd3b-9ace8521416a" width="6319" height="4213" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[DeFodi Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BARGTEHEIDE, GERMANY - MAY 03: (BILD ZEITUNG OUT)  In this photo illustration, a Spotify App in the IOS App Store on May 03, 2021 in Bargteheide, Germany. (Photo by Katja Knupper/Die Fotowerft/DeFodi Images via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[IPhone Apps]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The FCC releases its first mobile broadband map]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) has released its <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/BroadbandData/MobileMaps/mobile-map">first-ever mobile broadband coverage map</a>. The tool allows you to compare the LTE and voice coverage areas of the country’s four largest carriers, showing where you can expect to see wireless download and upload speeds of at least 5 Mbps and 1 Mbps, respectively.</p><p>The data you see on the map is accurate as of May 15th, 2021, and you can use the tool to compare what coverage looks like in your area away from the often misleading and confusing maps offered by AT&amp;T, T-Mobile, US Cellular and Verizon (Engadget’s parent company). The tool is the result of last year’s <a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2020/3/bill-to-improve-broadband-data-maps-signed-into-law">Broadband DATA Act</a>, which requires the FCC to collect and release robust data comparing different wired, fixed-wireless, satellite and mobile broadband service providers. To compile the map, the FCC collected standardized propagation information from the carriers. It also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fcc-speed-test-app-222047353.html">asked the public to help</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="ee8c0248f5dd4e1c9fb665d7474534cc"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">For too long the FCC has not had truly accurate broadband maps. But we&#39;re changing that. Starting right here and now. This is the first-of-its-kind wireless coverage map the agency has produced. And we&#39;re just getting started. More to come.<a href="https://t.co/FhgddIgRfh">https://t.co/FhgddIgRfh</a></p>— Jessica Rosenworcel (@JRosenworcel) <a href="https://twitter.com/JRosenworcel/status/1423645739025149959?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>“This map provides a preview of how the mobile data the FCC will collect under the standards set by the Broadband DATA Act will look when mapped,” the agency <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-374726A1.pdf">said</a>. “Never before have maps been created using these new, standardized mobile data specifications, which will improve the uniformity and consistency of broadband availability data collected by the FCC.”</p><p>The map isn’t perfect. For example, you can’t see the extent of each carrier’s current 5G buildouts. But it’s hard to overstate just how much of an improvement this new tool is over what the FCC offered previously. To put things into context. In 2019, Microsoft estimated that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-09-microsoft-says-fcc-data-on-improved-broadband-coverage-is-mislea.html">163 million Americans couldn’t</a> access the internet at or above broadband speeds. Meanwhile, the FCC put that number closer to 25 million.&nbsp;</p><p>That discrepancy was the direct result of how the FCC compiled its data at the time. It relied on Form 477 filings from the service providers, which could include errors and exaggerations. FCC <a href="https://www.engadget.com/joe-biden-names-jessica-rosenworcel-acting-fcc-chair-211204471.html">acting chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel</a> says the new mobile broadband map is just the start of what the agency has planned on that front.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/fcc-mobile-broadband-coverage-map-182120461.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">78605505-d29f-48fe-bc38-59ad21796ac7</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 18:21:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628274083</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T18:21:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Internet & Networking Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/506b0ec0-f6e1-11eb-bfb1-fcdcf82f831f" width="4920" height="3276" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/506b0ec0-f6e1-11eb-bfb1-fcdcf82f831f" width="4920" height="3276" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Daniel White via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Steamboat Springs, Colorado]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Cell Tower in Mountains - Autumn]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google may release the Pixel 5a on August 26th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google offered the first <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-faq-specs-ai-ml-160021397.html">official details</a> about the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-first-look-tensor-processor-better-cameras-160005582.html">Pixel 6</a> just a few days ago, and it seems the company is  gearing up to release the Pixel 5a as well. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5a-leak-144916127.html">Previous leaks</a> suggested the phone would be a revamped Pixel 4a 5G and a new report has shed some more light on the possible specs.</p><p>The device will reportedly have the same camera as the Pixel 5, as well as a headphone jack and an IP67 rating, according to Jon Prosser of <a href="https://www.frontpagetech.com/2021/08/05/exclusive-google-pixel-5a-launching-later-this-month-at-450-full-specs/"><em>Front Page Tech</em></a>. The report suggests the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/pixel%205a">Pixel 5a</a> will use Qualcomm&#39;s Snapdragon 765G 5G chipset and have 6GB of RAM. There&#39;ll be a 4,650mAh battery but no wireless charging support, according to Prosser. The phone&#39;s expected to have a 6.4-inch display and a single Mostly Black color option.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>If all of that grabs your interest, you might not have to wait too long to get your hands on the Pixel 5a. The report suggests Google will release the device on August 26th for $450.</p><p>Google said in April it was still making a Pixel 5a with 5G, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/goolge-pixel-5a-5g-confirmed-us-japan-173617692.html">contrary to rumors at the time</a>. It said the device would only land in the US and Japan and that it would be &quot;announced in line with when last year’s a-series phone was introduced.&quot; It <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-4a-5g-announcement-182159067.html">revealed</a> the Pixel 4a in September 2020, so an August announcement and release date just about matches up. It&#39;s unclear whether Google plans to release a non-5G Pixel 5a.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-5a-rumor-specs-release-date-170034517.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef361701-61bb-4a0e-a35b-1e7e8af6b3ab</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628321151</ingested><modified>2021-08-07T07:26:02+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/5d55da80-75da-11eb-aeff-6e375448d032" width="1600" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/5d55da80-75da-11eb-aeff-6e375448d032" width="1600" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks/Voice]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Pixel 5a leak]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 5a leak]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A sealed copy of 'Super Mario Bros.' has sold for a record-breaking $2 million]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An unopened copy of <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> has <a href="https://twitter.com/OnRallyRd/status/1423650688635187200?s=20">sold for $2 million</a>, shattering the previous record set by a video game sale set just last month when a collector <a href="https://www.engadget.com/super-mario-64-record-auction-110510247.html">paid $1.56 million</a> to obtain a mint version of <em>Super Mario 64</em>. Per an image shared by Rally, the company that sold the game, the copy had a 9.8 A+ rating on the <a href="https://www.watagames.com/what-we-do/wata-scale">Wata Scale</a>, meaning it was in  “exceptional” condition.</p><div id="a62e1797d6d54bcf90ea09ae096cc6a0"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Punks, X-Men, Declarations, and some news...<br><br>🏆A NEW WORLD RECORD on Rally🏆<br><br>...w/ the $2,000,000 sale of our 1985 Super Mario Bros., marking the HIGHEST PRICE EVER PAID for a video game of any title.<br><br>Read more in todays New York Times (cc: <a href="https://twitter.com/nytimes?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nytimes</a>): <a href="https://t.co/mJzEcVMXuQ">https://t.co/mJzEcVMXuQ</a><a href="https://t.co/segsfw6Jw9">pic.twitter.com/segsfw6Jw9</a></p>— Rally (@OnRallyRd) <a href="https://twitter.com/OnRallyRd/status/1423650688635187200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Once you get past the insane price, what makes this sale interesting is that it didn’t involve an auction. Instead, <a href="https://rallyrd.com/">Rally</a> positions itself as an “alternative asset investment” platform. Per <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/06/business/super-mario-bros-sale-record.html"><em>The New York Times</em></a>, the firm buys physical collectibles and holds “initial offerings” where people can buy shares in that item. When a collector wants to acquire something from Rally, the company takes their offer to everyone who has a stake, and they then vote on the matter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In the case of this recent <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> sale, Rally bought the copy for approximately $140,000 in April 2020. That same year, investors rejected a $300,000 offer for the game. Even with $2 million on the line, some didn’t want to part with the game just yet, with a quarter of those with a stake in the collectible voting to reject the offer.</p><p>If you’ve been following the market, you probably have a good idea of why some wanted to hold onto the copy for a while longer. Days before the previous record was set, a boxed version of <em>The Legend of Zelda</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-legend-of-zelda-auction-193914155.html">sold for $870,000</a> at auction. With no signs of the market cooling down anytime soon and only so many mint video games in existence, it seems it’s only a matter of time before another record is set.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/super-mario-bros-rally-sale-164126689.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">86bc04d5-f75f-43dd-8e95-9e1ffcec6724</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:41:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628266717</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T16:18:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/66a63b20-f6d1-11eb-a7ff-53a9703b06f7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/66a63b20-f6d1-11eb-a7ff-53a9703b06f7" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Super Mario Bros]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Super Mario Bros]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[DARPA's PROTEUS program gamifies the art of war]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The nature of war continues to evolve through the 21st century with conflict zones shifting from jungles and deserts to coastal cities. Not to mention the rapidly increasing commercial availability of cutting-edge technologies including UAVs and wireless communications. To help the Marine Corps best prepare for these increased complexities and challenges, the Department of Defense tasked DARPA with developing a digital training and operations planning tool. The result is the <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news-events/2021-06-22">Prototype Resilient Operations Testbed for Expeditionary Urban Scenarios</a> (PROTEUS) system, a real-time strategy simulator for urban-littoral warfare.</p><p>When the PROTEUS program first began in 2017, “there was a big push across DARPA under what we call a sustainment focus area, and that included urban warfare,” Dr. Tim Grayson, director of DARPA’s Strategic Technology Office, told Engadget, looking at how to best support and “sustain” US fighting forces in various combat situations until they can finish their mission.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/fdeaa020-f546-11eb-be7f-ae6588edd541" alt="PROTEUS screen" data-uuid="b25a98ab-2a61-3fda-a3a8-41440cce5a97"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">DARPA</div></figure><p>The PROTEUS program manager (who has since departed DARPA), Dr. John S Paschkewitz, “came to the realization that the urban environment is really complex, both from a maneuver perspective,” Grayson said, “but also going into the future where there&#39;s all this commercial technology that will involve communications and spectrum stuff, maybe even robotics and things of that nature.”</p><p>Even without the threat of armed UAVs and autonomous killbots, modern urban conflict zones pose a number of challenges including limited lines of sight and dense, pervasive civilian populations. “​​There&#39;s such a wide range of missions that happen in urban environments,” Grayson said. “A lot of it is almost like peacekeeping, stabilization operations. How do we… help the local populace and protect them.” He also notes that the military is often called in to assist with both national emergencies and natural disasters, which pose the same issues albeit without nearly as much shooting.</p><p>“So, if someone like the Marines or some other kind of sustainment military unit had to go conduct operations in a complex urban environment,” he continued, “it&#39;d be a limited footprint. So, [Paschkewitz] started looking at what we refer to as the ‘what do I put in the rucksack problem.’”</p><p>“The urban fight is about delivering precise effects and adapting faster than the adversary in an uncertain, increasingly complex environment,” Paschkewitz said in a DARPA release from June. “For US forces to maintain a distinct advantage in urban coastal combat scenarios, we need agile, flexible task organizations able to create surprise and exploit advantages by combining effects across operational domains.”</p><p>PROTEUS itself is a software program designed to run on a tablet or hardened PDA and allow anyone from a squad leader up to a company commander to monitor and adjust the “composition of battlefield elements — including dismounted forces, vehicles, unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), manned aircraft and other available assets,” according to <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news-events/2017-06-15">the release</a>. “Through PROTEUS, we aim to amplify the initiative and decision-making capabilities of NCOs and junior officers at the platoon and squad level, as well as field-grade officers, commanding expeditionary landing teams, for example, by giving them new tools to compose tailored force packages not just before the mission, but during the mission as it unfolds.”</p><p>But PROTEUS isn’t just for monitoring and redeploying forces, it also serves as a real-time strategy training system to help NCOs and officers test and analyze different capabilities and tactics virtually. “One of the beauties of [PROTEUS] is it&#39;s flexible enough to program with whatever you want,” Grayson said. It allows warfighters to “go explore their own ideas, their own structure concepts, their own tactics. They&#39;re totally free to use it just as an open-ended experimentation, mission rehearsal or even training type of tool.”</p><p>But for its design flexibility, the system’s physics engine closely conforms to the real-world behaviors and tolerances of existing military equipment as well as commercial drones, cellular, satellite and Wi-Fi communications, sensors and even weapons systems. “The simulation environment is sophisticated but doesn&#39;t let them do things that are not physically realizable,” Grayson explained.</p><p>The system also includes a dynamic composition engine called COMPOSER which not only automate the team’s equipment loadout but can also look at a commander’s plan and provide feedback on multiple aspects including “electromagnetic signature risk, assignment of communications assets to specific units and automatic configuration of tactical networks,” according to a DARPA press release.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1862bfa0-f547-11eb-bdff-05c5160c0214" alt="PROTEUS EMSO Wizard" data-uuid="cbf43a29-168d-3b56-8d49-32ad90d7586d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">DARPA</div></figure><p>“Without the EMSO and logistics wizards, it’s hard to effectively coordinate and execute multi-domain operations,” Paschkewitz said. “Marines can easily coordinate direct and indirect fires, but coordinating those with spectrum operations while ensuring logistical support without staff is challenging. These tools allow Marines to focus on the art of war, and the automation handles the science of war.”</p><p>Currently, the system is set up for standard Red vs Blue fights between opposing human forces though Grayzon does not expect PROTEUS to be upgraded to the point that humans will be able to compete against the CPU and even less likely that we’ll see CPU vs CPU — given our current computational and processing capabilities. He does note that the <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/program/constructive-machine-learning-battles-with-adversary-tactics">Constructive Machine-learning Battles with Adversary Tactics</a> (COMBAT) program, which is still underway at DARPA, is working to develop “models of Red Force brigade behaviors that challenge and adapt to Blue Forces in simulation experiments.”</p><p>“Building a commander’s insight and judgment is driven by the fact that there’s a live opponent,” Paschkewitz said in June. “We built ULTRA [the sandbox module that serves as the basis for the larger system] around that concept from day one. This is not AI versus AI, or human versus AI, rather there is always a Marine against an ADFOR (adversary force), that’s another Marine, typically, forcing the commander to adapt tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) and innovate at mission speed.”</p><p>“PROTEUS enables commanders to immerse themselves in a future conflict where they can deploy capabilities against a realistic adversary,” Ryan Reeder, model and simulation director, MCWL Experiment Division, <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news-events/2021-06-22">said in a statement</a>. “Commanders can hone their battlefield skills, while also training subordinates on employment techniques, delivering a cohesive unit able to execute in a more effective manner.</p><p>Technically, DARPA’s involvement with the PROTEUS program has come to an end following its transfer to the Marine Corps Warfighting Lab where it is now being used for ADFOR training and developing new TTPs and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept_of_operations">CONOPS</a>. “My guess is they will mostly use it for their own purposes, as opposed to continuing to develop it,” Grayson said. “The Warfighting Lab is less focused on technology and more focused on our future force, concepts and what are our new tactics.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/darpa-proteus-program-gamifies-the-art-of-war-162033175.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cfa8de63-ac2a-4c89-bec1-3c19b47a1557</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:20:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628269181</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T16:59:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Industrials]]></category><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Armed Forces]]></category><category><![CDATA[Military & Defense]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/64d64820-f547-11eb-aa7d-0817d6d239d6" width="4928" height="3280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/64d64820-f547-11eb-aa7d-0817d6d239d6" width="4928" height="3280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ian Hitchcock via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BOWEN, AUSTRALIA - JULY 22: A U.S Marine is seen as troops disembark from landing craft in the background on July 22, 2019 in Bowen, Australia. Exercise Talisman Sabre 2019 is the largest exercise that the Australian Defence Force (ADF) conducts with all four services of the United States armed forces. The biennial exercise focuses on crisis action planning and humanitarian missions, enhancing participating nations' capabilities to deal with regional contingencies and terrorism. It is the first time the NZDF has been invited to participate fully, with NZDF personnel to be working as part of a large force led by the Australians and NZDF military assets will be integrated with those of the ADF and the US armed forces. (Photo by Ian Hitchcock/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Soldiers Participate In Bowen Beach Landing As Part Of Exercise Talisman Sabre 2019]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[This week's best deals: $70 off Sony's WH-1000XM4 headphones, and more]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;re steadily moving through August, and that means more summer deals are popping up all over. If you&#39;ve got your eye on a pair of new high-end headphones, we&#39;ve seen Sony&#39;s excellent WH-1000XM4 noise-cancelling over-ears fall back to $278, while Jabra&#39;s long-lasting Elite 85h model have returned to a budget-friendly $150. If better internet connectivity is what you&#39;re after, Amazon has dropped the three-pack of Google&#39;s WiFi mesh system to $150, providing a stronger WiFi network across a much larger area inside (and potentially outside) your home. Here are the best tech deals from this week that you can still get today.</p><h2>Sony WH-1000XM4</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c01f6e10-f384-11eb-b7dd-cdf3572777c6" alt="Sony XM4" data-uuid="19b6c8f5-9a6d-3582-a6d8-954ef8ea4fd3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Sony&#39;s excellent WH-1000XM4 ANC headphones" href="https://amzn.to/3jfAIwj">Sony&#39;s excellent WH-1000XM4 ANC headphones</a> often bounce up and down in price, so if you missed previous deals on them you&#39;re in luck. The wireless over-ears are back down to the $278 we saw in the Spring, a solid $72 saving on their typical price of $350.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Sony WH-1000XM4 at Amazon - $278" href="https://amzn.to/3jfAIwj">Buy Sony WH-1000XM4 at Amazon - $278</a></p><h2>Jabra Elite 85h</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/087d7640-ec45-11ea-b7fd-477fca667319" alt="Jabra Elite 85h" data-uuid="de12f9ec-36d9-4deb-99b8-dd33c378567f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Jabra Elite 85h headphones" href="https://amzn.to/3fDI5wF">Jabra Elite 85h headphones</a> are back down to a low of $150 at Amazon, which is around $100 off their normal price. They <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-12-jabra-elite-85h-review.html">earned a score of 84 from us</a> for their custom EQ and ANC modes, comfortable and attractive design and impressive battery life.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Jabra Elite 85h Wireless Noise-Canceling Headphones at Amazon - $150" href="https://amzn.to/3fDI5wF">Buy Jabra Elite 85h Wireless Noise-Canceling Headphones at Amazon - $150</a></p><h2>Google WiFi</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c9536310-f5f5-11eb-bfb2-99dc60bb5966" alt="Google WiFi" data-uuid="96dcb89a-adea-3707-b462-a9fb8e64dec6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Families who are still largely working and studying at home might find that their WiFi network is feeling the strain, especially if someone&#39;s setup is far away from the router. If you&#39;re on the lookout for an upgrade, it may be <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:worth considering the Google WiFi mesh system" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Wifi-System-Router-Replacement/dp/B08GG9CMLR?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=a28ac540f250a97d6669cd054110c7ca&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">worth considering the Google WiFi mesh system</a>. A three-pack of nodes currently costs $150 on Amazon. That&#39;s the lowest price we&#39;ve seen to date on the most recent model, which debuted in October at a price of $199 for the three-pack.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Google WiFi (three-pack) at Amazon - $149" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Wifi-System-Router-Replacement/dp/B08GG9CMLR?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=a28ac540f250a97d6669cd054110c7ca&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Buy Google WiFi (three-pack) at Amazon - $150</a></p><h2>Echo Show 5 (1st Gen)</h2><h2></h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/8a7e2a50-f44f-11eb-8f77-673e3366979c" alt="Amazon Echo Show 5" data-uuid="885368e9-a6cb-3c3c-bce9-542821e92180"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Amazon</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon&#39;s first-gen Echo Show 5" href="https://amzn.to/3jybf1F">Amazon&#39;s first-gen Echo Show 5</a> has hovered around <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-echo-show-5-first-gen-good-deal-081030616.html">the $45 mark</a> for the past week, but you&#39;ve had to be quick to secure it from different retailers. If you missed the chance to get the Alexa-powered <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-24-amazon-echo-show-5-review.html">smart display</a> at a discount, though, now&#39;s your chance to get one: It&#39;s available for $45 again at Amazon. That&#39;s the lowest price we&#39;ve seen for the device, where it&#39;s been selling for around $50 these past months.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Amazon Echo Show 5 (1st Gen) at Amazon - $45" href="https://amzn.to/3jybf1F">Buy Amazon Echo Show 5 (1st Gen) at Amazon - $45</a></p><h2>Apple Mac Mini M1 (512GB)</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/89325eb0-29d3-11eb-bddd-ca6343a2fd7b" data-uuid="0f6cfd24-271f-3488-b4c0-01345707fce8"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://amzn.to/3syaUPv">Mac Mini M1</a> with extra storage is back down to $799 right now, offering a saving of $100. This is a great time to pick up the latest Mac Mini if you&#39;ve wanted to upgrade your desktop to something more powerful that&#39;s also compact enough to fit into most desk setups.</p><h2>MacBook Air M1</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fo.aolcdn.com%252Fimages%252Fdims%253Fimage_uri%253Dhttps%25253A%25252F%25252Fo.aolcdn.com%25252Fimages%25252Fdims%25253Fimage_uri%25253Dhttps%2525253A%2525252F%2525252Fo.aolcdn.com%2525252Fimages%2525252Fdims%2525253Fimage_uri%2525253Dhttps%252525253A%252525252F%252525252Fs.yimg.com%252525252Fos%252525252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%252525252F2020-11%252525252Fc8aea820-28a0-11eb-9f89-5ddd62987703%25252526thumbnail%2525253D675%252525252C%25252526client%2525253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%25252526signature%2525253D790259e200511d5eacf45dd933ea3273bd9f0ab7%252526thumbnail%25253D675%2525252C%252526client%25253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%252526signature%25253D83d83f8db48d402dc1d03b160df1344185161af7%2526thumbnail%253D675%25252C%2526client%253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%2526signature%253Ddf892914338a0dfa3b25e1180f3ce2453444c590%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3D4add98fbbe26dcf8b9e06d3caec4de636178f186&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=5004966283eb0506834ee350b7353ca04f3ec9f4" data-uuid=""><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The latest <a href="https://amzn.to/3faLWRy">MacBook Air M1</a> with 512GB of storage continues to maintain the low price we saw last week, meaning you can still grab it for $1,099. It&#39;s one of the best laptops for most people, and it&#39;s a great option for students going back to school. The Air M1 earned a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-140031323.html">score of 94</a> from us for its incredibly fast performance, excellent keyboard and trackpad, good battery life and lack of fan noise.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy MacBook Air M1 (512GB) at Amazon - $1,099" href="https://amzn.to/3feauJt">Buy MacBook Air M1 (512GB) at Amazon - $1,099</a></p><h2></h2><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/weekly-tech-deals-sony-wh1000xm4-jabra-elite-mac-mini-160050738.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">28623f63-ce75-4e34-8f65-762b19fa603a</guid><dc:creator>Engadget</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628266742</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T16:19:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Engadget]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/6ad2b130-f378-11eb-b77f-ba77e059b6d6" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/6ad2b130-f378-11eb-b77f-ba77e059b6d6" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony WH-1000XM4]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony WH-1000XM4]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Stranger Things' season 4 will arrive in 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#39;s been 25 months since Netflix dropped <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-30-stranger-things-3-review.html">season three</a> of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/stranger%20things"><em>Stranger Things</em></a>. You&#39;ll have to remain patient a while longer before returning to Hawkins, however. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-30-netflix-stranger-things-season-4-duffer-brothers.html">Season four</a> of the sci-fi horror series will emerge in 2022.</p><div id="58271080039b4a77b9e3d3e193b18ed7"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gM5OVZtq8xM?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>Along with the release window news, Netflix dropped <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILwLN6hV-X8">another</a> teaser. Most of the 30-second video features shots from previous seasons, but there&#39;s a glimpse of a monster that appears to be far larger than the Mind Flayer or the Demogorgon.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This could be the most ambitious season of <em>Stranger Things</em> to date, as filming has <a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/stranger-things-season-4-trailer-1235036006/">taken place</a> in Georgia, Lithuania and New Mexico. Part of the season <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-14-stranger-things-4-teaser.html">will be set in Russia</a>, where Jim Hopper is held captive. Hopefully, Netflix is looking at an early 2022 release date so fans don&#39;t have to wait too much longer.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/stranger-things-season-4-release-date-153637041.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b01d0dbd-dd49-4e78-bdc1-9fbfe6db1aae</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:36:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628266104</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T16:08:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/71262d90-f6d0-11eb-bb3d-2a831366ba98" width="2130" height="1189" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/71262d90-f6d0-11eb-bb3d-2a831366ba98" width="2130" height="1189" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netflix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A still from Stranger Things season 4.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Stranger Things season 4]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter appoints 'grievance officer' to obey India's internet rules]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is scrambling to reassure India and reclaim its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-loses-legal-protections-india-094349491.html">liability protections</a> for user-made content. <em>Bloomberg</em><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-06/twitter-says-has-appointed-officials-to-comply-with-india-rules?sref=10lNAhZ9">reports</a> that Twitter has told an Indian court it appointed grievance and nodal officers to honor new rules demanding local full-time staff to handle handle issues like compliance and law enforcement matters. The court previously claimed Twitter was in &quot;total noncompliance&quot; and had stripped the protections, leaving Twitter legally vulnerable if users posed illegal material.</p><p>Police have filed cases against Twitter multiple times based on user actions, including child pornography violations or posting controversial political maps.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The social media giant isn&#39;t safe yet. The government will have to determine whether or not the executives put India in compliance with the rules. Another hearing is due on August 10th. Companies like Facebook, Google and Telegram have already complied the requirements.</p><p>Twitter has had a fractious relationship with the Indian government. The social media giant <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-defies-order-in-india-to-block-activists-journalists-and-politicians-092609430.html">refused to block critics</a> of the Indian government after officials threatened to arrest employees in early February. Accordingly, India ordered Twitter to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/india-orders-twitter-to-remove-covid-19-tweets-164716146.html">pull criticism of its pandemic response</a> after COVID-19 cases surged in April. The alleged rule violations just represented an escalation of already-high tensions in that regard. Not that Twitter has much choice but to comply — leaving the Indian market would deliver a serious blow to its business while having little impact on censorship in the country.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-appoints-india-officers-150458176.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d9ecf019-1039-412d-bf22-942c8d82dc09</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:04:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628262321</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T15:05:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2018-12/fc2822e0-fdef-11e8-9eff-50249c81f0c2" width="3507" height="2472" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2018-12/fc2822e0-fdef-11e8-9eff-50249c81f0c2" width="3507" height="2472" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anushree Fadnavis / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey addresses students during a town hall at the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) in New Delhi, India, November 12, 2018. REUTERS/Anushree Fadnavis]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[INDIA-TWITTER/CEO]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['PUBG' is now 'PUBG: Battlegrounds']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/pubg"><em><ins>PUBG</ins></em></a>, aka <em>PlayerUnknown&#39;s Battlegrounds</em>, has a new name. It&#39;s now called <em>PUBG: Battlegrounds</em>, which technically makes it <em>PlayerUnknown&#39;s Battlegrounds: Battlegrounds</em>. It seems publisher Krafton quietly made the change in July. On the surface, it&#39;s a silly rebranding akin to &quot;ATM machine,&quot; but there seems to be some reasonable logic behind the decision.</p><p>&quot;Krafton is actively expanding the PUBG brand through a variety of new experiences set in its universe,&quot; the publisher told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/hold-up-pubg-is-called-pubg-battlegrounds-now/"><em><ins>PC Gamer</ins></em></a>. &quot;Rebranding <em>PlayerUnknown&#39;s Battlegrounds</em> to <em>PUBG: Battlegrounds </em>is the first step in us realizing this vision. Additional titles in the franchise will carry the PUBG name, as you see with our upcoming game, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pubg-new-state-jumps-30-years-into-the-future-093749502.html"><em><ins>PUBG: New State</ins></em></a>.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The next game in the series, <em>PUBG: New State</em>, is a mobile title with a futuristic setting. <em>The Callisto Protocol</em>, a horror game from the creators of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Dead%20Space"><em><ins>Dead Space</ins></em></a>, is also connected to the franchise. The name hasn&#39;t been weighed down with the <em>PUBG </em>prefix just yet, though.</p><p>Many players have referred to the original game simply as <em>PUBG </em>for years, and with more games in the franchise on the way, it makes sense to differentiate it a bit. The rebranding also takes the game away from the equally baffling former title, especially for folks who don&#39;t know who the devil PlayerUnknown actually is. Brendan &quot;PlayerUnknown&quot; Greene is the man who ushered in the battle royale craze by creating an <em>ARMA 2 </em>mod and then leading development of <em>PUBG. </em>He <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-13-playerunknown-leaves-pubg.html"><ins>left the game in 2019</ins></a>.</p><p>Still, Krafton could have called the phenomenally successful game literally anything else rather than giving it another awkward name. Simply <em>PUBG </em>or even <em>PUBG: OG </em>or <em>PUBG: Where Are We Dropping? </em>would have been better.</p><p>Meanwhile, <em>PUBG</em>: <em>Battlegrounds </em>(sigh) is going free-to-play for a week to mark the game&#39;s collaboration with K-pop megastars Blackpink. It won&#39;t cost you a dime to play between August 10th and August 16th.</p><p><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/playerunknowns-battlegrounds/pubg-free-to-play-blackpink"><ins>According to</ins></a> leaker PlayerIGN, Krafton may be using that week to test the waters and &quot;gauge player responses&quot; before potentially making the game free-to-play permanently. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pubg-mobile-tesla-update-145129031.html"><em><ins>PUBG: Mobile</ins></em></a> is free, as are rival battles royale such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/fortnite"><em><ins>Fortnite</ins></em></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Apex%20Legends"><em><ins>Apex Legends</ins></em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Warzone"><em><ins>Call of Duty: Warzone</ins></em></a>.</p><div id="514f2e59bbc14d88a2617ec197b5151b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Announcing the official collaboration of PUBG: BATTLEGROUNDS and <a href="https://twitter.com/BLACKPINK?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BLACKPINK</a>! Jump into the game and check out the changes made to celebrate!<br><br>Disclaimer: Please note that the faces included in the video are not part of the BLACKPINK Collaboration Bundles in PUBG: BATTLEGROUNDS. <a href="https://t.co/Bj1ew8zj4S">pic.twitter.com/Bj1ew8zj4S</a></p>— PUBG: BATTLEGROUNDS (@PUBG) <a href="https://twitter.com/PUBG/status/1423177301706092546?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pubg-battlegrounds-name-change-free-week-blackpink-143533828.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fe93ae54-38c1-4fd4-be4f-a69f86dce189</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628260539</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T14:35:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/9adc3120-8967-11ea-99e7-5f2575e8e8af" width="1193" height="667" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/9adc3120-8967-11ea-99e7-5f2575e8e8af" width="1193" height="667" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[PUBG Corp]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[PlayerUnknown's Battlegrounds]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[PUBG]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Windows 11's new focus timer feature will work with Spotify]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft is betting that a little Spotify streaming could help sharpen your mind. <em>The Verge</em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612554/microsoft-windows-11-focus-sessions-spotify-feature">reports</a> that product chief Panos Panay has <a href="https://twitter.com/panos_panay/status/1423343837934546946">previewed</a> a Focus Sessions feature in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-hands-on-microsoft-insider-preview-215041175.html">Windows 11</a> that uses Spotify to help you concentrate. Based on the Pomodoro Technique that divides tasks into timed segments with breaks, the new Clock app mode asks you to choose a task (from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-to-do-update-wunderlist-closure-225333701.html">Microsoft To Do</a>, at least for now), set a timer and choose a Spotify playlist if you need a soundtrack. When the timer is done, your music will stop and let you know it&#39;s time for a brief pause.</p><p>Focus Sessions aren&#39;t yet available in public Insider Previews, but there&#39;s a real chance they&#39;ll be available in the finished version of Windows 11 arriving late this year. Microsoft has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-08-08-spotify-arrives-on-xbox-one.html">integrated Spotify with Xbox consoles</a> before, but this appears to be the first major effort in Windows.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The concept of a Pomodoro app isn&#39;t new, but this will be built into Windows — and Microsoft is clearly hoping the Spotify tie-in will make a difference. It could be an important competitive advantage, too. Windows 11&#39;s focus elements could help it compete against <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-preview-public-beta-175927010.html">macOS Monterey&#39;s</a> Focus modes, not to mention parallel similar features in Android <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html">and iOS</a>.</p><div id="a6999f8d1b174eb7be28d01cd57c64f5"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Another first look from the team...<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FocusSessions?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FocusSessions</a> on <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Windows11?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Windows11</a> coming soon. This has been a game-changer for me, especially with <a href="https://twitter.com/Spotify?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Spotify</a> integration  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Productivity?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Productivity</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Creativity?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Creativity</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WindowsInsiders?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WindowsInsiders</a><a href="https://t.co/HfJh4niDiS">pic.twitter.com/HfJh4niDiS</a></p>— Panos Panay (@panos_panay) <a href="https://twitter.com/panos_panay/status/1423343837934546946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-focus-sessions-spotify-134158939.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8932f5b9-c72e-48e6-b960-0047de64e2c9</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:41:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628257321</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T13:42:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bb96e760-f6b3-11eb-b779-579d3b31f542" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bb96e760-f6b3-11eb-b779-579d3b31f542" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Windows 11 Focus Sessions using Spotify]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Windows 11 Focus Sessions using Spotify]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast: Digging into Google Tensor and the Pixel 6]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, Cherlynn is joined by guest co-host <a href="https://www.engadget.com/about/editors/terrence-obrien">Terrence O’Brien</a> and senior tech correspondent at Insider Lisa Eadicicco to discuss <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-faq-specs-ai-ml-160021397.html">Google’s own mobile chip Tensor</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-first-look-tensor-processor-better-cameras-160005582.html">the Pixel 6</a>. We share more insight from having seen and used the phones in person, too. Plus, we go over some updates from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html">the Activision Blizzard case</a> and a handful of new gadgets.</p><p>Listen below, or subscribe on your podcast app of choice. If you&#39;ve got suggestions or topics you&#39;d like covered on the show, be sure to <a href="mailto:podcast@engadget.com?subject=Engadget%20Podcast%20Feedback"><strong>email us</strong></a> or drop a note in the comments! And be sure to check out our other podcasts, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-01-engadget-podcasts.html">Morning After and Engadget News</a>!</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="dc50e82bc63049c1b44d5af8dfb7fd6e"><iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1101042754&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/googles-tensor-and-pixel-6" title="Google&#x002019;s Tensor and Pixel 6" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Google’s Tensor and Pixel 6</a></div></div><p></p><p><br>Subscribe!</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-engadget-podcast/id1142790530?mt=2">iTunes</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3EC3dMIRB99dkvoSBeSO7G?si=f7UALGKmRDWtOrU8Z4-uiQ">Spotify</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://pca.st/mlY3">Pocket Casts</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/engadget/the-engadget-podcast">Stitcher</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://podcasts.google.com/?feed=aHR0cDovL2ZlZWRzLnNvdW5kY2xvdWQuY29tL3VzZXJzL3NvdW5kY2xvdWQ6dXNlcnM6MjQ1MjIwOTU4L3NvdW5kcy5yc3M&amp;ep=14">Google Podcasts</a></p></li></ul><h2><br><strong>Topics</strong><br></h2><ul><li><p>Google announces Tensor, its own mobile chip, will debut on the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro – 1:47</p></li><li><p>Activision/Blizzard hit with another lawsuit – 33:08&nbsp;</p></li><li><p>NLRB recommends a new union election for Amazon’s Alabama warehouse – 40:04</p></li><li><p>Google Nest launches new battery-powered doorbell and security cameras – 43:06</p></li><li><p>Amazon releases a soap dispenser that counts to 20  – 47:58</p></li><li><p>R2-D2 Tamagotchi is coming later this year – 49:26</p></li><li><p>Working on – 52:23</p></li><li><p>Pop culture picks – 56:40</p></li></ul><h2><br>Video livestream</h2><div id="db83082766a34432b0672955e20834cc"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6IWMVJXxIb0?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p><p><strong><em>Credits</em></strong><br><em>Hosts: Cherlynn Low and Terrence O&#39;Brien</em><br><em>Guest: Lisa Eadicicco</em><br><em>Producer: Ben Ellman</em><br><em>Livestream producers: Julio Barrientos, Owen Davidoff</em>, <em>Luke Brooks</em><br><em>Graphics artists: Luke Brooks, Kyle Maack</em><br><em>Music: Dale North and Terrence O&#39;Brien</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/engadget-podcast-google-tensor-pixel-6-pixel-6-pro-ai-photography-123008838.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1fa1b4f3-8592-4109-a502-335b5da2716d</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 12:30:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628224540</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T04:35:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c8e851c0-2b3d-11eb-baea-6c6fe29971fb" width="703" height="469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/f43b53b0-909f-11ea-87fd-d8d721459924" width="1600" height="719" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jabra's Elite 85h ANC headphones fall back to $150 on Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://amzn.to/3fDI5wF">Jabra&#39;s Elite 85h</a> headphones are available for $150 on Amazon once again, giving you another chance to grab them at the price if you weren&#39;t able to last month. We praised the wireless headphones for offering active noise cancellation that rivals the technologies used by Bose and Sony and gave it a score of 84 in our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-12-jabra-elite-85h-review.html">review</a>. The device was priced at $300 upon launch in 2019, which we felt was a bit too high for what it can do. Amazon has been selling it for $174 after its sale in July, but now it&#39;s back down to its lowest price on the website.</p><p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3fDI5wF">Buy Jabra Elite 85h Wireless Noise-Canceling Headphones at Amazon - $150</a></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>To be clear, only the Titanium Black version is on sale for $150 on Jabra&#39;s official store on Amazon, while the rest will cost you a bit more. If you don&#39;t mind the lack of color options, though, one of the best features we liked about the headphones is their insane battery life that can last up for to 41 hours with noise cancelation turned off. During our tests, we used the Elite 85h for around two to three hours a day for seven days and still had 85 percent of power left by the time we were done.&nbsp;</p><p>We also liked that it has EQ and noise-cancellation presets you can choose from based on your environment. You can have different settings for use in public and in private, and you don&#39;t even have to manually switch between them. The headphones have the ability to analyze noise, so they can detect your location and switch to the appropriate profile.</p><p>In addition, we praised the headphones for having simple controls and a better design than some of their rivals. We noted in our review that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wh1000xm3-headphones-deal-114006907.html">Sony&#39;s 1000XM3</a> has better sound quality, but that device will set you back $100 more on Amazon right now.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jabra-elite-85h-anc-headphones-150-amazon-115755893.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1ee5d5ff-eace-4410-b008-63fb6b043f73</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:57:55 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628251119</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T11:58:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/cfa373f0-f6a3-11eb-bde9-787f0a47085d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/cfa373f0-f6a3-11eb-bde9-787f0a47085d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Billy Steele/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Jabra Elite 85h]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Jabra Elite 85h]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Disney’s immersive Star Wars experience is really expensive]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Disney&#39;s <a href="https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/star-wars-galactic-starcruiser/overview/"><ins>Star Wars: Galactic Starcruiser</ins></a> is going to cost you. For two guests in a standard cabin for a two-night adventure, you’ll have to set aside just shy of $5,000.</p><p>Disney is promising it as &quot;part live immersive theater, part themed environment, part culinary extravaganza, part real-life role-playing game.&quot; The company offers more details on how your story might unfold, with the ability to choose to side with the First Order (boo), or ally with the resistance.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-star-wars-galactic-starcruiser-prices-092012242.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/6b0f7340-f5c1-11eb-9bcf-2f13c73392e1" style="height:598;width:1064;" alt="Disney" data-uuid="f42bfd5d-1dfe-3feb-9880-ce13215b06e5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Disney</div></figure></a><p>There will also be lightsaber lessons, optional missions and the chance to interact with iconic SW characters who will, well, behave like video game NPCs. According to reports, each Starcruiser adventure is several months of salary one-of-a-kind, so if you can afford one journey on the cruiser, you can probably book a second, different, adventure.</p><p>The posit sounds very Westworld, and like that fictional theme park, it seems unashamedly aimed at only the wealthiest Star Wars fans. It also sounds like there will be no Star Wars experience like it. Temptation, however, might be outweighed by economic reality. Then again, it seems positively cheap compared to a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-reopens-ticket-sales-073418808.html"><ins>ticket to actual space</ins></a>.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-doorbell-camera-battery-powered-floodlight-130016075.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Google&#39;s upgraded Nest Cam and Doorbell are here</a></h2><h3>Floodlight options and battery-powered devices.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-doorbell-camera-battery-powered-floodlight-130016075.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/0df09590-f558-11eb-bebf-96205eeb3be3" style="height:3184;width:4943;" alt="Battery-powered Google Nest Cam and Doorbell" data-uuid="7337b315-6027-3fb6-8a72-87b2f4fff644"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure></a><p>Google’s first battery-powered Nest Cam and Doorbell can be installed just about anywhere around your home, and you can even connect them to a wired power source, if you prefer. The battery life depends on how many recorded events the devices detect and factors like the temperature and settings. Google says the Doorbell’s battery will run for up to six months on a single charge, while the Nest Cam can run for up to seven months before you need to recharge it over USB. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-doorbell-camera-battery-powered-floodlight-130016075.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-ios-15-193820644.html">Apple announces new iPhone features to detect child sex abuse</a></h2><h3>The Messages, Photos and Siri features will also come to watchOS and macOS.</h3><h3></h3><p>Apple has detailed new features focused on child safety. With the release of iOS 15, watchOS 8 and macOS Monterey later this year, the company says it will introduce a variety of child safety features across Messages, Photos and Siri.</p><p>To start, the Messages app will include new notifications to warn children, as well as their parents, when they either send or receive sexually explicit photos. When someone sends a child an inappropriate image, the app will blur it and display several warnings. Apple will also introduce new software tools in iOS and iPadOS that will allow the company to detect when someone uploads content to iCloud that shows children involved in sexually explicit acts. Rather than scanning photos when they&#39;re uploaded to the cloud, the system will use an on-device database of &quot;known&quot; images. These features and more will come to devices later this year. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-ios-15-193820644.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/president-biden-2030-ev-target-134025373.html">President Biden wants half of new vehicles to be zero-emissions by 2030</a></h2><p>Some carmakers and states want an even faster transition.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/president-biden-2030-ev-target-134025373.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/697ae410-b809-11eb-bff8-50ef7f64c83f" style="height:3668;width:5500;" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden delivers remarks after touring Ford Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Dearborn, Michigan, U.S., May 18, 2021.  REUTERS/Leah Millis" data-uuid="80970ffc-7e25-3b82-9249-62ba9f498981"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Leah Millis / reuters</div></figure></a><p>President Biden’s latest executive order sets a target for half of all new vehicles sold in 2030 to have some form of zero-emissions driving, whether it&#39;s a pure EV, plug-in hybrid or hydrogen fuel cell vehicle. The move is meant to not only promote clean transportation and limit climate change but help the US &quot;outcompete&quot; a Chinese car industry that&#39;s quickly shifting toward electrified vehicles. It could be an ambitious target: EVs have <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/06/07/todays-electric-vehicle-market-slow-growth-in-u-s-faster-in-china-europe/"><ins>represented</ins></a> about 2 percent of US car sales for the past three years, according to the International Energy Agency and Pew Research. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/president-biden-2030-ev-target-134025373.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-2021-q1-financial-post-animal-crossing-slump-100125720.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Nintendo&#39;s sales can&#39;t keep up with last year&#39;s lockdown boom</a></h2><h3>The success of ‘Animal Crossing’ makes business as usual look worse by comparison.</h3><h3></h3><p>In Nintendo’s latest financial report, it posted an operating profit of 119 billion yen, roughly $1.1 billion. That is, however, a 17.3 percent drop compared to the 144 billion yen ($1.3 billion) posted this time last year, when Switch consoles were consistently sold out and most of us were trapped indoors, isolating. Nintendo didn’t release a game that could match the success of <em>Animal Crossing</em> the year before. Amusingly, the company <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2021/210805_3e.pdf"><ins>made a graph</ins></a> to show that, if you remove the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/animal-crossing-video-game-sales-diablo-ii-virtual-economies-131547613.html"><em><ins>Animal Crossing</ins></em></a> spike, its software sales have constantly increased since at least 2018. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-2021-q1-financial-post-animal-crossing-slump-100125720.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><p><strong>But wait, there’s more...</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/senior-apple-employee-alleges-sexism-at-work-is-put-on-indefinite-leave-235626960.html"><ins>Senior Apple employee alleges sexism at work, is put on indefinite leave</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html"><ins>Inside the sexual harassment lawsuit at Activision Blizzard</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/paramount-plus-14-south-park-movies-171903072.html"><ins>Paramount+ is getting 14 South Park movies starting with two this year</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-walter-isaacson-biography-122527201.html"><ins>Elon Musk confirms Walter Isaacson is writing his biography</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/back-4-blood-turtle-rock-190023342.html"><ins>What you&#39;ll get in the &#39;Back 4 Blood&#39; open beta</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fba-grading-returns-wholesale-policy-changes-114014902.html"><ins>Amazon launches new resale programs following backlash over stock destruction</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-reopens-ticket-sales-073418808.html"><ins>Virgin Galactic starts selling tickets to space again for $450,000 per seat</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-treadmill-owners-will-be-able-to-run-again-without-a-paid-subscription-065018321.html"><ins>Peloton treadmill owners will be able to run again without a subscription</ins></a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-disneys-immersive-star-wars-experience-is-really-expensive-111515094.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">86a93d9f-ba46-4366-b7e2-a41ccdb7d858</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:15:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628248173</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T11:09:42+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/358de7c0-ace6-11eb-b37f-91b13fe8707c" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/358de7c0-ace6-11eb-b37f-91b13fe8707c" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Disney]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Disney's retractable lightsaber for Star Wars: Galactic Starcruiser]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Disney's retractable lightsaber for Star Wars: Galactic Starcruiser]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft is merging its OneNote apps for Windows]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the next 12 months, Microsoft is <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/office-365-blog/what-s-coming-to-onenote/ba-p/2612960">rolling out</a> a series of updates for its OneNote apps on Windows with the intention of creating a single user experience. At the moment, there are two versions people can use: The OneNote app installed with Office and the OneNote for Windows 10 app available in the Microsoft Store. Microsoft will update the OneNote app with features currently exclusive to its counterpart pre-installed on Windows 10, though, and it will also give the program a visual refresh.</p><p>Microsoft originally intended to kill the OneNote app when the one for Windows 10 became available, but it changed its plans and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-08-microsoft-onenote-2016-revival.html">revived</a> the app in 2019. It upgraded the note-taking program with a bunch of new features and bundled it with Office installs a year later. Now, the tech giant says it will update OneNote with visual elements that it&#39;ll share with other Windows apps as part of Microsoft&#39;s efforts to give Windows 11 a more seamless look. The merged OneNote application will also gain access to the latest Microsoft pen and ink features, as well as a new navigational UI layout option.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Those already using the app installed with Office don&#39;t have to do anything but wait for the upcoming updates to roll out. As for those using OneNote for Windows 10, Microsoft will send them an in-app invite to upgrade to the other application once it&#39;s ready. The company says it expects to start sending out invitations in the second half of 2022, and it now advising organizations to make their personnel use the OneNote app, so they don&#39;t have to migrate next year.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e7886240-f69f-11eb-9f7f-936b2c85885f" style="height:313;width:491;" alt="OneNote" data-uuid="9dd472a9-c676-392d-9afc-48693e16a6a5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-onenote-app-windows-102737016.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ca15bee5-4ba0-4994-b0b6-0793173b68e0</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:27:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628245701</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T10:28:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bb4b8220-f695-11eb-bdf6-626b1e0375b1" width="8058" height="5372" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/bb4b8220-f695-11eb-bdf6-626b1e0375b1" width="8058" height="5372" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ArtistGNDphotography via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Side view of beautiful businesswoman in home office.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Concentrated woman is working at home.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Detroit lets automakers test smart parking technology in a real garage]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The city of Detroit in partnership with both Ford and Bosch is about to open a new <a href="https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2021/08/05/detroit-smart-parking-lab.html">Smart Parking Lab</a>, hosted in Detroit’s Bedrock Assembly Garage. It’s a real-world environment to test future autonomous technologies that could be used to refine autonomous valet parking into a product. Opening in September, the facility will also enable these companies to test if it’s possible to introduce automatic smart charging into the system.</p><p>The Detroit Smart Parking Lab is designed to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ford-bosch-automated-parking-solution-detroit-103506308.html">continue work showcased last summer</a>, when Ford and Bosch showed off a self-parking Ford Escape in that same building. The vehicle was able to drive through the car park without human assistance, find a space, and reverse park into it without any stress. It’s hoped that, in some far-flung future when climate change doesn’t kill us all, that this sort of automatic valet parking could free people up to spend more time doing anything other than fighting for a space in a multi-storey car park.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As well as Ford and Bosch, rental company Enterprise is going to test how this technology could streamline its own processes. It hopes that cars that drive themselves to a valet station, then recharge themselves before parking back on the lot ready for pickup will reduce dead time between rentals. At this stage, at least, the hope is to just get the cars to park themselves in a manner that’s cost-effective for the company.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/detroit-smart-parking-lab-ford-bosch-enterprise-autonomous-valet-094708875.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3143d6aa-5c8c-4cc7-bf44-196ef53d50a1</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 09:47:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628251599</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T12:06:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/6944fc50-f699-11eb-bd77-0606559683f5" width="880" height="495" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/6944fc50-f699-11eb-bd77-0606559683f5" width="880" height="495" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[DSPL]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Concept render]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Detroit Smart Parking Lab]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic starts selling tickets to space again for $450,000 per seat]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You now have a chance to purchase a seat aboard one of Virgin Galactic&#39;s space tours — provided you can afford to pay $450,000 for it. The company has reopened ticket sales less than a month after <a href="https://www.engadget.com/can-richard-branson-really-call-himself-an-astronaut-after-sundays-virgin-galactic-flight-170015596.html">Richard Branson</a>, its founder, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-richard-branson-spaceflight-complete-154012847.html">flew</a> with other &quot;mission specialists&quot; for Virgin Galactic&#39;s first fully crewed spaceflight. It made the announcement alongside its <a href="https://investors.virgingalactic.com/news/news-details/2021/Virgin-Galactic-Announces-Second-Quarter-2021-Financial-Results/default.aspx">financial results</a> for the second quarter of the year, wherein it also said that the private space corporation &quot;made meaningful progress towards commencing commercial service in 2022.&quot;</p><p>Virgin Galactic is giving you three consumer options to choose from. In addition to a single seat that costs almost half a million, it&#39;s also selling multi-seat packages for groups and offering full-flight buy outs. The current iteration of the company&#39;s VSS Unity spacecraft can seat four passengers in addition to two pilots, so selling full flights isn&#39;t out of the realm of possibility. Virgin Galactic will prioritize its &quot;significant list of early hand-raisers,&quot; though it will create a follow-on priority list for customers interested in reserving future flights.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/05/virgin-galactic-spce-q2-2021-results-.html"><em>CNBC</em></a> notes, its next scheduled flight will have members of the Italian Air Force onboard. After that, the company will take a break until mid-2022 to refurbish VMS Eve, its jet-powered carrier aircraft. Since there will be one more scheduled test flight after that period, that means Virgin Galactic is delaying its first official flight for paying astronauts again. Earlier this year, the company was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-delays-space-tourism-flights-2022-140906661.html">hoping</a> to launch its first commercial flight in early 2022, but it now told <em>CNBC</em> that its new target is sometime in the late third quarter of 2022.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-reopens-ticket-sales-073418808.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ff47e696-7505-49cd-a1cc-332d8b9a0808</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 07:34:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628232133</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T06:42:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f2033650-f677-11eb-af9e-480c3db0b3ad" width="1600" height="1020" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f2033650-f677-11eb-af9e-480c3db0b3ad" width="1600" height="1020" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Jason Vancil for Virgin Galactic]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon delays employee office return until 2022 amid COVID-19 surge]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After previously announcing it expected corporate employees to return to the office on September 7th this year, Amazon has announced a further delay until January 3rd, 2022, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/amazon-delays-office-return-until-next-year-memo-2021-08-05/"><em>Reuters</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>has reported. The change of plans comes amid a surge of the highly contagious COVID-19 Delta variant across the US. &quot;As we continue to closely watch local conditions related to COVID-19, we are adjusting our guidance for corporate employees,&quot; the company said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p>Shortly after the pandemic started, Amazon said it expected employees to return to the office in October of 2020. That date was pushed back to 2021 as multiple waves of the virus forced lockdowns and business closures across the US.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Google and Microsoft also recently announced that they&#39;d be pushing back office returns until October 2021, later than the September date that Microsoft <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-delays-office-reopening-covid-19-215417217.html">originally planned</a>. However, while both Google and Microsoft require that any employees returning to the office be vaccinated, Amazon has said that unvaccinated employees may return as long as they wear masks.&nbsp;</p><p>Like other tech companies, Amazon has allowed for a hybrid office/home work structure due to the pandemic. However, in March this year, it seemed eager to get everyone back to the office. &quot;Our plan is to return to an office-centric culture as our baseline. We believe it enables us to invent, collaborate, and learn together most effectively,&quot; the company said in its <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/amazons-covid-19-blog-updates-on-how-were-responding-to-the-crisis#covid-latest">vaccination and testing blog</a>. Now, that will be delayed for at least another five months.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-delays-hq-office-return-until-2022-amid-covid-19-surge-055819058.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">19509a64-77c0-4b49-a13c-c616669e254f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 05:58:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628229501</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T05:58:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/ddcf85a0-f67a-11eb-bf7c-d870a5621da3" width="5226" height="3554" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/ddcf85a0-f67a-11eb-bf7c-d870a5621da3" width="5226" height="3554" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Lindsey Wasson / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The second and third floors of the new Amazon Spheres are seen during a grand opening event at Amazon's Seattle headquarters in Seattle, Washington, U.S., January 29, 2018.    REUTERS/Lindsey Wasson]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AMAZON.COM-SPHERES/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Evil Dead: The Game' is delayed until February 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year, Boss Team and Saber Interactive <a href="https://twitter.com/EvilDeadTheGame/status/1423282742586875909">announced</a> that <em>Evil Dead: The Game</em> with Bruce Campbell reprising his original movie role would arrive sometime in 2021. Now, the developers have <a href="https://twitter.com/EvilDeadTheGame/status/1423282742586875909">tweeted out</a> an update with a specific and slightly later release date: February 2022.&nbsp;</p><div id="70f54644a471497990f071710cef9d7f"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Evil Dead: The Game will be releasing in February 2022<br>Hey groovy gamers, we&#39;re targeting a new release date to give the team some extra time for polish and to ensure this is the ultimate Evil Dead experience you’re all waiting for! <a href="https://t.co/c5I4OSQshA">pic.twitter.com/c5I4OSQshA</a></p>— EvilDeadTheGame (@EvilDeadTheGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/EvilDeadTheGame/status/1423282742586875909?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The reason for the delay is to &quot;give the team some extra time for polish and to ensure this is the ultimate <em>Evil Dead</em> experience you&#39;re all waiting for,&quot; the team tweeted. &quot;This additional time is also allowing us to implement a single-player option that will let you enjoy the game when you are without your co-op compadres.&quot;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As we saw in the launch trailer in December, Campbell&#39;s Ash along with Kelly and crew have to work together to fight Deadites led by a powerful demon. You can think of it as a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/resident-evil-dead-by-daylight-jill-leon-nemesis-192940943.html"><em>Dead by Daylight</em></a>-style asymmetric title with a chainsaw hand and Bruce Campbell&#39;s clever catchphrases. It also comes with a big dollop of nostalgia with familiar characters, locales and plenty of gore in the form of blood-soaked zombies.</p><p><em>Evil Dead: The Game</em> will offer &quot;multiplayer co-op and PvP for PC, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and Nintendo Switch,&quot; according to the developer&#39;s <a href="https://evildeadthegame.com/en/">website</a>. They advised that you stay tuned to their Twitter page &quot;for more information about new character updates, pre-order availability, and the next gameplay video featuring Bruce Campbell.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/evil-dead-the-game-will-arrive-in-february-2022-041900474.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f0a4d083-2dda-4782-b58a-9bf3d057c33d</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 04:19:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628223542</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T04:19:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Commodity Markets]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/37f8bfe0-f669-11eb-aec7-65b10c51e31c" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/37f8bfe0-f669-11eb-aec7-65b10c51e31c" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Saber Interactive]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['Evil Dead: The Game' is delayed until February 2022]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Evil Dead: The Game' is delayed until February 2022]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[FTC rebukes Facebook for ‘misleading’ comments about NYU researchers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, Facebook <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-disables-accounts-nyu-ad-observatory-project-091040346.html"><ins>followed through</ins></a> on its threats to cut a group of New York University researchers off from its platform. The researchers were part of a project called the <a href="https://adobservatory.org/"><ins>Ad Observatory</ins></a>, which recruited volunteers to study how Facebook targets political ads on its platform.</p><p>In it decision to ban the researchers, Facebook repeatedly referred to its obligations to the FTC saying it was acting against the researchers “in line with our privacy program under the FTC Order” — a reference to the company’s 2019 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-12-facebook-ftc.html"><ins>settlement</ins></a> with the agency over lax privacy practices. But the social network’s actions were <a href="https://knightcolumbia.org/content/researchers-nyu-knight-institute-condemn-facebooks-effort-to-squelch-independent-research-about-misinformation"><ins>roundly criticized</ins></a> by the research community and free speech advocates, who said the company was preventing legitimate research under the guise of “scraping.” As <em>Wired</em> pointed out, the company’s agreement with the FTC doesn’t even prohibit what the researchers were actually doing.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Now, the FTC has <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/consumer-blog/2021/08/letter-acting-director-bureau-consumer-protection-samuel"><ins>weighed in</ins></a>, calling the company’s explanation of its actions was “misleading” and “inaccurate.” In a sharply worded letter addressed to Mark Zuckerberg, Acting Director of the Bureau of Consumer Protection Samuel Levine, said that he was “disappointed by how your company has conducted itself in this matter.”</p><p>“The FTC is committed to protecting the privacy of <em>people</em>, and efforts to shield targeted advertising practices from scrutiny run counter to that mission,” Levine wrote.  “Had you honored your commitment to contact us in advance, we would have pointed out that the consent decree does not bar Facebook from creating exceptions for good-faith research in the public interest. Indeed, the FTC supports efforts to shed light on opaque business practices, especially around surveillance-based advertising. While it is not our role to resolve individual disputes between Facebook and third parties, we hope that the company is not invoking privacy – much less the FTC consent order – as a pretext to advance other aims.”</p><p>Facebook didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ftc-letter-facebook-nyu-ad-observatory-014113346.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">552840b0-0921-4b86-8f95-a6b9db2c8167</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 01:41:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628214073</ingested><modified>2021-08-06T01:41:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/47346ad0-f656-11eb-a3f7-05a046a365f5" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/47346ad0-f656-11eb-a3f7-05a046a365f5" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook logo displayed on a phone screen is seen through raindrops on the window in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on July 17, 2021.  (Photo Ilustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TikTok And Facebook Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Senior Apple employee alleges sexism at work, is put on indefinite leave]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple is facing questions about its handling of sexism in the workplace after it placed a female employee on leave following tweets about her experiences at the company. Ashley Gjøvik, a senior engineering program manager with Apple, says she has spent months speaking with Apple about unsafe working conditions, sexism and a hostile work environment.</p><p>Her comments were <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610112/apple-female-engineering-manager-leave-sexism-work-environment">first reported</a> by <em>The Verge</em>, which notes the company closed a previous investigation into Gjøvik&#39;s claims — apparently without taking any action. Gjøvik said Apple initially responded to her complaints of sexism <a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1421220496444592128"><ins>by suggesting</ins></a> she request “disability accommodations.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On Wednesday, she was placed on “indefinite paid administrative leave” while Apple conducts a new investigation. In a statement to <em>The Verge</em>, she said the company “implied they did not want me on Slack where I had been vocal about my concerns with certain policies at the company.”</p><div id="bc064550813d482faa0a538ef191ba3b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">So, following raising concerns to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Apple</a> about <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexism?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#sexism</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/hostileworkenvironment?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#hostileworkenvironment</a>, &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/unsafeworkconditions?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#unsafeworkconditions</a>, I&#39;m now on indefinite paid administrative leave per <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Apple</a> employee relations, while they investigate my concerns. This seems to include me not using Apple&#39;s internal Slack.</p>— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) <a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1423014977661591552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>In a series of tweets, Gjøvik provided several examples of interactions she brought to the attention of Apple’s employee relations, who allegedly told her the behavior was “ok.” In one exchange, a manager referred to her “tone” in presentations, and said “I didn’t hear you going up an octave at the end of your statements.” She added that comments about her tone were also included in a mid-year review at one point.</p><div id="68731da58bff440f8c5799836899a30c"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Y&#39;all, I&#39;m a senior engineering program manager with decades of professional experience &amp; it was even in my mid-year review one year... <br><br>Someone needs to give me a Purple Heart. <a href="https://t.co/UCRqyTUtSR">pic.twitter.com/UCRqyTUtSR</a></p>— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) <a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1422381884324028425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>She <a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1422617203237556230"><ins>also said</ins></a> that Apple employee relations told her it was “okay” after she received complaints that a diversity training she led was “too hard on the white man.” In <a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1422953562724737024"><ins>another exchange</ins></a>, she said a “heartfelt email” asking leadership to show “support of women and condemn sexism and sexual assault” in 2018 was brushed off — an interaction the company’s employee relations also allegedly said was okay.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;We are and have always been deeply committed to creating and maintaining a positive and inclusive workplace,” an Apple spokesperson said in a statement. “We take all concerns seriously and we thoroughly investigate whenever a concern is raised and, out of respect for the privacy of any individuals involved, we do not discuss specific employee matters.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/senior-apple-employee-alleges-sexism-at-work-is-put-on-indefinite-leave-235626960.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8d738cfe-3090-4a4c-a7f8-a55d5f444ae5</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 23:56:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628207787</ingested><modified>2021-08-05T23:56:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/fefb9050-c7a6-11eb-bfb6-5de7053a3b66" width="5000" height="3335" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/fefb9050-c7a6-11eb-bfb6-5de7053a3b66" width="5000" height="3335" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[TOKYO, JAPAN - 2021/05/25: Apple brand logo seen inside an Apple store in Omotesando, Tokyo. (Photo by Stanislav Kogiku/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple brand logo seen inside an Apple store in Omotesando,...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces co-host feature lets users share moderation duties]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter’s experiment with ephemeral content may have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-kills-fleets-200051318.html">ended earlier in the week</a>, but its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-spaces-expansion-ticketing-170035722.html">take on Clubhouse</a> is going stronger than ever. Starting this week, Spaces hosts can invite other individuals to help them with moderation duties.</p><div id="f57c673373fd41e2bedca6c25e1361ab"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">making it easier to manage your Space…introducing co-hosting!<br><br>- hosts have two co-host invites they can send<br>- the table just got bigger: 1 host, 2 co-hosts, and 10 speakers<br>- co-hosts can help invite speakers, manage requests, remove participants, pin Tweets and more! <a href="https://t.co/s76JFbhTL2">pic.twitter.com/s76JFbhTL2</a></p>— Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1423333566675628039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>With today’s announcement, a single Space can include one host, two co-hosts and up to 10 speakers. As a co-host, you can invite additional people to talk, mute and remove rowdy participants and pin tweets. However, you won’t be able to remove the original host or your counterpart, nor can you end a broadcast. Adding a co-host is done through an invite system that allows you to search for specific users.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Of course, Twitter isn’t the only company making audio broadcasts an integral part of what it offers users. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-audio-podcast-features-clubhouse-181726338.html">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-stage-channels-203930584.html">Discord</a> quickly added Clubhouse-like features to their platforms following the app’s early <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-is-clubhouse-app-130015640.html">post-release success</a>. And if you <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-greenroom-locker-room-rebranding-221537708.html">believe Spotify CEO Daniel Ek</a>, most online services are likely to add live audio as a way for their users to communicate, much like they did when it came to video and Stories.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-spaces-co-host-feature-220436000.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2430ccfd-368f-4939-9bc6-11217a781267</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:04:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628200280</ingested><modified>2021-08-05T21:51:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/0c075350-beca-11eb-9bff-1ad572e04754" width="3888" height="2592" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/0c075350-beca-11eb-9bff-1ad572e04754" width="3888" height="2592" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[UKRAINE - 2021/03/12: In this photo illustration the Twitter Spaces page is seen on a smartphone screen  with a Twitter logo in the background. 
Twitter Spaces, the rival of the social Clubhouse network, is working towards a public launch in April, as the company announced on Twitter, reportedly by media. (Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration the Twitter Spaces page is seen...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple announces new iPhone features to detect child sex abuse]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-scan-iphones-child-abuse-neuralmatch-185009882.html">report</a> on work the company was doing to create a tool that scans iPhones for child abuse images, Apple has <a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/">published a post</a> that provides more details on its efforts related to child safety. With the release of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-15-public-beta-testing-hands-on-172526761.html">iOS 15</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watchos-8-beta-hands-on-175457215.html">watchOS 8</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-os-monterey-preview-public-beta-175927010.html">macOS Monterey</a> later this year, the company says it will introduce a variety of child safety features across Messages, Photos and Siri.&nbsp;</p><p>To start, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-messages-ios-15-shared-with-you-173052730.html">Messages app</a> will include new notifications that will warn children, as well as their parents, when they either send or receive sexually explicit photos. When someone sends a child an inappropriate image, the app will blur it and display several warnings. &quot;It&#39;s not your fault, but sensitive photos and videos can be used to hurt you,&quot; says one of the notifications, per a screenshot Apple shared.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As an additional precaution, the company says Messages can also notify parents if their child decides to go ahead and view a sensitive image. &quot;Similar protections are available if a child attempts to send sexually explicit photos,&quot; according to Apple. The company notes the feature uses on-device machine learning to determine whether a photo is explicit. Moreover, Apple does not have access to the messages themselves. This feature will be available to family iCloud accounts.&nbsp;</p><p>Apple will also introduce new software tools in iOS and iPadOS that will allow the company to detect when someone uploads content to iCloud that shows children involved in sexually explicit acts. The company says it will use the technology to notify the <a href="https://www.missingkids.org/HOME">National Center for Missing and Exploited Children</a> (NCMEC), which will in turn work with law enforcement agencies across the US. &quot;Apple’s method of detecting known CSAM [Child Sexual Abuse Material] is designed with user privacy in mind,&quot; the company claims.&nbsp;</p><p>Rather than scanning photos when they&#39;re uploaded to the cloud, the system will use an on-device database of &quot;known&quot; images provided by NCMEC and other organizations. The company says that the database assigns a hash to the photos, which acts as a kind of digital fingerprint for them.</p><p>A cryptographic technology called private set intersection allows Apple to determine if there&#39;s a match without seeing the result of the process. In the event of a match, an iPhone or iPad will create a cryptographic safety voucher that will encrypt the upload, along with additional data about it.  Another technology called threshold secret sharing makes it so that the company can&#39;t see the contents of those vouchers unless someone passes an unspecified threshold of CSAM content. &quot;The threshold is set to provide an extremely high level of accuracy and ensures less than a one in one trillion chance per year of incorrectly flagging a given account,&quot; according to the company.&nbsp;</p><p>It&#39;s only when that line is passed that the technology Apple plans to implement will allow the company to review the contents of the vouchers. At that point, the tech giant says it will manually review each report to confirm there&#39;s a match. In cases where there is one, it will disable the individual&#39;s iCloud account and forward a report to NEMEC. Users can appeal a suspension if they believe their account has been mistakenly flagged.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c3429780-f62b-11eb-a3f3-7ed00c1cb0cb" style="height:1200;width:1600;" alt="Siri Child Safety" data-uuid="4e706bda-0929-30f5-baf3-3f9956d659ce"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>Lastly, Siri, as well as the built-in search feature found in iOS and macOS, will point users to child safety resources. For instance, you&#39;ll be able to ask the company&#39;s digital assistant how to report child exploitation. Apple also plans to update Siri to intervene when someone tries to conduct any CSAM-related searches. The assistant will explain &quot;that interest in this topic is harmful and problematic,&quot; as well as point the person to resources that offer help with the issue.</p><p>Apple&#39;s decision to effectively work with law enforcement agencies is likely to be seen as something of an about-face for the company. In 2016, it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-02-18-fbi-apple-iphone-explainer.html">refused to help the FBI</a> unlock the iPhone that had belonged to the man behind the San Bernardino terror attack. Although the government eventually <a href="https://www.engadget.com/azimuth-apple-fbi-san-bernardino-iphone-unlock-141617737.html">turned</a> to an outside firm to access the device, Tim Cook called the episode &quot;chilling&quot; and warned it could create a backdoor for more government surveillance down the road.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-ios-15-193820644.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">aa253604-9ebc-4579-8249-e24e06de42a5</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 19:39:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628197782</ingested><modified>2021-08-05T21:10:04+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b9df60b0-f621-11eb-af5f-70693fc0d782" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b9df60b0-f621-11eb-af5f-70693fc0d782" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple Child Safety iOS15]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Child Safety iOS15]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>