<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></title><link>Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics</link><description><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:25:40 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard CEO says response to harassment lawsuit was 'tone deaf']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following nearly a week of internal unrest, Activision Blizzard has published a letter from CEO Bobby Kotick addressing the company’s original response to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html">sexual harassment lawsuit</a> brought against it by the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH) on July 20th. “Our initial responses to the issues we face together, and to your concerns, were, quite frankly, tone deaf,” Kotick says in the <a href="https://activisionblizzard.com/newsroom/2021/07/letter-from-CEO-bobby-kotick-to-all-employees">letter addressed to Activision Blizzard employees</a>. “It is imperative that we acknowledge all perspectives and experiences and respect the feelings of those who have been mistreated in any way. I am sorry that we did not provide the right empathy and understanding.”</p><p>Kotick claims Blizzard Activision is taking “swift action” to ensure a safe, respectful and inclusive working environment for women and other minority groups. The company has hired law firm <a href="https://www.wilmerhale.com/en">WilmerHale</a> to review its policies, and Kotick says Activision Blizzard will implement changes to its hiring practices. It also plans to make personnel tweaks and remove content from its games employees and players have said is “inappropriate” in light of the allegations against the company. On Tuesday, the World of Warcraft development team said it would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wow-remove-inappropriate-references-california-lawsuit-035510730.html">remove specific references from the MMO</a>. While the team didn’t elaborate, those references may involve items and non-playable characters named after Alex Afrasiabi, one of the former Blizzard employees singled out in the DFEH lawsuit for repeated inappropriate behavior.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Notably, the letter doesn’t make mention of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-07-riot-games-walk-out-sexism-lawsuits-arbitration.html">forced arbitration</a>, saying only the company “will continue to investigate each and every claim and will not hesitate to take decisive action,” nor does it promise greater transparency when it comes to employee compensation. Those are two issues Activision Blizzard employees who are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-activision-walkout-184945869.html#">staging a walkout</a> to protest for better working conditions highlighted in a statement of intent they shared on Tuesday.</p><p>In its initial public response to the lawsuit, Activision Blizzard said the allegations from DFEH included “distorted, and in many cases false, descriptions of Blizzard’s past.” In a separate email to employees, Frances Townsend, executive vice president of corporate affairs at the company, claimed the lawsuit presents “a distorted and untrue picture of our company, including factually incorrect, old and out of context stories — some from more than a decade ago.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-bobby-kotick-letter-172540779.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f46a34b4-fd16-40a2-a470-58877c09e8f2</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:25:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627493142</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T17:25:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/eafeab50-8764-11eb-97ad-91d4b0437865" width="3500" height="2435" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/eafeab50-8764-11eb-97ad-91d4b0437865" width="3500" height="2435" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Brendan McDermid / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bobby Kotick, Chief Executive Officer of Activision Blizzard, speaks at the Reuters Global Media Summit in New York November 30, 2010.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid (UNITED STATES - Tags: BUSINESS MEDIA)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[MEDIA-SUMMIT/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[James Bond's iconic Aston Martin is coming to 'Rocket League']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yet another iconic car is coming to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/rocket%20league"><em>Rocket League</em></a>, and it&#39;s one that&#39;ll be nigh-on impossible to drive without humming a certain theme tune. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/james%20bond">James Bond&#39;s</a> Aston Martin DB5 will arrive in the Item Shop on July 29th.&nbsp;</p><p>Until August 4th, you&#39;ll be able to snag the 1963 model of the car, along with a DB5 paint finish (which is designed to look like Aston Martin&#39;s signature Silver Birch color), engine audio, wheels and decal. Given the Bond movies&#39; focus on gadgetry, something about firing up the rocket boosters to score a goal with the DB5 seems just right.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This won&#39;t be a one-and-done deal for James Bond in <em>Rocket League</em>, either. More content related to the legendary superspy is in the pipeline. Developer Psyonix struck a multi-year deal with MGM and Aston Martin.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/97f83ed0-eefc-11eb-bdfc-3667c234eef3" alt="James Bond&#39;s 1963 Aston Martin DB5 in Rocket League" data-uuid="b1e12f16-3d4d-3145-840f-f8d73e61d389"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Psyonix</div></figure><p>This is the latest in a long line of crossovers between <em>Rocket League</em> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-09-stranger-things-rocket-league-halloween-event-haunted-hallows.html">pop culture tentpoles</a>. The DeLorean from <em>Back to the Future</em> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-05-rocket-league-80s-event-ghostbusters-back-to-the-future-voltron.html">Ecto-1 from <em>Ghostbusters</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>have made their way to the arena. More recently, three vehicles <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fast-and-furious-rocket-league-191549326.html">from the Fast and Furious franchise</a> rolled into the game.</p><p>Meanwhile, the latest Bond movie, <em>No Time to Die</em>, is scheduled to finally hit theaters on September 30th in the UK and October 8th in the US. The impact of COVID-19 forced distributors MGM and Universal to delay it several times.</p><div id="445ec5f7313b49e0a263d0a54d095274"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6-31KXAFyrA?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/james-bond-rocket-league-aston-martin-db5-170030428.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9eb23cc4-8ae0-4ac9-bb24-df5afd895d65</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:00:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627493190</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T17:26:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7a3e61d0-eefc-11eb-9f6e-59da4889f7da" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/7a3e61d0-eefc-11eb-9f6e-59da4889f7da" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Psyonix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[James Bond's 1963 Aston Martin DB5 in Rocket League]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[James Bond's 1963 Aston Martin DB5 in Rocket League]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to watch Rocket Lab's US Space Force satellite launch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Space%20Force"><ins>US Space Force</ins></a> is gearing up to launch a research and development satellite on Thursday with the help of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/rocket%20lab"><ins>Rocket Lab</ins></a>. The company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rocket-lab-20th-electron-mission-failure-150652708.html"><ins>Electron rocket</ins></a> is scheduled to launch from a site in New Zealand sometime between 2AM and 4AM ET (6PM-8PM local time) to take the Monolith satellite into low Earth orbit.</p><p>The aim of the mission, which is called &quot;It&#39;s a Little Chile Up Here&quot; (a reference to the green chile from the Space Test Program&#39;s New Mexico home), is to test small satellites for the Department of Defense. Monolith will help determine whether it&#39;s large deployable sensors are feasible. Such sensors account for a significant proportion of a spacecraft&#39;s total mass. Since the sensor may alter the spacecraft’s dynamic properties, the mission will examine whether it&#39;s possible to maintain altitude control after the sensor has been deployed.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;Analysis from the use of a deployable sensor aims to enable the use of smaller satellite buses when building future deployable sensors such as weather satellites, thereby reducing the cost, complexity, and development timelines,&quot; Rocket Lab <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/about-us/updates/rocket-lab-to-launch-u-s-space-force-mission-from-launch-complex-1-in-new-zealand/"><ins>wrote in a statement</ins></a>. &quot;The satellite will also provide a platform to test future space protection capabilities.&quot;</p><p>You can watch the launch as it happens on the <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/live-stream"><ins>Rocket Lab website</ins></a>. A stream may also be available on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/RocketLabNZ/videos"><ins>Rocket Lab&#39;s YouTube channel</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rocket-lab-us-space-force-satellite-launch-how-to-watch-153411215.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5e74370e-59cf-432f-9f24-a94fb0b66f72</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 15:34:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627486455</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T15:34:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Space & Astronomy]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/ab9a98f0-eb53-11ea-9172-050464e1ea05" width="4096" height="2645" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/ab9a98f0-eb53-11ea-9172-050464e1ea05" width="4096" height="2645" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab's Electron rocket makes successful return to flight]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Rocket Lab's Electron rocket makes successful return to flight]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google begins showing what its new Play Store safety listings will look like]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&#39;s still half a year to go before you start seeing Google Play&#39;s new safety section, which will show you an Android app&#39;s privacy information, in listings within the store. Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-requires-android-developers-to-disclose-privacy-data-173422000.html">announced</a> the upcoming feature that&#39;s similar to the Apple App Store&#39;s nutrition labels back in May. In a new post on the <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/">Android Developer blog</a>, though, Google has given us a glimpse of what that section may look like.&nbsp;</p><p>Within a listing, you will see a summary from the developer on what kind of data an app collects, so you can make a decision whether to install it or not. You&#39;ll also see safety details the developer chooses to highlight, such as whether an app encrypts your data, whether it&#39;s suitable for children and families and whether it&#39;s been independently validated against a global security standard.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/5917b2b0-ef8b-11eb-bcfa-5abd5aa4f796" style="height:900;width:1600;" alt="Google" data-uuid="928595c1-3b71-304b-8acb-01e1c985d041"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Further, you can tap the summary to see more details about the type of data an app collects and how it&#39;s used. It can show you whether an app collects location and contact data, personal information such as name and email address, as well as financial information. The section can also tell you whether the app uses your data for its features, for personalization or for other purposes. In addition, it can let you know whether you can opt out of getting your data collected or if giving an app access to your information really is necessary to be able to use it.</p><p>Google says the details might still change before the feature goes live, but all developers are required to provide a privacy policy for their apps and must provide accurate information for the safety section. Developers can start declaring privacy information in October and have until April 2022 to do so, but you&#39;ll start seeing the section pop up on Google Play sometime within the first quarter of next year.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-safety-section-play-android-apps-150052244.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2a46d685-42b9-41f7-ac17-4065471a4882</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627468917</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T10:42:15+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/47cd1c60-ef87-11eb-bd7b-9f467b83ba08" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/47cd1c60-ef87-11eb-bd7b-9f467b83ba08" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter tests new shopping features for businesses]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is the latest social media platform to experiment with new <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/twitter-shopping--testing-shoppable-profiles-on-twitter">shopping features</a>. The company is allowing a handful of brands to place a “Shop Module” at the top of their profiles that links to products their followers can buy.</p><p>While it’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-09-08-buy-from-twitter.html">not</a> the first time Twitter has tried out shopping features, it’s the first time the company has incorporated shopping directly into the profile. With the change, businesses can highlight a handful of products in a carousel in between the main profile info and their timeline. The feature is limited to only a few brands, including GameStop and bag-maker Arden Cove, in the US for now.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>While up until now Twitter hasn’t pursued shopping as aggressively as some other platforms, the company has recently signaled that could soon change. A “shop” button <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/twitter-tests-new-e-commerce-features-for-tweets/">for tweets</a> has also been spotted, and the company recently introduced new “business profiles.” Shopping features could also have interesting implications for creators, a demographic Twitter has also made a recent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-15th-anniversary-140008110.html">push to pursue</a> with new money-making features. Allowing creators to showcase their existing merch shop from their profile could provide an additional boost, and help the company compete with Facebook’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-creator-shops-content-marketplace-190211314.html">creator shops</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-shop-module-business-profile-150020142.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8e0da44e-70a1-4142-b53a-2f50de218006</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627488714</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T16:12:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hobbies & Personal Activities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2a5cba30-ef34-11eb-bf5f-c21e272fcef7" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2a5cba30-ef34-11eb-bf5f-c21e272fcef7" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Twitter]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitter is testing out a new "shop module" for brands and businesses.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[twitter shop module]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony has sold 10 million PS5 consoles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-review-130048353.html">PlayStation 5</a> just crossed a significant milestone. Sony has <a href="https://www.sie.com/en/blog/a-new-milestone-sie-sells-10-million-playstation-5-consoles-globally/">revealed</a> that it has sold 10 million PS5 consoles as of July 18th, eight months after the system&#39;s November 12th debut. The company considered that no mean feat between the pandemic and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-gaming-chief-says-the-ps-5-would-be-sold-out-even-without-covid-19-124538616.html">ongoing chip shortages</a> that reportedly held sales back. It&#39;s now Sony&#39;s fastest-selling console to date, outpacing the PS4 by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-08-12-sony-has-sold-10-million-playstation-4-consoles.html">nearly a month</a>.</p><p>Sales have slowed down since launch. Sony racked up <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-4-5-million-playstation5-console-sales-q4-2020-084453123.html">4.5 million PS5 sales in 2020</a>, but sold <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-q4-2020-ps5-sales-073708784.html">3.3 million</a> in the first quarter of 2021 — it took another four months to add 2.2 million to the tally. That&#39;s not surprising between supply constraints and the usual mid-year slump, but you might not see sales climb until the holidays.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>PlayStation chief Jim Ryan told <em>GamesIndustry.biz</em> in an <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-07-28-ps5-is-the-fastest-selling-playstation-as-it-hits-10-million-sales-milestone">interview</a> that it was &quot;too early to tell&quot; which markets were the hottest given widespread demand, but pointed out that China was a pleasant surprise. The company sold out its PS5 launch stock &quot;very, very quickly&quot; despite a local market focused on mobile games and the free-to-play model.</p><p>The PS5 doesn&#39;t have an easy road ahead. Even if Sony could quickly overcome hardware shortages, it still has a dearth of PS5-exclusive titles outside of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-interview-ps5-151025038.html"><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/returnal-review-ps5-shooter-133029657.html"><em>Returnal</em></a>. The biggest games tend to be enhanced versions of games available for the PS4, like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/miles-morales-ps5-review-spider-man-161228925.html"><em>Spider-Man: Miles Morales</em></a>, and even upcoming blockbusters like <em>Horizon Forbidden West</em> will have PS4 releases. While demand still appears to be brisk, there might not be much added incentive to buy a PS5 until <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gran-turismo-7-release-date-delayed-2022-164024717.html"><em>Gran Turismo 7</em></a> and other system exclusives arrive in force.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-playstation-5-ps5-10-million-sold-144729654.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b614748a-826a-473a-81cc-ad32ca498645</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:47:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627483653</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T14:47:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/82f3d290-efad-11eb-b7cf-146d0ea6045c" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/82f3d290-efad-11eb-b7cf-146d0ea6045c" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Aaron Souppouris/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony PlayStation 5 with Xbox consoles in background]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony PlayStation 5 with Xbox consoles in background]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla will reportedly move stores out of high-end malls and use remote fleets]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The days of seeing Tesla stores in fancy malls and retail centers may be over, according to <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/07/28/tesla-tsla-major-shift-retail-strategy-cheaper-locations-remote-working/">a report from Electrek</a>. Sources tell the site that Tesla will instead focus on finding cheaper spaces, like parking lots and warehouses, that will house a remote fleet of cars. The company also won&#39;t be firing its retail staff (it&#39;s actually in the <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/07/22/tesla-tsla-salesforce-hiring-spree-demand-us/">middle of a hiring spree</a>). Instead of being tied to individual stores, those workers will help to manage Tesla testing and purchases from those remote locations.</p><p>If this news sounds familiar, it&#39;s because Tesla previously said it was going to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-02-28-teslas-car-sales-are-going-online-only.html">close most of its stores</a> in 2019 before <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-11-tesla-decides-to-keep-more-stores-open-and-raise-prices-instead.html">quickly reversing course</a>. This new strategy, if it ends up being implemented, seems to be a smarter implementation of that plan. Most Tesla customers already buy their cars online, so there&#39;s less of a need to have pricey mall stores around. The cheaper locations will also be better for holding more vehicles, which should help to satisfy increased demand for purchases and test drives.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-stores-high-end-malls-remote-fleets-142829801.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e8a2a08d-8778-423a-a0b1-1fe0904c7703</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627482512</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T14:28:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/9d249360-efae-11eb-9347-56aa82530c42" width="3500" height="2241" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/9d249360-efae-11eb-9347-56aa82530c42" width="3500" height="2241" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Hannibal Hanschke / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Tesla car 'Model S' sits in a dealership in Berlin, Germany, November 18, 2015. REUTERS/Hannibal Hanschke]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GERMANY-BUSINESS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Uber is moving into flower deliveries]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The next time you open Uber Eats, you might see a new delivery option: a way to have flowers dropped off at your door swiftly with just a few taps. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/uber"><ins>Uber</ins></a> has teamed up with flower industry stalwart FTD for its first nationwide florist partnership as part of its latest on-demand delivery venture.</p><p>Folks in New York City, Philadelphia, Chicago, Los Angeles, Dallas, Miami and some other locations can now order flower arrangements from FTD’s ProFlowers locations. Uber expects to roll out the option nationwide by early 2022, so it should be available almost everywhere by Mother&#39;s Day next May. You can see the available options by tapping the flower icons in the Uber Eats app and selecting a ProFlowers location. Uber Pass and Eats Pass subscribers will get discounts and no-free deliveries on eligible orders of at least $15.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Deliveries have become an increasingly important part of Uber&#39;s business over the last couple of years. One key reason is that far fewer people took rides amid COVID-19 restrictions. The company recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-grocery-delivery-expansion-us-cities-new-york-san-francisco-162657661.html"><ins>doubled its grocery delivery</ins></a> markets to more than 400 US towns and cities, and it just started <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-costco-grocery-delivery-pilot-131110472.html"><ins>delivering Costco orders</ins></a> in Texas.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uber-flower-deliveries-ftd-proflowers-141016152.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0e8a968e-afd3-4988-a073-76accfd3ce38</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:10:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627481421</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T14:10:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/729bc7b0-efab-11eb-9fbf-703877fc50e8" width="4500" height="3000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/729bc7b0-efab-11eb-9fbf-703877fc50e8" width="4500" height="3000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[VictoriaBee via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bouquet of spring tulips flowers wrapped in gift paper]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bouquet of spring tulips flowers wrapped in gift paper]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hulu will livestream Lollapalooza 2021 this weekend]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lollapalooza is once again an in-person festival after a switch to a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lollapalooza-2020-online-festival-194815927.html">streaming-only gig in 2020</a>, but that&#39;s not the only big change for fans. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Hulu" href="https://fave.co/2QwdNTa">Hulu</a> has become the exclusive streaming partner for Lollapalooza 2021, and <a href="https://www.hulu.com/lollapalooza">will stream</a> the Chicago event to on-demand subscribers between July 29th and August 1st starting at 2PM Eastern (1PM Central). Yes, that means what you think it does — Lollapalooza won&#39;t be streaming <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-31-youtube-lollapalooza-2019-live-stream.html">on YouTube</a> like it has in recent years.</p><p>There&#39;s no extra charge, and you can watch if you <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:sign up for a free trial" href="https://fave.co/2QwdNTa">sign up for a free trial</a>. The Lollapalooza 2021 lineup includes plenty of big names, including Illenium (July 29th), Tyler, the Creator (July 30th), Post Malone (July 31st) and Foo Fighters (August 1st).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Hulu has streamed concerts before, including a Black History Month show in February and a <em>Summer of Soul</em> tribute on Juneteenth. However, this is the service&#39;s first exclusive live event. It&#39;s a big bet that livestreams like this can translate to more customers, not to mention draw attention away from free services like YouTube.</p><p>Whether or not music fans follow is another matter. YouTube is still a go-to destination for live festivals <a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-livestream-coachella-2022-063025456.html">like Coachella</a>, and that may be what virtual concertgoers are expecting. There&#39;s a real possibility that many would-be viewers will just skip Lollapalooza altogether rather than sign up for Hulu, no matter how easily they can cancel service afterward.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lollapalooza-2021-live-stream-hulu-140043962.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dd38225c-7c6b-4ef0-ad5e-ae8e4e23e15e</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627481440</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T14:10:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2002ca10-efa8-11eb-9d43-e80c882c0e9b" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2002ca10-efa8-11eb-9d43-e80c882c0e9b" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Gabriella Angotti-Jones / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tyler, the Creator performs during Governors Ball Music Festival at Randall's Island Park in New York, U.S. May 31, 2019. REUTERS/Gabriella Angotti-Jones]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[MUSIC-GOVERNORS BALL/USA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat’s map now helps you keep track of where you’ve been]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snapchat is updating its in-app map to help users keep track of places they’ve visited, and where they may want to go next. An update rolling out today adds a new “Places” section to the map, with educated sections for recommendations, locations you’ve visited and “favorites” to remember.</p><p>The idea is similar to Foursquare (the original check-in based iteration), except “checking in” in this case consists of tagging a specific location in a Snap. Places you’ve tagged are automatically saved in your “visited” tab, but you can also manually add establishments to your “favorites” list. Interestingly, Snap is also using the new feature to generate recommendations. The “popular” section of the map will surface a list of personalized suggestions based on places you’ve been and what’s popular in your area.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Though the Snap Map has been around <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-06-21-snapchat-snap-map.html"><ins>for years</ins></a> the company has been working to make it more useful — and more visible — within the app. The company gave the feature more prominent placement in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-app-redesign-action-bar-171555996.html"><ins>a redesign</ins></a> last year, and plans to add <a href="https://newsroom.snap.com/new-partnerships-and-tools-for-developers-to-build-with-snapchat"><ins>Map Layers</ins></a>, a feature that allows third-parties like Ticketmaster to incorporate events and other content directly into the map.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-snap-map-places-140030542.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">33f80887-7fb0-4aa2-8353-b20cdf4177ae</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627434048</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T01:01:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fe657e80-ef3d-11eb-b75b-988161094e05" width="1788" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/fe657e80-ef3d-11eb-b75b-988161094e05" width="1788" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Snap]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Snapchat's map can now track where you've been and serve up recommendations.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[snap map places]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nura's latest wireless earbuds sound truly unique]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nura might be a relatively new name in headphones, but the personalized-audio specialist is already revealing its third model: the Nuratrue. As the name suggests, the latest member of the family is a true wireless set (and the company’s first model without a wired option). As you might expect, Nura’s flagship automatic hearing test (for sound tailored to your hearing) is here, along with many other features the company has already made synonymous with its brand. But with a smaller form factor, are compromises inevitable?</p><p>The Nuratrue ($199/£199) is a simplified version of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-03-nura-nuraphones-review.html"><ins>Nuraphone </ins></a>over-ears and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nuraloop-wireless-headphones-review-120007318.html"><ins>Nuraloop </ins></a>wireless (but tethered) sports buds. As mentioned, the audio customization feature is present, as is the “ambient” mode — which Nura calls “social mode.” There’s even Active Noise Cancelling and “immersion” mode, which simulates the feeling of being at a live event. The last two are a little simplified compared to their bigger siblings, though.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The original Nuraphone’s immersion mode delivers tactile bass with transducers creating a sensation of volume and presence similar to being in front of a large speaker. On the Nuratrue, it feels more like a bass “boost” feature you might find on an equalizer. Active Noise Cancellation on the Nuratrue works pretty well, but is tied to the social mode feature which means they are activated as a pair. This makes no real functional difference, but something to bear in mind. Battery life is estimated at six hours here and seems accurate, which can be extended to around 24 hours via the charging case.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/eef58e40-ef7e-11eb-b5bd-586bc02fc4c2" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Nuratrue hands-on." data-uuid="d4f3ebed-4ee4-3437-b2f0-8057b61ab44e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>If you were a fan of the Nuraloop, you might have expected the Nuratrue to be broadly the same, minus the connecting cable. But you’d be wrong. The new buds barely share any visual or physical DNA with their cabled sibling. Instead the Nuratrue has a much larger, circular body which sorta looks like you’re wearing “plugs,” but in the middle of your ear. This extra size might sound like a negative, but it makes them easier to touch (for controls) and likely helps keep them wirelessly connected to each other.</p><p>That “touchability” is important, as, like most TWS earphones, it’s how you’ll interact with them — in particular, for activating things like immersion or social mode. (ANC can only be toggled via the app it seems, and as mentioned disables social mode with it). In my testing with them the touch was more responsive than most other TWS headphones I’ve tried, especially the tricky double-tap which I find often requires a few attempts to register correctly. As with all Nura headphones you can easily assign different tasks to either side for both single and double taps, making it easy to have the controls you use the most at hand (or finger, technically).</p><p>Obviously, the main selling point here is Nura’s proprietary audio personalization. The ability to create personal hearing profiles is kinda Nura’s whole <em>thing</em>. It’s a feature you see on other brands, too, but Nura’s is the simplest and, in my experience, the most reliable. Mostly, because it doesn’t involve any subjectivity. Just pop the buds in your ears, walk through the profile creation process in the app and the headphones do everything else. Most other similar “tests” require you to tell the app how well/if you heard something. As someone who’s done more than their fair share of hearing tests, I always start imagining phantom sounds and worry that affects my results.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/2be14240-ef7f-11eb-95ef-2ac45793c076" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Nuratrue hands-on." data-uuid="9c5efb9d-4837-31e9-bbbb-00680b14a3fc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>Cool features are… cool and all, but you probably just want to know how they sound? I guess the smart answer is, that will depend on your ears. The slightly more helpful answer is that, for me, the personalized audio definitely puts the Nuratrue above most of the TWS headphones I have tried. It’s not that they have better bass or polished treble, although those would be fair statements, it’s more that they feel neutral and balanced.</p><p>Whereas “unpersonalized” buds may be technically balanced on a graph, I know that my hearing isn’t perfect and thus might be slightly worse at certain frequencies. With Nura’s personalized tuning, it’s hard to know what frequency curve I am getting, or even if that’s what my hearing really “needs” but what I do know is that I like it!</p><p>Now, I guess I should also say that I am never sure just how effective Nura’s hearing test really is. The company claims that it uses <a href="https://www.asha.org/public/hearing/otoacoustic-emissions/">otoacoustic emissions</a> to determine the characteristics of your hearing. The same test is sometimes used to determine cochlear hearing loss in newborns. That said, every time I’ve been to an audiologist (which is more times than I would like) I have asked them about using OAE tests for headphones, and all of them have been skeptical it can be done on hardware at this price. When I asked Nura about this, they gave the following reply:</p><p>“The OAE signal produced by a person&#39;s ears is indeed faint - much like the signals of GPS satellites are faint by the time they reach the Earth&#39;s surface. That&#39;s why GPS-enabled devices of 20-15 years ago were much larger, less accurate, and took longer to acquire a signal than today&#39;s smartphones or even smartwatches. Similar advances in signal processing have enabled the huge improvement in GPS device performance and the quick &amp; reliable measurements of OAEs in devices as small as Nuratrue.”</p><p>In short, the company claims that advances in technology have allowed for the test to be practical in small, consumer devices.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/50366800-ef7f-11eb-8cff-18d24091138f" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Nuratrue hands-on." data-uuid="eeccb67b-bcbe-36cc-ab90-d6e5bd5ecdb4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">James Trew / Engadget</div></figure><p>Back to the physical design briefly. It might not be for everyone, but it feels very much in keeping with Nura’s apparent mission to do things a little bit differently. I’ve never really found a TWS design that I think has fully cracked it (although <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-23-jabra-elite-75t-review-specs-features.html"><ins>Jabra’s Elite 75t</ins></a> comes close?), and that’s true here. But, as mentioned earlier, I do appreciate the large surface area for controlling playback or activating/deactivating the extra features. Extended wear remains comfortable, and the fit works well for my ears.</p><p>If I had one minor gripe, it’d be the maximum volume. It’s not low. In fact, for me, it’s more or less ideal for comfortable, extended use. It’s just that, “comfortable” is the maximum, so when a song comes on that I really love and I decide that, heck, I can crank this one up a bit before going back to normal levels… there’s nowhere to go. Again, this might not be an issue for you. I’ll be the first to admit I probably haven’t done my ears any favors over the years, but it was something I noticed fairly quickly in my time with the Nuratrue.</p><p>In an ocean of true wireless headphones, it’s hard to stand out. But Nura’s personalized audio is certainly enough to do just that. Of all the “customizable” headphones I’ve tried, Nura’s are still the ones to beat. And with the Nuratrue priced at least $80 cheaper than the flagship models from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-160006474.html"><ins>Sony</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-19-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-2-review.html"><ins>Sennheiser </ins></a>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bose-quietcomfort-earbuds-review-144502194.html"><ins>Bose</ins></a>, that’s just another easy way for the company to garner attention.</p><p>The Nuratrue is available starting today.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nuratrue-true-wireless-headphones-140003973.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">296e041f-cc23-40c6-a533-1b50a3a95285</guid><dc:creator>James Trew</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627465321</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T09:42:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|James Trew]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/8a0e8490-eee9-11eb-bbff-5bcf24e5afe0" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/8a0e8490-eee9-11eb-bbff-5bcf24e5afe0" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[James Trew / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Nuratrue review.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Nuratrue review]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Archived WhatsApp chats will no longer come back to haunt you]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your archived <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whats-app-lets-you-use-different-wallpapers-for-individual-chats-080121431.html">WhatsApp chats</a> will no longer resurrect themselves — unless you let them. The messaging giant is <a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1420051741479821315">rolling out</a> a settings change that will keep those conversation threads tucked away in the Archived Chats folder by default, even if someone sends a new message. You&#39;ll have to remove a thread from the archives if you want to make it active again.</p><p>If you prefer the old behavior, you can <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/android/chats/how-to-archive-or-unarchive-a-chat-or-group">restore</a> it through the relevant settings in the Chats tab.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This could prove frustrating if someone wants to bring back a discussion you wouldn&#39;t mind revisiting, such as a classmate chat or a party planning session. However, it could easily be worthwhile if it prevents someone from dredging up bad memories or otherwise hijacking control of archives you&#39;d rather keep hidden.</p><div id="186d1790f5464965be3cee9ba550034b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Archive on WhatsApp lets you organize your private messages and prioritize important conversations. Your Archived chats will now remain archived and muted but you can always change them back! <a href="https://t.co/QbAY6iu81p">pic.twitter.com/QbAY6iu81p</a></p>— WhatsApp (@WhatsApp) <a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1420051741479821315?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-archived-chats-update-131627976.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">05b7692e-7d72-4155-aee9-5bfc6fb463fa</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:16:27 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627478191</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T13:16:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/347aa820-ad98-11eb-b2d7-f5270789331a" width="5332" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-05/347aa820-ad98-11eb-b2d7-f5270789331a" width="5332" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A 3D printed Whatsapp logo and keyboard buttons are placed on a computer motherboard in this illustration taken January 21, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[WHATSAPP/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Krispy Kreme has created official Xbox-branded doughnuts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gaming promos are getting zanier all the time. The days of grabbing a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-08-31-win-a-xbox-one-via-doritos-mountain-dew-promotion-online-at-pa.html">Mountain Dew or a pack of Doritos</a> for a chance to win an Xbox One are long gone. In our attention-zapped world, it has to be new or else it&#39;s DOA. With that in mind, Krispy Kreme has come up with the &quot;<a href="https://www.krispykreme.co.uk/xbox?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=uk_social-organic_xbox-launch">Nexus Level</a>&quot; doughnut as part of a new Xbox cross promotion in the UK and Ireland. That&#39;s it above in all its icing-covered glory.</p><div id="b3c250b3f63a4fb6a7110122e69b3c7b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Welcome to the next generation<br><br>Introducing... The Nexus Level Doughnut<br><br>Coming Soon 👀<a href="https://t.co/UVteHkCnjT">https://t.co/UVteHkCnjT</a><a href="https://twitter.com/xboxuk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@xboxuk</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KrispyKremeXbox?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KrispyKremeXbox</a><a href="https://t.co/Xf3hRuKybw">pic.twitter.com/Xf3hRuKybw</a></p>— Krispy Kreme UK (@krispykremeUK) <a href="https://twitter.com/krispykremeUK/status/1420289168920485890?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Buy a box of the Xbox-branded doughnuts between August 2nd and 22nd for a chance of winning an Xbox Series S and a month of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate (if you&#39;re a new subscriber). To check if you&#39;ve snagged the console, you need to scan the QR code on the box and enter your unique code.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>It&#39;s not as madcap as the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bungie-destiny-toaster-125538268.html">Destiny toaster</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/kfcs-viral-marketing-gets-real-with-a-chickenwarming-gaming-pc-112558482.html">KFC&#39;s bucket-shaped gaming PC</a>, or even the<a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-xbox-mini-fridge-release-date-191211916.html"> Xbox Mini Fridge</a>. But, you can&#39;t actually eat any of those. Krispy Kreme is clearly in on the joke. An accompanying video features actors as the team behind the doughnut, with corporate titles like &quot;product innovator&quot; and &quot;quality assurance guru,&quot; touting its &quot;revolutionary design&quot; and &quot;ergonomic form.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/krispy-kreme-xbox-doughnuts-122614458.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">42f929c7-d30a-4b49-967b-f63f12ff6502</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627479148</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T13:32:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/24093720-efa8-11eb-97ee-30e5a8fd7d90" width="1000" height="640" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/24093720-efa8-11eb-97ee-30e5a8fd7d90" width="1000" height="640" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Krispy Kreme]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Krispy Kreme Nexus Level Xbox donut.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Krispy Kreme Xbox]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: iPhone sales are up 50 percent year over year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The curse of buying new tech at the wrong time will get us all. In the last year, I’ve seen fellow Engadget employees buy a Nintendo Switch just before the OLED model broke cover, take the plunge with the iPhone SE just before the iPhone 12 mini was unveiled and make several more shopping missteps. Now, I might have done the same.</p><p>I picked up Sony’s vlogging camera, the ZV-1, earlier this month. I was looking for an agile video setup for the occasional time I have to record footage at Engadget without a skilled member of our video team. It’s very easy to make it work, with great face tracking capabilities and even a product showcase mode that helps me really show off whatever gadget I’m handling and I was happy with it.&nbsp;</p><p>For a couple of weeks.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/3a768330-eeec-11eb-9fbf-1ce709229319" alt="Sony mirrorless ZV-E10" data-uuid="d59cdf73-35f2-3b40-b640-c90d4d3fd498"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>Then I heard the rumors that Sony was about to expand its vlogging camera family, and my heart sank. Here it is, then. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-expands-its-vlogging-lineup-with-the-zv-e-10-mirrorless-camera-142731045.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">ZV E-10</a>, a new vlogging camera that fuses the tiny frame of the ZV-1 with interchangeable lenses.&nbsp;</p><p>The two major improvements seem to be a larger 24-megapixel sensor and an interchangeable mirrorless mount. The latter means you can use one of the 60-plus E-mount lenses, while that larger sensor should offer improved light sensitivity and a shallower depth of field. The ZV-E10 will launch by the end of August and will cost $700 for the body or $800 in a bundle with one of Sony&#39;s power zoom lens. The price is roughly level with how much I paid for the ZV-1 earlier this month. It’s probably too late to ask for a refund, right?&nbsp;</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-q2-2021-earnings-210238898.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><br>iPhone sales were up 50 percent year over year</a></h2><h3>Another record-breaking quarter for Apple.</h3><h3></h3><p>Despite the pandemic, Apple has spent most of the last two years relentlessly upgrading its product lineup, and its moves are definitely paying off. During its fiscal year third quarter, all of its product segments (the iPhone, Mac, iPad, services and wearables/home/accessories) increased in revenue year over year, leading to total revenue of $81.4 billion. iPhone revenue of $39.6 billion made up almost half of that figure, likely thanks to an unusual four devices making up the iPhone 12 lineup. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-q2-2021-earnings-210238898.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-delays-semi-truck-2022-102502178.html">Tesla pushes back Semi truck release to 2022</a></h2><h3>The company delayed its launch due to battery cell shortage and supply chain issues.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-delays-semi-truck-2022-102502178.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/65bc1430-eeb8-11eb-9a3f-142d8b690772" alt="Tesla" data-uuid="d4ba8fd4-e16c-34ae-9511-dcb5cd56dae9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Tesla</div></figure></a><p>Tesla has revealed during its most recent earnings call that it has pushed back the truck&#39;s arrival — yet again — to 2022, three years after its original launch target in 2019. Last year, the company announced it had to delay the vehicle&#39;s release to 2021 but didn&#39;t elaborate on why. Now, the company has told shareholders the delay is due to the limited availability of battery cells and global supply chain challenges. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-delays-semi-truck-2022-102502178.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/nothing-ear-1-wireless-earbuds-release-date-133011498.html">Nothing&#39;s Ear 1 wireless earbuds arrive on August 17th</a></h2><h3>A limited-edition online drop will take place on July 31st.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/nothing-ear-1-wireless-earbuds-release-date-133011498.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/8cae7810-eece-11eb-b7f7-f040681b80e0" alt="Nothing Ear 1
" data-uuid="e0a64299-b0d4-3cb3-8c97-541858c599b6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nothing</div></figure></a><p>The new hardware startup from the co-founder of OnePlus is almost ready to show off its first product — and I hope you like wireless earbuds. Taking a leaf out of Carl Pei’s former company, the dripfeed for Nothing’s Ear 1 hasn’t left much to reveal, although we’ve gleaned an eventual US launch date, mid-August, and some battery estimates. Rumor has it, we’ll have some first-hand impressions on these see-thru wireless buds very soon. Stay tuned. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nothing-ear-1-wireless-earbuds-release-date-133011498.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-activision-walkout-184945869.html">Activision Blizzard employees walk out today after harassment lawsuit response</a></h2><h3>They&#39;re demanding the company improve working conditions.</h3><h3></h3><p>After sharing an open letter decrying the company&#39;s &quot;abhorrent and insulting&quot; response to a harassment lawsuit from the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH), Activision Blizzard employees plan to hold a walkout.</p><p>According to <em>Kotaku</em>, at least 50 employees will protest the company&#39;s recent actions in person and call on it to improve working conditions for women by at least temporarily leaving their posts today. In the open letter, the employees call on Activision Blizzard to end the use of forced arbitration for all current and future employees, adopt new hiring policies designed to increase representation across the company, publish transparency data on compensation and hire a third-party firm to conduct a review of the studio&#39;s HR department and executive staff. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-activision-walkout-184945869.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>But wait, there’s more...</h2><h2></h2><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/arcade1up-the-simpsons-arcade-game-cabinet-153739981.html">&#39;The Simpsons&#39; gets a home arcade cabinet for its 30th birthday</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-threads-150018618.html">Discord finally adds threaded messaging</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-q4-fy21-earnings-203724611.html">Microsoft&#39;s profits skyrocketed by 47 percent in Q4</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-pre-drive-screen-information-144828779.html">Waze will warn you about traffic jams and detours before you drive</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-twitter-account-animated-show-chicago-party-aunt-162336991.html">Netflix turned a Twitter account into an animated show</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-google-earnings-q2-2021-202832294.html">Google parent Alphabet made a whopping $61.9 billion last quarter</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/quest-2-foam-facial-interface-recall-163432642.html">Facebook recalls Quest 2 foam inserts over skin irritation issues</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/pharma-bro-martin-shkrelis-wu-tang-clan-album-sold-192829283.html">US government sells &#39;Pharma Bro&#39; Martin Shkreli&#39;s one-off Wu-Tang Clan album</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/azio-izo-collection-keyboard-mouse-140016265.html">AZIO&#39;s colorful IZO collection looks great (and that&#39;s about it)</a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-iphone-sales-are-up-50-percent-111535169.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1c22fda2-59a5-4652-9bb5-883cf87d5946</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 11:15:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627472149</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T11:35:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/843fd250-1279-11eb-9df7-f0948508264f" width="3000" height="1658" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/843fd250-1279-11eb-9df7-f0948508264f" width="3000" height="1658" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 12 and 12 Pro review]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 12 and 12 Pro review]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The first 'Halo Infinite' multiplayer beta will open on July 29th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-delay-2021-193546027.html">series</a> of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-update-release-date-235826926.html">setbacks</a>, a small batch of beta testers will be among the first to play <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/haloinfinite"><em>Halo Infinite</em></a>. From tomorrow, July 29th, until August 1st, a bunch of Halo Insiders will get to try the sequel&#39;s <a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/en-us/news/inside-infinite-july-2021">multiplayer preview</a>. The invite-only test will see players sample gameplay including bot slaying in four-player teams  across three maps, with the action growing fraught as players wipe out more enemies.&nbsp;</p><p>Bots aren&#39;t the only first in the new Halo. Beta testers will also sample the new Academy experience at a firing range, where they&#39;ll try out a dozen weapons on strafing bots. As a taster of the customization on offer, players will be get a set amount of in-game credits to spend on items. This is so they can get accustomed with the Battle Passes, check their Challenges, use the Store, and apply their changes in the Armor Hall. However, these items won&#39;t carry over into the full game.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="5189946410b247f193335980d31e133d"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ok, so <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloInfinite?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HaloInfinite</a> tech preview invite confirmation emails started going out around 5PM PT today. A LOT of Insiders are being invited, but alas, we&#39;ve had so much growth with the program that not everyone will get into this one. How did we select participants? (1/8)</p>— Brian Jarrard (@ske7ch) <a href="https://twitter.com/ske7ch/status/1420220171159932928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Finally, chosen Insiders will also go hands-on with the Halo Waypoint web and mobile app experiences on iOS and Android. Offering some more insight into the invite process, 343 Industries&#39; Brian Jarrard said the developer is targeting a large number of testers across platforms (including Xbox One, Series X/S, and different PC configurations).&nbsp;</p><p>To meet that goal, preference may also be given to Insiders with valid profiles, those opted in to comms and the DXDIAG diagnostics tool, he added. The developer is also looking at tenure, with preference for long-standing Insiders. You can still sign up to the <a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/en-us/community/halo-insider">Halo Insider </a>program. Though it may be too late to jump on this test, more Halo previews are planned in the lead-up to the game&#39;s launch this fall.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-multiplayer-beta-110518513.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">acdce5a1-6d3e-41be-8abe-116b0a456ed8</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 11:05:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627467875</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T10:24:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b6c38960-ef8c-11eb-bf8f-d79b011ee5f8" width="1500" height="844" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/b6c38960-ef8c-11eb-bf8f-d79b011ee5f8" width="1500" height="844" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Halo Infinite]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Halo Infinite]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Halo Infinite]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify added more paying customers than free ones last quarter]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-2021-q1-financials-103256427.html">Three months ago</a>, Spotify predicted that user growth would start declining, because COVID-19 had prompted so many people to sign up than expected. Today, the audio giant was proved right, as new signups fell to nine million new users in the <a href="https://investors.spotify.com/financials/press-release-details/2021/Spotify-Technology-S.A.-Announces-Financial-Results-for-Second-Quarter-2021/default.aspx">most recent quarter</a>. That said, slower growth isn’t always a bad thing. Of that nine million figure, seven million users signed up for Premium, versus just two million who went ad-supported. It means that Spotify was also able to announce a second successive quarter of profitability after a long period of losses.</p><p>The total number of Spotify users now stands at 365 million, of which 165 million are paying for Premium, while the remaining 210 are ad-supported. Converting more of Spotify’s vast ad-supported user base into Premium users is one way to ensure the company remains profitable. Another, of course, is to boost its growing advertising business, which has been bolstered by Spotify’s numerous podcast offerings. The company said that it saw “triple digit” year-on-year gain in ad-sales for the company’s owned podcast outlets, including The Ringer, Parcast and Gimlet.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The last three months has seen Spotify intensify work to push users toward cheaper forms of audio content than music. It says that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-joe-rogan-experience-exclusive-podcast-203044280.html">Joe Rogan’s</a> podcast has performed “above expectations,” while shows out of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-05-spotify-buys-the-ringer.html">The Ringer</a> saw big bumps in listenership as the NBA headed into the playoff season. No mention this month of how many people are tuning in to listen to former President Barack Obama and Bruce Springsteen hang out, which was the second biggest podcast on the platform from the start of the year.</p><p>As for the future, Spotify says that it’s hoping to add at least 12 million more users in total, and at least another five million more paying customers. It is still expecting to reach the coveted 400 million user figure by the end of the year, although given the uncertainties still present with COVID-19, you never can be sure.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-q2-2021-premium-users-103530500.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">94d0ec5d-6309-4645-801b-9126cab3b915</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:35:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627478287</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T13:18:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-02/f937c040-2a0e-11e9-b2b8-b86eee421003" width="4000" height="2667" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-02/f937c040-2a0e-11e9-b2b8-b86eee421003" width="4000" height="2667" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mike Coppola via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BROOKLYN, NY - AUGUST 09:  Spotify CEO Daniel Ek speaks onstage during Samsung Unpacked New York City at Barclays Center on August 9, 2018 in Brooklyn City.  (Photo by Mike Coppola/Getty Images for Samsung)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked New York City]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch Cassie the bipedal robot run a 5K]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cassie, a bipedal robot that&#39;s all legs, has successfully <a href="https://today.oregonstate.edu/news/bipedal-robot-developed-oregon-state-makes-history-learning-run-completing-5k">run five kilometers</a> on a single charge, all without having a tether. The machine serves as the basis for Agility Robotics&#39; delivery robot Digit, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/cassie-the-bipedal-robot-runs-a-5k/?tpcc=ECTW2020"><em>TechCrunch</em></a> notes, though you may also remember it for &quot;blindly&quot; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/a-bipedal-robot-has-learned-to-tackle-stairs-blind-102647481.html">navigating a set of stairs</a>. Oregon State University engineers were able to train Cassie in a simulator to enable it to go up and down a flight of stairs without the use of cameras or LIDAR. Now, engineers from the same team were able to train Cassie to run using a deep reinforcement learning algorithm.</p><div id="2c44962149d04a7b857d99ed165293f9"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dY57qnD_O7U?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>According to the team, Cassie teaching itself using the technique gave it the capability to stay upright without a tether by shifting its balance while running. The robot had to learn to make infinite subtle adjustments to be able to accomplish the feat. Yesh Godse, an undergrad from the OSU Dynamic Robotics Laboratory, explained: &quot;Deep reinforcement learning is a powerful method in AI that opens up skills like running, skipping and walking up and down stairs.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The team first tested Cassie&#39;s capability by having it run on turn for five kilometers, which it finished with a time of 43 minutes and 49 seconds. Cassie finished its run across the OSU campus in 53:03. It took a bit longer because it included six and a half minutes of dealing with technical issues. The robot fell once due to a computer overheating and then again after it executed a turn too quickly. But Jeremy Dao, another team member from the lab, said they were able to &quot;reach the limits of the hardware and show what it can do.&quot; The work the team does will help expand the understanding of legged locomotion and could help make bipedal robots become more common in the future.</p><div id="1f74672132fe4a1081acd7d08dcbff43"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FSaSjd_HOaI?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/watch-cassie-bipedal-robot-run-5k-093045955.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7482a1ed-7ef7-40b5-ad78-ed266c1be7a9</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627475790</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T12:36:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/62827220-ef6a-11eb-bd36-1a42b00c4d07" width="1600" height="1032" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/62827220-ef6a-11eb-bd36-1a42b00c4d07" width="1600" height="1032" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Agility Robotics]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Cassie]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Cassie]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[LG will reportedly sell iPhones in its South Korean stores]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rumors swirled <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/20/apple-iphones-to-be-sold-lg-stores-korea/">last week</a> that LG would start selling iPhones in some of its South Korean stores, since it has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-mobile-worldwide-shutdown-020959355.html">stopped producing</a> its own smartphones,. Now, LG has confirmed that it will start selling iPhones and other Apple products next month, <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/amd-q2-strong-amid-epyc-ryzen-demand"><em>ZDNet</em></a> has reported.&nbsp;</p><p>LG and Samsung agreed in 2018 to only sell their own smartphones at their respective stores so they wouldn&#39;t compete with smaller phone distributors. As such, when LG started to consider selling iPhones, it reportedly faced resistance from a smartphone reseller trade organization. Now that it has stopped making its own phones, however, that group has reportedly signed a new contract that allows LG to sell phones from other manufacturers.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On top of selling iPhones starting next month, LG will reportedly sell the Watch and other Apple products. The company has 400 stores in South Korea, so the move could provide a significant boost to Apple. It could be to the detriment of Apple&#39;s arch-rival Samsung, though, which has essentially had the local smartphone market to itself since LG dropped out.&nbsp;</p><p>Apple supposedly started negotiating with LG to sell phones in its retail spaces after the Korean company announced it would end production of its own devices. Both Samsung and Apple have been offering to pay LG smartphone owners up to 150,000 won ($135) to trade in their phones.&nbsp;</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lg-will-reportedly-sell-i-phones-in-its-south-korean-stores-081516817.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d4133a30-7315-4c75-a05f-66839500264e</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:15:16 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627455400</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T06:56:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Smart Phones]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/44e4da40-ef6b-11eb-bdcd-e81c487eef97" width="3000" height="1688" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/44e4da40-ef6b-11eb-bdcd-e81c487eef97" width="3000" height="1688" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG will reportedly sell iPhones in its South Korean stores]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG will reportedly sell iPhones in its South Korean stores]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vivaldi's Accordion tab stacks expand when you need them and hide when you don't]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the start of June, Vivaldi released its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/vivaldi-browser-update-mail-translation-110321734.html">4.0 update</a>, which added features like a translation tool to the privacy-focused browser. Its new 4.1 update is a smaller release but still adds a handful of handy features, including a new way to organize tabs.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-chrome-tab-groups-feature-164057759.html">Like Chrome</a>, Vivaldi allows you to group multiple tabs to restore some semblance of order to your tab bar. In Vivaldi, those groups are called stacks. Before 4.1, you had two ways of using them. You could opt for either the compact view or the two-level one. In the latter case, the browser adds a bar that displays the tabs you have in that stack. The compact view, by contrast, only hints at the number of websites you have pinned to the same group.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/f88249b0-ef12-11eb-8f54-fec49ac3fa84" style="height:1200;width:1600;" alt="Accordion tab stack setting" data-uuid="467ada23-04d3-3675-bf99-b186637f5922"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Vivaldi</div></figure><p>The new &quot;Accordion&quot; stacks Vivaldi is introducing today give you a third option that is something of a compromise between its two siblings. The icon that represents the group will automatically expand when you click on it. Instead of on a second bar, you’ll see all the included tabs to the right of that icon. In that way, you can get context about your tabs without them taking up an entire extra element of the interface.</p><p>The other major feature the company is adding with 4.1 is called command chains. In Vivaldi, you can press “F2” (or “Command E” on Mac) to bring up a command-line interface, allowing you to quickly access most features without digging through the menu for the relevant option. Command chains allow you to group multiple actions and assign a name to them. Typing the name of the chain in the command interface will execute the included actions in a sequence. With more than 200 actions available, you have a lot of flexibility. For instance, you can create one that enables both fullscreen and reading modes at the same time. You can also assign the sequences you make to a custom keyboard shortcut or mouse gesture.</p><p>Outside of those features, 4.1 adds a timer in <a href="https://help.vivaldi.com/tutorials/reader-view-in-vivaldi/">reader view</a> that estimates how long it should take you to work your way through an article. Lastly, the browser’s Windows client will now install new features in the background automatically. There’s an option to turn off “silent updates” in the settings menu. You can try Vivaldi 4.1 today.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/vivaldi-accordion-tab-stacks-070000491.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">526f1b02-11ab-4b42-bf17-00c59f397f50</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627415708</ingested><modified>2021-07-27T19:55:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/83f4c0b0-ef11-11eb-a9ff-cc67090b4e07" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/83f4c0b0-ef11-11eb-a9ff-cc67090b4e07" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Vivaldi]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Vivaldi Accordion tab stacks]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Vivaldi Accordion tab stacks]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rivian reportedly plans to invest $5 billion in its second US assembly plant]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, news <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-second-factory-capacity-battery-cells-193825530.html">leaked out</a> that Rivian was planning to build a second US manufacturing plant for its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-r1s-suv-delivery-dates-151911858.html">electric vehicles</a> and batteries, and now more details have leaked out. The company plans to invest $5 billion initially in the second plant, dubbed Project Tera, with construction slated to start in the fall of 2021, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/exclusive-rivian-ready-invest-5-billion-second-us-assembly-plant-document-2021-07-27/"><em>Reuters</em></a>. The aim is to begin production by the second quarter of 2023.&nbsp;</p><p>The second plant will reportedly include a 50 gigawatt-hour (GWh) battery cell production operation and a product and technology center. There&#39;s no word on where it&#39;ll be built, but the company is reportedly looking at land east of Mesa, Arizona, near Gold Canyon, according to <em>Reuters</em>&#39; sources. Rivian Chief Executive R.J. Scaringe has reportedly spoken with Arizona Governor Doug Ducey about the project.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Rivian previously acknowledged that it&#39;s looking to expand. “The company has recognized that future production and product plans will not be fully met by the current capacity at Rivian’s Normal, Illinois facility,” it said in the document seen by <em>Reuters</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>The plant would supposedly support around 10,000 jobs, though many of those could come indirectly. For a startup that has so far not produced a single vehicle, however, the investment and job figures would be impressive. Rivian is backed by Ford, Amazon and other companies and could reportedly soar to a $50 billion value in a possible public listing later this year, according to Reuters&#39; previous story.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rivian-reportedly-plans-to-invest-5-billion-in-a-second-us-assembly-plant-052245738.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">313070a3-2a0e-4482-865e-ad259130fe7e</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 05:22:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627449822</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T05:23:58+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/7ee95050-93b7-11eb-9e7f-a226a0880ebc" width="6415" height="4277" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/7ee95050-93b7-11eb-9e7f-a226a0880ebc" width="6415" height="4277" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mike Blake / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Rivian introduces R1T all-electric pickup truck at Los Angeles Auto Show in Los Angeles, California, U.S. November 27, 2018.  REUTERS/Mike Blake]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AUTOSHOW-LA/ELECTRICPICKUP]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nintendo is shutting down 'Dr. Mario World' for mobile on November 1st]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nintendo transformed its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-23-mario-kart-tour-multiplayer.html"><em>Mario Kart</em></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pokemon-go-trial-inside-eggs-115525336.html"><em>Pokemon</em></a> franchises into successful mobile spinoffs, but it looks like another title didn&#39;t fare as well. The company has <a href="https://drmario-world.com/en-US/topics/#topics_20210728">announced</a> that it&#39;s ending service of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-08-dr-mario-world-hands-on-ios-android.html"><em>Dr. Mario World</em></a>, a mobile version of its highly successful <em>Dr. Mario</em> NES game, on November 1st. It will also end sales of &quot;diamonds&quot; used to buy buy more time, pills and power-ups starting tomorrow, July 29th.&nbsp;</p><div id="54ea174f9da34dd4ba74d22d1b6bf0da"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">End of service notice: The Dr. Mario World game&#39;s service will end on Oct. 31, 2021. Thank you very much to the players who have supported the game. For details, please check this link: <a href="https://t.co/fC5qnRnLFD">https://t.co/fC5qnRnLFD</a></p>— Dr. Mario World (@Drmarioworld_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/Drmarioworld_EN/status/1420195877822468098?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Much like the original, <em>Dr. Mario World</em> is a Tetris-style game that lets you use pills to zap viruses of the same color. Unlike the original, however, everything moves upward so it&#39;s more natural to flick things around with one hand on a mobile screen. The mobile game also has a multiplayer mode so you can get friends involved.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The game was developed by Nintendo in conjunction with Line, Japan&#39;s ultra-popular mobile messaging app. It launched on July 10th, 2019, just a hair over two years ago. Nintendo is keeping a vestige of the game on a web page called &quot;Dr. Mario World Memories&quot; that will allow players to look back on their history once the service ends.&nbsp;</p><p>Nintendo launched another mobile,<em>&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-03-nintendo-mobile-subscription-fire-emblem-heroes-feh-pass.html"><em>Mario Kart Tour</em></a>, with multiplayer support in early 2020. That title has reportedly been downloaded 200 million times and seen relatively high earnings for the company. Its most successful mobile game by far, however, is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-03-nintendo-mobile-subscription-fire-emblem-heroes-feh-pass.html"><em>Fire Emblem Heroes</em></a>, which had reportedly netted up to $656 million as of February, 2020. Nintendo didn&#39;t say why it shut down <em>Dr. Mario World</em>, but it wasn&#39;t doing great compared to other titles shortly after launch, according to a <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/nintendo-revenue-one-billion"><em>SensorTower</em></a> report from early 2020.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-dr-mario-world-is-shutting-down-on-november-1st-050347975.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">25135454-f513-4dba-a5ca-3fece1f45ee5</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 05:03:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627445116</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T04:05:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/935bdd40-ef52-11eb-99c7-48287e7b1c70" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/935bdd40-ef52-11eb-99c7-48287e7b1c70" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Nintendo's 'Dr. Mario World' is shutting down on November 1st]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Nintendo's 'Dr. Mario World' is shutting down on November 1st]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[WoW will remove 'inappropriate references' following California lawsuit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The official World of Warcraft Twitter account has <a href="https://twitter.com/Warcraft/status/1420129038912278529/photo/1">announced</a> that it will take immediate action to &quot;remove references that are not appropriate for [its] world.&quot; While it didn&#39;t elaborate on what those references are, they may pertain to in-game elements connected to its senior creative director Alex Afrasiabi, as <a href="https://kotaku.com/world-of-warcraft-removing-inappropriate-references-to-1847373517"><em>Kotaku</em></a> has noted. Afrasiabi was singled out in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-sues-activision-blizzard-090352763.html">lawsuit</a> filed by California authorities accusing Activision Blizzard of fostering a &quot;frat boy&quot; culture that&#39;s become a &quot;breeding ground for harassment and discrimination against women.&quot;</p><div id="3c749356fdad4fa195dd31324d41c855"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A message from the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Warcraft?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Warcraft</a> team. <a href="https://t.co/3gWCz1gu8T">pic.twitter.com/3gWCz1gu8T</a></p>— World of Warcraft (@Warcraft) <a href="https://twitter.com/Warcraft/status/1420129038912278529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>According to the lawsuit, Afrasiabi is known for hitting on and touching female employees inappropriately in plain view of other male employees who would try to intervene and stop him. He apparently has such a notorious reputation within the company that his suite was nicknamed the &quot;Crosby Suite after alleged rapist Bill Crosby.&quot;(The lawsuit has misspelled Bill Cosby&#39;s name.) In addition, executives allegedly knew about his behavior but &quot;took no effective remedial measures.&quot; Blizzard President J. Allen Brack talked to him a few times, the lawsuit reads, but gave Afiasiabi a slap on the wrist for the incidents.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Activision Blizzard denied the accusations in the lawsuit and said it &quot;includes distorted, and in many cases false, descriptions of Blizzard&#39;s past&quot; in its initial response. Executive Vice President Fran Townsend told employees <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-executives-harassment-discrimination-lawsuit-response-192228768.html">in a memo</a> that the lawsuit &quot;presented a distorted and untrue picture of [the] company, including factually incorrect, old and out of context stories.&quot;</p><p>A group of over 800 Activision Blizzard employees <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-employee-open-letter-221223475.html">decried</a> the company&#39;s response to the accusations as &quot;abhorrent and insulting.&quot; They wrote in an open letter: &quot;Categorizing the claims that have been made as ‘distorted, and in many cases false’ creates a company atmosphere that disbelieves victims.&quot; At least 50 employees working in the company&#39;s main office in California are now <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-activision-walkout-184945869.html">planning a walkout</a> on Wednesday to protest the company&#39;s actions and to demand better working conditions for women.</p><p>In WoW&#39;s announcement, it said the decision to remove inappropriate elements was made in order to rebuild trust. It admitted that it must earn people&#39;s trust with its &quot;actions in the weeks and months to come,&quot; though it didn&#39;t say what other steps the company intends to take in response to the lawsuit&#39;s allegations.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/wow-remove-inappropriate-references-california-lawsuit-035510730.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6b3f691f-314b-4dea-99d5-20f4ad0626ab</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 03:55:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627444536</ingested><modified>2021-07-28T03:55:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/996c8eb0-ef51-11eb-bf4d-f132d359a728" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/996c8eb0-ef51-11eb-bf4d-f132d359a728" width="1600" height="900" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter tests notification banner for suspended and locked accounts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1420074309998063619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1420074309998063619%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.trello.services%2Ftweets.html7B22secret223A22apnJdH90NUavyGVwBtNoufJRJlgChRHJFpmUL4685mWgkskXHlkZPKXNHMaBDRvB222C22context223A7B22version223A22build-8294222C22member223A2255510be57a7ff3d007df0c30222C22permissions223A7B22board223A22write222C22card223A22write227D2C22organization223A22535db1366cfbe3051ea534e7222C22board223A22535db14bdaa739561e16a033222C22card223A22610067a76c11452fbf9faad4222C22command223A22attachment-sections227D2C22locale223A22en-US227D">testing a new way</a> to inform individuals who may have broken its rules that their account has been suspended or locked. With the start of this latest test, a small group of users will see a banner appear at the top of their timeline informing them that they can’t tweet, retweet or like content due to their previous behavior on the platform. In the instance of a locked account, the notice currently says most users regain access within a week. Meanwhile, with permanent suspensions, the banner points the individual to the company’s appeal process.</p><div id="e380d16ce2c24ee4b5162bd1961189f8"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Knowing where your account stands is important. We’re testing a new way of letting you know — right when you log in. <br><br>If your account is locked or suspended, some of you will start seeing a banner making that clear. <a href="https://t.co/fOP53keghz">pic.twitter.com/fOP53keghz</a></p>— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1420074309998063619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>A spokesperson for Twitter told <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596615/twitter-notice-banner-suspended-locked-testing"><em>The Verge</em></a> the notices come in response to feedback the company has received from people who said they only realized their account was inaccessible after they tried to tweet or follow new accounts. Should Twitter decide to implement the banners, they could get a lot of work. In the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-second-half-2020-transparency-report-184953614.html">second half of 2020</a>, the company removed more abusive content than ever before on the back of more effective automated moderation tools and policies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-hate-speech-rules-race-ethnicity-194849330.html">against hate speech</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-tests-account-suspension-banners-215253369.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6c1adcd0-06be-4ded-9392-e183be2d389a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627418886</ingested><modified>2021-07-27T20:48:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/94518250-ef1a-11eb-b53d-0b0fcfb4055f" width="4392" height="2755" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/94518250-ef1a-11eb-b53d-0b0fcfb4055f" width="4392" height="2755" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitter app is seen on a smartphone in this illustration taken, July 13, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TECH-TWITTER/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple posts another record-breaking quarter thanks to the iPhone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite the pandemic, Apple has spent most of the last two years relentlessly upgrading its product lineup, and its moves are definitely paying off. The company just announced financial results for its fiscal year third quarter (for normal humans, the months of April through June), and the company made a shocking amount of money. All of its product segments (the iPhone, Mac, iPad, services, and wearables/home/accessories) increased in revenue year-over-year, leading to total revenue of $81.4 billion. As has often been the case, iPhone revenue of $39.6 billion made up almost half of that figure.&nbsp;</p><p>Quarterly revenue was up 36 percent year-over-year, and as such profit grew in a big way, too — in fact, it nearly doubled. Apple reported $21.7 billion in net income, up 93 percent compared to a year ago.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As already mentioned, all of Apple&#39;s product categories grew last quarter, but the biggest winner was the iPhone. Revenue grew 50 percent year-over-year, making it pretty clear the iPhone 12 lineup is a major success for the company. Apple&#39;s services division continues to explode; $17.5 billion in revenue represented 33 percent growth, and the category makes more than double the money of any other division in Apple, with the obvious exception of the iPhone.</p><p>The company&#39;s &quot;wearables, home and accessories&quot; group lumps the Apple Watch in with devices like the HomePod mini and the new AirTags. It grew 36 percent and made $8.8 billion in revenue. The Mac and iPad had more modest gains, with Mac revenue increasing 16 percent year over year to $8.2 billion and iPad revenue climbing 12 percent to $7.4 billion. While the Mac number isn&#39;t an eye-popper like services, it&#39;s worth nothing that just a few years ago, Mac revenue was pretty flat, sitting in the $4 billion range for a while — but it seems like the M1 Mac move has helped spur some big increases.</p><p>As usual, Apple CEO Tim Cook is holding a call with investors — we&#39;ll update this story with anything we learn.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-q2-2021-earnings-210238898.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fc8b7e84-d0a3-450e-8dc2-1c99bbb12648</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 21:02:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627420001</ingested><modified>2021-07-27T21:06:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e6b6c310-e417-11eb-bb99-2be7f7ad1e4f" width="5719" height="3805" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e6b6c310-e417-11eb-bb99-2be7f7ad1e4f" width="5719" height="3805" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ANGELA WEISS via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[People walk past an Apple retail store on July 13, 2021 in New York City. - Stock markets were slightly softer on news of the biggest jump in US inflation in more than two decades and disappointment in results from US investment banks. As trading ended in London, Frankfurt and Paris, major indices hovered around the zero mark, while the Dow Jones index was also a tiny bit lower in midday New York exchanges. (Photo by Angela Weiss / AFP) (Photo by ANGELA WEISS/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-ECONOMY-INFLATION]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft's profits skyrocketed by 47 percent in Q4]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft&#39;s business continues to thrive thanks to its leadership in cloud computing and productivity apps. In its <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/Investor/earnings/FY-2021-Q4/press-release-webcast">Q4 earnings report today</a>, the company reported a 21 percent increase in revenues compared to last year, reaching $46.2 billion. But even more impressive, its profits jumped by 47 percent to reach $16.5 billion. Microsoft&#39;s success is practically a broken record by this point — last quarter it saw <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-q3-2021-earnings-report-pandemic-204921611.html">a 44 percent increase in profit</a>, and before that it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-earnings-q2-2021-214039752.html">grew by 33 percent</a> — but it&#39;s still managing to <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/microsoft-q4-earnings-2021-205140685.html">beat the expectations of Wall Street analysts</a>.</p><p>The key to Microsoft&#39;s growth is the same as it has been for the past several years. Its Intelligent Cloud business is seemingly unstoppable, growing by 30 percent compared to last year. And it&#39;s still seeing plenty of growth with Office, Linkedin and its other business apps, which together have increased revenues by 25 percent. Even its More Personal Computing group, which includes Windows and Xbox, saw its business improve by 9 percent. (Thatcategory saw a few dips in the quarter though: Surface business fell by 20 percent, and Xbox content and services saw a 4 percent drop.)</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Microsoft&#39;s Q4 earnings aren&#39;t really telling us anything new, as the company&#39;s entire 2021 fiscal year has been strong. The company reported an overall revenue increase of 18 percent for 2021 ($168.1 billion), as well as a 38 percent jump in profit for the year ($61.3 billion). Microsoft&#39;s previous earnings report proved that it made out well during the pandemic, but now it seems like those gains aren&#39;t stopping anytime soon.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-q4-fy21-earnings-203724611.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">51e4e51b-9a7f-499a-a161-3d1701fd3d5a</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:37:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1627418297</ingested><modified>2021-07-27T20:38:27+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Company Earnings]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e1fb5d60-ef19-11eb-b277-3a0c338c7138" width="4865" height="3392" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e1fb5d60-ef19-11eb-b277-3a0c338c7138" width="4865" height="3392" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dado Ruvic / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[3D-printed Microsoft logos are seen on a computer motherboard in this picture illustration taken July 22, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TECH-MICROSOFT/]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>