<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter says its algorithms amplify the ‘political right’ but it doesn’t know why]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter said <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-will-study-algorithms-for-unintentional-harm-182722681.html"><ins>in April</ins></a> that it was undertaking a new effort to study algorithmic fairness on its platform and whether its algorithms contribute to “unintentional harms.” As part of that work, the company promised to study the political leanings of its content recommendations. Now, the company <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/rml-politicalcontent"><ins>has published</ins></a> its initial findings. According to Twitter’s research team, the company’s timeline algorithm amplifies content from the “political right” in six of the seven countries it studied.</p><p>The research looked at two issues: whether the algorithmic timeline amplified political content from elected officials, and whether some political groups received a greater amount of amplification. The researchers used tweets from news outlets and elected officials in seven countries (Canada, France, Germany, Japan, Spain, the United Kingdom, and the United States) to conduct the analysis, which they said was the first of its kind for Twitter.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>“Tweets about political content from elected officials, regardless of party or whether the party is in power, do see algorithmic amplification when compared to political content on the reverse chronological timeline,” Twitter’s Rumman Chowdhury <a href="https://twitter.com/ruchowdh/status/1451248454609506306"><ins>wrote</ins></a> about the research. “In 6 out of 7 countries, Tweets posted by political right elected officials are algorithmically amplified more than the political left. Right-leaning news outlets (defined by 3rd parties), see greater amplification compared to left-leaning.”</p><div id="2bbb007e23654f298c802064084f8cae"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here’s what’s complex: The team did phenomenal work identifying *what* is happening. Establishing *why* these observed patterns occur is a significantly more difficult question to answer and something META will examine. <br>5/n</p>— Rumman Chowdhury (@ruchowdh) <a href="https://twitter.com/ruchowdh/status/1451249531660562432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Crucially, as Chowdhury points out <a href="https://www.protocol.com/policy/twitter-algorithm-right-wing-bias"><ins>to </ins><em><ins>Protocol</ins></em></a>, it’s not yet clear why this is happening. In <a href="https://cdn.cms-twdigitalassets.com/content/dam/blog-twitter/official/en_us/company/2021/rml/Algorithmic-Amplification-of-Politics-on-Twitter.pdf"><ins>the paper</ins></a>, the researchers posit that the difference in amplification could be a result of political parties pursuing “different strategies on Twitter.” But the team said that more research would be needed to fully understand the cause.</p><p>While the findings are likely to raise some eyebrows, Chowdhury also notes that “algorithmic amplification is not problematic by default.” The researchers further point out that their findings “does not support the hypothesis that algorithmic personalization amplifies extreme ideologies more than mainstream political voices.”</p><p>But at the very least, the research would seem to <a href="https://www.stern.nyu.edu/experience-stern/faculty-research/false-accusation-unfounded-claim-social-media-companies-censor-conservatives"><ins>further debunk</ins></a> the notion that Twitter is biased against conservatives. The research also offers an intriguing look at how a tech platform can study the unintentional effects of its algorithms. Facebook, which has come under pressure to make more of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transparency-researchers-170021370.html"><ins>its own research</ins></a> public, has <a href="https://www.axios.com/facebook-algorithm-safety-nick-clegg-0c96e08a-9034-4379-9ca3-190b36a9a90f.html"><ins>defended</ins></a> its algorithms even as a whistleblower has suggested the company should <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-said-should-change-143051354.html"><ins>move back</ins></a> to a chronological timeline.</p><p>Twitter’s research is part of a broader effort by Twitter to uncover bias and other issues in its algorithms. The company has also published research about its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-image-cropping-algorithm-study-203010717.html"><ins>image cropping</ins></a> algorithm and started a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-bug-bounty-contest-algorithm-bias-image-cropping-185634779.html"><ins>bug bounty</ins></a> program to find bias in its platform.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-says-its-algorithms-amplify-the-political-right-but-it-doesnt-know-why-205859230.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b6c63f3f-fbe2-49a6-a0bb-0f184ec432d8</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634849046</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T20:44:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7efddc60-32ad-11ec-bd7e-5125a462d4b2" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7efddc60-32ad-11ec-bd7e-5125a462d4b2" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[In this photo illustration a Twitter logo seen displayed on a smartphone screen with a computer wallpaper in the background in Athens, Greece on May 5, 2021. (Photo by Nikolas Kokovlis/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Logo Illustrations In Athens]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Regulator orders Apple, Google to hand over app store payment system data]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>American tech heavyweights are facing yet more <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-play-store-suit-211116918.html">scrutiny of their payment practices</a>. The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau has <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-orders-tech-giants-to-turn-over-information-on-their-payment-system-plans/">ordered</a> Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, PayPal and Square to hand over info concerning their payment system plans. The bureau wants to learn how these companies harvest data and control access to spot any anti-consumer behavior and provide &quot;adequate&quot; protections to the public.</p><p>The CFPB will also study Chinese tech firms&#39; payment systems, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/trump-administration-bans-alipay-wechat-pay-103530923.html">Alipay and WeChat Pay</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Director Rohit Chopra justified the order by warning that payments can pose a threat to the fair market thanks to their &quot;tremendous scale and market power.&quot; He pointed to China as an example, noting that systems like Alipay and WeChat Pay are so thoroughly integrated with Chinese society that residents are effectively forced to use them as-is.</p><p>The bureau said it was following up on Federal Trade Commission <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-facebook-amended-antitrust-case-161230871.html">oversight of Big Tech</a>. The regulator has studied some of the companies&#39; behavior in detail and, in the faces of Facebook and Google, put them under close watch. In 2020, for instance, the FTC <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-11-ftc-antitrust-investigation-facebook-google.html">investigated Facebook and Google acquisitions</a> that hadn&#39;t been reported.</p><p>There&#39;s no certainty the CFPB orders will lead to regulatory action. However, they come right as politicians are trying to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bipartisan-open-app-markets-act-introduction-221732872.html">rein in Apple, Google and others</a> for allegedly abusing app store payments. The Biden administration as a whole is also determined to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lina-khan-ftc-confirmation-antitrust-big-tech-183254782.html">crack down on tech companies</a>. There&#39;s a chance CFPB will take corrective measures, even as those companies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-play-store-fees-subscriptions-e-books-music-streaming-apps-170908763.html">lower fees</a> and otherwise try to make peace offerings.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/cfpb-apple-facebook-google-payment-system-order-204005225.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">45ca38b5-50dc-4ed7-b257-3c9289c6922f</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:40:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634848808</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T20:40:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/3ac799b0-5a5d-11eb-b73b-60c80fa15277" width="3996" height="2664" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/3ac799b0-5a5d-11eb-b73b-60c80fa15277" width="3996" height="2664" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Tom Williams via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[UNITED STATES - FEBRUARY 14: Rohit Chopra, nominee to serve on the Federal Trade Commission, testifies during a Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee confirmation hearing in Hart Building on February 14, 2018. (Photo By Tom Williams/CQ Roll Call)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FTC]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon workers in New York City are building toward a union vote]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon may soon face a second unionization effort in less than a year. Per <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/21/technology/amazon-workers-union-staten-island.html"><em><ins>The New York Times</ins></em></a>, hourly workers at the company’s JFK8 fulfillment center in New York City are in the process of collecting signatures to file for a union election. They’re expected to contact the National Labor Relations Board on Monday. If the agency grants their request, it will lead to a vote with potentially significant ramifications for Amazon.</p><p>This past April, Amazon beat back a historic union vote at its BHM1 fulfillment center in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alabama-union-vote-154741754.html"><ins>Bessemer, Alabama</ins></a>. Approximately 1,700 of the more than 3,000 employees who took part in the election voted against unionization, handing Amazon a comfortable majority. However, the election was mired in controversy, with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), which sought to represent the approximately 5,800 workers at Bessemer, accusing the company of unfairly influencing the vote. In August, the National Labor Relations Board ruled that Amazon had <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-found-to-have-illegally-discouraged-union-organizing-in-alabama-035214235.html"><ins>violated US labor laws</ins></a>, and recommended that workers in Bessemer hold a new election.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Amazon employs more than 5,000 workers at JFK8. Beyond its sheer size, the facility has been the site of multiple protests since the start of the pandemic. Among those leading the unionization effort at JFK8 is Christian Smalls. Amazon fired Smalls after he organized a walkout over the company’s handling of COVID safety at the warehouse. At the time, the company said Smalls broke a quarantine order by attending the event. At the start of the year, New York <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-sued-by-new-york-over-flagrant-disregard-for-covid-19-safety-115013292.html">sued Amazon</a>, alleging the company had retaliated against Smalls.</p><p>When Engadget reached out to Amazon about the effort, the company noted its employees have always had the option to join a union but said it was against the idea.</p><blockquote><p>As a company, we don’t think unions are the best answer for our employees. Every day we empower people to find ways to improve their jobs, and when they do that we want to make those changes — quickly. That type of continuous improvement is harder to do quickly and nimbly with unions in the middle. The benefits of direct relationships between managers and employees can’t be overstated — these relationships allow every employee’s voice to be heard, not just the voices of a select few. We’ve made great progress in recent years and months in important areas like pay and safety. There are plenty of things that we can keep doing better, and that&#39;s our focus — to keep getting better every day.</p></blockquote><p>Even if the National Labor Relations Board calls an election after Monday, the workers at JFK8 face an uphill battle. They’re up against one of the world’s wealthiest and most powerful corporations. From competitive wages to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-amazon-anti-union-ads-212739548.html"><ins>Twitch ads</ins></a>, Amazon has consistently used nearly every tool available to it to dissuade its workers from unionizing.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-staten-island-warehouse-unionization-drive-193814629.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">46a651b5-9d48-4c52-8eae-90ccb13fd1fd</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:38:14 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634845059</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T19:37:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Unions]]></category><category><![CDATA[Labor Issues]]></category><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/c7afb1f0-3415-11eb-bff7-93bacb6e4452" width="3793" height="2529" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/c7afb1f0-3415-11eb-bff7-93bacb6e4452" width="3793" height="2529" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Brendan McDermid / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[An employee scans packages at Amazon's JFK8 distribution center in Staten Island, New York, U.S. November 25, 2020.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AMAZON.COM-HOLIDAY/WAREHOUSE]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Razer's smart RGB face mask is now available for $100]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-smart-mask-oled-gaming-chair-193027315.html">better part of a year</a>, but <a href="https://www.engadget.com/razer-project-hazel-shipping-early-q4-2021-070156937.html">Razer&#39;s smart face mask</a> is finally available. You can buy the Zephyr either by itself <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:for $100" href="https://fave.co/3BZDUEC">for $100</a> or a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:$150" href="https://fave.co/3joCs7C">$150</a> Starter Pack with three replacement filter kits. Individual replacements are $30. Just be prepared to hunt around, or at least to be patient — the Starter Pack is already listed as &quot;out of stock,&quot; and the mask by itself is still &quot;coming soon.&quot;</p><p>The Zephyr is, effectively a high-end pandemic protection kit for gamers. The transparent design and RGB lighting give it a bit of flash (this is a Razer product, after all), but the highlight is a dual-fan active air filtration system with N95 filters. This theoretically protects you as well as it does others. There&#39;s even a mobile app to customize the lights.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In a sense, Razer&#39;s mask is a gamble that paid off. While it&#39;s arriving relatively late in to the COVID-19 pandemic, there are many places that still require masks, some of which might mandate that protection for a while to come. The Zephyr could help people in those areas feel more comfortable in public, particularly if they&#39;re already Razer enthusiasts.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/razer-zephyr-face-mask-release-date-193032958.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">75517599-f156-47e6-80cd-4f0215f888fe</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:30:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634843500</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T19:11:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c2dbed10-329d-11ec-a77f-130ccbfff8ea" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c2dbed10-329d-11ec-a77f-130ccbfff8ea" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Razer Zephyr face mask]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Zephyr face mask]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[AMD and Microsoft issue fixes for Ryzen CPU slowdowns on Windows 11]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after Microsoft <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">released Windows 11</a> earlier this month, AMD warned that the OS <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-windows-11-bug-ryzen-100550246.html"><ins>could slow down apps</ins></a> on systems with Ryzen processors. The chipmaker promised to fix the bugs, and now AMD and Microsoft have issued patches that should do just that.</p><p>The latest chipset driver (version 3.10.08.506) should take care of the UEFI CPPC2 issue, which in some cases didn&#39;t &quot;preferentially schedule threads on a processor’s fastest core,&quot; <a href="https://www.amd.com/en/support/kb/faq/pa-400"><ins>AMD said</ins></a>. That could have slowed down apps that are sensitive to CPU thread performance. AMD noted that the problem was likely more noticeable in more powerful processors with more than eight cores and 65W or higher Thermal Design Power (TDP).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, Microsoft is rolling out a software update tackling a bug that increased L3 cache latency. The issue impacted apps that need quick memory access, which in turn caused CPUs to slow down by up to 15 percent. The patch, Windows 11 update KB5006746, will be available starting today, but at the time of writing, <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/KB5006746"><ins>a page containing instructions</ins></a> for installing it isn&#39;t yet live. You should be able to install it via Windows Update too.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amd-microsoft-ryzen-processor-windows-11-bug-fixes-190439836.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">61def37c-9658-4dca-b694-93c702731465</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:04:39 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634843081</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T19:04:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/e5883130-9c65-11eb-aa4f-b9457735d36a" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/e5883130-9c65-11eb-aa4f-b9457735d36a" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[AMD]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 5000G series CPU]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 5000G series CPU]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Razer’s $399 Enki is better than most office chairs, period]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past decade we’ve seen the tag “gamer” used increasingly as a lifestyle sales pitch. Sure, you can buy gaming headsets and gaming mice and gaming keyboards, but there are also gamer hoodies and gamer drinks and even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-pre-order-shipping-145328930.html">gamer furniture</a>. Chairs made especially for playing have been proliferating over the past few years and until now, they’ve tended to be overpriced and ostentatious. Razer’s new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Enki chair" href="https://fave.co/2XyeIpM">Enki chair</a> is still a bit over the top, but at least it’s a more affordable over the top, starting at <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:$299" href="https://fave.co/3ppASWJ">$299</a>.</p><p>To build the Enki, Razer called in ergonomics experts, paying attention not just to lumbar support, but also to how test subjects sat on the bottom cushion. The 21-inch-wide seat is shaped to distribute your weight more evenly, so you can sit for hours without getting a sore ass. They even considered the needs of those who like to sit in more unusual positions, like a half- or full-lotus. As someone who often sits cross-legged in my chair, I am grateful for the extra space and support.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><core-slideshow data-slideshowid="7f9ca757-9509-45dd-8f32-eb68174ade44"/><p>Perhaps the most impressive thing about the chair is how far back it can lean. It’s not quite 180 degrees, but 152 degrees is still pretty good — the kind of angle you might only see on an airliner’s international business class. It’s the kind of chair you can fall asleep in. It seems precarious but in use, the chair held my weight well when I opened it to its max. It didn’t feel too top heavy, like it would fall backward, but it felt a bit unnatural due to the lack of a footrest. But let’s be honest, you really should just retire to your couch or bed when you need a proper snooze. This is good for when you need a bit of a stretch between <em>Overwatch</em> matches or Zoom meetings.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/eeacfe00-31e1-11ec-bfdb-706099ddf858" alt="Razer Enki from rear" data-uuid="19d9c932-54a4-33b1-9041-09aa588bb812"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Kris Naudus / Engadget</div></figure><p>My one nitpick besides the lack of a footrest is the head pillow, which is only included with a more expensive $399 package. It’s a nice shape and the fabric feels good to the touch, but it’s also not very adjustable. It has to be strapped on around the moon-shaped cut out toward the top of the seat, which means the height is non-negotiable. I found it ended up in that limbo between my head and neck, where it just jutted out and supported neither of them. I found it incredibly uncomfortable and ended up tearing it off. However, it also felt weird to not have something supporting my head in this chair. I can only hope that Razer ends up offering more options for users of different heights.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/02d87480-31e3-11ec-aed6-4e84b5fdd520" alt="The headrest on the Razer Enki, it sucks" data-uuid="ff81871e-53ff-32b2-8481-b101f26ae5a3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Kris Naudus / Engadget</div></figure><p>Aside from that, it’s a very <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:good chair" href="https://fave.co/2XyeIpM">good chair</a> offered at a very good price — other chairs from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/minecraft-gaming-chair-secretlab-173058454.html">Secretlab</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/logitech-herman-miller-embody-gaming-chair-130000054.html">Logitech</a> might cost hundreds more, and a good non-gaming office chair can easily go above $1,000. And, while some might find it silly to buy a “gaming” chair, there’s no rule this has to be used only for gaming. You can use the chair for work, meetings and anything else. It’s not gaudy in any way that would draw attention on a video call, as Razer eschewed its usual use of lime green highlights.</p><p>In the end, it’s just a chair. A nice, comfortable chair that you can buy <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Razer Enki" href="https://fave.co/2XyeIpM">directly from Razer</a> or various retailers starting today, for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:$299 for the Enki X" href="https://fave.co/3ppASWJ">$299 for the Enki X</a> or the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Razer;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:$399 Enki" href="https://fave.co/3joSKxi">$399 Enki</a> that includes the head pillow, a more reactive seat tilt and an armrest adjustable in four directions. With all the time you’ve been spending in front of the computer lately, you should make it a little nicer.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/razer-enki-gaming-chair-hands-head-butt-on-180019360.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">08f06959-af9e-4ae4-bdb7-44bf90c7823d</guid><dc:creator>Kris Naudus</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 18:00:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634845371</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T19:43:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Naudus]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c15a2e20-31e4-11ec-9f77-3db2c637cd75" width="2400" height="1600" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c15a2e20-31e4-11ec-9f77-3db2c637cd75" width="2400" height="1600" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Product image of Enki in a room with a gaming desktop, guitar and couch]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Razer Enki]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Among Us' will hit Xbox and PlayStation on December 14th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Innersloth has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/among-us-xbox-2021-210714582.html"><ins>promising</ins></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/among-us-ps4-ps5-2021-exclusive-skin-213304316.html"><ins>for months</ins></a> that it will bring <em>Among Us </em>to Xbox and PlayStation sometime this year. Sure enough, the <em>Mafia-</em>style social deduction game <a href="https://www.innersloth.com/xbox-playstation-launch-on-dec-14/?utm_source=social&amp;utm_medium=tweet&amp;utm_campaign=console">is coming</a> to PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S on December 14th.</p><p>Just like on PC, <a href="http://engadget.com/tag/among%20us"><em>Among Us</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>will be included with Xbox Game Pass on consoles. Those on PlayStation, meanwhile, will get an exclusive Ratchet &amp; Clank cosmetic at a later date. <em>Among Us </em>has crossplay support, so you&#39;ll be able to play with friends across PC, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/among-us-switch-launch-today-173338948.html">Nintendo Switch</a> and mobile.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Innersloth also revealed details about the physical editions of <em>Among Us</em> for PlayStation, Xbox and Switch. Along with the base game and all of the DLC, the <a href="https://store.maximumgames.com/collections/among-us-collectors-editions/products/among-us-crewmate-edition"><ins>$30 Crewmate Edition</ins></a> includes a poster of the Skeld map, stickers and a holographic card. That version will hit Europe on December 14, Japan and South Korea two days later, and then the US, Canada and Latin America on January 11th.</p><p>The <a href="https://store.maximumgames.com/collections/among-us-collectors-editions/products/among-us-impostor-edition"><ins>$50 Impostor Edition</ins></a> includes the same gear as the Crewmate package, along with a purple crewmate plush, an enamel pin and a lanyard. The $90 Ejected Edition comes with even more goodies, including a steelbook case, a beanie and, best of all, a fleece blanket. Both of those editions will ship in spring 2022.</p><p><em>Among Us</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/among-us-2-canceled-innersloth-234805154.html"><ins>exploded in popularity</ins></a> in 2020, two years after its debut, as Twitch streamers and YouTubers started playing it en masse. People were also looking for ways to connect with their friends during COVID-19 lockdowns and, for many, lying to their buds about what they were doing in <em>Among Us&#39;</em> med bay fit the bill perfectly. It&#39;s coming to Xbox and PlayStation just in time for more people to play and argue with their loved ones over the holiday season.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/among-us-ps4-ps5-xbox-one-series-xs-release-date-174338652.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9ce22fb4-7cb1-4c5e-a45c-6b363fd89537</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:43:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634837929</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T17:38:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/cc69a660-3293-11ec-bddf-4d7bce9b99ca" width="1024" height="576" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/cc69a660-3293-11ec-bddf-4d7bce9b99ca" width="1024" height="576" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Innersloth]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Four crewmate characters from Among Us sit around a TV and play video games.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Among Us]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google will make it easier to separate your work and personal apps on Android]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google plans to bring Android’s work profile feature to more devices. If you’re not familiar with the tool, it separates your work and personal apps from one another and adds a toggle to your phone you can use to disable the former when you need to disconnect.</p><div id="40c9103a8cd0473e9255be339d988206"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lqwoXmaxs3M?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>When you flip the switch, any work-related apps you have installed on your device can’t send you notifications and access your location. It also silos the data from your personal apps, ensuring that your company’s IT department can’t access your personal information.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>At the moment, the tool is only available to enterprise customers, but <a href="https://www.blog.google/products/android-enterprise/art-of-control/"><ins>starting in 2022</ins></a> Google will begin rolling it out to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-workspace-open-everyone-free-spaces-100004157.html"><ins>Workspace users</ins></a>. It then plans to make it available to other identity providers. “This will eventually allow anyone using Android for business purposes to separate work and personal apps in one interface and pause all work-related apps in one click,” the company said. The feature’s expansion should be of great help to business owners and freelancers but nearly anyone can benefit from having a better work-life balance.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-android-work-profile-workspace-2022-173541051.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0da6979c-8919-416c-ba0f-2cc2f8f8837a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634837517</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T17:32:09+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fead340-3293-11ec-bd7d-550fbc780728" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7fead340-3293-11ec-bd7d-550fbc780728" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Android Work Profile]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Android Work Profile]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter buys a chat app to boost DMs and community features]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is willing to spend to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-direct-message-updates-195652044.html">bolster direct messaging</a>. <em>CNBC</em><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/21/twitter-buys-nick-daloisios-free-chat-app-sphere-.html">notes</a> Twitter has <a href="https://blog.sphere.me/sphere-has-joined-twitter-e7127cfe0467">acquired</a> the chat app Sphere for an unspecified amount. Engineering VP Nick Caldwell <a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1450854466127683588">said</a> the move would speed up development for DMs, Communities and Creators. There were no specific clues as to what was coming next, but Sphere said was &quot;winding down&quot; its app in November. You won&#39;t see a repurposed Sphere app, then.</p><p>Sphere is notable not just for its features (it focuses on &quot;essential&quot; messages and clearing out clutter), but on the tech industry star power surrounding the app. The company is the product of Nick D&#39;Aloisio, a serial entrepreneur who caught attention even as a teen — he sold Summly to Yahoo (now Engadget&#39;s parent company) <a href="https://allthingsd.com/20130325/yahoo-paid-30-million-in-cash-for-18-months-of-young-summly-entrepreneurs-time/">when he was 17</a>. His latest venture has high-profile investors, including co-founders from Airbnb and Tinder. While Sphere isn&#39;t particularly large with just 20 staffers headed to Twitter, there were clearly high hopes before the acquisition.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The purchase is a fitting one. Twitter has poured much of its recent energy into DMs and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-tip-jar-201442453.html">helping creators form communities</a>. Twitter could weave Sphere&#39;s focused community features throughout its social network and better compete against Instagram and other rivals that thrive on private messaging and influential figures.</p><div id="5bfa944cf72b42e4ab1f6a69eb5957d1"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Sphere team’s expertise and leadership’s passion for finding ways to help people connect will help accelerate our Communities, DM, and Creators roadmaps. 🚀</p>— Nick Caldwell 👨🏾‍💻⚡️ (@nickcald) <a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1450854466127683588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-buys-sphere-chat-app-for-dm-172041321.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f1e8b1ff-9acc-488e-85e5-5f96512ce2b4</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:20:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634836844</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T17:20:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/d5858610-1cc7-11ec-afff-41449b507315" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/d5858610-1cc7-11ec-afff-41449b507315" width="5000" height="3333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BRAZIL - 2021/08/27: In this photo illustration the Twitter logo seen displayed on a smartphone. (Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration the Twitter logo seen displayed...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google cuts Play Store fees for subscriptions and music streaming apps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google/"><ins>Google</ins></a> is cutting <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/play%20store/"><ins>Play Store</ins></a> service fees for more developers. The company currently charges a 30 percent commission for the first 12 months of a recurring subscription, which drops to 15 percent after the first year. Starting on January 1st, Google will lower the service fee to 15 percent from day one. The company said it&#39;s making the change because developers say &quot;customer churn makes it challenging for subscription businesses to benefit from that reduced rate.&quot;</p><p>Elsewhere, fees for music streaming apps and e-books will be as low as 10 percent. &quot;The new rates recognize industry economics of media content verticals and make Google Play work better for developers and the communities of artists, musicians and authors they represent,&quot; Sameer Samat, vice president of product management for Android and Google Play, <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/10/evolving-business-model.html"><ins>wrote in a blog post</ins></a>. The service fees for apps &quot;primarily offering video, audio or books in which users pay to consume content&quot; will be between 10 and 15 percent <a href="https://play.google.com/console/about/mediaprogram/"><ins>if they meet certain conditions</ins></a> as part of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-android-play-media-experience-program-205036524.html"><ins>Play Media Experience Program</ins></a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Earlier this year, Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-play-store-fee-reduction-july-1-172359771.html"><ins>reduced its Play Store fees</ins></a> from 30 percent to 15 percent for the first $1 million in annual income that an app generates. The company said that move would cut the fees that 99 percent of Android developers pay the company by half.</p><p>Apple has also slashed App Store fees in certain cases over the last two years. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-small-business-program-15-percent-112259064.html"><ins>Apps that make under $1 million in annual revenue</ins></a>, news organizations <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-news-partner-program-162921762.html"><ins>who use Apple News</ins></a> and some streaming video services give Apple 15 percent of payments rather than the standard 30 percent. However, as <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/21/google-slashes-service-fees-in-app-store-after-similar-move-by-apple.html?utm_term=Autofeed&amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;utm_content=Main&amp;utm_source=Twitter#Echobox=1634832766"><em><ins>CNBC</ins></em></a> notes, Apple still takes a 30 percent slice of subscriptions for the first year before lowering its cut to 15 percent, so Google&#39;s making its move before Apple this time around.</p><p>Google and Apple have been facing more intense antitrust scrutiny over their app stores in recent times. Dozens of state attorneys general <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/07/07/36-states-dc-sue-google-for-alleged-antitrust-violations-in-its-android-app-store-498622"><ins>filed suit</ins></a> against Google in July, in which they accused the company of maintaining a monopoly over Android app distribution.</p><p>Both companies are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-google-play-lawsuit-035741548.html"><ins>tangled up</ins></a> in litigation with Epic Games as well. Apple largely won its case against Epic, though it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-files-appeal-app-store-injunction-101556698.html"><ins>asked for a stay</ins></a> in the sole ruling in Epic&#39;s favor: a requirement to let App Store developers direct users to alternate forms <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-epic-games-lawsuit-ruling-app-store-153113436.html"><ins>of making payments</ins></a>. Google, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-countersues-epic-for-sidestepping-fees-on-in-game-purchases-084602622.html"><ins>countersued Epic this month</ins></a> for bypassing fees on in-app purchases and allegedly violating the Play Store developer agreement.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-play-store-fees-subscriptions-e-books-music-streaming-apps-170908763.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ee33e07e-ff60-45ac-a496-d27e37de8053</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:09:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634836150</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T17:09:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/577a6040-3290-11ec-b9ff-d9fb367b7911" width="3888" height="2592" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/577a6040-3290-11ec-b9ff-d9fb367b7911" width="3888" height="2592" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[UKRAINE - 2021/10/06: In this photo illustration a Google Play Store logo is seen on a smartphone. (Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration a Google Play Store logo is seen...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google is redesigning its smart home Developer Center to support Matter device makers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-io-2021-supercut-210712143.html"><ins>I/O 2021</ins></a>, Google reiterated its commitment to Matter with a handful of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-smart-home-io-2021-matter-nest-android-000026115.html"><ins>smart home-related Nest and Android updates</ins></a>. If you need a refresher, Matter was known as Project CHIP, or Connected Home over IP, before a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chip-rebrand-matter-221410229.html"><ins>rebranding this past May</ins></a>. It’s a pact between some of the biggest companies in tech, including Google, Amazon and Apple, that aims to bring standardization to the fragmented smart home space. When it launches in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/matter-smart-home-standard-delayed-164447784.html"><ins>first half of 2022</ins></a>, it will support a variety of voice assistants and networking protocols, including Alexa, Google Assistant, Siri as well as WiFi, Thread and Bluetooth LE.</p><p>At its simplest, the promise of Matter is that you’ll be able to buy a new device and it will simply work with your existing smart home setup. To support that vision, Google is introducing new tools to help developers build and integrate Matter devices into its wider smart home ecosystem. It starts with a new but familiar name for the company’s smart home devices and developer platform: Google Home. “By bringing our platform and tools under the same roof, it gives us a simpler way to show you why and how integrating your devices with Google Home makes them more accessible and helpful across the Google ecosystem,” the company said.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As part of the rebranding, will launch a redesigned Developer Center early next year. It says the dashboard will include everything developers need to build devices and applications that work with the wider Google Home ecosystem. It will support Matter at launch and Google will release two software development kits. The first of those is a Google Home Device SDK. The company says it will be one of the fastest ways to create Matter devices. Google also plans to update Nest and Android devices to support the protocol, a move it says will enable the seamless setup of Matter devices on those platforms. Once it rolls out the update, Google claims the process of adding a new smart home will be as easy as connecting a new set of headphones. One of the other ways the company hopes to support developers is by allowing them to create their own suggested routines.</p><p>For Google, the motive for doing all of this is straightforward. The easier it can make it for third-party developers to integrate their devices and applications with Google Home, the better experience consumers will find. In turn, they’ll be more likely to invest in the company’s ecosystem.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-home-matter-developer-center-170049360.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">300a2bf6-ddac-49ef-92fe-ca60b3c4bb7a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634833932</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T16:32:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f7484de0-fd1a-11eb-8eb4-4d8ac557fa35" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f7484de0-fd1a-11eb-8eb4-4d8ac557fa35" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Connectivity Standards Alliance]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Matter smart home devices]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Matter smart home devices]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google starts licensing Stadia tech to other companies]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-game-studios-shut-down-montreal-los-angeles-201811811.html"><ins>shut down</ins></a> its internal <a href="http://engadget.com/tag/stadia"><ins>Stadia</ins></a> game development studios earlier this year, Stadia general manager Phil Harrison said the company planned to &quot;work with partners seeking a gaming solution all built on Stadia’s advanced technical infrastructure and platform tools.&quot; We&#39;re starting to see that strategy in action, as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google/"><ins>Google</ins></a> is now licensing Stadia tech to other companies.</p><p>As first reported by <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/10/20/batman-arkham-knight-white-label-stadia-att/"><em><ins>9to5 Google</ins></em></a> and confirmed by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/google-stadia-white-label-arkham-knight-free"><em><ins>IGN</ins></em></a>, AT&amp;T is using the tech to offer wireless subscribers the chance to stream<em>&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-09-23-batman-arkham-knight-never-feels-too-big-to-play.html"><em><ins>Batman: Arkham Knight</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>(which isn&#39;t available on Stadia proper) for free. Customers can play the game for a limited time at up to 1080p through Google Chrome or Microsoft Edge.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;This is being powered by the Stadia technology,&quot; an AT&amp;T spokesperson told <em>IGN</em>. &quot;For this demo AT&amp;T created a front end experience to enable gamers to play <em>Batman: Arkham Knight</em> directly from their own website and the game is playable on virtually any computer or laptop.&quot;</p><p>Oddly enough, subscribers can&#39;t take advantage of this offer on a smartphone, despite it seeming like a solid opportunity for AT&amp;T to show off its network capabilities. AT&amp;T even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/att-free-stadia-pro-5g-internet-subscribers-130032328.html"><ins>offered six months of Stadia Pro access</ins></a> to 5G and fiber internet customers this year.</p><p>Harrison said in February that offering game streaming tech to other companies (without Stadia branding in this case) was &quot;the best path to building Stadia into a long-term, sustainable business that helps grow the industry.&quot; Although Google <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-studios-closure-173055505.html"><ins>isn&#39;t making its own games</ins></a> for Stadia anymore, it has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-100-games-stadia-061631000.html">continued</a> to add <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fifa-22-release-date-163029621.html"><ins>third-party games</ins></a> to the store.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-tech-licensing-att-batman-arkham-knight-160913912.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e711660a-a3f2-4382-9c90-57014517fb2a</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634832556</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T16:09:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7bf96b40-3287-11ec-bbcf-d75269c69be3" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7bf96b40-3287-11ec-bbcf-d75269c69be3" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rocksteady Studios/Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Batman: Arkham Knight]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Batman: Arkham Knight]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seagate now offers a 2TB expansion card for your Xbox Series X/S]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You finally have a way to upgrade the high-speed storage in your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-x-review-microsoft-140045437.html">Xbox Series X</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-s-review-140027758.html">S</a> with more than <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xbox-series-game-drive-1tb-220-053427485.html">1TB of extra space</a>. Seagate has <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/10/21/new-seagate-storage-expansion-cards/">introduced</a> a 2TB Storage Expansion Card that, for the Series X, effectively triples the capacity for next-gen games. It will cost $400 when it arrives in early December — nearly as much as the console itself — but might be worthwhile if you bristle at the thought of deleting games to make space.</p><p>There&#39;s also an option for those who need just a slight bump. Seagate is launching a 512GB card in mid-November, with pre-orders open now <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/2055067/565706/9383?subId1=7&amp;subId2=productpost2021&amp;subId3=Preorder-Xbox-Seagate-SSD&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2Fseort%2F678305132">for $130</a>. That&#39;s still not a trivial expense, but it could be compelling if you either have an Xbox Series S (and want to keep costs down) or just want a little more breathing room on a Series X.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The high prices are, for now, difficult to avoid. As <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-ps5-ssd-expansion-upgrade-150052315.html">with the PlayStation 5</a>, the Xbox Series X/S requires external storage as fast as the built-in SSD if you&#39;re going to run the latest games. That leaves vendors like Seagate little choice but to use cutting-edge NVMe drives. It won&#39;t be surprising if prices drop as the costs of the technology come down, but that might not happen for a while yet.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/seagateo-2tb-storage-expansion-card-xbox-series-x-s-152738919.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7e660e8c-2b6a-4b9c-aab5-885da485de4c</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634830061</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T15:27:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/68acd220-327d-11ec-bfe3-34b7bbc0dbc1" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/68acd220-327d-11ec-bfe3-34b7bbc0dbc1" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Seagate/Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Seagate 512GB 1TB and 2TB Storage Expansion Card options for Xbox Series X and S]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Seagate 512GB 1TB and 2TB Storage Expansion Card options for Xbox Series X and S]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft and AMD will give away a 'Halo Infinite' Radeon RX 6900 XT GPU]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Beyond a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-xbox-series-x-console-elite-series-2-controller-190258414.html"><ins>special-edition Xbox Series X and controller</ins></a>, there&#39;s more <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/halo%20infinite/"><em><ins>Halo Infinite</ins></em></a>-themed hardware on the way, this time for PC players. Not only have Microsoft and AMD teamed up to add ray-tracing to the game sometime after launch, they created a limited-edition <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amd-radeon-6800xt-rdna2-gpu-162246249.html"><ins>Radeon RX 6900 XT</ins></a><em>Halo Infinite </em>graphics card.</p><div id="7483dfda17f14227ba28b5abdb08f06f"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_J4QZEUPAug?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The GPU’s design is based on Master Chief&#39;s Mjolnir armor, and it features a reflective, iridium gold border around a fan, a blue light that mimics the Cortana AI module on the character&#39;s helmet and the 117 Spartan call sign. Microsoft <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/10/21/halo-infinite-the-great-journey-on-pc/">notes that</a> the graphics card uses the same <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-24-xbox-series-x-gpu-specs.html">RDNA 2 architecture</a> as the Xbox Series X/S consoles.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Here&#39;s the rub: you won&#39;t be able to buy the GPU. Microsoft, AMD, developer 343 Industries and some of their partners will be giving away the graphics card in the coming weeks. If you&#39;re interested, it&#39;s worth keeping an eye on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqbmNmZThtbTBCWmhVdVBfOTdzTE5XOTUtNExtd3xBQ3Jtc0ttOTFROHM5SUZQbzZ2akM4bFNYaDEzcUpjWENXNG4wTUV3X0l6dXFuOWl5VFRNYUIwd1VXak1JX2FWZjQ0LVdka2tONTg3OVNoM2tJczVzZ2pCNTBJNzUyVFdoTHhKc05UN1l5Ymd6LW40MVRDRGs2dw&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2FHalo"><ins>Halo</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqazduLVMzY0hEZy1pcmp6M19HMXN3S1BJZWtLQXxBQ3Jtc0ttQmJQZWxuYS1POFFiWmYzODhkbUJFVWVzR0RMOWxtMHJiRFl1UG1NOVJLTFlkVEZlZ1lTaXFnaHFzYzRsYzFGZTUwd0hoX0s3cHdUSUNvdXJWbUUxdU9jQ3lqMHFDYVRiQWg1NTl2dkRabDZNRjliNA&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2FRadeon"><ins>AMD Radeon</ins></a> Twitter accounts for more details.</p><p>AMD is 343 Industries&#39; exclusive PC partner for <em>Halo Infinite</em>. They’ve been working together for the last couple of years to optimize the game for AMD’s GPUs and Ryzen processors. For one thing, there’s support for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-06-amd-freesync-premium-pro-ces-2020.html"><ins>AMD FreeSync Premium Pro</ins></a>, which reduces screen tearing and boosts HDR visuals on compatible monitors.&nbsp;</p><div id="fe2f18ffd6454d329ec19ce16b412fa6"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fax-YPAvuq0?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Elsewhere, Microsoft released a video showcasing what the <em>Halo Infinite</em> experience will look like on PC. It’s the first time the company is bringing a Halo game to consoles and PC on the same day. From the outset, there will be support for ultrawide displays and old-school LAN setups, as well as framerate customization and triple keybinds. Microsoft is also promising “deep integration” with Discord and in-game events that sync with lighting on Razer Chroma RGB devices. There are some <em>Halo Infinite</em><a href="https://www.razer.com/campaigns/halo-infinite"><ins>Razer peripherals too</ins></a>.</p><p><em>Halo Infinite </em>will hit Xbox consoles and PC <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-december-8th-launch-date-134031534.html"><ins>on December 8th</ins></a>. As with ray-tracing, the campaign co-op and Forge modes <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-forge-release-date-343-industries-190153091.html"><ins>won&#39;t be available at launch</ins></a>. 343 Industries will add those features later.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-amd-halo-infinite-radeon-rx-6900-xt-gpu-151505531.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f5d70790-3398-4254-8e60-9af8ffacfbdf</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:15:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634828836</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T15:07:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f669f510-327e-11ec-8eff-fdd06405a306" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f669f510-327e-11ec-8eff-fdd06405a306" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft/AMD]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Radeon RX 6900 XT Halo Infinite Limited Edition GPU]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Radeon RX 6900 XT Halo Infinite Limited Edition GPU]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[We can make the steel of tomorrow without the fossil fuels of yesteryear]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The modern world has grown around steel bones — everything from tools and home appliances to skyscrapers and airplanes use the versatile material in their construction. But the process of making steel is a significant contributor to global warming and climate change. In 2018, <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/metals-and-mining/our-insights/decarbonization-challenge-for-steel">reportedly every ton of steel produced</a> generated 1.85 tons of carbon dioxide, accounting for about 7 percent of global CO2 emissions that year. This poses not just environmental challenges for our ever increasing world, it could also impact steel producers’ bottom line, which is why the industry is developing a “fossil-free” means of making the alloy, one that relies on renewable-sourced hydrogen rather than carbon coke.</p><p>Steel is an alloy composed of iron, which in its pure form is relatively soft, with a small amount of introduced carbon, usually about 2 percent of its total weight. This improves the material’s strength and reduces its propensity for fracturing. <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com.au/how-is-steel-made-blast-furnace-2017-11">The process starts by combining iron ore</a>, before coking coal and limestone (which remove impurities) in a <a href="https://www.britannica.com/technology/blast-furnace">blast furnace</a> to create pig iron.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>That molten pig iron is then poured into a<a href="https://www.britannica.com/technology/basic-oxygen-furnace"> furnace</a> and high pressure air is introduced via a water-cooled lance. The oxygen chemically reacts with the molten iron to purge impurities — as well as produce significant amounts of carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide. The oxygen also forces impurities like silicates and phosphates present in the pig iron to react with limestone flux, trapping them as waste slag. Today, <a href="http://v/">per the World Steel Association</a>, some 1,864 million metric tons of crude steel are produced annually with China producing a vast majority of it.</p><p>While the WSA points out that “<a href="https://www.worldsteel.org/en/dam/jcr:c4532192-07eb-43ba-955c-cec8aead6763/Climate+Change+Position+Paper+FINAL+WEB.pdf">in the last 50 years</a>, the steel industry has reduced its energy consumption per tonne of steel produced by 60 percent” and notes that steel is infinitely reusable, and that “new” steel typically contain 30percent recycled steel on average the traditional methods of iron and steel production are becoming untenable — at least if we want to mitigate its impacts on climate change. What’s more, the International Energy Agency <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/iron-and-steel-technology-roadmap">estimates that global steel production</a> will grow by a third by 2050, which will only compound the industry’s environmental impacts. That’s where fossil-free steel comes in.</p><p>Take HYBRIT (Hydrogen Breakthrough Ironmaking Technology), for example. This process has been developed as a joint venture between three Swedish companies: SSAB, which makes steel, energy company Vattenfall, and LKAB, which mines iron ore. Rather than using coking coal and a blast furnace to convert raw iron ore into metallic iron, the HYBRIT method uses hydrogen generated from renewable energy sources and a technique known as direct reduction, which lowers the amount of oxygen contained within the ore without heating it above the metal’s melting point, to create <a href="https://www.metallics.org/dri.html">sponge iron</a>.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/f2d16740-31c9-11ec-bfff-6b4a44bb5ac5" alt="Blast Furnaces vs HYBRIT" data-uuid="d6a96ff4-5068-3a7e-a810-82fac00c650b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">HYBRIT</div></figure><p>Like pig iron, sponge iron is an intermediary material in the steelmaking process (it’ll get shipped off to SSAB to be turned into steel slabs), but in HYBRIT’s case, its production results in the creation of water vapor rather than carbon dioxide.</p><p>“The first fossil-free steel in the world is not only a breakthrough for SSAB, it represents proof that it’s possible to make the transition and significantly reduce the global carbon footprint of the steel industry,” Martin Lindqvist, CEO of SSAB, told reporters in August. “We hope that this will inspire others to also want to speed up the green transition.”</p><p>The HYBRIT coalition opened a pilot direct reduction plant in Luleå, Sweden last year and has announced plans to <a href="https://www.hybritdevelopment.se/en/a-fossil-free-future/">increase production to an industrial scale by 2026</a>. The team claims that eliminating fossil fuels from the steelmaking industry in Sweden could drop the country’s total CO2 emissions <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidrvetter/2021/08/19/how-sweden-delivered-the-worlds-first-fossil-fuel-free-steel/?sh=4b9f51576b55">by at least 10 percent</a>. However, they are not the only group looking into fossil-free steel production. The H2 Green Steel company <a href="https://www.h2greensteel.com/about-us">has announced its intent</a> to open a large-scale plant in northern Sweden by 2024 and expects to produce 5 million tonnes of the material annually by 2030.</p><p>In June, <a href="https://www.media.volvocars.com/global/en-gb/media/pressreleases/282789/volvo-cars-is-first-car-maker-to-explore-fossil-free-steel-with-ssab">Volvo announced</a> that it would be partnering with SSAB to develop fossil-free steel for use in its products — both passenger cars and industrial machines. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/volvo-first-vehicle-fossil-free-steel-055542393.html">Last week</a>, Volvo unveiled the first vehicle to be made with fossil-free steel, an <a href="https://www.ssab.com/news/2021/10/ssabs-fossilfree-steel-featured-in-volvo-groups-vehicle">8-plus ton load carrier</a> designed to operate within mines. Not only is the load carrier powered by a fully electric drivetrain, it can autonomously navigate across a worksite as well. Granted only about 3 of the vehicle’s 8 tons were made from fossil-free steel (the drivetrain’s steel components, for example, were made through traditional smelting means), this marks an important first step towards a carbon-neutral transportation future.</p><p>“When we have been talking about ‘fossil free’ in the transport sector, we have been focusing a lot on emissions from the vehicles in use. But it&#39;s clear to us and to everyone else that we also need to address the carbon footprint from the production of our vehicles,” Volvo Group’s Chief Technology Officer Lars Stenqvist told <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidrvetter/2021/10/13/this-is-the-worlds-first-fossil-free-steel-vehicle-autonomous-electric-and-a-volvo/?sh=3a3d97f97a68"><em>Forbes</em></a>. “That&#39;s why it&#39;s so important now to team up with everyone in the value chain and collaborate in order to drive out all the fossil fuel also used in the production of components, parts and also running our production facilities.”</p><p>Volvo expects the autonomous load carriers to enter real-world operation by next year, though the company concedes that its ability to ramp up production of fossil-free vehicles will depend largely on SSAB’s ability to deliver sufficient quantities of the material.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/we-can-make-the-steel-of-tomorrow-without-the-fossil-fuels-of-yesteryear-150050946.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">af439040-1e03-42b9-9f45-cf72e5a8cd67</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634829035</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T15:10:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Basic Materials Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Commodity Markets]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6605b80-3280-11ec-bbb9-26feb1ee7632" width="5000" height="3155" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e6605b80-3280-11ec-bbb9-26feb1ee7632" width="5000" height="3155" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SAFIN HAMED via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Iraqi steelworkers and a forge.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[1229191270 Iraqi steelworkers / forge]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Polestar gives owners two years of free fast charging from Electrify America]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You won&#39;t have to pay for quick <a href="https://www.engadget.com/for-polestar-the-twos-are-anything-but-terrible-130059155.html">Polestar 2</a> charges — at least, not for a while.  The automaker has <a href="https://media.electrifyamerica.com/en-us/releases/159">struck a deal</a> that will give Polestar 2 drivers two years of free fast charging at Electrify America stations. You&#39;ll be limited to 30-minute sessions, but that won&#39;t matter so much when a 150kW charger can give you a healthy top-up (though likely not a full one) in that time frame.</p><p>The offer applies to both existing and future Polestar 2 owners. Electrify America is keen to highlight the potential advantages, including simpler payments and an easier time finding stations.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Polestar deal isn&#39;t as sweet as the three years Electrify America creator VW <a href="https://www.engadget.com/audi-e-tron-gt-free-fast-charging-142756581.html">gives its own brands</a>. It also doesn&#39;t address the coverage and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ford-charge-angels-repair-ev-stations-173442523.html">reliability issues</a> that EV charging networks sometimes face. Electrify America is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/electrify-america-boost-plan-ev-network-141651830.html">rapidly expanding</a> its network, but it might take years before the infrastructure is robust enough that you could assume a fast charger is reasonably close by. Still, this could make the Polestar 2 an easier choice if you were anxious about recharging away from home.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/polestar-2-free-fast-charging-electrify-america-143901973.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">23e43edd-40b9-41e4-b0bc-9cf3e15f8b9d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 14:39:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634826675</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T14:31:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1c5e3060-3275-11ec-9f9d-7aa2d2024782" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/1c5e3060-3275-11ec-9f9d-7aa2d2024782" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Electrify America]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Polestar 2 EV charging at an Electrify America station]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Polestar 2 EV charging at an Electrify America station]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to buy a monitor in 2021]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the COVID pandemic still upon us, a monitor is one of the most important computer buying decisions you can make. Luckily, there’s never been more choice, and we’ve seen vast improvements in color accuracy, size and resolution since our last update.</p><p>It’s great to have lots of choice, but it can also make your buying decision a challenge. For example, do you need HDR, and if so, how bright should your monitor be? How important is color accuracy, refresh rates and input lag? What size do you need? Should it be curved or straight?</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Luckily, we’ve done the research and can help you figure all that out depending on your specific needs and, most importantly, budget. Read on to see exactly what to look for in a monitor and which makes and models to choose.</p><iframe src="https://delivery.vidible.tv/htmlembed/pid=5706c5c8e4b03b51471aefba/564f3144ff690c0a7c285e51.html?vid=5ea668f1a2a07d2be27d22a8" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><h2>The basics</h2><h3>Screen size, resolution and display format</h3><p>In this day and age, screen size rules. Where 24-inch displays used to be more or less standard (and can still be useful for basic computing), 27-, 32-, 34- and even 42-inch displays have become popular for entertainment, content creation and even gaming these days.</p><p>Nearly every monitor used to be 16:9, but it’s now possible to find 16:10 and other more exotic display shapes. On the gaming and entertainment side, we’re also seeing very wide and curved monitors with aspect ratios like 21:9. If you do decide to buy an ultrawide display, however, keep in mind that a 30-inch 21:9 model is the same height as a 24-inch monitor, so you might end up with a smaller display than you expected. As a rule of thumb, add 25 percent to the size of a 21:9 monitor to get the size you need.</p><p>4K is nearly a must for content creators, and some folks are even going for 5K or all the way up to 8K. Keep in mind, though, that you’ll need a pretty powerful computer to drive all those pixels. And 4K should be paired with a screen size of 27 inches and up, or you won’t notice much difference between 1440p. At the same time, I wouldn’t get a model larger than 27 inches unless it’s 4K, as you’ll start to see pixelation if you’re working up close to the display.</p><p>One new category to consider is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-27-asus-240hz-portable-monitor-for-gamers-hands-on.html">portable monitors</a> designed to be carried and used with laptops. Those typically come in 1080p resolutions and sizes from 13-15 inches. They usually have a lightweight kickstand-type support that folds up to keep things compact.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><h3>HDR</h3><p>HDR is the buzzy monitor feature to have these days, but be careful before jumping in. Some monitors that claim HDR on the marketing materials don’t even conform to a base standard. To be sure that a display at least meets minimum HDR specs, you’ll want to choose one with a DisplayHDR rating with each tier representing maximum brightness in nits.</p><p>However, the lowest DisplayHDR 400 and 500 tiers may disappoint you with a lack of brightness, washed out blacks and mediocre color reproduction.If you can afford it, choose a model with DisplayHDR 600, 1000 or True Black 400, True Black 500 and True Black 600. The True Black settings are designed primarily for OLED models, with maximum black levels at .0005 nits.</p><p>Where televisions typically offer HDR10 and Dolby Vision or HDR10+, most PC monitors only support the HDR10 standard, other than a few (very expensive) models. That doesn’t matter much for content creation or gaming, but HDR streaming on Netflix, Amazon Prime Video and other services won’t look quite as punchy.&nbsp;</p><h3>Refresh rate</h3><p>Refresh rate is a key feature, particularly on gaming monitors. A bare minimum nowadays is 60Hz, and 80Hz refresh rates and up are much easier on the eyes. However, most 4K displays top out at 60Hz with some rare exceptions and the HDMI 2.0 spec only supports 4K at 60Hz, so you’d need at least DisplayPort 1.4 (4K at 120Hz) or HDMI 2.1. The latter is now available on a number of monitors, particularly gaming displays. However, it’s only supported on the latest NVIDIA RTX 3000- and AMD RX 6000-series GPUs and requires a very powerful PC.</p><h3>Inputs</h3><p>There are essentially three types of modern display inputs: Thunderbolt, DisplayPort and HDMI. Most monitors built for PCs come with the latter two, while a select few (typically built for Macs) will use Thunderbolt. To add to the confusion, USB-C ports may be Thunderbolt 3 and by extension, DisplayPort compatible, so you may need a USB-C to Thunderbolt or DisplayPort cable adapter depending on your display.</p><h3>Panel type</h3><p>The cheapest monitors are still TN (twisted nematic), which are strictly for gaming or office use. VA (vertical alignment) monitors are also relatively cheap, while offering good brightness and high contrast ratios. However, content creators will probably want an IPS (in-plane switching) LCD display that delivers better color accuracy, image quality and viewing angles.</p><p>If maximum brightness is important, a quantum dot LCD display is the way to go — those are typically found in larger displays.  OLED monitors are now available and offer the best blacks and color reproduction, but they lack the brightness of LED or quantum dot displays. Plus, they cost a lot.</p><p>The new panel on the block is MiniLED. It’s similar to quantum dot tech, but as the name suggests, it uses smaller LED diodes that are just 0.2mm in diameter. As such, manufacturers can pack in up to three times more LEDs with more local dimming zones, delivering deeper blacks and better contrast.&nbsp;</p><h3>Color bit depth</h3><p>Serious content content creators should consider a more costly 10-bit monitor that can display billions of colors. If budget is an issue, you can go for an 8-bit panel that can fake billions of colors via dithering (often spec’d as “8-bit + FRC”). For entertainment or business purposes, a regular 8-bit monitor that can display millions of colors will be fine.</p><h3>Color gamut</h3><p>The other aspect of color is the gamut. That expresses the range of colors that can be reproduced and not just the number of colors. Most good monitors these days can cover the sRGB and Rec.709 gamuts (designed for photos and video respectively). For more demanding work, though, you’ll want one that can reproduce more demanding modern gamuts like AdobeRGB, DCI-P3 and Rec.2020 gamuts, which encompass a wider range of colors. The latter two are often used for film projection and HDR, respectively.&nbsp;</p><h2>Engadget picks</h2><h2></h2><h2>Best monitor around $200</h2><h3>Acer KG241Q</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/55c5a3d0-326e-11ec-bf3b-372766298d5f" alt="Acer KG241Q monitor" data-uuid="5b587be7-7c4d-39d7-9033-be8fa41472ef"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Acer</div></figure><p>Whether you need a monitor for gaming, entertainment or work, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Acer&#x002019;s 24-inch KG241Q" href="https://fave.co/2XnUAXx">Acer’s 24-inch KG241Q</a> offers a lot of value. Resolution is limited to 1080p, but it delivers a 144Hz refresh rate and comes with AMD FreeSync support. Other features include a 1-millisecond lag time, 300 nits of brightness, HDMI and DisplayPort inputs and a tilting stand. The downsides are tricky access to the ports and a TN display that looks dim at an angle, but it’s a heck of a steal right now at $155.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/2XnUAXx" id="9df630df353d42d8ad64561ec2193d40" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 24-inch Acer KG241Q at B&amp;H Photo - $180</a><h2><br>Best monitors around $300</h2><h3>ASUS ProArt PA278QV</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/00e2eb00-3270-11ec-8f77-755b11cffa2d" alt="ASUS ProArt PA278QV" data-uuid="4577f475-cda5-3e07-8696-0063e499cbf4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">ASUS</div></figure><p>Moving your budget up by just $100 opens up a whole lot more options. A case in point is our pick for content creation chores, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:ASUS ProArt PA278QV" href="https://fave.co/3BYFQ06">ASUS ProArt PA278QV</a>. You get a larger 27-inch size, increased 2,560 x 1,440 resolution and a superior IPS panel. As with other ProArt models, the PA278QV is designed specifically for photo and video editing, with a 100 percent Rec.709 gamut, Calman verified color accuracy and ProArt presets and palettes for different kinds of work. It also offers DisplayPort and HDMI ports and tilt, swivel, pivot and height adjustments. That’s a lot of monitor for a current street price of $315.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3BYFQ06" id="92c10504ae564fb9b86de8df32713a32" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 27-inch ASUS ProArt PA278QV at B&amp;H - $319</a><h3>Dell S2522HG</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/128d0340-3270-11ec-95df-3c9ef41035fa" alt="Dell S2522HG" data-uuid="7cd374c7-ce0f-32fa-acae-0ec181cf106f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dell</div></figure><p>There are numerous decent gaming monitors around $300, but we’ve managed to narrow it down to one: <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Dell&#x002019;s S2522HG" href="https://amzn.to/3hBHVa6">Dell’s S2522HG</a>. For a monitor in this price range, you get a lot: a 24.5-inch IPS 1080p display with a 240Hz refresh rate, 400 nits of brightness, 1-millisecond response time and AMD Free-Sync and NVIDIA G-Sync compatibility. It comes with HDMI, DisplayPort and SuperSpeed USB 3.2 Gen1 inputs, along with a stand that allows  for height adjustment, tilt, swivel and pivot. You can pick one up now at Amazon for $320.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3hBHVa6" id="d29f8de961af45f49d7e8bb4151785c0" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 24-inch Dell S2522HG at Amazon - $320</a><h2><br>Best monitor around $400</h2><h3>LG 27UK500</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9a848780-3272-11ec-bfbe-cdec29ce30ee" alt="LG 27UK500" data-uuid="ea1ae171-2a3c-309f-8a35-1c48b74d0f50"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">LG</div></figure><p>LG’s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:27UK500" href="https://fave.co/3hzFkgU">27UK500</a> is a nice all around monitor that can cover gaming, entertainment and some content creation. The 27-inch 4K IPS display covers 98 percent of the sRGB gamut and supports HDR10 with 10-bit color, though it only outputs 300 nits of brightness so it isn’t DisplayHDR certified. If you like 4K gaming, it can handle that decently thanks to AMD FreeSync support, a 60 Hz refresh rate and a 5-millisecond response time. The downsides are a tilt only stand, but it’s very well priced at just $347.&nbsp;</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3hzFkgU" id="fc4ac202c39d4f4ab900d6b74eed131e" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 27-inch LG 27UK500 at B&amp;H - $347</a><h2><br>Best monitors around $500</h2><h3>BenQ PD2700U</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/b6381060-3276-11ec-b7f6-3d1a44be4f6d" alt="BenQ PD2700U" data-uuid="91db7ed8-501c-315a-92a1-b3167a81669c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">BenQ</div></figure><p>For creatives, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:BenQ PD2700U" href="https://fave.co/3lYaQrA">BenQ PD2700U</a> pushes all the right buttons. The 27-inch 4K IPS panel delivers 10-bit HDR color and covers 100 percent of the sRGB gamut with Calman verified Delta E color accuracy less than 3. It’s also a fine choice for entertainment and gaming with 350 nits of brightness, a 1300:1 contrast ratio, viewing angle of 178 degrees and a 5-millisecond response time. It has tilt, swivel, pivot and height adjustment and most of the ports you need, including HDMI 2.0 and DisplayPort 1.4. You can pick one up now at B&amp;H for $500.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3lYaQrA" id="136d764c14094450a10c7d1a2fb5c626" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 27-inch BenQ PD2700U at B&amp;H Photo - $500</a><h3>Acer Nitro XV252Q</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/eaa93450-3276-11ec-b7e9-d8b2ad939974" alt="Acer Nitro XV252Q" data-uuid="f75912fd-a239-3bfc-9707-26b3b5910e3f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Acer</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Acer&#x002019;s Nitro XV252Q" href="https://amzn.to/2YRSi31">Acer’s Nitro XV252Q</a> is the only gaming monitor under $500 that supports 360 Hz refresh rates, but there’s more to it than just that. The 24.5-inch HD display outputs 400 nits of brightness, so it’s DisplayHDR 400 certified for HDR games and movies. It also comes with AMD FreeSync compatibility, a 99 percent sRGB color gamut and DisplayPort 1.4 and HDMI 2.0 connections. You can tilt, swivel, pivot and adjust the height by up to 4.7 inches, and it looks pretty snazzy, with very slim side and top bezels.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/2YRSi31" id="b468f29a53104b448d639c68956662b4" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 25-inch Acer Nitro XV252Q at Amazon - $500</a><h2><strong><br></strong>Best monitors under $700</h2><h3>Dell UltraSharp 27 U2720Q</h3><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/ee742b30-8949-11ea-9cef-2873a6117a50" alt="Dell UltraSharp 27 U2720Q" data-uuid=""><figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dell</div></figcaption></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:Dell&#x002019;s 27-inch, 4K U2720Q" href="https://bit.ly/3hzLHkb">Dell’s 27-inch, 4K U2720Q</a> IPS monitor offers 4K HDR performance for a decent price. It conforms to the DisplayHDR 400 spec while offering 10-bits of color and 99 percent sRGB coverage, with a Delta E color accuracy of less than two out of the box. So this is a good monitor for HDR movies and doing some graphics chores, particularly HDR video work — all for under $700.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://bit.ly/3hzLHkb" id="ec0098f3113748e2a63ade80b0eda001" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Dell;elmt:viglink;pdid:">Buy 27-inch UltraSharp U2720Q at Dell - $580</a><h3>Acer Predator XB273K</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e9698fc0-3273-11ec-9deb-c5d8d1fd012a" alt="Acer Predator XB273K" data-uuid="49263075-941b-3e63-9ea3-53a65813f149"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Acer</div></figure><p>Though it’s marketed as a gaming monitor thanks to the 120Hz refresh rate, 1-millisecond response time and G-Sync support, Acer’s 4K quantum dot <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Predator XB273K" href="https://amzn.to/3kfPgOh">Predator XB273K</a> is really a jack of all trades. It’s also DisplayHDR 400 compatible, covers 90 percent of the challenging DCI-P3 color gamut and offers a Delta&lt;1 color accuracy. You also get tilt and height adjustments, HDMI 2.0 and DisplayPort 1.4 ports and pivot and height adjustment.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3kfPgOh" id="0070c06072ad429b86b223f9f1cdb4c2" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 27-inch Acer Predator XB273K at Amazon - $621</a><h2><br>Best monitor for Mac users</h2><h3>LG Ultrafine 4K and 5K</h3><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/10ff8d70-894a-11ea-a456-9e90d13f073c" alt="LG Ultrafine 5K" data-uuid=""><figcaption><div class="photo-credit">LG</div></figcaption></figure><p>Apple’s $5,000 Pro Display XDR is much too rich for most of us, so the next most logical option is LG’s <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HMUB2/lg-ultrafine-5k-display">$1,300 Ultrafine</a> 5K display, also sold on Apple’s Store. With a 27-inch 5K panel, you not only get very high resolution but also 500 nits of brightness (albeit, without HDR capability). It’s color-accurate out of the box, making it great for video- and photo-editing work on a Mac or MacBook. Finally, it supports Thunderbolt 3 with daisy chaining and power delivery, all of which is very useful for Mac users.</p><p>If that model is too much, you can also consider LG’s 24-inch Ultrafine 4K. For nearly half the price ($700), it offers many of the same features (including the powered and daisy-chained Thunderbolt ports, color accuracy and more) in a smaller size and with just a bit less resolution.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HMUB2/lg-ultrafine-5k-display" id="2ce7f369846244a98ef4846be48a18f3" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Apple;elmt:other;pdid:">Buy LG Ultrafine 5K at Apple - $1,300</a><a class="athena-button" href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HMUA2VC/A/lg-ultrafine-4k-display" id="d0e9b065a72e4177b8688e7fd203c81f" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Apple;elmt:other;pdid:">Buy LG Ultrafine 4K at Apple - $700</a><h2>Best ultrawide monitor</h2><h3>MSI Optix MPG341CQR</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7b89b420-3274-11ec-bbfd-4fa8adba2597" alt="MSI Optix MPG341CQR" data-uuid="e9b6b8e0-14c5-3df8-a746-3f3e0117dd83"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">MSI</div></figure><p>Ultrawide 21:9 monitors are a great option for some types of content creation, flight sims and financial work. The best model this year (with perhaps the worst name) is <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:MSI&#x002019;s Optix MPG341CQR" href="https://amzn.to/3AkCZxU">MSI’s Optix MPG341CQR</a>. With an 1800R curve and 3,440 x 1,440 resolution it’s ideal for gaming, with the 120Hz refresh rate, 1-millisecond response time and HDR 400 also helping in that regard. It also offers a frameless design, tilt, swivel and height adjustment and HDMI 2.0/DisplayPort 1.4 ports. It also has an LED strip that provides helpful cues for in-game status like remaining health or ammo, too.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3AkCZxU" id="d7de488f4ba3494bbe0115f6ae7793f8" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 43-inch MSI Optix MPG341CQR at Amazon - $645</a><h2>Best portable monitor</h2><h3>ViewSonic VG1655</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/0be25ef0-3275-11ec-abdf-7a4079db0815" alt="ViewSonic VG1655" data-uuid="ceb74864-06c0-33f3-a2f3-0da8d966ed84"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">ViewSonic</div></figure><p>To best complement your laptop, a portable monitor should be small, lightweight and not too expensive. The model that best meets all those requirements is <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:ViewSonic&#x002019;s VG1655" href="https://amzn.to/3ElR94b">ViewSonic’s VG1655</a>. At 15.6 inches and weighing under 2 pounds, the 1080p 60 Hz IPS display can be toted around fairly easily but still provide crisp, clear visuals. It’s also reasonably bright at 250 nits, comes in standard and touch version, packs dual speakers and has a built-in stand with a cover.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3ElR94b" id="f240eb83fff54b5aa728be36d86a266d" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy 15-inch ViewSonic VG1655 at Amazon - $250</a><h2>Best HDMI 2.1 monitor</h2><h3>Acer Nitro XV282K</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/63f02e10-3275-11ec-bdc7-c4ba588857e5" alt="Acer Nitro XV282K" data-uuid="e194f126-24c4-3a77-93cf-a17d597b43fc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Acer</div></figure><p>If you’re gaming on the bleeding edge at 4K and 120Hz, you’ll first need either a fast PC or PS5/Xbox Series X console. If you’ve got that and would prefer to use a monitor rather than a TV, your best bet will soon be Acer&#39;s Nitro XV282K display. Along with 4K resolution at up to 144Hz, it offers a 1-millisecond refresh rate, 10-bit color and 400 nits (DisplayHDR 400 compatible) of brightness. It comes, of course, with an HDMI 2.1 input, along with DisplayPort 1.4. It’s not yet available, but should <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:arrive soon for $900" href="https://fave.co/3tNvhtn">arrive soon for $900</a>.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3tNvhtn" id="a964386c08fc4c03959c9b85202a6430" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:B&amp;H Photo;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Pre-order 28-inch Acer Nitro XV282K at B&amp;H - $899</a><h2>Best luxury monitor</h2><h3>ASUS ProArt PA32UCG-K</h3><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/cf98e8f0-3275-11ec-bda7-a23bd2f3fc61" alt="ASUS ProArt PA32UCG-K" data-uuid="aab97cc3-70aa-3e3c-804a-8fdd0d90ea02"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">ASUS</div></figure><p>ASUS still holds the prize for best luxury monitor, but it discontinued the previous mini-LED $4,000 ProArt PA32UCX monitor and replaced it with the $5,000 <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:PA32UCG-K display" href="https://fave.co/3CwT3NN">PA32UCG-K display</a>. It uses the same mini-LED tech, but ups the ante with 1,600 nits of brightness, an HDMI 2.1 port, 4K 120Hz resolution, 10-bit, 98 percent DCI-P3 coverage and an impressive 85 percent Rec.2020 coverage. Oh, and it’s one of the few monitors out there that supports Dolby Vision, along with HDR10 and HLG.</p><p>You’re probably doing it wrong if you’re using a $5K monitor for gaming. However, it does support AMD FreeSync (good for gaming creation) and has a 5-millisecond response time, very respectable for a display essentially designed for professional colorists. And to that end, color accuracy is calibrated to Delta E &lt; 1 and it’s a true 10-bit panel delivering billions of colors.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3CwT3NN" id="b7135d2fd0894c62adf3e3636442b034" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:ASUS;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy 32-inch ASUS ProArt PA32UCG-K at B&amp;H - $4,999</a><h2>Best 8K display</h2><h3>Dell UltraSharp 32 UP3218K</h3><figure><img src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/5bacadd0-894a-11ea-ab9d-0ad2f61c95bc" alt="Dell UltraSharp 32 UP3218K" data-uuid=""><figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Dell</div></figcaption></figure><p>Faster than we think, 8K video will be upon us, so you might be pondering an 8K monitor to stay ahead of the curve. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:Dell&#x002019;s UP3218K" href="https://bit.ly/3jqk0v8">Dell’s UP3218K</a> is part of its UltraSharp lineup for creators, so it not only delivers 8K (7,680 x 4,320) 60p resolution but other nice pro features, too.</p><p>The 10-bit native IPS panel delivers 400 nits of brightness, though the UP3218K isn’t an HDR monitor. It also delivers 1.07 billion colors and covers 98 percent of the DCI-P3 color gamut, with a Delta E of less than two out of the box. It’s also one of the few monitors that flips around 90 degrees, making it good for portrait photo work.</p><p>This monitor isn’t cheap either at $3,500 (8K monitors are still very rare), but <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Dell&#x002019;s UP3216Q 4K monitor" href="https://fave.co/3aVgqop">Dell’s UP3216Q 4K monitor</a> has most of the features for less than half the price. It’s not quite as bright at 350 nits and covers just 87 percent of the DCI-P3 gamut, but it offers 1.07 billion colors and is just as precise for color correction out of the box.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://bit.ly/3jqk0v8" id="27d3699e73704fa29b04c6e65ac0c5c1" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Dell;elmt:viglink;pdid:">Buy 32-inch UltraSharp UP3218K at Dell - $3,755</a><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/how-to-buy-a-monitor-143000069.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">007f96e7-0ec9-3a79-a6ae-d5271643cdbd</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 14:30:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634828311</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T14:58:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[news]]></category><category><![CDATA[refreshrate]]></category><category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[HDR]]></category><category><![CDATA[4K]]></category><category><![CDATA[display]]></category><category><![CDATA[thebuyersguide]]></category><category><![CDATA[commerce]]></category><category><![CDATA[resolution]]></category><category><![CDATA[contentcreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[gear]]></category><category><![CDATA[monitors]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/36a4fb20-327f-11ec-b7ff-85e6e53cc6d7" width="1625" height="977" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/36a4fb20-327f-11ec-b7ff-85e6e53cc6d7" width="1625" height="977" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ASUS]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ASUS ProArt Display PA27UCX-K monitor in a video editing setup.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[ASUS ProArt Display PA27UCX-K]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony has finally <a href="https://pressroom.pixelshift.studio/sony-electronics-alpha-7-iv-goes-beyond-basic-with-33-megapixel-full-frame-image-sensor-and-outstanding-photo-and-video-operability">revealed</a> its mainstream $2,500 Alpha A7 IV full-frame mirrorless camera and it looks to have been worth the wait. Borrowing technology from the recent A1 and A7S III models, it offers large improvements over the A7 III <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-02-26-sony-a7-iii-mirrorless-camera.html">introduced</a> well over three years ago. Key features include an all-new 33-megapixel sensor, 4K 10-bit 60 fps video, new AI autofocus tricks and a lot more.&nbsp;</p><p>The A7 IV resembles the A7S III in terms of size and layout, but you can now select between still, video and S&amp;Q (slow and quick) options with a new dedicated dial below the mode dial. Each mode completely changes the settings and control layout of the camera to favor either photo- or video-centric controls. As with the A7S III, the video record button has been moved to a more practical spot on top for vloggers.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/c6f82be0-3278-11ec-bff7-ac7dee2e744f" style="height:1591;width:2000;" alt="Sony&#39;s A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video" data-uuid="1a676d77-53f2-314b-b430-d63ecf7964b5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>It comes with a 3.68-million dot electronic viewfinder (EVF) with a more comfortable 120 Hz refresh rate, up from the 2.36-million dot, 60Hz EVF on the A7 III. For videographers, the A7 IV offers a flip-out 1.03 million dot rear LCD display, making the camera far more usable for vlogging than the A7 III.&nbsp;</p><p>The 5-axis in-body stabilization delivers 5.5 stops of shake reduction, up slightly from before, but far below the 8 stops promised by Canon&#39;s like-priced EOS R6. However, it now offers an &quot;active mode&quot; for movies that helps smooth footsteps.&nbsp;</p><p>In terms of storage, the A7 IV offers two slots, with the top dual slot taking either SDXC UHS II (up to 300 MB/s speeds or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/pro-grade-undercuts-sony-with-its-new-c-fexpress-type-a-camera-memory-cards-082048079.html">CFexpress Type A</a> (up to 800 MB/s), and the bottom slot compatible with SDXC UHS II only. On the  A1 and A7S III, by comparison, both slots support both those formats. As for battery life, the A7 IV delivers 610 CIPA shots on a charge, compared to 700 on the A7 III.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/39da6b50-3279-11ec-bb7f-0c6f4a96ce4a" style="height:1325;width:2000;" alt="Sony&#39;s A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video" data-uuid="354b2963-b5ff-3328-a093-60bdee636636"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>The 33-megapixel backside illuminated (BSI) sensor provides a significant resolution boost over the A7 III&#39;s 24.1-megapixel sensor, while still offering good low-light sensitivity, Sony told Engadget. However, it doesn&#39;t offer the stacked chip-on-sensor technology of the A1 and A9/A9 II, so it lacks the sensor readout speeds of those models.&nbsp;</p><p>As such, the A7 IV is limited to the same 10 fps shootings speeds as the A7 III, both with the mechanical and electronic shutter — whereas the A1 can shoot at triple that speed. However, the A7 III was limited to around 90 RAW frames at a time, but the A7 IV can shoot an incredible 828 uncompressed RAW+JPEG images in a burst, provided you capture to a CFexpress Type A card.</p><p>Powered by the A1&#39;s BIONZ R processing engine, it offers the same 759 phase-detect AF points as the A1 with around 94 percent sensor coverage. It also comes with the same AI-powered image tracking that can process spatial information &quot;in real time at high speed,&quot; Sony said. That means more tenacious tracking, along with faster and more accurate eye AF for humans, animals and birds.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7a025e90-3279-11ec-bdb7-348b5f1f74b3" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Sony&#39;s A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video " data-uuid="7b47ed90-69a4-3a8e-a381-a20160170f30"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>Perhaps the biggest improvements with the A7 IV are on with video. Where the A7 III was limited to 4K/30p with 8 bits of color depth, the A7 IV can handle 4K at up to 60 fps with 10 bit, 4:22 All-I capture — putting it on par with Canon&#39;s EOS R6 and the Panasonic GH5 II. 4K 30fps is super-sampled using the entire 7K width of the sensor, while 4K/60p uses a 4.6K Super35 1.5X crop. That means there&#39;s no pixel binning, so video should be very sharp.&nbsp;</p><p>It supports a number of video file types, including XAVC S All-I at up to 600 Mbps for 4K/60 10-bit, 4:2:2 movies. All of the video modes, except one S&amp;Q setting that requires CFexpress Type A, can be captured to an SD UHS II card. However, unlike the A1 and A7S III, there&#39;s no support for 16-bit RAW video capture to an external recorder. RAW video isn&#39;t found on the EOS R6 either, but is available on Panasonic&#39;s $1,800<a href="https://www.engadget.com/panasonic-gh5s-firmware-prores-raw-140000967.html"> GH5s</a> and the $2,000 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nikons-latest-z-6-ii-firmware-unlocks-4-k-60-fps-recording-110552464.html">Nikon Z6 II</a>, via recorders from Atomos and Blackmagic Design.</p><div id="f7979042d93b446299bc509e368e5810"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zerSHqKWhYQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Video autofocus is improved with faster and more accurate tracking, and the A7 IV is Sony&#39;s first camera to support both human and animal/bird eye tracking for video. If the A7 IV&#39;s AF works nearly as well as the A7S III, it should be nearly on par with Canon&#39;s Dual Pixel AF.</p><p>What about overheating, the EOS R6&#39;s primary bugbear? With a heat-dissipating body structure, the A7 IV can record 4K 60p 10-bit 4:2:2 video continuously for more than an hour, Sony claims. The R6, meanwhile, is limited to around 40 minutes at 4K/30p before a cooling off period is required.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/7a8813e0-327a-11ec-8654-9b08d53bf242" style="height:1890;width:2000;" alt="Sony&#39;s A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video" data-uuid="9f8f4fe4-208c-35ef-b219-21ab8cc90137"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>With most camera lenses, pulling video focus from a foreground to background subject can cause an ugly change in framing. The A7 IV&#39;s Focus Breathing Compensation system essentially uses a digital zoom to compensate for that, making the transition smoother. However, since the system needs to track lens elements, it only supports Sony-branded glass — and only the rather expensive G and GM models, at that.&nbsp;</p><p>If you&#39;d rather focus manually, the A7 IV is debuting a new feature called Focus Map. It overlays colors onto a scene showing the parts within, behind and in front of the depth of field (DOF). That&#39;s supposed to help you pull focus quickly and in the right direction toward your subject. Related to that is the new &quot;AF Assist&quot; function borrowed from Sony&#39;s FX6 cinema camera that allows for manual focus, even during autofocus operation.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a5fd90e0-327a-11ec-bebf-ff683a4ee016" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Sony&#39;s A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video             " data-uuid="ed94d4c0-2af3-31eb-a670-114df9b0370e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>Lastly, Sony has introduced new live streaming and sharing features, though they&#39;re not quite up to the level we&#39;ve seen on other recent cameras. If you use Sony&#39;s Imaging Edge mobile app, it will now use Bluetooth to maintain a continuous connection, rather than disconnecting as before.&nbsp;</p><p>It also offers faster transfer speeds with 5GHz WiFi and superspeed USB-C 3.2 Gen2 (10Gbps). You can do video and audio streaming over USB-C at up to 1080p 60 or 4K 15p if resolution is a priority over smooth video. That allows for webcam or livestreaming via apps like OBS with digital audio and effects like soft skin. The camera can also record internally while you&#39;re live streaming, providing a backup. Unlike Panasonic&#39;s GH5 II however, you can&#39;t transmit via RTMP to Twitch, YouTube or other services without a phone or laptop.&nbsp;</p><p>The A7 IV is clearly a massive leap forward for Sony&#39;s &quot;basic&quot; full-frame mirrorless camera series, putting it on par or ahead of most rivals. The only deterrent is the $2,500 price tag ($2,699 with a 28-70mm f/3.5-5.6 OSS kit lens), which is $500 more than the A7 III cost at launch. I&#39;d wager, though, that it&#39;s going to be just as popular as the original, provided it delivers the promised performance — so stay tuned for our review. The A7 IV is set to arrive by the end of December 2021.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-a7-iv-camera-arrives-with-a-33-megapixel-sensor-and-4k-60p-video-141301936.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4857c28a-4adf-443b-9265-99a14a35cc7c</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 14:13:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634827095</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T14:40:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Cameras & Photography]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a8da35e0-3278-11ec-9fdf-0f49002706df" width="1852" height="1114" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/a8da35e0-3278-11ec-9fdf-0f49002706df" width="1852" height="1114" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony's A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony's A7 IV camera arrives with a 33-megapixel sensor and 4K 60p video]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Uncharted’ movie trailer plays Nathan Drake's greatest hits]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony is finally releasing an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/uncharted/"><em>Uncharted</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>movie after trying to make one for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2008-10-02-avi-arad-producing-uncharted-drakes-fortune-film.html">over a decade</a>. If you need more evidence that the film actually exists beyond a snap of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-movie-tom-holland-nathan-drake-first-look-155151891.html">Tom Holland in Nathan Drake&#39;s classic attire</a>, here&#39;s the first trailer.</p><p>Even though Holland plays <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-05-22-uncharted-prequel-tom-holland.html">a much younger version</a> of the character (which <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-13-mark-wahlberg-in-uncharted-movie.html">Mark Wahlberg&#39;s Sully</a> jokes about in the opening moments) than in the games, the enjoyable-enough trailer incudes some of the most memorable moments from Drake&#39;s globe-trotting adventures. There isn&#39;t a bit where he clambers up a train carriage that&#39;s dangling over a cliff, but there&#39;s the cargo plane set piece from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2011-10-24-uncharted-3-drakes-deception-review.html"><em>Uncharted 3</em></a> and a ship trapped inside a cave, just like in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-05-05-uncharted-4-photo-mode-screenshot-gallery.html"><em>Uncharted 4</em></a>. The clip includes some underground exploration too.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="d23e0be4ee064a2cb3e36b929a13d771"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eHp3MbsCbMg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>The film&#39;s set to arrive in theaters on February 18th, following several delays. Attempts to make an <em>Uncharted </em>movie stopped and started over the years, with directors including David O. Russell, Seth Gordon and Shawn Levy being attached at certain points before <em>Zombieland </em>and <em>Venom </em>helmer Ruben Fleischer saw the film through. The project had been in development for so long that, for a while, Wahlberg <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-11-24-uncharted-movie-to-star-mark-wahlberg.html">looked set to play Drake</a>, rather than the character&#39;s mentor.</p><p>Some viewers might be coming to the franchise with fresh eyes (maybe because they need more Tom Holland in their lives), and they might want to play the games to see what all the fuss is about. Sony Pictures included a handy reminder at the end of the trailer about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-4-and-uncharted-lost-legacy-are-coming-to-ps-5-and-pc-211007741.html">a remastered bundle</a> of <em>Uncharted 4</em> and <em>Uncharted: The Lost Legacy</em> that&#39;s coming to PlayStation 5 and PC in early 2022.</p><p>In case the trailer doesn&#39;t quite match up to what you might have expected, or Holland doesn&#39;t seem like the right person for the gig in your opinion, it&#39;s worth checking out this short fan film from a few years back in which Nathan Fillion plays the rogueish treasure hunter. It&#39;s a blast.</p><div id="4b34d04a3a054a8882153e0aa6bd483b"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v5CZQpqF_74?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-movie-trailer-tom-holland-nathan-drake-135811981.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c671f8fe-8369-436d-8246-596afe2a837e</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:58:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634832042</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T16:00:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e893b740-3275-11ec-a0ef-e9a33b8d5ffd" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/e893b740-3275-11ec-a0ef-e9a33b8d5ffd" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Clay Enos]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tom Holland (Nathan Drake) and Sophia Taylor Ali (Chloe Frazer) star in Columbia Pictures' Uncharted.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tom Holland and Sophia Taylor Ali in the Uncharted movie]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oversight Board slams Facebook’s lack of transparency in VIP moderation]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook&#39;s Oversight Board has issued a rebuke to the company in a <a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/215139350722703-oversight-board-demands-more-transparency-from-facebook/">new quarterly report</a>, claiming it was not &quot;fully forthcoming&quot; about its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-oversight-board-cross-check-183544254.html">XCheck program</a> for VIP users. The documents shows the limits of the board&#39;s power over Facebook, but also its ability to potentially apply public pressure.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;When Facebook referred <a href="https://www.oversightboard.com/decision/FB-691QAMHJ/">the case related to former US President Trump</a> to the Board, it did not mention the cross-check system,&quot; according to the report. &quot;Given that the referral included a specific policy question about account-level enforcement for political leaders, many of whom the Board believes were covered by cross-check, this omission is not acceptable.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Oversight Board, sometimes called Facebook&#39;s &quot;Supreme Court,&quot; started issuing important rulings earlier this year. One of its first <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-oversight-board-decision-trump-suspension-ban-130251901.html">major rulings</a> was that the ban of ex-President Donald Trump was &quot;appropriate,&quot; though it said an indefinite suspension was outside of Facebook&#39;s power.</p><blockquote><p>In the Board’s view, the team within Facebook tasked with providing information has not been fully forthcoming on cross-check. On some occasions, Facebook failed to provide relevant information to the Board, while in other instances, the information it did provide was incomplete.</p></blockquote><p>Last month, the board asked Facebook to explain its controversial rules for VIPs, saying that the information was key to its Trump decision. Facebook originally told the board that the XCheck program only applied to a &quot;small number of decisions,&quot; but later admitted that statement was misleading. The board also said that Facebook provided &quot;no meaningful transparency&quot; on how it determines which accounts should be included in XCheck.&nbsp;</p><p>An investigative report last month from the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739?mod=article_inline"><em>Wall Street Journal</em></a>, with information coming from a whistleblower later revealed to be former Facebook employee <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety-062311634.html">Frances Haugen</a>, showed that the program has actually enabled millions of high-profile users to skirt its rules.</p><p>The report also addressed the board&#39;s own performance and whether Facebook is following its recommendations. It said it took on average 74 days to decide and implement each case, and only handled a fraction that came up. In total, it has taken on 20 important cases &quot;covering topics from hate speech to COVID-19 misinformation&quot; and ruled on 17 of them, overturning Facebook&#39;s decisions eight times. It made 52 recommendations to Facebook, which has not agreed to implement all of them.&nbsp;</p><p>Facebook is facing a major fallout in Washington over the Frances Haugen document leak. Earlier this year, it promised to &quot;fully implement&quot; the Oversight Board&#39;s recommendations and explain the rationale, standards and review process of its VIP program.&nbsp;</p><p>According to the new report, however, Facebook is not following its own plan so far. The board, meanwhile, has been criticized for allowing Facebook to duck blame for key decisions, while having no authority to force Facebook to comply with its own decisions.&nbsp;</p><p>However, the board said that today it accepted a request from Facebook to review the XCheck program and make recommendations. Facebook is apparently looking for guidance on how to ensure fairness and objectivity, govern the program and make recommendations on how it can be changed. As part of that, the Oversight Board plans to issue a call for public comments &quot;which we will launch in the coming days.&quot;</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebooks-oversight-board-said-the-company-failed-to-provide-relevant-information-132603146.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">28e925b2-07de-4224-ba84-d4c10a848b50</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:26:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634823181</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T13:33:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/74baad60-71e6-11eb-aff7-53e52ef84289" width="3500" height="2137" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/74baad60-71e6-11eb-aff7-53e52ef84289" width="3500" height="2137" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Robert Galbraith / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Facebook logo is shown at Facebook headquarters in Palo Alto, California May 26, 2010. Facebook announced efforts to better guard the privacy of its more than 400 million users, addressing mounting pressure on the world's most popular online social network to protect personal data exchanged on its site.  REUTERS/Robert Galbraith  (UNITED STATES - Tags: BUSINESS SCI TECH)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FACEBOOK/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitch tests a rewind button for live streams]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever <em>just</em> missed a big moment during a live <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-chat-verification-192256743.html">Twitch stream</a>? You might not have to in the future. <em>The Verge</em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737098/twitch-testing-rewind-stream-button-remind-me-watch-trailer">reports</a> Twitch is <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitchSupport/status/1450869495392837632">launching</a> a month-long test that includes a &quot;Rewind the Stream&quot; button for live channels. Tap it and you&#39;ll jump two minutes back in the broadcast, with options to scrub through the entire stream history and play at different speeds. It&#39;s akin to playing an on-demand video, just with the choice to leap back to a live view.</p><p>The test also includes a &quot;Remind Me&quot; button (to alert you ahead of an upcoming stream) and &quot;Watch Trailer&quot; (for channels with intro videos). Twitch stressed that the test would &quot;inform future features only,&quot; and that the buttons would vanish after the test. About a quarter of viewers should see the rewind test.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There are potential safety issues. Just Chatting streamers (that is, real-world cameras) are <a href="https://twitter.com/jakenbakeLIVE/status/1450894994752081928">concerned</a> this poses a safety risk. People might have a better chance of spotting and clipping an unintentional terms-of-service violation (say, a prankster in the background) or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-peer2peer-trans-marginalized-streamers-identity-tags-212505408.html">doxxing</a> a streamer who inadvertently reveals sensitive info. This isn&#39;t the definitive implementation of the rewind button, though, and that&#39;s assuming it isn&#39;t scrapped. We wouldn&#39;t be surprised if Twitch let streamers restrict the rewind feature to certain viewers, or even disable it entirely.</p><div id="847ed55cec344aaeaae444ee0ef9bb56"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🔬 Over the next month, some viewers may see up to 3 new buttons on live channels pages: Rewind the Stream, Remind Me, &amp; Watch Trailer. This experiment will inform future features only and the buttons will be removed once it’s complete.<br><br>For feedback: <a href="https://t.co/52L43BAJsz">https://t.co/52L43BAJsz</a></p>— Twitch Support (@TwitchSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitchSupport/status/1450869495392837632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitch-rewind-button-test-132253918.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1606345a-7f49-4247-841c-fbf88a4c9282</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:22:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634821990</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T13:13:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/41963d10-326a-11ec-b75f-f0fc283518ab" width="5756" height="3804" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/41963d10-326a-11ec-b75f-f0fc283518ab" width="5756" height="3804" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Anadolu Agency via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[ANKARA, TURKEY - OCTOBER 6: The logo of "Twitch" is displayed on a smartphone in Ankara, Turkey on October 6, 2021. (Photo by Hakan Nural/Anadolu Agency via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Twitch]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's AirTags are 10 percent off at Woot today]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple&#39;s tiny Bluetooth trackers are already fairly affordable, but Woot&#39;s latest one-day sale makes them even cheaper. You can get an <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:AirTag" href="https://fave.co/3jiKWNx">AirTag</a> from the online retailer for $26 today only, which is 10 percent off its normal price. Woot <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airtag-four-pack-sale-140051531.html">knocked</a> the price of a four-pack down to $95 earlier this month, and while this price for one AirTag isn&#39;t as cheap as that, it remains the best discount we&#39;ve seen on a single pack. Just make sure to familiarize yourself with <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Woot&#39;s return policy" href="https://fave.co/3hQFqju">Woot&#39;s return policy</a> before picking one up.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://fave.co/3jiKWNx" id="a248b5aac5e14122bf312c47fc582914" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Woot;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:">Buy Apple AirTag at Woot - $26</a><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-airtags-trackers-first-look-hands-on-130036848.html">AirTags</a> are the trackers to get if you live within the Apple ecosystem. They pair just as quickly to iOS device as AirPods do and those with newer iPhones can use Precision Finding to see when they&#39;re close to their lost items. From the Find My app, you can force the AirTag to play a chime to better direct you to your things, and if the item isn&#39;t anywhere near you, the app can show you its last known location. With Lost Mode enabled, you&#39;ll get an alert when Apple&#39;s network of devices detects the location of the AirTag in question, and you can choose to share your phone number and message — just in case someone else finds your stuff.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Aside from the fact that AirTags will only work with Apple devices — sorry Android fans — the biggest problem with them is their lack of a keyring hole. So unless you plan on sticking the tracker in the folds of a wallet or a backpack pocket, you&#39;ll need an AirTag holder to hook it onto your keys and other items. Thankfully, you don&#39;t need to drop more than the price of the tracker itself on one of Apple&#39;s own cases; there are plenty of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-apple-airtag-cases-holders-accessories-123036404.html">solid, affordable third-party AirTag cases</a> out there right now. Also, while an AirTag&#39;s battery should last for a year, it&#39;s wise to keep a couple of extra watch batteries on hand for when you inevitably need to replace it.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apples-airtags-are-10-percent-off-at-woot-today-only-131007796.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4378543b-a2f0-49d3-9ba5-3e6a825ef20a</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:10:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634821473</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T13:04:36+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/85166150-a336-11eb-86ac-d7874ea0dfbc" width="2400" height="1350" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/85166150-a336-11eb-86ac-d7874ea0dfbc" width="2400" height="1350" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple AirTags]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple AirTags]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook Messenger adds group AR effects and games to video calls]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-messenger-portal-spark-ar-170048646.html">Facebook Messenger&#39;s augmented reality effects</a> are no longer limited to individuals. The social media company has introduced a Group Effects feature that, as the name implies, enables AR effects for everyone in a video call. Some of the 70-plus effects are just for giggles (such as giving everyone a beard), but others are shared experiences like games. You can compete to build a hamburger, if you&#39;re so inclined.</p><p>The feature is available today in both regular Messenger calls and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-messenger-rooms-video-calls-zoom-173025964.html">Messenger Rooms</a>, and should be &quot;coming soon&quot; to Instagram. If you have the option, you can tap the smiley icon in a group call to pick Group Effects.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The addition could help Facebook compete against Snapchat and others that have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-25-snapchat-snappables.html">had AR games for a while</a>. It might help Facebook shift its focus <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-reportedly-changing-name-042958266.html">to the metaverse</a>, for that matter. If nothing else, it&#39;s an acknowledgment that group video chat is still important even as the pandemic (hopefully) winds down. Shared AR may help you keep in touch with distant friends more effectively than basic face-to-face chats.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-messenger-group-effects-video-calls-130022910.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">37120efd-9d54-45d2-a7ee-402872b00d86</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634834306</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T16:38:32+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9ff04570-31b8-11ec-bfdf-209c26902acd" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9ff04570-31b8-11ec-bfdf-209c26902acd" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook Messenger Group Effects in video calls]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook Messenger Group Effects in video calls]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify now lets any creator use its video podcast platform]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spotify might have a much wider video podcast selection in the near future. In July last year, it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-video-podcasts-150554102.html">debuted</a> the video podcast format for select originals, but now it&#39;s <a href="https://blog.anchor.fm/video">opening up access</a> to the option to more people who want to launch their own. Creators can now apply to have their video podcasts published on the streaming platform via Anchor, which is Spotify&#39;s podcast creation tool.&nbsp;</p><p>The company says it&#39;s rolling out video podcasts on a rolling basis with a number of key creators, including existing podcasters who are expanding into video and video creators who want to reach a new audience. It&#39;s putting approved applicants in a waitlist, however, and giving them the power to make their videos available on the platform at a later date. Those who do get approved can upload episodes through their Anchor account, which will automatically be published on Spotify.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Since not all video creators will be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-joe-rogan-experience-exclusive-podcast-203044280.html">signing</a> $100 million deals with the company like Joe Rogan did, Spotify is giving them a way to earn from their shows. Creators in select markets will be able to monetize their podcasts through subscriptions, allowing them to share exclusive content with subscribers or to only make their shows available to paying customers altogether.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-video-podcast-rollout-130022700.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8f74b40a-26a2-4cef-9991-17a7f0468435</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634817710</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T12:01:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/960efb60-3266-11ec-adff-3596bdaf9994" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/960efb60-3266-11ec-adff-3596bdaf9994" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Spotify]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Spotify Video Podcasts]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Spotify Video Podcasts]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[NVIDIA's new 'GeForce Now RTX 3080' streams games at 1440p and 120 fps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NVIDIA has unveiled its next-generation cloud gaming platform called GeForce Now RTX 3080 with &quot;desktop-class latency&quot; and 1440p gaming at up to 120 fps on PC or Mac. The service is powered by a new gaming supercomputer called the GeForce Now SuperPod and costs double the price of the current <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-nows-price-increase-new-features-180648780.html">Priority tier</a>.</p><p>The SuperPod is &quot;the most powerful gaming supercomputer ever built,&quot; according to NVIDIA, delivering 39,200 TFLOPS, 11,477, 760 CUDA Cores and 8,960 CPU Cores. NVIDIA said it will provide an experience equivalent to 35 TFLOPs, or triple the Xbox Series X, roughly equal to a PC with an 8-core CPU, 28GB of DDR4-3200 RAM and a PCI-GEN4 SSD.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/9fb8f9d0-325d-11ec-bf9c-44ba371e8c1d" style="height:1125;width:2000;" alt="NVIDIA launches GeForce Now RTX 3080-class gaming at up to 1440p 120fps" data-uuid="44dbf143-8ef2-3271-9d6c-1ec0ca74a0a9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">NVIDIA</div></figure><p>As such, you&#39;ll see 1440p gaming at up to 120fps on a Mac or PC, and even 4K HDR on a shield, though NVIDIA didn&#39;t mention the refresh rate for the latter. It&#39;ll also support 120 fps on mobile, &quot;supporting next-gen 120Hz displays,&quot; the company said. By comparison, the GeForce Now Priority tier is limited to 1080p at 60 fps, with adaptive VSync available in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-nows-price-increase-new-features-180648780.html">latest update</a>.</p><p>It&#39;s also promising a &quot;click-to-pixel&quot; latency down to 56 milliseconds, thanks to tricks like adaptive sync that reduces buffering, supposedly beating other services and even local, dedicated PCs. However, that&#39;s based on a 15 millisecond round trip delay (RTD) to the GeForce Now data center, something that obviously depends on your internet provider and where you&#39;re located.&nbsp;</p><p>NVIDIA&#39;s claims aside, it&#39;s clearly a speed upgrade over the current GeForce Priority tier, whether you&#39;re on a mobile device or PC. There&#39;s a price to pay for that speed, though. The GeForce Now premium tier started at $50 per year and recently doubled to $100, which is already a pretty big ask. But the RTX 3080 tier is $100 for six months (around double the price) &quot;in limited quantities,&quot; with Founders and priority early access starting today. If it lives up to the claims, it&#39;s cheaper than buying a new PC, in any case.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nvidia-geforce-now-introduces-an-rtx-3080-tier-for-up-to-1440-p-120-fps-gaming-130011568.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c0efd587-f276-4580-aa27-a6cf9777422f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1634814825</ingested><modified>2021-10-21T11:13:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8cd0dcf0-3255-11ec-96f6-ee9ffbbd2d0c" width="1280" height="680" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/8cd0dcf0-3255-11ec-96f6-ee9ffbbd2d0c" width="1280" height="680" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NVIDIA launches GeForce Now RTX 3080-class gaming at up to 1440p 120fps]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NVIDIA launches GeForce Now RTX 3080-class gaming at up to 1440p 120fps]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>