<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:00:19 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Discord gives server owners the tools to put channels behind a paywall]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Discord has started testing a feature called <a href="https://discord.com/blog/building-sustainable-creator-communities-on-discord">Premium Memberships</a> with a small group of users. The tool allows community owners to gate access to part or all of their server behind a monthly subscription fee. It’s something the company’s growing number of users, particularly admins and mods, have been asking it to implement for a while. Before today, those individuals had to turn to third-party services like Patreon to monetize access to their servers.</p><p>By contrast, the Premium Memberships tool creates a streamlined interface for that same purpose. A new tab under the “Community” heading in the app’s setting’s menu allows server owners to do things like set price tiers and view related analytics. The feature similarly streamlines the process of signing up for paid channels for users. If you want to support a community, you don’t need to leave Discord to do so. When you tap on a premium channel, indicated by the new “sparkle” icon in the sidebar, the client will tell how much you need to pay for access, as well as what perks you’ll gain for doing so.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/da1e5800-5773-11ec-ab3e-50db057e408c" style="height:1133;width:1600;" alt="Discord Premium Memberships" data-uuid="69fd8975-211c-3632-8118-edd522bbfee1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Discord</div></figure><p>As for pricing, Discord says it will encourage server owners to experiment. As a baseline, the company will recommend a monthly fee of $2.99 as a minimum and $99.99 as a maximum. When it comes to most of the channels you visit, you probably won’t pay more than $5 or $10 a month for access. The top end of the price range is a reflection of how much Discord has changed since the start of the pandemic to accommodate a more diverse group of communities. Discord <a href="https://www.engadget.com/discord-rebranding-151953314.html">isn’t exclusively a place for gaming anymore</a>.</p><p>“Access to a channel can seem simplistic, but it’s a foundational piece that someone can build a lot of flexibility on top of,” said Jesse Wofford, group product marketing manager at Discord, in an interview with Engadget. One of the server owners the company is working with on this week’s soft launch is someone who runs gaming bootcamps. According to Wofford, they’ve built an entire business around private lessons. The company wants to give those people the opportunity to create a sustainable business on its platform.&nbsp;</p><p>Whatever someone decides to charge for access to their channels, the company plans to take a 10 percent cut of the subscription. “It&#39;s an important stake in the ground for us that this product, like a lot of other ones, is built around creator success,” Wofford said. Additionally, for people who want to continue to use services like Patreon to monetize their channels, Discord won’t stop them from doing so. “One of the important things here is that we’re still investing in those relationships,” said Wofford. “We want to create an ecosystem that gives creators as many options to succeed as possible.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b268f040-5773-11ec-bfd5-9432ce0d0309" style="height:1138;width:1600;" alt="Discord Premium Memberships" data-uuid="eea2733d-9fa0-3310-99fc-35f59a4d21b2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Discord</div></figure><p>Premium Memberships is something Discord has been working on for a while. “There’s probably a world where we could have released this a while ago,” Wofford told me. “We wanted to make sure we took in the right feedback from a diverse set of creators and built it in a way that we felt confident would deliver value.” To that end, the company plans to take its time testing the feature before it rolls it out more widely.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/discord-premium-memberships-announcement-160019679.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">68dfd6f5-36b7-401a-ab75-e0daa1ea0c87</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 16:00:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638892636</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:57:28+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/93e42220-5773-11ec-bdbd-d574ba91490d" width="1600" height="1138" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/93e42220-5773-11ec-bdbd-d574ba91490d" width="1600" height="1138" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Discord]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Discord Premium Memberships]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Discord Premium Memberships]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Hubble telescope is fully operational again after a month-long nap]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NASA&#39;s Hubble telescope has been in a &quot;coma&quot; since <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hubble-telescope-recovering-from-system-failure-151249317.html">going into system failure</a> in late October — but today, the agency <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2021/nasa-returns-hubble-to-full-science-operations">announced</a> that it is waking Hubble up. After multiple instrument sync failures that required putting Hubble into safe mode, NASA says the telescope is now functioning as normal, with all four active instruments collecting data.&nbsp;</p><p>On October 23rd, NASA first noticed that Hubble&#39;s instruments weren&#39;t receiving sync messages from the telescope&#39;s control unit. Communications issues continued for several days, which led NASA to put the telescope into a sort of safe mode — something that takes a long time to come out of because of the sensitivity of Hubble&#39;s hardware. Rapid power or temperature changes aren&#39;t good for its lifespan, so NASA took its time here.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This shutdown was the second that was required in 2021, with another month-long &quot;coma&quot; taking place in July to deal with an unrelated issue. Given the 31-year-old telescope&#39;s age, it&#39;s entirely possible that Hubble is nearing the end of its useful life in space, but for now NASA expects Hubble to work in tandem with the Webb telescope &quot;well into this decade.&quot; After numerous delays, the Webb telescope is expected to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/james-webb-space-telescope-launch-delay-215323872.html">finally launch on December 22nd</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nasa-hubble-telescope-is-operational-again-155710162.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">748c1972-bf40-4d5f-8623-9c5ab0c05f2e</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:57:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638892633</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:57:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/faf2bb70-5773-11ec-bdf5-071d24c531ce" width="2048" height="1361" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/faf2bb70-5773-11ec-bdf5-071d24c531ce" width="2048" height="1361" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Hubble telescope is fully operational again after a month-long nap]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter buys would-be Slack competitor Quill]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may not have heard of messaging service Quill, but it was positioned as a Discord- or Slack-style app for team communications that tried to be less noisy and more structured. The platform only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-new-new-slack-quill/">launched this past February</a>, but today Twitter has announce it is purchasing Quill and shutting it down this weekend. Twitter&#39;s tech GM Nick Caldwell announced the move this morning, and Quill <a href="https://quill.chat/updates/2021-12-07-quill-twitter/">confirmed the news</a> in a blog post on its own site.</p><div id="48148a1901454c398c93e18fdd2bc6b1"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Excited to share that today we’re welcoming <a href="https://twitter.com/QuillChat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@QuillChat</a> to Twitter! 👋🏿👋🏿🪶🪶</p>— Nick Caldwell🔪🧼 (@nickcald) <a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1468221427354517504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>The fact that it&#39;s shutting down this weekend is a stunningly fast turn-around; Quill is offering details on how to export data, which any team using it will probably want to do ASAP. (They&#39;ll also want to go and find a new messaging service to use post-haste.)&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The app had billed itself as &quot;messaging for people that focus,&quot; and it&#39;s not clear how that mission will continue as part of Twitter. Caldwell said that the goal was to have the Quill team help &quot;make messaging tools like DMs a more useful &amp; expressive way people can have conversations.&quot; Chances are good this is more of an acqui-hire situation, in which Twitter wanted to have the Quill team working on Twitter&#39;s existing products. Given how fast Quill is shutting down, it&#39;s pretty clear Twitter doesn&#39;t have any interest in spending resources on that existing product.</p><p>It&#39;s the second major acquisition Twitter has made in the last month or so — in mid-November, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-buys-threader-194631446.html">Twitter purchased Threader</a>, a popular tool that pulled threads of tweets together into an easier to read format. Just like the Quill purchase, Twitter didn&#39;t waste much time shutting down Threader — the app is set to disappear on December 15th. (At least it got a longer lease on life than Quill.) Threader is expected to be rolled into the Twitter Blue subscription service; we&#39;ll have to see if some of Quill&#39;s legacy ends up there, as well.</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-purchases-quill-messaging-service-153151449.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">80911ee2-4a6d-4730-be9d-fb157ecea0eb</guid><dc:creator>Nathan Ingraham</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638890160</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:16:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nathan Ingraham]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c9788d30-576f-11ec-b377-eb768af176e8" width="1426" height="846" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/c9788d30-576f-11ec-b377-eb768af176e8" width="1426" height="846" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Quill]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Quill messaging service]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Quill messaging service]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A hacker named Bowser agrees to pay Nintendo $10 million to settle a civil piracy suit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A Canadian hacker named Gary Bowser (yes, like Mario&#39;s nemesis) has agreed to pay the company $10 million to settle <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-bowser-lawsuit-switch-hacks-205618404.html"><ins>a civil piracy lawsuit</ins></a>. Bowser, who was part of Switch hacking group Team Xecuter, was accused of being part of a &quot;cybercriminal enterprise that hacked leading gaming consoles,&quot; as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-12-07-nintendo-hacker-gary-bowser-agrees-to-pay-usd10m-fine"><em><ins>Eurogamer</ins></em></a> notes. Nintendo argued Bowser violated the company&#39;s copyright and it seems the hacks were not in another castle.</p><div id="cd4a6e34ad644d568d0df277b6891d23"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">NEW: Gary Bowser agrees to pay Nintendo $10 million in video game piracy civil lawsuit. This follows Bowser&#39;s guilty plea in October in the federal criminal case against him (where he agreed pay Nintendo $4.5 million in restitution.) <a href="https://t.co/zohn0SPHnH">https://t.co/zohn0SPHnH</a><a href="https://t.co/KMJro3l8Zw">pic.twitter.com/KMJro3l8Zw</a></p>— Rob Romano (@2Aupdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/2Aupdates/status/1467989403876352009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>News of the settlement emerged several weeks after Bowser pleaded guilty to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/team-xecuter-arrests-214400208.html"><ins>multiple federal hacking charges</ins></a>. He was fined $4.5 million in that case and faces up to 10 years in prison. Bowser, who was arrested in the Dominican Republic in October 2020 and deported to the US, admitted to having &quot;developed, manufactured, marketed, and sold a variety of circumvention devices&quot; that let people play ROMs on consoles.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bowser-nintendo-civil-piracy-lawsuit-settlement-152050856.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">dc737d88-61b3-4876-919f-526db85092b1</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:20:50 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638890160</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:16:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Crime & Justice]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/b59fd5b0-32e6-11eb-af4f-fcdb72a28cfd" width="3968" height="2674" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/b59fd5b0-32e6-11eb-af4f-fcdb72a28cfd" width="3968" height="2674" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[KYODO Kyodo / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A statue of Bowser or King Koopa is displayed inside Bowser's Catsle at Super Nintendo World, a new attraction area featuring the popular video game character Mario where set to open in the spring of 2021, at the Universal Studios Japan theme park in Osaka, western Japan, November 30, 2020, in this photo taken by Kyodo.  Mandatory credit Kyodo/via REUTERS ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE WAS PROVIDED BY A THIRD PARTY. MANDATORY CREDIT. JAPAN OUT.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[NINTENDO-UNIVERSAL STUDIOS JAPAN/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rohingya refugees sue Facebook for $150 billion over Myanmar genocide]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook has been <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-09-20-facebook-accused-of-supporting-ethnic-cleansing-in-myanmar.html">repeatedly accused</a> of enabling Myanmar&#39;s genocide against the country&#39;s Rohingya minority, and now it will deal with those accusations in court. A Rohingya woman has filed a class-action lawsuit on behalf of refugees against Facebook parent company Meta, alleging the company both amplified anti-Rohingya hate speech through its algorithms and failed to remove content fostering violence. The refugees ask for over $150 billion in damages.</p><p>The plaintiffs argued that Facebook only took meaningful action against pro-genocide factions after it was pushed. The Myanmar military launched its purge of Rohingya in 2017, with officials and nationalist monks spreading slurs and misinformation on Facebook to either justify or cover up atrocities. Facebook only started cracking down in August 2018 following a UN report linking unchecked behavior on the social network to real-world violence. The company requested an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-06-facebook-myanmar-bsr-report.html">independent audit</a> at the same time that reached a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-06-facebook-myanmar-bsr-report.html">similar conclusion</a>. This was too little too late, according to the refugees — the company admitted it &quot;should and could have done more&quot; only after mass displacements and deaths.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meta has already declined to comment on the lawsuit. A similar complaint is expected in the UK in 2022.</p><p>The firm was quick to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-limiting-myanmar-military-reach-065458912.html">clamp down on the Myanmar military</a> following its February 2021 coup, and went so far as to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-takes-down-myanmar-military-page-160843607.html">pull the military&#39;s main page</a>. However,  that swifter response won&#39;t help much with a lawsuit over past actions. While it&#39;s too soon to say whether or not the lawsuit will succeed, let alone obtain the hoped-for damages, the company may have a difficult time defending itself.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rohingya-lawsuit-facebook-meta-genocide-150644112.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4ce3889f-ac31-417d-b5ae-35a8eabcf6a1</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638889608</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T15:06:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9483db00-5767-11ec-abcb-58e872336e1a" width="3856" height="2560" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/9483db00-5767-11ec-abcb-58e872336e1a" width="3856" height="2560" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Beawiharta Beawiharta / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A protester holds a placard during protest against Myanmar's treatment of its Rohingya Muslim minority in front of Myanmar's embassy in Jakarta, Indonesia, December 5, 2018. REUTERS/Beawiharta]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[MYANMAR-ROHINGYA/INDONESIA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's Alexa Together caregiver service is available today]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alexa-together-service-171909617.html">Alexa Together</a> to help take care of aging family members. Amazon has <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alexa-Together/b?ie=UTF8&amp;node=21390531011">launched</a> the $20 per month ($199 per year) service, with a six-month free trial available for a &quot;limited time.&quot; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-2020-alexa-breathing-teach-voice-profiles-for-kids-172918631.html">Care Hub</a> users get a full free year from now until December 7th, 2022. Your loved one will need an Alexa-capable device, but after that it&#39;s relatively hands-off — they ideally get more independence while you get some peace of mind.</p><p>The elderly relative can reach an emergency helpline if they ask Alexa to &quot;call for help,&quot; but Together is mainly useful for notifications. You&#39;ll get alerts if your family member calls that line, or simply for their first Alexa interaction of the day. Use a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-24-walabot-home-fall-detection.html">fall detection sensor</a> from ATS or Vayyar (more device support is coming) and you&#39;ll also get word if there&#39;s an incident.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Amazon stressed that seniors would still have their privacy. They have to grant permission for you to remotely assist them by adding contacts, reminders and services. Any Alexa interaction alerts are also generic. You&#39;ll know your loved one made an entertainment request, for instance, but you won&#39;t know what was playing.</p><p>The service is still relatively limited. Amazon doesn&#39;t expect to support multiple caregivers until early 2022, for instance, so this won&#39;t help if your siblings also want to pitch in. It might still be useful if you want that safety net, though. If nothing else, it&#39;s clear between this and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-halo-fitness-nutrition-164816502.html">Halo services</a> that Amazon wants to be a part of your daily wellness checks — whether they&#39;re your own or someone else&#39;s.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alexa-together-service-release-date-140003827.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">527694f2-b792-4509-a97c-658834d1c27b</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638885192</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:53:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a3909040-5760-11ec-affb-38da2f528fab" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a3909040-5760-11ec-affb-38da2f528fab" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon Alexa Together 'start my day' routine]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Alexa Together 'start my day' routine]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's second-generation AirPods are back on sale for $100]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite the addition of the third-generation AirPods to Apple&#39;s earbud lineup, the second-gen versions remain a decent option for those that liked the fit of the company&#39;s old-school EarPods. They&#39;ve also become a budget-friendly option this holiday shopping season as we&#39;ve seen the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:second-gen AirPods" href="https://amzn.to/3Ewo4Th">second-gen AirPods</a> go on sale a few times. Now you can pick them up for only $100, which is roughly $60 off their normal price. While they were on sale for $89 last month for a brief period of time, this remains one of the best prices we&#39;ve seen.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3Ewo4Th" id="9b0ac9ea2c774ad89561c147e40f05e8" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy AirPods (2nd gen) at Amazon - $100</a><p>You probably know the drill about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-03-apple-airpods-review-2019-more-of-the-same.html">AirPods</a> by now, but we&#39;ll provide a refresher. These are the &quot;classic&quot; style AirPods that made Apple&#39;s earbuds some of the most popular in the wireless audio space. Their kicker is the H1 chipset inside that allows them to quickly pair and switch between Apple devices. Not only do they connect to your iPhone in seconds, but they can also switch to, say, your MacBook while you watch a YouTube video pretty seamlessly.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The EarPods-like design of these buds will be great for some, but a bit cumbersome for others. That&#39;s one of the improvements Apple made with its <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:third-gen earbuds" href="https://amzn.to/3GrWx69">third-gen earbuds</a>, but those come in at $179. The second-gen models have decent sound quality and a good battery life, too — you&#39;ll get around five hours of use before they need more power, and you can get more than 24 hours of total listening time after a few recharges with the included case. Overall, they may not have some of the newer bells and whistles you&#39;ll find on the latest AirPods, but these make a good pair of wireless earbuds for Apple users on a budget.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apples-second-generation-airpods-are-back-on-sale-for-100-133533441.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7f510e1b-76bb-4eb6-8ef5-969cbeca9807</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:35:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638884135</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:35:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/9b12fa70-e79f-11ea-bebd-5d587fda2efa" width="2000" height="1350" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/9b12fa70-e79f-11ea-bebd-5d587fda2efa" width="2000" height="1350" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Velazco / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple AirPods]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple AirPods]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony stops producing its new ZV-E10 camera due to chip shortages]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony only just launched its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-expands-its-vlogging-lineup-with-the-zv-e-10-mirrorless-camera-142731045.html">ZV-E10</a> mirrorless vlogging camera in July, but as of December 3rd, it has suspended orders and ceased production due to the ongoing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/chip%20shortage/">chip shortage</a>, Sony Japan <a href="https://www.sony.jp/ichigan/info2/20211203.html">announced</a>. The company added that a resumption of production and sales will depend upon &quot;the status of parts supply,&quot; and that interested buyers should keep an eye on the camera&#39;s <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/imaging/interchangeable-lens-cameras/aps-c/p/ilczve10l-b">product page</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The ZV-E10 was released as a more capable follow-up to the popular, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-zv-1-vlogging-camera-review-162822651.html">compact ZV-1</a> vlogging camera, thanks to the option to change lenses. It&#39;s essentially a reworked A6100 model with a flip-out display, no electronic viewfinder (EVF), a high-quality built-in three-capsule microphone and a button that makes it easy to switch from video to still photography.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Sony has also paused production of the A7 II, A6400 and A6100 cameras. The latter two are fairly recent models, but the A7 II originally launched in 2014 — so it&#39;s hard to see a particular pattern.&nbsp;</p><p>Cameras aren&#39;t the only Sony products affected by semiconductor shortages. Sony also reportedly reduced PS5 production, something that might put its delivery target of 14.8 million consoles by March 2022 in jeopardy. Sony and TSMC recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-tsmc-confirm-japan-factory-chip-shortage-153515725.html">announced</a> that they&#39;d team up on a chip factory in Japan for specialized chips used in cars, cameras and other gadgets. However, the plant won&#39;t come online until 2024 at the earliest, so it&#39;ll do nothing to help Sony or anyone else, anytime soon.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-suspends-orders-for-the-new-zv-e-10-because-of-shortages-132051883.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ac8e72b5-8706-46e6-8aaf-739e8eaf1e60</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638882962</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:16:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d2e798c0-5756-11ec-beff-c160986f0d69" width="2500" height="1579" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d2e798c0-5756-11ec-beff-c160986f0d69" width="2500" height="1579" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony suspends orders for the new ZV-E10 because of chip shortages]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony suspends orders for the new ZV-E10 because of chip shortages]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's smart thermostat falls to $48 in first ever discount]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in November, Amazon <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-60-dollar-alexa-powered-thermostat-161738943.html">started selling</a> its own smart thermostat for a price that&#39;s less than half what a Google Nest thermostat costs. Now, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat" href="https://amzn.to/3lDS0Fp">Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat</a> has gotten its first price drop and is currently on sale for $48, or 20 percent off its original retail price. It&#39;s not as feature-rich as its much expensive rivals — it doesn&#39;t have motion activation, for instance — but it&#39;s a solid option for a fraction of the price.&nbsp;</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3lDS0Fp" id="60a0f326fa61417c806d5d04a2a9ba1b" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:">Buy Amazon Smart Thermostat at Amazon - $48</a><p>The device is Energy Star-certified, which means it was designed to save you an average of $50 on electric bills per year. It works with Alexa voice control, as you would expect from an Amazon product, but it doesn&#39;t have speakers or a microphone. You&#39;ll have to issue voice commands through a compatible Alexa-enabled device, such as an Echo or the Alexa app.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Once set up, Alexa can take over for you. It can set the temperature if you want it to and update it throughout the day for maximum savings potential. Through the thermostat&#39;s learning feature called Hunches, Alexa will be able to automatically adjust the temperature based on its observations. For example, it can turn down the heat if it believes that nobody&#39;s home.&nbsp;</p><p>Amazon&#39;s smart thermostat also has a simple, modern design that doesn&#39;t make it look cheap despite being a budget option. The $48 device doesn&#39;t come with a C-wire power adapter. If you need the adapter, you can also get the bundle with one for $63 or 25 percent lower than its usual price, though it&#39;s currently not in stock.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p><p><em>All products recommended by Engadget are selected by our editorial team, independent of our parent company. Some of our stories include affiliate links. If you buy something through one of these links, we may earn an affiliate commission.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-smart-thermostat-first-price-drop-131009736.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3d3da35d-0211-4810-b092-7bd4c2521dfc</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638882827</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:13:56+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa71aab0-5757-11ec-affd-13cf53c2fc44" width="1600" height="1036" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa71aab0-5757-11ec-affd-13cf53c2fc44" width="1600" height="1036" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon smart thermostat]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon smart thermostat]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: The latest Unreal Engine demo is ‘The Matrix Awakens’]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That’s a digital Keanu and, yes, Epic Games’ interactive demo ties into <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em> feature film landing later this month. On December 9th,<em>&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-awakens-unreal-engine-5-interactive-demo-165501226.html"><em>The Matrix Awakens</em></a> will be available on your PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X/S console ahead of its debut at The Game Awards.</p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-awakens-unreal-engine-5-interactive-demo-165501226.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/e9754dc0-574d-11ec-bbf6-850d168c676c" style="height:422;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="145e743b-88e0-3151-9856-64d332bf233d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Epic Games</div></figure></a><p>It appears to be a slick technical demo of Unreal Engine 5, showing what the next-generation engine is capable of, with some help from Neo et al. For most, this will be the first chance to see UE5 in action. Epic previewed the engine partway through last year with a stunning PS5 demo, but has been largely quiet since. The Game Awards, this Thursday, sounds like a good time to show off.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Samsung’s major shake-up</a></h2><h3>It’s replaced all its CEOs.</h3><h3></h3><p>Samsung has merged its mobile business, the company&#39;s biggest moneymaker, with its consumer electronics division in a major restructuring meant to &quot;strengthen its business competitiveness.&quot; The tech giant has also replaced all of its CEOs and shuffled many around.</p><p>Jong-Hee Han, head of its TV business, has been named as Vice Chairman and co-CEO of the newly merged mobile and consumer electronics divisions. Han won&#39;t be leaving his duties as Head of Visual Display, though, and will instead lead both businesses. Han reportedly has no experience in mobile, but Samsung credits him with playing a key role in the company dominating global TV sales over the past 15 years.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html https://www.engadget.com/...">The SEC is investigating Tesla over defective solar panels</a></h2><h3>The probe stems from a 2019 whistleblower complaint.</h3><h3></h3><p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission is investigating Tesla after a whistleblower complaint alleging the company failed to disclose a variety of safety risks associated with its rooftop solar panels. According to a <em>Reuters </em>report, the agency acknowledged the probe in a Freedom of Information Act request made by Steven Henkes (pictured above), a former Tesla employee.</p><p>The investigation follows several years of reports of safety concerns with Tesla’s solar panels. In 2019, Walmart sued the company after its solar panels led to seven store fires. While the two companies eventually settled, the retailer claimed at the time that Tesla regularly sent inspectors who “lacked basic solar training and knowledge.&quot; That same year, Tesla solar panels at an Amazon warehouse in California reportedly caught fire as well.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Concept hydrogen-powered plane could fly halfway around the world without refueling</a></h2><h3>But the main word is concept, for now.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/cb1ca340-574e-11ec-bdef-c39d7251a0c9" style="height:370;width:675;" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="0fa1513f-741f-3c7d-962e-bf7d591467e1"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Aerospace Technology Institute</div></figure></a><p>Electric planes won&#39;t be feasible until batteries become more powerful and lightweight, but hydrogen-powered flight is another possible way to reduce the flight industry’s carbon emissions.</p><p>The FlyZero project, led by the Aerospace Technology Institute and funded by the UK government, came up with a concept for a liquid hydrogen-powered midsize aircraft. It said the plane would be able to fly 279 passengers non-stop from London to San Francisco or from London to Auckland, New Zealand, with one stop for refueling.</p><p>We&#39;re years away from commercial hydrogen aircrafts, with refueling infrastructure non-existent and hydrogen more expensive and difficult to store than standard kerosene fuel. The FlyZero project plans to publish more detailed findings early next year.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hydrogen-plane-concept-flyzero-uk-aerospace-technology-institute-163107894.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html">Instagram launches Take a Break and other safety features for teens</a></h2><h3>Just in time for Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony.</h3><h3></h3><p>Instagram has launched a number of new and experimental features meant to make its app a safer place for teens ahead of Instagram head <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-adam-mosseri-congress-testify-184609082.html"><ins>Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony</ins></a>. The previously announced <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-teen-take-a-break-205617444.html"><ins>Take a Break</ins></a> feature has now launched in the US, UK, Canada and Australia. Now, when a user — teens, in particular — scolls through Instagram for a long while, the app will ask them to take a break and to set reminders for the future.</p><p>In March, Instagram will be launching tools for parents and guardians to give them a way to view how much time their kids are spending on the app and to set time limits.</p><p>Adam Mosseri is set to testify this week as part of a series of hearings about protecting kids online. Instagram and Facebook have come under fire in recent months after whistleblower Frances Haugen told Congress about the social networks&#39; effect on teens based on Meta&#39;s own research. Haugen revealed that &quot;engagement-based ranking on Instagram can lead children from very innocuous topics like healthy recipes… to anorexia-promoting content over a very short period of time.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><p></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/shatner-in-space-documents-the-90-year-olds-blue-origin-voyage-134555889.html"><ins>William Shatner&#39;s space voyage is becoming an Amazon documentary</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/toshibas-flagship-amazon-fire-hands-free-alexa-140014641.html"><ins>Toshiba&#39;s flagship Fire TV set has hands-free Alexa</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-firefox-95-rlbox-190712215.html"><ins>Firefox 95 enhances the browser&#39;s protection against malicious code</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/doordash-15-minute-grocery-delivery-nyc-ultra-fast-200711153.html"><ins>DoorDash tests 15-minute grocery deliveries in New York City</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/googles-pixel-6-can-now-be-used-to-unlock-bmw-vehicles-180000062.html"><ins>Google Pixel update delivers time-saving improvements on new and older models</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-copyright-transparency-report-184854080.html"><ins>YouTube says most disputed copyright claims are resolved in the uploader&#39;s favor</ins></a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-the-latest-unreal-engine-demo-is-the-matrix-awakens-121518809.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">284ea041-2290-4172-9af3-b3e121bcabe0</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 12:15:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638876159</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T11:22:55+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/beb9a050-574c-11ec-bfcf-4012fd9e8060" width="1432" height="792" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/beb9a050-574c-11ec-bfcf-4012fd9e8060" width="1432" height="792" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Matrix Awakens]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Matrix Awakens]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla is reportedly replacing some faulty Autopilot cameras for free]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tesla will replace the Autopilot cameras in the front fenders of some its electric vehicles for free, according to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/06/tesla-is-replacing-faulty-autpilot-cameras-in-some-model-s-x-3-cars.html"><em>CNBC</em></a>. While Tesla has yet to issue a recall, the news organization has seen internal documents distributed to authorized service providers in late November, asking them to replace faulty repeater cameras at no cost to owners. Apparently, the cameras on some Model S, X and 3 vehicles manufactured by the company at its Fremont, California plant have faulty printed circuit boards.&nbsp;</p><p>Those cameras capture the car&#39;s blind spots, and Autopilot wouldn&#39;t work without them. If they&#39;re not working as intended, drivers typically only see a block box on their main display and may get alerts that their Autopilot has limited function. <em>CNBC</em> says Tesla may have to replace cameras for at least several hundred vehicles as a result of the faulty PCBs it used.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>A Tesla sales manager told the publication that internal service notices are sometimes followed by voluntary recalls, but the automaker has yet to issue a statement. Tesla recalled vehicles several times in the past over various issues. In October, it recalled nearly 3,000 Model 3 and Y vehicles, because their front suspension lateral link fasteners <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-recall-suspension-model-y-3-191031712.html">may loosen</a>. The company also recalled 11,704 Tesla EVs from 2017 and later in November after they became prone to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-braking-recall-software-glitch-132442476.html">false-positive braking</a> following a buggy Full Self-Driving beta update.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-replacing-faulty-autopilot-cameras-115552280.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eb766432-e3ad-4f8e-97d9-b054a694e0f7</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:55:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638876404</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T11:26:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-12/0099abe0-1605-11ea-99e7-1a2853920ae2" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-12/0099abe0-1605-11ea-99e7-1a2853920ae2" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[jetcityimage via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Indianapolis, US - March 29, 2016: Tesla Motors Store in Indianapolis Selling Electric Cars III]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Indianapolis - March 2016: Tesla Motors Store III]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[BMW says it hit its goal of delivering one million 'electrified' vehicles]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, BMW <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-19-bmw-now-has-500-000-evs-on-the-road.html">delivered</a> its 500,000th electrified vehicle (including EVs and hybrids), promising to deliver one million units in two years. Now, the company has <a href="https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0362353EN/delivered-as-promised:-bmw-group-hands-over-one-millionth-electrified-vehicle-and-achieves-next-milestone-in-transformation">announced</a> that it&#39;s met that goal by delivering its one millionth electrified vehicle, an iX xDrive40 SUV (shown above), to a customer in Europe. It&#39;s also promising to double that tally to two million by next year, while delivering two million fully electric EVs by 2025.&nbsp;</p><p>BMW was a pioneer in the pure electric category with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-07-29-bmw-unveils-i3-electric-car-in-the-carbon-fiber-flesh-video.html">i3</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-09-10-bmw-i8-plug-in-hybrid-pricing.html">i8 EVs</a>, but has been slow to ramp up its offerings since then. As such, the majority of its electrified sales have been hybrid, rather than pure EVs. (The term &quot;electrified&quot; generally encompasses both PHEVs, mild hybrids and EVs.) Between January and September of 2021, BMW reportedly sold 59,688 EVs and 171,887 plug-in hybrid vehicles worldwide, according to <a href="https://cleantechnica.com/2021/11/05/bmws-ev-sales-double-in-2021-but-still-cant-catch-tesla/"><em>CleanTechnica</em></a>. In 2020, it sold 192,646 plug-in vehicles, including PHEVs and EVs, <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/465907/bmw-group-plugin-electric-car-sales-2020/"><em>InsideEVs</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>reported.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This year, the company launched the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bmw-i4-m50-first-drive-video-163055887.html">i4 sedan</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bmw-ix-ev-first-drive-video-193002612.html">iX SUV</a> pure electric models into the US market, but they only went on sale last month. It also offers <a href="https://www.bmwusa.com/vehicles/plug-in-hybrid-electric.html">four PHEVs</a>, including versions of the 7, X5, 3 and 5 models. Over the next year, BMW will add the fully electric BMW 7 series and X1, plus the high-volume BMW 5 series by 2023. It plans to have &quot;about ten million fully-electric vehicles on the road&quot; by 2031 or so.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bmw-says-it-hit-its-goal-of-delivering-a-million-electrified-vehicles-by-2021-112235105.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">37e4e0b5-e42c-4f93-b1b6-14358aca884f</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:22:35 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638883601</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:26:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/44ee2690-5749-11ec-b7d7-8bf1242f770a" width="2560" height="1624" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/44ee2690-5749-11ec-b7d7-8bf1242f770a" width="2560" height="1624" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Uwe Fischer / BMW]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[BMW one millionth electrified vehicle sale]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW one millionth electrified vehicle sale]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[ESPN+ will offer 4,300 hours of PGA Tour Live golf streaming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Golf has been <a href="https://www.golfdigest.com/story/national-golf-foundation-reports-numbers-for-2020-were-record-se">booming</a> during the pandemic as folks look for socially distanced outdoor activities, and that has extended to <a href="https://golf.com/news/5-takeaways-golf-tv-ratings-2021-hot-mic/">interest</a> in televised golf. There&#39;s going to be a lot more to watch in 2022, as ESPN+ has announced that it will offer 4,300 hours of golf coverage across 35 tournaments as part of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-09-pga-tour-live-espn-plus-in-2022.html">PGA Tour Live streaming deal</a>. US viewers will also pay less to access the service.</p><p>In the past, we&#39;ve seen &quot;Featured Groups&quot; and &quot;Featured Holes&quot; on PGA Tour Live. Next year, however, ESPN+ will offer four concurrent feeds, adding a &quot;Marquee Group&quot; with the most interesting players. It&#39;s also introducing a &quot;Main Feed&quot; that will resemble a traditional broadcast with the best content from all its cameras around the course.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>ESPN+ said the PGA Tour Live production crew will increase from 85 to 210 people as part of its new commitment to the tour. Each feed will have hosts and on-course analysts including Stuart Appleby, Christina Kim, Chantel McCabe and Mark Immelman.&nbsp;</p><p>PGA Tour Live first launched as a free service on pgatour.com, and has recently been available for free <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-01-05-twitter-will-livestream-portions-of-pga-golf-tournaments.html">on Twitter</a> during select broadcasts. Now, you&#39;ll need to pay $6.99 per month for ESPN+, or pick it up in the Disney Bundle that includes Disney+, Hulu and ESPN+ for $13.99 per month (ESPN+ is only available in the US). That&#39;s a significant sum, but PGA Tour Live currently costs $9.99 per month on NBC Sports Gold, and ESPN+ offers other live sports coverage (soccer, MLB baseball, NHL hockey, MMA, etc.) on top of golf.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/espn-is-the-new-home-for-pga-tour-lives-extended-golf-coverage-094741252.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2b75045e-27b8-48d3-973d-2e624bc4c6bd</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 09:47:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638870463</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T09:47:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Golf]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/384528b0-5741-11ec-bbf3-7acd75beedaa" width="5985" height="3982" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/384528b0-5741-11ec-bbf3-7acd75beedaa" width="5985" height="3982" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Keyur Khamar via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[OWINGS MILLS, MD - AUGUST 28:  Bryson DeChambeau at the top of his swing as he plays his shot from the 13th hole drop zone after hitting his tee shot in the water during the third round of the BMW Championship, the second event of the FedExCup Playoffs, at Caves Valley Golf Club on August 28, 2021 in Owings Mills, Maryland. (Photo by Keyur Khamar/PGA TOUR via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BMW Championship - Round Three]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instagram adds more teen safety features ahead of parental control rollout next year]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Instagram has launched a number of new and experimental features meant to make its app a safer place for teens ahead of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-adam-mosseri-congress-testify-184609082.html">Adam Mosseri&#39;s Senate testimony</a>. To start with, it&#39;s launching the previously announced &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-teen-take-a-break-205617444.html">Take a Break</a>&quot; feature in the US, UK, Canada and Australia today. Now, when a user has been scrolling Instagram for quite some time, the app will ask them to take a break and to set reminders for the future. Teens, in particular, will get notifications to set those reminders on to make sure they&#39;re aware of the feature. They&#39;ll also see expert-backed tips to help them &quot;reflect and reset.&quot;</p><p>In March, Instagram will be launching tools for parents and guardians that will give them a way to view how much time their kids are spending on the app and to set time limits. Teens will get the option to notify their parents if they report someone, as well, serving as a way to signal the adults in their life that they may need to talk about it.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>One of the experimental features Instagram is testing will come in handy for teens and young adults who want to remove their activity on the app from when they were a lot younger. It will allow users to bulk delete the photos and videos they posted, as well as all their likes and comments. The feature will be available to everyone in January.&nbsp;</p><p>Another test feature will expand what Instagram started earlier this year when it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-restricts-adult-dms-to-teens-140416475.html">prohibited</a> adults from DMing teens who don&#39;t follow them. Early next year, it will also switch off the ability to tag or mention teens by adults who don&#39;t follow them, or to include their content in Reels Remixes or Guides. Finally, it&#39;s exploring the possibility of limiting the sensitive content teens see even more and is currently building an experience that would nudge users towards another topic if they&#39;ve been scrolling one topic for a while.&nbsp;</p><p>Instagram head Adam Mosseri is set to testify this week as part of a series of hearings about protecting kids online. Instagram and Facebook have come under fire in recent months after whistleblower Frances Haugen <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-said-should-change-143051354.html">told Congress</a> about the social networks&#39; effect on teens based on Meta&#39;s own research. Haugen made a lot of disclosures about Facebook&#39;s algorithms and other internal systems, and one of the things she revealed was that &quot;engagement-based ranking on Instagram can lead children from very innocuous topics like healthy recipes… to anorexia-promoting content over a very short period of time.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/instagram-launches-take-a-break-features-for-teens-080049775.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">581eaf03-0510-4b11-996e-4c539f3fe800</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638886739</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T14:19:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/12a07320-572e-11ec-9fff-3363a7aecdf6" width="3000" height="1996" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/12a07320-572e-11ec-9fff-3363a7aecdf6" width="3000" height="1996" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Steve Jennings via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SAN FRANCISCO, CA - SEPTEMBER 14:  Vice President of Product Management at Facebook Adam Mosseri speaks onstage during TechCrunch Disrupt SF 2016 at Pier 48 on September 14, 2016 in San Francisco, California.  (Photo by Steve Jennings/Getty Images for TechCrunch)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt SF 2016 - Day 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung merges mobile and consumer electronics divisions in major shakeup]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung has <a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-electronics-announces-new-leadership-2">merged</a> its mobile business, the company&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-q3-earnings-chip-mobile-record-high-030342880.html">biggest moneymaker</a>, with its consumer electronics division in a major restructuring meant to &quot;strengthen its business competitiveness.&quot; In addition, to combining divisions, the tech giant has also replaced all of its CEOs.&nbsp;</p><p>Jong-Hee Han, the head of its TV business, has been named as Vice-Chairman and co-CEO of the newly merged mobile and consumer electronics divisions. Han won&#39;t be leaving his duties as head of visual display, though, and will instead lead both businesses. According to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/samsung-elec-says-it-will-reorganise-company-structure-2021-12-07/"><em>Reuters</em></a>, Han has no experience in mobile, but Samsung credits him for playing a key role in the company achieving top position in global TV sales over the past 15 years.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Meanwhile, Samsung President Kyehyun Kyung has also been named co-CEO and will now lead its chip and components division. Kyung is a semiconductor design expert and used to leading the company&#39;s flash product and technology team. He&#39;s expected to &quot;help maintain&quot; Samsung&#39;s semiconductor leadership and conjure innovative ideas at the same time.&nbsp;</p><p>While mobile generated the biggest revenue (US$24.2 billion) for Samsung in the third quarter of 2021, its chip business isn&#39;t that far behind. Its semiconductor business posted US$22.6 billion in revenue due to the heightened demand for server DRAMs and for computers in general during the pandemic. Samsung is aiming to become the number 1 chip contract manufacturer within the next decade and has poured hundreds of billions into the business. Just this November, it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-17-billion-chip-factory-texas-054150875.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s building a $17 billion semiconductor factory in Texas to manufacture high-end and advanced chips for smartphones, 5G and artificial intelligence.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsung-combines-mobile-consumer-electronics-055424678.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ef90d74e-3eab-4aa9-a19b-6d86dd504ce1</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 05:54:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638856512</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T05:55:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/59faabe0-5716-11ec-bdff-18a1bf083db7" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/59faabe0-5716-11ec-bdff-18a1bf083db7" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chung Sung-Jun via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SEOUL, SOUTH KOREA - AUGUST 25:  A Samsung flag flies outside the Samsung office on August 25, 2017 in Seoul, South Korea. Prosecutors are seeking a 12-year jail sentence. Lee, de facto chief of South Korean conglomerate, faces five charges connecting the bribery scandal involving ousted former President Park Geun-hye and her confidant Choi Soon-sil. The verdict affects the business of Samsung, which has launched new Galaxy Note 8 smartphone to wipe out the misery of exploding Note 7 last year.  (Photo by Chung Sung-Jun/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung Group Heir Lee Delivered Ruling Over Bribery Scandal Involving Former President Park]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[EV startup Arrival is building a $11.5 million battery plant in North Carolina]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>British-American vehicle manufacturer Arrival today <a href="https://arrival.com/us/en/news/arrival-announces-high-voltage-battery-module-assembly-plant-in-charlotte-nc">announced</a> it plans to establish an $11.5 million battery plant in Charlotte, North Carolina. The factory will be the company’s third overall facility in the city. It will be located just steps away from its soon-to-be-complete North American headquarters. Once the plant is operational, it will supply batteries to the company’s Van “Microfactory,” creating approximately 150 additional jobs.&nbsp;</p><p>“By bringing the assembly of our proprietary High Voltage Battery Modules in-house, we’re striving to be as vertically integrated as possible,” Arrival CEO Mike Ableson said. “This will enable us to have even greater control over the functionality and cost of our products and pass those cost savings on to the customer while also working toward our goal of zero waste production.” The company told <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/ev-maker-arrival-to-build-high-voltage-battery-module-assembly-plant-in-north-carolina/"><em>TechCrunch</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>the facility should have a production capacity of up to 350,000 battery modules per year.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Arrival has a lot riding on the success of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/arrival-ups-delivery-van-beta-trials-us-uk-090059767.html">Van EV</a>. In 2020, UPS <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-29-ups-arrival-electric-trucks-order-investment.html">ordered 10,000</a> electric trucks from the automaker, with the option to buy an additional 10,000 vehicles if everything goes well. The announcement comes on the same day Toyota said it would build a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/toyota-greensboro-randolph-megasite-ev-annoucement-202448241.html">$1.29 billion battery plant</a> in central North Carolina.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/arrival-north-carolina-221732120.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">95ecf494-821d-42c0-8f15-5be87c02f91f</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 22:17:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638883625</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T13:27:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0e497c10-56e1-11ec-a6f5-a1fb94e2fc33" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0e497c10-56e1-11ec-a6f5-a1fb94e2fc33" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Arrival]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Arrival battery]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Arrival battery]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The SEC is investigating Tesla over defective solar panels]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission is investigating Tesla following a whistleblower complaint alleging the company failed to disclose a variety of safety risks associated with rooftop solar panels from its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-11-21-tesla-solarcity-acquisition.html"><ins>SolarCity division</ins></a>. Per <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/exclusive-sec-probes-tesla-over-whistleblower-claims-solar-panel-defects-2021-12-06/"><em><ins>Reuters</ins></em></a>, the agency acknowledged the probe in a Freedom of Information Act request made by Steven Henkes (pictured above), a former Tesla employee.&nbsp;</p><p>He contacted the SEC in 2019 after the automaker allegedly ignored his pleas to notify consumers and regulators about the safety issues with its solar panels. One of those involved defective electrical connectors that could cause fires.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In 2020, Henkes later sued Tesla, alleging the company had dismissed him in retaliation for his actions. &quot;The top lawyer cautioned any communication of this issue to the public as a detriment to the Tesla reputation,” Henkes said in his complaint. According to the lawsuit, more than 60,000 residential customers were affected by the issues Henkes documented in his complaint.</p><p>The investigation follows several years of reports of safety concerns with Tesla’s solar panels. In 2019, Walmart <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-20-walmart-sues-tesla-over-solar-panel-fires.html"><ins>sued the company</ins></a> after its solar panels led to seven store fires. While the two companies eventually settled, Walmart claimed at the time Tesla regularly sent inspectors who “lacked basic solar training and knowledge.&quot; It also asserted the company’s panels were plagued by visible defects. That same year, the Tesla solar panels at an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-24-bloomberg-tesla-solar-panel-amazon-fire.html"><ins>Amazon warehouse</ins></a> in California reportedly caught fire as well.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sec-tesla-investigation-solar-panels-211402848.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4cac06e1-671b-4455-8d57-ae42838023ac</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 21:14:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638825246</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T21:14:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/24bc07f0-56d8-11ec-a1ff-d55e983b28b8" width="4032" height="2268" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/24bc07f0-56d8-11ec-a1ff-d55e983b28b8" width="4032" height="2268" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Frandino / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Steven Henkes, a former Tesla and Toyota employee who complained to the SEC in 2019 that Tesla failed to properly notify shareholders and consumers of fire risks of its solar panel systems, is seen during an interview in San Francisco, California, U.S. on December 1, 2021. Picture taken December 1, 2021. REUTERS/Nathan Frandino]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TESLA-SOLAR/SEC]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Toyota will build its $1.29 billion battery plant in North Carolina]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Toyota has <a href="https://pressroom.toyota.com/toyota-selects-north-carolina-greensboro-randolph-site-for-new-u-s-automotive-battery-plant/">selected a site</a> for its proposed $1.29 billion US battery manufacturing facility. On Monday, the automaker said it would build the plant on the Greensboro-Randolph Megasite, a tract of land located in Randolph County in central North Carolina. When the facility is complete sometime in 2025, it will consist of four production lines, each capable of producing batteries for 200,000 vehicles per year. Toyota plans to eventually expand the facility to produce enough power cells to support up to 1.2 million cars annually.</p><p>The plant is part of a broader <a href="https://www.engadget.com/toyota-us-battery-investment-155141624.html">$3.4 billion investment</a> the automaker has earmarked to expand its battery production capabilities in the US. When Toyota first announced the $1.29 billion facility, it said it would create approximately 1,750 jobs. The company notes it picked Greensboro-Randolph Megasite for a handful of reasons. One of the more notable ones is that it’s a location with access to renewable energy. Toyota says it’s “committed” to using 100 percent clean energy to produce batteries at the facility.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The scale of the project is an acknowledgment by the automaker that it needs to diversify its electrification strategy. More so than any other automaker, Toyota invested significantly into fuel cell technology. So far, it has little to show for its efforts. Outside of California, you can’t buy its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/toyota-mirai-2021-video-130028882.html">Mirai fuel-cell sedan</a>. However, the company’s latest plan is to offer 70 different electric models, including 15 battery electric vehicles, by 2025.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/toyota-greensboro-randolph-megasite-ev-annoucement-202448241.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">550cdfed-93be-4666-87a7-1e02cd4f9d01</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 20:24:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638885605</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T14:00:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Renewable Energy & Energy Saving]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a6f12d60-56d1-11ec-bbdf-481103bc4cd6" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a6f12d60-56d1-11ec-bbdf-481103bc4cd6" width="1600" height="1001" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Toyota]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Toyota PHEV]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Toyota PHEV]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[DoorDash tests 15-minute grocery deliveries in New York City]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/doordash/"><ins>DoorDash</ins></a> is <a href="https://ir.doordash.com/news/news-details/2021/DoorDash-Introduces-Ultra-Fast-Grocery-Delivery-Providing-Busy-Consumers-with-a-Reliable-and-Convenient-Way-to-Restock-Instantly/default.aspx"><ins>piloting</ins></a> an ultra-fast grocery delivery service in Manhattan, with the goal of delivering items to customers in less than 15 minutes. The service will initially be available at a new DashMart outlet in Chelsea, and DoorDash plans to expand ultra-fast deliveries to more locations and partners over the coming months.</p><p>The company opened its first DashMarts last year to provide a central location for shoppers to find fresh and frozen groceries, household items and goods from local merchants. The company says DashMart offers more than 2,000 items. The Chelsea location will be open between 7AM and 2AM for orders within a small radius, and excess produce will be donated to a local food bank.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition, DoorDash notes that the ultra-fast service will require a different operating model than its typical approach of using gig workers to fulfill orders. A team of full-time employees will <a href="https://doordash.news/2021/12/06/introducing-ultra-fast-deliveries-with-doordash/"><ins>handle those deliveries</ins></a>. The company says the workers will be on regular schedules, have wages starting at $15/hour plus tips and receive benefits.&nbsp;</p><p>The company says 90 percent of its couriers (or Dashers) in the US want to stay as contractors and have greater flexibility over their schedule. DoorDash has been at odds with the city and other jurisdictions, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/california-voters-reaffirm-that-uber-drivers-are-indeed-employees-091216147.html"><ins>including California</ins></a>, on worker classification and other fronts. NYC lawmakers passed a series of bills in September that, among other things, set <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/sep/23/gig-economy-doordash-grubhub-food-delivery"><ins>minimum pay</ins></a> for gig economy and food delivery workers. In addition, DoorDash, along with Uber Eats and Grubhub, recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uber-eats-door-dash-grubhub-new-york-city-lawsuit-restaurant-fees-182342368.html"><ins>sued New York City</ins></a> over limits on the delivery fees they&#39;re allowed to charge restaurants.</p><p>DoorDash will be competing against other companies that offer ultra-fast deliveries in the city, including Gorillas, Buyk, Gopuff and Jokr. However, it&#39;s a well-known brand that could potentially carve out a significant slice of the market.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/doordash-15-minute-grocery-delivery-nyc-ultra-fast-200711153.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5f270e63-4ab9-4130-a56a-c6433bda16a7</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 20:07:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638821235</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T20:07:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa51ba50-56cd-11ec-bae9-ebf17b2cd311" width="1024" height="683" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/aa51ba50-56cd-11ec-bae9-ebf17b2cd311" width="1024" height="683" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A DoorDash courier (or Dasher) holding a phone as they look into the distance on a city street.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firefox 95 enhances the browser's protection against malicious code]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mozilla is introducing a new security feature it claims will make Firefox the most secure browser available to consumers. Dubbed <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/12/webassembly-and-back-again-fine-grained-sandboxing-in-firefox-95/"><ins>RLBox</ins></a> and available through today&#39;s Firefox 95 update, it’s a new sandboxing tool the company developed in collaboration with the University of California San Diego and the University of Texas.</p><p>All modern browsers use sandboxing to protect users against malicious code. The problem is that many of the most advanced exploits chain together two vulnerabilities to bypass those protections. With RLBox, Firefox will compile a process into <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-03-07-mozilla-video-games-browser.html">WebAssembly</a> and then convert it into native code. According to Mozilla, this approach presents two significant advantages. It prevents code from jumping between different parts of a program and limits access to specific areas of your system’s memory.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>With today’s release, Mozilla will use RLBox to isolate five components of Firefox, including the browser’s Graphite font rendering engine and Ogg multimedia module. If the system works as expected, the company says “even a zero-day vulnerability in any of [the five components] should pose no threat to Firefox.”</p><p>Mozilla is quick to note it won’t be able to use RLBox to protect every component of Firefox. For instance, it’s not suitable for modules that depend on sharing memory with the rest of the program to function. However, the company is hopeful that other developers will use the technology to make their software safer. In the meantime, RLBox is now rolling out to all desktop and mobile versions of Firefox.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-firefox-95-rlbox-190712215.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eea547a2-2579-4ffe-b97a-fde0572cabaf</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 19:07:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638817636</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T19:07:31+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/656fe1a0-c316-11eb-bcd9-f4beb9fb4f38" width="1600" height="894" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/656fe1a0-c316-11eb-bcd9-f4beb9fb4f38" width="1600" height="894" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Firefox]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Firefox]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[YouTube says most disputed copyright claims are resolved in the uploader's favor]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/youtube/">YouTube</a> is <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/access-all-balanced-ecosystem-and-powerful-tools/">shedding more light</a> on the tidal wave of copyright claims it receives in its first copyright transparency report. It <a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/transparencyreport/report-downloads/pdf-report-22_2021-1-1_2021-6-30_en_GB_v1.pdf">notes</a> that more than 2.2 million (around 60 percent) of disputed claims were resolved in favor of the uploader, versus just under 1.5 million in the claimant&#39;s favor.</p><p>Over 99 percent (722.7 million) of all copyright claims between January and June emerged through <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/content%20id/">Content ID</a>, which automatically monitors YouTube for potential copyright issues. Only 0.5 percent of these were disputed.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Other copyright claims were submitted via webforms and the Copyright Match tool. YouTube says claims that are filed manually are twice as likely to be disputed than automated ones. That indicates creators are perhaps more reluctant to appeal against Content ID claims, even though most disputes are resolved in their favor.</p><p>Copyright owners can opt to have a video that&#39;s deemed to violate their rights deleted, track viewership stats and/or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-07-google-anti-piracy-report.html">receive revenue</a> it generates. Earlier this year, YouTube started offering creators a way to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-copyright-check-video-upload-144103931.html">check for potential copyright violations</a> when they upload a video. The platform offers creators a way to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-26-youtube-creators-address-copyright-claims.html">remove sections of a video</a> that cause issues.</p><p>YouTubers have long criticized how the platform handles copyright claims, as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820318/youtube-copyright-claims-transparency-report"><em>The Verge</em></a> notes. They can lose money or even face having their channel banned as a result of claims, many of which are evidently incorrect. While the report provides more insight into how big an issue copyright claims are, YouTube acknowledges &quot;no system is perfect&quot; and that it&#39;s &quot;impossible for matching technology to take into account complex legal considerations like fair use or fair dealing.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/youtube-copyright-transparency-report-184854080.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4e23afc7-1c06-4838-80a5-b2216da53d8e</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:48:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638821228</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T20:07:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/fcc598b0-f87d-11ea-bffe-d777cf82d89a" width="5032" height="3367" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/fcc598b0-f87d-11ea-bffe-d777cf82d89a" width="5032" height="3367" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Toby Melville / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[YouTube signage is seen at their offices in King's Cross, London, Britain, September 11, 2020. REUTERS/Toby Melville]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[BRITAIN-ECONOMY/YOUTUBE]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ford's Mustang Mach-E is coming to 'Rocket League' this week]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Psyonix is bringing a couple more Ford vehicles to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Rocket%20League/"><em>Rocket League</em></a> this week, and whether players are more interested in brand-new cars or classics, there should be something to catch their interest. On December 9th, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fords-mach-e-is-a-stylish-and-capable-ev-but-its-no-mustang-153044259.html">Ford Mustang Mach-E EV</a> will land in the Item Shop. Perhaps to underscore that this is an electric vehicle, you&#39;ll see a visual lightning effect when it goes supersonic.</p><div id="3396aa42cd284efcb5f88567c5c15b15"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A-zMRYU0Tdc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Joining the Mach-E in the store this week is the classic 1965 Ford Mustang Shelby GT350R. Each car is part of a bundle that includes themed decals, wheels, a player banner and engine audio. You can buy each bundle for 1,100 Credits or both for 2,000 Credits. The bundles will be available until December 22nd.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The addition of the Mach-E and GT350R builds on the partnership between Psyonix and Ford. The F-150 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rocket-league-ford-f-150-185000327.html">arrived in the game</a> earlier this year. The automaker is also sponsoring the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/rocket-league-championship-series-global-esport-asia-africa-psyonix-193600199.html">Rocket League Championship Series</a> Fall Major, an in-person tournament that takes place in Stockholm this week.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rocket-league-ford-mustang-mach-e-ev-shelby-gt-350-r-180040475.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5768c8ea-9874-488e-84e0-3004a1318f24</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:00:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638815578</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T18:33:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ed3c2af0-56b7-11ec-b1f2-cc9c864f0d77" width="4000" height="2250" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ed3c2af0-56b7-11ec-b1f2-cc9c864f0d77" width="4000" height="2250" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Psyonix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Ford Mustang Mach-E EV in Rocket League.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ford Mustang Mach-E EV in Rocket League]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook Gaming streamers and viewers can play 'Pac-Man' together]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/facebook%20gaming/"><ins>Facebook Gaming</ins></a> is about to become more interactive. Two features are rolling out today that should help creators and their fans seamlessly play games together, and give viewers other ways to get involved with streams.</p><p>Play With Streamer is self-explanatory. There will be a button on livestreams that lets viewers play <em>Pac-Man Community </em>(a version of <em>Pac-Man</em> developed in partnership with Genvid and Bandai Namco) with streamers and other community members. <em>Pac-Man Community </em>includes a four-player co-op mode, a mobile-optimized maze creator, rankings and community challenges.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Facebook Interactives, meanwhile, are interactive layers viewers will see on top of livestreams. When <em>Pac-Man Community</em>&#39;s Watch Mode is enabled, they can help or hamper an AI-controlled Pac-Man or the ghosts through the in-game video player. Facebook says these features form some of the first steps of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-connect-metaverse-zuckerberg-171507437.html">its vision for the metaverse</a>.</p><p>Other platforms have long had ways for players to interact directly with streams. On Twitch, viewers can control <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-02-22-twitch-plays-pokemon-its-history-highlights-and-bird-jesus.html"><em><ins>Pokémon</ins></em></a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/directory/game/Twitch%20Plays"><ins>other games</ins></a> by entering commands in the chat. There are also extensions that let viewers <a href="https://crowdcontrol.live/"><ins>impact the game</ins></a> the streamer is playing by, for instance, granting them extra items or even instantly killing their character. With Stadia&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-stadia-is-now-rolling-out-direct-you-tube-streaming-100047706.html"><ins>Crowd Play feature</ins></a>, viewers can play with a streamer who&#39;s broadcasting their gameplay on YouTube, as long as they also own the game and have <a href="https://support.google.com/stadia/answer/9824891"><ins>a sufficient setup</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-gaming-interactive-play-together-pac-man-180031115.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f8ea92e7-c570-4462-bb4f-068460ab035c</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:00:31 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1637956484</ingested><modified>2021-12-07T05:47:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5412d280-4ef0-11ec-b7c7-325feb3d3339" width="5056" height="3371" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/5412d280-4ef0-11ec-b7c7-325feb3d3339" width="5056" height="3371" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mike Blake / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Facebook Gaming logo is shown at E3, the annual video games expo revealing the latest in gaming software and hardware in Los Angeles, California, U.S., June 12, 2019.  REUTERS/Mike Blake]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GAMING-E3/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google TV makes it easier to watch free, live streaming channels]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/google%20tv/">Google TV</a> is placing a bigger focus on things users can watch for free. The platform has teamed up with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/pluto%20tv/">Pluto TV</a> to highlight more than 300 ad-supported channels folks in the US can check out through the Live tab. Free live TV recommendations will also appear in the For You tab. The Pluto TV integration is coming to all Google TV devices in the coming weeks.</p><p>There are other ways users can find free stuff to watch on Google TV. In the YouTube app&#39;s Movies &amp; Shows tab, for instance, they can find thousands of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-17-youtube-free-movies.html">ad-supported movies</a> to watch. The platform&#39;s Apps tab, meanwhile, includes a row of Free Movies &amp; TV apps to download, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/tubi/">Tubi</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-25-comcast-acquires-xumo.html">Xumo</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>What&#39;s more, for a limited time, those who activate a Google TV or Android TV OS device in the US will get six months of access to Peacock Premium at no extra cost. Peacock Premium usually costs $5/month and, along with ad-free viewing, it includes much more content than the free tier, such as Peacock Originals, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nbc-sports-premier-league-deal-expansion-222712283.html">a ton of live sports</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/wwe-network-peacock-exclusive-streaming-us-155406623.html">a host of WWE content</a>. Google noted it will offer more ways for TV users to watch shows, movies and other content for free in 2022 as well.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-tv-pluto-tv-live-channels-180025973.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">60dbe07c-9551-4440-beaf-f48adf3b35e0</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:00:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638816182</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T18:43:17+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a94b4370-56a4-11ec-9e7f-3b5fd75c5254" width="937" height="527" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a94b4370-56a4-11ec-9e7f-3b5fd75c5254" width="937" height="527" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Pluto TV channels on Google TV]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Pluto TV channels on Google TV]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Pixel update delivers time-saving improvements on new and older models]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has rolled out a number of updates that will help owners of both older Pixel and the latest Pixel 6 devices. To start with, the Pixel 6 Pro is getting UWB (Ultra-wideband) capability, letting you quickly share photos and other files using the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-android-nearby-share-specs-availability-160054637.html">Nearby Share</a> function. As we mentioned earlier, Pixel 6 and 6 Pro users will also get the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-12-digital-car-keys-assistant-widgets-photos-youtube-music-170006763.html">digital car key</a> function that lets you unlock and start select BMW models.&nbsp;</p><p>Other features will appeal to a wider group. The Quick Tap to Snap feature lets Pixel 4a 5G and higher users access Snapchat directly from their lock screens by double tapping the back of the phones, to start with. Until now, the feature has only been available on the Pixel 6.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Pixel 3 or newer smartphones, meanwhile, will now be able to adjust how long they hold the power button to activate Google Assistant. This feature makes it possible to avoid activating the Assistant by mistake when you&#39;re just trying to, say, turn off the phone. Another key feature for Pixel 3 (and up) owners is the Bass Slider that allows you to double the bass range available for Pixel Buds A-series earphones, now from -1 to +4.</p><p>Google is expanding car crash detection to Taiwan, Italy and France, letting you automatically send your location and details to emergency responders when a car crash is detected. It&#39;s also added the &quot;Now Playing&quot; feature that lets you detect a song and quickly add it to your favorites. Finally, Google has added new languages, including Japanese, French and German, that can be transcribed in the recorder app. All of these features are now rolling out to Pixel devices.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/googles-pixel-6-can-now-be-used-to-unlock-bmw-vehicles-180000062.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">51410a4c-0596-41f6-bf3f-653247bcc9d6</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1638789763</ingested><modified>2021-12-06T11:22:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/670ce460-5685-11ec-bd1d-014fea2f6631" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/670ce460-5685-11ec-bd1d-014fea2f6631" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google update delivers time-saving improvements for Pixel devices]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google update delivers time-saving improvements for Pixel devices]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>