<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 12:50:37 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[GOG's store adds six classic 'Star Trek' games]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;re a fan of classic <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-04-18-why-i-play-star-trek-online.html"><em>Star Trek games,</em></a> GOG has some new offerings that may grab your attention. The site now offers no less than <a href="https://adtr.co/AnXANB">six new titles</a> in its store: <em>Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</em> (2000), <em>Star Trek: Elite Force II</em> (2003), <em>Star Trek: Bridge Commander</em> (2002), <em>Star Trek: Starfleet command III</em> (2002), <em>Star Trek: Hidden Evil</em> (1999) and <em>Star Trek: Away Team</em> (2001). On top of that, GOG will soon add another two games, <em>Star Trek: Armada</em> and <em>Star Trek: Armada II</em>.</p><p>The additions help mark the 55th anniversary of the original show, along with the 100th birthday of the late Gene Roddenberry, GOG wrote. As it noted, the first text-based <em>Star Trek</em> computer games first appeared in 1971, &quot;with many official and even more unofficial releases appearing in arcades, on Apple I and II computers, various models of Atari, the Commodore 64 and all the way to DOS and Windows PCs&quot; — a testament to the staying power of the franchise.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="7288e031d70645dc896093360af796cd"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s time to boldly go where no man has gone before! 🌌<br><br>Grab Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force, Elite Force II, Star Trek: Bridge Commander, Star Trek: Starfleet Command III and more!<br><br>🖖 <a href="https://t.co/LkhGb8Qf1o">https://t.co/LkhGb8Qf1o</a><a href="https://t.co/CfGbGSpoqi">pic.twitter.com/CfGbGSpoqi</a></p>— GOG.COM (@GOGcom) <a href="https://twitter.com/GOGcom/status/1435546972140748800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>So how do these games rank in the <em>Star Trek</em> pantheon? Games like <em>Star Trek: 25th Anniversary</em> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-11-22-the-game-archaeologist-perpetuals-star-trek-online.html"><em>Star Trek: Online</em></a> are perhaps better known, to be sure. But as <a href="https://www.gog.com/news/6_classic_star_trek_games_ready_to_beam_up_new_players_and_fans_alike">GOG writes</a>, &quot;an absolute golden era of Star Trek games began at the end of the ’90s and the beginning of the 2000s with new games landing every few months.&quot;</p><p>Particularly, <em>Star Trek: Voyager - Elite Force</em> and <em>Star Trek: Bridge Commander</em> are considered to be some of the best <em>Star Trek</em> titles out there, as <a href="https://screenrant.com/best-star-trek-video-games-ranked/"><em>Screen Rant</em></a> notes. Many of those titles have become unavailable and are unplayable on modern machines, as well. &quot;This changes now with [these games] releasing for the first time in digital distribution,&quot; GOG said.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gog-now-lets-you-play-six-classic-star-trek-games-125037822.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c2e14c92-fdef-44d2-be48-8b462ffa83f5</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 12:50:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631105350</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T12:49:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/0d8a65d0-1098-11ec-afb4-3be5304415a9" width="1228" height="756" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/0d8a65d0-1098-11ec-afb4-3be5304415a9" width="1228" height="756" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[gigan85]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[GOG's store adds six classic 'Star Trek' games]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GOG's store adds six classic 'Star Trek' games]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify opens up Release Radar for brand sponsorships, starting with Disney+]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-08-05-spotifys-release-radar-playlist-new-music.html">Release Radar</a> is one of the most popular algorithmically generated playlists on Spotify, and for good reason. The mix is updated weekly with a collection of new material from the artists you listen to often. The playlist has been keeping users in the loop for five years at this point, and now the streaming service is <a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-09-08/spotifys-release-radar-personalized-playlist-celebrates-five-years-and-16-billion-streams/">opening it up to advertisers</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>This is actually the third playlist Spotify has offered up for ads, joining <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-07-spotify-discover-weekly-brand-sponsorship.html">Discover Weekly</a> and On Repeat as potential sponsorship opportunities for brands. With Release Radar, Disney+ will be the first to jump on board in the US, promoting its Billie Eilish film <em>Happier Than Ever: A Love Letter To Los Angeles</em>. Spotify says free users will see ads in the form of audio, video and graphics and direct them to the playlist. Once inside, logos will appear on the playlist art along with messages from the sponsor at each ad break (audio and video). Along with music-focused advertisements, you&#39;ll likely see sponsorships from gaming, automotive, fashion and tech brands as well as phone service providers. However, Spotify explains the opportunity is open to all companies, not just those that fit in the aforementioned categories. As always, Premium users won&#39;t see, or hear, any of the sponsored content.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Release Radar has a captive audience. The playlist has been streamed over 16 billion times globally since its launch in 2016. It&#39;s a a top-three personalized playlist for Spotify users in several regions, including North America, Latin America, Europe, the Middle East, Africa and Asia. Most listeners are 18-29 year olds, and Spotify says that group accounts for over 50 percent of Release Radar streaming.&nbsp;</p><p>Free users in the US should be seeing the Disney+ sponsorship on Release Radar soon, if you haven&#39;t already. If you stream on the ad-supported tier outside of the States, sponsored messages will appear for you as well: the playlist is available for brands to advertise in 31 markets around the world.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spotify-release-radar-ads-120051401.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7bd2c30e-4a34-4cce-aef6-c1a44ed46cee</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631044513</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T19:55:16+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/082f24f0-0fd9-11ec-af7e-61a9ea3dedfd" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/082f24f0-0fd9-11ec-af7e-61a9ea3dedfd" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Spotify]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Spotify Release Radar]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Spotify Release Radar]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snapchat makes it easier to track and celebrate friends' birthdays]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snap is introducing a fun new way for Snapchat users to track and celebrate the birthdays of their friends. The company’s new Birthday Mini gives you one place to see a list of all the upcoming birthdays of people you follow on the app. You can either see them organized by how soon they’re coming up or by zodiac signs. The tool comes courtesy of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-mini-apps-174530579.html">Minis</a> functionality Snap introduced last summer. And as with all other Minis, you can find this one by tapping the rocket icon in Snapchat or by searching for it individually.</p><p>For privacy reasons, the Mini won’t display the birth year of your friend nor their exact age. Similarly, other Snapchat users won’t see that same information about you. You also won’t see the birthdays of friends who haven’t consented to display them in the app.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Birthday Mini is the first one to include lens sharing, a feature that allows you to unlock special themed lenses you can send as snaps to your friends or include in your stories. When someone sees them in those contexts, they can swipe up to join the Mini. It’s a small feature addition, to be sure, but one that makes keeping track of everyone’s special day easier. Previously, Snap would indicate your friend was celebrating their birthday through an emoji in your friends feed.  You can access the Birthday Mini starting today.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/snapchat-birthday-mini-120015292.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fd1ce68a-2f67-47f4-81cf-2d6d70be39ae</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631097541</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T10:39:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/efa461a0-1048-11ec-b5b7-a24d8495cbfe" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/efa461a0-1048-11ec-b5b7-a24d8495cbfe" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Snap]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Snapchat Birthday Mini]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Snapchat Birthday Mini]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Apple’s next iPhone event is next week]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought BMW’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bm-ws-recyclable-i-vision-cirulcar-concept-has-a-very-weird-crystal-interface-085205690.html">bizarre crystal sculpture car dash</a> was going to be the weirdest vehicle of the week, but Hyundai thought otherwise. Not only does it involve next-gen fuel cell technology — a car fuel system that’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-12-23-hydrogen-fuel-cell-explainer.html">struggled</a> in the face of EVs — but it also introduces Trailer Drone to the world. This cab-less &quot;hydrogen-powered container transportation system” can apparently function entirely autonomously, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyundais-hydrogen-vision-2040-includes-trailer-drones-and-a-670-hp-hybrid-sports-car-085744900.html">according to Hyundai.</a></p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyundais-hydrogen-vision-2040-includes-trailer-drones-and-a-670-hp-hybrid-sports-car-085744900.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/16c0be10-1093-11ec-afe7-3145fdc32d36" alt="Morning After" data-uuid="c6b223b9-ea5f-3d2a-ad8a-1bd324fc2c83"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Hyundai</div></figure></a><p>On arrival, the trailer could automatically unload itself by lifting on to legs, yes like a real-life Transformer, while the e-Bogie driving frame below dashes off to its next task. And yet, I think betting on hydrogen fuel cell tech still seems the most outlandish part, at least right now.</p><p>— Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-event-2021-date-161123048.html">It’s time for the next iPhone event</a></h2><h3>September 14th.</h3><h3></h3><p>Apple has announced a &quot;California Streaming&quot; event on September 14th at 1 PM ET. The invitation doesn&#39;t offer many clues, but there are already plenty of rumors about what you can expect for the new iPhone, updated Apple Watch. Those have so far included a smaller notch, an always-on display and improved cameras across the line. We might also get new ultra-wide sensors and more camera stabilization. It would include the seemingly obligatory chip upgrade and a slightly larger battery. That last one would be music to my ears.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-13-event-2021-date-161123048.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-references-new-iphone-models-magsafe-fcc-filing-100602419.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Four new iPhones are on their way, according to FCC filing</a></h2><h3>Interesting.</h3><p></p><p>An FCC filing for a revised MagSafe charger, spotted by <em>MacRumors </em>and <em>9to5Mac</em>, suggests  four &quot;New Phone&quot; items will work with it, alongside last year’s iPhone 12 family.</p><p>Unfortunately, this FCC filing doesn&#39;t identify the four &quot;New Phone&quot; items it used for testing, but it&#39;s very much possible they&#39;re the current generation&#39;s direct successors, meaning the iPhone mini — my favorite — gets another shot at glory.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-references-new-iphone-models-magsafe-fcc-filing-100602419.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/impossible-chicken-nuggets-130035016.html">Impossible&#39;s plant-based nuggets are now available in select restaurants</a></h2><h3>It&#39;ll be in a few restaurants this week and in grocery stores later this month.</h3><h3></h3><p>Impossible Foods’ plant-based “chicken” nuggets are now available to buy and gorge on. Mostly made of soy protein and sunflower oil, the Impossible Chicken Nuggets will initially be available in select restaurants across the country, and then sold in grocery stores in the frozen aisle later this month.</p><p>Notable restaurants that will be serving them include David Chang’s Fuku in New York City, Marcus Samuelsson’s Red Rooster in Harlem and Miami, Sean Brock’s Joyland in Nashville, Tal Ronnen’s Crossroads Kitchen in Los Angeles.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/impossible-chicken-nuggets-130035016.html"><strong>Read our taste test here.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-4-resurrections-teaser-website-180059094.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">&#39;The Matrix Resurrections&#39; teasers keep changing with different clips from the film</a></h2><h3>It’s like a trailer, but on shuffle.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-4-resurrections-teaser-website-180059094.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e7e8b520-1092-11ec-81d7-6c8ce36a0902" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="d648fe73-571b-36c0-aa68-b1956fb3e715"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Warner Bros.</div></figure></a><p>Ahead of September 9th, when the first full trailer for <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em> is set to appear, Warner Bros. has launched a teaser for the upcoming film. The website, <a href="https://thechoiceisyours.whatisthematrix.com/">whatisthematrix.com</a>, offers a first look at Neo&#39;s latest adventure.</p><p>In a call back to the first film, you&#39;ll see a red and blue pill on the screen when you first visit the website. Each offers a different narration of several cuts from the movie. But, refresh the site and you get a different barrage of clips and cuts. Time to start sleuthing.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-4-resurrections-teaser-website-180059094.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/xpeng-robot-unicorn-193029853.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Don’t you want a rideable robot unicorn?</a></h2><h3>Just like a unicorn, it doesn&#39;t exist. Yet.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/xpeng-robot-unicorn-193029853.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e7ceeb90-1092-11ec-abef-fec2ec96437a" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="749924a1-e32d-3bc8-875f-a048823868cb"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Xpeng</div></figure></a><p>Chinese EV maker Xpeng has teased a robot unicorn for children to ride. As <em>SCMP </em>notes, the quadruped will take advantage of Xpeng&#39;s experience with autonomous driving and other AI tasks to navigate multiple terrain types, recognize objects and provide &quot;emotional interaction.&quot;</p><p>The company is shy on most other details, but the design looks and trots like a cuter, more kid-friendly version of Boston Robotics&#39; Spot. It&#39;s about as tall as a child, which I read as meaning I won’t be able to ride it.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/xpeng-robot-unicorn-193029853.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><h3></h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/bose-smart-soundbar-900-dolby-atmos-spatial-audio-144433233.html">Bose&#39;s high-end Smart Soundbar 900 includes Dolby Atmos support</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-air-64gb-wifi-drops-to-500-all-color-options-on-sale-with-coupon-131523018.html">Engadget Deals: Apple&#39;s iPad Air drops to $500 at Amazon</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/polestar-re-move-working-prototype-electric-cargo-sled-090000981.html">Polestar made a working version of its electric cargo sled</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/technics-1210-g-annoucement-172036404.html">Technics made a black version of its SL-1200 turntable you can actually buy</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-15-instant-pot-guide.html">How to make the most of that Instant Pot you just bought</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transparency-researchers-170021370.html">The fight to study what happens on Facebook</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-apples-new-i-phone-event-is-next-week-111549805.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1d0c731e-e8ba-4adc-bdc7-6df45cd16dbf</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:15:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631101922</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T11:52:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/20b3f9c0-0ff6-11ec-abfe-6046e483c270" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/20b3f9c0-0ff6-11ec-abfe-6046e483c270" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple 'California Streaming' iPhone 13 event]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple 'California Streaming' iPhone 13 event]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft issues Windows attack warning that uses malicious Office files]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Attackers are actively exploiting a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-start-personalized-news-feed-164505328.html">Microsoft</a> remote code execution vulnerability using malicious Office files, the tech giant has <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2021-40444">warned</a>. The vulnerability known as CVE-2021-40444 affects Windows Servers from version 2008 and Windows 7 through 10. What attackers are doing is sending potential victims an Office file and tricking them into opening it. That file automatically opens Internet Explorer to load the bad actor&#39;s web page, which has an ActiveX control that downloads malware onto the victim&#39;s computer.</p><p>Several security researchers reported the zero-day attacks to Microsoft. One of them, Haifei Li of EXPMON, told <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-shares-temp-fix-for-ongoing-office-365-zero-day-attacks/"><em>BleepingComputer</em></a> that the method is 100 percent reliable — all it would take to infect a system is for the victim to open the malicious file. In Li&#39;s case, the attack they came across used a .DOCX document. Microsoft has yet to roll out a security patch for the vulnerability, but it has published mitigation methods to prevent infection.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The tech giant says Microsoft Defender Antivirus and Microsoft Defender for Endpoint can both detect the vulnerability and prevent infection, so users need to keep them updated and running. Further, it advises disabling all ActiveX controls in Internet Explorer to render it inactive for all websites. Microsoft&#39;s security warning contains information how to do that, which involves updating IE&#39;s registry and rebooting the computer.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-windows-vulnerability-malicious-office-files-105010735.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">429ed859-0af8-4194-98d8-45f8fbe15426</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:50:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631100558</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T11:29:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/8143a120-1094-11ec-9fd1-0997b068eeb7" width="4208" height="2567" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/8143a120-1094-11ec-9fd1-0997b068eeb7" width="4208" height="2567" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Shannon Stapleton / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Microsoft logo is seen at a pop-up site for the new Windows 10 operating system at Roosevelt Field in Garden City, New York July 29, 2015. Microsoft Corp's launch of its first new operating system in almost three years, designed to work across laptops, desktop and smartphones, won mostly positive reviews for its user-friendly and feature-packed interface.REUTERS/Shannon Stapleton]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[MICROSOFT-LAUNCH/WINDOWS-10]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon's cashierless 'Just Walk Out' tech is coming to Whole Foods stores]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After launching it in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-12-05-amazon-go-grocery-store.html">Go stores</a> and then bringing it to larger <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fresh-just-walk-out-technology-washington-114044465.html">Fresh</a> supermarkets, Amazon&#39;s cashierless &quot;Just Walk Out&quot; tech will soon arrive in two Whole Foods locations. The service, which lets you pick up goods from shelves and (yep) just walk out, is coming to new stores in Washington DC and Sherman Oaks, California next year, the company <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/whole-foods-market-to-launch-just-walk-out-technology-at-two-locations">announced</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;By collaborating with Amazon to introduce Just Walk Out shopping at these two Whole Foods Market stores, our customers will be able to... save time by skipping the checkout line,&quot; said Whole Foods co-founder John Mackey.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As we&#39;ve detailed <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-12-05-amazon-go-grocery-store.html">previously</a>, Just Walk Out uses computer vision, sensors and AI to let you walk into a store, sign in with an app, fill up your bags and leave without the need to join a checkout line. On top of using the tech in its own Go and Fresh stores, Amazon signed a deal <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-09-amazon-checkout-free-technology-business-just-walk-out.html">last year</a> to license its technology to third-party retailers.&nbsp;</p><p>The technology will work the same at Whole Foods, which is owned by Amazon. Shoppers can opt to use the tech when they enter the store by scanning an app, inserting a debit card linked to their Amazon account, or by placing their palm over the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-adds-its-contactless-palmreading-one-tech-to-more-go-stores-103800363.html">Amazon One</a> palm-scanning system.&nbsp;</p><p>Unions have <a href="https://www.ufcw.org/press-releases/ufcw-amazon-grocery-expansion-with-cashierless-technology-threatens-good-paying-jobs-of-essential-workers/">proclaimed</a> that Amazon&#39;s cashierless tech will cost workers jobs, but Amazon said the new Whole Foods locations will &quot;employ a comparable number of team members as existing Whole Foods stores of similar sizes.&quot; Rather, employees will be able to &quot;spend even more time interacting with customers and delivering a great shopping experience,&quot; Amazon said in a press release.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazons-just-walk-out-tech-comes-to-two-whole-foods-stores-101036042.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fbd5b17a-6b39-47e8-8160-b67b2a9619eb</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:10:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631104783</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T12:39:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/002ce600-1085-11ec-bbea-ce112211791d" width="1320" height="743" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/002ce600-1085-11ec-bbea-ce112211791d" width="1320" height="743" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon's 'Just Walk Out' cashierless tech comes to two Whole Foods stores]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon's 'Just Walk Out' cashierless tech comes to two Whole Foods stores]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[LG claims its new 'Real Folding Window' display material is as hard as glass]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review-s-pen-camera-battery-test-190051606.html">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">Z Flip 3</a> devices did very well in their home country, and market research groups like <a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/foldable-smartphone-shipments-2023/">Counterpoint</a> believe foldable shipments are bound to grow in the coming years. Foldable devices might soon no longer be niche products, and LG has developed a new material that could help make that a reality. LG Chem has <a href="https://www.lgchem.com/company/information-center/press-release/news-detail-8713?lang=en_GLOBAL">designed</a> a new type of cover window — that is, the outermost pre-installed part of displays protecting them from impact — that it says is as hard as glass while also having the capability to prevent fold impressions on the connecting part of a device.&nbsp;</p><p>The company calls the material &quot;Real Folding Window,&quot; and it&#39;s made of PET film coated on both sides with a new coating technology it developed. A spokesperson explained: &quot;Unlike existing polyimide films and tempered glass-type materials, the cover window that applied LG Chem&#39;s new coating technologies will maximize flexibility, while also providing optimized solutions for foldable phones such as making improvements to chronic issues like fold impressions on the connecting part of the screen.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition, the Real Folding Window can be folded both outwards and inwards unlike current counterparts that are optimized to be bent one way. LG Chem says it&#39;s thinner than tempered glass, is priced competitively and has been tested to be able to endure being folded over 200,000 times.&nbsp;</p><p>While the coating on both sides is only a few micrometers thick, the company is developing another type of Real Folding Window that doesn&#39;t use PET film. The idea is to create a very thin cover window for use in devices like foldable phones and rollable displays. LG Chem is planning to start mass producing the Real Folding Window in 2022 and to start selling them the year after that.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lg-real-folding-window-foldable-display-material-093502085.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9404c108-31ac-4bc5-b8bf-1aa6f9a7566c</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 09:35:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631104867</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T12:41:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/fc656240-107a-11ec-97fb-00baa49f010f" width="850" height="546" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/fc656240-107a-11ec-97fb-00baa49f010f" width="850" height="546" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LG]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG Real Folding Window]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG Real Folding Window]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HBO Max arrives in Europe on October 26th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-app-vizio-smartcast-tv-191121848.html">HBO Max</a> is heading to Europe. Back in June, the streaming service finally became available outside the US when it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-expands-to-39-new-territories-082604619.html">expanded</a> to 39 territories across Latin America and the Caribbean. Now, the WarnerMedia-owned platform is making its debut in Europe on October 26th, starting with six countries in particular:  Sweden, Denmark, Norway, Finland, Spain and Andorra.&nbsp;</p><p>As part of the service&#39;s phased rollout, 14 other European regions will get access to it next year, namely Bosnia and Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Croatia, Czech Republic, Hungary, Moldova, Montenegro, North Macedonia, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Serbia, Slovakia and Slovenia. WarnerMedia is also planning more territory launches for 2022, though it didn&#39;t say whether it&#39;s making the streaming service available in more continents.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Johannes Larcher, Head of HBO Max International, said in a statement:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;This is a historic moment as HBO Max lands in Europe. WarnerMedia movies and series like Harry Potter, Game of Thrones and The Big Bang Theory are passionately consumed by fans all across Europe, and HBO Max has been created to provide them with the most intuitive and convenient viewing experience to watch these and a diverse range of other amazing titles.&quot;</p></blockquote><p>HBO Max typically offers two types of plans: Standard and Mobile. In the US, there&#39;s also an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-ad-supported-tier-launch-window-155756778.html">ad-supported</a> tier that costs $10 a month instead of $15. As always, its subscription prices in Europe will vary per region, though it will likely be around that much, as well. WarnerMedia will reveal more details, including the service&#39;s prices and content offering in Europe, at a virtual launch event in October.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hbo-max-europe-october-26th-090033191.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eef6ba40-c496-4ac2-9815-67912559fc75</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 09:00:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631086775</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T07:39:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/64150ca0-1072-11ec-9f1f-2218885d87ea" width="1584" height="1012" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/64150ca0-1072-11ec-9f1f-2218885d87ea" width="1584" height="1012" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[PayPal acquires buy now, pay later provider Paidy]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PayPal is continuing its push into buy-now-pay-later (BNPL) services with the acquisition of Japanese company Paidy for 300 billion yen ($2.7 billion), <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-08/paypal-to-acquire-japanese-unicorn-paidy-in-2-7-billion-deal"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> has reported. That represents its second largest acquisition to date after the $4 billion dollar purchase of online coupon aggregator <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-21-paypal-buys-money-saving-service-honey.html">Honey</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>BNPL services let users divide purchases into multiple payments with paying any interest. Instead, PayPal and other providers make money by charging fees to merchants when a consumer buys a product, much as credit card providers do. PayPal&#39;s move follows Jack Dorsey&#39;s Square much larger <a href="https://www.engadget.com/square-will-pay-29-billion-to-acquire-a-leading-buy-now-pay-later-company-083547010.html">acquisition</a> of Australian BNPL firm AfterPay for $29 billion.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Paidy differs from other BNPL firms in that it allows Japanese consumers to purchase items online and then pay them off in person at local convenience stores. PayPal doesn&#39;t currently offer a BNPL service in Japan, so the acquisition will help it break into that market.&nbsp;</p><p>“Paidy pioneered buy-now-pay-later solutions tailored to the Japanese market,” said PayPal Japan chief Peter Kenevan. “Combining Paidy’s brand, capabilities and talented team with PayPal’s expertise, resources and global scale will create a strong foundation to accelerate our momentum in this strategically important market.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pay-pal-acquires-buy-now-pay-later-provider-paidy-082228572.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">390b6054-b93e-4c85-9211-1b45c1e3dbce</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 08:22:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631089351</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T08:22:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Mergers, Acquisitions & Takeovers]]></category><category><![CDATA[Investment & Company Information]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/0b4b46e0-107a-11ec-bffd-3293f690ff03" width="3000" height="1997" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/0b4b46e0-107a-11ec-bffd-3293f690ff03" width="3000" height="1997" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Justin Sullivan via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SAN JOSE, CA - APRIL 09:  A sign is posted outside of the PayPal headquarters on April 9, 2018 in San Jose, California. PayPal is looking to offer basic banking services including Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. insurance for customer balances, a debit card and direct-deposit.  (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[PayPal Experiments With More Traditional Banking Services]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lenovo's IdeaPad Slim 7 Carbon is an ultralight laptop with an OLED display]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-legion-5-pro-review-2021-172935947.html">Lenovo</a> has announced a new lineup of PCs, tablets and monitors at Tech World 2021. The most notable of the bunch is the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:IdeaPad Slim 7 Carbon" href="https://bit.ly/3DZIlAQ">IdeaPad Slim 7 Carbon</a> — a 14-inch Windows 11 laptop that weighs 2.37 lbs and is equipped with an OLED display made by Samsung. As its name implies, the device&#39;s chassis is made of carbon fiber and magnesium alloy for lightness and strength. Its display has a QHD+ resolution and 16:10 aspect ratio, with features that include a 90Hz refresh rate, Dolby Vision and true black certification. Customers can also opt to get a touchscreen version that&#39;s strengthened with Gorilla Glass.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/1975a180-106a-11ec-bf6c-2c08f86ffcf2" alt="Lenovo" data-uuid="6b0b4286-e3f3-35b1-9a73-b19778ca9e06"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Lenovo</div></figure><p>The device is powered by AMD&#39;s Ryzen 7 5800U Series Mobile Processors (up to 8-core) with AMD Radeon Graphics, and customers can get the NVIDIA GeForce MX450 graphics card as an optional install. Buyers can also equip the laptop with up to 16GB of RAM and up to 1TB of SSD storage. Other features include up to 14.5 hours of battery life, WiFi 6 and built-in Alexa support with an Alexa Show experience. It will be available in Cloud Grey starting in October 2021 with prices starting at $1,290.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Another notable device in the brand&#39;s new lineup is the Chromebook Duet 5. It&#39;s a 2-in-1 laptop-tablet hybrid running Chrome OS with access to Google Play. The device has a laptop-grade keyboard that can be detached from its 13.3-inch OLED display and is powered by the Snapdragon 7c Gen 2 SoC. It comes with 256GB of SSD storage and up to 8GB of memory. The Duet 5 will also be available in October in Storm Grey or Abyss Blue for at least $430.</p><p>Those who prefer a larger laptop could get the ldeaPad Slim 7 Pro instead. It&#39;s a 16-inch Windows 11 laptop with a QHD IPS screen, powered by AMD&#39;s Ryzen 7 5800H Mobile Processors. The device can be equipped with NVIDIA&#39;s GeForce RTX 3050 Laptop GPU and can have up to 16GB of RAM and up to 1TB of SSD storage. It will be out in October for at least <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:$1,449" href="https://bit.ly/3DZIlAQ">$1,449</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-ideapad-slim-7-carbon-062515675.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2fbb8a38-5802-42c4-9775-be4b6bf8f179</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 06:25:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631103974</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T12:26:26+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c482fc70-1066-11ec-b6ef-3469cf804795" width="1600" height="978" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c482fc70-1066-11ec-b6ef-3469cf804795" width="1600" height="978" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft snaps up in-browser video editing software startup Clipchamp]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-start-personalized-news-feed-164505328.html">Microsoft&#39;s</a> latest acquisition could add an easy-to-use video editing experience to its software suite. The tech giant has purchased a startup called Clipchamp, which is known for its in-browser video creation and editing tool. In its <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/blog/2021/09/07/microsoft-acquires-clipchamp-to-empower-creators/">announcement</a>, Microsoft says Clipchamp&#39;s approach combines &quot;the simplicity of a web app with the ability to process video using the full computing power of a PC with graphics processing unit (GPU) acceleration,&quot; which is &quot;something that was formerly limited to traditional video applications.&quot;</p><p>Clipchamp specifically targets non-professionals and non-creatives — people who don&#39;t have or know how to use specialized software for videos, in other words. &quot;Our mission is to empower anyone to tell stories worth sharing and millions of people around the world... We will continue to make video creation even easier, more accessible and fun,&quot; company CEO Alexander Dreiling wrote in a <a href="https://clipchamp.com/en/blog/microsoft-acquires-clipchamp-to-empower-creators/">post</a> announcing the acquisition.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Neither party has disclosed the terms of their agreement, but as <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/07/microsoft-acquires-video-editing-software-start-up-clipchamp.html"><em>CNBC</em></a> notes, Clipchamp said in July that it has 17 million registered users with an adoption rate that&#39;s up 54 percent year over year. The service saw huge growth in 9:16 aspect ratio exports, in particular, which are commonly used for TikTok and Instagram or Facebook Stories. Microsoft was one of its clients before the acquisition, along with Google. While Microsoft has yet to announce how it will offer Clipchamp to its customers, it called the tool a &quot;natural fit&quot; for its cloud-powered productivity experiences in Microsoft 365. A spokesperson also told <em>CNBC</em> that the tech giant will eventually introduce a process to convert existing Clipchamp users to Microsoft subscribers.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-acquires-clipchamp-040823250.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">eab47aee-5e27-47bc-beae-06fd4a1bf6f2</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 04:08:23 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631074148</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T04:09:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mergers, Acquisitions & Takeovers]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/d27a0780-1055-11ec-b853-4863939064a7" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/d27a0780-1055-11ec-b853-4863939064a7" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Clipchamp]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Clipchamp]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Clipchamp]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The latest animated Pokémon movie is coming to Netflix on October 8th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After making its debut in Japan last year, the Pokémon franchise’s 23rd animated movie is <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/newest-animated-pokemon-movie-pokemon-the-movie-secrets-of-the-jungle-to"><ins>making its way to Netflix</ins></a>. Outside of Japan, China and Korea, <em>Pokémon the Movie: Secrets of the Jungle</em> will debut globally on the streaming platform on October 8th. The premiere will mark the film’s international debut.</p><div id="c28f66a53d644676846de26109ee16cd"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ByzhuRr8StU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The film is essentially Pokémon’s take on the tale of Tarzan. When Ash and Pikachu go to explore the forest of Okoya, they discover a boy named Koko. Thanks to an upbringing at the hands of a Pokémon named Dada Zarude, Koko believes he too is a Pokémon. Ash and Pikachu’s arrival in his forest home leads him to question everything he thought was true about his existence.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Ahead of the movie’s release, you can add Dada Zarude and a shiny Celebi to your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-13-pokemon-sword-and-shield.html"><em><ins>Pokémon Sword and Shield</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>roster by signing up for the <a href="https://zarude.pokemon.com/en-us/">Trainer’s Club</a> newsletter by September 25th. The Pokémon Company, Niantic and Netflix also plan a special Pokémon Go event tied to the film’s release. They promised to share more information on that front soon.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/pokemon-secrets-of-the-jungle-netflix-october-8-230042697.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">77906479-5947-465f-87fc-af3ceb2e264c</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631050839</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T21:40:41+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/b8484800-1022-11ec-bf9f-0f3d3de818bc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/b8484800-1022-11ec-bf9f-0f3d3de818bc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[The Pokémon Company]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Pokemon the Movie: Secrets of the Jungle]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Pokemon the Movie: Secrets of the Jungle ]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter web test lets you remove followers without blocking them]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter has launched its second <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-edge-to-edge-media-test-ios-181152251.html">feature test</a> in one day, and this one could be particularly helpful if you&#39;ve ever been subjected to online abuse. A newly <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1435323978734841857">available</a> web test lets you remove followers without blocking them. You&#39;ll disappear from their feed without notifications that might spark harassment and threats.</p><p>The social network hasn&#39;t said if or when it might roll out follower removals. This is coming alongside a string of anti-harassment and privacy-related projects, though, including a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-tests-safety-mode-164638754.html">&quot;Safety Mode&quot; test</a> and an experimental option to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-auto-archive-tool-concept-161842078.html">automatically archive tweets</a>. It might be just a matter of time before tighter follower control is available to a wider audience.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This test may be particularly useful in fighting abuse. Until now, Twitter users have typically had to either report offending accounts (and hope Twitter takes action) or block them and risk retaliation. This won&#39;t prevent creeps from following your activity if you have a public account, but it could lessen the chance of immediate outrage.</p><div id="90dacf2c9e344275818eab8f1f58cac9"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We&#39;re making it easier to be the curator of your own followers list. Now testing on web: remove a follower without blocking them.<br><br>To remove a follower, go to your profile and click “Followers”, then click the three dot icon and select “Remove this follower”. <a href="https://t.co/2Ig7Mp8Tnx">pic.twitter.com/2Ig7Mp8Tnx</a></p>— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1435323978734841857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-test-remove-followers-without-blocking-210001793.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">91aaf224-9209-410b-add8-d13346e468a1</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 21:00:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631047887</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T20:51:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/668af9d0-6a1a-11eb-be9a-b022e54ee491" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/668af9d0-6a1a-11eb-be9a-b022e54ee491" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Dumlao on Unsplash]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitter on an iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Twitter on an iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple loses automotive executive Doug Field to Ford]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Add another wrinkle to Apple’s oft-rumored efforts to build its own electric vehicle. On Tuesday, Ford <a href="https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2021/09/07/doug-field.html"><ins>announced the hire of Doug Field</ins></a>. The former Tesla executive, known for his involvement in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-07-02-tesla-engineering-lead-doug-field-leaves-the-company.html"><ins>development of the Model 3</ins></a>, most recently held the position of vice president of special projects at Apple. It’s believed Field oversaw Project Titan.</p><p>In his new position of chief advanced technology and embedded systems officer, Field will report to Ford CEO and president Jim Farley. He will oversee Ford’s Embedded Software and Hardware division, which will see him lead development on the automaker’s Blue Oval intelligence stack. It’s expected he will have a say in everything from vehicle controls to enterprise connectivity features and driver assistance technology. For Field, this is something of a return to where everything started. He began his career at Ford back in 1987.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="c3634ed086744122b7c29d94eb71e538"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple: “We’re grateful for the contributions Doug has made to Apple and we wish him all the best in this next chapter.” <a href="https://t.co/Trs0xNxL0o">https://t.co/Trs0xNxL0o</a></p>— Mark Gurman (@markgurman) <a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1435320561064890376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>What’s unclear is what this means for Apple’s automotive ambitions. <em>Bloomberg</em> reporter and Apple insider Mark Gurman says it’s bad news for the company. “This is probably the largest setback in a history filled with setbacks for Apple’s car project,” he tweeted. “As I wrote in January, there is no Apple Car launching anytime soon, not 2024, not 2025. Further out now, if ever.” Apple does have executives who could take over Field’s role. For instance, the company recently hired <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-hires-ulrich-kranz-222301202.html"><ins>Ulrich Kranz</ins></a>, a former BMW executive who led the development of the i3. All the same, it&#39;s never a good sign when a high-profile executive leaves a company.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ford-hires-doug-field-204511159.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6c4221b1-b5bc-48f2-a2db-84ff887e707a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 20:45:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631047354</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T20:42:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Board & Management Changes]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/24c22f30-101b-11ec-bfee-d279e05a6d7c" width="3500" height="2333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/24c22f30-101b-11ec-bfee-d279e05a6d7c" width="3500" height="2333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Edgard Garrido / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Ford logo is pictured at a store of the automaker, in Mexico City, Mexico, April 5, 2016.  Ford Motor Co reported a 113 percent surge in quarterly net income and records for global and North American operating margins, thanks to robust pricing of its F-150 pickup trucks in North America and improved profit in Europe. REUTERS/Edgard Garrido/File Photo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FORD-RESULTS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Continental's eco-friendly concept tire includes a renewable tread]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many efforts are underway to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-18-ibm-research-ev-battery-cobalt-free.html">reduce the environmental impact of cars</a>, but what about the tires those cars ride on? Continental thinks it might help. <em>Roadshow</em><a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/continental-greenconcept-future-tire-dandelions-rice-retreads/">reports</a> the company has <a href="https://www.continental.com/en/press/press-releases/20210906-tires-greenconcept/">introduced</a> the Conti GreenConcept (yes, a concept tire) where more than half of the materials are &quot;traceable, renewable and recycled.&quot; You can even renew the natural rubber tread with little trouble — not a completely new idea, but refreshable treads have generally been reserved for large commercial trucks. Three renewals would be enough to ensure the material used for casing is cut in half relative to the total mileage.</p><p>About 35 percent of the materials are renewables, including dandelion rubber, silicate made from rice husk ash and a string of vegetable oils and resins. Another 17 percent is polyester yarn made from recycled PET bottles, reclaimed steel and recovered carbon black.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The design should improve the efficiency of the cars themselves, Continental added. New casing, sidewall and tread patterns make the GreenConcept about 40 percent lighter than a conventional tire at about 16.5lbs, That, in turn, leads to 25 percent lower rolling resistance than the highest-rated tires in the EU. Continental estimates you&#39;d get six percent more range from an electric vehicle.</p><p>While you might not outfit your car with these exact tires any time soon, this is more than just a thought exercise. Continental plans to gradually deploy its recycling technology starting in 2022, including the production of tires using recycled bottles.&nbsp;</p><p>Efforts like the Conti GreenConcept are partly meant to burnish Continental&#39;s public image. It wants to be the most environmentally responsible tire company by 2030, and become completely carbon-neutral by 2050 &quot;at the latest.&quot; However, it also hints at a more holistic approach to eco-friendly cars where many components, not just the powertrain, are kinder to the planet.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/continental-conti-greenconcept-renewable-tread-tire-201058901.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d6654ebd-7ddb-4a27-acdd-dac05121cbc5</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631044927</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T20:02:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Conservation & Recycling]]></category><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/4c3278a0-1010-11ec-abfe-fa2cae99edb7" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/4c3278a0-1010-11ec-abfe-fa2cae99edb7" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Continental]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Continental Conti GreenConcept tire with renewable tread]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Continental Conti GreenConcept tire with renewable tread]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latest 'Call of Duty: Vanguard' trailer offers a first look at multiplayer]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With <em>Vanguard</em>, Activision’s Call of Duty franchise is returning to the Second World War for the first time since <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-04-21-call-of-duty-world-war-ii-sledgehammer-activision-tease.html">2017’s WWII</a><em>. </em>We already had a chance to take in the new <a href="https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-november-5-174533819.html"><ins>single-player story</ins></a> lead developer Sledgehammer Games plans to tell, but we’ve only seen a few glimpses of the title’s multiplayer offering outside of its <a href="https://youtu.be/q67A2jn-MAA">Champion Hill mode</a>. That changed on Tuesday when the studio broadcast a nearly 30-minute multiplayer deep dive and shared a new trailer.</p><div id="d64386df6b5440f28d3c5821e88b18f9"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EfFU-vxbzd0?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p><em>Vanguard</em> looks to attract new players to the series with a feature called Combat Pacing that allows you to decide how hectic you want matches to play out. Three filters — Tactical, Assualt and Blitz — determine the number of players in a match. Tactical, for instance, limits things to a 12-person match, while in Blitz there can be as many as 24 players on each team.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>Vanguard</em> also introduces a new game mode called Patrol. It’s a fresh take on Domination that sees a capture zone slowly move across the map. It’s joined by classics like Team Deathmatch, Kill Confirmed, Domination and Search and Destroy. Returning from previous Call of Duty titles is Gunsmith. It’s a feature that allows you to customize your weapons with various accessories.</p><div id="d80b43ef107e4118a295d54811a56d6a"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lyd44qL8QVQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>If you want to see more of <em>Call of Duty: Vanguard’s </em>multiplayer before the game comes out on November 5th, the game’s <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2021/09/Call-of-Duty-Vanguard-Multiplayer-Revealed-Everything-You-Need-to-Know">multiplayer beta</a> starts later this week. Provided you pre-ordered <em>Vanguard </em>on PlayStation, you can see what’s new before anyone else. The beta will open up to all PlayStation users on September 16th. That same day, those who pre-ordered the game for Xbox and PC can also see what&#39;s on offer. For everyone else, the beta opens up on September 18th and runs through to the 20th.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-multiplayer-195522647.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e0bf888e-0b1f-4169-a618-26f13c8bdbc3</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 19:55:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631044119</ingested><modified>2021-09-08T04:24:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a577a460-1012-11ec-b7eb-25af3f98024e" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a577a460-1012-11ec-b7eb-25af3f98024e" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sledgehammer Games / Activision]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Vanguard]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Vanguard]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Chinese EV startup wants to build a ridable robot unicorn for kids]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Never mind buying a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-02-27-sony-aibo-review-just-get-a-puppy.html">robot dog</a> for your kids — you might just get them a mythical creature instead. Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xpeng-p7-ev-183226796.html">Xpeng</a> has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XpM_zX0Fe7U">teased</a> a robot unicorn meant for children to ride. As <em>SCMP</em><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3147903/xpengs-unveils-smart-robot-pony-children-taking-it-step-closer">notes</a>, the quadruped will take advantage of Xpeng&#39;s experiences with autonomous driving and other AI tasks to navigate multiple terrain types, recognize objects and provide &quot;emotional interaction.&quot;</p><p>The company is shy on most other details, although the design looks and trots like a cuter, more kid-friendly version of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spot-boston-dynamics-commercial-sales-140018961.html">Boston Robotics&#39; Spot</a>. It&#39;s appropriately about as tall as a child. Sorry, folks, you won&#39;t prance your way to work.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This robot unicorn is just about as mythical as the &#39;real&#39; thing, too. Xpeng hasn&#39;t revealed when it expects to deliver its robotic horse-with-a-horn, let alone pricing or availability. It might not cost as much as a $75,000 Spot, but we&#39;d expect something this sophisticated to cost more than the $2,900 Aibo from 2019.</p><p>To some extent, profit is beside the point. Xpeng chief He Xiaopeng said the unicorn was part of a broader move into the robotics space by taking advantage of the company&#39;s existing technology. Think of this as a first step. What Xpeng learns from its unicorn could lead to more sophisticated (and hopefully adult-oriented) robots you&#39;re more likely to buy.</p><div id="aefc890225ed4c4bb3e4ee3f8eeab54c"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XpM_zX0Fe7U?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/xpeng-robot-unicorn-193029853.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6e3270d2-1b94-457b-894b-59ca3e4006f6</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 19:30:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631043456</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T19:37:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/98264e00-1009-11ec-a97f-e7bfd4296189" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/98264e00-1009-11ec-a97f-e7bfd4296189" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Xpeng Robotics]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Xpeng robot unicorn for kids]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Xpeng robot unicorn for kids]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix is releasing an interactive WWE horror movie on October 5th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/netflix"><ins>Netflix</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/wwe"><ins>WWE</ins></a> have been <a href="https://comicbook.com/wwe/news/wwe-films-netflix-upcoming-movies/"><ins>working together</ins></a> for quite a while, and their next project is a little spookier than usual. <em>Escape the Undertaker</em> is an interactive horror movie that&#39;s coming to Netflix on October 5th — just in time for Halloween.</p><p>The flick stars the legendary Undertaker, along with Big E, Xavier Woods and Kofi Kingston, who comprise The New Day, one of WWE&#39;s most popular acts of the last decade. The film sees the trio visit The Undertaker&#39;s mansion, which turns out to be &quot;an extreme haunted house, packed to the brim with supernatural challenges,&quot; according to <a href="https://bloody-disgusting.com/movie/3681842/escape-undertaker-interactive-wwe-horror-movie-netflix-brings-new-day-undertakers-haunted-house/"><em><ins>Bloody Disgusting</ins></em></a>. You&#39;ll decide the fate of The New Day as the group tries to &quot;survive the wrath of The Undertaker.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Other WWE-related fictional projects have landed on Netflix over the last few years, including a sitcom called <em>The Big Show Show</em> and <em>The Main Event</em>, a movie in which a kid becomes a wrestler after finding a magical mask. The latest offering will add to Netflix&#39;s growing library of interactive content, which includes the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-08-unbreakable-kimmy-schmidt-interactive.html"><em>Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt </em>finale</a>, a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-25-netflix-interactive-carmen-sandiego-special.html">Carmen Sandiego special</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-headspace-unwind-your-mind-june-15-170552142.html">a mindfulness experience</a> and, more recently, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-mobile-games-app-subscription-test-android-poland-stranger-things-155325550.html">video games</a>.</p><p>WWE actually has <a href="https://screenrant.com/wwe-studios-horror-movies-ranked-best-worst/"><ins>a long history</ins></a> of making horror movies through its WWE Studios arm, including an ill-fated reboot of the Leprechaun series. It has had a hand in some fine horror flicks, such as <em>Oculus </em>and <em>Mohawk</em>, so <em>Escape the Undertaker</em> could turn out to be pretty solid. Just try to keep The New Day out of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hq3gXMG4-CE"><ins>The Undertaker&#39;s boiler room</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-wwe-interactive-horror-movie-escape-the-undertaker-the-new-day-185934596.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">801ca6bd-9159-4360-925d-39a350c6fa96</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631041234</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T19:00:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7ce8db50-100c-11ec-beff-324dc4c1ac8b" width="2240" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/7ce8db50-100c-11ec-beff-324dc4c1ac8b" width="2240" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Netflix/WWE]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Escape The Undertaker. (L-R) Big E, Xavier Woods, Kofi Kingston and The Undertaker in Escape The Undertaker. c. Netflix Â© 2021]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Netflix interactive WWE movie Escape the Undertaker.]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter's latest test gives iOS users a larger, edge-to-edge view of photos]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-full-size-image-previews-now-available-ios-android-201809678.html">increasingly visual social network</a>, and it&#39;s accordingly giving your media some more breathing room. The company has started <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1435287486411022337">testing</a> an &quot;edge-to-edge&quot; timeline on iOS that gives you a much larger, borderless view for photos and videos.. You won&#39;t have to tap on a picture just to make full use of your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-12-pro-max-review-cameras-battery-price-233156949.html">big smartphone screen</a>, to put it another way.</p><p>The firm didn&#39;t say how soon the feature might move beyond the experimental stage, but did vow to &quot;iterate&quot; on the test. We&#39;ve asked about the possibility of (and timing for) Android and web tests.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The test is a bid to &quot;bring more focus to the content&quot; as more Twitter users share media. We&#39;d add that it could also help Twitter counter Instagram, TikTok and other imagery-driven social networks. You may have a stronger incentive to post on Twitter if you know people are more likely to see (and appreciate) your snapshots.</p><div id="18864579275e4591aa02b5ff2ad30389"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Now testing on iOS:<br><br>Edge to edge Tweets that span the width of the timeline so your photos, GIFs, and videos can have more room to shine. <a href="https://t.co/luAHoPjjlY">pic.twitter.com/luAHoPjjlY</a></p>— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1435287486411022337?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitter-edge-to-edge-media-test-ios-181152251.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">48ecfb4c-5934-4113-b309-401fb97db74d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 18:11:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631038315</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T18:12:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/012ef150-1004-11ec-aa8f-1fa00f3b404a" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/012ef150-1004-11ec-aa8f-1fa00f3b404a" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Twitter]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitter test displays bigger photos on iOS]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Twitter test displays bigger photos on iOS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['The Matrix Resurrections' teasers keep changing with different clips from the film]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of September 9th, when it plans to share the first full trailer from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/matrix-resurrections-name-matrix-4-091250445.html"><em>The Matrix Resurrections</em></a><em>, </em>Warner Bros. has launched a teaser for the upcoming film. The website, <a href="https://thechoiceisyours.whatisthematrix.com/">whatisthematrix.com</a>, offers a first look at Neo&#39;s latest adventure.&nbsp;</p><div id="bca25205da3f46248c08423d47d7905c"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Don&#39;t mind me, I&#39;ll just be editing <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheMatrixResurrections?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TheMatrixResurrections</a> trailer together as I piece together screenshots from the tens of thousands of unique teases on the website all day. <a href="https://t.co/Uu3hrAdy3u">pic.twitter.com/Uu3hrAdy3u</a></p>— Germain Lussier (@GermainLussier) <a href="https://twitter.com/GermainLussier/status/1435280291392733187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>In a call back to the first film, you&#39;ll see a red and blue pill on the screen when you first visit the website. Choose the former and Yahya Abdul-Mateen II will narrate the clip that follows, while the latter will treat you to the voice of Neil Patrick Harris. Each will present a different interpretation of what follows and a different series of cuts from the movie.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>What&#39;s more, each time you refresh the website and watch the clips again, you&#39;ll see a different set of scenes from the movie, as well as a mention of the current time — you know, to break the fourth wall. There aren&#39;t an infinite number of variations of each teaser, but you can piece together quite a few different scenes together if you watch each one multiple times.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Either way, it&#39;s a fun way to build up excitement for the film before the first official trailer drops later this week. Of course, if you want to go into <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em> blind, then it&#39;s best to wait until December to see it on your own terms.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-matrix-4-resurrections-teaser-website-180059094.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">92bedd74-92ea-44ba-be8b-90e1b7a066c8</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631037664</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T18:01:06+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3fb55470-1002-11ec-bf5d-956e22488030" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3fb55470-1002-11ec-bf5d-956e22488030" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Warner Bros. Pictures]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Matrix 4]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Matrix 4]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hulu's basic and ad-free plans are increasing by a dollar per month]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/disney">Disney</a> is jacking up the prices of two <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/hulu">Hulu</a> plans. As of October 8th, the standard plan is increasing from $6 to $7 per month, and the ad-free option is also jumping up by a dollar a month to $13. As <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/09/hulu-raises-prices-disney-ad-supported-premium-streaming-1234827203/"><em>Deadline</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>notes, the Hulu + Live TV and Disney Bundle prices are staying the same.</p><p>The cost of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-price-012056437.html">Disney+</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/espn-plus-annual-price-increase-191511250.html">ESPN+</a> and Disney Bundle plans have increased in recent months, so it&#39;s not exactly shocking that Hulu has followed suit. It&#39;s the first change to on-demand Hulu plans since the basic option actually <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-23-hulu-cuts-price-of-basic-service.html">dropped by $2/month in February 2019</a>. Disney <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hulu-live-tv-price-increase-211018162.html">bumped up</a> the live TV subscription price by $10/month last December.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hulu-price-increase-on-demand-basic-ad-free-plans-174251467.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">0f93acaf-9e53-40af-9717-590b9789c4e6</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 17:42:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631036741</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T17:45:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/89a13d20-1001-11ec-9ffd-a5a781973f57" width="5000" height="3359" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/89a13d20-1001-11ec-9ffd-a5a781973f57" width="5000" height="3359" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[CHINA - 2021/04/14: In this photo illustration, the American global on-demand Internet streaming media provider Hulu logo is seen on an Android mobile device screen with the currency of the United States dollar icon, $ icon symbol in the background. (Photo Illustration by Chukrut Budrul/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, the American global on-demand...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Technics made a black version of its SL-1200 turntable you can actually buy]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After dipping its toes in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/panasonic-technics-true-wireless-earbuds-us-pricing-availability-130008671.html">world of Bluetooth earbuds</a> last year, Technics is back to releasing new turntables and audiophile equipment. The company announced a raft of new products on Monday. The SB-G90M2 leads the company&#39;s fall lineup. Like the SB-G90, the M2 is a three-way bass reflex speaker pair. It features a two-way coaxial driver that combines a 25mm dome with a 160mm aluminum midrange cone and two 160mm subwoofers. The SB-GM90M2 will go on sale in October, with each one costing $2,699.&nbsp;</p><p>For those who don’t have nearly $3,000 to spend on a single speaker, Technics also announced its new SB-C600 bookshelf speakers. You’ll pay $999 for a pair of them. They went through much of the same design process as the SB-GM90M2 to reduce distortion and vibrations. Each one features a 15cm woofer paired with a 25mm aluminum dome tweeter. You can buy them starting in November.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/4d4e2700-0ffe-11ec-b777-5eb5b517cf47" alt="Technics SU-G700M2" data-uuid="955eae1f-e750-30a5-ab05-d2ee410a8805"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Technics / Panasonic</div></figure><p>Alongside the two speakers systems, Technics announced an updated version of its SU-G700 amplifier. The mark two model borrows features from the company’s reference-level SU-R100 amp. Among other features, it includes its JENO anti-jitter and distortion technology. In designing the SU-G700M2, Technics sourced new semiconductor parts, including some made from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gallium-nitride-upscaled-133000829.html">gallium nitride</a>, to improve power delivery. The company says the new model is more efficient and reactive than its predecessor and better at driving a variety of speakers. There’s also a Phono Input Phase selector to improve playback when you listen to older vinyl albums that were recorded with the inverted phase. The SU-G700M2 goes on sale in October for $2,699. It will be available in both black and silver versions, with the former including an extra “-K” in its model designation.</p><p>Lastly, Technics announced a new version of its direct-drive <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-02-29-technics-explains-sl-1200-turntable-price.html">SL-1200</a> turntable. If the SL-1210G looks familiar, it’s because the company released a limited edition black model of the SL-1200G, known as the <a href="https://www.whathifi.com/us/news/technics-reveals-all-black-sl-1210gae-anniversary-turntable">SL-1210GAE</a>, back in June 2020. A spokesperson for Technics told <a href="https://www.whathifi.com/us/news/technics-sl-1210g-turntable-brings-a-black-finish-to-the-sl-1200-series"><em>What Hi-Fi</em></a> the SL-1210GAE sold out almost immediately. The SL-1210G then gives those who missed the GAE another chance to get the company’s historic turntable in black. The GAE will cost $3,999 when it goes on sale next month.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/technics-1210-g-annoucement-172036404.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9d2d6505-1572-47cb-b134-4e23b9770d03</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 17:20:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631038526</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T18:15:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/81f0b3d0-1001-11ec-bfff-5ba7d2f702cc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/81f0b3d0-1001-11ec-bfff-5ba7d2f702cc" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Technics / Panasonic]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A press shot of the black Technics SL-1210G turntable.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Technics SL-1210G]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The fight to study what happens on Facebook]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook recently added a new report to its transparency center. The &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-widely-viewed-content-170843073.html">widely viewed content</a>&quot; report was ostensibly meant to shed light on what’s been a long-running debate: What is the most popular content on Facebook?</p><p>The 20-page report raised more questions than answers. For example, it showed that the most viewed URL was a seemingly obscure website associated with former Green Bay Packers players. It boasted nearly 90 million views even though its official Facebook page has just a few thousand followers. The report also included URLs for e-commerce sites that seemed at least somewhat spammy, like online stores for CBD products and Bible-themed t-shirts. There was also a low-res cat GIF and several bland memes that asked people to respond with foods they like or don’t like or items they had recently purchased.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Notably absent from the report were the right-wing figures who regularly dominate the unofficial “Facebook Top 10” Twitter account, which ranks content by engagement. In fact, there wasn’t very much political content at all, a point Facebook has long been<a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-explains-what-people-see-news-feed-crowdtangle-015627086.html"> eager to prove</a>. For Facebook, its latest attempt at “transparency” was evidence that most users’ feeds aren’t polarizing, disinformation-laced swamps but something much more mundane.</p><p>Days later, <em>The New York Times</em> reported that the company had prepped an earlier version of the report, but opted not to publish it. The top URL from <em>that</em><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q-1-widely-viewed-content-report-175024538.html">report</a> was a story from the <em>Chicago Sun Times</em><a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2021/08/facebook-sent-a-ton-of-traffic-to-a-chicago-tribune-story-so-why-is-everyone-mad-at-them/">that suggested</a> the death of a doctor may have been linked to the COVID-19 vaccine. Though the story was from a credible news source, it’s also the kind of story that’s often used to fuel anti-vaccine narratives.</p><p>Almost as soon as the initial report was published, researchers raised other issues. Ethan Zuckerman, an associate professor of public policy and communication at University of Massachusetts at Amherst, <a href="https://ethanzuckerman.com/2021/08/18/facebooks-new-transparency-report-is-really-strange/">called it</a> “transparency theatre.” It was, he said, “a chance for FB to tell critics that they’re moving in the direction of transparency without releasing any of the data a researcher would need to answer a question like ‘Is extreme right-wing content disproportionately popular on Facebook?’”</p><h2>The promise of ‘transparency’</h2><p>For researchers studying how information travels on Facebook, it’s a familiar tactic: provide enough data to claim “transparency,” but not enough to actually be useful. “The findings of the report are debatable,” says Alice Marwick, principal researcher at the Center for Information Technology and Public Life at University of North Carolina. “The results just didn&#39;t hold up, they don&#39;t hold up to scrutiny. They don&#39;t map to any of the ways that people actually share information.”</p><p>Marwick and other researchers have suggested that this may be because Facebook opted to slice its data in an unusual way. They have suggested that Facebook only looked for URLs that were actually in the body of a post, rather than the link previews typically shared. Or perhaps Facebook just has a really bad spam problem. Or maybe it’s a combination of the two. “There&#39;s no way for us to independently verify them … because we have no access to data compared to what Facebook has,” Marwick told Engadget.</p><p>Those concerns were echoed by Laura Edelson, a researcher at New York University. “No one else can replicate or verify the findings in this report,” she wrote in a <a href="https://twitter.com/LauraEdelson2/status/1429803816556371974">tweet</a>. “We just have to trust Facebook.” Notably, Edelson has her own experience running into the limits of Facebook’s push for “transparency.”</p><p>The company recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-disables-accounts-nyu-ad-observatory-project-091040346.html">shut down</a> her personal Facebook account, as well as those of several NYU colleagues, in response to their research on political ad targeting on the platform. Since Facebook doesn’t make targeting data available in its ad library, the researchers recruited volunteers to install a browser extension that could scoop up advertising info based on their feeds.</p><p>Facebook called it “unauthorized scraping,” saying it ran afoul of their privacy policies. In doing so, it cited its obligation to the FTC, which the agency later said was “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-letter-facebook-nyu-ad-observatory-014113346.html">misleading</a>.” Outside groups had vetted the project and confirmed it was only gathering data about advertisers, not users’ personal data. Guy Rosen, the company’s VP of Integrity, later said that even though the research was “well-intentioned” it posed too great a privacy risk. Edelson and others said Facebook was trying to silence research that could make the company look bad.“If this episode demonstrates anything it is that Facebook should not have veto power over who is allowed to study them,” she wrote in a statement.</p><p>Rosen and other Facebook execs have said that Facebook does want to make more data available to researchers, but that they need to go through the company’s official channels to ensure the data is made available in a “privacy protected” way. The company has a platform called FORT (Facebook Open Research and Transparency), which allows academics to request access to some types of Facebook data, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-election-ad-targeting-data-researchers-185000167.html">election ads</a> from 2020. Earlier this year, the company said it would expand the program to make more info available to researchers studying <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-researcher-api-fringe-groups-195545901.html">“fringe” groups</a> on the platform.</p><p>But while Facebook has billed FORT as yet another step in its efforts to provide “transparency,” those who have used FORT have cited shortcomings. A group of researchers <a href="https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2021/08/05/facebooks-illusory-promise-of-transparency/">at Princeton</a> hoping to study election ads ultimately <a href="https://digiday.com/marketing/princeton-researchers-ditch-facebook-political-ad-project-after-the-platform-used-a-debunked-ftc-privacy-defense/">pulled</a> the project, citing Facebook’s restrictive terms. They said Facebook pushed a “strictly non-negotiable” agreement that required them to submit their research to Facebook for review prior to publishing. Even more straightforward questions about how they were permitted to analyze the data were left unanswered.</p><p>“Our experience dealing with Facebook highlights their long running pattern of misdirection and doublespeak to dodge meaningful scrutiny of their actions,” they wrote in a statement describing their experience.</p><p>A Facebook spokesperson said the company only checks for personally identifiable information, and that it’s never rejected a research paper.</p><p>“We support hundreds of academic researchers at more than 100 institutions through the Facebook Open Research and Transparency project,” Facebook’s Chaya Nayak, who heads up FORT at Facebook, said in a statement. “Through this effort, we make massive amounts of privacy-protected data available to academics so they can study Facebook’s impact on the world. We also pro-actively seek feedback from the research community about what steps will help them advance research most effectively going forward.”</p><p>Data access affects researchers’ ability to study Facebook’s biggest problems. And the pandemic has further highlighted just how significant that work can be. Facebook’s unwillingness to share more data about <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-vaccine-misinformation-policies-170012241.html">vaccine misinformation</a> has been repeatedly called out by researchers and public health officials. It’s all the more vexing because Facebook employs a small army of its own researchers and data scientists. Yet much of their work is never made public. “They have a really solid research team, but virtually everything that research team does is kept only within Facebook, and we never see any of it,” says Marwick, the UNC professor.</p><p>But much of Facebook’s internal research could help those outside the platform who are trying to understand the same questions, she says. “I want more of the analysis and research that&#39;s going on within Facebook to be communicated to the larger scholarly community, especially stuff around polarization [and] news sharing. I have a fairly strong sense that there&#39;s research questions that are actively being debated in my research community that Facebook knows the answer to, but they can&#39;t communicate it to us.”</p><h2>The rise of ‘data donation’</h2><p>To get around this lack of access, researchers are increasingly looking to “data donation” programs. Like the browser extension used by the NYU researchers, these projects recruit volunteers to “donate” some of their own data for research.</p><p>NYU’s <a href="https://adobserver.org/">Ad Observer</a>, for example, collected data about ads on Facebook and YouTube, with the goal of helping them understand the platform’s ad targeting at  amore granular level. Similarly, Mozilla, maker of the Firefox browser, has a browser add-on called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mozilla-rally-data-platform-130034616.html">Rally</a> that helps researchers study a range of issues from COVID-19 misinformation to local news. <em>The Markup</em>, a nonprofit news organization, has also created <a href="https://themarkup.org/citizen-browser/2021/06/24/after-repeatedly-promising-not-to-facebook-keeps-recommending-political-groups-to-its-users">Citizen Browser</a>, a customized browser that aids journalists’ investigations into Facebook and YouTube. (Unlike Mozilla and NYU’s browser-based projects, <em>The Markup</em> pays users who participate in Citizen Browser.)</p><p>“The biggest single problem in our research community is the lack of access to private proprietary data,” says Marwick. “Data donation programs are one of the tactics that people in my community are using to try to get access to data, given that we know the platform&#39;s aren&#39;t going to give it to us.”</p><p>Crucially, it’s also data that’s collected independently, and that may be the best way to ensure true transparency, says Rebecca Weiss, who leads Mozilla’s Rally project. “We keep getting these good faith transparency efforts from these companies but it&#39;s clear that transparency also means some form of independence,” Weiss tells Engadget.</p><p>For participants, these programs offer social media users a way to make sure some of their data, which is constantly being scooped up by mega-platforms like Facebook, can also be used in a way that <em>is</em> within their control: to aid in research. Weiss says that, ultimately, it’s not that different from market research or other public science projects. “This idea of donating your time to a good faith effort — these are familiar concepts.”</p><p>Researchers also point out that there are significant benefits to gaining a better understanding of how the most influential and powerful platforms operate. The study of election ads, for example, can expose bad actors trying to manipulate elections. Knowing more about how health misinformation spreads can help public health officials understand how to combat vaccine hesitancy. Weiss notes that having a better understanding of why we see the ads we do — political or otherwise — can go a long way toward demystifying how social media platforms operate.</p><p>“This affects our lives on a daily basis and there&#39;s not a lot of ways that we as consumers can prepare ourselves for the world that exists with these increasingly more powerful ad networks that have no transparency.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transparency-researchers-170021370.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3ca3f309-c36d-40a6-8541-0d91f5125982</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631032295</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T16:31:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2f5b7fe0-0c52-11ec-bbff-680a2ef21d02" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/2f5b7fe0-0c52-11ec-bbff-680a2ef21d02" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Aly Song / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A Facebook sign is seen at the second China International Import Expo (CIIE) in Shanghai, China November 6, 2019. REUTERS/Aly Song]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[CHINA-TRADE/EXPO]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft rolls out a personalized news feed called Start]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/microsoft"><ins>Microsoft</ins></a> is rolling out a revamped personalized news service called Start. The feed will be <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2021/09/07/the-content-you-care-about-simplified-and-reinvented-introducing-microsoft-start/"><ins>baked into</ins></a> the Windows 10 taskbar and the Windows 11 widgets section. You can also access it via <a href="https://www.microsoftstart.com/"><ins>the web</ins></a>, <a href="https://aka.ms/Start_Blog_QR"><ins>iOS and Android apps</ins></a> and the new tab page in Microsoft Edge.</p><p>Start draws from Microsoft&#39;s artificial intelligence and machine learning expertise (as well as human curation) to create a news feed featuring up-to-date info tailored to your interests. It curates news from more than 1,000 publishers around the world.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The more you use Start and indicate what you&#39;re interested in, the closer the feed will hew to the things you prefer to read about. You can tell the app when you see a publisher or story you&#39;re not keen on, or hit the Personalize button to refine the feed whenever you like. Your preferences are linked to your Microsoft account, so the service should offer the same experience on all platforms where you&#39;re logged in.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/714b8ca0-0ffa-11ec-bc95-5cdacded7598" style="height:528;width:853;" alt="Microsoft Start" data-uuid="45d17491-51ca-3a53-965f-862933fb3b91"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Start includes information cards for certain key topics, such as weather, traffic, sports and finance. You can decide which cards you want to pop up for at-a-glance information.</p><p>Although MSN isn&#39;t going anywhere, Start is replacing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-partnership-with-europe-news-publishers-163545839.html"><ins>Microsoft News</ins></a>. The icon and name for that app will change to Start branding the next time users update it. Those who visit the Microsoft News website will be redirected to the Start home page as well.</p><p>The name of the feed might cause a little confusion for Windows users, given the prominence of the Start button in the operating system over the last couple of decades (that menu is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-launch-microsoft-151140403.html"><ins>getting an overhaul in Windows 11</ins></a>). Still, Microsoft Start looks like a polished experience, and it could be a solid way to keep tabs on the news in which you&#39;re interested.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-start-personalized-news-feed-164505328.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7b9465e4-a44d-4914-beaa-fce3c0338af3</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:45:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631033284</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T16:48:15+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3f7d2710-0ffa-11ec-bf7a-56b8c228baf2" width="773" height="576" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3f7d2710-0ffa-11ec-bf7a-56b8c228baf2" width="773" height="576" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Microsoft Start]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Microsoft Start]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[El Salvador starts accepting Bitcoin as legal currency]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador is officially the first country in the world to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/el-salvador-bitcoin-legal-tender-120440725.html">accept Bitcoin as legal currency</a>. <em>CNBC</em><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/07/el-salvador-buys-400-bitcoin-ahead-of-law-making-it-legal-currency.html">reports</a> the Central American nation&#39;s Bitcoin law took effect on September 7th, letting Salvadorans use the cryptocurrency in physical and online shops. Accordingly, locals can use a Chivo wallet app on their phones to make purchases and manage their funds.</p><p>The government has been eager to give itself a good start. President Nayib Bukele <a href="https://twitter.com/nayibbukele/status/1435263064933285898">revealed</a> El Salvador had bought 550 Bitcoin as of this writing (about $26 million), and the country&#39;s Congress passed a law last week establishing a $150 million fund to aid conversions from Bitcoin to US dollars (also accepted in El Salvador).</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Bukele previously claimed the move would not only foster investment, tourism and overall economic development, but would make El Salvador&#39;s financial system more inclusive by courting the 70 percent of residents who don&#39;t have bank accounts. It&#39;s also an acknowledgment of the financial reality of the country. Its economy relies in part on remittances from migrants, and Bitcoin theoretically streamlines those transfers.</p><p>Not everyone is thrilled with the decision, though. <em>Cointelegraph</em><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/el-salvadorians-take-to-the-streets-to-protest-bitcoin-law">noted</a> that some Salvadorans have protested the adoption of Bitcoin, arguing that politicians didn&#39;t consult with the public. They&#39;re also worried <a href="https://www.engadget.com/coinbase-outage-amid-cryptocurrency-price-drop-150658356.html">cryptocurrency&#39;s volatility</a> could pose a serious risk next to the relative stability of the US dollar. <em>Reuters</em><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/elsalvador-bitcoin-gomez/el-salvador-police-investigate-vocal-critic-of-presidents-bitcoin-plan-idUSL8N2Q34WU">added</a><em>&nbsp;</em>that police briefly held an outspoken critic of the Bitcoin law, Mario Gomez. Officials said it was related to a financial fraud investigation, but supporters were concerned this was an act of intimidation meant to silence political opposition.</p><p>We wouldn&#39;t count on other countries rushing to join El Salvador. Countries like the US are exploring <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-federal-reserve-is-looking-closer-at-a-digital-currency-125534039.html">central bank cryptocurrencies</a>, potentially more stable and easily regulated than Bitcoin. Other countries are hostile. China banned many companies and institutions from handling cryptocurrency, and India has looked into <a href="https://www.engadget.com/india-proposed-law-bans-private-cryptocurrencies-181519169.html">banning private currencies</a>. There&#39;s also the simple matter of varying economic conditions. Successful Bitcoin adoption in El Salvador wouldn&#39;t guarantee success elsewhere — other countries might gain little if anything from embracing digital money.</p><div id="f105c6e785e24e95bb222980b632e6f3"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It appears the discount is ending 🥲<br><br>Thanks for the dip <a href="https://twitter.com/IMFNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IMFNews</a>. We saved a million in printed paper.<br><br>El Salvador now holds 550 bitcoin.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BitcoinDay?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BitcoinDay</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BTC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BTC</a>&nbsp;🇸🇻</p>— Nayib Bukele 🇸🇻 (@nayibbukele) <a href="https://twitter.com/nayibbukele/status/1435263064933285898?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/el-salvador-accepts-bitcoin-legal-currency-162452362.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6d35cfbe-f6f4-4bae-97a9-798889b78476</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 16:24:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1631031361</ingested><modified>2021-09-07T16:16:04+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/9c0677c0-0ff0-11ec-bfbc-f7b4560de7e2" width="6377" height="4250" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/9c0677c0-0ff0-11ec-bfbc-f7b4560de7e2" width="6377" height="4250" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Jose Cabezas / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Men buy snacks at a store where bitcoins are accepted at El Zonte Beach in Chiltiupan, El Salvador June 16, 2021. REUTERS/Jose Cabezas]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[EL SALVADOR-BITCOIN/]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>