<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 09:01:34 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon settles with employees allegedly fired over working condition criticisms]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon was supposed to defend its decision in court to let Emily Cunningham and Maren Costa go last year. The former Amazon employees were outspoken critics of the company, and both were, the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) previously decided, illegally <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fires-two-more-critics-173050857.html">fired</a>. The e-commerce giant didn&#39;t have to defend itself, however, because it has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/29/amazon-settlement-fired-workers/">settled</a> with the affected parties shortly before the hearing could take place.</p><p>Cunningham and Costa, who worked on user experience design, openly criticized Amazon&#39;s climate policies and workplace practices. They previously slammed the company&#39;s climate policies in a <a href="https://twitter.com/SenSanders/status/1214308530183983110">video</a> that gained national attention. And before they were let go in April 2020, both of them tweeted that they&#39;d match donations up to $500 to support their warehouse worker colleagues. Cunningham <a href="https://twitter.com/emahlee/status/1243441985173651456">said</a> the &quot;lack of safe and sanitary working conditions&quot; puts the workers and the public at risk, while Costa <a href="https://twitter.com/marencosta/status/1243585580736237568">tweeted</a> that the workers &quot;struggle to get consistent, sufficient protections and procedures&quot; from their employer.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Amazon said when the news broke that they were let go for violating internal policies, namely for discussing the company without prior approval, and not for speaking out about working conditions specifically. The NLRB looked into accusations that Amazon retaliated against its employees for organizing or participating in protests, however, and determined that Cunningham and Costa were illegally fired.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/29/amazon-settlement-fired-workers/"><em>The Washington Post</em></a>, the settlement still needs to be approved by the NLRB regional director in Seattle, though Cunningham and Costa are already considering the settlement a victory. In a <a href="https://twitter.com/emahlee/status/1443359550803877889">joint statement</a>, they said the development is a &quot;win for protecting workers rights&quot; and that Amazon will be required to pay them lost wages. The whole statement reads:</p><blockquote><p>&quot;We are thrilled to announce that we have reached an agreement to settle the charge against Amazon at the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) alleging that the company illegally fired us for speaking up about warehouse workers&#39; conditions during COVID. This is a win for protecting workers rights, and shows that we were right to stand up for each other, for justice, and for our world. Amazon will be required to pay us our lost wages and post a notice to all of its tech and warehouse workers nationwide that Amazon can&#39;t fire workers for organizing and exercising their rights.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>It’s also not lost on us that we are two women who were targeted for firing. Inequality, racism, and sexism are at the heart of both the climate crisis and the pandemic.&nbsp;</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Tech workers standing up together have immense power to move the biggest corporations in the world. Everything we love is threatened by climate chaos. Workers at every company need to be standing up for each other and the world, together. Now is the time to be our best, bravest selves. We can only do this together. We hope you’ll join us.&quot;</p></blockquote>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-settles-employees-working-condition-criticisms-090134228.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">33c0ca49-3c65-48cd-b89f-5feab4cc038c</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 09:01:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632988936</ingested><modified>2021-09-30T08:02:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Society & Culture]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c34bcd10-2376-11eb-9ff5-fd6c86aa0c67" width="4435" height="2957" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c34bcd10-2376-11eb-9ff5-fd6c86aa0c67" width="4435" height="2957" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Andrei Stanescu via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Jan 24, 2020 Sunnyvale / CA / USA - Amazon headquarters located in Silicon Valley, San Francisco bay area]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon headquarters located in Silicon Valley]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Honda announces plans to build electric VTOLs and telepresence robots]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Honda builds much more than cars and trucks — power equipment, solar cells, industrial robotics, alternative fuel engines and even aircraft are all part of the company&#39;s production capacity. On Thursday, Honda announced that it is working to further expand its manufacturing portfolio to include Avatar-style remote telepresence robots and electric VTOLs for inter- and intracity commutes before turning its ambitions to building a fuel-cell driven power generation system for the lunar surface.&nbsp;</p><p>For its eVTOL, Honda plans to leverage not only the lithium battery technology it&#39;s developed for its EV and PHEV vehicles but also a gas turbine hybrid power unit to give the future aircraft enough range to handle regional inter-city flights as well. Honda foresees air taxis as a ubiquitous part of tomorrow&#39;s transportation landscape, seamlessly integrating with both autonomous ground vehicles and traditional airliners (though they <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xwing-first-autonomous-commercial-cargo-flight-160057111.html">could soon be flown by robots</a> as well). Obviously, the program is still very much in the early research phase and will likely remain so until at least the second half of this decade. The company anticipates having prototype units available for testing and certification by the 2030s and a full commercial rollout sometime around 2040.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Honda will have plenty of competition if and when it does get its eVTOLs off the ground. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gm-cadillac-ev-drone-vtol-concept-lyriq-celestiq-144643388.html">Cadillac showed off</a> its single-seater aircar earlier this year, while Joby (in partnership with NASA) already has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-joby-air-taxi-testing-200052607.html">full-scale mockups flying</a>. In June, Slovakian transportation startup, Klein Vision, flew from Nitra and to the Bratislava airport in its inaugural inter-city flight — and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/aircar-first-inter-city-flight-092852060.html">then drove home after the event</a>. But building a fleet of flying taxis is no easy feat — <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-10-bell-nexus-air-taxi-of-the-future-uber-2023.html">just ask Bell helicopters</a> — and we&#39;re sure to see more companies drop out of the sector before eVTOLs become commonplace.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/89921e20-2169-11ec-9ff9-794fb112123b" alt="Honda Motor&#39;s Asimo robot puts on a demonstration for the media at the Jacob Javits Convention Center during the New York International Auto Show in New York April 17, 2014.  REUTERS/Carlo Allegri (UNITED STATES - Tags: TRANSPORT BUSINESS)" data-uuid="b2c8f5b0-0063-3f4a-b391-46e20cb94d00"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Carlo Allegri / reuters</div></figure><p>Honda reps also discussed the company&#39;s future robotics aspirations during a media briefing on Wednesday. The company envisions a future where people are unencumbered by space and time, where telepresence robots have visual and tactile acuity rivalling that of humans. Rather than hopping on a plane to inspect remote factory floors or attend product demonstrations in person, tomorrow&#39;s workers may simply don VR headsets and step into the body of an on-site humanoid robot.&nbsp;</p><p>The company announced that it wants its Avatar Robot — a newly refined iteration of the Asimo (above) — put into practical use in the 2030s and will conduct technology demonstration testing by the end of Q1, 2024 in order to meet that goal. But before that happens Honda reps noted that the company has work to do downsizing the robot&#39;s hand hardware and improving its grasping dexterity.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/8189d3b0-2170-11ec-bb37-b23b13547c8e" alt="Honda&#39;s circulative renewable energy system" data-uuid="4e49a5d1-667c-3f50-84e9-42f648c2357c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JAXA/Honda</div></figure><p>Honda also has big plans for its space ventures including working on ways to adapt its existing fuel cell and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-pressure_electrolysis">high differential pressure water electrolysis</a> technologies to work on the lunar surface as part of a circulative renewable energy system.</p><p>This system would use electricity gathered from renewable energy sources (like solar) to break the molecular bonds of liquid water, resulting hydrogen and oxygen. Those two elements would then be run through Honda&#39;s fuel cell to generate both electricity and supply the lunar habitats with oxygen for breathing and hydrogen for rocket fuel.&nbsp;</p><p>The company also hopes to utilize the more-nimble Avatar hands its developing as manipulators on a fleet of remote controlled lunar rovers which will perform tasks on the lunar surface rather than subject astronauts to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/what-it-will-take-for-humans-to-colonize-the-moon-and-mars-160026478.html">moon&#39;s many dangers</a>. Honda has partnered with Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) and <a href="https://global.honda/newsroom/news/2021/c210614eng.html">began joint research</a> into both of these systems in June.</p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/honda-announces-plans-avatar-style-remote-robot-and-electric-vtol-090002765.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">65191e3b-00c0-4c8e-b2a7-418358401ccc</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 09:00:02 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632964755</ingested><modified>2021-09-30T01:19:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/f97da840-2168-11ec-b797-a483d53ffe20" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/f97da840-2168-11ec-b797-a483d53ffe20" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[20th Century Studios]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[avatar]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[avatar]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic cleared to fly again following FAA investigation]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Virgin Galactic has been <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210929005972/en/Virgin-Galactic-Cleared-to-Fly-Following-Conclusion-of-FAA-Inquiry">cleared to fly again</a> by the US Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) following an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/faa-bars-virgin-galactic-spaceflights-203534520.html">anomaly</a> on its previous flight, the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/faa-ends-probe-of-virgin-galactic-flight-11632958891"><em>WSJ</em></a> has reported. The agency launched a probe into the space company&#39;s first crewed flight after it dropped below its approved trajectory.&nbsp;</p><p>The FAA determined that the SpaceShip Two Unity craft, with founder Richard Branson and five others aboard, had deviated from its assigned airspace for a minute and 41 seconds and failed to report the error as required. However, it accepted Virgin Galactic&#39;s proposal to expand the protected airspace for a wider array of possible trajectories and to communicate with air traffic control in real time during flights.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;The updates to our airspace and real-time mission notification protocols will strengthen our preparations as we move closer to the commercial launch of our spaceflight experience,&quot; said Virgin Galactic CEO Michael Colglazier in a statement.&nbsp;</p><div id="195c681bd23c4f2b98619f73b768de4b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Virgin Galactic is cleared to fly FAA-licenced spaceflights following the conclusion of an FAA inquiry. Read more here; <a href="https://t.co/G4UaH5KLU9">https://t.co/G4UaH5KLU9</a><a href="https://t.co/qs5vOoxoGb">pic.twitter.com/qs5vOoxoGb</a></p>— Virgin Galactic (@virgingalactic) <a href="https://twitter.com/virgingalactic/status/1443329649015234570?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>According to a report in the <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-red-warning-light-on-richard-bransons-space-flight"><em>New Yorker</em></a>, pilots saw a &quot;red light&quot; warning near the end of the powered flight indicating that the spacecraft had veered outside its entry glide cone, putting it at risk of an emergency landing. Virgin Galactic said that the deviation was due to high altitude winds and that the craft didn&#39;t fly outside the lateral confines of its protected airspace. &quot;At no time did the ship travel above any population centers or cause a hazard to the public,&quot; a spokesperson said.</p><p>With a flight clearance in hand again, Virgin Galactic may fly its next mission in mid-October, potentially with members of the Italian Air Force. After that, both the current SpaceShipTwo and its WhiteKnightTwo host aircraft would spend four months receiving upgrades, the company previously said.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-cleared-to-fly-again-following-faa-investigation-071032837.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">16eae776-c7f0-4596-a7eb-c7e28e663e44</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:10:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632985834</ingested><modified>2021-09-30T07:10:45+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/6c3ee560-0c24-11ec-87e7-afec10069ceb" width="5568" height="3712" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/6c3ee560-0c24-11ec-87e7-afec10069ceb" width="5568" height="3712" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[PATRICK T. FALLON via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Virgin Galactic SpaceShipTwo space plane Unity returns to earth after the mothership separated at Spaceport America, near Truth and Consequences, New Mexico on July 11, 2021. - Billionaire Richard Branson took off July 11, 2021 from a base in New Mexico aboard a Virgin Galactic vessel bound for the edge of space, a voyage he hopes will lift the nascent space tourism industry off the ground.A massive carrier plane made a horizontal take-off from Spaceport, New Mexico at around 8:40 am Mountain Time (1440 GMT) and will ascend for around an hour to an altitude of 50,000 feet (15 kilometers).The mothership will then drop a rocket-powered spaceplane called VSS Unity, which will ignite its engine and ascend at Mach 3 beyond 50 miles (80 kilometers) of altitude, which marks the boundary of space according to the United States. (Photo by Patrick T. FALLON / AFP) (Photo by PATRICK T. FALLON/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-SPACE-TOURISM-BEZOS-BRANSON]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nintendo denies it supplied developers with tools for a 4K Switch]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-29/nintendo-switch-4k-developers-make-games-for-nonexistent-console?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> report claims that Nintendo provided at least 11 developers with a toolkit to create games for the Switch that support 4K graphics. Shortly after it was published, though, the gaming giant has issued a statement firmly denying that it&#39;s supplying tools to drive the development of titles for a 4K console. &quot;[T]his report is not true,&quot; the company <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoCoLtd/status/1443366440183074819">tweeted</a>. Further, it reiterated that it has no plans for a new Switch model other than the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-oled-switch-not-switch-pro-161744624.html">OLED variant</a> that&#39;s coming out on October 8th.&nbsp;</p><div id="8f92f37160df4084a04320886d6a840b"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We also want to restate that, as we announced in July, we have no plans for any new model other than Nintendo Switch – OLED Model, which will launch on October 8, 2021. (2/2)</p>— 任天堂株式会社（企業広報・IR） (@NintendoCoLtd) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoCoLtd/status/1443366443374899205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p><em>Bloomberg</em> said Nintendo had already handed out 4K toolkits and had already asked developers to create games with 4K resolution by the time it announced the OLED model. The publication also said that the 11 companies it talked to are made up of large publishers and small studios, including Zynga.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Nintendo&#39;s upcoming OLED Switch doesn&#39;t support 4K graphics, though its screen does offer better colors and contrast than its predecessors. In the past, <em>Bloomberg</em> reported that the company was working on a Switch with OLED screen and an NVIDIA chip that would enable it to generate 4K graphics when connected to a TV. A source told the publication, however, that Nintendo struggled with component shortages due to the COVID-19 pandemic and had to drop its 4K plans.&nbsp;</p><p>Releasing a 4K Switch seems like the logical next step for Nintendo to take, seeing as its competitors already have consoles that support the resolution. Based on the company&#39;s statement, though, that won&#39;t be happening anytime soon.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-denies-4k-switch-043422202.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">38c13a11-c8f5-44ca-ba0e-501928998cc5</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 04:34:22 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632976500</ingested><modified>2021-09-30T04:35:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/dd8a7520-21a2-11ec-b89f-e2c4a878fb2d" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/dd8a7520-21a2-11ec-b89f-e2c4a878fb2d" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook publishes slides on how Instagram affects teen mental health]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook has <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/research-teen-well-being-and-instagram/">published</a> two slide decks detailing its research into how Instagram affects teens’ mental health. The slides were heavily cited by <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739"><em>The Wall Street Journal</em></a> earlier this month in a story that reported the company’s own researchers had found that ““Instagram is harmful for a sizable percentage” of teens, particularly teenage girls.”</p><p>Instagram has attempted to rebut those claims, saying that its research was mischaracterized. But the ensuing backlash has already forced the company to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-is-pausing-work-on-instagram-kids-app-124639135.html">“pause”</a> its work on an Instagram Kids app. It also raised pressure on Facebook to release the underlying research, which the company ultimately <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-instagram-teen-safety-research-212546087.html">agreed</a> to do. Facebook’s head of safety is scheduled to testify at a Senate Commerce Committee hearing on child safety on Instagram Thursday.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The slides offer a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transparency-researchers-170021370.html">rare glimpse</a> into how Facebook researches thorny issues affecting its own services. Many include lengthy annotations with additional “context” on the more controversial aspects of the research. For example, a slide titled “The Perfect image, feeling attractive, and having enough money are most likely to have started on Instagram,” states that the information in the slide “should not be used as estimates of average experience among teen users.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/5f64f210-2189-11ec-bdaf-908507cf8eec" alt="Facebook&#39;s slides on how teens use Instagram." data-uuid="689d4195-fb4e-362e-a956-f206acfecbdd"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Facebook</div></figure><p>Other annotations, like one on a slide, titled “One in five teens say that Instagram makes them feel worse about themselves, with UK girls the most negative,” attempt to downplay the findings. “This research was not intended to (and does not) evaluate causal claims between Instagram and health or well-being.” (That line is repeated on several other slides.)</p><p>The research also offers insight into what type of content is positively perceived by teens on Instagram. One slide states that meme accounts are among the content that “make teens feel the best.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/dd39ed80-2189-11ec-9fdd-385b66d5851c" alt="An internal slide published by Facebook." data-uuid="a5a9ea18-39b8-3b09-812e-3b94f37e78e4"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Facebook</div></figure><p>The release of the research is unlikely to quiet Facebook’s critics, particularly those in Congress who were already deeply suspicious of the company’s attempts to woo children onto its services. Some Democratic lawmakers have called on the company to abandon its work on Instagram Kids entirely. For Facebook, younger users are not just one of the most important demographics, but one where the company has been consistently losing out to rivals like Snapchat and Instagram.</p><p>Other research, also conducted by Facebook and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-instagram-kids-tweens-attract-11632849667">published</a> by <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> this week, found that Facebook has been struggling to keep tween and teens engaged. In one slide, which has not been made public by Facebook, the company discussed whether young children’s playdates could be used “as a growth lever for Messenger Kids.” Facebook later said that it “was an insensitive way to pose a serious question and doesn’t reflect our approach to building the app.”</p><p><strong>Update 9/29/21 11:32PM ET:</strong><em>The Wall Street Journal</em> has published internal documents, including ones Facebook didn&#39;t include in its report about how Instagram affects teens&#39; mental health.&nbsp;</p><div id="5cdce2373cb440f6920b9ccf5032e986"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here are six internal Facebook documents that <a href="https://twitter.com/JeffHorwitz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JeffHorwitz</a> and I used to report the teen mental health on Instagram story. I&#39;d suggest starting with: TEEN GIRLS BODY IMAGE<a href="https://t.co/VTDf1AzKHE">https://t.co/VTDf1AzKHE</a></p>— Georgia Wells (@georgia_wells) <a href="https://twitter.com/georgia_wells/status/1443394051240124416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-research-instagram-teen-mental-health-slides-003452675.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">89f12f4d-1a0b-45c6-91f1-f625d5f145ba</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:34:52 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632972978</ingested><modified>2021-09-30T03:36:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c395bca0-2185-11ec-bb59-4dee6bda354d" width="5000" height="3283" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c395bca0-2185-11ec-bb59-4dee6bda354d" width="5000" height="3283" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[OLIVIER DOULIERY via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[In this photo illustration, a person looks at a smart phone with a Instagram logo displayed on the screen, on August 17, 2021, in Arlington, Virginia. (Photo by OLIVIER DOULIERY / AFP) (Photo by OLIVIER DOULIERY/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-IT-LIFESTYLE-INTERNET]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple finally lets you rate its apps on the App Store]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You&#39;ve the option to re-download Apple&#39;s in-house apps for a while, but you haven&#39;t been allowed to write App Store reviews for them like you can for third-party titles. Apple is now treating its apps more as equals, though. <em>9to5Mac</em><a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/rate-and-review-apple-iphone-built-in-apps/">notes</a> Apple has quietly enabled App Store ratings and reviews for its own software. If you want to laud <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-3d-maps-rollout-ios-15-london-washington-dc-canada-161715719.html">improvements to Maps</a> or trash Mail, you can.</p><p>The volume of reviews is relatively low compared to equivalent third-party apps that have been around for years, like Gmail or Google Maps. However, it won&#39;t surprise you to hear the ratings are relatively low. Apple&#39;s Podcasts client is sitting at two stars as of this writing, while Apple News is sitting at 2.3 stars. Maps has only partly mended its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-09-28-tim-cook-apologizes-for-maps-mess.html">early reputation</a> with a three-star rating. Like with third-party software, some customers are using the ratings and reviews to gripe about technical issues instead of design.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The change treats Apple&#39;s apps more fairly, and might even be useful to help the company spot and respond to criticism. It might likewise see this as another way to improve public perception of the App Store. On top of an Epic lawsuit that could soon force Apple to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-epic-games-lawsuit-ruling-app-store-153113436.html">alter App Store policies</a>, the iPhone maker has preemptively <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-09-apple-app-store-search-rank-changes.html">stopped favoring its own apps</a> in rankings and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-rolls-out-small-business-program-fees-051742717.html">reduced its cut</a> of small developers&#39; apps revenues. Ratings and reviews won&#39;t dramatically change Apple&#39;s image, but they likely won&#39;t hurt.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-allows-rating-first-party-app-store-apps-230528659.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">aa18a187-651a-42f4-ae04-1b038330b8f1</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 23:05:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632953083</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T22:04:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1dcd9640-fafb-11eb-8fde-3d5cdabb0674" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1dcd9640-fafb-11eb-8fde-3d5cdabb0674" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[App Store icon displayed on a phone screen is seen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on July 18, 2021.  (Photo Ilustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TikTok And Facebook Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[A revamped wired Nest Doorbell is coming in 2022 with 24/7 video recording]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google is feeling the smart home heat. Shortly after Amazon announced its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-blink-video-doorbell-floodlight-camera-170141201.html">dirt-cheap $50 Blink video doorbell</a>, <a href="https://www.googlenestcommunity.com/t5/Blog/Message-from-our-GM-Updates-for-our-Nest-customers/ba-p/17122">Nest VP Rishi Chandra announced </a>that Google <em>also</em> has a competing second-generation Nest Doorbell coming next year. And unlike the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-doorbell-camera-battery-powered-floodlight-130016075.html">recently launched battery-powered Nest Doorbell</a>, the new device will be hardwired like the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-04-27-nest-hello-review.html">original Nest Hello</a>. That opens the door for 24/7 video recording, something the battery-powered cameras can&#39;t handle due to thermal issues (plus you&#39;d likely have to recharge them often).</p><p>Chandra also says Google plans to launch a web view for the Home app next year as well, which will allow you to control cameras and other devices from your computer. Honestly, it&#39;s a shock Google still hasn&#39;t managed to build that, especially when competitors like Arlo and Ring have offered them for years. Google also plans to bring older Nest devices into the Google Home app eventually, but for now, Nest customers will have to juggle between two separate apps.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-doorbell-wired-24-7-recording-220749729.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">002cc7eb-9e4f-43f6-b3c1-171c5c24644f</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 22:07:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632949502</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T21:05:04+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/eeff9c80-2167-11ec-af7f-697d3e361ad8" width="675" height="380" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/eeff9c80-2167-11ec-af7f-697d3e361ad8" width="675" height="380" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[A revamped wired Nest Doorbell is coming in 2022 with 24/7 video recording]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bungie makes it easier to sue over harassment following Activision scandal]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bungie <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-10-bungie-takes-control-of-publishing-destiny.html">split from Activision</a> a long time ago, but that isn&#39;t stopping the company from distancing itself from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html">sexual harassment scandal</a> affecting its former publisher. The <em>Destiny 2</em> creator is <a href="https://www.bungie.net/en/Explore/Detail/News/50746">implementing</a> a number of reforms that it hopes will foster diversity and inclusion, prevent harassment and clamp down if abuse takes place. Most notably, it&#39;s joining other tech companies in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-easier-sue-arbitration-claims-090815254.html">dropping the mandatory arbitration clause</a> in employee agreements. It should be easier for harassment targets to sue and otherwise make their complaints public.</p><p>The company has also hired inclusion-oriented leaders, including a Chief People Officer and an as yet unnamed but &quot;deeply experienced&quot; director. Bungie is further reviewing its hiring practices to prevent biased selections, and is adding a third-party anonymous reporting tool (on top of existing options) to reduce the reluctance to flag harassment. CEO Pete Parsons added that half of Bungie&#39;s board, and four out of nine executives, were either women or from underrepresented demographics.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Parsons stressed that there was &quot;more that can be done,&quot; and that there was no ideal ending. He felt it was important for Bungie to set an example for others, though, and was hopeful the game industry as a whole would improve its practices.</p><p>Bungie hasn&#39;t faced harassment allegations like Activision, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-07-riot-games-walk-out-sexism-lawsuits-arbitration.html">Riot Games</a> or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-harassment-lawsuit-france-205931367.html">Ubisoft</a>. This appears to be a proactive step rather than a reaction to internal turmoil. All the same, the move illustrates the pressure on developers to rethink their anti-harassment strategies — studios like Bungie want to prevent incidents long before they lead to lawsuits and protests.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bungie-drops-arbitration-boosts-inclusivity-efforts-212351819.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">46011e46-5a12-4a75-9d4a-1ede59ff11b8</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 21:23:51 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632948189</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T20:43:20+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/e9396220-720f-11eb-9f2f-536857a6479f" width="5064" height="3384" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-02/e9396220-720f-11eb-9f2f-536857a6479f" width="5064" height="3384" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Chesnot via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[PARIS, FRANCE - OCTOBER 31:  A gamer plays the video game 'Destiny 2' developed by Bungie Studios and published by Activision during the 'Paris Games Week' on October 31, 2017 in Paris, France. 'Paris Games Week' is an international trade fair for video games to be held from October 31 to November 5, 2017.  (Photo by Chesnot/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Paris Games Week 2017 : Day One At Porte De Versailles In Paris]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's latest big sale includes deals on 'Returnal' and 'The Last of Us Part II']]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony&#39;s latest big <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/afd7cea8-25fc-4274-8e2e-4e27c60f0bcc/1">PlayStation sale</a> is underway with discounts on hundreds of games. As the name of the Blockbuster Games sale suggests, you&#39;ll be able to save on a ton of major <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ps4">PS4</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ps5">PS5</a> titles. The sale runs until October 13th.</p><p>Some Sony exclusives are on the list, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/returnal"><em>Returnal</em></a> (which is down from $70 to $49.69), <em>Sackboy: A Big Adventure</em> ($34.79, usually $60), <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/the%20last%20of%20us%20part%20ii"><em>The Last Of Us Part II</em></a> ($26, saving you $14) and <em>God of War </em>($10, half off). The deluxe edition of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/days%20gone"><em>Days Gone</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>($30) is actually less expensive than the $40 regular version at the minute.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Third-party titles on sale include <a href="https://www.engadget.com/cyberpunk-2077-playstation-store-124829914.html"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a> ($33.49, usually $50), <em>Mortal Kombat 11</em> (down from $50 to $12.49) and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/outriders-xbox-game-pass-irl-150014907.html"><em>Outriders</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>($36, typically $60). A bunch of Call of Duty and Assassin&#39;s Creed games are included as well. Among them are 2019&#39;s <em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare </em>(half off at $30) and <em>Assassin&#39;s Creed Valhalla</em>, which is down 25 percent to $45.&nbsp;</p><p>If you didn&#39;t pick up <em>Star Wars: Squadrons </em>when it was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ps-plus-june-2021-games-star-wars-squadrons-virtua-fighter-5-163808845.html">in the PlayStation Plus library</a> a while back, you can buy it now for $16 (usually $40). <em>Star Wars: Battlefront II</em>, meanwhile, is 70 percent off at $6.</p><p>In some cases, you&#39;ll save more if you&#39;re a PlayStation Plus member. Speaking of which, Sony has announced <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/29/playstation-plus-games-for-october-hell-let-loose-pga-tour-2k21-mortal-kombat-x/">the next batch of games</a> subscribers can snag at no extra cost. New tactical shooter <em>Hell Let Loose </em>(PS5), <em>Mortal Kombat X </em>and <em>PGA Tour 2K21</em> (both PS4) will be available to claim starting on October 5th. Until then, you can add <em>Predator: Hunting Grounds, Overcooked: All You Can Eat!</em> and <em>Hitman 2 </em>to your library.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-blockbuster-games-sale-ps4-ps5-returnal-the-last-of-us-part-ii-sackboy-203139000.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4f28230c-62a5-4e7a-913c-2afec8f01e6b</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 20:31:39 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632947502</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T20:31:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/e381ff20-c839-11ea-bf9f-473f43f5e614" width="883" height="552" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-07/e381ff20-c839-11ea-bf9f-473f43f5e614" width="883" height="552" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony / Naughty Dog]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitch lets streamers require verification before viewers can chat]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitch might have another way to deter &quot;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-sues-hate-raiders-cruzzcontrol-and-creatine-overdose-184439305.html">hate raids</a>&quot; and similar abuse: make it impractical to create a troll account. The livestreaming service has <a href="https://blog.twitch.tv/en/2021/09/29/securing-your-chat-with-phone-and-email-verification/">introduced</a> an option that lets streamers and moderators require one-time phone or email verification for chatters. Broadcasters can either require it for everyone or set  exemptions based on account age, follow duration or status. A streamer can require verification only for first-timers, for example, or waive the requirement for subscribers and VIPs.</p><p>The company will allow as many as five accounts to verify through one phone number for the sake of businesses. However, trolls can&#39;t rely on this to evade bans. Twitch will ban every account linked to a phone number if one of them faces a ban, whether it&#39;s one channel or across the entire service. You also can&#39;t use VOIP or landline numbers</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Twitch said it would gauge the impact of verification after launch. It also teased plans for another tool to fight ban evasion in the &quot;coming months.&quot;</p><p>This might not spook the most determined harassers. They may create new email addresses or borrow phone numbers. It might reduce the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitch-moderation-aoc-jimmy-fallon-adl-study-090014206.html">dependence on moderators</a> to curb bad behavior, however, and could discourage &#39;casual&#39; harassment from those who were previously unafraid to lose their accounts. Don&#39;t be surprised if you see fewer hit-and-run incidents the next time you&#39;re watching a stream.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/twitch-chat-verification-192256743.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2745e94c-2044-4069-b1d6-5de9cd6e1ecd</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 19:22:56 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632943380</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T19:23:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/24b69330-993a-11eb-9aef-3342bb79817d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/24b69330-993a-11eb-9aef-3342bb79817d" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Caspar Camille Rubin on Unsplash]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Twitch app on an iPhone]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Twitch app on an iPhone]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM's new software hub will update your next EV like a smartphone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Compared to what we were driving just a decade ago, today&#39;s connected cars and trucks are practically computers on wheels. From content streaming infotainment systems to the background processes that interpret sensor data and power the advanced driver assist features, software has become a fundamental component in modern vehicles. To better manage those countless lines of code, GM announced on Wednesday that it has developed an end-to-end software platform, dubbed Ulfiti (rhymes with &quot;multiply&quot;).</p><p>GM&#39;s latest vehicles already enjoy features like OTA software updates and on-board internet connectivity thanks to the company&#39;s Vehicle Intelligence Platform (VIP). the Linux-based Ulfiti is designed to sit on top of that existing architecture and serve as a central hub for select software systems, separating them from the vehicle&#39;s core operations.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>&quot;In all of the embedded controllers, we refactored them and extracted the software from the hardware out of them, making them available to our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service-oriented_architecture">SOA layer</a>,&quot; Scott Miller, Vice President of Software Defined Vehicle. at General Motors, said during a recent teleconference. &quot;Basically we&#39;re abstracting them and making them available for a powerful hub for all the vehicle&#39;s systems.&quot;</p><p>&quot;Then we&#39;re adding this service oriented layer on our high performance computing that we have in the vehicle for infotainment and safety,&quot; he continued. &quot;And we&#39;re going to organize those abstractions as services.&quot;</p><p>This will enable GM to more quickly develop and deploy updates, new features and apps to customers. In essence, Ultifi will serve a similar function as Android does on smartphones — an API layer sitting between the underlying hardware and the end user. GM did note that Ultifi will run in conjunction with existing automotive OSes, such as Android Automotive, which GM announced in 2019 it would begin supporting.&nbsp;</p><p>&quot;Android Automotive is a certain subset of functionality in the car,&quot; Darryl Harrison, GM&#39;s Director of Global Product Development, explained. &quot;Ultifi is more of an umbrella overall strategy. Some vehicles will have Android Automotive and some will have other infotainment apps and services.&quot;</p><p>In essence, GM wants to treat your vehicle like a rolling smartphone, offering users continuous OTA updates, cloud-based personalization options that drivers can transfer between GM vehicles, and smart home connectivity. The company is also considering pushing out various safety and comfort upgrades through via OTA, such as using the vehicle&#39;s onboard cameras to automatically engage the child locks when they detect children in the back seat or remotely closing the vehicle&#39;s sunroof if you parked outdoors and the weather forecast calls for rain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>GM is also considering using Ultifi to offer subscription services to users, such as on-demand Supercruise that drivers can enable on long road trips but cancel once they reach their destination. Ulfiti could also allow for improved V2V (vehicle to vehicle) and V2X (vehicle to everything) applications including near-real time traffic and road hazard updates. Expect to see Ulfiti in select GM vehicles — both internal combustion and EV — starting in 2023.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gm-ultifi-software-hub-update-ev-smartphone-190041857.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bd22d307-986d-4929-ba8e-f1d2d164be42</guid><dc:creator>Andrew Tarantola</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 19:00:41 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632945596</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T19:59:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Andrew Tarantola]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/29cbf850-06a0-11ec-ab45-bd72c97d6ea1" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/29cbf850-06a0-11ec-ab45-bd72c97d6ea1" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bill Pugliano via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[DETROIT, MI - AUGUST 05: A GMC Hummer EV truck is shown at General Motors Factory Zero on August 5, 2021 in Detroit, Michigan. Secretary Granholm is touring several manufacturing facilities in southeast Michigan today to help promote the Biden administrations infrastructure proposal. (Photo by Bill Pugliano/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Energy Sec. Granholm Tours Manufacturing Plants In Michigan]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Lens is coming to Chrome on the desktop]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You no longer have to point your phone at your computer screen if you want to use <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-lens-socratic-math-problems-102931355.html">Google Lens</a> on your computer. As part of a string of updates, Google has <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1443265782067220483">revealed</a> that Lens will be available for Chrome on the desktop in the &quot;coming months.&quot; You just have to right-click on a website, choose to search with Lens and select the part of the page you want to examine. After that, you&#39;ll get results relating to the content you highlighted. Needless to say, that could be helpful if you&#39;re trying to identify an animal or a hot new jacket.</p><p>There are some upgrades coming to Lens on your phone. An update in early 2022 will let you ask a question after snapping a photo. If you need to know how to repair a part on your bike, for instance, you&#39;ll get results even if you don&#39;t know what that part is. The Google app for iPhones, meanwhile, will let you search for products within images.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This is a not-so-subtle effort to boost Google Shopping. You might be more likely to buy apparel or bike parts if you can identify them, after all. Even so, the expansion could make Lens more useful as a general search tool, not just for special circumstances.</p><div id="a7d5815c8a9a4985bbaf92b2929b029a"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Inspiration can strike at any time. ⚡ Soon you&#39;ll be able to use <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleLens?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoogleLens</a> to instantly search for products within images while browsing on the Google app on iPhone. And psst… Lens is coming to Chrome on desktop too 👀 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SearchOn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SearchOn</a><a href="https://t.co/HTQCz7sjoO">pic.twitter.com/HTQCz7sjoO</a></p>— Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1443265782067220483?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p><div id="1eef0f95c28844a898defd22ae89126d"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">MUM, our advanced AI model, is coming to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleLens?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoogleLens</a> early next year. You’ll be able to snap a photo AND ask a question, which can be helpful in those moments you need to fix a broken part and have no idea what it is 🤷🔧 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SearchOn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SearchOn</a><a href="https://t.co/cmedce3dB2">pic.twitter.com/cmedce3dB2</a></p>— Google (@Google) <a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1443262726697070594?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-lens-chrome-desktop-174633237.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f78f5c15-1aba-41c5-9b66-6c4ecd1ebed7</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 17:46:33 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632937596</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T17:46:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e7a32cd0-214a-11ec-b77b-f86186a9fb12" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e7a32cd0-214a-11ec-b77b-f86186a9fb12" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Lens on Chrome for desktop computers]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Lens on Chrome for desktop computers]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google wants to streamline the tricky process of assigning addresses in rural areas]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many places in the world that don&#39;t have an address system, which can restrict the opportunities available for people who live and work in those areas. Without an address, you can&#39;t get mail or packages, nor can you vote or sign up for bank accounts, for example. Emergency responders can&#39;t even find you easily if you don&#39;t have an address. Google&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-maps-plus-codes-android-address-system-160019436.html">open-source Plus Codes system</a> has been around since 2015 to help assign addresses to places, matching a series of letters and numbers to a set of latitude and longitude coordinates.</p><p>But, according to Google, &quot;previously, creating addresses for an entire town or village could take years.&quot; The company is releasing a new tool today called Address Maker that would make mass generation of these codes easier for governments and organizations. Google said that governments and non-government organizations (NGOs) in Kenya, India, South African and the US are already using Address Maker, &quot;with more partners on the way.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Anyone can enter one of these codes, which look like &quot;P2J5+7C,&quot; into Google Maps and see where that place is or get directions. For people who already have existing addresses that are long or complicated, these could be helpful in making sure your contacts find you at the correct spot. If you&#39;ve ever tried to send a package to an industrial area in a country you&#39;re not familiar with, you&#39;ll probably find Plus Codes helpful, too.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/100afd00-213d-11ec-9ddf-45c99c7c5324" alt="An animated GIF showing how Google&#39;s new Address Maker app works. " data-uuid="d1101c03-f2ba-340c-9043-4e1650a95f30"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>Address Maker is a free Android app and shorted the previously years-long process to a few weeks, Google said. Based on an animated render, it appears you can outline segments on a map and add addresses for multiple structures within the area at once. You can check out <a href="http://g.co/maps/addressmaker">Google&#39;s page</a> for more help, especially if you&#39;re part of a local government or NGO.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-address-maker-plus-codes-app-174025559.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">01d535e5-265d-49ff-b9b7-aa477355acd7</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 17:40:25 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632937519</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T17:45:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/eab711a0-214c-11ec-a17f-e5aa036c9a1b" width="1724" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/eab711a0-214c-11ec-a17f-e5aa036c9a1b" width="1724" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Address Maker]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Address Maker]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google adds more information to its ‘About this result’ feature]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the start of the year, Google added a feature to its search engine called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-about-this-result-193227324.html">About This Result</a>. By tapping on the three dots icon located next to most results, the tool allows you to find out more about a website before you navigate to it. With the initial rollout of About This Result, Google displayed information from Wikipedia, and, if that wasn’t available, it pulled what it could from one of its services. The panels also included details about the website like when it was first indexed by the company, and if you could expect a secure connection.</p><p>Today, Google is making those panels more robust by adding to the diversity of information they display. To start, in addition to a description from Wikipedia, you’ll see what each website has to say about itself in its own words. You will also see what others have had to say about them — be that through reviews or a simple news article. In the “about the topic” section, Google will include other coverage or results from different sources.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>As before, the idea behind the About This Result feature is to save you an extra search when you want to find out more about a website you’re about to visit. Google also sees it as a way to help people make more informed decisions about how they use the internet and provide peace of mind if you’re looking for important information related to important topics.&nbsp;</p><p>Aside from these &quot;Information Literacy features,&quot; the company also announced new features coming to its results pages during its Search On event today. They&#39;re called Things to Know, Refine This Search, Broaden This Search and Related Topics to its results to make it easier to learn more about different topics. Things To Know, for example, will pull up the basics you&#39;ll need to understand a new subject, while refining and broadening your search can help you explore related issues.</p><p>Google Search users in the US will see today&#39;s expansion roll out over the coming weeks and months.</p><p><em>Cherlynn Low contributed to this post.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-about-this-result-update-170038402.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c0c58ef1-0741-4090-9a72-b41811386d25</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic,Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 17:35:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632937373</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T17:43:03+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/73d50060-2142-11ec-afeb-321198cb8e51" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/73d50060-2142-11ec-afeb-321198cb8e51" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google About the Source]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google About the Source]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Maps will roll out wildfire tracking worldwide]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google has introduced a wildfire layer for Maps, allowing users around the world to keep a close eye on multiple fires at once. The tech giant says this new feature builds on the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-maps-california-colorado-wildfire-tracking-hourly-142455609.html">wildfire boundary map</a> it rolled out in the US last year and it&#39;s meant to help people &quot;make quick, informed decisions during times of emergency.&quot; With the layer enabled, users will be able to see the wildfires raging in their location — tapping on any of them will bring up links to emergency websites, helpline numbers and evacuation details provided by local government.&nbsp;</p><p>If available, the tool will also show details about the fire, including its containment, the acres it has already burned and the time that information was last reported. The wildfire layer will start its global rollout to Android devices this week and to iOS devices and PCs in October. While it will display most major fires — the kind that necessitates evacuations — around the world, it&#39;ll have the capability to display smaller incidents in the US, thanks to data provided by the National Interagency Fire Center. Google is planning to offer that level of detail in more locations, starting with Australia in the coming months.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e5c88d20-210d-11ec-ba8f-18765f47d12c" alt="Google" data-uuid="ff564a74-8314-3e8b-9a96-1be4cb7ce021"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p>In addition, Google is expanding the information available through its Tree Canopy tool. At the moment, it can only provide data for 15 cities in the US, but it&#39;ll be able to show information for 100 cities around the world in 2022. Google&#39;s Tree Canopy Insights combines AI capabilities with aerial data to determine the parts of a city with the greatest risk of rapidly rising temperatures. It could help local governments figure out where to plant trees and where to focus any project they may have to fight climate change. Los Angeles authorities, for instance, are already using the tool to help them increase the city&#39;s tree canopy by 50 percent by 2028. While Google didn&#39;t say which cities are getting access to the tool by next year, it said Guadalajara, London, Sydney and Toronto are in the list.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-maps-wildfire-tracking-worldwide-170837067.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1bc2e388-1135-4ad1-a04f-d2cac2d76a5e</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 17:08:37 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632935321</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T17:08:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e3ad2400-2109-11ec-ba9f-88ec9d360ea2" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e3ad2400-2109-11ec-ba9f-88ec9d360ea2" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Kara Capaldo via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Firefighters battleing fire as Flames approaching Highway 50 during Caldor Fire in California]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Caldor Fire California]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[IMDb's free TV service arrives in the UK]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Folks in the UK looking for a show or movie to stream have even more options at their disposal. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/imdb%20tv"><ins>IMDb TV</ins></a> is now available in the country.</p><p>The free, ad-supported service offers a mix of originals and popular movies and shows from elsewhere, as <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/09/amazon-launches-ad-supported-streamer-imdb-tv-uk-1234846526/"><em><ins>Variety</ins></em></a> notes. Alongside IMDB TV&#39;s own projects such as <em>Luke Bryan: My Dirt Road Diary</em>, <em>Moment of Truth</em> and <em>Top Class: The Life and Times of the Sierra Canyon Trailblazers</em>, you can watch the likes of <em>Pulp Fiction, Anger Management, The English Patient, Person of Interest, Community</em> and <em>2 Broke Girls</em>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You can access IMDb TV through the Prime Video app, even if you aren&#39;t an Amazon Prime member. A Fire TV app is on the way in the coming weeks. Standalone IMDb TV apps for Android and iOS <a href="https://www.engadget.com/imdb-tv-standalone-apps-android-ios-053142618.html"><ins>hit the US last month</ins></a>, so perhaps they&#39;ll be available in the UK later as well.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/imdb-tv-uk-amazon-prime-video-163945431.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4bfcf614-ce05-4aa3-adb8-31393c48e689</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 16:39:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632933590</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T16:39:52+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/ddb30d60-2142-11ec-bfdd-32face65b118" width="1366" height="768" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/ddb30d60-2142-11ec-bfdd-32face65b118" width="1366" height="768" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony Pictures Television]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A scene from Community's Troy and Abed in the Morning skit.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Community]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA['Mandalorian' spin-off 'The Book of Boba Fett' premieres December 29th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Disney said <a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-book-of-boba-fett-mandalorian-spin-off-series-143119062.html"><em>The Book of Boba Fett</em></a> would premiere this December, and it&#39;s making good on its promise — if only just. The media giant has <a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/the-book-of-boba-fett-premiere">revealed</a> that the<em> Mandalorian</em> spin-off will debut December 29th on <a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/LP2JEZ">Disney+</a>. The art accompanying the release date doesn&#39;t show much, but you can assume Boba Fett won&#39;t suffer fools lightly. (Caution: mild <em>Mandalorian</em> spoliers ahead.)</p><p>The series follows Boba Fett and his mercenary ally Fennec Shand shortly after the end of <em>Mandalorian</em> season two, as the pair return to Tatooine and lay claim to Jabba the Hutt&#39;s former territory. Temeura Morrison and Ming-Na Wen will reprise their respective roles. Producers from the earlier show are helming this latest project, including Jon Favreau, Robert Rodriguez and Kathleen Kennedy.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This won&#39;t satisfy fans looking for <em>Mandalorian</em> season three, which will <a href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/tv/a35013423/the-mandalorian-season-3/">only arrive after</a><em>Boba Fett</em>. It does give fans another <a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-wars-visions-marvel-studios-what-if-season-one-153109359.html">Star Wars fix</a> before the end of 2021, at least, and it ensures you&#39;ll have another major Disney+ show to watch once you&#39;ve finished with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-hawkeye-trailer-premiere-date-clint-barton-kate-bishop-hailee-steinfeld-140006373.html"><em>Hawkeye</em></a>.</p><div id="95c7030435174e56880f53f466ad3f1e"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">His story is only beginning. The Book of <a href="https://twitter.com/bobafett?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BobaFett</a>, an all-new Original Series, starts streaming December 29 on <a href="https://twitter.com/disneyplus?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DisneyPlus</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheBookOfBobaFett?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TheBookOfBobaFett</a><a href="https://t.co/bWPg0D0Z6l">pic.twitter.com/bWPg0D0Z6l</a></p>— Star Wars (@starwars) <a href="https://twitter.com/starwars/status/1443229087980457986?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-book-of-boba-fett-release-date-disney-plus-161153623.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8f0a9334-b081-43cb-a04b-c0cb87fc3002</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 16:11:53 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632934470</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T16:54:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c6f0e9a0-2145-11ec-bebe-37adc0853ead" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/c6f0e9a0-2145-11ec-bebe-37adc0853ead" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Disney]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Star Wars The Book of Boba Fett]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Star Wars The Book of Boba Fett]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rachel Brosnahan's golden arm outshines the rest of Roku's Halloween lineup]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/quibi"><ins>Quibi</ins></a> tried and failed to create much of a buzz last year with its mobile video streaming service. But there was at least one thing from the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/quibi-is-dead-222257192.html">ill-fated platform</a> that went viral: a scene from a show where Rachel Brosnahan, of <em>The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel </em>fame, plays a woman with a golden arm. You&#39;ll soon be able to relive that moment of pop culture history thanks to <a href="http://engadget.com/tag/roku"><ins>Roku</ins></a>.</p><div id="77993400f551429b95d2eb9e093d6eec"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Losing my fucking MIND at this Quibi show where actual Emmy winner Rachel Brosnahan plays a woman obsessed with her golden arm <a href="https://t.co/rSfqCv75SG">pic.twitter.com/rSfqCv75SG</a></p>— Zach Raffio (@zachraffio) <a href="https://twitter.com/zachraffio/status/1250273191810875392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 15, 2020</a></blockquote></div><p>When Quibi closed shop, Roku <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-buys-quibi-shows-151546993.html"><ins>bought</ins></a> the company&#39;s content and rebranded the shows as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-quibi-originals-streaming-roku-channel-130012993.html"><ins>Roku Originals</ins></a>. It didn&#39;t re-release <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-originals-quibi-may-20th-streaming-day-130016440.html"><ins>all of those series</ins></a> right away though, and it&#39;s marking Halloween season with three horror-themed Originals. First up as part of the Freak Out Friday season is <em>When the Streetlights Go On</em>, which hits The Roku Channel on October 15th. The &#39;90s-set show centers on a double homicide that took place in a midwestern suburb.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The following Friday, you&#39;ll be able to watch anthology series <em>50 States of Fright</em>. The first episode of that show is where you can hear a doctor tell a woman with a metallic arm that she has &quot;pulmonary gold disease.” Quibi, in case you need a reminder, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/quibi-shut-down-155124687.html"><ins>shut up shop</ins></a> less than eight months after it debuted.</p><p>Lastly, on October 29th, you&#39;ll be able to catch <em>The Expecting</em>, a sci-fi thriller that tells the story of a strange pregnancy. As well as on Roku devices, The Roku Channel is available on the web, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-channel-fire-tv-now-available-210537235.html"><ins>Amazon Fire TV</ins></a>, mobile devices and some <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-03-20-roku-free-movie-channel-on-samsung-smart-tvs-summer.html"><ins>Samsung TVs</ins></a>.</p><p>In August, Roku added <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-adds-more-quibi-shows-to-original-144530038.html"><ins>another 23 Quibi shows</ins></a> to its streaming library. The company is also working on its first original film, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-first-original-movie-christmas-140518395.html"><em><ins>Zoey’s Extraordinary Christmas</ins></em></a>, which continues the story of the canceled NBC show <em>Zoey&#39;s Extraordinary Playlist</em>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/roku-originals-horror-october-the-golden-arm-160004270.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c04be5d2-066a-460e-b23b-f2224b52bf4e</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632931166</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T15:59:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e194ea30-213c-11ec-bfef-f1ee2820bd78" width="1152" height="648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e194ea30-213c-11ec-bfef-f1ee2820bd78" width="1152" height="648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Roku]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A screenshot from The Golden Arm episode of Roku's 50 States of Fright.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[The Golden Arm episode of Roku's 50 States of Fright]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk tells Jeff Bezos you can't 'sue your way to the Moon' (updated)]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk isn&#39;t fond of Jeff Bezos&#39; Blue Origin, and he just made that patently clear. <em>CNET</em><a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/elon-musk-on-blue-origin-suing-nasa-you-cant-sue-your-way-to-the-moon/">reports</a> that Musk told <a href="https://voxmediaevents.com/code2021">Code</a> conference attendees Bezos should put more effort into &quot;getting into orbit than lawsuits,&quot; and that you couldn&#39;t &quot;sue your way to the Moon&quot; as Blue Origin allegedly tried when it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-federal-claims-court-nasa-challenge-163927526.html">lost its lunar lander bid</a>. He was also less-than-flattering to Virgin Galactic, describing its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-richard-branson-spaceflight-complete-154012847.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">first passenger flight</a> and Blue Origin&#39;s as &quot;a step in the direction of orbit&quot; that fell short of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/watch-spacex-inspiration4-splashdown-live-stream-214529012.html">SpaceX&#39;s efforts</a>.</p><p>While Musk is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-08-elon-musk-painted-as-thin-skinned-billionaire-in-court-documen.html">known for being harsh</a>, he might have some support in this case. <em>The Verge</em> has <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22689729/blue-origin-moon-lunar-lander-price-nasa-hls-foia">obtained</a> NASA legal documents showing that the space agency felt Blue Origin &quot;gambled&quot; with its originally proposed $5.9 billion lunar lander price. Bezos&#39; company allegedly set the price far higher than necessary as it expected NASA to award the contract and negotiate for a lower cost. Blue Origin also reportedly assumed NASA would get the full funding from Congress needed for that initial price, even as the Senate made clear NASA wouldn&#39;t get the necessary amount.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>You know what happened next. Rather than haggle the price, NASA picked the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-nasa-artemis-lunar-lander-contract-report-184448656.html">$2.9 billion SpaceX bid</a>. Blue Origin <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gao-denies-blue-origin-dynetics-protest-nasa-human-landing-system-181019362.html">challenged the award</a> and even made a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-nasa-open-letter-181522642.html">last-ditch $2 billion offer</a>, but by then it was too late. The Government Accountability Office <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gao-denies-blue-origin-dynetics-protest-nasa-human-landing-system-181019362.html">rejected Blue Origin&#39;s claims</a>, saying NASA didn&#39;t violate regulations in picking SpaceX. Bezos&#39; outfit took NASA to court roughly two weeks later.</p><p>In an interview, Blue Origin VP Megan Mitchell told <em>The Verge</em> the company rejected NASA&#39;s views. She felt Blue Origin made a &quot;great offer&quot; and that it disagreed with NASA&#39;s gambling characterization. The GAO separately said NASA partly botched its safety review requirements for the proposal, although it still sided with SpaceX on grounds that Blue Origin didn&#39;t explain how the move provided an unfair edge.</p><p>This isn&#39;t to say Musk and SpaceX are innocent. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-22-spacex-sues-over-air-force-contracts.html">SpaceX sued the US</a> in 2019 after it lost an Air Force rocket contract to Blue Origin and other competitors, for example. It&#39;s just that Musk&#39;s trash talking appears to carry some weight in this modern Moon race.</p><p><strong>Update 9/29 5PM ET:</strong> An Amazon spokesperson, not Blue Origin, emailed Engadget claiming SpaceX has a &quot;long track record&quot; of suing the US government over contracts and other decisions. To that end, it even sent a lengthy document listing 16 lawsuits and regulatory objections from SpaceX. Most of them are FCC oppositions, and some of the other issues are quite old (such as a 2004 lawsuit). One thing&#39;s for certain: the slap fight between Musk and Bezos is getting uglier by the day.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-on-blue-origin-lawsuit-151130133.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c5dceae2-669d-432e-bd0b-bc16a12e0509</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 15:11:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632949364</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T21:02:46+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d85fc750-fe4b-11eb-8e55-f2f4f16e40da" width="3678" height="2706" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d85fc750-fe4b-11eb-8e55-f2f4f16e40da" width="3678" height="2706" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[PATRICK PLEUL via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[US entrepreneur and business magnate Elon Musk gestures during a visit at the Tesla Gigafactory plant under construction, on August 13, 2021 in Gruenheide near Berlin, eastern Germany. (Photo by Patrick Pleul / POOL / AFP) (Photo by PATRICK PLEUL/POOL/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[GERMANY-US-POLITICS-ELECTION-ECONOMY-TESLA]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook will promote Instagram Reels in News Feed]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook’s TikTok clone is no longer just for Instagram. As of today, the social network is officially <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/launching-reels-on-facebook-in-us/">bringing Reels</a> to the main Facebook app. With the change, users can create Reels directly from Facebook, and the company will recommend the short-form videos in all users’ News Feeds.</p><p>Facebook has been testing out various ways of bringing Reels out of Instagram for awhile, and began testing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-reels-us-test-172544167.html">cross-posting</a> features last month. Now, it’s also testing a feature that allows Reels creators on Instagram to promote their videos in Facebook’s News Feed directly, even if they don’t use the app.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Reels has become increasingly important to facebook and its efforts to challenge TikTok. The company has been steadily adding features to the service, and is attempting to lure creators with the promise <a href="https://www.engadget.com/why-facebook-is-betting-1-billion-on-creators-170006159.html">of payouts</a> for hitting certain milestones. Now, the company is adding a new &quot;invite-only&quot; bonus program to coincide with Reels&#39; launch on Facebook and encourage creators to start posting on the social network.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/f12971b0-20b4-11ec-bb4b-b96d9cf78b11" alt="Facebook will let creators promote Reels in News Feed." data-uuid="024d135b-be6f-3b4a-8c7f-b7e542d6f385"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Facebook</div></figure><p>But it’s the potential challenge to TikTok that could be most significant for the company. Documents reported by <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> show that Facebook has been <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-instagram-kids-tweens-attract-11632849667">struggling</a> to incentivize teens and younger users to post original content. Internally, the company is reportedly worried about ceding influence to TikTok, where teens spend much more time than on Facebook’s apps.</p><p>Promoting Reels in the main Facebook app, which is already not especially popular with teens, may not seem like the most direct way to solve that. But getting more eyes on users’ Reels will help the feature grow even if its top users don’t spend much time on Facebook itself.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-reels-news-feed-launch-150057328.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bbe1097b-1985-4b88-b1f7-c66e5a5fb778</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632929038</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T15:24:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/77018340-20b5-11ec-b9df-e1c64e339228" width="2047" height="1140" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/77018340-20b5-11ec-b9df-e1c64e339228" width="2047" height="1140" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Reels are coming to Facebook.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook Reels]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sony's latest true wireless earbuds are only $100]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sony&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wh-1000xm4-headphones-review-150050779.html">flagship noise-cancelling headphones</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-160006474.html">tech-filled true wireless earbuds</a> were refreshed with new 1000XM4 models in recent months. However, the company&#39;s more affordable options are still due for a refresh, and Sony begins that process today. With the <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/audio/headphones/truly-wireless/p/wfc500">WF-C500</a>, the company offers a solid set of true wireless earbuds capable of handling immersive 360 Reality Audio for $100. And if over-ear noise-cancelling headphones are more your vibe, the <a href="https://electronics.sony.com/audio/headphones/headband/p/whxb910n">WF-XB910N</a> pairs ANC (active noise cancellation) with 30-hour battery life for $250.&nbsp;</p><p>The true wireless WF-C500 replaces the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/sony-wf-xb700-review-true-wireless-earbuds-163042660.html">WF-XB700</a> at the bottom of Sony&#39;s price range. What&#39;s more, they&#39;re $30 cheaper than the XB700 was initially at $99.99. This substitution is a good thing because despite handling the basics well, the tiered design wasn&#39;t as ergonomic or comfy as the company suggested. With the WF-C500, Sony takes design cues from its high-end WF-1000XM4 earbuds. The result is smaller size and a more secure fit that should be more comfortable during hours of continuous use. And an IPX4 rating means you can use these during workouts without worrying about moisture damage.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Inside, the C500 is equipped with Sony&#39;s DSEE (Digital Sound Enhancement Engine) that restores some of the detail lost when music is compressed for streaming over Bluetooth. The company also allows you employ sound presets and adjust the EQ with its Headphones app. Plus, you have the option of listening in Sony&#39;s 360 Reality Audio if you&#39;re willing to splurge for the priciest streaming plan on select services (Amazon Music HD, Tidal HiFi, etc.). On-board controls give you the ability to manage music, adjust volume, take calls and activate a voice assistant without reaching for your phone. Lastly, the C500 will give you up to 10 hours of listening time with one additional charge in the included case. A quick-charge feature offers an hour of tunes in 10 minutes.&nbsp;</p><p>The WF-C500 is available for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:pre-order" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CFP6J6D/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">pre-order</a> today, but colors vary by retailer. Sony will offer them in black, as will <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CFP6J6D/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">Amazon</a>, Best Buy and Target. Exclusive colors include white (<a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CFP6J6D/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">Amazon</a>), green (Best Buy) and orange (Target). The earbuds are set to ship in October.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/8888e3c0-2122-11ec-988d-273ba59d1db8" alt="Sony XB-910N" data-uuid="839cb176-84c6-3bdb-8012-1e70167e5b04"><figcaption>Sony XB-910N</figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Sony</div></figure><p>For the over-ear noise-cancelling crowd, the WH-XB910N replaces the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-06-25-sony-xb900n-noise-cancelling-headphones-review.html">WH-XB900N</a> in the middle of Sony&#39;s headphone lineup. The price stays the same at $249.99, but the company offers a new design and improved ANC thanks to a Dual Noise Sensor. As the &quot;XB&quot; signifies, this model is equipped with the company&#39;s Extra Bass feature that amps up the low-end tone when activated. DSEE tech makes streaming over Bluetooth a bit more enjoyable by restoring detail lost to compression. The XB910N can also manage Sony&#39;s 360 Reality Audio content and employs Adaptive Sound Control, a staple of the company&#39;s pricier headphones, that can automatically adjust settings based on activity or location.&nbsp;</p><p>Sony is also angling at the remote working crowd here. The company explains that Precise Voice Pickup tech uses a combination of microphones and signal processing to amplify your voice on calls. There&#39;s also &quot;a more natural listening experience&quot; in ambient sound mode as Sony says the XB910N can pick up more of what&#39;s going on around you. That&#39;s handy whether you need to stay tuned in to what&#39;s going on either at home or in the office. On-board controls include Sony&#39;s quick attention feature which lets outside noise in when you place your hand over an earcup and there&#39;s a dedicated button to quickly change from ANC to ambient sound.&nbsp;</p><p>Sony says the XB910N will last up to 30 hours with the option of 4.5 hours of listening time after a 10-minute quick charge. To further cater to travelers, the company opted for soft, oval-shaped earpads for extra cushion and a design that folds flat for easy storage. If you prefer to save even more on your noise-cancelling headphones, the excellent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-04-01-sony-wh-ch710n-headphones-announced-price-specs-availability.html">WH-CH710N</a> will stick around and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:are currently $98" href="https://amzn.to/3B70fzT">are currently $98</a>. Although they lack a lot of the handy features from Sony&#39;s other models, the noise-cancelling CH710N are light and comfy, handling the basics very well for that price.</p><p>The WF-C500 is available for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:pre-order" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CGB6VRR/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">pre-order</a> today, and once again, the colors vary by retailer. Sony will offer them in black, as will <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CGB6VRR/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">Amazon</a> and Best Buy. Exclusive colors include blue (<a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09CGB6VRR/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;language=en_US">Amazon</a>) and gray (Best Buy). The headphones are scheduled to ship in October.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sony-wf-c500-earbuds-wh-xb910n-headphones-announced-150013440.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">6b3024ff-dbf3-4c48-8d67-91b5a911db11</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632921565</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T13:19:37+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Game Consoles]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/55b85f30-211c-11ec-bece-b41ddf3e6f75" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/55b85f30-211c-11ec-bece-b41ddf3e6f75" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sony WF-C500]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Sony WF-C500]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce plans to stop making gas-powered cars by 2030]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another major automaker has revealed plans to move entirely to electric vehicles within the next decade. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/rolls-royce">Rolls-Royce</a> is the latest one to make the pledge, following other luxury brands such as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jaguar-will-only-make-electric-cars-starting-in-2025-121436428.html">Jaguar</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lincoln-all-electric-vehicles-2030-100028732.html">Lincoln</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bentley-plugin-hybrid-ev-2026-094121635.html">Bentley</a>.</p><p>Spectre, Rolls-Royce&#39;s first EV (and one that sounds like it&#39;s rolling off the set of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-12-25-radiohead-spectre-theme-tune-soundcloud.html">a James Bond film</a>), will arrive in the last quarter of 2023. The BMW brand plans to start testing the vehicle soon, according to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/29/luxury-carmaker-rolls-royce-to-switch-to-all-electric-vehicles-by-2030.html"><em>Reuters</em></a>. Rolls-Royce teased the EV in some images, but it literally kept the Spectre&#39;s design under wraps.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/3f627ab0-2133-11ec-bdff-4ccfed34848a" alt="Rolls-Royce Spectre EV tease" data-uuid="c7df837e-fd5e-386d-915d-a0e7ef331387"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Rolls-Royce</div></figure><p>Rolls-Royce CEO Torsten Muller-Otvos said that by 2030, the automaker &quot;will no longer be in the business of producing or selling any internal combustion engine products.&quot; Sibling brand Mini has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mini-to-go-all-electric-by-2030-174220353.html">made a similar pledge</a>. Parent company BMW has not set a date for making a full switch to EVs, though it aims to move half of production to electric models by the end of this decade.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/rolls-royce-electric-vehicle-spectre-2030-145128453.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d53265a8-dfc7-4a55-9b22-a6ca8d84c8bf</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 14:51:28 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632927401</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T14:56:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/43a97330-2133-11ec-b7fe-53aa7f47a06a" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/43a97330-2133-11ec-b7fe-53aa7f47a06a" width="3840" height="2160" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce Spectre EV tease]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce Spectre EV tease]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jeep's Grand Cherokee plug-in hybrid will arrive in early 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As promised, Jeep has detailed its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeep-2022-grand-cherokee-4xe-debut-september-29-173239673.html">first Grand Cherokee plug-in hybrid</a>. The company has <a href="https://media.stellantisnorthamerica.com/newsrelease.do?id=23144&amp;mid=">confirmed</a> the Grand Cherokee 4xe will arrive in North American dealers in early 2022, and will sport more capabilities than you might have expected. The estimated 25 miles of all-electric driving (440 miles total) won&#39;t necessarily cover your entire commute, but Jeep is promising a rough-and-ready PHEV that can climb hills without touching the 2.0L turbo gas engine. You can also drive in a full hybrid mode for peak performance and an &quot;eSave&quot; mode to preserve the 17kWh battery for later.</p><p>You can also expect new technology inside, such as 10-inch front and rear passenger displays with built-in Fire TV — your kids can stream Prime Video in the backseat. The driver, meanwhile, gets a 10-inch display with a much faster Uconnect 5 platform that supports over-the-air updates.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The 4xe and its regular counterparts are improved off-roaders with semi-active damping for air suspension as well as a front-axle disconnect when the SUV senses it doesn&#39;t need all-wheel drive. You&#39;ll also get semi-autonomous help through an optional Active Driving Assist system that takes over so long as your hands are on the wheel and your eyes are on the road. Jeep is promising a 6,000lbs maximum towing capacity.</p><p>Jeep hasn&#39;t divulged pricing for the Grand Cherokee 4xe, although it will be available in increasingly loaded Limited, Trailhawk, Overland, Summit and Summit Reserve editions. It&#39;s already safe to say this is an important vehicle for the brand, though. Parent company Stellantis is racing to catch up with rivals in electrifying its vehicles, with plans for a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeep-4xe-2025-plan-200527710.html">fully electric version of every SUV</a> by 2025. The plug-in hybrid is a critical first step in that direction.</p><div id="5d876757aa724fbc8da23c5b2cb894f5"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FucFL3G7VXY?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jeep-grand-cherokee-4xe-plug-in-hybrid-141057823.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2c4a2df4-297e-47cb-96e9-eacf46295378</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 14:10:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632924660</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T14:11:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/86e297b0-212b-11ec-8bef-bda4f50680f5" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/86e297b0-212b-11ec-8bef-bda4f50680f5" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Stellantis]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Jeep Grand Cherokee 4xe plug-in hybrid]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Jeep Grand Cherokee 4xe plug-in hybrid]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[YouTube bans all content containing vaccine misinformation]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/youtube">YouTube</a> has <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/managing-harmful-vaccine-content-youtube/">banned all videos</a> containing misinformation about vaccines that are currently administered and have been approved by local health authorities or the World Health Organization. The measure is an expansion of a policy covering COVID-19 vaccines.</p><p>The service says that users <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/11161123">shouldn&#39;t</a>, for instance, post videos in which they claim that vaccines lead to chronic side effects (other than rare side effects that health authorities have acknowledged); content that alleges vaccines don&#39;t reduce transmission or contraction of diseases; or videos that have inaccuracies about vaccine ingredients.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="08bab1243245429585283de7f3f547e6"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4MpAKk1M-Ok?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>There are some exceptions. YouTube &quot;will continue to allow content about vaccine policies, new vaccine trials and historical vaccine successes or failures.&quot; Users can also share scientific discussions of vaccines and personal testimonials about their experiences, as long as they don&#39;t have a history of promoting vaccine misinformation and their video complies with YouTube&#39;s other rules. Posting videos that &quot;condemn, dispute or satirize misinformation&quot; that violates YouTube&#39;s policies should be okay too.</p><p>YouTube told the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/29/youtube-ban-joseph-mercola/"><em>Washington Post</em></a> that it&#39;s taking down channels linked to prominent anti-vaccine advocates, including Joseph Mercola and Robert F. Kennedy Jr. The reason it didn&#39;t move to ban all anti-vaccine content sooner is because it was focusing on COVID-19 vaccine misinformation.</p><p>“Developing robust policies takes time,” YouTube’s vice president of global trust and safety Matt Halprin told the publication. “We wanted to launch a policy that is comprehensive, enforceable with consistency and adequately addresses the challenge.”</p><p>YouTube, as well as Facebook and Twitter, banned <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-04-05-youtube-to-remove-5g-coronavirus-videos.html">COVID-19 misinformation</a> in the early days of the pandemic in the spring of 2020. YouTube has removed more than 130,000 videos that broke its rules about COVID-19 vaccines, which it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-bans-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation-145803592.html">announced last October</a>, and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/youtube-covid-19-misinformation-takedowns-201041091.html">more than a million videos in total</a> that included coronavirus misinformation.</p><p>Meanwhile, Facebook has been working to reduce the spread of anti-vaccine content <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-07-facebook-instagram-anti-vaccine-content.html">since at least 2019</a>. It formally <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-bans-vaccine-misinformation-193754704.html">banned vaccine misinformation</a> in February.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/youtube-anti-vaccine-video-ban-channel-takedowns-134545387.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8cb38046-9c35-4e62-b725-02b78c765516</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 13:45:45 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632947161</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T20:26:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e2757640-2128-11ec-bfee-fb7c51aee2d2" width="4900" height="3267" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/e2757640-2128-11ec-bfee-fb7c51aee2d2" width="4900" height="3267" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Pacific Press via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[COLOMBO, SRI LANKA - 2021/09/28: A health personnel extracts a dose of Pfizer-BioNTech vaccine against COVID-19 at the Sri Jayewardenepura Hospital in Colombo, as the country began inoculating children of over 12 years of age. (Photo by Saman Abesiriwardana/Pacific Press/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[A health personnel extracts a dose of Pfizer-BioNTech...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intense rhythm game 'Thumper' comes to Apple Arcade on October 1st]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple is adding another <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tetris-beat-available-today-apple-arcade-225345729.html">classic game</a> to Arcade&#39;s repertoire, albeit a relatively recent one. Drool&#39;s &quot;rhythm hell&quot; title <em>Thumper: Pocket Edition</em> will be available through the all-you-can-play subscription service starting October 1st for iPhone, iPad and Mac gamers. The mechanics will be familiar if you&#39;ve played the title on one of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-03-09-trippy-rhythm-action-game-thumper-is-coming-to-xbox-one.html">many other platforms</a>, but that doesn&#39;t make it any less intense — you&#39;re barrelling through a rhythm course at high speed, with precious little room for error.</p><p>The addition represents a familiar strategy for Apple. It&#39;s counting on recognizable and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-arcade-lego-star-wars-battles-exclusive-rts-180046178.html">sometimes exclusive</a> Arcade games to reel in subscribers and boost its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-q2-2021-earnings-210238898.html">increasingly important services business</a>. Not that you&#39;ll necessarily mind. <em>Thumper</em> normally costs $5 by itself, so this might tip the balance if you were already considering Arcade or an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-one-launch-date-210455448.html">Apple One</a> bundle.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/thumper-pocket-edition-apple-arcade-133019149.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">06c817b0-8789-45b9-a4c2-cd44dfb79640</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 13:30:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1632922223</ingested><modified>2021-09-29T13:30:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/4c2a1b90-2124-11ec-bdbf-d305aa787e0f" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/4c2a1b90-2124-11ec-bdbf-d305aa787e0f" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Drool]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA['Thumper: Pocket Edition' for Apple Arcade]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA['Thumper: Pocket Edition' for Apple Arcade]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>