<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2021</copyright><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 17:00:12 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Why is Facebook so bad at countering vaccine misinformation?]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been six months since Facebook announced a major reversal to its policies on vaccine misinformation. Faced with a rising tide of viral rumors and conspiracy theories, the company said it would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-bans-vaccine-misinformation-193754704.html"><ins>start removing</ins></a> vaccine mistruths from its platform. Notably, the effort not only encompassed content about COVID-19 vaccines, but all vaccines. That includes many of the kinds of claims it had long allowed, like those linking vaccines and autism, statements that vaccines are “toxic” or otherwise dangerous.</p><p>The move was widely praised, as disinformation researchers and public health officials have long urged <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/facebook"><ins>Facebook</ins></a> and other platforms to treat vaccine misinformation more aggressively. Since then, the company has banned some prominent anti-vaxxers, stopped recommending health-related groups and shown vaccine-related PSAs across Facebook and Instagram. It now labels <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/facebook-to-label-all-covid-19-vaccine-posts-with-pointer-to-official-info/"><ins>any post at all</ins></a> that mentions COVID-19 vaccines, whether factual or not.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Yet, despite these efforts, vaccine misinformation is still an urgent problem, and public health officials say Facebook and other social media platforms aren’t doing enough to address it. Last month, the Surgeon General issued <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-surgeon-general-health-misinformation-advisory-191241209.html"><ins>an advisory</ins></a> warning of the dangers of health misinformation online. The accompanying 22-page report didn’t call out any platforms by name, but it highlighted algorithmic amplification and other issues commonly associated with Facebook. The following day, President Joe Biden made headlines when he said that misinformation on Facebook was “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-surgeon-general-health-misinformation-advisory-191241209.html"><ins>killing people</ins></a>.”</p><p>While Facebook has <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/support-for-covid-19-vaccines-is-high-on-facebook-and-growing/"><ins>pushed back</ins></a>, citing its numerous efforts to quash health misinformation during the pandemic, the company’s past lax approach to vaccine misinformation has likely made that job much more difficult. In a statement, a Facebook spokesperson said vaccine hesitancy has decreased among its users in the US, but the company has also repeatedly rebuffed requests for more data that could shed light on just how big the problem really is.</p><p>“Since the beginning of the pandemic, we have removed 18 million pieces of COVID misinformation, labeled hundreds of millions of pieces of COVID content rated by our fact-checking partners, and connected over 2 billion people with authoritative information through tools like our COVID information center,” a Facebook spokesperson told Engadget. “The data shows that for people in the US on Facebook, vaccine hesitancy has declined by 50% since January, and acceptance is high. We will continue to enforce against any account or group that violates our COVID-19 and vaccine policies and offer tools and reminders for people who use our platform to get vaccinated.”</p><h2>Facebook’s pandemic decision</h2><p>Throughout the pandemic, Facebook has moderated health misinformation much <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-covid-forced-social-media-misinformation-reckoning-150051622.html"><ins>more aggressively</ins></a> than it has in the past. Yet for the first year of the pandemic, the company made <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-covid-forced-social-media-misinformation-reckoning-150051622.html"><ins>a distinction</ins></a> between coronavirus misinformation — e.g., statements about fake cures or disputing the effectiveness of masks, which it removed — and vaccine conspiracy theories, which <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-anti-vaxxers-coronavirus-conspiracy-theories-173021562.html"><ins>it said</ins></a> did not break the company’s rules. Mark Zuckerberg <a href="https://www.axios.com/coronavirus-vaccine-facebook-mark-zuckerberg-9eae01a2-e6b2-4f4c-a48c-986bac665a2b.html"><ins>even said</ins></a> that he would be reluctant to moderate vaccine misinformation the same way the company has with COVID misinformation.</p><p>That changed this year, with the advent of COVID-19 vaccines and the rising tide of misinformation and vaccine hesitancy that accompanied them, but the damage may have already been done. A peer-reviewed study published <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41562-021-01056-1"><ins>in </ins><em><ins>Nature</ins></em></a> in February found that exposure to misinformation about the COVID-19 vaccines “lowers intent to accept a COVID-19 vaccine” by about 6 percent.</p><p>People are also more likely to be unvaccinated if they primarily get their news from Facebook, according to <a href="https://osf.io/uvqbs/"><ins>a July report</ins></a> from the COVID States Project. The researchers sampled more than 20,000 adults in all 50 states and found that those who cited Facebook as a primary news source were less likely to be vaccinated. While the authors note that it doesn’t <em>prove </em>that using Facebook affects someone’s choice to get vaccinated, they found a “surprisingly strong relationship” between the two.</p><p>“If you rely on Facebook to get news and information about the coronavirus, you are substantially less likely than the average American to say you have been vaccinated,”<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/07/27/people-are-more-anti-vaccine-if-they-get-their-covid-19-news-facebook-rather-than-fox-news-new-data-shows/"><ins> they write</ins></a>. “In fact, Facebook news consumers are less likely to be vaccinated than people who get their coronavirus information from Fox News. According to our data, Facebook users were also among the most likely to believe false claims about coronavirus vaccines.”</p><p>The researchers speculate that this could be because people who spend a lot of time on Facebook are less likely to trust the government, the media or other institutions. Or, it could be that spending time on the platform contributed to that distrust. While there’s no way to know for sure, we do know that Facebook has for years been an effective platform for spreading disinformation about vaccines.</p><h2>A spotty record</h2><p>Doctors and researchers have warned for years that Facebook wasn’t doing enough to prevent lies about vaccines from spreading. Because of this, prominent anti-vaxxers have used Facebook and Instagram to spread their message and build their followings.</p><p>A report published earlier this year from the CCDH found that more than half of all vaccine misinformation online could be linked to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/anti-vaccine-misinformation-report-12-accounts-212245856.html"><ins>12 individuals</ins></a> who are part of a long-running, and <a href="https://252f2edd-1c8b-49f5-9bb2-cb57bb47e4ba.filesusr.com/ugd/f4d9b9_00b2ad56fe524d82b271a75e441cd06c.pdf"><ins>often coordinated</ins></a>, effort to undermine vaccines. But while the company has banned some accounts, some of those individuals still have a presence on a Facebook-owned platform, <a href="https://252f2edd-1c8b-49f5-9bb2-cb57bb47e4ba.filesusr.com/ugd/f4d9b9_6946cb0059624ec093a427552b1b2bc3.pdf"><ins>according to</ins></a> the CCDH. Facebook has disputed the findings of that report, which relied on analytics from the company&#39;s CrowdTangle tool. But the social network’s own research into vaccine hesitancy indicated “a small group appears to play a big role” in undermining vaccines, <em>The Washington Post</em><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/03/14/facebook-vaccine-hesistancy-qanon/"><ins>reported</ins></a> in March.</p><p>There are other issues, too. For years, Facebook’s search and recommendation algorithm have made it extraordinarily easy for users to fall into rabbit holes of misinformation. Simply searching the word “vaccine” would be enough to surface recommendations for accounts spreading conspiracy theories and other vaccine disinformation.</p><p>Engadget reported<a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-anti-vaxxers-coronavirus-conspiracy-theories-173021562.html"><ins> last year</ins></a> on Instagram’s algorithmic search results associated anti-vaccine accounts with COVID-19 conspiracies and QAnon content. More than a year later, a recent study <a href="https://secure.avaaz.org/campaign/en/fb_algorithm_antivaxx/"><ins>from Avaaz</ins></a> found that although this type of content no longer appears at the top of search results, Facebook’s recommendation algorithms continue to recommend pages and groups that promote misinformation about vaccines. In their report, researchers document how users can fall into misinformation “rabbit holes” by liking seemingly innocuous pages or searching for “vaccines.” They also found that Facebook’s page recommendation algorithm appeared to associate vaccines and autism.</p><blockquote><p>“Over the course of two days, we used two new Facebook accounts to follow vaccine-related pages that Facebook suggested for us. Facebook’s algorithm directed us to 109 pages, with 1.4M followers, containing anti-vaccine content — including pages from well-known anti-vaccine advocates and organizations such as Del Bigtree, Dr. Ben Tapper, Dr. Toni Bark, Andrew Wakefield, Children&#39;s Health Defense, Learn the Risk, and Dr. Suzanne Humphries. Many of the pages the algorithm recommended to us carried a label, warning that the page posts about COVID-19 or vaccines, giving us the option to go directly to the CDC website. The algorithm also recommended 10 pages related to autism — some containing anti-vaccine content, some not — suggesting that Facebook’s algorithm associates vaccines with autism, a thoroughly debunked link that anti-vaccine advocates continue to push.”</p></blockquote><p>Facebook has removed some of these pages from its recommendations, though it’s not clear which. Avaaz points out that there’s no way to know why Facebook’s recommendation algorithm surfaces the pages it does as the company doesn’t disclose how these systems work. Yet it’s notable because content associating vaccines with autism is <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/230764881494641/"><ins>exactly</ins></a> one of the claims that Facebook said it would ban under its stricter misinformation rules during the pandemic. That Facebook’s suggestions are intermingling the topics is, at the very least, undermining those efforts.</p><h2>Claims and counterclaims</h2><p>Facebook has strongly opposed these claims. The company repeatedly points to its messaging campaign around covid-19 vaccines, noting that more than 2 billion people have viewed the company’s COVID-19 and vaccine PSAs.</p><p>In a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/support-for-covid-19-vaccines-is-high-on-facebook-and-growing/"><ins>blog post</ins></a> responding to President Biden’s comments last month, Facebook’s VP of Integrity Guy Rosen argued that “vaccine acceptance among Facebook users in the US has increased.” He noted that the company has “reduced the visibility of more than 167 million pieces of COVID-19 content debunked by our network of fact-checking partners so fewer people see it.”</p><p>He didn’t share, however, how much of that misinformation was about vaccines, or details on the company’s enforcement of its more general vaccine misinformation rules. That’s likely not an accident. The company has repeatedly resisted efforts that could shed light on how misinformation spreads on its platform.</p><p>Facebook executives declined a request from their data scientists who asked for additional resources to study COVID-19 misinformation at the start of the pandemic, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/19/technology/facebook-misinformation-blind-spot.html"><ins>according to</ins></a><em>The New York Times</em>. It’s not clear why the request was turned down, but the company has also pushed back on outsiders’ efforts to gain insight into health misinformation.</p><p>Facebook has declined to share the results of an internal study on vaccine hesitancy on its platform, according to Washington DC Attorney General Karl Racine’s office, which has launched a consumer protection investigation into the company’s handling of vaccine misinformation.</p><p>“Facebook has said it’s taking action to address the proliferation of COVID-19 vaccine misinformation on its site,” a spokesperson said. “But then when pressed to show its work, Facebook refused.”</p><p>The Biden Administration has also — unsuccessfully — pushed Facebook to be more forthcoming about vaccine misinformation. According to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/10/technology/facebook-vaccine-misinformation.html"><em><ins>The New York Times</ins></em></a>, administration officials have met repeatedly with Facebook and other platforms as part of its effort to curb misinformations about coronavirus vaccines. Yet when a White House official asked Facebook to share “how often misinformation was viewed and spread,” the company refused. According to <em>The Times</em>, “Facebook responded to some requests for information by talking about vaccine promotion strategies,’ such as its PSAs or its tool to help users <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-will-show-you-when-and-where-you-can-get-vaccinated-085707231.html"><ins>book</ins></a> vaccine appointments.</p><p>One issue is that it’s not always easy to define what is, and isn’t, misinformation. Factual information, like news stories or personal anecdotes about vaccine side effects, can be shared with misleading commentary. This, Facebook has suggested, makes it difficult to study the issue in the way that many have asked. At the same time, Facebook is a notoriously data-driven company. It’s constantly testing even the smallest features, and it employs scores of researchers and data scientists. It’s difficult to believe that learning more about vaccine hesitancy and how misinformation spreads is entirely out of reach.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-vaccine-misinformation-policies-170012241.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">8c1216d4-1c88-4ccf-97cd-a4c915a7bc34</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 17:00:12 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628874013</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T17:00:34+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-04/bf05fe00-5501-11e9-bfe5-db90a6a6fae8" width="2200" height="1467" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-04/bf05fe00-5501-11e9-bfe5-db90a6a6fae8" width="2200" height="1467" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Elijah Nouvelage / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The entrance sign to Facebook headquarters is seen through two moving buses in Menlo Park, California, on Wednesday, October 10, 2018. REUTERS/Elijah Nouvelage]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FACEBOOK-RESULTS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook Messenger rolls out end-to-end encrypted voice and video calls]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook is <a href="https://messengernews.fb.com/2021/08/13/messenger-updates-end-to-end-encrypted-chats-with-new-features/"><ins>rolling out</ins></a> a host of features for Messenger users who switch on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-10-04-facebook-messenger-now-lets-you-toggle-end-to-end-encryption.html"><ins>end-to-end encryption</ins></a><ins>&nbsp;</ins>(E2EE). You can now call Messenger contacts using voice or video <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-31-facebook-audio-video-calls-secret-conversations.html"><ins>with E2EE enabled</ins></a>, just like in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-phone-multi-device-end-to-end-encryption-192123565.html"><ins>WhatsApp</ins></a>.</p><p>No one other than the person you&#39;re speaking with can <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-analyze-encrypted-messages-ad-targeting-175739715.html"><ins>see or listen to your E2EE chats or calls</ins></a><ins>,</ins> so you can add an extra layer of protection to your voice and video conversations on Messenger. However, Facebook says you can still report messages if needed.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>There are updates for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-07-08-facebook-secret-messaging.html"><ins>disappearing messages</ins></a> as well. You&#39;ll see an option for them when you tap your profile photo in a chat, as well as in the message compose field (tap the timer icon there). You can now activate disappearing messages for everyone in a chat, not just yourself. On top of that, you&#39;ll have more control between how long messages are viewed and when they vanish — between five seconds and 24 hours.</p><p>Facebook has some other E2EE features in the works. It&#39;s planning to start public tests of E2EE group chats and calls in Messenger in the coming weeks. The company will also begin a limited test E2EE for Instagram direct messages. You&#39;ll need to have an existing chat with someone or to follow each other before you can enable E2EE on a DM exchange.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-messenger-e2ee-voice-video-calls-group-instagram-164140952.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c87718d5-1fe5-4bd4-9a39-cb4bce23341f</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 16:41:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628872902</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T16:41:50+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/36301ce0-fc53-11eb-bfbd-d3d267300754" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/36301ce0-fc53-11eb-bfbd-d3d267300754" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Facebook]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Facebook E2EE features]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Facebook E2EE features]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[This week's best deals: $100 off the Apple Watch Series 6 and more]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung may have announced a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-august-11-supercut-170007617.html">bunch of new devices</a> this week, but it was Apple and Amazon that led the week when it came to online deals. While Woot&#39;s flash sale on the Apple Watch Series 6 Product Red Edition came and went quickly, you can still get the smartwatch for $299 at Amazon. The Mac Mini M1 got a $100 discount while a number of Echo devices went on sale as well — including the new, second-generation Echo Show 5. And through Sunday, you can save on laptops, tablets, TVs and more in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-buy-three-day-anniversary-sale-microsoft-surface-laptop-go-samsung-galaxy-tab-s7-google-wifi-125047416.html">Best Buy&#39;s anniversary sale</a>. Here are the best tech deals from this week that you can still get today.</p><h2>Apple Watch Series 6</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/c55fd260-ec8c-11eb-b7af-fcf1d94f9d2c" alt="Apple Watch Series 6 Product Red with Count Up face" data-uuid="492dd140-b2ba-33cc-9332-0c0ae4d59880"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple Watch Series 6 Product Red Edition" href="https://amzn.to/3lZzubG">Apple Watch Series 6 Product Red Edition</a> is $100 off right now, bringing it down to $299. While not an all-time low, it&#39;s still a great deal on Apple&#39;s more powerful smartwatch. We gave the Series 6 a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-6-review-153047133.html">score of 89</a> for its speedy performance, improved battery life and faster charging. However, if you&#39;re willing to wait, you&#39;ll be able to get the next-generation Apple Watch pretty soon — we expect to see it debut sometime in September.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Series 6 Product Red at Amazon - $299" href="https://amzn.to/3lZzubG">Buy Series 6 Product Red at Amazon - $299</a></p><h2>Mac Mini M1</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/b90d6ba0-e088-11ea-bf7d-559c3cbc732c" alt="Apple Mac mini" data-uuid="fb4e7c46-569e-4488-afa8-27945091b6d6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple&#39;s Mac Mini M1" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5PHB83?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=5ef4638ae7ebeef79e1a4b68bc8d9d3d&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Apple&#39;s Mac Mini M1</a> has returned to $600, or $100 off its normal price. The sale price is actually $650, but an automatically applied coupon will bring the final cost down even more. This is the device to get if you want a compact desktop with the power and efficiency of Apple&#39;s M1 chipset.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Apple Mac Mini (256GB) at Amazon - $600" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5PHB83?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=5ef4638ae7ebeef79e1a4b68bc8d9d3d&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Buy Apple Mac Mini (256GB) at Amazon - $600</a></p><h2>AirPods Pro</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/7e945160-f699-11ea-beef-f468e8c9049c" alt="Apple AirPods Pro" data-uuid="8548c1c2-f894-402e-ab1a-6cabce7f0e86"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele / Engadget</div></figure><p>Apple&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:AirPods Pro" href="https://amzn.to/3CzNDCu">AirPods Pro</a> remain $60 off at Amazon, bringing them down to $190. These are the best sounding earbuds you can get from Apple, and we gave them a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-06-apple-airpods-pro-review.html">score of 87</a> for their better, more secure fit, IPX4 water resistance and solid audio quality.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy AirPods Pro at Amazon - $190" href="https://amzn.to/3CzNDCu">Buy AirPods Pro at Amazon - $190</a></p><h2>10.2-inch iPa<strong>d</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fo.aolcdn.com%252Fimages%252Fdims%253Fimage_uri%253Dhttps%25253A%25252F%25252Fo.aolcdn.com%25252Fimages%25252Fdims%25253Fimage_uri%25253Dhttps%2525253A%2525252F%2525252Fo.aolcdn.com%2525252Fimages%2525252Fdims%2525253Fimage_uri%2525253Dhttps%252525253A%252525252F%252525252Fs.yimg.com%252525252Fos%252525252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%252525252F2020-10%252525252F13f63760-0d50-11eb-bbff-b88a88f6f782%25252526thumbnail%2525253D675%252525252C%25252526client%2525253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%25252526signature%2525253Ddef31d7ff41ffcabc6875ada926e9143a3f7b189%252526thumbnail%25253D675%2525252C%252526client%25253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%252526signature%25253D563526ab9cde12c8b65c262a18c61180f558eaf4%2526thumbnail%253D675%25252C%2526client%253D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%2526signature%253Dffbd1873333e4bb9389427b236e776bb5c244828%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3Db0a131074357c044f168a14f91e2730073aef268&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=7fc1308467502c848c7bb1826d2d20b84180b4ee"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Apple&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:10.2-inch iPad" href="https://amzn.to/3zUZGb1">10.2-inch iPad</a> is still on sale for $299, or $30 off its normal price. It&#39;s arguably the best iPad for new tablet owners and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-2020-ipados-14-review-170023713.html">we liked</a> its improved performance, familiar design and support for the first-generation Apple Pencil.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy 10.2-inch iPad at Amazon - $299" href="https://amzn.to/3zUZGb1">Buy 10.2-inch iPad at Amazon - $299</a></p><h2>Beats Studio Buds</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/b66415d0-cd12-11eb-b1f6-d37d378036c8" alt="Beats Studio Buds review" data-uuid="d9136a4d-06a3-3d87-b692-ec47945bc2f2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Billy Steele/Engadget</div></figure><p>Beats&#39; new <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Studio Buds" href="https://amzn.to/3fLrDdY">Studio Buds</a> are $20 off right now, bringing them down to $130. It&#39;s the first discount we&#39;ve seen on the buds since they came out a few months ago. We gave them a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/beats-studio-buds-review-150014566.html">score of 84</a> for their smaller, more comfortable design, balanced sound and quick pairing on both Android and iOS.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Beats Studio Buds at Amazon - $130" href="https://amzn.to/3fLrDdY">Buy Beats Studio Buds at Amazon - $130</a></p><h2>Amazon Echo devices</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-06/578bb540-d591-11eb-97d5-2503b1925bba" alt="Amazon Echo Show 5" data-uuid="51bf0d27-5eff-310b-9900-489c4beff4fc"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>A handful of Echo devices are on sale right now at Amazon, including the second-generation <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo Show 5" href="https://amzn.to/3g3B7S7">Echo Show 5</a> for $55. That&#39;s the best price we&#39;ve seen since the device came out earlier this year. You can also grab the latest <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo Show 8" href="https://amzn.to/3xxK382">Echo Show 8</a> for $100 and the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Echo Frames" href="https://amzn.to/3jIYhhE">Echo Frames</a> for $180.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Echo Show 5 at Amazon - $55" href="https://amzn.to/3g3B7S7">Buy Echo Show 5 at Amazon - $55</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Echo Show 5 Kids at Amazon - $65" href="https://amzn.to/3lLkZs0">Buy Echo Show 5 Kids at Amazon - $65</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Echo Show 8 at Amazon - $100" href="https://amzn.to/3xxK382">Buy Echo Show 8 at Amazon - $100</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Echo Frames at Amazon - $180" href="https://amzn.to/3jIYhhE">Buy Echo Frames at Amazon - $180</a></p><h2>Anova Precision Cooker Nano</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/2b665470-f918-11eb-bbee-5d55a51b70a8" alt="Anova Precision Cooker Nano" data-uuid="f76c297c-4595-3aea-922f-00bb6f032aeb"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Anova</div></figure><p>Anova&#39;s entry-level sous-vide machine, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Nano" href="https://amzn.to/3s3XQ58">Nano</a>, remains discounted to $99. It&#39;s a great option for those interested in giving sous-vide cooking a try, but don&#39;t want to spend a ton of money upfront to do so. The Nano uses 750 watts of power to cook food submerged in water, and it can run for up to 3,000 hours before it needs recharging.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Anova Precision Cooker Nano at Amazon - $99" href="https://amzn.to/3s3XQ58">Buy Anova Precision Cooker Nano at Amazon - $99</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Anova Precision Cooker Nano at Best Buy - $99" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/QONX0A">Buy Anova Precision Cooker Nano at Best Buy - $99</a></p><h2>Comic-Con 2022 sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-07%2F619b2930-eed7-11eb-bd17-d6cba8d900bc&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=8b6e9d101a1e6ef829b56dc2e4f42e2d3d2e3020"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Through December 8, you can enter to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:win four-day passes to San Diego Comic-Con 2022" href="http://shrsl.com/339h5">win four-day passes to San Diego Comic-Con 2022</a>. Along with the passes, you&#39;ll get access to a special preview night, reserved seating in Hall H, a personal concierge, a private tour of the Comic-Con Museum, dinner in Balboa Park and tickets to the &quot;Night at the Comic-Con Museum&quot; event. It&#39;s free to enter, but funds from this sweepstakes will go to the San Diego Comic Convention.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:Enter to win at Omaze" href="http://shrsl.com/339h5">Enter to win at Omaze</a></p><h2>Virgin Galactic sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%252F2021-07%252F079c6ce0-e25d-11eb-9ff7-705aa7bbb4fc%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3Db3417e6882ae2d86a626d582960e8881cc8a5d72&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=0985ecf955db8ed12c665b4fbff24d79a5e58447"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>In this Omaze giveaway you can win <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:two seats on one of the first Virgin Galactic flights to space" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fvirgin%2Dgalactic%2D2021&amp;afftrack=07132021VirginGalactic">two seats on one of the first Virgin Galactic flights to space</a>. In addition, you&#39;ll go on a tour of Spaceport America in New Mexico with Richard Branson. You don&#39;t have to pay to enter, but funds from all paid entries will support Space for Humanity, an organization that hopes to make space more accessible for all.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:Enter to win at Omaze" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fvirgin%2Dgalactic%2D2021&amp;afftrack=07132021VirginGalactic">Enter to win at Omaze</a></p><h2>Gaming PC sweepstakes</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fo.aolcdn.com%2Fimages%2Fdims%3Fimage_uri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fs.yimg.com%252Fos%252Fcreatr-uploaded-images%252F2021-06%252F067d0cd0-d8de-11eb-bf7f-328a4f92ae83%26thumbnail%3D675%252C%26client%3D49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo%26signature%3D7b90f9f0acdc474ea6ab7ece951c9ed87fcc507e&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=03cd24acc60acb8d1d2ae232a919aa9a74a77afe"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Omaze is giving away another <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:$20,000 to build your ultimate gaming PC" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fgaming%2Drig%2D6%3F&amp;afftrack=6292021GamingPC">$20,000 to build your ultimate gaming PC</a>. This sweepstakes is free to enter, but funds donated with purchased entries will benefit Schools on Wheels, an organization that provides free tutoring and mentoring services to children experiencing homelessness across Southern California.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:other;pdid:Enter to win at Omaze" href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1198722&amp;u=2747581&amp;m=80499&amp;urllink=www%2Eomaze%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fgaming%2Drig%2D6%3F&amp;afftrack=6292021GamingPC">Enter to win at Omaze</a></p><p><em>Pricing and availability is subject to change. No donation or payment necessary to enter or win this sweepstakes.</em><a href="https://www.omaze.com/pages/rules"><em>See official rules on Omaze.</em></a></p><h2>New tech deals</h2><h3>Elgato Key Light Air</h3><p>Elgato&#39;s slim <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Key Light Air" href="https://amzn.to/2VKItCV">Key Light Air</a> has been a favorite of ours for streamers and now you can get it for $110, or $20 off its usual price. It&#39;s a sleek LED panel with 1,400 lumens that can provide just the right amount of light for your streams without taking up too much space. It&#39;s also WiFi-enabled, so you can turn it on and off and switch up your light settings directly from your smartphone.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Key Light Air at Amazon - $110" href="https://amzn.to/2VKItCV">Buy Key Light Air at Amazon - $110</a></p><h3>Instant Pot Duo Plus (8-quart)</h3><p>This 9-in-1 <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Instant Pot" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B075CWJ3T8?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=a9819d8a2216aaca39d297a4aa8aea6f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Instant Pot</a> is $40 off at Amazon thanks to a clippable coupon that knocks an additional $20 off the sale price. Along with pressure cooking, you&#39;re getting rice cooking, yogurt making, steaming, warming, sous vide and other functions in this device, plus a capacity large enough to make food for a big party.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Instant Pot Duo Plus at Amazon - $100" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B075CWJ3T8?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkId=a9819d8a2216aaca39d297a4aa8aea6f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Buy Instant Pot Duo Plus at Amazon - $100</a></p><h3>Aukey Omnia Duo 65W Dual-Port PD Charger</h3><p>This <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:65W GaN USB-C charger" href="https://fave.co/37BTetH">65W GaN USB-C charger</a> from Aukey is only $26 when you use the code <strong>OMNIADUO</strong> at checkout. It includes two USB-C ports, so you can quickly power up two mobile devices at once or even your laptop and your smartphone simultaneously. And because it uses GaN technology, it&#39;s smaller than other similar chargers and isn&#39;t as susceptible to overheating.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy Omnia Duo 65W charger at Aukey - $26" href="https://fave.co/37BTetH">Buy Omnia Duo 65W charger at Aukey - $26</a></p><h3>NordVPN</h3><p>One of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-vpn-services-130028530.html">our recommended VPNs</a> is running a decent summer sale on a two-year subscription. You can sign up for <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:NordVPN" href="https://fave.co/3uCgyAL">NordVPN</a> for $99 for the first two years, which comes out to $49.50 per year, and get three additional months of access for free. We like NordVPN for its speed, its no-logs policy, the thousands of servers it has to choose from and that one account supports up to six connected devices.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Buy NordVPN (2 years) - $99" href="https://fave.co/3uCgyAL">Buy NordVPN (2 years) - $99</a></p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/weekly-tech-deals-apple-watch-series-6-product-red-edition-mac-mini-m1-amazon-echo-devices-sale-154521347.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">ea139b40-7e12-47c7-915a-beac4045c1ce</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:45:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628868882</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T15:35:01+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hobbies & Personal Activities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/ac7336e4-f852-11ea-9fee-ca69cd82441a" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/ac7336e4-f852-11ea-9fee-ca69cd82441a" width="1800" height="1200" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Valentina Palladino / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Apple Watch Series 6 sitting on a wooden table.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple Watch Series 6]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Airbnb drops sexual harassment and assault arbitration rules for guests and hosts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/airbnb"><ins>Airbnb</ins></a> will update its terms of service to drop arbitration provisions for sexual assault or harassment claims by guests or hosts. The company expects the updated terms to be ready this fall.</p><p>&quot;We believe that survivors should be able to bring claims in whatever forum is best for them,&quot; Airbnb <a href="https://news.airbnb.com/supporting-and-empowering-survivors/"><ins>wrote</ins></a> in a blog post. &quot;We encourage our industry peers within the travel and hospitality space to consider taking similar steps for their respective communities.&quot;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The move will formalize Airbnb&#39;s current approach to such cases, which it adopted in January 2019. The company hasn&#39;t asked a court to force sexual assault or harassment claims by hosts or guests into arbitration since then. Nor will it do so until the updated terms of service are in effect.</p><p>&quot;Incidents of sexual assault are extremely rare on Airbnb, but in these rare cases, Airbnb’s highly-trained Safety team works with survivors to put their wellbeing first,&quot; the company said. According to the blog post, members of its safety team have &quot;undergone training in trauma-informed methodology and they prioritize supporting and empowering survivors in their healing process.&quot;</p><p>Airbnb didn&#39;t say whether it plans to change its arbitration rules for other types of harassment. It ended forced arbitration for sexual harassment and assault claims by employees in late 2018. Other notable tech companies ditched forced arbitration for sexual assault and/or harassment claims around that time, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-05-15-uber-no-longer-forces-sexual-assault-survivors-into-arbitration.html"><ins>Uber</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-05-15-lyft-drops-forced-arbitration-for-sexual-assault-cases.html"><ins>Lyft</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-08-google-updates-sexual-harassment-policies.html"><ins>Google</ins></a> and Square.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/airbnb-sexual-harassment-assault-forced-arbitration-guests-hosts-153010488.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1a6eff7a-7c1f-4b14-81d7-14e666ae332a</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:30:10 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628868612</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T15:30:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Travel & Tourism]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2019-04/49002a80-59ae-11e9-beff-a01ead0ea73d" width="5473" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2019-04/49002a80-59ae-11e9-beff-a01ead0ea73d" width="5473" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Charles Platiau / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Airbnb logo is seen on a little mini pyramid under the glass Pyramid of the Louvre museum in Paris, France, March 12, 2019. Airbnb and the Louvre museum will offer the chance to spend a night in the Louvre museum on April 30 where a contest winner with a guest will have an aperitif in front of the painting "Mona Lisa" (La Joconde) by Leonardo Da Vinci, a dinner in front of the Venus de Milo statue during a private visit and finally sleep in their own little mini pyramid under the glass Pyramid. Picture taken March 12, 2019. REUTERS/Charles Platiau]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[FRANCE-AIRBNB/LOUVRE]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple acknowledges 'confusion' over child safety updates]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple is ready to acknowledge the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html">controversy over its child safety updates</a>, but it sees this as a matter of poor messaging — not bad policy. Senior software engineering VP Craig Federighi <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-executive-defends-tools-to-fight-child-porn-acknowledges-privacy-backlash-11628859600?mod=rss_Technology">told the <em>Wall Street Journal</em></a> in an interview that introducing both the scans for child sexual abuse material (CSAM) on iCloud and opt-in local monitoring of iMessage sexual content was a &quot;recipe for this kind of confusion.&quot; People conflated the two and thought that Apple might spy on messages, Federighi claimed, adding that he wished Apple had &quot;come out a little more clearly.&quot;</p><p>The executive maintained that Apple was striking the right balance between child safety and privacy, and addressed some of the concerns that surfaced since the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-ios-15-193820644.html">announced its new measures</a> in early August. He stressed that the scans of iCloud-destined photos would only flag existing images in a CSAM database, not any picture in your library. The system only sends an alert when you reach a threshold of 30 images, so false positives aren&#39;t likely.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The system also has &quot;multiple levels of auditability,&quot; Federighi said. On-device scanning will reportedly make it easier for researchers to check if Apple ever misused the technology.  Federighi also rejected the notion that the technique might be used to scan for other material, such as politics, noting that the database of images comes from multiple child safety groups, not just the agency that will receive any red-flag reports (the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children).</p><p>The response won&#39;t satisfy those who object to the very notion that Apple is scanning photos on their phones, even with privacy protections in place. It is, however, a recognition that it can be a challenge to properly address privacy issues — it doesn&#39;t take much to prompt an uproar.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-on-confusion-over-child-safety-updates-csam-150121989.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f80fb9bf-28e4-41ff-9a9b-fcefc4836887</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:01:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628874025</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T17:00:44+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/95838b10-fc3e-11eb-b7ff-a4f65f41eba6" width="3810" height="2706" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/95838b10-fc3e-11eb-b7ff-a4f65f41eba6" width="3810" height="2706" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Justin Sullivan via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA - JUNE 03:  Apple's senior vice president of Software Engineering Craig Federighi speaks during the keynote address during the 2019 Apple Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) at the San Jose Convention Center on June 03, 2019 in San Jose, California. The WWDC runs through June 7. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple CEO Tim Cook Delivers Keynote At Annual Worldwide Developers Conference]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[House bill takes aim at iOS and Android app store competition]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A bipartisan bill that targets app store competition has been introduced in the House of Representatives. It&#39;s the House version of a Senate bill that was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/bipartisan-open-app-markets-act-introduction-221732872.html"><ins>introduced this week</ins></a> by a group of Republican and Democrat senators, and it would likely have a drastic impact on Apple&#39;s App Store and the Google Play Store were it to come into effect.</p><p>&quot;For far too long, companies like Google and Apple have had a stranglehold on app developers who are forced to take whatever terms these monopolists set in order to reach their customers,&quot; Ken Buck, the ranking Republican member of the House Judiciary Committee antitrust panel, <a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1426163173795770374">wrote</a> in a tweet. As <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-house-members-introduce-bill-targeting-apple-google-app-stores-2021-08-13/"><em>Reuters</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>notes, Buck introduced the bill alongside Democrat Hank Johnson.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Should the Open App Markets Act become law, it could level the playing field for third-party app stores and in-app payment services. Using a third-party app marketplace on an iPhone is difficult without jailbreaking the device. Google says <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/android%2012"><ins>Android 12</ins></a> makes it easier for users to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-12-google-play-194125627.html"><ins>install apps from other stores</ins></a>, but it still requires developers to handle payments through the Play Store&#39;s billing process.</p><p>Both Apple and Google take a 30 percent cut of in-app payments. That&#39;s a key reason why the likes of Spotify and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-emails-show-how-it-tried-to-stop-netflix-from-dropping-in-app-purchases-082653224.html"><ins>Netflix</ins></a> don&#39;t allow users to sign up through mobile apps. They direct users to their mobile websites instead.</p><p>&quot;Apple has used the iOS platform and its App Store policies to insulate itself from competition and disadvantage rivals for far too long,&quot; Horacio Gutierrez, Spotify’s head of global affairs and chief legal officer, told Engadget in a statement. &quot;By introducing the Open App Markets Act in both chambers of Congress, we’re one important step closer to curbing Apple’s anticompetitive behavior, leveling the playing field, and restoring competition for all.” The company has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-spotify-antitrust-statement-watch-event-191517363.html"><ins>accused Apple</ins></a> of operating as a monopoly on iOS.</p><p>The bill would also allow developers to inform consumers about lower prices elsewhere, according to <a href="https://www.axios.com/house-lawmakers-bill-targets-app-stores-46e5f088-5c56-4165-b4a4-00ead4ab2599.html"><ins>its sponsors</ins></a>. Epic Games&#39; legal battles with Apple and Google kicked off when it offered mobile <em>Fortnite</em> players a discount on virtual goods if they <a href="https://www.engadget.com/epic-games-fortnite-direct-payment-discounts-143422257.html"><ins>bypassed</ins></a> the iOS and Android payment systems. Apple and Google swiftly <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-removes-fortnite-190920925.html"><ins>removed</ins></a> the game from their app stores and Epic responded quickly by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-maker-epic-games-sues-apple-195415590.html"><ins>filing lawsuits</ins></a> against <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-google-play-lawsuit-035741548.html"><ins>both companies</ins></a>. A judge&#39;s decision is pending in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tim-cook-apple-epic-testimony-221352974.html"><ins>Apple case</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/house-bill-ios-android-app-store-competition-open-app-markets-act-143026966.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">64fa902c-f07e-49e7-92f4-05c90a0cfea7</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 14:30:26 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628865028</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T14:30:49+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mobile Apps]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1dcd9640-fafb-11eb-8fde-3d5cdabb0674" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/1dcd9640-fafb-11eb-8fde-3d5cdabb0674" width="3000" height="2000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[App Store icon displayed on a phone screen is seen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on July 18, 2021.  (Photo Ilustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[TikTok And Facebook Photo Illustrations]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turns out, I like cooking food from scratch... in a microwave]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a sucker for newfangled kitchen appliances. I bought into the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/instantpot">Instant Pot</a> hype a few years ago and tried out an air fryer as well. (I ended up getting the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Breville Smart Oven Air" href="https://amzn.to/3CDBgFu">Breville Smart Oven Air</a>, a toaster oven with an air-frying setting.) I also own a host of other contraptions cluttering up my kitchen cabinets: a juicer, food processor, ice cream maker and <em>two</em> sous vide machines.</p><p>Yet, the appliance I use the most is the humble microwave. Like many of you, I use it mainly for reheating leftovers or warming up frozen dinners. I’ve never really considered using it for actual cooking, except for the occasional “microwave mug cake” recipe I’ve seen go viral on social media. Oh, I’ve heard of cookbooks from the ‘70s and ‘80s that tried to sell the public on the wonders of microwave cooking — I’m sure my mom even bought a few back in my youth — but those have largely turned out to be full of culinary deception. (A roast beef dinner via microwave? I don’t think so.)</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>But a few months ago I saw an Instagram ad for a new line of cookware that was designed to be used specifically with the microwave. It’s called <a href="https://fave.co/2V5GbOh">Anyday</a>, and it was co-founded by renowned chef David Chang of Momofuku and Ugly Delicious fame. The ad showed luscious photos of mashed potatoes, mapo tofu, mac and cheese, and a chicken and pea dish that all looked really delicious. Could all of this really be made with just the microwave? Perhaps the best kitchen appliance was under my nose all along? Needless to say, I was intrigued.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/aaf93390-fa78-11eb-bbf3-20a272778099" alt="Anyday Cookware" data-uuid="ac9003db-cb85-3ebe-b4a1-aa20dcad3e3d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>According to Anyday, the main thing differentiating its cookware from regular microwave-safe containers is its glass lid. It has a silicone gasket that blocks splatters and keeps moisture in, as well as a knob at the top that can be pulled out for steam to escape through air vents. The knob can also be pushed down to create an airtight leakproof seal, at which point the containers are also stackable. In contrast, my existing set of Pyrex containers just have regular plastic lids, which even the manufacturer recommends shouldn’t be used in the microwave since they can warp.</p><p>I should note here that the Anyday lids do have stainless steel rims, which you might think is a little dangerous to put in the microwave. But they’re actually safe on account of their smooth, curved shape, which prevents arcing. The company does warn against heating up two dishes at once, however, as the combination of two stainless steel lids might result in sparks flying.</p><p>Also, the Anyday dishes themselves are made of a frosted borosilicate glass which can withstand large temperature fluctuations without cracking. This last part is important, as certain ceramics and glass aren’t completely microwave safe. For example, I tried heating up a potato once on a plate I bought from IKEA, and it ended up splitting in two. The plate, that is, not the potato.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/2d695770-fa78-11eb-b7db-3af8518eb459" alt="Mac and Cheese in Anyday Cookware" data-uuid="77ec823a-39df-346b-b811-cc567c276251"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Still, I was a little skeptical. So I went ahead and purchased a <a href="https://fave.co/2V5GbOh">full set of Anyday cookware</a> just to try everything out. That’s four dishes total — shallow and deep in medium and large sizes — which is admittedly quite expensive at $120. Alternatively, you can get the <a href="https://fave.co/3wnvQdo">medium set</a> of two dishes for $55 or the <a href="https://fave.co/3BUrrCA">large set</a> for $75. You can also opt to buy each dish separately; the two medium ones go for $30 a piece while the large options are $40 a piece. That definitely makes this pretty pricey compared to an average set of microwave-safe containers — a full 18-piece Snapware Pyrex set, for example, is just $30.</p><p>The Anyday set comes with several recipe cards, which are very handy to start out with, but the best place to find recipes is on the Anyday website. You’ll find everything from one-ingredient recipes (e.g., you just want to steam some rice) to full recipes such as black bean soup and squash curry. On each recipe page, you can select your desired serving size as well as the wattage of your specific microwave oven, which will determine variables such as dish size, cook time and what power level you should use.</p><p>I’ve used the Anyday cookware for several weeks now, and I’ve actually been mostly impressed with the results. The first recipe I tried was a chicken and rice meal with peas and marinara sauce. I was nervous about whether it would work, but it turned out to be delicious, with the chicken cooked through to the bone and the rice tender and fluffy. The Thai pineapple chicken recipe also worked out well. I think I would’ve preferred it if the onions were browned and caramelized like they would be on the stove, but for microwave cooking, it was completely satisfactory.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/7e3b7f20-fa78-11eb-bebf-14b201f59ba7" alt="Anyday Cookware" data-uuid="3ac00efc-e4df-3e03-a6c7-96a224fddf29"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>One dish in particular was a revelation for me: Silky Chinese steamed egg. This is a recipe that can be quite tricky to master on the stove, as you need to steam it slowly over a gentle heat. But in the microwave, it’s a matter of heating the custard solution at a lower power level for just four to five minutes, depending on your microwave wattage. (The company&#39;s site recommends Power Level 4.)  I’ve never really fiddled around with my microwave’s power settings before, but now that I see it can result in a smooth custard, I will definitely be using it more often.</p><p>Another killer application, at least for me, is poached eggs. I usually find poaching eggs to be a bit of a chore; you have to heat up a pot of water, carefully drop in the egg and hope you’re able to rescue it when it’s done just right. It’s especially challenging when it’s six in the morning and I haven’t had my coffee just yet. But with the Anyday and the microwave, all I have to do is fill up a shallow dish with cold water straight from the tap, crack an egg into it, cover it, nuke it for two minutes and it’s done. The yolk is cooked just enough so that it’s a little runny, which is how I like it. I almost couldn’t believe it.</p><p>The experience wasn’t perfect, however. For example, I tried using the Anyday to cook white rice, and even though I followed the recipe exactly, the water in the dish boiled over, pushing the lid up and spilling out into the microwave. As a result, the rice wasn’t cooked correctly, and I had to add the water back in and cook it further. I tried cooking the rice in a much larger dish later on and it worked out better, but I wish the site had suggested that instead of me finding out on my own.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5044ae70-fa78-11eb-aff7-f6e6313688ef" alt="Silky Chinese Steamed Egg Custard via Anyday" data-uuid="b95e112e-d04f-3ac3-8c47-41e6ea3debd2"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>Speaking of the recipes, I should note that not all microwave ovens are the same, even among those with the same wattage. My microwave, for example, is apparently more powerful than normal, and it took way less time for me to steam broccoli than the site recommended. I also found that not all microwave ovens&#39; power levels are the same either. My Power Level 4 could be your Power Level 3. I definitely had to play around with different variables in order to get certain foods to cook properly.</p><p>Plus, there are certain kinds of cooking that the microwave just cannot do. You’re just not going to get the same kind of browning that you can get on the stove or in the oven. You can’t use it to deep fry or roast or bake. What you’re basically doing is steaming food, albeit in a more controlled way. The microwave won’t replace your stove or your oven or your Instant Pot completely.</p><p>But, for all its flaws, I still think the Anyday cookware is great. It’s made me realize that the microwave has a lot more uses than just reheating leftovers. It’s opened up a whole new world of culinary possibilities that I had not realized existed before. Sure, the mac and cheese I made in the microwave won’t be as amazing as the one baked in the oven, but the former can be done in under 10 minutes, and it still tastes creamy and cheesy. I’ve also made instant ramen in the Anyday and the microwave to great success.</p><p>It might not make the best food you’ve ever tasted, but for college students and time-pressed parents and professionals, the microwave might just be the most versatile appliance in the kitchen. As long as you have the right cookware for it anyway.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/anyday-cookware-irl-hands-on-140042882.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d2390786-aac2-41c9-8fc0-0cd5d3afbbae</guid><dc:creator>Nicole Lee</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628868496</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T15:28:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Food & Cooking]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Nicole Lee]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/0ad73e70-fa78-11eb-bf7d-e0a0f9a7be41" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/0ad73e70-fa78-11eb-bf7d-e0a0f9a7be41" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Anyday Cookware]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Anyday Cookware]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Senators ask Amazon how it will use palm print data from its stores (updated)]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;re concerned that Amazon might misuse <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-one-palm-recognition-go-stores-seattle-100718649.html">palm print data from its One service</a>, you&#39;re not alone. <em>TechCrunch</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/amazon-biometric-data-senate-letter">reports</a> that Senators Amy Klobuchar, Bill Cassidy and Jon Ossoff have sent a letter to new Amazon chief <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-ceo-final-date-174948346.html">Andy Jassy</a> asking him to explain how the company might expand use of One&#39;s palm print system beyond stores like Amazon Go and Whole Foods. They&#39;re also worried the biometric payment data might be used for more than payments, such as for ads and tracking.</p><p>The politicians are concerned that Amazon One reportedly uploads palm print data to the cloud, creating &quot;unique&quot; security issues. The move also casts doubt on Amazon&#39;s &quot;respect&quot; for user privacy, the senators said.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In addition to asking about expansion plans, the senators wanted Jassy to outline the number of third-party One clients, the privacy protections for those clients and their customers and the size of the One user base. The trio gave Amazon until August 26th to provide an answer. We&#39;ve asked Amazon for comment.</p><p>This won&#39;t necessarily lead to government restrictions on One and other biometric payment tech. Amazon might not get much sympathy, however. The company has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-is-offering-10-in-credit-for-your-palm-print-data-114014151.html">offered $10 in credit</a> to potential One users, raising questions about its eagerness to collect palm print data. This also isn&#39;t the first time Amazon has clashed with government — cities have <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-19-orlando-amazon-rekognition-pilot.html">dropped Amazon&#39;s Rekognition</a> face detection system, and Congress has<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-22-congress-committee-facial-recognition-tech-regulation.html"> proposed face detection regulations</a> with Rekognition in mind. It wouldn&#39;t be surprising if the One investigation eventually led to legislative action, even if the effort isn&#39;t targeted specifically at Amazon.</p><p><strong>Update 8/13 at 11:05AM:</strong> Amazon declined to comment, but pointed to an earlier <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-one-continues-expansion-now-available-as-a-contactless-payment-option-at-initial-whole-foods-market-store-in-seattle">blog post</a> where it said One palm images were never stored on-device and were sent encrypted to a &quot;highly secure&quot; cloud space devoted just to One content.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/senators-amazon-palm-print-data-investigation-134424558.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">451c840e-9934-4575-9a7e-f8207daf977d</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 13:44:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628867168</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T15:06:18+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e62ca7f0-fc33-11eb-b3bb-37c2f81426cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/e62ca7f0-fc33-11eb-b3bb-37c2f81426cc" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Amazon One palm print reader]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon One palm print reader]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Best Buy discounts Surface laptops, Galaxy tablets in its latest weekend sale]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Best Buy is back with a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:new three-day sale" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/jWnL5n">new three-day sale</a> that reduces the prices of many gadgets, including laptops and tablets from Microsoft and Samsung. Through August 15, you can grab the Surface Pro 7 with its Type Cover for as low as $599 and a Core i5 model of the Surface Laptop Go for $750. Samsung&#39;s flagship tablets, the Tab S7 and S7+, are both on sale, while the already affordable Tab S6 Lite is even cheaper at $270. Here are the best tech deals we found in Best Buy&#39;s latest weekend sale.</p><h2>Google WiFi (3 pack)</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c9536310-f5f5-11eb-bfb2-99dc60bb5966" style="height:491;width:708;" alt="Google WiFi" data-uuid="96dcb89a-adea-3707-b462-a9fb8e64dec6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Google</div></figure><p><a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Google&#39;s mesh WiFi kit" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/6bPNbb">Google&#39;s mesh WiFi kit</a> with one router and two access points is $50 off, bringing it down to $150 (Amazon&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:matching the deal" href="https://amzn.to/3ABBxH5">matching the deal</a> as well). This system came out at the end of last year and it supports speeds up to 1.2Gpbs. Each node covers up to 1,500 square feet, so you&#39;re getting a ton of coverage with this three-pack. While it&#39;s not as fast as the Nest WiFi system, it&#39;s a good upgrade for those who may still be relying on a router from their ISP.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Google WiFi (3 pack) at Best Buy - $150" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/6bPNbb">Buy Google WiFi (3 pack) at Best Buy - $150</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Google WiFi (3 pack) at Amazon - $150" href="https://amzn.to/3ABBxH5">Buy Google WiFi (3 pack) at Amazon - $150</a></p><h2>Galaxy Chromebook 2</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-04/ab871810-96d5-11eb-b5fe-41c2db4984ea" style="height:1333;width:2000;" alt="Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 laptop with its lid open sitting on a wooden table." data-uuid="7ab2a381-4ce9-3e15-8d3d-497f2294540d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Galaxy Chromebook 2" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/YgqagB">Galaxy Chromebook 2</a> is down to $449 for the Intel Celeron model with 4GB of RAM and 64GB of storage. The Core i3 model will set you back $599, but that&#39;s still a decent deal. We gave this laptop a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-review-140021243.html">score of 82</a> for its impressive screen, loud speakers and solid performance.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Galaxy Chromebook 2 at Best Buy - $449" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/YgqagB">Buy Galaxy Chromebook 2 at Best Buy - $449</a></p><h2>Surface Pro 7 bundle</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/95b103f0-fb9f-11eb-bef3-2333486f1079" style="height:1067;width:1600;" alt="Surface Pro 7" data-uuid="76104c97-a179-30cb-a8a1-9d65c4b3d27d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Engadget</div></figure><p>The base <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Surface Pro 7" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/9WMYW0">Surface Pro 7</a> with its Type Cover is down to $599 for this sale, or $360 off its normal price. This model has a Core i3 processor, 4GB of RAM and 128GB of storage — we&#39;d be wary about using a device with 4GB of RAM as your primary device (unless it&#39;s a Chromebook), but this would make a good convertible for those that want a lighter device to tote around with them.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Surface Pro 7 bundle at Best Buy - $599" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/9WMYW0">Buy Surface Pro 7 bundle at Best Buy - $599</a></p><h2>55-inch LG A1 OLED 4K TV</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-07%2F0491dbb0-ebc3-11eb-b7ed-b1d8b2faa20b&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=ac7c42b3a2e1a403bc76243db5d85995c8468d58"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The latest <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-2021-oled-tv-pricing-c1-g1-a1-151137971.html">LG OLED lineup</a> just became available a few months ago and now you can grab the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:55-inch A1 model" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/3P91ry">55-inch A1 model</a> for $1,300. The A1 series is the most affordable of the bunch, making these sets good options for anyone looking to upgrade to OLED while on a tight budget.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy 55-inch LG A1 OLED at Best Buy - $1,300" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/3P91ry">Buy 55-inch LG A1 OLED at Best Buy - $1,300</a></p><h2>55-inch LG C1 OLED 4K TV</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-07%2F3108c320-ebc3-11eb-ae7f-176aaf6441fa&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=4013534f24f507e868918f1d3a54cad487f0d7bc"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:55-inch, mid-tier LG C1 OLED TV" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/15DAd6">55-inch, mid-tier LG C1 OLED TV</a> is down to $1,500, or $300 off its normal price. It uses LG&#39;s a9 Gen4 AI Processor 4K and supports HDMI 2.1, G-SYNC and FreeSync for gaming and voice commands using Alexa or the Google Assistant.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy 55-inch LG C1 OLED at Best Buy - $1,500" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/15DAd6">Buy 55-inch LG C1 OLED at Best Buy - $1,500</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy 55-inch LG C1 OLED at Amazon - $1,500" href="https://amzn.to/3eOqWQJ">Buy 55-inch LG C1 OLED at Amazon - $1,500</a></p><h2>Surface Laptop Go</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-10/bf66a6e8-0cbd-11eb-befd-9da52d6c06d5" style="height:1040;width:1600;" alt="Surface Laptop Go review" data-uuid="48f9e9c3-fa08-357a-ae5b-87b21fb8b6e3"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure><p>Microsoft&#39;s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Surface Laptop Go" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/RyO95a">Surface Laptop Go</a> with a 10th-gen Core i5 processor, 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is $150 off right now, bringing it down to $750. This is a good price for the upgraded model with more RAM, as most people will need at least 8GB on their daily driver. We gave the Laptop Go a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-laptop-go-review-130030486.html">score of 81</a> for its solid, minimalist design, excellent keyboard and trackpad and speedy performance.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Surface Laptop Go at Best Buy - $750" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/RyO95a">Buy Surface Laptop Go at Best Buy - $750</a></p><h2>Galaxy Tab S7</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/7b2a6510-f94f-11ea-ae77-8d4e7219b35c" style="height:1066;width:1600;" alt="Galaxy Tab S7 and S7+" data-uuid="8827f47e-237b-37f3-b8fb-2626085e6201"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>Best Buy and Amazon have knocked $120 off <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Samsung&#39;s Galaxy Tab S7" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/QONQ2Y">Samsung&#39;s Galaxy Tab S7</a>, bringing the total price to $530. The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:S7+" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/EazNRX">S7+</a> is also on sale for $730. This slab earned a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-tab-s7-s7-plus-review-dex-120hz-specs-130043834.html">score of 80</a> from us for its lovely 120Hz display, attractive build and long battery life.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S7 at Best Buy - $530" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/QONQ2Y">Buy Galaxy Tab S7 at Best Buy - $530</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S7 at Amazon - $530" href="https://amzn.to/3lWmkw9">Buy Galaxy Tab S7 at Amazon - $530</a></p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S7+ at Best Buy - $730" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/EazNRX">Buy Galaxy Tab S7+ at Best Buy - $730</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S7+ at Amazon - $730" href="https://amzn.to/2VTJ7xq">Buy Galaxy Tab S7+ at Amazon - $730</a></p><h2>Galaxy Tab S6 Lite</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/b74b07e0-a11e-11ea-9dd6-89cd4eeb0389" style="height:1066;width:1600;" alt="Galaxy Tab S6 Lite review" data-uuid="45d4e391-3666-4863-9911-c85f5d157726"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>Samsung&#39;s affordable Android tablet is even cheaper in this sale — the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Galaxy Tab S6 Lite" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/5bMNKn">Galaxy Tab S6 Lite</a> is down to $270, or $80 off its normal price. If you&#39;re looking for a capable Android tablet that won&#39;t break the bank, this is one that gives you a number of premium features at a great price. We gave it a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review-s-pen-android-tablet-120040291.html">score of 84</a> for its sturdy, attractive design, long battery life and excellent note-taking features with the S Pen.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S6 Lite at Best Buy - $270" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/5bMNKn">Buy Galaxy Tab S6 Lite at Best Buy - $270</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Galaxy Tab S6 Lite at Amazon - $270" href="https://amzn.to/3jUQQnm">Buy Galaxy Tab S6 Lite at Amazon - $270</a></p><h2>Fujifilm X-T3</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?crop=1600%2C958%2C0%2C0&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;resize=1600%2C958&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2018-10%2F20fa2390-d16b-11e8-bdff-dcb73c22bcf4&amp;client=a1acac3e1b3290917d92&amp;signature=8578c285e97e5690ceb18f7aca506e81cfc54897" style="height:958;width:1600;" alt="Engadget" data-uuid="99326660-3829-3f30-8038-90fb56343d40"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Fujifilm X-T3" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/XxLeW5">Fujifilm X-T3</a> mirrorless camera is $300 off during this sale, bringing it down to $1,200. Although Fujifilm debuted the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fujifilm-x-t4-mirrorless-camera-review-140024236.html">X-T4</a> last year, the X-T3 remains a good option if you&#39;re on a tight budget. We gave it a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-10-16-fujifilm-x-t3-review.html">score of 90</a> for its faster autofocus, excellent image quality and its compact, weatherproof design.&nbsp;</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Fujifilm X-T3 at Best Buy - $1,200" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/XxLeW5">Buy Fujifilm X-T3 at Best Buy - $1,200</a><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Buy Fujifilm X-T3 at Amazon - $1,200" href="https://amzn.to/3m4XxWH">Buy Fujifilm X-T3 at Amazon - $1,200</a></p><h2>Google Pixelbook Go</h2><figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?resize=2000%2C2000%2Cshrink&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2019-10%2F9092d850-f69a-11e9-bced-5cc6df6ec198&amp;client=a1acac3e1b3290917d92&amp;signature=551b12258af3babb8f0475488cfc1d65842757b8" style="height:1066;width:1600;" data-uuid="a1cb0383-471f-3732-acf4-692069a6d892"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>We thought the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Pixelbook Go" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/YgqaLO">Pixelbook Go</a> was a bit too expensive for a Chromebook (even a high-powered one at that), but this sale knocks it down to $750. That gets you a Core i5 processor, 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage — more than enough power for most Chrome OS users. We gave the Go a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-25-google-pixelbook-go-review.html">score of 84</a> for its thin-and-light design, good performance and solid battery life.</p><p><a class="athena-button" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:impact radius;pdid:Buy Pixelbook Go at Best Buy - $750" href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/YgqaLO">Buy Pixelbook Go at Best Buy - $750</a></p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-buy-three-day-anniversary-sale-microsoft-surface-laptop-go-samsung-galaxy-tab-s7-google-wifi-125047416.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3d5a4297-7ddb-4585-8e04-c788e2327996</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:50:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628858721</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T12:45:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/b3aed160-8828-11eb-9947-93a522517fbe" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-03/b3aed160-8828-11eb-9947-93a522517fbe" width="1600" height="1066" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Best Buy discounts Surface laptops, Galaxy tablets in its latest weekend sale]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast: Diving into Samsung and foldables with Mr. Mobile]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, Cherlynn and guest co-host Mat Smith are joined by foldable aficionado and tech personality <a href="https://twitter.com/Captain2Phones">Michael Fisher</a> (aka Mr Mobile) to talk all about foldables. Specifically, Samsung’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-z-fold-3-hands-on-specs-price-available-now-140051893.html">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-z-flip-3-hands-on-specs-price-available-now-140057384.html">Z Flip 3</a>, as well as the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-watch-4-hands-on-price-specs-availability-wear-os-tizen-body-composition-fat-scan-140031859.html">new Galaxy Watch 4 series</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-150002889.html">Buds 2</a>. Then, our hosts try to make sense of the confusion around <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html">Apple’s CSAM-detecting features</a>, and go over some other gadgets launched this week.</p><p>Listen below, or subscribe on your podcast app of choice. If you&#39;ve got suggestions or topics you&#39;d like covered on the show, be sure to <a href="mailto:podcast@engadget.com?subject=Engadget%20Podcast%20Feedback"><strong>email us</strong></a> or drop a note in the comments! And be sure to check out our other podcasts, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-01-engadget-podcasts.html">Morning After and Engadget News</a>!</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="dc2e30a6d7d04db6bda0296765c4baa0"><iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1105099702&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/diving-into-samsungs-foldables-and-wearables-with-mr-mobile" title="Diving into Samsung&#x002019;s foldables and wearables with Mr. Mobile" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Diving into Samsung’s foldables and wearables with Mr. Mobile</a></div></div><p></p><h2><br>Subscribe!</h2><ul><li><p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-engadget-podcast/id1142790530?mt=2">iTunes</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3EC3dMIRB99dkvoSBeSO7G?si=f7UALGKmRDWtOrU8Z4-uiQ">Spotify</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://pca.st/mlY3">Pocket Casts</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/engadget/the-engadget-podcast">Stitcher</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://podcasts.google.com/?feed=aHR0cDovL2ZlZWRzLnNvdW5kY2xvdWQuY29tL3VzZXJzL3NvdW5kY2xvdWQ6dXNlcnM6MjQ1MjIwOTU4L3NvdW5kcy5yc3M&amp;ep=14">Google Podcasts</a></p></li></ul><h2><br><strong>Topics</strong></h2><ul><li><p>Samsung <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-august-11-supercut-170007617.html">Galaxy Unpacked News</a>: Z Fold 3 and Z Flip 3 with Mr. Mobile – 1:58</p></li><li><p>Where the Z Fold and Z Flip sit in foldable history – 27:47</p></li><li><p>Also announced at Unpacked: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-watch-4-hands-on-price-specs-availability-wear-os-tizen-body-composition-fat-scan-140031859.html">Galaxy Watch 4 and Watch 4 Classic</a> – 38:00</p></li><li><p>Making sense of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html">Apple’s Child Sexual Abuse Material (CSAM) detection</a> feature – 44:16</p></li><li><p>Xiaomi&#39;s robot dog <a href="https://www.engadget.com/xiaomi-cyberdog-robot-dog-141128369.html">is terrifying</a> – 52:49</p></li><li><p>What we&#39;re working on – 54:44</p></li><li><p>Pop culture picks – 57:00</p></li></ul><h2><br>Video livestream</h2><p></p><div id="b2dd9259f22d44ee9c9437eddcac2398"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aTdoKWjH5NU?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p><strong><em>Credits</em></strong><br><em>Hosts: Cherlynn Low and Mat Smith</em><br><em>Guest: </em><a href="https://twitter.com/Captain2Phones"><em>Michael Fisher</em></a><em> aka MrMobile</em><br><em>Producer: Ben Ellman</em><br><em>Livestream producers: Julio Barrientos, Owen Davidoff</em>, <em>Luke Brooks</em><br><em>Graphics artists: Luke Brooks, Kyle Maack</em><br><em>Music: Dale North and Terrence O&#39;Brien</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/engadget-podcast-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-flip-3-galaxy-watch-4-classic-apple-csam-michael-fisher-mr-mobile-123038641.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a04ca752-8609-4005-b2f9-376bf98063ed</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:30:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628835045</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T06:10:54+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c8e851c0-2b3d-11eb-baea-6c6fe29971fb" width="703" height="469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/f43b53b0-909f-11ea-87fd-d8d721459924" width="1600" height="719" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Poly Network offers $500,000 reward to crypto hacker who returned stolen assets]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the latest twist to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/poly-network-cryptocurrency-heist-returned-funds-133025946.html">Poly Network crypto hack</a>, the perpetrator who returned most of the $611 million in stolen digital tokens is being offered a $500,000 reward. The prize is a bug bounty to be precise, an incentive offered by tech organizations to those who report security vulnerabilities. In a statement, Poly Network referred to the culprit as a &quot;white hat&quot; in reference to his status as an ethical hacker. The decentralized finance platform thanked the hacker for &quot;helping to improve&quot; its security, but did not mention how it would pay the reward or whether it had been accepted.&nbsp;</p><div id="77756129a32f4e3ca4e3d98c7f0a9384"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">$342 million (As of 12 Aug 08:18:29 AM +UTC) of assets had been returned: <br>Ethereum: $4.6M <br>BSC: $252M <br>Polygon: $85M <br><br>The remaining is $268M on Ethereum</p>— Poly Network (@PolyNetwork2) <a href="https://twitter.com/PolyNetwork2/status/1425733950614360064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>A person claiming to be the perpetrator confirmed that Poly Network had offered him a $500,000 bounty to return the stolen assets and promised that he would not be held accountable for the incident, according to messages shared on Twitter by Tom Robinson, the chief scientist and co-founder of Elliptic, a crypto tracking firm.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="d2c3a0f189594a55939f1c9d4e7c0deb"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s not over yet! The PolyNetwork hacker seems to have sent the last $235m to a &quot;shared multisig&quot; account. Keys from both Poly &amp; hacker are required to access them. The hacker says they will &quot;PROVIDE THE FINAL KEY WHEN _EVERYONE_ IS READY&quot;. Full story:<a href="https://t.co/ifku7VUoqu">https://t.co/ifku7VUoqu</a></p>— Tom Robinson (@tomrobin) <a href="https://twitter.com/tomrobin/status/1426065812092297217?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Poly Network connects different blockchains, the ledgers upon which cryptocurrencies are based, so they can work together. The company revealed on Tuesday that it was the victim of a massive crypto heist that saw a hacker make away with about $611 million in Ethereum, Shiba Inu and other digital currencies.&nbsp;</p><p>On Wednesday, the hacker began returning the stolen funds after claiming they were ready to surrender. Poly Network said on Friday that the hacker had repaid $340 million worth of assets into a digital wallet. All that remains is the $33 million in tether frozen by the company behind the cryptocurrency.</p><p>It&#39;s still unclear what prompted the hacker to backtrack. Some experts believe that they may have found it hard to launder and cash out the large amount of stolen crypto. While others suggest that the hacker was afraid of being exposed and prosecuted after researchers discovered a trove of identifying info, including an email and IP address. More broadly, the bizarre series of events further illustrates the pitfalls involved with cryptocurrency, an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-treasury-crypto-transfers-irs-105605772.html">unregulated</a> domain where <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-01-27-coincheck-hack.html">hacks</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/crypto-ponzi-scam-roger-nils-jonas-karlsson-doj-071142854.html">scams</a> are rife.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/poly-network-rewards-crypto-hacker-121507483.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4ebfe9e6-8dc5-4ed1-b4ce-e7bd8dd4a542</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628861879</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T13:38:24+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/adf711b0-fc22-11eb-adef-96cc0787c4d3" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/adf711b0-fc22-11eb-adef-96cc0787c4d3" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Poly Network logo displayed on a phone screen and representation of Ethereum cryptocurrency is seen in this illustration photo taken in Sulkowice, Poland on August 12, 2021. (Photo by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Poly Network Photo Illustration]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: Understanding Apple’s child safety updates]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Apple announced that it was taking new steps to prevent the distribution of CSAM on its platform. This included a system to detect such material by scanning the images in people’s iCloud libraries, which has proved controversial. Privacy campaigners have said that this is the first step on a slippery slope to allowing governments all over the world access to people’s phones. That could have implications for activists and journalists in more authoritarian countries, something Apple has prior form in bowing to.</p><p>That’s why Engadget’s Karissa Bell has taken a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html">deep, deep dive</a> into what exactly is going on with all of this. If you’ve only heard snatches of what’s going on, and don’t quite get what the real world impacts are, then we’ve got you covered. She’s explored how the technology works, what Apple has said, and if anyone really needs to be concerned.</p><p>-Dan Cooper</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/zooms-new-focus-mode-is-designed-to-block-student-distractions-082533097.html"><strong>Zoom&#39;s new Focus mode hides people who might distract you</strong></a></h2><h3>Teachers can stop classmates from pulling focus away from the lesson.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/zooms-new-focus-mode-is-designed-to-block-student-distractions-082533097.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d9ec1010-fb3f-11eb-97fa-77330bbd0bf9" alt="Zoom&#39;s new Focus mode is designed to block student distractions" data-uuid="043a27a0-902c-3d93-8900-87d2a49e4ffe"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Zoom</div></figure></a><p>Zoom knows that not even the internet can dampen the allure of watching the class clown instead of your teacher. That’s why the company is unveiling Focus Mode, which is designed for educators trying to wrest control of their lesson back from the students. With it, teachers can see all of the students on their own feed, but each student can only see the teacher and whatever presentation the teacher is giving. That could be a key tool to keep kids paying attention especially with the Delta variant threatening to derail the start of school. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/zooms-new-focus-mode-is-designed-to-block-student-distractions-082533097.html"><strong>Continue Reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-behaviosec-keystroke-software-report-175350458.html">Amazon may monitor employee keystrokes to protect customer data</a></h2><h3>It says it needs to in order to protect its users.</h3><p></p><p>Amazon is planning to license keystroke-monitoring software to keep an eye on its employees when they work from home. A leaked document purportedly from the company says that there is a concern that remote working could lead to a rise in data breaches. As such, it’s planning to use software from a company called BehavioSec which tracks keyboard and mouse use. In a statement, Amazon said that it treated the security of user data with the highest respect, and that it was always exploring new ways of safeguarding its customers. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-behaviosec-keystroke-software-report-175350458.html"><strong>Continue Reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-vr-headsets-140012529.html">The best VR headsets you can buy</a></h2><h3>There&#39;s something for every budget.&nbsp;</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-vr-headsets-140012529.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-07/e35896d1-eb10-11eb-b7ff-c8fd80773144" alt="HTC Vive Pro 2" data-uuid="31169255-820a-32dc-9309-a7c6c02fe00e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar/Engadget</div></figure></a><p>If you’ve been waiting for VR to mature to the point where you can really get some value out of the technology, now may be the time. A number of companies are now making comfortable, usable and in some cases surprisingly affordable headsets for standalone and PC gaming. In our latest buyer’s guide, we explore the best VR gear for most people, the most affordable way to get set up, and which headset comes out on top as the best that money can buy. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-vr-headsets-140012529.html"><strong>Continue Reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/honor-magic3-flagship-125020517.html">Honor’s new Magic3 heralds the company’s glorious return</a></h2><h3>Photography is at the heart of this new handset, and the specs are outrageous.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/honor-magic3-flagship-125020517.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/b03162a0-fb64-11eb-8fdf-721d4a0179c6" alt="Honor Magic 3" data-uuid="330ba3c3-fd17-325a-9729-652651d4173d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Honor</div></figure></a><p>Honor, for many years, was a subsidiary of Chinese mega-corp Huawei responsible for making budget phones. When the US sanctions against the company began to bite, however, Huawei sold Honor off so it could try to flourish as a standalone business. Now, Honor is reintroducing itself to the world with the Magic3, a new flagship with a “more-is-more-is-more” approach to photography. The Magic3 Pro+, for instance, has a 50-megapixel primary camera, flanked by a trio of <em>64-megapixel</em> sensors for zoom, wide-angle and monochrome photography. Honor says that it can even shoot cinema-quality video, which is a feature we can’t wait to test. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/honor-magic3-flagship-125020517.html"><strong>Continue Reading. </strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-lower-decks-season-two-premiere-strange-energies-070032163.html">The new season of ‘Star Trek: Lower Decks’ stays true to the show’s core</a></h2><h3>The crew of the USS Cerritos is back.</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-lower-decks-season-two-premiere-strange-energies-070032163.html"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5d3312e0-f945-11eb-a9f5-d304df63cf07" data-uuid="cd1b2bdc-c010-3362-9554-19c1f2faa458"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">CBS</div></figure></a><p>The best <em>Star Trek</em> series since <em>Deep Space Nine</em> is back, and it’s as good as it ever was in its first year. <em>Lower Decks</em> features the crew of the USS Cerritos, with an emphasis on those folks who aren’t doing all of the top-tier adventuring on the bridge. In our preview of the second season premiere, you’ll find out if it remains as funny as it was, if it stays true to the show’s core and if it’s worth tuning in, although given that it airs on Paramount+, we probably shouldn’t say “tuning in&#39;&#39; any more, should we? <a href="https://www.engadget.com/star-trek-lower-decks-season-two-premiere-strange-energies-070032163.html"><strong>Continue Reading. </strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>All the news you might have missed</h2><h2></h2><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/polestar-2-single-motor-price-range-151503533.html">The entry-level Polestar 2 with a single motor will start at $45,900</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/home-sweet-home-alone-november-12-disney-plus-154826755.html">Home Alone reboot debuts on Disney+ on November 12th</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-loses-designers-121905544.html">Activision Blizzard loses three senior designers amid sexual harassment lawsuit</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/criterion-is-releasing-citizen-kane-and-five-other-classics-in-4-k-055641188.html">Criterion is releasing &#39;Citizen Kane&#39; and five other classics on 4K Blu-ray</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-limits-teen-access-130931754.html">TikTok limits the visibility of teens&#39; videos amid safety push</a></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/morning-after-apple-child-safety-zoom-vr-honor-magic3-111540397.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">5e313311-8c66-4c53-bdb9-099b939c8ae3</guid><dc:creator>Daniel Cooper</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628846775</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T09:26:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Daniel Cooper]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/333dbed0-fa59-11eb-bbeb-9b1adbf47f68" width="5000" height="3362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/333dbed0-fa59-11eb-bbeb-9b1adbf47f68" width="5000" height="3362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[SOPA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[HONG KONG, CHINA - 2021/08/10: American multinational technology company Apple store seen in Hong Kong. (Photo by Budrul Chukrut/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[American multinational technology company Apple store seen...]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple TV's Tom Hanks sci-fi movie 'Finch' arrives November 5th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple has given a release date for the second of two Tom Hanks films it acquired during the pandemic. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-tom-hanks-finch-movie-131022786.html"><em>Finch</em></a>, a futuristic tale about a reclusive inventor and his canine and robot road buddies, hits Apple TV+ on November 5th. Like Hanks&#39; war movie <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-greyhound-tom-hanks-ww-ii-drama-july-10-092506494.html"><em>Greyhound </em></a>before it, the film became a casualty of the pandemic, mired by release date delays until Apple swooped in to acquire it from Universal. The robot (pictured above) is played by Caleb Landry Jones, fresh off a best actor win at Cannes.&nbsp;</p><p>Hanks plays the titular character, an ailing robotics engineer who emerges from his self-imposed underground exile to journey across a desolate American wasteland. Along for the ride are his dog, Goodyear, and an android who names himself Jeff. Together, they make a dysfunctional family, but can they learn to get along? I guess we&#39;ll have to wait till November to find out.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p><em>Finch </em>is also loaded with offscreen talent. The good-natured sci-fi flick is directed by Emmy-winning <em>Game of Thrones</em> lead Miguel Sapochnik, with <em>Alien</em> scribe Ivor Powell and newcomer Craig Luck on screenwriting duties. While director Robert Zemeckis<em>&nbsp;</em>serves as an exec-producer and the film hails from Steven Spielberg&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/steven-spielberg-netflix-ambiln-175031862.html">Amblin Entertainment</a>, which may explain why the plot gives off major <em>Cast Away</em> and <em>AI </em>vibes.</p><p>The November release date also signals Apple&#39;s possible confidence in the film&#39;s awards chances. Either that or it&#39;s just looking to add a major movie to its fall line-up, which is already stocked with big hitters like sci-fi series <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-tv-plus-foundation-isaac-asimov-release-date-152711615.html"><em>Foundation</em></a><em>, </em>the second season of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-show-season-2-teaser-apple-tv-plus-141241307.html"><em>The Morning Show</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and current affairs show <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jon-stewart-apple-tv-plus-221022043.html"><em>The Problem with Jon Stewart</em></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-tom-hanks-finch-release-date-085915154.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">62b4d578-0a0e-4469-af81-d05e0be4787c</guid><dc:creator>Saqib Shah</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 08:59:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628857176</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T12:19:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Saqib Shah]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/14839d00-fc13-11eb-b771-ff01baf6651d" width="2500" height="1665" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/14839d00-fc13-11eb-b771-ff01baf6651d" width="2500" height="1665" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Apple]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Finch]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Finch]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disney says it found ways to compensate talent in the wake of 'Black Widow' lawsuit]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Disney has apparently <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/12/disney-ceo-on-talent-compensation-after-scarlett-johansson-lawsuit.html">found</a> &quot;ways to fairly compensate&quot; talent, even if it continues its hybrid release strategy. Company CEO Bob Chapek said during an earnings call that Disney has &quot;entered hundreds of talent arrangements with [its] talent and by and large, they&#39;ve gone very very smoothly.&quot; Chapek&#39;s statement comes in the wake of the lawsuit <em>Black Widow</em> star Scarlett Johansson <a href="https://www.engadget.com/black-widow-scarlett-johansson-sues-disney-streaming-marvel-cinematic-universe-183341118.html">filed</a> against the company over its streaming strategy.&nbsp;</p><p>Johansson&#39;s salary was tied to the movie&#39;s box office success, and her original contract didn&#39;t cover earnings from a hybrid release. According to her complaint, she could lose over $50 million due to the company&#39;s decision to simultaneously launch <em>Black Widow</em> in theaters and on Disney+, where it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/black-widow-disney-plus-opening-weekend-174633013.html">made $60 million</a> during its opening weekend. Back then, Disney released a statement calling the lawsuit &quot;especially sad and distressing in its callous disregard for the horrific and prolonged global effects of the Covid-19 pandemic.&quot;&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Now, Chapek said Disney is &quot;trying to do the best thing for all [its] constituents and make sure that everybody who&#39;s in the value chain [...] feels like they&#39;re having their contractual commitments honored both from a distribution and a compensation standpoint.&quot; He didn&#39;t talk about specifics, however, or Johansson&#39;s lawsuit in particular. In Johansson&#39;s complaint, she said her camp tried to renegotiate her deal with the company upon learning about the simultaneous release. However, Disney and Marvel were allegedly unresponsive.</p><p>Chapek also <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/marvels-shang-chi-set-to-hit-disney-plus-in-mid-october-possibly-free/#ftag=CAD590a51e">talked</a> about implementing an experimental release strategy for <em>Shang-Chi</em>. Unlike <em>Black Widow</em>, it will be a theater-exclusive for 45 days before making its way to Disney+. Further, subscribers may be able to watch it for free instead of having to pay extra for it like they&#39;ve had to do with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-mulan-date-232629863.html"><em>Mulan</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/disney-compensate-talent-black-widow-lawsuit-070554946.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">01ee3bb7-a0f8-4801-a037-ecc23c2081b5</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 07:05:54 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628862197</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T13:43:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Company Legal & Law Matters]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c2263280-fbf3-11eb-bed3-bf1de5baeb27" width="1600" height="993" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c2263280-fbf3-11eb-bed3-bf1de5baeb27" width="1600" height="993" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Marvel Studios]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Black Widow]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Black Widow]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google makes Meet moderation easier by allowing up to 25 people to co-host]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It can be hard for a single host to manage large unruly video meetings, particularly given the complexity and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-meet-filters-masks-ios-android-084044336.html">features</a> available in video conferencing apps these days. Now, Google has a solution for its Meet app with a new feature that allows you to have up to 25 co-hosts in a meeting, as <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/08/12/google-meet-co-hosts/"><em>9to5Google</em></a> has reported. That way, they can split chore like muting participants, launching polls, managing Q&amp;As and more, while you focus on the business at hand.&nbsp;</p><p>Until now, the feature was only available to Google Workspace for Education customers. Now, it&#39;s on all of Google&#39;s Meet apps across desktop and mobile, including users with personal Google accounts.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>On top of that, Google introduced new controls for meeting hosts, which can be extended to co-hosts. All hosts will be able to limit who can share their screen, limit who can send chat messages, mute all with one click, end the meeting for all and control who can join the meeting and how they can join with the &quot;quick access&quot; setting. The latter allows participants in the same domain to enter automatically.&nbsp;</p><p>“Quick access” allows automatic video call entry for users in the same domain. If disabled, hosts must join first, and those that are not invited will have to request permission to enter. Otherwise, the host must join first and give permission to anyone who isn&#39;t invited.&nbsp;</p><p>The last feature, the &quot;People&quot; panel, adds search to let hosts quickly find participants if moderation actions are needed. The new features will begin rolling out next week on the web and Meet for Android, and the iOS version will arrive at the end of the month.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-meet-makes-moderation-easier-by-allowing-up-to-25-people-to-co-host-055344666.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">901ee10b-64c0-448a-b59a-f3d6ad475a58</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 05:53:44 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628834024</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T05:53:57+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4b2a47f0-fbfa-11eb-bd7d-619dd2837feb" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/4b2a47f0-fbfa-11eb-bd7d-619dd2837feb" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Google Meet makes moderation easier by allowing up to 25 people to co-host]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Meet makes moderation easier by allowing up to 25 people to co-host]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google's Nest Hub will display air quality levels as wildfire season continues]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google is <a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/thread/120800522/stay-in-the-know-about-the-air-around-you-on-your-nest-display?hl=en">updating</a> its Nest Hub displays with a new feature that displays the air quality index (AQI), <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-start-providing-air-quality-updates-nest-hub-devices"><em>Android Central</em></a> has reported. The feature will appear on the weather widget, showing a numeric ranking from 0 to 500 and color coding from green (good) to maroon (hazardous). Google is taking the data from the US government&#39;s <a href="https://www.airnow.gov/aqi/aqi-basics/">AQI site</a> used by the EPA to monitor air quality across the US.&nbsp;</p><p>Along with the AQI index and colors in the weather widget, Nest display owners can also ask Google Assistant for air quality information by saying &quot;what&#39;s the air quality near me&quot; or something similar. You can also ask Assistant to give alerts when the air quality your location drops to unsafe levels, a feature that could be handy for folks with respiratory problems.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The feature is rolling out as wildfires rage across the western United States, particularly in Oregon and California. &quot;Between wildfire season and recent increased efforts to reduce air pollution, it’s more important than ever to know about the air quality in your area,&quot; Google said in a Nest community update.&nbsp;</p><p>The update will be rolling out in select markets &quot;over the coming weeks,&quot; hopefully in those regions affected by wildfires and smoke. In our <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-nest-hub-2nd-gen-2021-review-sleep-tracking-radar-price-specs-130026942.html">review</a>, we called the <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/nest_hub_2nd_gen?hl=en-US">$100 Nest Hub</a> (2nd generation) &quot;a great smart display and mediocre sleep tracker.&quot;&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/googles-nest-will-display-air-quality-levels-as-wildfires-continue-to-rage-040101324.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f48cefdc-57f5-48c2-b054-f5299bb59a2c</guid><dc:creator>Steve Dent</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:01:01 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628858812</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T12:47:00+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Nature & Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Steve Dent]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/3c9b01c0-f813-11ea-afc7-4fb3bee8ce24" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-09/3c9b01c0-f813-11ea-afc7-4fb3bee8ce24" width="5472" height="3648" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Stephen Lam / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Bay Bridge is seen under an orange sky darkened by the smoke from California wildfires in San Francisco, California, U.S., September 9, 2020. REUTERS/Stephen Lam     TPX IMAGES OF THE DAY]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[USA-WILDFIRES/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Want a 1972 Ford Bronco turned into an EV? It'll cost you $380,000]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While it seems we won’t have to wait much longer for Ford to <a href="https://www.autoblog.com/2020/03/09/baby-bronco-leaked/"><ins>announce an all-electric Bronco</ins></a>, it probably won’t have the same classic styling as the 1972 version of the SUV. But if you have at least $260,000 in the bank, a company called <a href="https://www.gatewaybronco.com/"><ins>Gateway Bronco</ins></a> will happily build you a vintage Bronco that’s specced like a modern EV. This week, it announced two new models, the Fuelie Electric and Luxe-GT Electric, that feature 220 kW electric motors that the company claims can accelerate the former gas-guzzler from zero to 60 miles per hour in less than five seconds.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/c6dff990-fbbd-11eb-b73b-aabd97d896e3" style="height:1200;width:1600;" alt="Gateway Bronco EV" data-uuid="24048b06-b5cd-3d0a-a86a-d4e7c2581f5c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Gateway Bronco</div></figure><p>Range on the less expensive Fuelie model comes in at a claimed 200 miles, while the Luxe-GT (pictured throughout), which starts at an eye-watering $380,000, can travel up to 300 miles on a single charge. Other noteworthy features include 18-inch wheels that Gateway Bronco has fitted with Wilwood disc brakes and 33-inch Toyo tires. You also get a seven-year warranty on the electric drivetrain. Oh, and the interior looks sublime.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/72f8b7c0-fbbf-11eb-99fe-8296e443d2d5" style="height:1200;width:1600;" alt="Bronco" data-uuid="51e9c2aa-801d-3f82-a0c4-30ddadb12284"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Gateway Bronco</div></figure><p>Even when you account for inflation and the cost of all the modern technology Gateway Bronco has included in the Fuelie and Luxe-GT, a minimum of $260,000 is a lot of money for a restomod of a car that cost $2,194 in 1966. But it’s about the going rate for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/electric-ford-bronco-zero-labs-163500928.html"><ins>electric conversions of this type</ins></a>. You could do the work yourself once automakers like Chevy <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chevy-ecrate-2021-174002305.html"><ins>release electric crate motors</ins></a> later in the year, but you’re still likely looking at an expensive project.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/gateway-bronco-luxe-gt-electric-230136271.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">c631a2e5-a63a-4107-a697-54c7445acd2a</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 23:01:36 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628808911</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T22:55:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/a461b6b0-fbbd-11eb-bfed-21c52e43fb18" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/a461b6b0-fbbd-11eb-bfed-21c52e43fb18" width="1600" height="1000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Gateway Bronco]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Ford Bronco]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ford Bronco]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wendy's plans 700 kitchens expressly for food delivery apps]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Given how convenient it is to tap a few buttons and have someone bring dinner to your door, food delivery isn&#39;t likely to drop in popularity anytime soon. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Wendys"><ins>Wendy&#39;s</ins></a> is looking to meet surging demand by opening hundreds of delivery-only kitchens in the next few years. The likes of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/uber%20eats"><ins>Uber Eats</ins></a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/doordash"><ins>DoorDash</ins></a> and <a href="http://engadget.com/tag/grubhub/"><ins>Grubhub</ins></a> will handle orders.</p><p>Wendy&#39;s is planning to open 700 such kitchens in the US, UK and Canada by 2025, as the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/lifestyle-canada-business-health-coronavirus-pandemic-edfc595733eb1492f40415f152beda43"><em><ins>Associated Press</ins></em></a> reports. The locations will primarily be in major cities and the first 50 should be up and running this year.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Reef Technology, which already manages around 5,000 so-called &quot;ghost kitchens,&quot; will open the Wendy&#39;s locations and hire workers. Wendy&#39;s will take around a six percent cut of sales, which are expected to hit at least $500,000 annually at each kitchen.</p><p>The concept of ghost kitchens has been around for several years. They&#39;re kitchens without storefronts that make food orders only for delivery or pickup — some are run out of existing brick-and-mortar restaurants. Other fast food chains have experimented with the idea, including Chick-fil-A and <a href="https://newsroom.chipotle.com/2020-11-11-Chipotle-To-Open-Its-First-Digital-Only-Restaurant">Chipotle</a>. Meanwhile, YouTuber MrBeast <a href="https://www.producebluebook.com/2021/07/16/ghost-kitchens-dont-work-for-everyone/#"><ins>uses ghost kitchens</ins></a> for his burger chain, which has more than 900 locations.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/wendys-ghost-kitchen-food-delivery-uber-eats-doordash-grubhub-220215092.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f5c5dd28-7b21-4811-8b74-65ce5b97761f</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 22:02:15 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628805737</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T22:02:26+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Professional Services]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f2cc0a50-fbb6-11eb-9ace-d65d0e54273f" width="5359" height="3521" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/f2cc0a50-fbb6-11eb-9ace-d65d0e54273f" width="5359" height="3521" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Justin Sullivan via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[RICHMOND, CALIFORNIA - MAY 12: A view of a Wendy's restaurant on May 12, 2021 in Richmond, California. Wendy's reported first quarter earnings that beat analyst expectations with revenues of $460.2 million compared to $405 million one year ago. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Wendy's Reports Rise In Q1 Earnings With 13 Percent Increase In Same Store Sales]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook delays office re-opening to January 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook employees will be working from home at least until the end of the year. The company has pushed back its plans to bring US employees back to the office due to concerns about rising COVID cases due to the delta variant. The company had said earlier this summer that it planned to reopen US offices at 50 percent capacity <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/facebook-says-track-reopen-all-us-offices-by-october-2021-06-09/">by September</a>. But that timeline has now been pushed back to January as cases have risen.</p><p>“Data, not dates, is what drives our approach for returning to the office,” the company said in a statement <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/12/facebook-delays-return-to-office-until-january-2022-for-us-some-international-employees.html">to <em>CNBC</em></a>. “Given the recent health data showing rising Covid cases based on the delta variant, our teams in the U.S. will not be required to go back to the office until January 2022. We expect this to be the case for some countries outside of the US, as well. We continue to monitor the situation and work with experts to ensure our return to office plans prioritize everyone’s safety.”</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Facebook made headlines in early 2020 for being <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/06/facebook-tells-bay-area-employees-to-stay-home-amid-coronavirus-outbreak.html">among the first</a> to close its offices, well before many areas instituted their own lockdowns policies. The company has also said that it will require its US employees to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-and-facebook-employees-can-work-from-home-for-the-rest-of-the-year-130010883.html">be vaccinated</a> against COVID-19. Whenever it does re-open, it’s likely that work will look and feel much different to many employees. The company has said it will embrace remote work going forward, with Mark Zuckerberg saying that as much as <a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10111936543502931">50 percent</a> of the company’s workforce could remote in the next five to 10 years.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/facebook-delays-office-reopening-plans-211711342.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">20f45201-fa64-4374-b6e6-872d1b14ae5c</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 21:17:11 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628862098</ingested><modified>2021-08-13T13:41:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/3378b790-fbaf-11eb-afb7-54e1797c6754" width="3000" height="1969" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/3378b790-fbaf-11eb-afb7-54e1797c6754" width="3000" height="1969" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Dominic Lipinski - PA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A man walks past a Facebook logo at Facebook's new Frank Gehry-designed headquarters at Rathbone Place in London. (Photo by Dominic Lipinski/PA Images via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[New Facebook London office]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[HomePods get spatial audio and Apple Music lossless support in latest beta]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It looks like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/homepod"><ins>HomePod</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/homepod%20mini"><ins>HomePod mini</ins></a> will soon have support for spatial audio and lossless audio via Apple Music. The HomePod 15 beta 5 includes options that enable lossless and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-homepod-dolby-atmos-apple-tv-4k-142055970.html"><ins>Dolby Atmos</ins></a> playback.</p><p>Not all beta users will see the toggles, according to <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/12/homepod-15-beta-spatial-audio-lossless-support-apple-music/"><em><ins>9to5Mac</ins></em></a>. If you&#39;re running the latest iOS 15 and HomePod betas, you can check whether they&#39;re active by accessing the home options menu in the Home app, tapping your profile, then Media and Apple Music.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Earlier this year, Apple said it would <a href="https://www.engadget.com/homepod-mini-apple-music-lossless-support-update-151446333.html"><ins>bring Apple Music lossless streaming to HomePod</ins></a> and HomePod mini through a software update, but it didn&#39;t provide a timeline. Now, it seems the speakers will be able to stream lossless music soon (unless the option&#39;s already life for you in the beta).</p><p>Apple is expected to roll out its latest operating systems broadly within the next couple of months. When it does, you&#39;ll be able to pair a second HomePod mini to Apple TV for stereo audio.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/homepod-mini-spatial-audio-apple-music-lossless-support-beta-210300048.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">2bdb7b3d-115d-4e5a-ac71-826107cd4368</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628802183</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T21:03:12+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audio Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/74c373a1-244d-11eb-af8f-77d21fbd118b" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/74c373a1-244d-11eb-af8f-77d21fbd118b" width="1600" height="1067" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple HomePod mini review photos.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple HomePod mini]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon ditches policy claiming ownership of employees’ personal games]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/amazon"><ins>Amazon</ins></a> has reportedly scrapped a policy that claimed ownership rights to any games that employees created outside of work. Under the previous rules, the company required employees to using Amazon products while working on personal projects and to distribute those games on its storefronts.</p><p>Those policies are longer in place, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-12/amazon-drops-company-policies-on-game-development-after-backlash?sref=10lNAhZ9"><em><ins>Bloomberg</ins></em></a>. In an email to staff seen by the publication, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/Amazon%20Game%20Studios">Amazon Game Studios</a> head <a href="https://www.engadget.com/andy-jassy-committed-to-amazon-game-studios-213722395.html"><ins>Mike Frazzini</ins></a> said the company was dropping the rules immediately. &quot;These policies were originally put in place over a decade ago when we had a lot less information and experience than we do today, and as a result, the policies were written quite broadly,&quot; Frazzini wrote. Engadget has contacted Amazon for comment.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Amazon received a backlash over the rules after an engineer who interviewed at the company disclosed the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/amazon-games-personal-game-policy"><ins>Amazon Personal Games policy</ins></a>. The rules granted Amazon “a royalty free, worldwide, fully paid-up, perpetual, transferable license” to the intellectual property of games its employees made off the clock. The policy was decried as &quot;draconian&quot; by some developers when a now-deleted tweet from the engineer gained traction.</p><p>However, Amazon isn&#39;t the only company to have enacted such a policy. Google has also <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/former-googlers-google-ip-open-source-policy-iarc-2020-1"><ins>been accused</ins></a> of claiming ownership of employees&#39; own external projects.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/amazon-personal-games-policy-ditched-200718582.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">fc6e3397-bce4-4ea9-9ab1-7dbe20486e3d</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:07:18 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628798841</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T20:07:30+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/18b27c40-fba8-11eb-99b7-bede4d188787" width="5315" height="3543" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/18b27c40-fba8-11eb-99b7-bede4d188787" width="5315" height="3543" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ivan Romano via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[NAPLES, ITALY - MARCH 22: The Ariete 1 sorting warehouse of the multinational Amazon on March 22, 2021 in Arzano, Italy. The first strike of Amazon workers organized by the CGIL, Cisl and Uil unions at the Arzano headquarters was totally deserted by the workers who did not join the presidium to which, in addition to the unions, some formations of the extra-parliamentary left joined. The unions had called the strike day to ask for a review of many aspects of staff contracts: workloads, shifts, meal vouchers, bonuses, travel allowances and reduced working hours, and a general stabilization of drivers, the logistics sector and the administered employees. For some trade unionists, the absence of workers from the garrison should be read as "fear that their contracts will not be renewed". (Photo by Ivan Romano/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amazon Workers Strike In Naples]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung's Galaxy Z Flip 3 will be the first foldable phone available on Google Fi]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-z-flip-3-hands-on-specs-price-available-now-140057384.html"><ins>Galaxy Z Flip 3</ins></a> goes on sale later this month, you’ll be able to <a href="https://fave.co/3fZ4y7E"><ins>buy it from Google Fi</ins></a>, marking the first time the MVNO has sold a foldable device. Moreover, if you decide to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/how-to-pre-order-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-5g-galaxy-z-flip-3-galaxy-watch-4-galaxy-watch-4-classic-galaxy-buds-2-144623619.html">pre-order the clamshell phone</a> from the search giant, you can get a $400 bill credit.</p><p>If you’re new to the carrier, you’ll need to port your number to Fi from your current wireless provider. As part of the promotion, you can also get a $150 credit from Samsung, which you can use on its website, provided you order the foldable before its August 27th release date and then register your purchase through the Samsung Shop app before the end of September 26th. The credit is valid until November 9th. You can find the full details of the deal on <a href="https://fi.google.com/about/promo-terms/?p=2021-august-samsung-flip"><ins>Google’s website</ins></a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>When Samsung announced the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/galaxy-z-flip-3-hands-on-specs-price-available-now-140057384.html"><ins>Galaxy Z Flip 3</ins></a> at its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-august-11-supercut-170007617.html"><ins>Unpacked event</ins></a> on Wednesday, it said it was ready to make foldables mainstream. With a more affordable $1,000 price tag, the company certainly has a chance to make that happen. It also doesn’t hurt to have aggressive promotions like the one Google is offering through Fi.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-fi-galaxy-z-flip-3-195457726.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7639e213-545d-432e-b648-7b97bdd85cbd</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 19:54:57 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628798101</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T19:55:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/56d925c0-fa3e-11eb-b3df-f3a11c876eca" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/56d925c0-fa3e-11eb-b3df-f3a11c876eca" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Cherlynn Low / Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 3]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 3]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft rolls out updated Mail, Calendar and Calculator apps to Windows 11 testers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft is <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/08/12/first-set-of-windows-app-updates-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders-for-windows-11/">updating some of the apps</a> that come preloaded with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-hands-on-microsoft-insider-preview-215041175.html">Windows 11</a>. To start, you’ll find a new version of the Snipping Tool that borrows a handful of features from Microsoft’s Snip &amp; Sketch app. Press the “Win,” “Shift” and “S” keys on your keyboard simultaneously to activate the software and then select the part of your screen you want to capture. Once you’ve snapped a screenshot, you’ll find various tools that allow you to edit and annotate the image. With Windows 11, the Snipping Tool also finally includes a dark mode, and you can set it independent of your system theme.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/9bff1710-fb9f-11eb-a997-e56059b630a5" style="height:1001;width:1800;" alt="Windows 11 Snipping Tool" data-uuid="03426793-b5e4-3171-9294-b91fd95a923d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Microsoft</div></figure><p>Microsoft is also updating the Mail and Calendar apps in Windows 11. You’ll notice they now feature rounded corners “and other adjustments” that should help make them feel more like a natural extension of the operating system.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Last but certainly not least, the humble calculator app has received some love from Microsoft. It too now includes a dark mode you can set independent of Windows. The company has also rewritten the software in C# in hopes of more people contributing to its development over on <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/calculator">GitHub</a>.</p><p>According to Dave Grochocki, a senior program manager lead for Windows inbox apps, Microsoft plans to release “even more updates to the apps that come in Windows 11.” Look for previews of those to arrive before the company releases Windows 11 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-launch-microsoft-151140403.html">later this year</a>. In the meantime, you can test the newly updated apps if you’re in the Windows Insider Dev Channel.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-updates-windows-11-mail-calendar-calculator-apps-190448163.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">802eace5-bd23-49c9-9c8e-f422b347ef4b</guid><dc:creator>Igor Bonifacic</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 19:04:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628795092</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T19:05:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Igor Bonifacic]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/409ede10-fb9e-11eb-a3b1-5c00a2a2081f" width="1600" height="999" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/409ede10-fb9e-11eb-a3b1-5c00a2a2081f" width="1600" height="999" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Calculator Windows 11]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Calculator Windows 11]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Apple's child safety updates are so controversial]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Apple previewed a number <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-ios-15-193820644.html">of updates</a> meant to beef up child safety features on its devices. Among them: a new technology that can scan the photos on users’ devices in order to detect child sexual abuse material (CSAM). Though the change was widely praised by some lawmakers and child safety advocates, it prompted immediate pushback from many security and privacy experts, who say the update amounts to Apple walking back its commitment to putting user privacy above all else.</p><p>Apple has disputed that characterization, saying that its approach balances both privacy and the need to do more to protect children by preventing some of the most abhorrent content from spreading more widely.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><strong>What did Apple announce?</strong></h2><p>Apple announced <a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/">three separate updates</a>, all of which fall under the umbrella of “child safety.” The most significant — and the one that’s gotten the bulk of the attention — is a feature that will scan iCloud Photos for known CSAM. The feature, which is built into iCloud Photos, compares a user’s photos against a database of previously identified material. If a certain number of those images is detected, it triggers a review process. If the images are verified by human reviewers, Apple will suspend that iCloud account and report it to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC).</p><p>Apple also previewed new “communication safety” features for the Messages app. That update enables the Messages app to detect when sexually explicit photos are sent or received by children. Importantly, this feature is only available for children who are part of a family account, and it’s up to parents to opt in.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/d4ff9d40-fb96-11eb-9eef-a4cc2fb18968" alt="Apple&#39;s new Messages feature for children will send warnings when sexually explicit images are sent or received. " data-uuid="4b2162e0-2b79-3ef5-9430-3a26a1a69efa"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>If parents do opt into the feature, they will be alerted if a child under the age of 13 views one of these photos. For children older than 13, the Messages app will show a warning upon receiving an explicit image, but won’t alert their parents. Though the feature is part of the Messages app, and separate from the CSAM detection, Apple has noted that the feature could still play a role in stopping child exploitation, as it could disrupt predatory messages.</p><p>Finally, Apple is updating Siri and its search capabilities so that it can “intervene” in queries about CSAM. If someone asks how to report abuse material, for example, Siri will provide links to resources to do so. If it detects that someone might be searching <em>for</em> CSAM, it will display a warning and surface resources to provide help.</p><h2><strong>When is this happening and can you opt out?</strong></h2><p>The changes will be part of iOS 15, which will roll out later this year. Users can effectively opt out by disabling iCloud Photos (instructions for doing so can be found <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204570">here</a>). However, anyone disabling iCloud Photos should keep in mind that it could affect your ability to access photos across multiple devices.</p><h2><strong>So how does this image scanning work?</strong></h2><p>Apple is far from the only company that scans photos to look for CSAM. Apple’s approach to doing so, however, is unique. The CSAM detection relies on a database of known material, maintained by NCMEC and other safety organizations. These images are “hashed” (Apple’s official name for this is NeuralHash) — a process that converts images to a numerical code that allows them to be identified, even if they are modified in some way, such as cropping or making other visual edits. As previously mentioned, CSAM detection only functions if iCloud Photos is enabled. What’s notable about Apple’s approach is that rather than matching the images once they’ve been sent to the cloud — as most cloud platforms do — Apple has moved that process to users’ devices.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/19d14270-fb97-11eb-85f3-29411f6e1ef6" alt="Apple&#39;s CSAM hashing system, NeuralHash." data-uuid="24126b46-5516-3a7b-adf1-782bc779a159"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>Here’s how it works: Hashes of the known CSAM are stored on the device, and on-device photos are compared to those hashes. The iOS device then generates an encrypted “safety voucher” that’s sent to iCloud along with the image. If a device reaches a certain threshold of CSAM, Apple can decrypt the safety vouchers and conduct a manual review of those images. Apple isn’t saying what the threshold is, but has made clear a single image wouldn’t result in any action.</p><p>Apple also published a detailed technical explanation of the process <a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/pdf/CSAM_Detection_Technical_Summary.pdf">here</a>.</p><h2><strong>Why is this so controversial?</strong></h2><p>Privacy advocates and security researchers have raised a number of concerns. One of these is that this feels like a major reversal for Apple, which five years ago refused the FBI’s request to unlock a phone and has put up <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/01/05/apple-privacy-billboard-vegas-ces/">billboards </a>stating “what happens on your iPhone stays on your iPhone.” To many, the fact that Apple created a system that can proactively check your images for illegal material and refer them to law enforcement, feels like a betrayal of that promise.</p><p>In a statement, the Electronic Frontier Foundation <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/08/apples-plan-think-different-about-encryption-opens-backdoor-your-private-life">called it</a> “a shocking about-face for users who have relied on the company’s leadership in privacy and security.” Likewise, Facebook — which has spent years taking heat from Apple over its privacy missteps — has taken issue with the iPhone maker’s approach to CSAM. WhatsApp chief, Will Cathcart, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-head-apple-child-safety-surveillance-system-201956787.html">described it</a> as “an Apple built and operated surveillance system.”</p><p>More specifically, there are real concerns that once such a system is created, Apple could be pressured — either by law enforcement or governments — to look for other types of material. While CSAM detection is only going to be in the US to start, Apple has suggested it could  eventually expand to other countries and work with other organizations. It’s not difficult to imagine scenarios where Apple could be pressured to start looking for other types of content that’s illegal in some countries. The company’s concessions in China — where Apple reportedly <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-chinese-government-control-data-131343119.html">“ceded control”</a> of its data centers to the Chinese government — are cited as proof that the company isn’t immune to the demands of less-democratic governments.</p><p>There are other questions too. Like whether it&#39;s possible for someone to abuse this process by maliciously getting CSAM onto someone’s device in order to trigger them losing access to their iCloud account. Or whether there could be a false positive, or some other scenario that results in someone being incorrectly flagged by the company’s algorithms.</p><h2><strong>What does Apple say about this?</strong></h2><p>Apple has strongly denied that it’s degrading privacy or walking back its previous commitments. The company published a second document in which it <a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/pdf/Expanded_Protections_for_Children_Frequently_Asked_Questions.pdf">tries to address</a> many of these claims.</p><p>On the issue of false positives, Apple has repeatedly emphasized that it is only comparing users’ photos against a collection of known child exploitation material, so images of, say, your own children won’t trigger a report. Additionally, Apple has said that the odds of a false positive is around one in a trillion when you factor in the fact that a certain number of images must be detected in order to even trigger a review. Crucially, though, Apple is basically saying we just have to take their word on that. As Facebook’s former security chief Alex Stamos and security researcher Matthew Green wrote in a joint <em>New York Times </em>op-ed, Apple hasn’t provided outside researchers with much visibility into how all this <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/11/opinion/apple-iphones-privacy.html">actually works</a>.</p><p>Apple <a href="http://apple.com/child-safety/pdf/Expanded_Protections_for_Children_Frequently_Asked_Questions.pdf">further</a> says that its manual review, which relies on human reviewers, would be able to detect if CSAM was on a device as the result of some kind of malicious attack.</p><p>When it comes to pressure from governments or law enforcement agencies, the company has basically said that it would refuse to cooperate with such requests. “We have faced demands to build and deploy government-mandated changes that degrade the privacy of users before, and have steadfastly refused those demands,” it writes. “We will continue to refuse them in the future. Let us be clear, this technology is limited to detecting CSAM stored in iCloud and we will not accede to any government’s request to expand it.” Although, once again, we kind of just have to take Apple at its word here.</p><h2><strong>If it’s so controversial, why is Apple doing it?</strong></h2><p>The short answer is because the company thinks this is finding the right balance between increasing child safety and protecting privacy. CSAM is illegal and, in the US, companies are obligated to report it when they find it. As a result, CSAM detection features have been baked into popular services for years. But unlike other companies, Apple hasn’t checked for CSAM in users’ photos, largely due to its stance on privacy. Unsurprisingly, this has been a major source of frustration for child safety organizations and law enforcement.</p><p>To put this in perspective, in 2019 Facebook reported 65 million instances of CSAM on its platform, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/07/us/online-child-sexual-abuse.html">according to </a><em>The New York Times</em>. Google reported 3.5 million photos and videos, while Twitter and Snap reported “more than 100,000,” Apple, on the other hand, reported 3,000 photos.</p><p>That’s not because child predators don’t use Apple services, but because Apple hasn’t been nearly as aggressive as some other platforms in looking for this material, and its privacy features have made it difficult to do so. What’s changed now is that Apple says it’s come up with a technical means of detecting collections of known CSAM in iCloud Photos libraries that still respects users’ privacy. Obviously, there’s a lot of disagreement over the details and whether any kind of detection system can truly be “private.” But Apple has calculated that the tradeoff is worth it. “If you’re storing a collection of CSAM material, yes, this is bad for you,” Apple’s head of privacy <a href="http://nytimes.com/2021/08/05/technology/apple-iphones-privacy.html">told</a><em>The New York Times</em>. “But for the rest of you, this is no different.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-child-safety-csam-detection-explainer-183029927.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1d1e05c6-27fe-4bf5-9e29-0ec9d5605925</guid><dc:creator>Karissa Bell</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 18:30:29 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628801122</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T20:45:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Karissa Bell]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/90989ad0-6145-11eb-b7ad-1bcea169fe04" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/90989ad0-6145-11eb-b7ad-1bcea169fe04" width="6000" height="4000" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Shubhashish5 via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tokyo, Japan - May 23, 2020 : Apple iPhone during iOS update. New Apple watch & iPhone OS releases are widely followed every year]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone during iOS update]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Spelunky’ and ‘Spelunky 2’ hit Nintendo Switch on August 26th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We learned all the way back in December that the terrific <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/spelunky"><em><ins>Spelunky</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spelunky-2-trailer-playstation-4-release-date-september-111514275.html"><em><ins>Spelunky 2</ins></em></a> were coming to Nintendo Switch <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spelunky-2-roguelike-nintendo-switch-summer-2021-release-date-175133657.html">sometime this summer</a>, and the wait&#39;s almost over — at least in a few regions. The two games will hit the eShop in North America, Europe and Australia on August 26th, adding another pair of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-indie-world-august-2021-showcase-192608269.html"><ins>indie gems</ins></a> to the Switch library.</p><div id="06bc7c31fa504b0ba40d4cc6aed5bbb4"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🔥👀<br>The light of your torch illuminates the glint of a gold idol... <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Spelunky?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Spelunky</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Spelunky2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Spelunky2</a> are both coming to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitch?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NintendoSwitch</a> on August 26, in North America, Europe, and Australia! Other regions will be announced soon! <a href="https://t.co/fClL27JfHO">pic.twitter.com/fClL27JfHO</a></p>— Spelunky World (@spelunkyworld) <a href="https://twitter.com/spelunkyworld/status/1425838755114405894?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p><em>Spelunky </em>supports local multiplayer, and <em>Spelunky 2</em> adds online play to the mix. Although there are distinct areas in both platformers — each with their own enemies, lethal traps and rules — the levels are procedurally generated, so things are always going to be a bit different on each run.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>It&#39;s hardly the first time <em>Spelunky,</em> a stone-cold classic,<em>&nbsp;</em>has landed on a handheld console. It was released <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-03-25-spelunky-dares-to-explore-ps3-and-vita-this-summer.html"><ins>on PS Vita</ins></a> (and PlayStation 3) all the way back in 2013, a year after the remake of the 2008 original <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-07-04-spelunky-review.html"><ins>debuted on PC and Xbox 360</ins></a>. The sequel, however, has only been available on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spelunky-2-trailer-playstation-4-release-date-september-111514275.html">PC, PlayStation 4</a> and PS5 until now.</p><p>If you&#39;d like to plunder the caverns on Switch, you&#39;ll be able to pick up <em>Spelunky</em> for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/spelunky-switch/"><ins>$10</ins></a>. <em>Spelunky 2</em> will cost <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/spelunky-2-switch/"><ins>$20</ins></a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/spelunky-2-nintendo-switch-release-date-181832059.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">1a8354a8-3fc7-483b-bd74-5bb92b022bb9</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 18:18:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1628792328</ingested><modified>2021-08-12T18:19:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5f1dc780-fb98-11eb-b7f7-1c8f03f92f29" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/5f1dc780-fb98-11eb-b7f7-1c8f03f92f29" width="1280" height="720" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mossmouth]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Spelunky 2]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Spelunky 2]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>