<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ss="http://contenthub.aol.com/slideshow/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/</link><description><![CDATA[Engadget is a web magazine with obsessive daily coverage of everything new in gadgets and consumer electronics]]></description><language>en-US</language><copyright>copyright Oath 2022</copyright><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 14:34:42 +0000</pubDate><generator>Oath http://oath.com</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Tech that can help you stick to your New Year’s resolutions]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Regardless of how 2021 went for you, 2022 is another chance for all of us to make the new year better than those that came before it. We set New Year’s resolutions with the best of intentions, but it’s no wonder that so many people fail after just a few weeks – old habits die hard. Just as it’s important to have a supportive group of people cheering you on during those particularly hard days, it’s also important to have tools that make it easier to achieve your goals. Whether you’re trying to get healthy, be more organized, or read more, there are tech tools that can make your journey a bit easier (and maybe even more enjoyable).</p><h2>Fitness tracker</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/4b7789e2-e632-11ea-bbd5-a22cf771a412" alt="Fitbit Inspire 2 fitness tracker" data-uuid="2fe7e163-029a-4d63-a0da-e1f0b2b6228f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Fitbit</div></figure><p>A fitness tracker can help kickstart your exercise journey by passively monitoring your wins and showing you daily data about your steps, sleep patterns and more. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Fitbit&#x002019;s Inspire 2" href="https://amzn.to/2ZZZnj7">Fitbit’s Inspire 2</a> is an all-around good option, not only because it’s fairly affordable at $100, but because it does pretty much everything a beginner would need a fitness tracker to do. It tracks daily steps, calories, heart rate, sleep and more, and it comes with 20 goal-based exercises that you can manually track or let the device’s automatic SmartTrack feature monitor for you. It also has 10-day battery life, so you rarely have to take it off to charge it. And with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fitbit-inspire-2-tile-tracking-130028749.html">built-in Tile functionality</a>, you’ll be able to more easily find the device if you do misplace it.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2>Smartwatch</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/7343f520-5db5-11ec-9776-245470b1b273" alt="Apple Watch SE" data-uuid="d45b3dbe-2e62-3f7b-b9a5-0959da9d9799"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cherlynn Low / Engadget</div></figure><p>If you’d rather invest in an all-purpose wearable that also has serious fitness chops, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple Watch SE" href="https://amzn.to/3rGRN8f">Apple Watch SE</a> is a good choice. While it doesn’t include some of the bells and whistles that the Series 7 does, it still fferes the same core experience as any Apple Watch. It tracks all-day activity and heart rate, and watchOS finally does basic sleep tracking, too. In addition to  built-in GPS for outdoor workouts, it supports dozens of trackable exercises along with fall detection and high and low heart rate notifications. The Apple Watch also excels over basic fitness trackers when it comes to table-stakes smartwatch features: You’ll be able to send and receive text messages from the device, as well as control music playback, smart home devices and more.</p><h2>Workout classes</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/987db3b0-3b1c-11eb-9f1f-b34b932f444c" alt="Smiling sportswoman crouching, taking a break, and using phone after running in nature."><figcaption>millann via Getty Images </figcaption></figure><p>If running isn’t your thing, or it’s just inconvenient to do it where you live, finding exercise classes that you enjoy can make working out a habit you’re more likely to stick with for the long haul. You may prefer to do this through your local gym — that push to get out of the house and into a dedicated exercise space can be really effective for some — but there are plenty of online fitness classes as well that you can participate in from the comfort of your living room. I’ve tried my fair share of these services and my favorite has been <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Peloton" href="https://fave.co/3dJCK5T">Peloton</a>. No, you don’t need one of the company’s expensive bikes or treadmills to take advantage of their classes. Access to the app-only version of the subscription costs $13 per month and it lets you take HIIT, strength, yoga and even outdoor running classes, many of which require little to no equipment at all.</p><p>If you can’t afford another monthly subscription fee, the internet has tons of free exercise resources — you just have to work a little harder to find the ones you jive with most. I highly recommend <a href="https://www.fitnessblender.com/">Fitness Blender</a>, a free website where you can watch hundreds of workout videos and even set a schedule for yourself, assigning videos to specific days of the week. I like the quality and consistency of their videos, but you may connect more to YouTube workout videos if they’re taught by instructors you like; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Heatherrobertsoncom">Heather Robertson</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/MoveWithNicole/featured">Move with Nicole</a> are two personal favorites.</p><h2>Habit tracker</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/3d55ffc0-5db6-11ec-bfff-d84ee8a510a0" alt="Forest app" data-uuid="27d43642-aca4-3372-b494-4cd893d1f26a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Forest</div></figure><p>At least in the beginning, keeping track of new habits you’re trying to build can help you stick to them. While you can get deep into this subject if you wander down the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=habit+tracker+bullet+journal">bullet-journal rabbit hole</a>, a habit-tracking app is probably the easier option. <a href="https://thedoneapp.com/">Done</a> and <a href="https://www.stridesapp.com/">Strides</a> are two iOS options that let you log when you’ve completed a new habit you’re trying to build or when you avoided a bad habit that you’re trying to break. You can get pretty granular, customizing how often you want to do a task, setting reminders to log, reviewing stats and more. However, both apps have paid tiers to which you’ll be asked to subscribe after you create a few trackable habits.</p><p>If you’d rather avoid yet another subscription, consider an app like <a href="https://streaksapp.com/">Streaks</a>, which can be all yours for a one-time fee of $5. As for Android, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pl.przybylski.grow">Grow</a> is a free app that takes a similar approach to habit tracking that <a href="https://www.forestapp.cc/">Forest</a> takes with time management. Plant a virtual tree for each new habit tracked and watch it grow every time you log a completion. There’s also <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.habitrpg.android.habitica">Habitica</a>, which turns habit tracking to an 8-bit RPG game in which your custom avatar levels up every time you log a task.</p><h2>To-do and note-taking apps</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/05d98240-3bcc-11eb-bdfd-f127d1f859d6" alt="Things 3"><figcaption>Things 3 </figcaption></figure><p>The new year provides an opportunity to get back on track, and one way to do that is by finding organizational tools that work for you — and making sure those tools are as uncomplicated as possible. The worst thing that could happen is that your to-do list or note-taking system ends up being so cumbersome that you avoid using it. Keeping all of your necessary tasks in your head may work on easy days, but it can quickly get overwhelming when you have a million things to handle in both your personal and professional life. I’m a fan of <a href="https://culturedcode.com/things/">Things</a> for iOS and macOS because it’s detailed enough for big work projects, but simple enough for casual personal tasks. I also love the Today view, which shows me everything across all of my projects that requires immediate attention.</p><p>However, you’ll spend $80 to get Things for iOS, iPadOS and macOS — and it’s only available for Apple devices. <a href="https://todo.microsoft.com/tasks/">Microsoft’s To Do</a> is an alternative that, while less involved than Things 3, is free and works on almost every platform including iOS, Android and Windows, among others. You can keep it simple and just have a task list and a grocery list, or you can go deeper and add due dates, sub-tasks and even share lists with family members. And if you don’t want to bother with an extraneous app, you can always opt for the reminders app that (most likely) came preinstalled on your phone. That would be Reminders for iOS users and Google Keep for Android users.</p><p>Google Keep also doubles as a note-taking app, which will be a better solution if you’ve been constantly jotting down ideas for new projects on Post-It notes or scraps of paper that you eventually lose. Apple Notes is the default option for this on iOS devices, and there are plenty of other note-taking apps out there as well. I’m partial to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Evernote" href="https://fave.co/3Im7GHg">Evernote</a> simply because it’s become my digital file box of sorts. I take notes in it almost every day, but tons of things like online order receipts, messages from my doctor’s office and e-signed contracts all come to me through my email and eventually get saved and tagged in Evernote so I can easily find them in the future.</p><h2>Password manager</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-04/7350afb0-888f-11ea-96fd-f8175b1f8740" alt="1Password password manager app."><figcaption>1Password </figcaption></figure><p>If you’re looking to up your organization game in the new year, a password manager is a great place to start. I’m partial to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:1Password" href="https://fave.co/3s6dIT2">1Password</a>, but there are plenty of other options including <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:viglink;pdid:LastPass" href="https://bit.ly/3kyFcjb">LastPass</a> (which has a free version), <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Bitwarden" href="https://fave.co/3ptqJH7">Bitwarden</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Dashlane" href="https://fave.co/3sgDOCJ">Dashlane</a>. After saving all of your passwords for various accounts, you only need to remember one (hence the name) to log in to your 1Password account and access all of the others. The service has browser extensions Chrome, Edge and others that will let you seamlessly log in with the proper credentials with just a few clicks, and 1Password has apps for most platforms including iOS and Android, so you can use it on all of your devices.</p><p>I also appreciate the Password Generator feature, which helps you create a new, secure password whenever one of yours has expired. LassPass has this too, and Dashlane even has a <a href="https://fave.co/3IO1Bnc">free tool</a> that anyone can use to make more secure passwords. Not only does this take the onus of coming up with a strong key off your shoulders, but it also makes it easy to override old credentials with new ones.</p><h2>Travel tech organizer</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/611e27c0-5db6-11ec-bfaf-551ae16b37ed" alt="Bellroy Desk Pouch" data-uuid="4da36da5-6d02-3300-9711-8c88ca1b8606"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Bellroy</div></figure><p>One of the consequences of the past two is the dual-office life. Many of us now work both from home and from an office, and the last thing you want to do when you arrive in either place is rummage around your backpack only to realize that you’ve left your mouse, charging cable or dongle at your other desk.</p><p>An organizer bag can prevent this before it happens – we’re partial to <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:BagSmart tech organizers" href="https://amzn.to/3dpAfpa">BagSmart tech organizers</a> thanks to their utilitarian, water-repellent designs and their multiple pockets and dividers. They also come in <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:different sizes" href="https://amzn.to/31uWlUl">different sizes</a>, so you can pick the best one for your commuter bag. If you want something a bit more elevated, <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Bellroy&#x002019;s Desk Pouch" href="https://fave.co/3lESRWz">Bellroy’s Desk Pouch</a> is a good option. It’s pricier but for the money you get a more elegant design, with a higher-quality material (recycled nylon, weave or ripstop, depending on the color you choose) and a structured base that keeps the bag upright on your desk.</p><h2>Computer docking station</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/83b007d0-d654-11ea-aeff-c1042953df04" alt="CalDigit TS3 Plus Thunderbolt 3 dock" data-uuid="3732d3bf-0818-4f6f-9163-cff993f5255c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">CalDigit</div></figure><p>It’s all too easy for your work-from-home setup to get really messy <em>really</em> quickly. When you’re going through your busiest times at work, the last thing you’re thinking about is cable management, but dedicating a bit more effort into tidying up your workspace can make your day to day more efficient and more enjoyable.</p><p>We recommend some sort of docking station to keep your laptop, monitors, accessories and the like in check. A couple good options are <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:CalDigit&#x002019;s TS3 Plus" href="https://amzn.to/3DuMR91">CalDigit’s TS3 Plus</a> and <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Plugable&#x002019;s Universal Docking Station" href="https://amzn.to/3IrqnJs">Plugable’s Universal Docking Station</a>. The former has a compact, rectangular design with a total of 16 different ports on it, including a Gigabit Ethernet jack, five USB-A connections, two Thunderbolt 3 sockets and analog audio in/out ports. The latter stands up vertically on your desk and has 13 connectors, including HDMI and DVI ports, six USB-A connections and a Gigabit Ethernet jack. That DVI port may be a deciding factor for you depending on which monitor you have, and Plugable’s device comes with both DVI to HDMI and DVI to VGA adapters.</p><p>While both of those options are stationary, there are plenty of adapters out there that can give you similar organization while on the go, albeit in a less elegant package. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Anker&#x002019;s USB-C hub" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Upgraded-Delivery-Pixelbook-A83460A2/dp/B07ZVKTP53?&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=buyersguide2021-20&amp;linkId=bbe8214279ab7872711167166f4664c0&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Anker’s USB-C hub</a> is an affordable solution that includes an HDMI port, microSD and SD card readers, two USB-C connections and two USB-A ports. It also supports 100W power pass-through, so you can charge your laptop through the hub while using it.</p><h2>Instant Pot</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-08/2bb9e500-e950-11ea-bf53-c4412630af8a" alt="Instant Pot Smart WiFi"><figcaption>Instant Pot / Best Buy </figcaption></figure><p>Eating healthier — or even just avoiding takeout multiple times a week — can be challenging in part because it usually means cooking more at home. Not only is that hard to do when you’re starting from zero, but it’s especially tough because it takes more time than ordering in from your phone. But tools like an Instant Pot can make the process easier because it cuts your active cooking time down drastically. You can find a plethora of recipes in which you simply <a href="https://eatinginstantly.com/instant-pot-dump-dinners/">throw a bunch of ingredients into the pot</a>, set it and forget it until it’s time to eat.</p><p>We recommend the Instant Pot Duo for beginners because it’s relatively affordable and combines seven different cooking methods into one appliance, including rice cooking, steaming, pressure cooking, slow cooking and more. If you’re primarily cooking for yourself and a partner, the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:three-quart model" href="https://amzn.to/3rEDt01">three-quart model</a> will serve you just fine, but we recommend the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:six-quart model" href="https://amzn.to/3IoIH6d">six-quart model</a> if you’re routinely cooking for four or more. If the thought of cooking at home actually excites you rather than fills you with anxiety, consider the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Instant Pot Ultra" href="https://amzn.to/3xZfjhV">Instant Pot Ultra</a>, which includes a few extra modes like cake maker and egg cooker, or the <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Instant Pot Duo Crisp" href="https://amzn.to/3DsynGD">Instant Pot Duo Crisp</a>, which includes an air-fry lid.</p><h2>Recipe organization</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/274320d0-3bcc-11eb-bef7-73478c5c5a89" alt="A woman prepares a healthy meal in her kitchen, using a scale to portion the ingredients."><figcaption>RichLegg via Getty Images </figcaption></figure><p>One of the best things about cooking at home is finding recipes that you love so much that you want to make over and over again. You’ll want to keep those recipes safe and readily available so you can refer to them when you need a quick weeknight meal or a dish to bring to your next family reunion. <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Recipe cards" href="https://amzn.to/3dlwot8">Recipe cards</a> are a great way to do this, and you’ll build up your rolodex of delicious meals over time. If you’d rather have a cookbook of sorts that you fill in yourself over time, opt for a <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:recipe book" href="https://amzn.to/3GdlJwS">recipe book</a> instead.</p><p>If you’d rather keep your arsenal of recipes accessible at any time, anywhere from your phone, <a href="https://www.paprikaapp.com/">Paprika’s recipe management app</a> is the best solution I’ve tried. The $5 app basically acts as your digital recipe box, allowing you to enter recipes of your own as well as download them from the internet. You know those hundreds of words that precede online recipes, in which the author divulges their entire life story before telling you their secret to making deliciously moist cornbread? Paprika strips all of those unnecessary bits out and only saves the ingredient list and the instructions. You can also make grocery lists and keep track of pantry staples in the app, so don’t be surprised if it quickly becomes one of your most-used kitchen tools.</p><h2>Reading app</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b7d91110-5db6-11ec-bef5-ab966a0e7fcb" alt="Scribd" data-uuid="7fcef73a-f2b8-3505-9ba3-b18a425b1f55"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Scribd</div></figure><p>Don’t take your habit of doom-scrolling on Twitter for hours every day into the new year. You could instead use the internet to find other things to read and the free <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Libby app" href="https://fave.co/3Gg6enW">Libby app</a> is a good place to start. Powered by Overdrive, it connects you with your local library’s digital collection, allowing you to borrow and download all kinds of e-books, audiobooks, magazines, graphic novels and more. Libby also has a tag system that you can use to “save” titles for later without actually putting a hold on them (although you can do that in the app, too). If you find a bunch of audiobooks you eventually want to get to, you can give them all a “TBR” tag so you can quickly find them and borrow one when you need new reading/listening material.</p><p>As someone who uses Libby on a regular basis, I love how easy it is to borrow from my local library without leaving my home. However, there have been numerous times in which my library doesn’t have a title I’m looking for. If that happens to you often, you may want to consider a subscription service like <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Kindle Unlimited" href="https://amzn.to/3357xrD">Kindle Unlimited</a> or <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Scribd" href="https://fave.co/3dpVDdH">Scribd</a>, both of which give you unlimited access to a wide library of e-books for $10 per month. And for audiobook lovers, your options are Amazon’s <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Audible" href="https://amzn.to/3y21M9G">Audible</a> or <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:skimlinks;pdid:Libro.fm" href="https://fave.co/3BDeg8m">Libro.fm</a>, the latter of which lets you choose the local bookstore you want to support with your purchases.</p><h2>E-reader</h2><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/629b3dd0-35d5-11ec-9ffb-68a8f5cf7272" alt="Amazon&#39;s latest Kindle Paperwhite e-reader, which was released at the end of October 2021." data-uuid="5d6b88d4-7629-3d21-847b-584e9b44c1fa"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Nathan Ingraham / Engadget</div></figure><p>E-readers are still around because so many people recognize how much better it can be to read e-books on a dedicated device — especially one with an e-paper display. Sure, you could read on your smartphone or a tablet, but staring at those screens all day long can be tiring for your eyes. An e-reader like <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Amazon&#x002019;s Kindle Paperwhite" href="https://amzn.to/3y74Xgg">Amazon’s Kindle Paperwhite</a> or <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:;elmt:amazon;pdid:Kobo&#x002019;s Clara HD" href="https://fave.co/2ZXcVM8">Kobo’s Clara HD</a> is a better choice not only for its more comfortable display, but also because it focuses your attention on reading. (If you’ve ever picked up your smartphone intending to finish a chapter only to be distracted by email or Twitter, you know how crucial this is.)</p><p>The new Kindle Paperwhite has a 6.8-inch display with adjustable warm lights, 20 percent faster page turns and weeks of battery life. The Clara HD is similar, with a 6-inch E-Ink display, adjustable brightness and color temperature, along with weeks of battery life. If you already get most of your e-books through Amazon, the Paperwhite is the best option. You can listen to Audible audiobooks, too, if you connect a pair of wireless earbuds to the e-reader. Kobo’s device primarily gets books via the Kobo Store, but it also supports various file types like EPUB, PDF and MOBI. Plus, it has on-device integration with Overdrive, allowing you to borrow library books directly from the e-reader.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tech-to-help-you-stick-to-new-years-resolutions-150034002.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">d268cac0-7edc-3db7-9652-0f5053b214ba</guid><dc:creator>Valentina Palladino</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 14:34:42 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1641047694</ingested><modified>2022-01-01T14:35:10+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[news]]></category><category><![CDATA[Organization]]></category><category><![CDATA[AppleWatch]]></category><category><![CDATA[thebuyersguide]]></category><category><![CDATA[skillshare]]></category><category><![CDATA[Audible]]></category><category><![CDATA[commerce]]></category><category><![CDATA[todoapp]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fitbit]]></category><category><![CDATA[instantpot]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masterclass]]></category><category><![CDATA[habittracker]]></category><category><![CDATA[paprika]]></category><category><![CDATA[NewYear]]></category><category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category><category><![CDATA[newyear'sresolution]]></category><category><![CDATA[Passwordmanager]]></category><category><![CDATA[kindle]]></category><category><![CDATA[gear]]></category><category><![CDATA[Small Businesses]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Valentina Palladino]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/d7db5700-3e1a-11eb-b2f8-45107f303171" width="7562" height="5044" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/d7db5700-3e1a-11eb-b2f8-45107f303171" width="7562" height="5044" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[luza studios via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A red yoga mat on white hardwood floor in a domestic living room at home. Ready to be used in some home exercises.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Yoga mat, Water and Wireless Headphones on the floor]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hyundai built an air purifier out of recycled Ioniq 5 EV parts]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every car is the result of a long development process in which automakers build many pre-production vehicles that never see the light of day. Rather than scrapping one of its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyundai-ioniq-first-drive-180018819.html">Ioniq 5</a> test vehicles entirely, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/hyundai/">Hyundai</a> repurposed the car&#39;s parts to make an air purifier.</p><p>According to a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DguHjRqBTtc">YouTube video description</a>, the model &quot;went through numerous tests to ensure our safety.&quot; The video notes that, over the course of a year, the vehicle was used to test the likes of the Acoustic Vehicle Alerting System, pass-by noise regulation and wind tunnel noise.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="3c16f92ea3ed4e2987a2256ce36d3839"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DguHjRqBTtc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>The video shows Hyundai engineers stripping the Ioniq 5 to its bones, then designing a completely different product using the components. Among other parts, they used the cooling fan, door panels, LED tail lamp, infotainment unit and, of course, the filter unit. The engineers put a 20-inch alloy wheel on the top of the case (so the purifier is probably pretty large), while the car&#39;s emblem adds some professional branding.</p><p>Although many car parts are already recyclable, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ford-ev-battery-recycling-redwood-materials-investment-141338076.html">including batteries</a>, this is a neat experiment. It suggests there are other sustainable ways to repurpose a car that&#39;s otherwise outlived its usefulness. Meanwhile, Hyundai started deliveries of the Ioniq 5 in the US <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hyundais-ioniq-5-ev-crossover-will-start-at-39700-when-it-arrives-231519210.html">this month</a>.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/hyundai-ioniq-5-ev-air-purifier-013047535.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b43c6a71-3559-4250-8dc2-c4182a3f4150</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640983029</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T20:37:11+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Automotive Industry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/cbd45fa0-5ce2-11ec-bddf-5074a75ac1c5" width="2273" height="1410" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/cbd45fa0-5ce2-11ec-bddf-5074a75ac1c5" width="2273" height="1410" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Hyundai Ioniq 5 in blue sits parked in front of a modern building plaza.]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Hyundai Ioniq 5]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netflix will be required to stream 20 state TV channels in Russia]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting in March, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/netflix/">Netflix</a> will have to stream 20 state television channels in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/russia/">Russia</a>. Roskomnadzor, the country&#39;s media watchdog, registered the platform as an &quot;audiovisual service&quot; this week. Among the channels Netflix will have to carry are the flagship Channel One, entertainment network NTV and a Russian Orthodox Church channel called Spas (which means &quot;Saved&quot;).</p><p>Streaming services with more than 100,000 daily users in Russia are included on the register, which was established late last year. Not only must registered platforms offer state TV channels, they need to set up a Russian company, according to <a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2021/12/29/russia-to-require-netflix-to-stream-state-television-broadcasts-a75949"><em>The Moscow Times</em></a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Companies on the register also have to abide by Russian laws. For one thing, Netflix will not be allowed to promote &quot;extremism.&quot; Critics claim that provision has been wielded against those who support the Kremlin&#39;s opponents.</p><p>Other video services in the country reportedly argued that Netflix should be added to the register to level the playing field, since it meets the requirements. The Russian version of Netflix is <a href="https://tass.com/economy/1382009">operated</a> by Entertainment Online Service, a subsidiary of National Media Group, which has a stake in Channel One.</p><p>Engadget has contacted Netflix for comment.</p><p>In November, it emerged Russia was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/russia-netflix-lgbt-content-investigation-035020849.html">investigating a complaint</a> over LGBTQIA+ content on Netflix. The company told Engadget such content was rated appropriately. That same month, Russia <a href="https://www.engadget.com/russia-tells-tech-companies-to-set-up-in-country-211922268.html">ordered</a> several tech giants (including Apple, Google, Meta, TikTok and Twitter) to set up offices within its borders by the end of this year.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/netflix-russia-state-tv-channels-streaming-223008823.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a2f1f015-e108-4bc4-af7d-5612b69d5905</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:00:08 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640983008</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T20:36:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/13476990-3173-11ec-af4f-56e641bd9a60" width="4000" height="2665" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/13476990-3173-11ec-af4f-56e641bd9a60" width="4000" height="2665" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ROBYN BECK via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Netflix logo is seen on the Netflix, Inc. building on Sunset Boulevard in Los Angeles, California on October 19, 2021. - Netflix reported billion-dollar profits and booming subscriber growth on October 19 that beat forecasts as global hits like Squid Game drew viewers in droves. (Photo by Robyn Beck / AFP) (Photo by ROBYN BECK/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-NETFLIX-INTERNET-TELEVISION-EARNINGS]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The tech industry's accessibility report card for 2021]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In spite of all the advancements we’ve seen in tech, the industry as a whole has consistently neglected people with disabilities. There have been some <a href="https://www.engadget.com/accessibility-in-tech-2020-150002855.html"><ins>improvements</ins></a>, including video call apps like FaceTime, Zoom, Microsoft Teams, Google Hangouts and more adding better support for sign language interpreters and closed captioning. And, this year, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-stories-captions-172051963.html"><ins>Instagram</ins></a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-automatic-captions-120049862.html"><ins>TikTok</ins></a> finally added stickers that enable automated captioning for speech in videos, too. But major organizations continued to make decisions that exclude people with disabilities. The organizer of E3 2021, for example, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/e3-2021-closed-captions-fail-224552954.html"><ins>failed its deaf and hard of hearing viewers</ins></a> during its live streamed show.</p><p>There are too many individual transgressions and improvements to exhaustively detail here. Due to their sheer size, though, tech’s largest companies wield the greatest influence over what the rest of the industry does. By holding them accountable, we have a better chance of seeing widespread change in the way tech thinks about inclusive design. Here’s how Apple, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, Meta (formerly Facebook) and more did to improve the accessibility of their products and services in 2021.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><section data-eng-breakout="ab74f97dc0eb48a197650d6d686b274b" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/25c681c0-1cfe-11ec-b1ed-aff3c2fd2c38" alt="A blue iPhone 13 Pro Max and a starlight gold iPhone 13 Pro standing with their backs facing the camera." data-uuid="3352817d-2823-392b-b212-88cc85993a7c"></section><h3>Apple</h3><p>Apple has led the way in inclusive design for years, and in 2021 the company continued to launch new features that made its products easier for those with disabilities to use. In addition to updating its screen reader, VoiceOver, to enable better descriptions of images for the visually impaired, Apple also launched several new products. In May, it rolled out a service called <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apples-sign-time-brings-up-a-sign-language-translator-on-demand-172828126.html"><ins>SignTime</ins></a>, which allowed customers to engage sign language interpreters on demand when communicating with customer service representatives (via their browsers at least). The feature is available in the US, UK and France and supports American, British or French sign languages in their respective countries.</p><p>Apple also introduced Assistive Touch for the Watch this year, allowing for touch-free interaction with its wearable. The idea is that users can clench their fists or pinch their fingers together to navigate the smartwatch. In practice, Assistive Touch took some learning, and it still may not be feasible for those who don’t have the dexterity or strength to clench their fists to trigger the “double clench” action. But it’s a start, and one that few other smartwatches offer.</p><p>For those with very limited range of motion, this year also saw the launch of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/td-pilot-ipad-eye-tracking-tobii-dynavox-140046055.html"><ins>first medically certified eye-controlled iPad</ins></a> by Tobii Dynavox. Called the TD Pilot, it’s a case for iPads as large as the 12.9-inch Pro model and comes with Tobii’s powerful eye-tracking sensor, large speakers, additional batteries and a wheelchair mount. Together with iPadOS 15, this will allow those with cerebral palsy, for example, to interact not only with the tablet, but also communicate with others more easily. A window on the other side of the case can display words to show what the user is saying.</p><div id="7e189c57ff32487ab958f95214c55a35"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nfZ0ntD4grQ?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Apple also added improvements for hearing aid users with iPhones this year, allowing for bi-directional communication. This means that those who connect compatible hearing aids to their iPhones no longer have to use their handset’s mic to be heard by their callers — the hearing aid can pick up the speaker’s voice, too. So far, Starkey and ReSound have released compatible “made for iPhone” devices.</p><p>On macOS, Apple also made it possible to customize the outline and fill color of the cursor so those with visual impairments can more easily tell when the mouse moves or changes shape. The company also expanded its keyboard shortcuts to allow users to control everything on a Mac with a keyboard (no need for a mouse or trackpad).</p><p>Finally, Apple added tools for developers using SwiftUI to make their apps more accessible. With this simplified workflow, there are now fewer obstacles in the way when trying to make more inclusive products.</p><p>Unfortunately, when Apple released iOS 15, it removed some features from Siri that were “used by many individuals for accessibility purposes,” according to Clark Rachfal. He’s the director of advocacy and governmental affairs for the American Council of the Blind. Rachfal told Engadget that users “could no longer access their calling history, voicemails, emails and messages through Siri” when the OS was updated. The council and its members alerted Apple of these issues, he said, adding that the company said it’s working on “restoring this functionality to Siri.”</p><section data-eng-breakout="551648cb41774f2694b0bac6a997def5" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/267f31c0-3518-11ec-b77a-eaedc4ec3ccf" alt="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro." data-uuid="40874fff-6e5e-39d8-ac75-cb8c8e620fa2"></section><h3>Google</h3><p>Google continued to add tools for people with disabilities <a href="https://www.google.com/accessibility/"><ins>across its broad portfolio of products and services</ins></a> in 2021. One highlight was the launch of Project Relate, an Android app that would generate custom voice recognition models for people with severe speech impairments. Then, the app can transcribe, display and read out what the user said. Project Relate is currently in beta, with Google inviting those with atypical speech to sign up as testers.</p><p>The company did plenty to improve its existing products, too. In <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/all-new-talkback/"><ins>February</ins></a>, it revamped its Talkback screen reader to offer new gestures and voice commands. In March, it <a href="https://blog.google/products/chrome/live-caption-chrome/"><ins>announced </ins></a>that the Chrome browser could transcribe audio from the web for users who are deaf or hard of hearing. That transcription would be performed on-device, meaning you could get your captions without worrying about connecting to the cloud.</p><p>Later in the year, Google also added 10 languages to its auto-generated image descriptions tool, brought <a href="https://blog.google/products/chromebooks/accessibility-features/"><ins>more natural-sounding voices</ins></a> to the “Select to speak” feature in Chromebooks and made it easier to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/android-accessibility-camera-switch-project-activate-160013117.html"><ins>interact with Android devices using facial expressions</ins></a>.</p><div id="7a15c7850ab947789a9028c371cf1174"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CSLv-dhVKxs?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>In addition to improving its existing products, Google also explored accessible experiences that could produce learnings for the industry at large. It teamed up with the Royal National Institute of Blind People (RNIB) and <em>The Guardian</em> on <a href="https://auditorial.withgoogle.com/?utm_source=gblog"><ins>Auditorial</ins></a>, which it describes as an experiment in storytelling that “adapts to suit the reader.” It’s a fully customizable experience that Google said will “offer those with visual disabilities an experience that is as comfortable, rich and creative as any other reader.”</p><p>According to the company, Auditorial “is intended to pose a question about how much more accessible the world’s information could be, if you could simply tailor every website to suit your personal sensory needs and preferences.” The hope is that this triggers a discussion on how the web could become more inclusive instead of “a one-size-fits-all approach.” Google published its findings in an “Auditorial Accessibility Notebook,” in order to help other publishers learn tips on how to “open up online storytelling to millions of blind and low vision users.”</p><p>Google also launched a browser-based game this year called SignTown, which uses your camera to teach you sign language and assess your progress. The game is just “one component of a broader effort to push the boundaries of technology for sign language and Deaf culture.” The company said it’s also exploring building “a more comprehensive dictionary across more sign and written languages, as well as collaborating with the Google Search team on surfacing these results to improve search quality for sign languages.”</p><section data-eng-breakout="83b5237498e34cadad6478132da4a55f" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/5f8be630-6a73-11ec-be4b-53b887109c97" alt="Microsoft Surface Adaptive Kit packaging and label." data-uuid="f9061fea-7bdc-3a27-b565-090e61db8024"></section><p></p><h3>Microsoft</h3><p>In 2021, Microsoft surprised us by releasing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html"><ins>Windows 11</ins></a>, which it <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2021/10/04/making-windows-11-the-most-inclusively-designed-version-of-windows-yet/"><ins>called</ins></a> the “most inclusively designed version of Windows yet.” The new OS brings nicer-looking dark and high contrast themes, plus updated sounds that are more soothing and can be heard by more users. The company also renamed its “Ease of Access” section to “Accessibility” to make assistive tools easier to find. Windows Voice Typing also makes it easier to dictate your messages.</p><p>Prior to launching Windows 11, though, Microsoft <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2021/04/28/doubling-down-on-accessibility-microsofts-next-steps-to-expand-accessibility-in-technology-the-workforce-and-workplace/"><ins>announced</ins></a> a five-year commitment to “help bridge the ‘Disability Divide’.” It focuses on hiring and educating people with disabilities, as well as building more accessible products. That includes using AI in Word to detect and convert heading styles for blind and low-vision readers, a <a href="https://insider.office.com/en-us/blog/see-the-big-picture-with-navigation-pane-for-excel"><ins>new navigation pane in Excel</ins></a> for screen readers and expanding Immersive Reader to better convey what’s on PowerPoint slides and notes. It added a new accessibility checker that works in the background and prompts users to fix issues across Microsoft Office <a href="https://insider.office.com/en-us/blog/accessibility-ribbon-in-powerpoint-accessibility-made-easier"><ins>apps</ins></a> and <a href="https://insider.office.com/en-us/blog/sending-accessible-emails-in-outlook-for-windows"><ins>Outlook</ins></a>.</p><p>The company not only expanded live captioning and transcription capabilities in Teams, but  also rolled out support for CART (Communication Access Realtime Translation) captions, as well as the ability to pin and spotlight multiple presenters. Auto-captioning is also available for LinkedIn Live broadcasts.</p><div id="3e43cf4d41584652a6a762ed7d5eabba"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yb63YJe_Vyg?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>To make its hardware easier to use, the company launched a new Surface Adaptive Kit <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-surface-adaptive-kit-accessibility-160002034.html"><ins>in September</ins></a>. The bundle includes tags, labels, keycaps and more to make PC parts and important buttons more identifiable. Like Apple, Microsoft also added sign language support (specifically ASL) to its Stores to assist deaf shoppers. Unlike Apple, however, Microsoft doesn’t appear to offer this for after-sales support yet.</p><p>Microsoft is one of few companies in tech that’s transparent about its efforts to improve training and hiring processes for people with disabilities. It made investments via its Urban Airband initiative “to provide affordable broadband, hardware and software to people with disabilities starting in Los Angeles and New York.” Following a pilot at the University of Illinois, Microsoft said it’s expanding to additional tertiary education institutes to “increase graduation rates of students with disabilities in STEM education.” It’s also working to “create best-in-class Universal Design Learning (UDL) environments in STEM education.”</p><p>To connect people with disabilities to employers, Microsoft announced that it’s adding new accessibility resources and features to LinkedIn, including a LinkedIn Learning course focusing on “accessibility in the modern workplace.” There were also LinkedIn Coaches events specifically aiming to help job seekers with disabilities find employment opportunities. The company also partnered with <a href="https://www.bemyeyes.com/"><ins>Be My Eyes</ins></a>, an app that connects blind and low vision users with sighted volunteers, to make LinkedIn staff available for visual assistance on video calls.</p><p>Microsoft also launched an <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ai/ai-for-accessibility"><ins>AI for Accessibility</ins></a><a href="https://sway.office.com/eifyflyGQXin1GIt"><ins>Low-Cost Assistive Technology Fund</ins></a> to make assistive technology reachable to those who can’t afford it. Considering how expensive assistive technology currently is, this is a promising step towards getting people the gear they need. Though it’s still limited in its reach, the Fund is at least an acknowledgement of the high price that people with disabilities continue to have to pay to be part of the world able-bodied people take for granted.</p><section data-eng-breakout="098ad44f646a4ccb84ab35ea5e19cdab" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/041728e0-6a74-11ec-b3e9-ea8c5711f13d" alt="UNSPECIFIED - SEPTEMBER 28: In this screengrab, Amazon Astro is introduced during Amazon Devices and Services Announcement on September 28, 2021. (Photo by Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images)" data-uuid="e7e29622-0f28-3527-9ae5-49971587c167"></section><h3>Amazon</h3><p>Amazon’s accessibility efforts aren’t just aimed at people with disabilities. The company says it pays attention to aging individuals and helping them feel more confident living independently. This year, it introduced two programs as part of its Alexa Smart Properties service that enable administrators to offer voice-assisted experiences in places like senior living facilities and hospitals. The company also launched <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alexa-together-service-171909617.html"><ins>Alexa Together</ins></a> to keep caregivers and elderly individuals connected via an Alexa-enabled device. It would offer features like fall detection and remote assist to give loved ones peace of mind.</p><p>Amazon also updated the Alexa app to offer light and dark modes, as well as text scaling. It rolled out a new option to give people more time to finish speaking before Alexa gives a response, which it said is designed to help people with certain speech impediments. The company also included cards with braille text in the boxes for the Echo Frames 2nd gen, guiding users to a website with screen-reader-friendly setup instructions. On the Kindle app for iOS, Amazon launched a dictionary audio feature to read out individual selected words and help those with learning disabilities or foreign language speakers better understand pronunciations.</p><p>This year, the company introduced a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-astro-robot-165934602.html"><ins>new home robot called Astro</ins></a> that follows you around your home and provides easy access to helpful info via its display. It works with Alexa Together to help caregivers look out for loved ones remotely and keeps an eye on your home while you’re away. The robot features similar accessibility features to the Echo Show smart displays and has been trained “to work for customers who use wheelchairs, walkers or canes.” It will also play specialized driving sounds to stop it becoming a tripping hazard.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/2fbf9cc0-6a74-11ec-93ae-39611dfa5635" style="height:1024;width:1920;" alt="A Cognixion headset on a white mannequin head." data-uuid="15f3d53e-d3b2-3035-9b58-6a3ded5089c5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Cognixion</div></figure><p>Amazon also invests in several accessibility-minded projects through its Alexa Fund, including Labrador Systems, which makes home robots to help people with limited mobility live more independently. The company has also worked with neural interface startup Cognixion to <a href="https://www.cognixion.com/blog/2021/11/16/cognixion-raises-12-million-to-advance-assisted-reality-tech-for-millions-affected-by-communication-disabilities"><ins>add Alexa support to its brain-computer interface headsets</ins></a> for easier smart home device control. Amazon and Voiceitt also released <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/il/news-releases/voiceitt-launches-state-of-the-art-speech-recognition-app-to-empower-communication-for-individuals-with-speech-impairments-301307887.html"><ins>a new speech recognition app</ins></a> this year to help users with atypical speech converse with Alexa and other people.</p><p>Though its Alexa-focused products have received many updates to improve accessibility, Amazon’s Prime content appears to have been neglected. According to Rachfal, though Prime TV offers audio descriptions on a large amount of content, many titles use text to speech with synthetic voices. Rachfal added that these “lack the quality of human narrated audio description and the overall quality of the content suffers, making it less enjoyable for blind and low vision consumers.”</p><p>To Rachfal, this is an example of something that’s done for people with disabilities “without input, feedback and collaboration with the disability community.”</p><section data-eng-breakout="4cc7b27f5e1248919413ba82a7600844" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6bfafb50-3b47-11ec-8bed-bf2e27c6e69c" alt="A sign of Meta, the new name for the company formerly known as Facebook, is seen at its headquarters in Menlo Park, California, U.S. October 28, 2021. REUTERS/Carlos Barria" data-uuid="e0c978e6-2b7b-32a5-993b-e4b993b6ec9d"></section><h3>Meta / Facebook</h3><p>Amid all the drama surrounding Facebook, its whistleblower and its rebrand this year, it’s easy to overlook the company’s accessibility-related updates. At the start of 2021, the company updated its Automatic Alt Text (AAT) system to recognize over 1,200 objects and concepts in photos on Instagram and Facebook. According to Meta, this represented a 10x increase since AAT’s debut in 2016. It also rolled out additional features to Facebook on iOS that provided more detailed descriptions like positions of objects in a picture and their relative sizes.</p><p>Unfortunately, as it pushed out these updates, Facebook may have broken some accessibility features along the way. Rachfal said that when the company turned off its facial recognition system this year, it led to less-informative descriptions for users who are blind or have low-vision. Rachfal said this change “was done due to privacy concerns,” and he believes these decisions were made without considering accessibility and the disability community. “Nor were they given the same weight and consideration as privacy concerns,” Rachfal added.</p><p>Facebook <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/11/update-on-use-of-face-recognition/"><ins>published a post addressing this issue</ins></a> in November. In it, the company’s vice president of artificial intelligence Jerome Pesenti wrote, “We need to weigh the positive use cases for facial recognition against growing societal concerns, especially as regulators have yet to provide clear rules.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ba2ee9b0-6a74-11ec-b3f6-aa7d829fbf7c" style="height:1080;width:1920;" alt="A banner showing an example of Automatic Alternative Text on Instagram, with a green box around a picture and words saying " data-uuid="c983f3a2-c769-304d-805b-3512ad452dc6"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Meta</div></figure><p>In the post, Pesenti acknowledges the critical role face recognition plays in AAT to help blind and low-vision users identify their friends in pictures. But while some facial recognition tools, like identity verification, will remain, for the most part features like alerting users to photos potentially including them or automatically labeling their friends are going away. That’s for both sighted and visually impaired users.</p><p>“We know the approach we’ve chosen involves some difficult tradeoffs,” Pesenti wrote, adding that “we will continue engaging in that conversation and working with the civil society groups and regulators who are leading this discussion.”</p><p>Elsewhere in Meta’s family of products, the company added an Accessibility tab to the Oculus Settings menu to make assistive features easier to find. It also brought Color Correction and Raise View tools to offer more legible palettes and enable a standing perspective for seated users respectively. Meta said it’s still iterating on Raise View, working with the Oculus community to improve the feature and will permanently add it to the Accessibility menu when ready.</p><p>Meta also collaborated with ZP Better Together, a company that makes technology for deaf and hard-of-hearing users, to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/meta-portal-video-relay-services-for-deaf-153223465.html"><ins>bring sign language interpreters into video calls</ins></a> on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-new-portals-go-170004952.html"><ins>Portal devices</ins></a>. As of December, people who are deaf or hard-of-hearing can also apply on ZP’s website to get free Portals which will come with the ZP apps.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/fe6427d0-6a74-11ec-9575-0d4c265cd3bb" style="height:3319;width:5900;" alt="New models of Facebook&#39;s Portal video-calling devices are pictured in this undated handout image obtained by Reuters. Facebook/Handout via REUTERS   ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE HAS BEEN SUPPLIED BY A THIRD PARTY. MANDATORY CREDIT" data-uuid="0e5f3747-8e1b-387f-8a0b-fb8fb4623fb5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Handout . / reuters</div></figure><p>Facebook <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-audio-content-hub-live-audio-rooms-podcasts-170633543.html"><ins>launched Clubhouse-like audio rooms in the US</ins></a> this year and, notably, did so with live captioning included from the start. It also included a visual cue to indicate who’s speaking, and offers captions for other audio products like <a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators/molly-burke-facebook-video"><ins>Soundbites</ins></a> and Podcasts on iOS and Android.</p><p>Let’s not forget the company’s renaming to Meta this year and its new focus on the metaverse. According to head of accessibility Mike Shebanek, “we&#39;re already working to bring the metaverse to life and are excited to explore the breakthrough possibilities it presents to make the digital world even more accessible and inclusive for people with disabilities.”</p><p>We’ll have to wait and see if and how that comes true, but in the meantime, Meta must continue to engage with the accessibility community to make sure that its expansion of the metaverse is inclusive from the start.</p><p></p><h3>Twitter</h3><p>Twitter only set up its two accessibility teams last year, after an embarrassing launch of Voice Tweets that excluded its deaf and hard of hearing users due to a lack of captions. Since then, though, the company has shown noteworthy improvement. In 2021, Twitter introduced captions for voice tweets, added captions and accessibility labels in Spaces and brought automatic video captions. That last one is “available globally in most languages,” according to the company and supported on Android, iOS and the web.</p><div id="27fd0f5bf03a4da4b42e4115c848e378"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A couple months ago we rolled out video caption file upload. Starting today, all videos will be auto-captioned. <br><br>To see them, turn on captioning in your mobile device settings, or select the CC button on Web. <br><br>What do you think of the experience? <a href="https://t.co/fywdjC6yDI">https://t.co/fywdjC6yDI</a></p>— Twitter Accessibility (@TwitterA11y) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterA11y/status/1470870652215345165?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 14, 2021</a></blockquote></div><p>Though this may seem like a small set of updates compared to the rest of the companies in this roundup, Twitter also has a smaller portfolio of products. Still, it has managed to make significant changes. Rachfal praised Twitter as being “the first social media platform to conspicuously prompt users to include alt text with images,” though he did note that filling out the field is still optional.</p><h3>Other noteworthy developments in tech this year</h3><p>Alt text and captioning continue to be tricky accessibility features for the industry. They’re labor-intensive processes that companies tend to delegate to AI, which can result in garbled, inaccurate results. This was especially evident at this year’s virtual E3 gaming convention, where <a href="https://www.engadget.com/e3-2021-closed-captions-fail-224552954.html"><ins>illegible closed captions</ins></a> sometimes made the show incomprehensible for those who relied on subtitles to understand the announcements.</p><p>There are also large parts of the online world that are in dire need of accessibility-related upgrades. According to a February 2021 study by <a href="https://webaim.org/projects/million/"><ins>WebAIM (Web Accessibility In Mind)</ins></a>, for example, a whopping 97.4 percent of websites had mistakes that failed the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (<a href="https://webaim.org/standards/wcag/checklist"><ins>WCAG 2</ins></a>). The most common errors included missing alt text, low contrast text, missing form input labels and more.</p><p>It’s not just websites that need work: Other media formats also need to be more inclusively designed. The National Association of the Deaf (NAD), for example, <a href="https://www.nad.org/2021/12/14/lawsuit-challenges-inaccessibility-of-major-podcast-platforms/"><ins>filed a lawsuit</ins></a> with Disability Rights Advocates (DRA) this year against three major podcast providers: SiriusXM, Stitcher and Pandora.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b6b3d740-6a75-11ec-bdab-9abd5ec27cea" style="height:329;width:675;" alt="A banner showing three Spotify screenshots with an example of a transcript on the left." data-uuid="e92a301f-586a-3acd-95d7-7828509055c9"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Spotify</div></figure><p>According to the NAD, because the three defendants “do not make transcripts or captions available for any of the podcasts offered on their platforms, more than 48 million deaf and hard of hearing Americans are denied full and equal enjoyment of the content they offer their hearing users.” Meanwhile, Spotify <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-automatically-transcribe-podcasts-accessbility-mobile-165029865.html"><ins>announced this year</ins></a> that it will start offering automatically generated transcripts for podcasts, and Amazon Music <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-music-synchronized-podcast-transcripts-160548838.html"><ins>launched synchronized transcripts</ins></a> in November.</p><p>Then there are entire industries that could use accessibility improvements. Rachfal notes that healthcare is a continually problematic area for people who are blind or have visual impairments. “This is still an entire sector that we hear about far too often from our members,” he said. Given that we are currently in the mires of the third wave of COVID-19, it’s inexcusable to continue excluding people with disabilities when it comes to things like scheduling vaccination or testing appointments.</p><p>In November this year, the Justice Department <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-secures-agreement-rite-aid-corporation-make-its-online-covid-19-vaccine"><ins>announced</ins></a> it had reached a settlement with Rite Aid to make COVID-19 testing and vaccination websites accessible. Rite Aid’s vaccine registration portal was not compatible with some screen readers and was not accessible to “those who have a hard time using a mouse.” The calendar on its website, for example, “did not show screen reader users any available appointment times,” while people relying on keyboard-based navigation instead of a mouse could not use the tab key to complete a consent form required to schedule an appointment.</p><p>The ACB also worked with CVS to offer accessible prescription information in all locations in the country. This includes a <a href="https://cvshealth.com/news-and-insights/press-releases/spoken-rx-talking-prescription-labels-now-available-in-all-cvs">Spoken RX feature</a> that would read out prescription labels via the CVS Pharmacy app.</p><p>Though there have been many transgressions in the past year, we also saw many promising developments in ensuring technology is inclusive. The FCC, for example, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fcc-emergency-alert-system-deaf-accessibility-171239252.html"><ins>proposed rules in December</ins></a> to make emergency alerts more useful and informative for people who are deaf or hard of hearing.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/1f746650-6a76-11ec-b0d6-667e2c7cb6fa" style="height:1816;width:3360;" alt="A TV monitor showing the new Emergency Alert System(EAS) test is seen on November 9, 2011 in Washington, DC. The FCC and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, FEMA, conducted the first-ever nationwide test of the national Emergency Alert System. EAS participants broadcast alerts and warnings regarding severe weather alerts, child abductions and other types of emergencies. The EAS alerts are transmitted over radio and television broadcast stations, cable television and other media services.   AFP PHOTO / KAREN BLEIER (Photo credit should read KAREN BLEIER/AFP via Getty Images)" data-uuid="cc55f6c8-b715-39eb-9c4a-cacf9cc0d3ef"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">KAREN BLEIER via Getty Images</div></figure><p>Meanwhile, HBO Max launched 1,500 hours of audio-described content starting in March 2021 and committed to including the descriptions to all newly produced original content as well as adding more to its back catalog. Also, in collaboration with the Coalition for Inclusive Fitness, Planet Fitness <a href="https://www.acb.org/planet-fitness"><ins>said</ins></a> it will buy and install accessible exercise equipment in its stores across the country.</p><p>I’ve only scratched the surface in this roundup of updates. What’s most encouraging, though, is the increasing willingness of companies to work with disability rights groups and advocates at the earliest stages of product design. Lizzie Sorkin, director of engagement for the NAD, said it’s “seeing more and more companies reach out to us in the beginning phases for input rather than late in the process.” Rachfal also noted a “growing commitment to accessible media and content” that’s “born out of the advocacy work of ACB and the Audio description Project through collaborative discussions with industry.”</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/accessibility-in-tech-2021-report-card-apple-google-microsoft-amazon-facebook-meta-twitter-210034415.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b559da73-3d56-4866-9713-525fe97b54a5</guid><dc:creator>Cherlynn Low</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 21:00:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640983397</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T20:43:25+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Physical Disabilities]]></category><category><![CDATA[Social & Online Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Cherlynn Low]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a24ccc70-6a76-11ec-9bff-cffdaad37b87" width="4364" height="2933" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a24ccc70-6a76-11ec-9bff-cffdaad37b87" width="4364" height="2933" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Brian Lawless - PA Images via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[IrelandÕs first socially assistive AI robot 'Stevie II' from robotics engineers at Trinity College Dublin, with Brendan Crean, who helped trial the robot through the charity ALONE, during a special demonstration at the Science Gallery in Dublin. (Photo by Brian Lawless/PA Images via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Irelands first socially assistive AI robot 'Stevie II' unveiled]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[CES 2022 will end one day early amid COVID-19 surge]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lenovo-wont-attend-ces-2022-172655236.html">several</a> companies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-cancels-ces-2022-in-person-plans-221822468.html">cancelled on-site plans entirely</a> for CES next week, the organization that runs the show announced today that the event will close one day early. The Consumer Technology Association (CTA) said CES 2022 will now run January 5th-7th &quot;as an additional safety measure to the current health protocols that have been put in place.&quot; January 3rd and 4th are media-only days when press conferences and keynotes take place.&nbsp;</p><p>Protocols include masks and proof of vaccination to attend in-person events. The CTA also recently announced that it would provide Abbott BinaxNOW COVID-19 tests at badge pickup. The association has asked attendees to complete a rapid test 24 hours before entering a CES venue. If someone experiences symptoms while in a CES venue, the CTA has advised them to report to a first aid station for testing. The organization says it will also provide PCR tests for any attendees who are required to have one by their destination prior to departure from Las Vegas.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In the last week, high-profile exhibitors like Amazon, Google, Intel, Lenovo, Meta and more have cancelled in-person plans for CES 2022. As part of today&#39;s announcement, the CTA explained that over 2,200 companies will still show off their goods on the ground in Vegas, noting that it has added 143 more in the last two weeks.&nbsp;</p><p>CTA CEO Gary Shapiro <a href="https://www.reviewjournal.com/opinion/commentary-ces-will-and-must-go-on-in-las-vegas-2502202/">has defended the decision</a> to keep the show an in-person event as the omicron variant causes COVID-19 case numbers to surge in several parts of the world. “As the world’s most influential technology event, CES is steadfast in its pledge to be the gathering place to showcase products and discuss ideas that will ultimately make our lives better,” said Shapiro. “We are shortening the show to three days and have put in place comprehensive health measures for the safety of all attendees and participants.” Shapiro has pointed to the smaller companies that rely on the event as a potential springboard for products as a key reason for not cancelling the event. CES 2021 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ces-2021-what-to-expect-210017996.html">was entirely virtual</a>.</p><p>&quot;We will all be taking risks,&quot; he said <a href="https://www.reviewjournal.com/opinion/commentary-ces-will-and-must-go-on-in-las-vegas-2502202/">in a recent op-ed</a> for the <em>Las Vegas Review-Journal.</em> &quot;But without risk there is no innovation.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/ces-2022-closing-early-203017318.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">069a3f88-7c72-4603-a77e-1a345309a0ff</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 20:30:17 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640981669</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T20:14:33+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2020-01/f5fb94b0-3723-11ea-b99d-62564adef8f5" width="5000" height="3327" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2020-01/f5fb94b0-3723-11ea-b99d-62564adef8f5" width="5000" height="3327" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[ROBYN BECK via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Attendees walk through the Las Vegas Convention Center January 10, 2020 on the final day of the 2020 Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas, Nevada. (Photo by Robyn Beck / AFP) (Photo by ROBYN BECK/AFP via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[US-IT-LIFESTYLE-CES]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Premier League games will stay on Peacock as NBC Sports Network shuts down]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the clock strikes midnight to ring in 2022 on the east coast, NBC Sports Network will shut down. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/NBCUniversal/"><ins>NBCUniversal</ins></a> will <a href="https://sports.nbcsports.com/2021/12/30/how-to-watch-stream-sports-on-usa-network-after-nbcsn-shuts-down-on-january-1st/">shift</a> much of its sports coverage, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/premier%20league/"><ins>Premier League</ins></a> matches, over to the USA Network.</p><p>Assuming more games aren&#39;t suspended due to teams having too many COVID-19 cases, Premier League coverage will get off to a flying start on USA Network with <a href="https://soccer.nbcsports.com/2021/12/31/premier-league-usa-network-details-schedule-tv-info-stream/"><ins>three matches</ins></a> on New Year&#39;s Day. Arsenal will square off against league leaders Manchester City at 7:30AM ET before Watford host Tottenham and Crystal Palace take on West Ham. Sunday brings a match between Everton and Brighton, before Chelsea host Liverpool in a clash between title contenders.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The shift to USA Network shouldn&#39;t change much for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/peacock/">Peacock</a> users, though. Overflow games and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nbc-sports-premier-league-deal-expansion-222712283.html"><ins>streaming-only matches</ins></a> will remain on that platform, including three matches that are scheduled to stream on Peacock Premium on Sunday. Some of the bigger games will still air on the main NBC network, and NBCU will continue to broadcast every Premier League match across its multitude of platforms.</p><p>It&#39;s not clear as yet whether there are plans to broadcast overflow games on other NBCU networks. On the last day of the 2020-21 season, when all 10 matches kicked off at the same time, USA Network, CNBC and the Golf Channel each aired one game.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/nbc-sports-network-premier-league-peacock-usa-network-streaming-193007469.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3fd41bc9-6fe1-45ed-8c65-ef4317f136c4</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 19:30:07 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640972125</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T17:36:22+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category><category><![CDATA[English Premier League]]></category><category><![CDATA[Sports & Recreation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/525720e0-6a5c-11ec-b7de-3f98eced6f82" width="4253" height="2835" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/525720e0-6a5c-11ec-b7de-3f98eced6f82" width="4253" height="2835" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Robin Jones via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LONDON, ENGLAND - DECEMBER 29: Christian Pulisic of Chelsea gives chase to Solly March of Brighton & Hove Albion during the Premier League match between Chelsea  and  Brighton & Hove Albion at Stamford Bridge on December 29, 2021 in London, England. (Photo by Robin Jones/Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Chelsea v Brighton & Hove Albion - Premier League]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[This is a shiatsu hand massager for gamers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of us know at least one person who plays games for hours on end, perhaps tiring their hands out in the process. To help soothe their weary mitts, Japanese company <a href="https://japanese.engadget.com/jp-2018-11-04-5mm.html">Bauhutte</a> has created a hand massager for gamers.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.bauhutte.jp/product/msg01h/">MSG-01H-BK hand massager</a>, which works on either hand, has a 15-layer airbag for each finger and a shiatsu plate for the palm. There are two main options: a Shiatsu mode for the entire hand, and one that focuses on stretching fingers.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/128668a0-6a4c-11ec-affb-4d2915de244d" alt="Bauhutte Hand Massager" data-uuid="22bd8363-104d-3936-9ca7-a62fe054264b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Bauhutte</div></figure><p>There are a few intensity settings, as well as an optional hand warmer that&#39;s said to improve circulation. You&#39;ll need to slide in your hand sideways to massage your thumb. The hand massager automatically shuts off after 10 minutes. Bauhutte suggests using the device before gaming sessions to warm up your hands, when taking breaks and afterward to cool down.</p><p>While some might scoff at a hand massager for gamers, it&#39;s not too ridiculous of an idea. Many esports competitors <a href="https://www.redbull.com/za-en/What%20is%20the%20big%20idea%20eSports%20players%20using%20hand%20warmers">use hand warmers</a> between rounds to absorb moisture, keep their fingers toasty and improve circulation. Some esports organizations <a href="https://beta.ctvnews.ca/national/features/w5-on-the-esports-revolution.html">employ a masseuse</a> to keep players in top condition.</p><p>Other companies have made <a href="https://www.engadget.com/theragun-elite-hands-on-irl-123008214.html">hand massagers</a>, though it makes sense that Bauhutte is marketing its version to gamers. It caught attention last year for its <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/japanese-gaming-bed/">gaming bed</a>, and the company sells a wide range of furniture and accessories with gamers in mind, such as a <a href="https://www.bauhutte.jp/product/msg02f/">portable foot massager</a>.</p><p>Bauhutte&#39;s hand massager is only available in Japan for now and it costs around $150. As <a href="https://kotaku.com/behold-a-japanese-hand-massaging-device-for-gamers-1848285815"><em>Kotaku</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>notes, the company has an English-language site, so it might offer the device elsewhere too.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/bauhutte-hand-massager-gamers-160006506.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">bad894e9-3e99-4b61-9198-2f22c7fbefeb</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640966053</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T15:54:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0f704f00-6a4c-11ec-aeab-741e4387732b" width="800" height="584" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0f704f00-6a4c-11ec-aeab-741e4387732b" width="800" height="584" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Bauhutte]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Bauhutte Hand Massager]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Bauhutte Hand Massager]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[And the biggest losers in tech in 2021 are...]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It feels like forever since we all were able to look back on the last 12 months and <em>not</em> say “good riddance, you garbage fire hellscape of a year.” 2021 kicked off with <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-capitol-riots-cybersecurity-threats-144553438.html">riots at the Capitol</a> and though things seemed to quiet down a little after, all was not well in tech.</p><p>There are companies that are obvious additions to this list, like Meta (formerly Facebook) with its repeated transgressions this year. Activision Blizzard faces multiple lawsuits and investigations over allegations of sexual harassment and gender discrimination in the workplace, revealing that despite all the growth we hoped we’d made in the last few years, the gaming industry remains toxic.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>But there are other businesses that made the lives of workers and consumers miserable on a daily basis, too. And all major companies in Big Tech have to share in the blame. When we put together this roundup of the worst players in tech this year, it’s clear that we’re overdue a reckoning. Let’s hope that in the years to come, the people with the most influence learn how to treat people better.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/6bfafb50-3b47-11ec-8bed-bf2e27c6e69c" alt="A sign of Meta, the new name for the company formerly known as Facebook, is seen at its headquarters in Menlo Park, California, U.S. October 28, 2021. REUTERS/Carlos Barria" data-uuid="e0c978e6-2b7b-32a5-993b-e4b993b6ec9d"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Carlos Barria / reuters</div></figure><h2>Meta / Facebook</h2><p>For the company now known <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-new-name-meta-182151399.html">as Meta,</a> 2021 went sideways from the very beginning.</p><p>For all its talk about safeguarding the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-twitter-2020-election-planning-192024550.html">2020 presidential election</a>, Facebook was ill-prepared for the insurrection that followed on January 6th. The company failed to recognize <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-stop-the-steal-policies-report-205339822.html">the danger</a> posed by the “Stop the Steal” movement until after a violent mob stormed the Capitol. Then COO Sheryl Sandberg <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/11/sandberg-says-us-capitol-riot-was-not-organized-on-facebook.html">downplayed</a> the role Facebook had played in the insurrection, only to be promptly <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/01/13/facebook-role-in-capitol-protest/">proven wrong</a>. In the end, the events of January 6th ultimately forced the platform to do something it had studiously avoided for most of the Trump presidency: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-and-twitter-trump-suspensions-173002449.html">Enforce</a> its rules for his account. (Sort of. Trump’s Facebook ban <a href="https://www.engadget.com/donald-trump-could-be-back-on-facebook-in-time-for-primaries-164200140.html">isn’t permanent</a>.)</p><p>Elsewhere, the arrival of coronavirus vaccines only highlighted Facebook’s poor track record at combating <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-vaccine-misinformation-policies-170012241.html">vaccine misinformation</a>, which surged throughout the pandemic. After years of dragging its feet, the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-bans-vaccine-misinformation-193754704.html">finally banned</a> misleading or inaccurate vaccine content. But enough damage had already been done. The US Surgeon General said viral health misinformation was an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/us-surgeon-general-health-misinformation-advisory-191241209.html">“urgent threat”</a> to public health. President Joe Biden went a step further: saying that Facebook was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/joe-biden-facebook-killing-people-vaccine-misinformation-195433641.html">“killing people.”</a></p><p>This year was also the first time the Oversight Board, created so Facebook could outsource its thorny content moderation decisions, was operational. The body has pushed the social network to change some policies and has repeatedly criticized the company for a lack of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebooks-oversight-board-said-the-company-failed-to-provide-relevant-information-132603146.html">transparency</a> and ability to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-oversight-board-lost-rule-193222133.html">enforce</a> its rules evenly.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/658479d0-6271-11ec-bc1a-aa011d940046" alt="Former Facebook employee and whistleblower Frances Haugen testifies during a Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation hearing entitled &#39;Protecting Kids Online: Testimony from a Facebook Whistleblower&#39; on Capitol Hill, in Washington, U.S., October 5, 2021.   Jabin Botsford/Pool via REUTERS" data-uuid="70f30484-a3cb-353d-9346-694f35eec9a5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">POOL New / reuters</div></figure><p>Then came Frances Haugen, the former employee turned whistleblower who left the company with thousands of pages of internal research and other documents that have since become known as the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-papers-release-120713316.html">“Facebook Papers.”</a> Her disclosures paint a picture of a company that is unwilling or unable to adequately tackle some of its biggest problems, particularly outside the United States and Europe. She also revealed internal research about the effect of Instagram on teens, which was immediately seized on by lawmakers in Congress.</p><p>Amid all that, Zuckerberg announced not an overhaul of the company’s policies, nor a review of its internal research, but… a new name: Meta. It’s meant to symbolize the company’s newfound commitment to a metaverse that no one can <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-metaverse-meta-explained-or-not-120032885.html">fully explain</a>. Will the company change its content moderation policies when it comes to the metaverse? Will it invest more in safety for non-western countries? How will it address hate speech in the metaverse? Facebook, er Meta, has yet to meaningfully address any of those questions. But if recent history is a guide, we all have a lot to worry about.</p><p>— <em>Karissa Bell</em></p><h2>Truth Social</h2><p>You’d be forgiven if, amidst the news of actual importance in 2021, you forgot about TRUTH Social — the upcoming site built by disgraced former president Donald J. Trump. Trump spent most of his presidency fear-mongering and spouting lies on Twitter and other social platforms, which finally resulted in him being banned from Twitter, Facebook, YouTube and most other services of note. While Trump is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-10/twitter-tells-judge-trump-has-free-speech-wrong-in-suit-over-ban?sref=10lNAhZ9">wrongfully convinced</a> that this is an unlawful witch hunt, he’s also decided to say “who needs ‘em?” and launch his own.</p><p>TRUTH <a href="https://www.engadget.com/trump-truth-social-061457538.html">was announced in October</a>, with a limited beta planned for November before a full public launch in 2022. Immediately, dedicated internet pranksters <a href="https://www.engadget.com/trump-social-network-defaced-124507041.html">found a test version of the site</a> in the open and signed up for a slew of high-profile accounts (including, naturally, donaldjtrump and mikepence). (The donaldjtrump account had a profile picture of a defecating pig, for good measure.)</p><p>The test was quickly shut down, but not before it was revealed to be basically a Twitter clone running on the open-source software Mastodon. But since TRUTH Social didn’t properly cite its usage and didn’t share the source code with users, the site <a href="https://www.engadget.com/trump-truth-social-software-license-violation-185629984.html">was in violation</a> of Mastadon’s open-source license agreement.</p><p>TRUTH’S terms of service were also revealed, and we learned that it was essentially hoping to be protected by Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act, which currently states that services like Twitter and even TRUTH aren’t responsible for what their users post. This shields companies from liability for the awful things those users might share.</p><p>We blissfully haven’t heard much about TRUTH Social since its disastrous first few days in the public spotlight; the company missed the November beta launch date and there’s no update on when the promised full launch might happen. Based on these early struggles, it’s easy to call TRUTH Social a loser of 2021 – but the citizens of the internet who didn’t have to deal with the ugly reality of a Trump-backed social network are all undoubtedly winners.</p><p>— <em>Nathan Ingraham</em></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b426c930-6271-11ec-bbff-e855f71c3329" alt="A woman looks at a data chip containing encryption codes for mobile and landline phones at the booth of Secusmart during the CeBIT trade fair in Hanover March 8, 2014. The German company Secusmart is known for supplying German Chancellor Angela Merkel with a secure mobile phone. The world&#39;s biggest computer and software fair will be open to the public from March 10 to 14.  REUTERS/Wolfgang Rattay (GERMANY - Tags: BUSINESS TELECOMS SCIENCE TECHNOLOGY)" data-uuid="bcd2fa42-abbf-3ee5-9af1-aa13d4295c7e"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Wolfgang Rattay / reuters</div></figure><h2>Global chip supply</h2><p>The rise in demand for PCs, gadgets and cars couldn&#39;t keep up with the slowing production in global chip supply. That&#39;s why it&#39;s still tough to find a PlayStation 5 a year after its launch, and why <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/buying-a-car/when-to-buy-a-used-car-a6584238157/">used car prices have gone absolutely bonkers</a>. This is our new reality for the next few years, at least until chip suppliers can ramp up production and start spinning up new fabrication plants. Basically, be prepared to use all of your gear for a bit longer without upgrading.</p><p>— <em>Devindra Hardawar</em></p><h2>Activision Blizzard</h2><p>There are far too many stories of sexual harassment and discrimination in the video game industry. Over the past few years, reports of systemic misogyny and abuse have poured out of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-07-riot-games-walk-out-sexism-lawsuits-arbitration.html">Riot Games</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ubisoft-harassment-lawsuit-france-205931367.html">Ubisoft</a> and many other studios <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-30-gamergate-sexual-abuse-twitter-developers-zoe-quinn.html">large and small</a>, and the problems date back decades.</p><p>Among all this trash, Activision Blizzard stands out as one of the worst.</p><p>Activision Blizzard was accused of fostering <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html">a culture of sexual harassment</a> by California’s fair-employment agency in July, and multiple organizations have since launched investigations into the studio, uncovering years of mismanagement in the process. According to the California lawsuit, leaders at the studio cultivated a frat house-style environment where sexual harassment was commonplace and gender discrimination was systemic. The fair employment agency found that all of Activision Blizzard’s top leadership positions were held by white men, just 20 percent of all employees identified as women and reports of harassment were routinely ignored.</p><p>In December, an employee named Christine <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-sexual-harassment-christine-statement-dec-2021-211910288.html">went public</a> with her experience at Blizzard, saying she was inappropriately touched by male coworkers, propositioned for sex by her superiors and subjected to crude comments about her body. After reporting the abuse to management, she said she was demoted and told to “get over it.”</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d9e9fde0-6271-11ec-af1d-216c54b18660" alt="Irvine, CA - July 28: Several hundred Activision Blizzard employees stage a walkout which they say is in a response from company leadership to a lawsuit highlighting alleged harassment, inequality, and more within the company outside the gate at Activision Blizzard headquarters on Wednesday, July 28, 2021 in Irvine, CA. (Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images)" data-uuid="1e0a8bb3-9990-39ab-9073-0e68a46d53c7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Allen J. Schaben via Getty Images</div></figure><p>Activision Blizzard’s response to these accusations has been tragic. Back in July, CEO Bobby Kotick sent an email to employees dismissing the California lawsuit, but he signed <a href="https://kotaku.com/bobby-kotick-actually-wrote-fran-townsends-deranged-co-1848069983">a female employee’s name to it</a>. The response was roundly and loudly criticized, with employees calling it “insulting” and “abhorrent.” Kotick let Frances Townsend, one of the few women executives at Activision Blizzard, take the heat for that letter for months, losing her spot on the studio’s women’s network in the process. Publicly, Kotick called the email “tone-deaf.”</p><p>Blizzard head J. Allen Brack <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blizzard-leader-j-allen-brack-steps-down-133538233.html">lost his job</a> shortly after the lawsuit was filed, and Kotick offered a co-leadership role to Mike Ybarra and Jennifer Oneal, who became the first woman to hold a president title since the studio’s founding in 1979. Oneal left the company shortly after this promotion, reportedly because she was being <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/blizzard-jen-oneal-mike-ybarra-equal-pay-after-resignation">paid less than Ybarra</a>, and she felt “tokenized, marginalized and discriminated against” at the studio.</p><p>Activision Blizzard employees have walked out multiple times this year, calling for a culture shift. Major business partners, including PlayStation and Xbox, have said they’re reevaluating their relationships with the studio. Shareholders and media outlets alike are calling for Kotick to resign.</p><p>At this point, investors, employees, analysts, major gaming companies and multiple government agencies agree that Activision Blizzard is a hotbed of discrimination and sexual harassment, and it’s in urgent need of restructuring. In his 30 years as CEO of Activision Blizzard, this is the closest Kotick has come to actually being ousted from his position of power.</p><p>From that angle, it almost feels like a good year for the company. Almost.</p><p>— <em>Jessica Conditt</em></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/67989750-6272-11ec-baa7-4bb31ffcfc6c" alt="A large red sign saying " data-uuid="430546b9-2a2f-36d1-8b7a-e67e2247c28f"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Miquel Benitez via Getty Images</div></figure><h2>5G</h2><p>I’m so disappointed with 5G. If, like me, you’ve watched the networking standard since at least 2014, you’ll likely agree. The promises about downloading feature films in seconds were really mostly advantages of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-07-23-how-5g-makes-use-of-millimeter-waves.html">mmWave technology,</a> which as of today still hasn’t broadly rolled out. The sub-6 network that’s more widely available today on carriers like T-Mobile and AT&amp;T offer a barely noticeable speed boost, and the reported latency improvements it was supposed to bring haven’t been delivered in the real world.</p><p>Yes, the telecom industry did meet its target launch date of 2020 for an initial rollout of the new standard. But 5G is still too confusing for the average consumer. Any time a company says in a briefing that a new product is 5G-ready, a guaranteed follow-up question is “Does that mean sub-6 or mmWave?” And with the recent addition of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-29-fcc-5g-auction.html">mid-band spectrum</a> to the mix, the layers of compatibility are only going to make things more tedious.</p><p>I’ve been more than forgiving in the last couple of years, but it’s been difficult to ignore the complete mess that is the state of 5G in the US today. Sure, we’ve had more pressing issues to deal with, but if consumers are going to embrace the new standards (and be convinced to spend money for the privilege of 5G on their devices), the industry needs to get its act together and either commit to a more coherent message or more consistent rollout.</p><p>— <em>Cherlynn Low</em></p><h2>Workers and big tech&nbsp;</h2><p>For a long time, working at a tech giant like Google or Apple was an enviable position. But 2021 pulled back the curtain a bit on some of these companies, exposing deep-rooted issues with how employees are treated. While not everyone at these massive organizations may be dealing with sexual harassment or poor working conditions (to name just a few issues), the many employees speaking out across the industry are indicative of an underlying trend that need to be confronted by tech’s most powerful leaders.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ab2c1730-6272-11ec-ae7f-0007a092ae61" alt="Amazon&#39;s warehouse facility DSD8 is shown in Poway, California, U.S., September 28, 2021. Picture taken September 28, 2021. REUTERS/Mike Blake" data-uuid="d114270c-3d27-32d7-bd20-6f5b5a93348c"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Mike Blake / reuters</div></figure><p>Amazon’s poor treatment of its warehouse workers <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-200-million-prime-subscribers-165713430.html">is well-known</a>, and reports persisted in 2021. At the same time, the company <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-alabama-union-vote-154741754.html">pushed back hard against unionization efforts in Alabama</a>. While the union drive was defeated in a vote, a regional office of the National Labor Relations Board recently <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/29/business/amazon-bessemer-alabama-election.html">ordered a new election</a>, effectively invalidating the results of the earlier one. The union had filed a formal objection right after the election, and while there’s no word on when a new election will take place, it’s clear that Amazon will be under intense scrutiny when it does. The same should hold if New York City Amazon workers hold a union vote; reports have indicated that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-staten-island-warehouse-unionization-drive-193814629.html">could happen soon</a>.</p><p>Apple workers also exposed issues within the company this year. In late August, a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-workers-201202748.html">call went out</a> for current and former employees to share stories of discrimination, harassment and retaliation that they had experienced. This <a href="https://www.engadget.com/appletoo-starts-publishing-toxic-workplace-stories-051204973.html">led to the start of the #AppleToo</a> website, where these stories are regularly <a href="https://medium.com/appletoo">published</a>.</p><p>As Jess already explained in detail above, employees at Activision Blizzard spoke up about a misogynistic culture rife with sexual harassment, as well. Reports indicated male executives groped female colleagues while other employees joked about rape or ignored women for promotions. The revelations have been so damning a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-discrimination-abuse-video-163056567.html">lawsuit</a> was filed by California’s Department of Fair Employment, though somehow Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick still has his job.</p><p>Google isn’t free from sin, either – employees led a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-01-google-walkout-demands.html">massive walkout</a> back in 2018 around how it dealt with sexual harassment (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-03-google-walkout-for-real-change.html">among other concerns</a>). It hasn’t dealt with things on the same scale as other companies this year, but Google’s recent decision that it wasn’t raising pay to match inflation has certainly rankled workers. These are just a few high-profile examples, but together they paint a dark picture of the environment at some of tech’s biggest corporations. Perhaps the only upside here is that these hopefully put pressure on those in charge to clean house and improve things as quickly as possible.</p><p>— <em>N.I.</em></p><p><strong>Oculus</strong></p><p>Meta didn&#39;t even give Oculus a proper funeral. Instead of a celebratory news announcement, Meta CTO Andrew Bosworth pushed out <a href="https://www.facebook.com/boz/posts/10114026973983491">a quick post</a> to announce that the<a href="https://www.engadget.com/meta-facebook-oculus-retirement-194217530.html"> Oculus brand was being retired</a>. What a sad fate for a company directly tied to the rise of consumer VR. (But perhaps this was the best way for Meta to separate itself from the legacy of<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-03-30-oculus-co-founder-palmer-luckey-is-leaving-facebook.html"> Oculus&#39;s controversial founder Palmer Luckey</a>.)</p><p>— <em>D.H.</em></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/87f60090-6273-11ec-ba8f-526c8eafdd23" alt="A Blue Origin New Shepard rocket lifts off with a crew of six, including Laura Shepard Churchley, the daughter of the first American in space Alan Shepard, for whom the spacecraft is named, from Launch Site One in west Texas, U.S. December 11, 2021. REUTERS/Joe Skipper" data-uuid="caf24b4f-1b68-30fa-b632-e826f5cfdec5"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Joe Skipper / reuters</div></figure><h2>Blue Origin</h2><p>2021 was a massive year for the burgeoning private spacelift industry. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/virgin-galactic-richard-branson-spaceflight-complete-154012847.html">Firsts were made</a>, <a href="http://v/">records were achieved</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-nasa-artemis-lunar-lander-contract-report-184448656.html">billions of dollars worth of government contracts</a> were awarded. It should have been a surefire win for all three of the industry’s leading companies — SpaceX, Virgin Galactic, and Blue Origin — but then one of them managed to repeatedly shoot itself in the proverbial landing strut more than the other two combined.</p><p>Now, that’s not to say Blue Origin didn’t enjoy its share of success this year. CEO Jeff Bezos <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-completes-first-crewed-spaceflight-132937714.html">put his money where his oversized stetson is</a> and made a historic trip out to the Karman line along with both the oldest (at least at that point) and youngest people to ever venture into space. This past November, the company even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-backs-blue-origins-orbital-reef-space-station-220247282.html">won financial backing from NASA</a> to help build out its bonkers <a href="https://www.engadget.com/orbital-reef-200848765.html">Orbital Reef commercial space station</a> design.</p><p>However, those achievements were often overshadowed by the company’s public pettiness and truculence. For example, ahead of Sir Richard Branson’s Virgin Galactic making its own historic first successful flight into space this past July, <a href="https://twitter.com/blueorigin/status/1413521631717122059">Blue Origin took to Twitter to talk a little trash</a>. This is a little rich from the company that has reportedly become <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-toxic-workplace-employee-letter-181051514.html">a toxic workplace</a>.</p><p>More embarrassing still was Bezos’ repeated, and ultimately unsuccessful, attempts to secure Blue Origin a lucrative NASA contract. See, back in April, NASA awarded SpaceX a $2.9 billion (yes, with a B) Artemis lunar lander contract.</p><p>Blue Origin immediately protested to the US Government Accountability Office (GAO) over NASA’s “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-blue-origin-225547469.html">fundamentally unfair</a>” decision against it, bringing work on the lunar program to a standstill <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gao-denies-blue-origin-dynetics-protest-nasa-human-landing-system-181019362.html">until July, when the GAO kindly told Blue Origin</a> to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jeff-bezos-nasa-open-letter-181522642.html">take its $2 billion and get out</a>. Blue Origin did not.</p><p>Instead, the space lift company doubled down, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-federal-claims-court-nasa-challenge-163927526.html">suing NASA</a> in open federal court, &quot;in an attempt to remedy the flaws in the acquisition process found in NASA&#39;s Human Landing System,&quot; per a Blue Origin representative <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-federal-claims-court-nasa-challenge-163927526.html">in August</a>. The court was not at all convinced and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/blue-origin-loses-nasa-lawsuit-over-spacex-151101253.html">ruled against the plaintiffs</a>, proving SpaceX CEO Elon Musk’s jab true. Blue Origin really can’t <a href="https://www.engadget.com/elon-musk-on-blue-origin-lawsuit-151130133.html">sue its way to the Moon</a>.</p><p>— <em>Andrew Tarantola</em></p><h2>Microsoft Edge</h2><p>Microsoft finally managed to make its Edge web browser a solid competitor to Chrome, Safari and Firefox by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-15-microsoft-chromium-edge-launch-window-mac.html">integrating the Chromium open source framework</a>. And then, inexplicably, it began to pile on bloat, like a predatory <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-59492429">&quot;buy now pay later&quot; feature</a> and <a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/microsoft-says-its-own-edge-browser-is-more-trustworthy-than-so-2008-google-chrome/">cringey anti-Chrome warnings</a>. All of a sudden, Edge seems more like a way to trap and commodify its users, instead of delivering a solid web experience. It&#39;s as if Microsoft made it harder to change your default browser in Windows 11 on purpose (thankfully, it&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-is-killing-recent-changes-that-made-it-hard-to-switch-browsers-143041174.html">testing out a simpler method</a>, following plenty of industry criticism).</p><p>— <em>D.H.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/worst-products-and-companies-in-2021-153034006.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">388949f7-2079-40d1-ad2c-a7c5ba615856</guid><dc:creator>Engadget</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 15:30:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640966424</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T16:00:39+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Engadget]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/7c4c4b00-6a52-11ec-af79-c6fd467c6131" width="703" height="469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a1398790-64ab-11ec-bdeb-4f7767c006c7" width="2024" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Year in review losers]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Year in review losers]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast: Quantum Dot OLED and other tech we're expecting at CES 2022]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re back from the holidays and gearing up to (virtually) cover CES 2022. Cherlynn and Devindra chat about some of the most interesting new tech we expect to see, like Quantum Dot OLED displays and new CPUs. And they discuss what the global chip shortage could mean for CES and the rest of 2022. (Prepare to wait a lot longer for all your near gear!)</p><p>Listen below, or subscribe on your podcast app of choice. If you&#39;ve got suggestions or topics you&#39;d like covered on the show, be sure to <a href="mailto:podcast@engadget.com?subject=Engadget%20Podcast%20Feedback"><strong>email us</strong></a> or drop a note in the comments! And be sure to check out our other podcasts, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-08-01-engadget-podcasts.html">Morning After and Engadget News</a>!</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="undefined"><iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1187662972&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe><div style="font-size:10px;color:#cccccc;overflow:hidden;white-space:nowrap;font-family:Interstate, Lucida Grande, Lucida Sans Unicode, Lucida Sans, Garuda, Verdana, Tahoma, sans-serif;font-weight:100;"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast" title="Engadget" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">Engadget</a> · <a href="https://soundcloud.com/engadget-podcast/ces-2022-preview" title="CES 2022 preview: Quantum Dot OLED, new PC gear and more" target="_blank" style="color:#cccccc;text-decoration:none;">CES 2022 preview: Quantum Dot OLED, new PC gear and more</a></div></div><h2><br>Subscribe!</h2><ul><li><p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-engadget-podcast/id1142790530?mt=2">iTunes</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3EC3dMIRB99dkvoSBeSO7G?si=f7UALGKmRDWtOrU8Z4-uiQ">Spotify</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://pca.st/mlY3">Pocket Casts</a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/engadget/the-engadget-podcast">Stitcher</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://podcasts.google.com/?feed=aHR0cDovL2ZlZWRzLnNvdW5kY2xvdWQuY29tL3VzZXJzL3NvdW5kY2xvdWQ6dXNlcnM6MjQ1MjIwOTU4L3NvdW5kcy5yc3M&amp;ep=14">Google Podcasts</a></p></li></ul><h2><br><strong>Topics</strong><br></h2><ul><li><p>Our second pandemic CES is going to be a little weird – 1:41</p></li><li><p>What is Quantum Dot OLED? – 14:23</p></li><li><p>What we expect from new PC CPUs and GPUs – 24:37</p></li><li><p>What will wearables look like at CES? – 28:05</p></li><li><p>Cars and CES – 31:18</p></li><li><p>Pop Culture Picks – 39:07</p></li></ul><p><strong><em>Credits</em></strong><br><em>Hosts: Cherlynn Low, Devindra Hardawar</em><br><em>Producer: Ben Ellman</em><br><em>Music: Dale North and Terrence O&#39;Brien</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/engadget-podcast-ces-2022-quantum-dot-oled-133024275.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">699e7059-84ec-474e-b71d-90be87ea7b42</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 13:30:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640917487</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T02:24:51+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-11/c8e851c0-2b3d-11eb-baea-6c6fe29971fb" width="703" height="469" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-05/f43b53b0-909f-11ea-87fd-d8d721459924" width="1600" height="719" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Engadget Podcast]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: 2021's winners in tech]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy almost new year! We’re wrapping up 2021 with some of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-tech-products-and-companies-2021-143005186.html">big winners</a> of the last twelve months, whether that was NFTs (ugh), the metaverse (double ugh), Apple’s change of direction on device repair or the boom in home workout tech.</p><p>We also mention Samsung’s Galaxy Z Flip 3, which makes the most compelling case for foldables so far. Samsung has <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsunge-galaxy-flip-3-more-people-to-switch-than-flagships-085330086.html https://www.engadget.com/...">noticed the same</a>. It said the Flip 3 motivated more people to switch than its flagships, leading to four times more foldable devices sold in 2021 compared to 2020. The argument for buying your first folding smartphone strengthens year by year.</p><p>-Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/blackberry-os-devices-january-4th-service-shutdown-220421328.html?src=rss https://www.engadget.com/...">BlackBerry OS devices are pretty much dead after January 4th</a></h2><h3>Data, phone calls, and texting will no longer work.</h3><h3></h3><p>BlackBerry has announced that from January 4th, devices running BlackBerry OS 7.1 or earlier, as well as OS 10, will lose key services. And by key, we mean it. It’ll include losing the ability to make phone calls, texting, data and even emergency 911 access. You can also expect to have issues with WiFi and apps like BlackBerry World and Desktop manager.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/blackberry-os-devices-january-4th-service-shutdown-220421328.html?src=rss https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html?src=rss">Yukai Engineering&#39;s cute stuffed animal robot will nibble on your finger</a></h2><h3>The face of robotics I want to see</h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html?src=rss"><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/9e163930-6a2a-11ec-a37f-07fd8cfa89f8" style="height:450;width:675;" alt="TMA" data-uuid="9c36b46f-b56a-38f3-8b45-3b5625760580"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Yukai Engineering</div></figure></a><p>Yukai Engineering, the maker of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/qoobo/"><ins>Qoobo robotic cat tail pillow</ins></a>, has revealed a soft robot that nibbles on a user’s fingertip.  <a href="https://hamham.ux-xu.com/"><ins>Amagami Ham Ham</ins></a> has an algorithm called a “Hamgorithm” that selects one of two dozen nibbling patterns, designed to replicate the feeling of a baby or pet nibbling on one’s finger. Pricing hasn&#39;t been determined, but there are plans to run a crowdfunding campaign in the spring.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html?src=rss"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html https://www.engadget.com/...">Sega left one of its European servers wide open</a></h2><h3>A malicious attacker could have accessed 250,000 users&#39; personal data.</h3><h3></h3><p>According to a report by security firm VPN Overview, a major breach in one of Sega&#39;s servers appears to have been closed. The misconfigured Amazon Web Services S3 bucket contained sensitive information which allowed researchers to arbitrarily upload files to a huge swath of Sega-owned domains, as well credentials to abuse a 250,000-user email list.</p><p>The domains impacted included the official landing pages for major franchises, including Sonic the Hedgehog, Bayonetta and Total War, as well as the Sega.com site itself.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/sega-data-breach-europe-s3-averted-163032473.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-apps-to-download-on-your-new-smartphone-ios-android-180049321.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><br>The best apps to download on your new smartphone</a></h2><h3>A few apps we think every iPhone or Android user should try.</h3><h3></h3><p>Did you just pick up a new phone? Did you stick with iOS and Android or make the transition to the rival? Are you in need of some new productivity apps or time killers? We’ve got you covered.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-apps-to-download-on-your-new-smartphone-ios-android-180049321.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsunge-galaxy-flip-3-more-people-to-switch-than-flagships-085330086.html">Samsung says the Galaxy Flip 3 motivated more people to switch than its flagships</a></h2><h3>The company sold four times more foldable devices in 2021.</h3><h3></h3><p>Samsung says it shipped four times more foldables in 2021 than it did in 2020. Further, it took only one month after they were released for the Galaxy Z Fold 3 and the Galaxy Z Flip 3 to exceed the total accumulative sales of their predecessors last year. The company also said that it saw a &quot;massive increase&quot; in consumers who jumped brands specifically for its foldable phones — in fact, more people switched to Samsung for the Flip 3 than for its flagship Galaxy S devices.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsunge-galaxy-flip-3-more-people-to-switch-than-flagships-085330086.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tomb-raider-reboot-trilogy-free-epic-games-store-180234051.html https://www.engadget.com/...">The &#39;Tomb Raider&#39; reboot trilogy is free on the Epic Games Store</a></h2><h3>You can&#39;t beat that price.</h3><h3></h3><p>Free game promos are easy to find, but Epic is going one step further by offering an entire game trilogy for no charge. The Epic Games Store is offering all three Tomb Raider reboot titles (Tomb Raider, Rise of the Tomb Raider and Shadow of the Tomb Raider) for free between now and January 6th at 11AM.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tomb-raider-reboot-trilogy-free-epic-games-store-180234051.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p><strong></strong></p><p></p><h3></h3><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/jlab-go-air-tones-announced-price-specs-availability-060024516.html"><ins>JLab&#39;s latest $20 earbuds are designed to complement your skin tone</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-model-3-s-camera-trunk-recall-142249417.html"><ins>Tesla recalls nearly half a million cars over camera and trunk defects</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/new-york-city-mustang-mach-e-cars-130943173.html"><ins>New York City orders 184 Mustang Mach-E cars for police and government use</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-2021-ipad-amazon-new-years-sale-152313959.html"><ins>Apple&#39;s 2021 iPad is back to $299 at Amazon</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-hidden-unfinished-cutscene-211419052.html"><ins>Unfinished &#39;Halo Infinite&#39; cutscene hints at a future storyline</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tumblr-ios-tags-restriction-115024668.html"><ins>Tumblr blocks tags for &#39;sensitive content&#39; in order to stay on the App Store</ins></a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/telegram-spoilers-reactions-translation-qr-codes-195406629.html"><ins>Telegram adds iMessage-style reactions and hidden text for spoilers</ins></a></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-2021-s-winners-in-tech-122038974.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b554c5cb-ee50-4300-ba9c-bb75ab3906db</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:20:38 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640954034</ingested><modified>2021-12-31T12:34:07+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a67ba130-6946-11ec-bcfc-5a201b3122f2" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a67ba130-6946-11ec-bcfc-5a201b3122f2" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[David Imel for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[BlackBerry OS devices are pretty much dead after January 4th]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pour one out for the BlackBerry, the former king of mobile. The company has announced that as of January 4th, classic devices running BlackBerry OS 7.1 or earlier, as well as OS 10, will lose key services. And by key, we mean absolutely crucial capabilities, like phone calls, texting, data and even emergency 9-1-1 access. You can also expect to have issues with Wi-Fi and apps like BlackBerry World and Desktop manager, <a href="https://liliputing.com/2021/12/blackberry-os-devices-will-stop-working-on-january-4-2022.html"><em>Liliputing </em>reports</a>. January 4th will also mark the end for the PlayBook, the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2012-10-09-playbook-disappearing-from-us-stores.html">company&#39;s ill-fated tablet</a>.</p><p>Of course, none of this comes as a surprise. BlackBerry <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-12-15-blackberry-app-store-closes-in-2019.html">shut down its app store</a> and its <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-05-31-blackberry-messenger-shuts-down.html">popular Messenger (BBM) service</a> in 2019. There really was no coming back from that. If you&#39;ll recall, the company was way too late to respond to the threat of the iPhone, and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-11-06-blackberry-priv-review.html">failed to find much success by adopting Android</a>. At least it still has QNX, BlackBerry&#39;s modern operating system that powers infotainment systems from Toyota, Audi, Honda, and plenty of other popular car makers.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/blackberry-os-devices-january-4th-service-shutdown-220421328.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">b11c0738-b295-4889-a70d-8defaed1217e</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 22:04:21 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640901213</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T21:53:43+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Telecommunication]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/31a89c90-69ba-11ec-bebd-22ebb6d81f38" width="3500" height="2370" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/31a89c90-69ba-11ec-bebd-22ebb6d81f38" width="3500" height="2370" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Mark Blinch / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[A person uses the new Blackberry Bold 9900 at a release party to promote the BlackBerry OS 7 devices in Toronto August 3, 2011. Research In Motion (RIM) on Wednesday took the wraps off two more powerful versions of its touchscreen BlackBerry Torch, aiming to buy time until it can introduce a radically new software package in its smartphones.   REUTERS/Mark Blinch (CANADA - Tags: SCI TECH BUSINESS)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[RIM/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unfinished 'Halo Infinite' cutscene hints at a future storyline]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Caution: Major </em>&#39;Halo Infinite&#39;<em> story spoilers follow</em>.</p><p>There&#39;s more to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-review-campaign-xbox-microsoft-080158610.html"><em>Halo Infinite</em>&#39;s story</a> than it appears — unofficially, at least. <em>Windows Central</em><a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/secret-halo-infinite-ending-cutscene-discovered">notes</a> fans have <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fyb6FjYhGac">discovered</a> an unfinished mid-credit cutscene hidden in the game&#39;s code. As you can see below, it&#39;s not just a throwaway moment, either. If anything, it&#39;s a strong hint at what might come next in a story add-on or sequel.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><div id="03806e165a134777ab07cebf92ee8b7d"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fyb6FjYhGac?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>The cutscene shows Esparza, the pilot you meet at the start of <em>Halo Infinite</em>, alerting Master Chief to a friendly UNSC tag. While the short segment is mysterious, some have speculated the tag belongs to a character that wasn&#39;t present in the core campaign, such as Commander Palmer or Spartan Locke. You might have a &#39;new&#39; ally when the story picks up.</p><p>It&#39;s not clear why 343 Industries left the cutscene code in the official release, or whether the clip reflects what you&#39;ll see in future content. We&#39;ve asked for more information. Whatever the explanation, it&#39;s rare to see such potentially important material hiding in files a player could uncover.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/halo-infinite-hidden-unfinished-cutscene-211419052.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">507bd15f-6eac-42cd-8ceb-3deab2e12413</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 21:14:19 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640898863</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T21:14:26+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ed5d6670-69ae-11ec-b777-94b02b0d4902" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/ed5d6670-69ae-11ec-b777-94b02b0d4902" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[343 Industries/Xbox Game Studios]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Master Chief in 'Halo Infinite']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Master Chief in 'Halo Infinite']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro update 'paused' to fix dropped calls]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bad news, Pixel fans: <a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/143183382/december-2021-update-paused?hl=en">Google has confirmed</a> it&#39;s pausing the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">Pixel 6 and 6 Pro</a> December update over reports of call dropping and disconnecting. As <a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/12/30/google-confirms-pixel-6-december-update-pause/"><em>Droid Life </em>reports</a>, the news explains why many Pixel 6 owners haven&#39;t received the update over the past few weeks. For the lucky few who managed to snag it and aren&#39;t having any issues, Google says you can sit tight.&nbsp;</p><p>But for those those experiencing connectivity issues, your only fix is to <a href="https://flash.android.com/welcome">flash your phone to an earlier version of Android</a> and perform a factory reset. As always, be sure to backup your device before attempting such a massive undertaking. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/googles-pixel-6-can-now-be-used-to-unlock-bmw-vehicles-180000062.html">December update</a> was meant to add new features like ultra-wideband on the Pixel 6 Pro, and Quick Tap to Snap for easily accessing Snapchat from your lockscreen. Google says those features will make their way to the January fix.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The delay is something of a debacle for the company, especially since the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro were meant to show off the combined power of Google&#39;s custom processor and software. This probably isn&#39;t the best way to prove it could build the Android equivalent of an iPhone.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/google-pauses-pixel-6-pro-december-update-call-dropping-203048469.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">50a6e8da-ea19-4c34-ac0c-552f821a01cd</guid><dc:creator>Devindra Hardawar</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:30:48 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640895137</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T20:12:29+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Devindra Hardawar]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b9139d70-69aa-11ec-bffe-c528d7da2408" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b9139d70-69aa-11ec-bffe-c528d7da2408" width="2100" height="1182" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro update &#39;paused&#39; to fix dropped calls]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Telegram adds iMessage-style reactions and hidden text for spoilers]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/telegram/"><ins>Telegram</ins></a> is squeezing in one last <a href="https://telegram.org/blog/reactions-spoilers-translations">major update</a> before 2021 wraps up. Among the new features is hidden text to mask spoilers. So, if you can&#39;t wait to blab about what happens in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amc-sony-spider-man-no-way-home-nft-190650100.html"><em><ins>Spider-Man: No Way Home</ins></em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>before everyone in the chat has seen it, you can select any section of your text and use the Spoiler formatting. This will hide the text in the chat, notifications and chat list. When your friends are ready to read what you think about [redacted] showing up, they can tap the spoiler text to read it.</p><p>Also new are iMessage-style reactions. You can double tap any message to send a thumbs-up reaction. Tapping once (or tapping and holding on iOS) will let you select other emoji, such as a grin, fire, a shocked face or a thumbs down. You can change the default double-tap emoji in the Chat Settings on Android, and under the Stickers and Emoji section in iOS settings.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In private chats, reactions are always enabled. Channel and group admins can decide whether to switch them on and what reactions the other members can choose from.</p><p>Elsewhere, Telegram now has a useful translation option. Through the Language section in Settings, you can enable translation, which adds a Translate button to the context menu. You can nix languages you&#39;re able to understand and the Translate button won&#39;t be available on messages you receive in those languages. Translation is available on all Android devices, but iPhone and iPad users will need to be running iOS 15 or later. The number of languages Telegram supports depends on your operating system.</p><p>In addition, users can generate QR codes for anyone with a public username, as well as bots, groups and channels. You can tap the QR code icon next to their username and select the colors and pattern before sharing it elsewhere. You can find your own QR code in Settings.</p><p>The Telegram team redesigned the context menus on macOS with new shortcut hints and animated icons. The app will display a full-screen effect in one-on-one chats when you send certain emoji too.</p><p>Earlier this year, Telegram added <a href="https://www.engadget.com/telegram-group-video-calling-now-available-182705546.html"><ins>group video calls</ins></a> and other features, including a way to <a href="https://telegram.org/blog/protected-content-delete-by-date-and-more"><ins>block</ins></a> others in group chats from taking screenshots and saving shared media, as well as <a href="https://telegram.org/blog/live-streams-forwarding-next-channel"><ins>live streams</ins></a> with unlimited viewers. There&#39;s been some blowback against Telegram this year, however, with reports <a href="https://www.engadget.com/telegram-sharp-rise-cybercriminal-activities-072559131.html"><ins>suggesting</ins></a> there has been a significant uptick in the level of cybercriminal activity taking place on the encrypted messaging app.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/telegram-spoilers-reactions-translation-qr-codes-195406629.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">a8595e1e-a5b8-40bd-ad38-67521cb4056d</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 19:54:06 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640894050</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T19:54:14+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Small Businesses]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/c27a79d0-6170-11eb-b7e1-088f49fc3c0e" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-01/c27a79d0-6170-11eb-b7e1-088f49fc3c0e" width="3543" height="2362" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[NurPhoto via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Telegram Messenger logo on the App Store is seen displayed on a phone screen in this illustration photo taken in Poland on January 14, 2021. Signal and Telegram messenger apps gained popularity due to the new WhatsApp's privacy policy. (Photo illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Signal And Telegram Messenger Apps Gained Popularity]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 'Tomb Raider' reboot trilogy is free on the Epic Games Store]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/january-ps-plus-games-persona-5-strikers-dirt-5-deep-rock-galactic-174854063.html">Free game promos</a> are easy to find, but Epic is going one step further by offering an entire game trilogy for no charge. The Epic Games Store is offering all three Tomb Raider reboot titles (<a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/tomb-raider"><em>Tomb Raider</em></a>, <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/rise-of-the-tomb-raider"><em>Rise of the Tomb Raider</em></a> and <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider"><em>Shadow of the Tomb Raider</em></a>) for free between now and January 6th at 11AM. They&#39;re Windows-only if you grab them from the EGS, but they&#39;re also complete versions that include post-launch DLC.</p><p>Your experience with the games may vary. Some will highlight <em>Rise of the Tomb Raider</em> as the star of the series, and aren&#39;t always enthusiastic about <em>Shadow</em>. And expect to do a lot of crafting in between adventures. They&#39;re solid releases as a whole, though, and represented a return to form for a franchise that many felt had lost its way. At the least, they&#39;ll serve as good training tools for <a href="https://www.engadget.com/uncharted-4-lost-legacy-ps5-release-date-172821857.html"><em>Uncharted</em>&#39;s eventual PC launch</a>.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tomb-raider-reboot-trilogy-free-epic-games-store-180234051.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">7a262fc6-f90b-4cd6-9335-7d038a5e3a42</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 18:02:34 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640887357</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T18:02:47+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b0a42b90-6997-11ec-bf76-afc9a7b41578" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/b0a42b90-6997-11ec-bf76-afc9a7b41578" width="1920" height="1280" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Crystal Dynamics/Square Enix]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Lara Croft running from a crashing aircraft in 'Tomb Raider']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Lara Croft running from a crashing aircraft in 'Tomb Raider']]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sega left one of its European servers wide open]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What could have been a damaging breach in one of Sega&#39;s servers appears to have been closed, according to a <a href="https://vpnoverview.com/news/sega-europe-suffers-major-security-breach/">report</a> by security firm VPN Overview. The misconfigured Amazon Web Services S3 bucket contained sensitive information which allowed researchers to arbitrarily upload files to a huge swath of Sega-owned domains, as well credentials to abuse a 250,000-user email list.</p><p>The domains impacted included the official landing pages for major franchises, including Sonic the Hedgehog, Bayonetta and Total War, as well as the Sega.com site itself. VPNO was able to run executable scripts on these sites which, as you can imagine, would have been quite bad if this breach had been discovered by malicious actors instead of researchers.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>An improperly stored Mailchimp API key gave VPNO access to the aforementioned email list. The emails themselves were available in plaintext alongside associated IP addresses, and passwords that the researchers were able to un-hash. According to the report, &quot;a malicious user could have distributed ransomware very effectively using SEGA’s compromised email and cloud services.&quot;</p><p>So far there&#39;s no indication that bad actors made use of this vulnerability before VPNO discovered and helped Sega to fix it. Sega Europe was not available for comment.</p><p>Misconfigured S3 buckets are, unfortunately, an extremely common problem in information security. Similar errors this year have impacted audio company <a href="https://www.vpnmentor.com/blog/report-sennheiser-leak/">Sennheiser</a>, <a href="https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/senior-citizens-personal-data/">Senior Advisor</a>, <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/1000-gb-of-local-government-data-exposed-by-massachusetts-software-company/">PeopleGIS</a>, and the government of <a href="https://www.vpnmentor.com/blog/report-ghana-nss-leak/">Ghana</a>. Sega was the target of a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-sega-hackers/sega-says-1-3-million-users-affected-by-cyber-attack-idUSL3E7HJ01520110619">major attack</a> in 2011 which led to the exfiltration of personally identifiable information pertaining to 1.3 million users. Thankfully, this misconfigured European server didn&#39;t result in a similar incident.</p><p></p><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/sega-data-breach-europe-s3-averted-163032473.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">f7578d81-833d-4cc7-9f73-68d9a8456909</guid><dc:creator>Bryan Menegus</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:30:32 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640881503</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T16:25:13+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Bryan Menegus]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/dd009d40-6983-11ec-9ffe-13d40d86ead8" width="3500" height="2320" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/dd009d40-6983-11ec-9ffe-13d40d86ead8" width="3500" height="2320" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Kim Kyung Hoon / reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Sega Corp. logos are reflected in windows near the company headquarters in Tokyo June 20, 2011. Japanese video game developer Sega Corp said on Sunday that information belonging to 1.3 million customers has been stolen from its database, the latest in a rash of global cyber attacks against video game companies. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon (JAPAN - Tags: CRIME LAW SCI TECH BUSINESS)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[SEGA-HACKERS/]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yukai Engineering's cute stuffed animal robot will nibble on your finger]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It wouldn’t be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ces%202022/"><ins>CES season</ins></a> without at least a couple of offbeat robots showing up. Yukai Engineering, the maker of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/qoobo/"><ins>Qoobo robotic cat tail pillow</ins></a>, has revealed a soft robot that nibbles on a user’s fingertip. The company hopes the &quot;somewhat pleasing sensation&quot; will brighten up your day.</p><p><a href="https://hamham.ux-xu.com/"><ins>Amagami Ham Ham</ins></a> has an algorithm called a “Hamgorithm” that selects one of two dozen nibbling patterns, so you’ll never be sure exactly what you’ll feel when you shove your digit into the robot’s maw. Yukai designed the patterns — which include Tasting Ham, Massaging Ham and Suction Ham — to replicate the feeling of a baby or pet nibbling on one’s finger.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/cdba0260-6981-11ec-9aff-8160bca77886" style="height:281;width:500;" alt="A soft robot called Amagami Ham Ham " data-uuid="aa34e227-1d5b-36f0-8aea-5f2488291e35"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Yukai Corporation</div></figure><p>“Amagami” means “soft biting” and “ham” means “bite” in Japanese. Yukai based the look of the robot on a character from Liv Heart Corporation’s Nemu Nemu stuffed animal series. There’ll be a couple of finger-munching models to choose from: Yuzu (Calico Cat) and Kotaro (Shiba Inu).</p><p>“Most people like the nibbling sensation but know they need to teach their children or pets to stop it, because kids and animals will otherwise bite them with full force eventually,&quot; said Yukai Engineering CMO Tsubasa Tominaga, who invented the robot at a hackathon earlier this year. &quot;Amagami Ham Ham is a robot that frees humankind from the conundrum of whether ‘to pursue or not to pursue’ the forbidden pleasure.”</p><p>Pricing hasn&#39;t been determined, but Yukai and Liv Heart plan to run a crowdfunding campaign in the spring. In the meantime, those braving CES can check out Amagami Ham Ham at the show, and perhaps leave Yukai&#39;s booth with a slightly more tender finger.</p><div id="81a53a0589d9420383acb42177bbb7d6"><div style="left:0;width:100%;height:0;position:relative;padding-bottom:56.25%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_GiQswlhps4?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></div><p>Among the other devices Yukai will show off at CES is Bocco Emo. The company has updated the original <a href="https://japanese.engadget.com/jp-2015-05-12-bocco-kickstarter.html">Bocco robot</a> to act as a smart medical device. Yukai says hospitals in Japan are using it to monitor patients&#39; vitals (via connected sensors like pulse oximeters and thermometers) and notify nurses about a patient&#39;s condition.</p><p>During a pilot period, Bocco Emo was used to inform patients&#39; families about how they&#39;re doing. It can also communicate with patients using sound effects, facial expressions and gestures while they wait for a nurse to arrive.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">471cb456-3a49-4774-9a36-3b91aa5ce332</guid><dc:creator>Kris Holt</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:00:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640878138</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T15:30:21+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Finance - Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hobbies & Personal Activities]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Kris Holt]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/03afca80-6982-11ec-bf04-a7d867334a78" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/03afca80-6982-11ec-bf04-a7d867334a78" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Yukai Corporation]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Two models of Yukai Corporation's Amagami Ham Ham soft robot: Yuzu (Calico Cat) and Kotaro (Shiba Inu)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Amagami Ham Ham]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's 2021 iPad is back to $299 at Amazon]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don&#39;t worry if you didn&#39;t get (or give) the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-9th-generation-review-143045685.html">latest iPad</a> this holiday season — you can still score one at a discount. Amazon is once again selling the 64GB standard iPad <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple iPad" href="https://amzn.to/3pARUku">for $299</a>, or $30 off its usual price. You can also buy the 256GB version at an all-time low price <a data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple iPad" href="https://amzn.to/3ufJ5xm">of $449</a>. You may have to wait a while when the 64GB model isn&#39;t due to ship until mid-February, but it could be worthwhile if you&#39;re not in a rush to grab Apple&#39;s most affordable tablet.</p><a class="athena-button" href="https://amzn.to/3pARUku" id="f127752e0e4749ee8a799faa46ca0bd4" data-i13n="elm:affiliate_link;sellerN:Amazon;elmt:amazon;pdid:Apple iPad">Buy iPad at Amazon - $299</a><p>The 2021 iPad is another modest update to a core design that hasn&#39;t changed for years, but those changes could make all the difference in some cases. The wide-angle front camera is much better-suited to video calls. The A13 Bionic chip is still very fast for this class of tablet, and the 10-plus hours of battery life is more than enough for typical tablet uses. There&#39;s even a headphone jack — imagine that.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>This isn&#39;t the iPad for you if you insist on Apple&#39;s latest technology: you won&#39;t find USB-C, thin bezels or second-gen Pencil support. You&#39;ll want an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-air-2020-review-130044886.html">iPad Air</a> (or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-mini-6th-generation-2021-review-130009170.html">mini</a>, or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ipad-pro-2021-m1-review-liquid-retina-xdr-5g-features-price-130049005.html">Pro</a>) for that. If all you want is a big screen for games, reading and TV marathons, though, this base iPad is an easy choice at a price like this.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://twitter.com/EngadgetDeals"><em>@EngadgetDeals</em></a><em> on Twitter for the latest tech deals and buying advice.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/apple-2021-ipad-amazon-new-years-sale-152313959.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">729a803b-3275-49d4-97dd-3093d9697c14</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:23:13 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640877203</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T15:13:38+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handheld & Connected Devices]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d34a56b0-6974-11ec-bfdd-b5fda3704729" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/d34a56b0-6974-11ec-bfdd-b5fda3704729" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Nathan Ingraham/Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Apple iPad (2021)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Apple iPad (2021)]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here are the winners in tech for 2021]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Though this year is by no means one to celebrate, there were still some bright spots in the world of tech. It’s with plenty of loathing that we admit this: NFTs somehow won this year. They’ve taken over. Reddit’s day traders also deserve recognition for the way they’ve managed to manifest GameStop’s slogan, “Power to the players.”</p><p>Also (and this might be the most painful to acknowledge), the Metaverse (sorta) took off this year. At least in terms of our lexicon, with mentions of the word skyrocketing since Mark Zuckerberg uttered it while <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-q3-2021-earnings-young-adults-metaverse-220703590.html">announcing plan for a richer VR and AR-focused world</a>. Maybe people were confused between “metaverse” and “multiverse” as in <em>Dr. Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</em>?</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Besides the things we love to hate, there are some products this year we genuinely liked as well. Apple continued to impress with its M1 chips and, more importantly, gave users a way to repair their own devices (kinda). Google’s first-ever mobile chip powered clever experiences on the latest Pixel phones and showcased the company’s AI and software prowess at a competitive price. As we continue to be bombarded by depressing news every day, it’s worth taking the time to reflect on the wins this year, no matter how tiny.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/bc783520-626b-11ec-8efa-762a1008a7f7" alt="NEW YORK, NEW YORK - JUNE 28: Digital artist FEWOCiOUS auctions five new unique NFT works of art, along with five physical paintings and never-before-seen drawings in a collection titled " data-uuid="b0827a8c-add6-3fb2-93e6-c4be1e3f9e8b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Noam Galai via Getty Images</div></figure><h2>NFTs</h2><p>2021 has not been a quiet year, so NFTs deserve something approaching praise for securing a spot in the highlights reel. NFTs, or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nft-explainer-digital-art-collectibles-blockchain-environment-business-investment-cryptocurrency-153023551.html">Non-Fungible Tokens</a>, are an attempt to create an immutable digital asset in an environment where such a thing has historically been tricky. For the industry’s proponents, it’s a way of imposing some form of scarcity on digital artifacts that you can’t easily make scarce. Anyone can right-click and save a picture of a monkey wearing sunglasses and a Hawaiian shirt after all. But only the person who paid a lot of money for the NFT can go around calling themselves the “owner” of the same. As Nietzche didn’t say, NFTs are the lie agreed upon, suggesting that people respect the owner of the certificated copy of something over everything else.</p><p>So far, the biggest and most notable moves in the NFT space have happened in the art market, with pieces being bought and sold for eye-watering numbers. On March 11th, digital artist Beeple sold <em>Everydays: The First 5,000 Days</em> at <a href="https://onlineonly.christies.com/s/beeple-first-5000-days/beeple-b-1981-1/112924">Christie’s auction house</a> for $69,346,250. Those hefty sums are, in some people’s minds, justified because they believe that NFTs will become the new crypto, with everyone trying to get aboard the bandwagon before it goes big. After all, there are lots of folks who got rich during the Bitcoin boom that want to further enhance their fortunes, while some who were left behind now hope to get in on the ground floor on the next big thing. Others, meanwhile, think that the big craze in NFTs right now is to help folks move large quantities of <a href="https://rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/nfts-new-frontier-money-laundering">money around</a> away from the auspices of, you know, <em>regulators</em>.</p><p>The NFT market is so awash with speculator cash that it’s normal to have... questions. A recent <a href="https://hbr.org/2021/11/how-nfts-create-value"><em>Harvard Business Review</em></a> article talks about how commerce can’t work without “clear property rights,” which NFTs help to impose. There’s also the matter of whether NFTs could better enable more reliable and secure ticketing and permission systems? I’ll be honest, I’m personally unconvinced by the argument that NFTs offer rights of ownership, since they don’t necessarily confer upon the buyer the proper rights of ownership.</p><div id="689eca03462645eb968606cf3f25db75"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mrNOYudaMAc?rel=0" style="top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;position:absolute;border:0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no"></iframe></div><p>These issues are, however, going to be worked out over the next few years, and it will only be when the speculation has died down that we’ll see if NFTs have any residual worth. And, hey, not every deeply-technical cryptographic ownership record gets their own SNL sketch shortly after they broke into the mainstream, do they.</p><p>— <em>Daniel Cooper</em></p><h2>The Metaverse</h2><p>Mark Zuckerberg didn&#39;t invent the term, but by <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-new-name-meta-182151399.html">rebadging Facebook as &quot;Meta,&quot;</a> he helped kick off a wave of interest in the metaverse. While it was originally a dystopian view of cyberspace via Neal Stephenson&#39;s Snow Crash, the metaverse now represents the next big online goldrush. You can think of it as the logical step forward from the mobile internet, a world where our online experiences can easily transition between multiple devices. And eventually, it could be something we interact with via AR and VR glasses.</p><p>To be clear, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-metaverse-meta-explained-or-not-120032885.html">we still don&#39;t have an exact idea</a> of what the metaverse will be. The Meta renaming could easily be seen as a way for Zuckerberg to avoid his responsibilities as the leader of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whats-in-the-facebook-papers-and-what-it-means-for-the-company-194502237.html">a fundamentally broken social media company</a>. But other companies have been exploring this idea for years: Microsoft&#39;s HoloLens has proven to be surprisingly useful for commercial and front-line workers, and it&#39;s also <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-mesh-holograms-hololens-ar-vr-164001796.html">core to Mesh</a>, the company&#39;s ambitious solution for virtual meetings. The Borg-like Google Glass was widely ridiculed, but its failure hasn&#39;t stopped Google from thinking about <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-17/google-ceo-sees-company-s-next-trillion-in-value-from-search-ai">its role in the metaverse</a>, either.</p><p>Maybe it&#39;ll take a killer new device, like<a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-requirement-chip-175931492.html"> Apple&#39;s fabled AR glasses</a>, to bring the metaverse into focus. Or maybe it&#39;ll go the way of wearables — a category of devices that&#39;s useful for some people, but not necessarily essential for everyone. Either way, it&#39;s something that will forever be tied to 2021.</p><p>— <em>Devindra Hardawar</em></p><h2>Home fitness tech is here to stay</h2><p>As the pandemic kept many of us indoors and out of gyms, companies like Peloton, Apple, Tonal and even Amazon were able to pull us into new fitness habits and equipment.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/227f4f60-4aef-11eb-beb3-07edc2f2bd9f" alt="Apple Fitness Plus" data-uuid="c805e4d7-fd68-3d4a-836f-496ebac6df1b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Apple</div></figure><p>Meanwhile, major fitness studios and gyms like Equinox, Soulcycle, OrangeTheory and F45 have modulated (while some created from scratch) their online services. Many companies expanded replayable class options or added live lessons, leaderboards and more in a bid to keep members fit – and keep those membership dues coming in.</p><p>COVID-19 offered a chance to shift our workout habits and reduce gym costs. Why pay $50 for a high-intensity interval training gym membership when I can track myself in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-fitness-plus-review-two-weeks-test-watch-music-workout-160058155.html">Apple’s Fitness Plus classes</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ios-15-review-150030599.html">SharePlay with my friends</a> and jump in my own shower, all for just $10 a month?</p><p>Of course, the comparison isn’t oranges for oranges, and despite cheerleading Peloton trainers and form corrections from gym coaches over video livestreams, it’s very hard to get the degree of attention gained from in-person training. That’s likely one reason why at-home exercise injuries have never been higher. <em>The Wall Street Journal </em>reported that emergency room visits after home workouts increased by more than 48% from the end of 2019 through the end of 2020, according to a survey by Medicare Advantage.</p><p>However, just like traditional gyms did when the pandemic first hit, these businesses have to figure out how to hold onto their customers.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/8879dac0-626c-11ec-b73b-713465923241" alt="A woman using the Tonal wall-mounted workout system, performing a pulldown. " data-uuid="652dd337-131b-3575-87f4-94fbaa440072"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Tonal</div></figure><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tonal-live-workouts-smart-home-gym-150033495.html">Tonal</a> is a ‘Peloton for weight training&#39; product that Engadget tested back in 2018. When our usual bench-press machines and squat racks were locked inside gyms over the last year and a half, Tonal saw demand for its resistance-training system rocket. Sales grew more than eight times year-over-year. In a bid to hold onto these new customers, the company recently introduced live classes for Tonal owners, with direct feedback from coaches and classes reportedly calibrated for each user.</p><p>Meanwhile, Peloton, arguably the most recognizable at-home fitness company, faces more competition from (and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-lawsuit-patent-infringement-on-demand-classes-202028622.html">litigation</a> with) rivals and a tougher business outlook. After a rough earnings report in November, the company said it didn’t expect to be profitable again until 2023. <em>Worse,</em> its Bike was involved in the death of an important character in the <em>Sex and the City</em> reboot,<em> And Just Like That</em>. But the company has plans (and cheeky <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/12/peloton-fires-back-at-its-portrayal-in-sex-and-the-city-reboot-with-own-parody-ad.html">responses</a>). It’s integrated into many corporate fitness plans, launched its first exercise game, announced a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-guide-machine-learning-strength-training-152637209.html">fitness camera for strength training</a> and finally — added <a href="https://www.engadget.com/peloton-bike-plus-pause-button-tread-205410305.html">a pause button</a>.</p><p>The challenge will be keeping many of us from returning to our old gyms, cycling commutes, or our old, less healthy habits when things eventually return to normal.</p><p>— <em>Mat Smith</em></p><section data-eng-breakout="2b67b5bad8604c02906e1185f2ed51b5" data-eng-breakout-type="e2ehero"><img class="e2ehero-url" src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/e3384af0-626c-11ec-bff6-49155c024622" alt="An illustration showing a person using tools to repair a gadget while looking at a tablet."></section><h2>Apple takes baby steps toward the right to repair</h2><p>Apple continued to impress the industry with its M1 Pro and M1 Max chips this year, putting them in new MacBooks that garnered <a href="https://www.engadget.com/mac-book-pro-14-16-inch-review-2021-apple-mighty-macs-130011975.html">rave reviews</a>. And though <a href="https://www.engadget.com/iphone-13-pro-and-pro-max-review-120-hz-promotion-screen-macro-camera-cinematic-mode-samples-battery-life-143041678.html">the iPhone 13 Pro</a> is just catching up to Android phones with its 120Hz screen, it&#39;s an undeniably good device with solid cameras and excellent performance. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-watch-series-7-review-all-about-the-screen-130036181.html">Apple Watch Series 7</a> isn&#39;t much different from its predecessor, barring its larger display, but it&#39;s still the best smartwatch around. Plus, Apple TV+ gained much more credibility in 2021 with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-and-apple-tv-clean-up-at-the-emmys-with-the-crown-and-ted-lasso-053901458.html">giant pile of awards its original series <em>Ted Lasso</em></a> brought home.</p><p>But the biggest thing that Apple did this year was to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-user-iphone-repair-policy-change-173047862.html">start selling DIY iPhone and Mac repair kits</a> to consumers. After it was discovered Face ID on an iPhone 13 would stop working if a third party replaced its screen, the company first issued a software fix for this specific issue and announced the repair kits shortly after. The move was hailed by activists as a victory for the right-to-repair movement, given the company’s history of making it obnoxiously difficult for you to get your Apple products fixed by anyone else.</p><p>Of course, Apple could still do better — activists say the company’s plans could be more comprehensive, for example. But this is a major reversal of policy that shows the company is opening up, ever so slightly. Last year, it allowed users to set third-party browsers and email apps as their <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ios-14-change-default-apps-email-browser-195555516.html">default on iPhones and iPads</a>. This year, it introduced FaceTime on the web as a means to allow PC and Android users to join calls that they had previously been excluded from. The company may never fully embrace integrating different ecosystems into its walled garden, but it seems they’re at least listening to what people want and taking small steps towards giving users what they deserve.</p><p>— <em>Cherlynn Low</em></p><h2>Gamestop</h2><p>At the start of 2021, Gamestop’s share price was $17.25. As of this writing, it’s <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=gamestop+share+price&amp;oq=gamestop+share+price&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0i512j69i64l3j69i60l3.2191j1j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">$136.88</a>. This year has been so long that it’s easy to forget many things that happened in January, including the Reddit-driven short squeeze that pushed Gamestop’s stock price to as high as $500 at its peak. Despite subsequent criticism, calls for better regulation, a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/reddit-gamestop-squeeze-congress-hearings-002519817.html">congressional hearing on</a> what <a href="https://www.engadget.com/robinhood-reddit-ceo-testify-house-gamestop-hearing-152845471.html">happened</a> and multiple class-action lawsuits having been filed against <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gamestop-reddit-wallstreetbets-roaring-kitty-lawsuit-204813659.html">parties</a> like brokering app Robinhood, here we are 12 months later with the company’s stock still higher than it’s ever been before 2021.</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/0e4123d0-58f3-11ec-8fb3-38f4c87c9875" alt="People walk by a GameStop in Manhattan, New York, U.S., December 7, 2021. REUTERS/Andrew Kelly" data-uuid="bc54b69f-c4f2-3f3b-8548-08b1c431c266"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Andrew Kelly / reuters</div></figure><p>Of course, a company’s share price isn’t a true indicator of its overall performance and health. But this is a far cry from <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-15-gamestop-store-renovations.html">2019</a> when GameStop was <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-11-gamestop-to-close-over-200-stores.html">posting tens of millions in losses and planning to shutter up to 200 stores</a>. In 2020, its main challenges were around trying to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-20-gamestop-essential.html">keep its outlets open</a> in the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-20-gamestop-closes-california-stores.html">face of stay-home mandates</a> and making sure it had <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gamestop-ps5-preorder-restrock-203545363.html">enough consoles to sell</a>.</p><p>This year, in possibly the most 2021 combination of words ever, GameStop announced it’s working on an <a href="https://nft.gamestop.com/">NFT platform</a> based on Ethereum. It also <a href="https://news.gamestop.com/news-releases/news-release-details/gamestop-reports-financial-results-q2-2021">signed a lease for a new 530,000 square-foot fulfilment center</a> in Nevada and opened a new customer care center in Florida. It made $1.18 billion in the second quarter compared to $942 million in the same period in 2020. That could partly be due to the fact that Sony and Microsoft launched their consoles after the second quarter in 2020. Basically, 2021 has been a great year for GameStop, and not just for its business.</p><p>Discovery+ is even working on a documentary (narrated by “Wolf of Wall Street” Jordan Belfort) on the entire fiasco titled <em>GameStop:The Wall Street Hijack</em>. Nine other films based on these events are reportedly in the works, according to <a href="https://www.vulture.com/2021/02/inside-hollywoods-rush-to-make-the-first-gamestop-movie.html"><em>Vulture</em></a>. Gamestop wasn’t the only company that Reddit’s day traders flocked to in their nostalgia-driven frenzy, either. Companies like BlackBerry and AMC also saw their share prices surge, with the latter’s stock <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GameStop_short_squeeze#Other_affected_assets">jumping 480 percent</a> at its peak. GameStop’s slogan uncannily sums up the situation: “Power to the players.”</p><p>— <em>C.L.</em></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/7438ce80-626d-11ec-b02e-6a37eb329d72" alt="A screenshot of the Windows 11 desktop with a browser showing the Engadget homepage snapped to the right half of the screen." data-uuid="6fd11945-46a9-3409-8c6e-032226706a4a"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Devindra Hardawar / Engadget</div></figure><h2>Windows 11</h2><p>If you had told me in January that Microsoft had its Windows 10 successor primed and ready for release by the end of the year, I would have laughed in your face. But <a href="https://www.engadget.com/windows-11-review-microsoft-mindful-os-200028040.html">Windows 11 is actually here</a>, and it&#39;s a pretty solid step forward aesthetically (despite some clunky usability issues). I&#39;d bet even Microsoft was surprised it managed to make that happen.</p><p>Windows 11 rose from the ashes of Windows 10X, an OS variant that was originally supposed to focus on dual-screen devices, but was eventually canceled in May. That would explain why Windows 11 feels more like a fresh coat of paint on its predecessor. But despite that inauspicious start, it&#39;s still a worthwhile update: there&#39;s more of an emphasis on security, and the facelift brings some Mac-like pleasantries into the typically stark world of Windows.</p><p>It&#39;s not a complete success — upgrading is an annoying process if you&#39;ve got a self-built PC, and very old computers won&#39;t be able to upgrade at all (at least, not without going through <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-windows-11-supported-processors-update-175544403.html">a manual ISO installation</a>). But at the very least, Microsoft managed to keep most of what made <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-windows-11-supported-processors-update-175544403.html">Windows 10 such a successful operating system</a>, while also delivering a more mindful experience for PC users.</p><p>— <em>D. H.</em></p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/3f8059f0-351e-11ec-b0ff-08ac0f4a7d11" alt="The Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro held up in mid-air with their camera bars facing out." data-uuid="eabd75c1-6680-3f1e-9797-75c903593cae"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">David Imel for Engadget</div></figure><h2>Google Pixel 6 Pro</h2><p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-review-specs-camera-samples-battery-test-160014200.html">Pixel 6 Pro</a> is my favorite Pixel yet. Yes, I wish Google offered a smaller handset in its latest flagship series, but that complaint aside, there’s plenty to love. The company’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-tensor-faq-specs-ai-ml-160021397.html">first-ever mobile chip Tensor</a> powers the phone’s impressive AI features like live translation in messages and captions, as well as smarter voice typing features.</p><p>Most of all, I adore the Pixel 6 Pro’s cameras. If I’m headed out somewhere that I have the slightest sense might warrant some sort of picture-taking, I make sure to bring the 6 Pro with me. Its portrait mode, which I abuse for my food photos, is superior to every other phone I’ve used, and frankly, I’m partial to Google’s colors and clarity.</p><p>Plus, bonus features like Magic Eraser, Face Unblur and Action Pan give me the option to add fun effects or clean up my shots. Everyone I’ve taken pictures of has been impressed by the quality. Of course, the Pixel 6 is not without its flaws. Setting aside my complaint about its size, the Pixel 6 Pro also has a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/googles-surprise-pixel-6-patch-improves-the-fingerprint-scanner-113422282.html">finicky in-screen fingerprint sensor</a>. Google has also had to issue <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-fixes-pixel-6-auto-dialing-bug-183730003.html">several</a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-confirms-pixel-6-pro-display-flickering-issue-will-be-fixed-next-month-122533947.html"> fixes</a> in recent weeks to address bugs that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-disables-hold-for-me-pixel-6-bug-in-december-upgrade-111504567.html">themselves were caused by over the air updates</a>. Still, as a showcase for Google’s strengths in software and AI, the Pixel 6 Pro fully delivers. Best of all, it does so for hundreds of dollars less than rival flagships.</p><p>— <em>C.L.</em></p><h2>Samsung foldables&nbsp;</h2><p>In an admittedly niche industry, Samsung has pulled far ahead. Sure, it was one of the first to try its hand at foldables, but it&#39;s also arguably the last one standing. The foldable phone race really kicked off when relative unknown Royole showed off the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-11-how-royole-built-the-worlds-first-foldable-phone.html">first working prototype at CES 2019</a>. Soon after, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-02-25-huawei-mate-x-closer-look-june-launch-cameras-screen-crease-bump.html">Huawei</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-02-20-samsung-galaxy-fold.html">Samsung</a> announced their own devices. The original Mate X and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-15-samsung-galaxy-fold-hands-on-price-release-date.html">Galaxy Fold</a> made the rounds at various press events after, but only Samsung eventually sold its first-gen foldable to the general public (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-23-huawei-mate-x-china-november-15.html">outside of China</a>, anyway).</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-08/7243b550-0754-11ec-9fca-3bf7ca5ab8c0" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 3 laying open, flat on its back, on a window ledge." data-uuid="e5202088-1b98-3058-86d9-fd11f48eae8b"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">David Imel for Engadget</div></figure><p>Motorola <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-11-13-motorola-razr-foldable-hands-on-preview-2019.html">jumped on the trend</a>, capitalizing on the sheer nostalgia value of its Razr Flip phone. Alas, all these initial attempts were doomed to fail. Foldables, it turns out, with their soft, vulnerable displays and damage-prone hinges, are hard to nail. Worse, the Razr Flip&#39;s screen just <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-14-motorola-razr-review-2020-foldable-fashion-statement.html">felt weird and flimsy</a>, and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-07-motorola-razr-cnet-fold-test.html">its hinge</a> would make a cracking sound when you open or close the phone.</p><p>After a slew of reports of broken review units, Samsung returned with updated iterations of the Fold. It also released the Flip series, a smaller, Razr-like version that received its share of early complaints. Yet, today, Samsung not only continues to produce these foldables, but at cheaper prices, too. The Z series is now in its third generation, and Samsung said it shipped four times more foldables in 2021 than in 2020. While Huawei also unveiled a third version this year, its foldables haven’t been available in most places outside of China. We&#39;ve also yet to see a new version of the Razr this year, although Motorola did roll out a 5G-capable update in 2020 that we never got to test. Companies like Oppo and Xiaomi have also unveiled their own foldables recently, but they’re relatively new to the game.</p><p>By bringing the price of the Z Flip 3 down to a more competitive $999 while continuing to improve the durability and usefulness of its products, Samsung has shown it may be the only company with the resources and expertise to continue to deliver foldable phones, even if they may never gain mainstream popularity.</p><p>— <em>C.L.</em></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/best-tech-products-and-companies-2021-143005186.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">9b3840c7-dcc6-4b3d-9e1d-13c056b3e7c3</guid><dc:creator>Engadget</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 14:30:05 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640878305</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T15:44:19+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Personal Investing Ideas & Strategies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Engadget]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6db401c0-641f-11ec-becf-13c992f13693" width="2024" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6db401c0-641f-11ec-becf-13c992f13693" width="2024" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Tech year in review winners]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tech year in review winners]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla recalls nearly half a million cars over camera and trunk defects]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tesla&#39;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-had-a-phenomenal-2021-150044600.html">recall-filled 2021</a> isn&#39;t over quite yet. <em>Bloomberg</em><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-30/tesla-recalls-over-475-000-u-s-cars-on-camera-trunk-issues?sref=10lNAhZ9">reports</a> Tesla has issued recalls for just over 475,000 vehicles to fix defects in camera systems and trunks. To start, the automaker has <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/rcl/2021/RCLRPT-21V00D-5923.PDF">recalled</a> all Model 3 cars in the 2017 to 2020 model years over a concern repeated use of the trunk may wear down a coaxial cable for the rearview camera — too much use and you may lose the signal entirely.</p><p>The other <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/rcl/2021/RCLRPT-21V00B-6667.PDF">recall</a> covers 119,009 Model S sedans in the 2014 to 2021 model years. A factory misalignment of the front trunk (aka frunk) latch assembly can prevent a secondary latch from working properly, increasing the chances the trunk will pop open mid-drive.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>The Model 3 flaw doesn&#39;t exist in 2021 and newer production runs, while Model S drivers are safe if their EVs were built after December 23rd, 2020.  You&#39;ll have to visit Tesla to get a fix, but the company will compensate anyone who paid for relevant repairs before the recalls took effect.</p><p>None of the defects led to crashes or injuries, Tesla said. However, the recalls cap a series of issues that include an <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-autopilot-investigation-nhtsa-141310451.html">NHTSA investigation</a> over Autopilot safety, recalls for components like touchscreens, and complaints about build quality problems like panel gaps. Simply speaking, the company developed more of a reputation for less-than-stellar reliability in 2021, and it&#39;s not clear when that situation might improve.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tesla-model-3-s-camera-trunk-recall-142249417.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">12e05a80-ca39-4105-9a92-1258c4dc5a93</guid><dc:creator>Jon Fingas</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 14:22:49 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640874173</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T14:23:05+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Autos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Jon Fingas]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/001e7880-317e-11ec-bdbb-3ca0a1aed4bd" width="4000" height="2666" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-10/001e7880-317e-11ec-bdbb-3ca0a1aed4bd" width="4000" height="2666" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Barcroft Media via Getty Images]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[YANTAI, CHINA - OCTOBER 17, 2021 - A Tesla Model 3 is displayed at the Tesla Experience store in Joy City, Yantai, East China's Shandong Province, Oct 17, 2021. In September 2021, Tesla China set a new record of 56,006 vehicles. (Photo credit should read Tang Ke / Costfoto/Barcroft Media via Getty Images)]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Tesla China Set A Record Of 56,006 Vehicles in September]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[New York City orders 184 Mustang Mach-E cars for police and government use]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New York City has <a href="https://www1.nyc.gov/site/dcas/news/21-020/nyc-taking-another-step-towards-achieving-all-electric-municipal-fleet">purchased</a> 184 all-electric <a href="https://www.engadget.com/fords-mach-e-is-a-stylish-and-capable-ev-but-its-no-mustang-153044259.html">Mustang Mach-Es</a>, and they&#39;re all going to be used for law enforcement and emergency response purposes. As <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/12/30/nypd-buys-184-ford-mustang-mach-e-approves-option-buy-250-tesla-model-3/"><em>Electrek</em></a> noted, the move is part of the city&#39;s plans to buy over 1,250 electric vehicles in 2022. That, in turn, is part of a larger endeavor to &quot;drastically cut citywide climate emissions&quot; with the help of a $420 million investment.&nbsp;</p><p>In its announcement, the local NYC government said the Mach-Es will be used by the New York Police Department (NYPD), the New York City Sheriff&#39;s Office, the Department of Correction, the Department of Parks and Recreation, the Department of Environmental Protection, NYC Emergency Management, DCAS Police and the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner. They&#39;ll be replacing those agencies&#39; gas-powered vehicles after the city receives them by June 30th, 2022.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>NYC also said that its Mach-E purchase is part of its biggest EV purchase to date, though that may not be the case for long. The city has also approved the option to buy up to 250 Tesla Model 3 vehicles any time over the next five years.&nbsp;</p><p>Earlier this month, Ford <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ford-delays-explorer-aviator-ev-triple-mustang-mach-e-output-101527917.html">announced</a> that it&#39;s increasing the production of the Mach-E to 200,000 vehicles per year in the US starting in 2022 and in Europe by 2023. Company CEO Jim Farley said there&#39;s a huge demand for the electric vehicle, and Ford is reportedly delaying its Explorer and Aviator EVs to ensure that it can manufacture enough Mach-Es to keep up with the demand.</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/new-york-city-mustang-mach-e-cars-130943173.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">cd45b68f-6bce-49d5-af5e-8906e45bf063</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 13:09:43 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640869786</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T13:09:59+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Politics & Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Government]]></category><category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/68c3ce50-696c-11ec-953e-18c0d475905c" width="1440" height="810" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/68c3ce50-696c-11ec-953e-18c0d475905c" width="1440" height="810" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Ford]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Ford]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Ford]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Morning After: 30 percent brighter OLED TVs are coming]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I didn’t get it in time for our best buys of 2021, I am now the proud owner of an LG C1 OLED TV. It is beautiful, does 4K, HDR, variable refresh rates and more. Everything looks amazing on it.</p><p>As I bought it, I thought about how I’ve never been at the vanguard of TV tech, and how it would only last a couple of weeks until LG ruins it all with even newer TV models.</p><p>And like clockwork, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-oled-ex-enhance-brightness-30-percent-095813152.html">here it comes</a>. LG Display’s next generation of OLED tech, called &quot;OLED EX,&quot; that&#39;s supposed to &quot;enhance brightness up to 30 percent compared to conventional OLED displays,&quot; The company also upgraded the TV’s designs too, reducing bezel thickness by up to 30 percent on its 65-inch OLED displays.</p><p>In defense of my new 55-inch OLED, this is LG Display, not LG, the part of the multinational company that brings this new TV tech to stores, so that doesn’t mean it’s landing in a new TV immediately. It’s just, sigh, already on the horizon.</p><p>-Mat Smith</p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-down-183417137.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">‘Fortnite’ went briefly offline yesterday</a></h2><h3>It’s back now.</h3><h3></h3><p>If you had tried to play <em>Fortnite</em> yesterday, you may have had issues. Many players were unable to log in to their accounts and play games. At 1:13PM ET, Epic Games said it was investigating &quot;an issue,&quot; and roughly six hours later, the battle royale hit was back online.</p><p>Epic Games said that it would have “more details next week on what we’re doing to help you make up for lost time.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/fortnite-down-183417137.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-spacex-starlink-un-complaint-221835093.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">China says its space station dodged Starlink satellites twice this year</a></h2><h3>SpaceX&#39;s constellation might pose a safety risk.</h3><h3></h3><a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-spacex-starlink-un-complaint-221835093.html https://www.engadget.com/..."><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/6097a930-6968-11ec-9f7e-795b1062dc88" alt="The Morning After" data-uuid="3a12a7ee-43c3-32ef-a815-549c07085b50"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Getty Images</div></figure></a><p>China has filed a complaint with the United Nations over two reported near-collisions between the in-progress Tiangong space station and Starlink vehicles. According to Chinese officials, the station had to perform evasive maneuvers on July 1st and October 21st this year to minimize the chance of a collision. In its complaint, the country asked the UN Secretary-General to remind countries (read: the US) that parties in the Outer Space Treaty are responsible for incidents beyond Earth, even if they involve private companies.</p><p>The accusations line up with astronomer Jonathan McDowell&#39;s conjunction observations for both days. China further argued that SpaceX&#39;s satellites weren&#39;t always predictable. During the October incident, the Starlink craft was &quot;continuously&quot; maneuvering in a way that made it difficult to predict the orbital path.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-spacex-starlink-un-complaint-221835093.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-review-150019762.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Rivian’s R1T electric truck brings adventure to the EV crowd</a></h2><h3>Not just an impressive EV, but an impressive truck.</h3><h3></h3><p>Announcing a vehicle is one thing, actually following through and building that vehicle at a factory and then selling it, that’s an almost impossible feat for a new company. But like Tesla before it, Rivian has pulled it off and in doing so has built one of the best trucks on the road today, EV or otherwise. Roberto Baldwin gives it a test drive.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-review-150019762.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/jabra-elite-4-active-wireless-earbuds-142911217.html">Jabra&#39;s Elite 4 Active earbuds add ANC and better sweat resistance</a></h2><h3>They&#39;re only available in some countries right now.</h3><h3></h3><p>Jabra only just launched its Elite 3 wireless earbuds, but here’s their sequel. The Elite 4 Active is a step-up model that adds active noise cancellation and improved IP57 water resistance (up from IP55).</p><p>Expect to get a claimed seven hours of battery life from the buds themselves and 28 hours when you include the charging case. The Elite 4 Active is available now in the UK for £120 (about $161), but they haven&#39;t been announced for the US just yet.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/jabra-elite-4-active-wireless-earbuds-142911217.html"><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-expands-tv-ready-program-140038201.html%20https://www.engadget.com/...">Roku expands its TV Ready program</a></h2><h3>More audio devices will be able to automatically pair with Roku TVs.</h3><h3></h3><p>Roku TVs will be able to pair quickly with even more audio products in the future. The company has expanded its TV Ready Certification Program, adding Element, JVC, Pheanoo and Philips this year, with Polk Audio and Westinghouse joining the list in 2022. Roku also opened the program internationally, and partners like Bose are expected to launch TV Ready devices in the United Kingdom, Canada and Mexico soon.</p><p>The TV Ready initiative makes it easy to connect soundbars and speakers to Roku TVs — so long as the audio device supports the feature, it will automatically be detected as soon as you plug it in.</p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/roku-expands-tv-ready-program-140038201.html%20https://www.engadget.com/..."><strong>Continue reading.</strong></a></p><p></p><h3>The biggest news stories you might have missed</h3><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-ray-ban-stories-vs-snapchat-spectacles-173247974.html"><br></a><a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsunge-galaxy-flip-3-more-people-to-switch-than-flagships-085330086.html">Samsung says the Galaxy Flip 3 motivated more people to switch than its flagships</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/lets-play-oink-games-jackbox-irl-160044668.html">&#39;Let&#39;s Play! Oink Games&#39; is no Jackbox, but it&#39;s a worthy party game collection</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/amenhotep-ct-scan-204504392.html">Researchers used CT scans to virtually unwrap a pristine mummy</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-playstation-5-accessories-140018902.html">The best accessories for your new PlayStation 5</a></p><p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/january-ps-plus-games-persona-5-strikers-dirt-5-deep-rock-galactic-174854063.html">January&#39;s PS Plus games include &#39;Persona 5 Strikers&#39; and &#39;Dirt 5&#39;</a></p><h3></h3><p></p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/the-morning-after-30-percent-brighter-oled-t-vs-are-coming-122031193.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">4466192e-2bc1-43c8-a9c9-b58fdcae4080</guid><dc:creator>Mat Smith</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 12:20:31 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640872362</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T13:52:48+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mat Smith]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/7055bce0-688c-11ec-b6ef-98d09ce8bbf2" width="2700" height="1737" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/7055bce0-688c-11ec-b6ef-98d09ce8bbf2" width="2700" height="1737" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[LG Display]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[LG Display Unveils Next-Generation OLED TV Display 'OLED EX']]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[LG-Display-image]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tumblr blocks tags for 'sensitive content' in order to stay on the App Store]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-13-tumblr-back-on-the-app-store.html">Tumblr</a> has <a href="https://staff.tumblr.com/post/671928371391938560/for-those-of-you-that-may-have-missed-our-post-on">restricted</a> what its users can see on its iOS app in an effort to make sure it doesn&#39;t get kicked out of Apple&#39;s App Store again. One of the steps it has taken to comply with Apple&#39;s guidelines is to limit the results for certain tags or search terms that Tumblr says &quot;may fall under the expanded definition of sensitive content.&quot; The website will even completely block some of them — make that more than some, based on this pretty <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1YG7E84Dvs2PyoKMgSgZFgEX0Kh0RtJqsazZsyVGY8dk/mobilebasic">lengthy list</a> of banned and limited terms collected by Tumblr users that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tumblr-ios-tags-ban-apple/"><em>TechCrunch</em></a> posted.&nbsp;</p><p>While the inclusion of specific words in the list is self explanatory, it also has some curious entries, such as &quot;Eugene Levy&quot; and &quot;Tony the Tiger.&quot; The restriction will also make it harder to search for content related to mental health, such as PTSD, depression and anxiety, as well as issues like racism and transphobia. Those searching for a blocked tag will get a screen that says &quot;This content has been hidden&quot; instead of a page with results. They&#39;ll see the same notification if they try to access a blog that&#39;s been flagged as &quot;explicit&quot; on the app. Users may also see fewer suggestions under the &quot;stuff for you&quot; and &quot;following&quot; sections due to the new restrictions.&nbsp;</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>Tumblr has implemented these changes three years after it started completely <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-12-03-tumblr-blocking-adult-content-december-17th.html">blocking adult content</a> on its platform. If you&#39;ll recall, Tumblr prohibited adult content in 2018 after Apple <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-20-tumblr-pulled-app-store-child-exploitation.html">pulled</a> its app from iTunes in response to finding child exploitation photos on the website. The social network said these changes only apply to its iOS app and that they won&#39;t affect anyone browsing Tumblr on the web or on Android. A spokesperson also told <em>TechCrunch</em> that the company is &quot;working on more thoughtful solutions which will be rolled out in the near future.&quot;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/tumblr-ios-tags-restriction-115024668.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">93fa43d5-aa41-4218-9381-480724b1d0dd</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 11:50:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640864868</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T11:47:53+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Software]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-images/2018-12/e560f4a0-f724-11e8-bbfd-8a61f9182b6e" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-images/2018-12/e560f4a0-f724-11e8-bbfd-8a61f9182b6e" width="5184" height="3456" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[Thomas White / Reuters]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[The Tumblr application is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration photo March 7, 2018.      REUTERS/Thomas White/Illustration]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[INDONESIA-PORNOGRAPHY/TUMBLR]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung says the Galaxy Flip 3 motivated more people to switch than its flagships]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest foldable Galaxy devices are a hit. Samsung shipped four times more foldables in 2021 than what it did in 2020, the tech giant has <a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/a-decade-in-the-making-how-samsung-foldables-are-defining-the-future-of-smartphone-innovation">revealed</a>. Further, it took only one month after they were released for the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review-s-pen-camera-battery-test-190051606.html">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a> and the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review-price-specs-cameras-screen-170051882.html">Galaxy Z Flip 3</a> to exceed the total accumulative sales of their predecessors last year. The company also said that it saw a &quot;massive increase&quot; in consumers who jumped brands specifically for its foldable phones — in fact, more people switched to Samsung for the Flip 3 than for its flagship devices.&nbsp;</p><p>While Samsung didn&#39;t rattle off specific numbers, it said it saw a 150 percent increase in consumers who switched brands for the Flip 3 compared to the Galaxy Note 20. It saw a 140 percent increase in people switching brands for the foldable compared to the Galaxy S21, as well. The Flip&#39;s form factor is of course its main draw, along with its front screen that gives users a way to use their phone without having to open it. As for the Fold 3, people who responded to Samsung&#39;s survey said they got it for its large screen, multitasking capabilities and S Pen support.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><p>In its post, Samsung said foldables are expected to grow tenfold by 2023, and it&#39;s heavily investing in research and development to be able to keep up with rival devices that will surely pop up. One of those competitors is <a href="https://www.engadget.com/huawei-p-50-pocket-revealed-harpers-bazaar-072121090.html">Huawei&#39;s P50 Pocket</a> phone, which is the company&#39;s first model that folds vertically like the Galaxy Z Flip.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/samsunge-galaxy-flip-3-more-people-to-switch-than-flagships-085330086.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">3cced768-4a47-443f-971e-bb74f3f486ed</guid><dc:creator>Mariella Moon</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 08:53:30 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640854413</ingested><modified>2021-12-30T08:54:08+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Consumer Discretionary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology & Electronics]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Mariella Moon]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a67ba130-6946-11ec-bcfc-5a201b3122f2" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/a67ba130-6946-11ec-bcfc-5a201b3122f2" width="1920" height="1080" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[David Imel for Engadget]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:title></media:content></item><item><title><![CDATA[JLab's latest $20 earbuds are designed to complement your skin tone]]></title><description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to blending in, nearly all <a href="https://www.engadget.com/best-wireless-earbuds-120058222.html">true wireless earbuds</a> fail miserably. That&#39;s mostly due to predominantly black and white color options, with a few brightly-hued variants tossed in along the way. Even if the buds are tiny, they&#39;re still highly visible due to their color. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-02-10-jlab-go-air-review-29-dollar-true-wireless-earbuds.html">JLab</a> is on a quest to remedy this and the audio company teamed up with nail care brand ORLY to develop a solution. With <a href="https://www.jlab.com/TONES">the Go Air Tones</a>, the duo selected a collection of seven Pantone colors that are &quot;flattering for people across a spectrum of skin tones.&quot;&nbsp;</p><p>JLab says it worked with ORLY to select the final hues from an original collection of over 60 options. Given the beauty brand&#39;s experience with creating nude nail polishes, the seven colors &quot;encompassed a variety of skin tones with a mix of warm, neutral and cool undertones. While the colors reflect actual skin tones, most users will find the colors &quot;flattering&quot; without an exact match, according to JLab. If you&#39;re having trouble selecting the best option, JLab offers <a href="https://www.jlab.com/pages/fitting-room">an AR fitting room</a> for a virtual try-on that might help you decide.</p><span id="end-legacy-contents"></span><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/599715c0-68f6-11ec-9757-e551f6b92a1c" style="height:1334;width:2000;" alt="JLab Go Air Tones" data-uuid="1b50bcad-bf48-3149-ad0b-c612acf6aba7"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JLab</div></figure><p>The Go Air Tones are the same earbuds as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/jlab-go-air-pop-true-wireless-earbuds-20-dollars-130024634.html">the $20 Go Air Pop</a> that JLab debuted back in August. This means you&#39;ll get on-board touch controls, the ability to use either bud on its own, a collection of EQ presets and IPX4 protection from moisture. There&#39;s also an enclosed case with built-in USB cable for charging. JLab says you can expect up to eight hours on the earbuds themselves with an additional three charges from the included case. The only difference between the Pop and the Tones are the available color options for each.&nbsp;</p><p>The Go Air Tones are <a href="https://www.jlab.com/TONES">available for pre-order today</a> for $20. They&#39;re scheduled to begin shipping in mid-January.&nbsp;</p><figure><img src="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/30f30840-68f6-11ec-afee-54b77283596a" style="height:233;width:1176;" alt="JLab Go Air Tones" data-uuid="1eea310f-23ff-3ecb-8890-b2d431c1c5ab"><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">JLab</div></figure>]]></description><link><![CDATA[https://www.engadget.com/jlab-go-air-tones-announced-price-specs-availability-060024516.html?src=rss]]></link><source_id>engadget_479</source_id><guid isPermalink="false">e485cbb8-3ba7-4f3c-827c-24d992e8e113</guid><dc:creator>Billy Steele</dc:creator><source><![CDATA[Engadget]]></source><dc:publisher>Engadget</dc:publisher><dc:rightsHolder>Engadget</dc:rightsHolder><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 06:00:24 +0000</pubDate><ingested>1640817375</ingested><modified>2021-12-29T22:36:23+00:00</modified><category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category><category><![CDATA[site|engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[provider_name|Engadget]]></category><category><![CDATA[region|US]]></category><category><![CDATA[language|en-US]]></category><category><![CDATA[author_name|Billy Steele]]></category><media:content url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/70e9b250-68f6-11ec-b2ff-41a68941a614" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:keywords>headline</media:keywords><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[1]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[]]></media:title></media:content><media:content url="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/70e9b250-68f6-11ec-b2ff-41a68941a614" width="2000" height="1333" medium="image"><media:media_html><![CDATA[]]></media:media_html><dc:identifier><![CDATA[2]]></dc:identifier><media:credit><![CDATA[JLab]]></media:credit><media:description><![CDATA[JLab Go Air Tones]]></media:description><media:title><![CDATA[JLab Go Air Tones]]></media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>