<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-19T22:10:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T22:10:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T22:10:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Horizon Zero Dawn: Complete Edition is now free for PS4 and PS5 owners</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Horizon Zero Dawn" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5JmCwX50MCz70y_RkSd3zGhfD-4=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69153960/Outro.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image:&amp;nbsp;Guerrilla Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1sO8gL"&gt;Sony and Guerrilla Games’ PS4 hit&lt;em&gt; Horizon Zero Dawn &lt;/em&gt;is now available, free of charge, to PS4 and PS5 owners. PlayStation owners on both consoles can redeem a free digital copy of the game until May 14th at 8PM PT / 11PM ET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H07eii"&gt;The free copy Sony is offering is the &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP9000-CUSA10237_00-HRZCE00000000000"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Complete Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you get not only the base game but some extras, including the &lt;em&gt;Frozen Wilds &lt;/em&gt;expansion and a digital artbook. Unlike the PS Plus free games, which require an active subscription to the service, Sony is giving away the game for free, no strings attached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3nSHIa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The promotion is part of Sony’s Play at Home initiative&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1Yc7AP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; was originally released in 2017 as a PS4 exclusive. Players control a young hunter named Aloy who roams a post-apocalyptic world dominated by machines while searching for clues about her past. The game is also receiving a sequel titled &lt;em&gt;Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;, which is slated to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21294561/horizon-forbidden-west-ps5-release-date-2021-guerrilla-games-details-playstation"&gt;launch sometime this year on the PS4 and PS5&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZDABm0"&gt;The promotion is part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297009/ratchet-and-clank-free-ps4-ps5-playstation-sony"&gt;Sony’s “Play at Home”&lt;/a&gt; initiative, which aims to encourage PlayStation owners to stay home during the pandemic by incentivizing players with free games until June. Additionally, Sony is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350340/ps4-ps5-games-sony-astro-bot-rescue-mission-play-at-home-psvr"&gt;also giving away nine titles&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;em&gt;Astro Bot Rescue Mission&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Enter the Gungeon&lt;/em&gt; for free until April 22nd at 8PM PT / 11PM ET. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392094/horizon-zero-dawn-free-ps4-ps5-playstation-sony"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392094/horizon-zero-dawn-free-ps4-ps5-playstation-sony</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T18:22:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T18:22:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Parler will relaunch on Apple’s App Store next week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration a Parler logo is seen behind a..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1cz50eEVSzl-LzVPheLh799FFrs=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69152391/1230591907.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Thiago Prudêncio/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WwqCuM"&gt;The embattled social network Parler is slated to reappear on iOS on the week of April 26th, following its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391943/apple-parler-app-store-lawmakers-hearing-google-play"&gt;re-acceptance into Apple’s App Store&lt;/a&gt; earlier today. However, the iOS app will block some content that’s available on the Android and web versions of Parler — a compromise that apparently satisfies Apple’s developer guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DdlQdH"&gt;Parler announced the news in a press release. Interim CEO Mark Meckler said the company had “worked to put in place systems that will better detect unlawful speech and allow users to filter content undesirable to them, while maintaining our strict prohibition against content moderation based on viewpoint.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ymeJ98"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple reversed its ban earlier today&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tzQTy2"&gt;Apple reaccepted Parler after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324028/apple-parler-app-store-ban-upheld-nazi-symbols"&gt;months-long ban&lt;/a&gt; under pressure from lawmakers, two days before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376127/apple-senate-judiciary-hearing-klobuchar-app-store-google-play-antitrust"&gt;a hearing on Apple’s App Store policies&lt;/a&gt;. The company said Parler — which promotes itself as a less strictly moderated alternative to Facebook or Twitter — had engaged in “substantial conversations” with Parler, resulting in a set of proposed changes that would meet Apple’s content policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzrKz1"&gt;According to Parler’s press release, that includes filtering some content on iOS. “While the App Store version of Parler will prohibit some posts that Parler allows, those posts will still remain visible on the web-based and Android versions of Parler,” the release notes. Parler didn’t elaborate on what kinds of content that would include, but Apple broadly requires a system for filtering “objectionable” material posted by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ueCEao"&gt;Apple, Google, and Amazon all &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22224860/parler-trump-deplatformed-capitol-raid-moderation-censorship-facebook-amazon-twitter"&gt;banned Parler&lt;/a&gt; after the January 6th attack on the US Capitol, saying Parler had failed to police violent threats and hateful content. Parler sued Amazon, which it had worked with for web hosting, but the suit has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310873/parler-amazon-aws-lawsuit-antitrust-hosting-free-speech"&gt;so far fared poorly&lt;/a&gt; in court. Google has continued to bar Parler from its Play Store, but users can install the app directly on Android — making the ban far less of a liability.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392727/parler-relaunch-apple-app-store-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392727/parler-relaunch-apple-app-store-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T17:54:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T17:54:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oatly investors should beware climate change</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Oprah-Backed Vegan Milk Brand Oatly Said To Plan 2021 U.S. IPO" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dRGwWNLZNL1vF3Q2-7NR8RveoMU=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69152269/1228558733.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9rqkqr"&gt;Oatly is going public, so out of prurient interest, I picked up their &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1843586/000119312521121323/d123209df1.htm"&gt;registration statement&lt;/a&gt;. Did you know: a risk factor to Oatly’s business? Climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="we8JpK"&gt;In 2010, the Securities and Exchange Commission provided guidance about how to apply climate change disclosures — since it might be required in the risk factor section, among other places. And according to the SEC, investor demand for climate change disclosures has “&lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/lee-climate-change-disclosures"&gt;grown dramatically.&lt;/a&gt;” The SEC is mulling over whether existing disclosures are good enough, and it has &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/lee-climate-change-disclosures"&gt;requested feedback from the public&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c3pD4T"&gt;Oatly’s registration provides a nice demonstration of that interest: the risks of climate change laid out bluntly by a corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3sEUCl"&gt;“Our ability to ensure a continuing supply of high-quality oats and other raw materials for our products at competitive prices depends on many factors beyond our control,” the materials say. Well, yes, this is true for many kinds of agricultural products. There’s some hemming and hawing about what might happen if a supplier goes bankrupt or whatever. Fine. Then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="wo2iBO"&gt;Additionally, the oats from which our products are sourced are vulnerable to adverse weather conditions and natural disasters, such as floods, droughts, frosts, earthquakes, hurricanes, pestilence and other shortages and disease, which can adversely impact quantity and quality, leading to reduced oat yields and quality, which in turn could reduce the available supply of, or increase the price of, our raw materials. The monocultures that we use are also sensitive to diseases, pests, insects and other external forces, which could pose either short term effects, such as result in a bad harvest one year, or long term effects, which could require new oat varieties to be grown. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="x7NHWg"&gt;This is the first time I’ve seen “monocultures” referenced in a regulatory filing. It’s been used three times, &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/edgar/search/#/q=monocultures&amp;amp;dateRange=all"&gt;per the SEC’s search&lt;/a&gt;; “monoculture,” no plural, &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/edgar/search/#/q=monoculture&amp;amp;dateRange=all"&gt;has been used about 80 times&lt;/a&gt;. It is something of a surprise to see this jargon — it refers to a lot of a single crop being grown on a large scale — in a registration statement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQ478F"&gt;If you are, like me, from farm country, “monoculture” pretty much just describes the farming as you know it. The idea is that it’s more efficient, more profitable, and easier to manage, letting farmers specialize in a specific crop, such as oats. It also means more pesticide use, and when pests arise, it’s easier for them to wipe out &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2020/09/coffee-rust/616358/"&gt;a shocking amount of plants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Zjmgx"&gt;Monocultures &lt;em&gt;are &lt;/em&gt;a risk factor. Banana wilt, for instance, is tied &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28791467/"&gt;closely to industrial banana production&lt;/a&gt; and the overwhelming number of Cavendish bananas that are planted. &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1164556319303516"&gt;Rotating crops&lt;/a&gt; may help prevent the bacterial disease, though. In oats, crown rust, stem rust, barley yellow dwarf virus, oat smut, and other diseases are seen in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhCPZX"&gt;But this isn’t what dropped my jaw. Instead it was: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="JMCDjl"&gt;There is also the concern that carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases in the atmosphere may have an adverse impact on global temperatures, weather patterns and the frequency and severity of extreme weather and natural disasters. If such climate change has a negative effect on agricultural productivity, we may be subject to decreased availability or less favorable pricing for oats and other raw materials that are necessary for our products. Due to climate change, we may also be subjected to decreased availability of water, deteriorated quality of water or less favorable pricing for water, which could adversely impact our manufacturing and distribution operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="X8DDR0"&gt;North Dakota, Wisconsin, South Dakota, Minnesota, and Iowa are among &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/191084/top-10-us-states-by-production-value-of-oats/"&gt;the top US producers of oats&lt;/a&gt; — so events like the August 2020 derecho may screw up your oat milk. It &lt;a href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/money/agriculture/2020/10/09/usda-iowa-acres-farmers-unable-harvest-grow-more-than-third-850-000-corn/5937329002/"&gt;destroyed 850,000 acres of crops&lt;/a&gt; in Iowa alone. Derechos are fairly normal in the plains, but the August 2020 one was &lt;a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2020-extreme-weather-climate-change-hurricane-derecho-wildfire"&gt;notable for its scale and destruction&lt;/a&gt;. It’s possible that climate change will make storms like it more likely — one scientist &lt;a href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/2020/09/10/think-2020-disasters-wild-experts-see-worse-future-iowa-derecho-climate-change-hurricanes-wildfires/3458296001/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Des Moines Register&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that “I strongly believe we’re going to look back in 10 years, certainly 20 and definitely 50 and say, ‘Wow, 2020 was a crazy year, but I miss it.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xk6puN"&gt;Happy investing!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392621/oatly-climate-change-monoculture-risk-factors-ipo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392621/oatly-climate-change-monoculture-risk-factors-ipo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T17:30:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T17:30:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Geico data breach exposed customers’ driver’s license numbers for more than a month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mVs4RlT8KKH6tit5hicbZgi5nSQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69152165/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nqwRlQ"&gt;Insurance company Geico suffered a data breach earlier this year that exposed customers’ driver’s license numbers for more than a month, according to a &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22455630/DL3_IndNoticeLttr_CA_Redacted.pdf"&gt;data breach notice&lt;/a&gt; filed with the attorney general of California. First reported by &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Geico says in the notice that it has fixed the security issue that led to the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="69ydfQ"&gt;“We recently determined that between January 21, 2021 and March 1, 2021, fraudsters used information about you – which they acquired elsewhere – to obtain unauthorized access to your driver’s license number through the online sales system on our website,” the notice reads. “We have reason to believe that this information could be used to fraudulently apply for unemployment benefits in your name.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jkL7OZ"&gt;The notice does not indicate how many customers may have been affected or whether the breach was confined to California. But &lt;a href="https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/databreach/reporting"&gt;California law states&lt;/a&gt; that “any person or business that is required to issue a security breach notification to more than 500 California residents as a result of a single breach” must submit a copy of the notice to the attorney general’s office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqY5se"&gt;State unemployment offices have been inundated with claims over the past year, with millions of people unemployed due to the coronavirus pandemic. Some &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/economy/washington-halts-unemployment-payments-for-two-days-after-finding-1-6-million-in-fraudulent-claims-amid-coronavirus-pandemic/"&gt;states reported a sharp rise in fraudulent claims&lt;/a&gt; last spring, which were discovered when people began receiving notifications about unemployment benefits for which they never applied. Most US states require identification such as a driver’s license to file for unemployment benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KbPih"&gt;Geico did not immediately reply to requests for comment from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Monday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392566/geico-data-breach-exposed-customer-drivers-license-numbers-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392566/geico-data-breach-exposed-customer-drivers-license-numbers-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T17:23:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T17:23:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Genesis’ first electric car is way less exciting than its concept EVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O-dl29J8lpTKhvcdhod0Ko9Hq-I=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69152115/2276_ElectrifiedGenesisG80.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Genesis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="elOzdB"&gt;Genesis, Hyundai’s luxury brand, has &lt;a href="https://www.genesisnewsusa.com/en-us/releases/217"&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; its first all-electric car. It’s called the Electrified G80 because, well, Genesis took the existing G80 sedan and is refitting it to run on electricity. The carmaker claims it will travel about 427 kilometers (roughly 265 miles) on a full battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4MVWxv"&gt;It’s a very straightforward idea that pales in comparison to some of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/23/11294762/genesis-new-york-concept-car-announced-new-york-auto-show-2016"&gt;truly exciting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/28/17174294/genesis-essentia-is-an-electric-gt-with-an-awesomely-retro-futuristic-bubble-roof"&gt;concept cars&lt;/a&gt; Genesis has shown off &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a35983440/genesis-x-concept-revealed/"&gt;over the years&lt;/a&gt;, many of which are purported to be electric. Basically none of those progressive styling choices and daring ideas are coming across in the Electrified G80. It’s also not mold-breaking like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"&gt;Hyundai’s Ioniq 5&lt;/a&gt; sedan or Kia’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357654/kia-ev6-revealed-specs-photos-electric-car-release-date"&gt;EV6&lt;/a&gt;, both of which are built on the parent company’s new e-GMP electric vehicle platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ixpmty"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10455081"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E2MHzY"&gt;That’s obviously by design, as Genesis will try to sell customers on something that looks and feels more familiar. And the Electrified G80 will borrow a &lt;em&gt;bit&lt;/em&gt; from the e-GMP — namely, the high-voltage tech that allows for fast recharging as well as two-way charging, meaning the G80 will be able to power all sorts of electric appliances. But it’s unclear what other work Genesis put into the rest of the G80’s electric underpinnings, as the company has said it’s saving the full e-GMP platform for its future electric SUVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wdqOPu"&gt;Genesis’ first electric production sedan was debuted at Auto Shanghai 2021, and it will be sold in China, but Genesis says the electric sedan is also coming to North America. The car will be all-wheel drive and can make a 0-to-60mph run in under five seconds, and there are plenty of luxury touches, like a road noise-cancellation feature and a camera-aided adaptive suspension. But Genesis didn’t otherwise share any specifications, pricing, or release dates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9bSAQ"&gt;Fitting an electric motor and battery in a car designed to run on an internal combustion engine may be cost-effective for the automaker up front, but it naturally leads to compromises that you wouldn’t have to make if you created an EV from the ground up. Genesis has teased at some big ideas in the past with its electric concepts, but the luxury brand is clearly not going to try to realize them with the Electrified G80. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392557/genesis-electrified-g80-ev-electric-sedan-auto-shanghai-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392557/genesis-electrified-g80-ev-electric-sedan-auto-shanghai-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T17:16:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T17:16:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube halts ads on James Charles videos over messages with minors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9XIjo_YaKrU2xRPgqM89Td-yVPk=/185x0:2128x1295/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69152041/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_4.55.05_PM_1.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xxeRhK"&gt;YouTube has stopped running ads on James Charles’ channel after the creator was accused of sending sexual messages to minors. Charles apologized on April 1st and acknowledged the accusations. YouTube now says that Charles has violated its “creator responsibility policy,” resulting in the temporary demonetization of his channel. &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/james-charles-demonetized-youtube-temporarily-sexting-minors-scandal-2021-4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insider &lt;/em&gt;first reported&lt;/a&gt; the action and YouTube verified the report with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The company didn’t clarify how long Charles’ channel would be demonetized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYUGdc"&gt;The policy is essentially a catchall that YouTube uses to crack down on creators when their behavior leads to widespread negative attention, even if they haven’t explicitly violated YouTube’s rules. Charles is one of YouTube’s biggest creators with 25.5 million subscribers, putting him just above Eminem and Katy Perry. His behaviors cast a negative light on a platform that’s already been combating issues of child safety, resulting in the temporary suspension of advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="evl1SB"&gt;Charles addresses two of the allegations against him in his apology video and says these people had claimed they were 18 or over. “As an adult it is my job and my responsibility to verify who I’m talking to, and therefore there is no one to blame for this other than myself,” he says in this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YAtoF7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GsjwRp8_lWA?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=640&amp;amp;start=640" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QkTdni"&gt;YouTube has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22351945/youtube-demonetize-david-dobrik-vlog-squad-sexual-assault-allegations"&gt;previously applied this rule&lt;/a&gt; to David Dobrik after a former member of his Vlog Squad was accused of rape, as well as Shane Dawson &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308288/shane-dawson-youtube-suspends-monetization-channels-blackface-older-videos"&gt;who published&lt;/a&gt; racist, anti-Semitic, and other offensive content, which gained widespread attention.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392588/youtube-james-charles-demonetization-sexting-minors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392588/youtube-james-charles-demonetization-sexting-minors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T16:40:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T16:40:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>There are a lot of dog poop robots in the season 2 trailer for Netflix’s Love, Death and Robots</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zWOsDpe8I4Ygu0SbOanvu4HwoWM=/0x116:3266x2293/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151760/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_12.51.47_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vvctlg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love, Death and Robots&lt;/em&gt; is heading back to Netflix for “Volume 2” on May 14th, according to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1384220323218825224"&gt;a new trailer&lt;/a&gt; the company released today. The science fiction anthology series originally debuted in 2019 and was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/10/18660052/love-death-and-robots-second-season-netflix-director"&gt;renewed for more episodes&lt;/a&gt; that same year. Now, Netflix is showing off a new bundle of episodes and teasing more for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9dYNUs"&gt;The joy of a good animation anthology is the grab bag quality of it — experiencing a variety of stories, made in a variety of different styles. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/14/18225087/love-death-robots-netflix-trailer-first-look-david-fincher-tim-miller-animation-anthology-nsfw"&gt;The original trailer for &lt;em&gt;Love, Death and Robots&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;played up the frenetic, over-stimulating feeling that sometimes gets associated with “the future,” but it seems like Volume 2 is taking a different tack, focusing on the drama and gravity of these new episodes’ stories and scoring the trailer with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MVnSFj6XQZY"&gt;a track from the horror film &lt;em&gt;Hereditary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6KEwZg"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gj2iCJkp6Ko?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bKutZn"&gt;If last season was any indication, there will naturally be some misses mixed in with the hits, but this seems to be an intriguing collection of episodes. The episodes will explore all kinds of wild things like alien space whales, stop-motion Christmas, a giant foot, and that aforementioned dog poop robot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5fcGWD"&gt;A notable unknown is if Netflix will continue &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18277634/netflix-love-death-robots-different-episode-orders-anthology-show"&gt;A/B testing the series&lt;/a&gt;, showing the episodes in different orders to see which get the most clicks. The company tested four different episode orders with the first season, something it would never have admitted if it wasn’t initially accused of targeting based on viewers’ sexual orientation. The specific claim about Netflix taking sexuality into account was denied by the company and never independently verified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vzNaO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love, Death and Robots &lt;/em&gt;Volume 2 will premiere on May 14th. Netflix says a third volume will arrive some time in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hE0gTI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ScnTmF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392424/netflix-love-death-robots-season-two-trailer-dog-poop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392424/netflix-love-death-robots-season-two-trailer-dog-poop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T16:03:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T16:03:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s latest foldable phone perk is free dessert</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4R5C2YZGCrWt_kyEZiJrMgt-NrI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151573/vpavic_200907_4181_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z8Zago"&gt;Samsung is giving owners of its foldable phones some free dessert. Specifically, an order of “Chef Daniel Boulud’s signature &lt;a href="https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/daniel-bouluds-madeleines"&gt;Madeleines&lt;/a&gt; and Canelé,” designed by the chef exclusively for &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-premier/benefits/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Premier program&lt;/a&gt;, which offers Galazy Z Fold and Flip owners free perks in exchange for having bought the luxury-styled phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1ppMS"&gt;The new perk is being offered in partnership with the Michelin Guide through Boulud’s restaurant, &lt;a href="https://www.danielnyc.com/cuisine"&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; (which itself has two Michelin stars). Samsung’s announcement claims that the dessert in question is valued at $75, which seems like a lot for French pastries, but if you already own a Galaxy foldable, the price tag isn’t something you’ll need to worry about, given that it’s free. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IGpu-z0mcw0De16eOEqspIujx1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22455352/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_3.36.35_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fgGlFt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Who doesn’t like free French pastries?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QSDy62"&gt;The company has been offering additional perks for foldable owners through its Galaxy Z Premier program since it relaunched the service alongside last year’s Galaxy Z Fold 2. And Samsung has since been adding bonus offers for the owners of its most expensive phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ltk2TI"&gt;In addition to the free snacks (which will take three to four weeks for delivery), Samsung is offering a free year of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ffounderscard.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F19%2F22392343%2Fsamsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FoundersCard&lt;/a&gt; membership, letting owners join a “community of over 50,000 entrepreneurs and business executives who receive unprecedented benefits and networking opportunities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iB8A3H"&gt;The Galaxy Z Premier program already includes a free six-month trial of LinkedIn’s Premium Career service, a free round of golf through ClubLife, and six months of Obé Fitness. Samsung is also promising that it’ll have “new partners and benefits” to announce in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392343/samsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392343/samsung-galaxy-z-premier-program-new-perks-madeleines-canele-free-dessert-founderscard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T15:27:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T15:27:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nextdoor will alert users if it thinks they’re about to post something racist</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SBlStyNIzCSO8KVEMOYQ7GFN22Y=/220x0:1828x1072/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151295/Anti_racism_blog_header_NEW_2048x1072.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nextdoor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OONU7q"&gt;Nextdoor &lt;a href="https://blog.nextdoor.com/2021/04/19/nextdoor-launches-anti-racism-notification-to-prevent-discriminatory-language/"&gt;is introducing a new anti-racism notification&lt;/a&gt;, which asks users to reconsider posting content if the app thinks it may be offensive. As with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20871894/nextdoors-kindness-reminder-mean-comments-community-guidelines"&gt;its previous Kindness Reminder&lt;/a&gt;, if a user tries to post something with words or phrases Nextdoor thinks may be objectionable, it will give them the option to edit the post before it actually goes live. The users can, however, ignore the warning and post it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WvzcR49VvEHe5NApZYOoLi4DQuY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22455207/Anti_racism_blog_header_NEW_2048x1072.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nextdoor&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The notification users may receive if they try to post something containing the phrases “all lives matter,” “blue lives matter,” etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LwnUGs"&gt;In the blog post announcing the anti-racism notification, Nextdoor says that its similar Kindness Reminder has reduced “incivil content” by 30 percent. It’s hard to say whether this new feature will be as effective. The example that Nextdoor shows — someone responds to a Black Lives Matter post by saying “all lives matter,” then decides that they’d actually like to hear the person out after seeing the anti-racism notification — doesn’t really seem to match up with real-life behavior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ISYH1a"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yLUWsZp5Ug?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hqIQBs"&gt;Nextdoor is probably aware of this. In its &lt;a href="https://help.nextdoor.com/s/article/About-the-anti-racism-notification?language=en_US"&gt;support page for the feature&lt;/a&gt;, the company says that it’s mostly aiming to make sure people are aware that they could be violating the social network’s discrimination policy — according to the announcement blog post, comments about blue lives matter, all lives matter, or white lives matter are already regulated on Nextdoor. While the new notification may not change many people’s minds, hopefully it can at least reduce some of the bad behavior on the platform, making it a safer place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Dnti1s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inside Nextdoor’s ‘Karen problem’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21283993/nextdoor-app-racism-community-moderation-guidance-protests"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392304/nextdoor-anti-racism-notification-community-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392304/nextdoor-anti-racism-notification-community-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-19T15:26:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T15:26:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sen. Tammy Duckworth on hate crimes, racism, and environmental justice  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Senators Schumer, Kaine And Duckworth Address Media At The Capitol" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zy1NKL96-VXQpcVORBH-3Prm0no=/0x0:6533x4355/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151291/1286220992.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sen. Tammy Duckworth (D-IL) talks to reporters during a news conference at the U.S. Capitol on November 17, 2020 in Washington, DC. | Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;‘There are structures that are racist in our society.’&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="o3GeFT"&gt;Senator Tammy Duckworth (D-IL) has been tackling racism on multiple fronts recently, particularly against Asian Americans. A bill aimed at curbing anti-Asian hate crimes during the pandemic finally &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/14/us/senate-anti-asian-american-hate-crimes.html"&gt;picked up bipartisan support&lt;/a&gt; last week, which Senator Mazie Hirono (D-HI) sponsored and Duckworth supported. And following criticism from Duckworth and Hirono on a lack of Asian American and Pacific Islanders (AAPI) in his cabinet, President Joe Biden last week &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/14/president-biden-announces-erika-l-moritsugu-as-deputy-assistant-to-the-president-and-asian-american-and-pacific-islander-senior-liaison/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that Erika Moritsugu would step into the role of deputy assistant to the president and Asian American and Pacific Islander senior liaison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RO4Uhq"&gt;In March, Duckworth released a memoir detailing her childhood as a biracial kid growing up in Southeast Asia and Hawaii. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; talked with Duckworth about how those experiences inform her work now, and how she’s navigating her role during a time of dramatic reckoning with racism in America. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIs1rt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been lightly edited for length and clarity. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgBvth"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As an Asian American woman, I’m still reeling from the murders in Atlanta last month, and what feels like a steady stream of attacks against people who look like me and my elders. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmaEYb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s it like for you to see the recent rise in violence against Asian Americans, particularly against Asian American women? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OiYtoE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’ve always known that Asian women were targeted.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dxkp5C"&gt;This is something I have been bringing to my colleagues’ attention: the fact that, yes, we have a &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/anti-asian-hate-crimes-increased-nearly-150-2020-mostly-n-n1260264"&gt;150 percent rise&lt;/a&gt; in reported hate crimes against Asian Americans last year alone, about &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/there-were-3-800-anti-asian-racist-incidents-mostly-against-n1261257"&gt;3,800&lt;/a&gt;. Those were just the ones that were reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IR1ivc"&gt;Almost two-thirds of those were against Asian women. And so it’s really affecting how I go about doing what we’re doing. Mazie Hirono and I, along with Senator Richard Blumenthal , are moving forward with this anti Asian racism bill. But one of the things that is going to be an amendment to it is the fact that we need to recognize that, how we classify a crime as being race motivated is really not accurate. So for example, a lot of crimes against AAPIs are listed as robberies or muggings. But if your motivation for who you choose to be your victim for the robbery that you’re about to conduct is based on racism, like you’re choosing Asian American women in particular, or you’re choosing elderly Asian American women like my 80-year-old mom, then that should be reported as a hate crime, not as a mugging or a burglary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAufCD"&gt;And so for me, watching what has happened this past year... I’ve always known that Asian women were targeted, but to have what little data we have clearly point out that two-thirds of those crimes are directly targeting Asian women really crystallized for me what I have always known instinctively. It bothers me a lot because my mom is very independent and she goes out and she drives and she goes shopping, and I know that she is a potential target, and I worry about her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R4I4A3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have similar worries about my parents. Thank you for sharing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="do3iLB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve also supported the Black Lives Matter movement and have &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.military.com/daily-news/2021/04/14/sen-duckworth-calls-doj-probe-of-brazenly-violent-police-treatment-of-black-army-officer.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asked the DOJ to probe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; into the police treatment of Army Second Lieutenant Caron Nazario, who is Black and Hispanic and was pepper sprayed while in uniform during a traffic stop in Virginia. Can you talk with me about why those issues are important to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ns9JGQ"&gt;We shouldn’t be fighting each other over the one slice of diversity pie. I’m tired of the Black community being pitted against the Latinx community, being pitted against the Asian community. We should all have a seat at the table. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="tfMTEu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We should all have a seat at the table.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ixrSjh"&gt;I tried to learn to be a good ally this past summer in the Black Lives Matter movement, and I learned a lot actually from my own staff members. So I hope that transfers over into my work now as a senator, trying to be each other’s allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsU5DX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You confronted the White House about a lack of AAPI representation in the president’s Cabinet. Why is that a problem? What do you see as the consequences of excluding Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IOKqd8"&gt;I’ve been working with the Biden administration for a long time — like for six months —  setting forward names of well-qualified Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders to be considered for the top Cabinet posts. And I voted for every nominee they put forward. I voted for every single one, whether they were white, Black, Native American, Latinx. Time and time again I was told that there was going to be a Cabinet-level AAPI nominee. And then we had 15 Cabinet secretaries nominated and not a single one of them were AAPI. And there were well-qualified AAPI candidates who were not even interviewed. That was very frustrating to me, and it led to a conversation where a member of the White House team basically said, “Well you have Kamala, that should be enough.” I was incredibly offended, and I said wait a minute, you would never say, “We have a white male president, that should be enough. We shouldn’t need any more white male Cabinet secretary nominees.” You wouldn’t say that to the Black Caucus. You wouldn’t say that to the Latinx caucus. Why would you say that to Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="VhqPde"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I was incredibly offended.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IY34vC"&gt;It’s important to have representation because government needs to look like the people that it represents. This is the first time in 20 years that we do not have a single Cabinet secretary in either a Republican or a Democratic administration that is AAPI. That’s not good for the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ltn7se"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In your memoir, you describe how being biracial shaped your experiences growing up in Southeast Asia. And you write about how America’s history of segregation and racism might even have influenced your American dad’s decision not to return to the US sooner — since his marriage to your mom, who is Thai Chinese, would have been illegal in some states when they met in the 1960s. How have all those experiences shaped your work today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6hk5wO"&gt;Well, if you read my memoir you know that there are themes of both prejudice and racism, but then there’s also structural racism that existed. My parents’ marriage would not have been deemed legal when they met. So there are structures that are racist in our society — even if we maybe never thought of them as racist — and that really affected how I look at the work that I do today. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FX5WfU4abUwjQGYGTl22E8PEnj8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22454752/9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tammy Duckworth’s office&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Duckworth’s new memoir describes her experience growing up biracial. Her father was born in the US and met her mother in Thailand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LFZDsB"&gt;For example with environmental justice, we continue to grant permits for polluting industries on a one-off basis without looking at them cumulatively. So you have Black and brown communities exposed to far greater amounts of pollutants because that’s where we’ve always put the petcoke industry, now we’re going to put the ethylene oxide industry, and then we’re going to do manganese recycling there. And it just keeps going into the same communities because the structure of how we do permitting doesn’t look at cumulative effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="uLm46m"&gt;So when I started the Environmental Justice Caucus with Senator Tom Carper and Senator Cory Booker, I understood instinctively that there are systems in place that are inherently unequal, and that we have to lift up communities of color to an equal footing, and then make an investment across the board. It’s not that we’re going to say “Okay, we’re going to give a wealthy white suburb $50,000 and we’re going to also give a poor Black suburb $50,000. That’s equal, right?” Well, no — because of history and how things have been, one is not on an equal footing. So I think it really does speak to what I’m trying to do today and how I approach my job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oRXVbL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfEcfJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22392050/senator-tammy-duckworth-racism-anti-asian-hate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22392050/senator-tammy-duckworth-racism-anti-asian-hate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
