<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-25T16:40:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T16:40:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T16:40:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android 101: how to organize your homescreen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/me8Y6AW5VInxaipnalsWFxPioeo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775715/jbareham_171013_2050_0271.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8IxcRR"&gt;If you’ve had an Android phone for any length of time, it’s easy to get used to living with, well, chaos. If you’re anything like me, you’re constantly adding new apps, deciding they’re okay but not great, adding another, and so on. Then, a few months later, as you’re scrolling through your app drawer, you’re surprised to see several apps that you forgot about and perhaps don’t even remember what they’re used for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kXzBSB"&gt;In a very short time, it can become a mess. And if you’re really an app enthusiast, it can start taking up more space than you can spare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5VFyLn"&gt;There are essentially two steps to making sense of all of those Android apps: find a way to organize them (and there are a variety of ways, depending on what you’re comfortable with) and periodically remove all of the extra apps that you’ve accumulated and no longer use. Here are a few tips to help you do both. If you’re new to Android, this may help you stay organized from day one; if you’re an experienced user, you might pick up a few tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Vk7gF"&gt;As you go through these suggestions, keep in mind that not all Android interfaces are the same. This how-to was created using a Pixel 3 XL running Android 12 beta, so your interface may be slightly different, depending on the model of your phone and which Android version you’re running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="22tYBt"&gt;Get organized&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="ykPApH"&gt;At the most basic (and anyone who’s had an Android phone for more than a week or two can skip down a bit), you can just use the app drawer, which is accessed either by swiping up from the bottom of the phone or (if you’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495830/android-11-multitasking-pane-recent-apps-screenshots-google-how-to"&gt;kept the navigation buttons&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of the screen) by pressing on the apps icon at the bottom center of your display. Place the apps you use the most on one or more of your homescreens by long-pressing and dragging them out of the app drawer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oGE9WH"&gt;The app drawer is (thankfully) organized in alphabetical order, with your last-used apps on top. Swipe up to go through the apps or type the name of the app in the search bar at the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uZNO2u"&gt;However, once you start accumulating apps, you may want to save some time by creating a more structured system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ir3HCC"&gt;Fill the favorites tray&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Hc1pEL"&gt;You can quickly access your most-used apps by putting them in the Favorites Tray, the bottom row of apps that is just above the search field and is always available, no matter which homescreen you’ve swiped to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cgfetL"&gt;The tray is already filled with apps? No problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="THuLEV"&gt;Long-press on an app you no longer need to keep in the favorites tray. Move it to another place on the homepage, or move it up until you see the Remove and Uninstall choices at top of the screen. Choose one and move the app there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WHDuPB"&gt;Long-press on an app from the homescreen or from the app drawer, and move it into the tray.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wkbM0E"&gt;Create folders on your homescreen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="7G7dor"&gt;A good way to organize your apps is to use folders. For example, you can put all of your music and podcast apps into a folder called “Listen,” or all your social media apps into a folder called “Social.” It’s simple to create a folder. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Folders on Android screen" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x97Gh4YLGVM276SGa3knTqrF3nA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15633403/org_making_a_folder.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s easy to create a folder by dropping one app onto another.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ROCl84"&gt;Put the first two apps you want to include on your homescreen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hF6cmX"&gt;Long-press one and move it on top of another. This will create a new folder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CSUGF0"&gt;Give the folder a name: tap on the folder, tap on the name just below the apps (if Android hasn’t supplied a name, it will probably say “Edit Name”), and type in your new name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="60JqcA"&gt;You can add more apps to the folder by long-pressing on other apps and moving them into the folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5SQu3V"&gt;Remove an app from a folder by reversing that process: long-press on the app and move it from the folder to the homepage. If you only had two apps in the folder, the folder will disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vQn7c1"&gt;Get rid of unused apps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="z3fpk9"&gt;Sometimes when I install a new app, I’ll know immediately that it’s not for me, and I uninstall it then and there. More often, unfortunately, I’ll try out an app, decide that I may want to use it sometime in the future, and I leave it there. Where it sits. For months. Or years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQKqJ6"&gt;Once you start accumulating apps, it’s incredibly easy to forget about the ones that you no longer need. But allowing old apps to remain on your phone may not be as harmless as it seems. Not only are they taking up useful storage space, but they may be unnecessarily collecting data (assuming you gave them the permission to). And if they’re working in the background, they could be draining your battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAuEdK"&gt;As a result, it doesn’t hurt to check out what apps you haven’t used recently and remove them from your phone. There are several ways to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Y9QtxN"&gt;Use the app drawer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vbk11K"&gt;Yes, this is the obvious one, but it has to be said. Spend a little time cleaning out your app drawer: open it up, and see what’s in there. You may be surprised by what you’ve forgotten and what you may no longer need. Anything you don’t need, swipe up to uninstall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ACQ762"&gt;Visit the Play Store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sxUhPV"&gt;It’s not as simple as going to your App Drawer or as efficient as Files by Google, but if you happen to be in the Play Store and want to get rid of a few unnecessary apps in order to install some new ones, there’s a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In the Play Store, you can look for updates in “Manage apps &amp;amp;amp; devices”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WHTJoakRnCCS91zg9nRuXZRDXFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805097/Screenshot_20210825_131516.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Play Store, you can look for updates in “Manage apps &amp;amp; devices”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Do a sweep of your installed apps and uninstall any you no longer use." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xvGbBCu_C7HOuPNK_9gX0i20e8A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805099/Screenshot_20210825_131606.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do a sweep of your installed apps and uninstall any you no longer use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ACElsq"&gt;Once in the Play Store, tap on your personal icon in the upper right corner and choose “Manage apps &amp;amp; devices.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZCX6Fq"&gt;If you want to see which apps need to be updated, look for “Updates available” and tap on “See details.” You can also just tap on “Update all” if that’s what you want to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rqesAE"&gt;Otherwise, tap on the “Manage” tab at the top of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JORHTY"&gt;You’ll see a list of your installed apps. You can click on the listing to see what the latest update did, or if you want to uninstall any, tap the check box on the right of each entry and then on the trash-can icon that has appeared on top. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="V8EVqr"&gt;If you want to see a list of your uninstalled apps, tap on the “Installed” label at the top of the screen and select “Not installed.” This can be handy if you accidentally delete an app and then later think, “I shouldn’t have done that,” or you suddenly remember an app that you’d like to use again. Use the check box to the right of each entry to reinstall any app. (If the app has been removed from the Play Store, it won’t be in this list.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Check your “Not installed” apps for any you want to re-install." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y6wcxJUul7nQvciQJecta_IOJSg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805177/Screenshot_20210825_132116.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check your “Not installed” apps for any you want to reinstall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can sort your app list in a variety of ways to check which can be removed." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VssM--QqX9to-OEq3AfEaH97omU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805178/Screenshot_20210825_132209.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can sort your app list in a variety of ways to check which can be removed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OIx6TA"&gt;Tap on the parallel lines to the right and you’ll be able to sort according to name, most used, least used, recently updated, or size. This can be very handy if you’re running out of space and want to figure out which apps to get rid of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DIR7DQ"&gt;Other tabs in the “Manage” section includes “Updates available” and “Games.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7xRSY7"&gt;Try Files by Google&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TpUZQu"&gt;Files by Google is a surprisingly handy app that, among other things, helps you get rid of unneeded files that are taking up space. If you decide to install Files, this is how you can use it to get rid of unused apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Files by Google lets you delete unused apps." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mdhwGSfoXCrZ8LL-RBIfgPO6mqU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805291/Screenshot_20210825_143239.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Files by Google lets you delete unused or too-big apps to save space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="As with Google Play, you can sort the app list in several ways." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sH6yJ1BwtkH5vYoc_T7b2r6AcM4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805292/Screenshot_20210825_143329.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As with Google Play, you can sort the app list in several ways.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="owSpI2"&gt;If it’s not already selected, tap on the “Clean” icon on the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7Zg2qC"&gt;Scroll down until you find the section labeled “Delete unused apps.” Tap on “Select apps.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZDr6In"&gt;You can see how much space each app is taking up and the date it was last used. By tapping on the parallel lines on the upper right, you can sort the list by oldest &amp;gt; newest, newest &amp;gt; oldest, largest &amp;gt; smallest, smallest &amp;gt; largest, or alphabetically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hMWhP5"&gt;Tap on the circle on the right of each app to select any you want to uninstall, and then tap on the bottom “Uninstall” button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oKKhVA"&gt;Use another app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="c8hTDM"&gt;There are a variety of Android apps available in the Play Store besides Files by Google that can help. To begin with, there are other file managers that can make it easier to track and administer the contents of your phone, such as &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.alphainventor.filemanager"&gt;File Manager Plus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mi.android.globalFileexplorer"&gt;File Manager: free and easily&lt;/a&gt;. (There are, in fact, several apps called “File Manager” in the Play Store.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYxQid"&gt;Some create overlays to help you organize your homescreen. &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mobeedom.android.jinaFS"&gt;Jina&lt;/a&gt;, for example, lets you create a sidebar that pulls out from the side of your screen and gives you a compact list view of all your apps. &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.farmerbb.taskbar"&gt;Taskbar&lt;/a&gt; puts a configurable Windows-like start menu on your display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ndvnhO"&gt;If you want even more control over your Android environment, there are launchers such as &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.teslacoilsw.launcher"&gt;Nova&lt;/a&gt; that allow you to more thoroughly customize your app drawer and homescreen with icons, animations, and different layouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NwzLW8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 25th, 2021, 4:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on March 6th, 2019 and has been updated to reflect changes in Android and its apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2QQX7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22641251/android-how-to-organize-home-screen-pixel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22641251/android-how-to-organize-home-screen-pixel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T16:27:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T16:27:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>The biggest trailers and announcements from Gamescom Opening Night Live</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G3ssurBJVIKElA09sFjRuHNmPq4=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775628/LEGO_Star_Wars_The_Skywalker_Saga___Young_Anakin_1846026126849c5bc957.42486138.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6xFbIN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638193/xbox-gamescom-2021-news-trailers-flight-sim-forza"&gt;Xbox kicked off Gamescom a little early&lt;/a&gt;, but the show got its proper start with Opening Night Live hosted — as always — by Geoff Keighley. It was a lengthy event clocking in at a hefty two hours, but there was a lot on show, from surprising crossovers to big names like &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="75iSvX"&gt;If you weren’t able catch the event, here’s all the biggest announcements and best trailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BtCt9Q"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wz8Vw5tOf5M?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BCJZZV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641590/midnight-suns-marvel-tactics-rpg-xcom-firaxis-trailer-release-date-gamescom"&gt;Firaxis is making a Marvel game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="W9beTj"&gt;One of the biggest surprises was news that &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; developer Firaxis is dabbling in the Marvel universe with &lt;em&gt;Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt;. It’s described as a tactical RPG — surprise, surprise — and will include a brand-new customizable superhero designed specifically for the game. The studio will show off a gameplay trailer on September 1st, and the game itself is expected to launch next March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rzVipt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PkqgCYxHSOk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bU3Rj9"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22637945/halo-infinite-release-date-launch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; gets a release date&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller"&gt;a special edition console&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="M1hol2"&gt;This one actually leaked out a bit before the show, but it’s big news nonetheless: &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; is finally launching on December 8th. The game was originally expected to launch last year, serving as a big showcase for the Xbox Series X, but those plans were delayed in part due to the pandemic. The new trailer, meanwhile, focuses on the story for the game’s multiplayer component. And while the game will be out this year, it’ll be missing a few pieces; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634448/halo-infinite-co-op-campaign-forge-delay-launch"&gt;namely campaign co-op and the creative Forge mode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7U7te"&gt;Oh, and if you still need an Xbox Series X to play it on, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller"&gt;Microsoft is making a special edition console and controller just for &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nYBuSGnMrHwe2BGguc4SCT5lFJk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805413/HZN_FW_DATE_CLEAN_1920x1080.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="QjpxSR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22602306/horizon-forbidden-west-playstation-delay-2022-february"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt; is delayed to 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="aCCxoE"&gt;One of PlayStation’s biggest exclusives &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22602306/horizon-forbidden-west-playstation-delay-2022-february"&gt;has been delayed&lt;/a&gt;, with Sony confirming that &lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West &lt;/em&gt;will now be coming to the PS4 and PS5 on February 22nd, 2022. There’s some good news, at least: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641595/horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-update-ps5-1-53"&gt;the original game just got a 60fps patch for PS5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DyPcQn"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fTZdCYKkzUc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7xb8AA"&gt;A whole lot of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; (and Lego)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="yyYpwM"&gt;Perhaps the most adorable trailer was for &lt;em&gt;The Skywalker Saga&lt;/em&gt;, the latest &lt;em&gt;Lego Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; game, which covers all nine of the main films. It looks cute and extensive — and is dropping next spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sas27t"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dVvgR3e1Fbk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IMmgBF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22405201"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt; comes to... &lt;em&gt;Super Monkey Ball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4jnL0u"&gt;The upcoming &lt;em&gt;Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania&lt;/em&gt; is becoming something akin to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros.,&lt;/em&gt; adding all kinds of unexpected characters to its roster. Previously that included &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22631024/yakuza-kazuma-kiryu-super-monkey-ball-banana-mania"&gt;Kiryu from &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and now Sega has announced that &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;’s Morgana will be a DLC character as well. &lt;em&gt;Banana Mania &lt;/em&gt;is out on October 5th, but Morgana won’t arrive until November 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3zy5z7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgjzDJA1o1E?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IVgT9n"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22404676"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saints Row&lt;/em&gt; gets a reboot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="i94Ipa"&gt;Open-world action series &lt;em&gt;Saints Row&lt;/em&gt; is getting rebooted with a new game due out next year. It’s called simply &lt;em&gt;Saints Row&lt;/em&gt;, and based on what we’ve seen, it looks just as wild as its predecessors. The game is slated to come to a huge range of platforms (PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X / S, and PC) when it’s out on February 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ilyiWi"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jNcnsjlo-kM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6IWgas"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jett&lt;/em&gt; is launching in October&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ETC3RA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jett&lt;/em&gt;, the long-awaited follow-up to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/24/11297534/superbrothers-sword-and-sworcery-retrospective"&gt;early iPhone hit &lt;em&gt;Superbrothers: Sword &amp;amp; Sworcery EP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, finally has a release date. The game will be out on October 5th — and it looks gorgeous in the latest trailer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Zu4Wc7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1C8y7X5aXOc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HyXB2m"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22404697"&gt;Amazon’s &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt; is getting an open beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="IaZFjG"&gt;Amazon’s MMO &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt; has been getting a surprising amount of positive feedback based on its closed beta. And soon the game will be much more accessible: Amazon announced that an open beta will kick off on September 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mUU9Jt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-usmP3hjK8k?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MTBRQc"&gt;Another look at &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding: Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="mIlJMr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/12/22573731/death-stranding-directors-cut-hideo-kojima-missions-name-debate"&gt;It may not really be a director’s cut&lt;/a&gt;, but the enhanced version of &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; still looks interesting, expanding on some of the ideas from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20941606/death-stranding-review-ps4-hideo-kojima"&gt;Hideo Kojima’s 2019 hit&lt;/a&gt; while adding next-gen improvements. The latest trailer gets into the nitty-gritty of what’s new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VrBhsj"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EtZWVTTyFNU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="XxsSLu"&gt;A glimpse at &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qpTULN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631315/call-of-duty-vanguard-release-date-trailer-sledgehammer-ps5-xbox"&gt;Sledgehammer officially revealed &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; last week&lt;/a&gt;, and today the studio showed off a good chunk of gameplay to give viewers a taste of its more grounded WWII action. You can watch all nine minutes of it above. &lt;em&gt;Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; is slated to launch on November 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="o94LSQ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_RfrrEF1VLo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ge7sDp"&gt;April joins the cast of &lt;em&gt;Shredder’s Revenge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dANIQa"&gt;The delightfully retro &lt;em&gt;Shredder’s Revenge&lt;/em&gt; looks to channel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323160/tmnt-shredders-revenge-trailer-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-game"&gt;classic arcade-era Ninja Turtles beat ‘em ups&lt;/a&gt;. And at Gamescom, a new character was revealed: joining the four turtles is April O’Neil. The game is due on the Switch and PC next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kMYpcW"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6uM7CQGZ6rE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kvRw6G"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cult of the Lamb&lt;/em&gt; looks wild&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CfXDfV"&gt;Look, I’m just going to let the official description do all of the work here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="5equbu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cult of the Lamb&lt;/em&gt; casts players in the role of a possessed lamb saved from annihilation by an ominous stranger, and must repay their debt by building a loyal following in his name. Start your own cult in a land of false prophets, venturing out into diverse and mysterious regions to build a loyal community of woodland worshippers and spread your Word to become the one true cult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Q0K138"&gt;It’s expected to launch in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P5zPWk"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FaRbQHlegaM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xX0kHK"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;DokeV&lt;/em&gt; looks amazing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="O3m3hM"&gt;I’m not entirely sure what &lt;em&gt;DokeV&lt;/em&gt; actually is, but the debut trailer is incredible, with a great sense of style and gameplay that spans genres, from skateboarding to monster battling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="I9Z6xc"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fmNL7L2IRbA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vehaIG"&gt;Martial arts game &lt;em&gt;Sifu&lt;/em&gt; is out in February&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="8T6n26"&gt;One of the more intriguing upcoming action games is &lt;em&gt;Sifu&lt;/em&gt;, which looks to channel a classic martial arts movie, only in interactive form. And now it has a release date: February 22nd, 2022. It’ll be out on PlayStation and PC, via the Epic Games Store.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22640993/gamescom-opening-night-live-2021-trailers-halo-call-of-duty-marvel-xbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22640993/gamescom-opening-night-live-2021-trailers-halo-call-of-duty-marvel-xbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T16:12:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T16:12:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Panasonic’s wearable gaming speaker will literally blow your mind, if I’m seeing this image right</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_rkQbRaN8f0wdKNHAQeXIZJhf50=/1x0:2200x1466/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775592/panasonic_sc_gn01_wearable_immersive_gaming_speaker_wigss_2200.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aC4Msz"&gt;Panasonic knows that gamers want to be blown away. But maybe not quite this literally? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sKLHvr"&gt;That looks a little painful. So does this: &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="I’m not sure I’d want a dragon breathing fire directly into my ear? " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WAeMHSvtGdoKttVidzM0U11G-Mw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805328/GN01_CUT06_210728.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m not sure I’d want a dragon breathing fire directly into my ear? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ofbVoa"&gt;But what do you expect from a product called the SoundSlayer? It had &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; slay or my money back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLR5H0"&gt;And because gamers like acronyms, you should know that the SoundSlayer WIGSS (Wearable Immersive Gaming Speaker System) will come with True MAGESS (Majestic Augmented Gaming Environment Sound System) when it arrives this October for $199.99. Wigs and mages? Not quite, because Panasonic snuck in that extra “S”! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MmmBEv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“feel enveloped by sound in all directions”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkXyH2"&gt;Panasonic promises its four full-range speakers will create a ”360-degree pocket of sound around the head” so players “feel enveloped by sound in all directions,” and it comes with a pair of built-in noise-canceling microphones for communication. It’s also got a mode tuned for &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV Online&lt;/em&gt;, Panasonic says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAODS3"&gt;In all seriousness, this might be a great idea — many gamers don’t have true rear speakers for quality surround sound, opting for the virtual surround you can get from headphones or a soundbar instead. We’d have to try it to be sure. But know that the “W” in “WIGSS” doesn’t stand for Wireless: this is one neckband speaker you’ll be plugging into your console and PC with a physical USB-A cable and / or audio cable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LRbOek"&gt;If the design reminds you of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/29/4783132/the-amazing-products-of-weird-sony"&gt;Weird Sony&lt;/a&gt;, you’re half-right: Sony introduced &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-SRSWS1-Wearable-Speaker-System/dp/B081GFKGML?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its own (wireless) wearable speaker system&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 and brought it to the US in 2019. It costs the same price but only has two speakers for virtual surround, with a quoted seven hours of battery life. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/4/17311570/bose-soundwear-companion-review-neck-speaker-bluetooth"&gt;We also enjoyed Bose’s neckband speaker&lt;/a&gt;, though it comes in at $300. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDFjVB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C81NIu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/8/25/22641563/panasonic-soundslayer-wigss-wireless-gaming-speaker-sc-gn01-price-release-date-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/8/25/22641563/panasonic-soundslayer-wigss-wireless-gaming-speaker-sc-gn01-price-release-date-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T15:53:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T15:53:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft wants Chrome OS users running Office web apps, not Android apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Lenovo Flex 5 Chromebook" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/al3rSVSfPhJpB70z5akvXY2Nwys=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775503/mchin_210727_4682_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4yZrWg"&gt;Starting September 18th, Microsoft will end support for the Office and Outlook Android apps on Chrome OS and start pushing Chromebook users to its web apps instead, according to &lt;a href="https://www.aboutchromebooks.com/news/microsoft-ending-chromebook-support-for-office-android-apps-in-september/"&gt;a statement it gave &lt;em&gt;About Chromebooks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As recently as July 31st, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210731012201/https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/how-to-install-and-run-microsoft-office-on-a-chromebook-32f14a23-2c1a-4579-b973-d4b1d78561ad"&gt;Microsoft’s support documents&lt;/a&gt; recommended installing the Android versions of Office, Outlook, OneNote, and OneDrive, but &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/how-to-install-and-run-microsoft-office-on-a-chromebook-32f14a23-2c1a-4579-b973-d4b1d78561ad"&gt;now those documents say&lt;/a&gt; that the apps are unsupported for Chrome OS users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkzoaY"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;About Chromebooks&lt;/em&gt;’ Kevin Tofel points out, though, the move to web apps makes the offline situation for Office users more complicated. While certain Office web apps, &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/using-outlook-web-app-offline-3214839c-0604-4162-8a97-6856b4c27b36"&gt;like Outlook&lt;/a&gt;, have a dedicated offline mode, Tofel reports not being able to open existing documents using Microsoft’s progressive web app for Chrome OS while offline. While Chrome OS &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/2481498?hl=en#zippy=%2Cupdate-your-document-or-edits-will-not-be-automatically-saved"&gt;does offer&lt;/a&gt; some offline editing capabilities for Office files natively, it doesn’t offer the real Office experience &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/can-i-work-offline-3cdc0690-7332-4d4b-8884-ba2a353a42d8#ID0EAABAAA=Android"&gt;like the Android apps did&lt;/a&gt; while disconnected from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CHBELl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;For the most part, the web version of Office does the job&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RTZkpf"&gt;Microsoft wasn’t immediately available to answer questions about what offline functionality the Office web experience for Chrome OS offered, or whether it would be making improvements before the September switchover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k7vytv"&gt;For those who are always online, though, the move from Android to web app may not make too much of a difference. For the most part, the web version of Office offers many of the features that you’d need for basic word processing, spreadsheeting, and presentation making — though I’m certainly not one to judge those who don’t prefer web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="phvYCv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft says the web apps will let Chrome OS users access “additional and premium features.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IoN2in"&gt;Microsoft’s statement to &lt;em&gt;About Chromebooks &lt;/em&gt;doesn’t really go into why the company is making the change, though it does say that it will let Chrome OS users access “additional and premium features.” (It’s worth noting that Chrome OS users could already use the Office web apps if they chose.) Tofel reports that this change doesn’t mean that Office for Android will be going away for phone users. We’ve reached out to Microsoft to confirm this and will let you know if we hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXLwJo"&gt;There is some irony in Microsoft pushing Chromebook users away from using Android apps on their laptops, as Windows 11 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548428/microsoft-windows-11-android-apps-support-amazon-store"&gt;will have support for running Android apps&lt;/a&gt;. That said, Android apps’ functionality on Chrome OS has long been criticized, and even Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/13/21219075/google-chrome-os-android-apps-webs-chromebook-replacing-progressive-twitter-youtube-tv"&gt;has replaced some of its own apps with PWAs&lt;/a&gt; on the platform. Most PWAs are only useful while you have a live internet connection, but that’s not really the case for apps like Office. Hopefully, Chromebook users will get the option for an offline experience back after the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641535/microsoft-chrome-os-office-365-android-app-replacement-pwa-web-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641535/microsoft-chrome-os-office-365-android-app-replacement-pwa-web-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T15:39:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T15:39:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s New World MMO is getting an open beta on September 9th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vTzlm565KVMDrIxkbunk6ajORu4=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775452/ss_45594186d0784865980a9c8b009675b5c5e8c0ac.1920x1080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon Games’ &lt;/em&gt;New World&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SFYIp3"&gt;Amazon’s upcoming PC MMO, &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;, is getting an open beta ahead of its September 28th release date, Amazon Games announced at Gamescom’s Opening Night Live on Wednesday. The open beta will take place from September 9th to September 12th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06vVzB"&gt;The public beta will give players a chance to try out the game before its official launch just a few weeks later on September 28th, even if it’s only for a few days. In addition to the open beta, Amazon Games also revealed a new trailer for the upcoming MMO showing off more of the supernatural world of &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHgUxe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;’s open beta follows a &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-07-28-theres-a-real-buzz-about-amazons-new-world-mmo"&gt;well-received closed beta&lt;/a&gt; and should give more people a chance to try out the game before it officially launches. The game, like others from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21510190/amazon-crucible-canceled-game-studios-closed-beta"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/4/2/17187836/amazon-game-studios-breakaway-status-canceled"&gt;Games&lt;/a&gt;, has had a troubled history — a recent delay to September 28th from August 31st &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609898/new-world-mmo-amazon-delayed-release-launch-date"&gt;was the game’s fourth&lt;/a&gt; — but the open beta could be an opportunity for Amazon to iron out as many issues as possible before &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;’s release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vxMQqJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New World &lt;/em&gt;is available for preorder now &lt;a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/game-editions"&gt;starting at $39.99&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike some other MMOs, the game won’t have a monthly subscription. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22640656/amazon-games-new-world-mmo-open-beta-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22640656/amazon-games-new-world-mmo-open-beta-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T15:31:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T15:31:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Horizon Forbidden West delayed to February 18th, 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4pt0UTq6oUWX6A5oZISDDpf2e5M=/600x0:3840x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775414/Horizon_Forbidden_West_Dive_Logo_TM_LegalLine.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SZtVtz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;, the sequel to &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;, has officially been delayed until February 18th, 2022, according to &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/08/25/horizon-forbidden-west-arrives-on-february-18-2022/"&gt;a PlayStation blog post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Guerrilla/status/1430611047308677123"&gt;Guerrilla Games&lt;/a&gt;. The game was expected to release near the end of 2021, but it was clear that timeframe was more of a target than a fixed date — the &lt;a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/horizon-forbidden-west/"&gt;game’s page on PlayStation.com&lt;/a&gt; had its release date listed as “to be confirmed,” and PlayStation Studio head Hermen Hulst &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/06/02/hermen-hulst-qa-whats-next-for-playstation-studios/#sf246401757"&gt;said during an interview&lt;/a&gt; that the developers thought they were “on track” for a holiday 2021 release but couldn’t be sure. He also said that part of the uncertainty was due to developers’ access to motion-capture equipment and actors during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0AcLt"&gt;Sony’s PlayStation Studios, which &lt;em&gt;Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;’s developer Guerrilla Games is a part of, is currently involved in making a lot of games: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432601/sony-playstation-studios-ps5-games-25-new-ip-interview"&gt;more than 25, according to Hulst&lt;/a&gt;. Other titles included in this initiative have been delayed as well, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297059/gran-turismo-7-ps5-playstation-5-release-date-delay-2022"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;the next &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465232/god-of-war-ragnorok-ps5-ps4-delay-2022"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xd5Rvg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Horizon Forbidden West is coming to PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 on 18 February 2022! Pre-orders will begin next week, on 2 September. Are you ready to continue Aloy's journey?&lt;a href="https://t.co/aMD8LIWbf8"&gt;https://t.co/aMD8LIWbf8&lt;/a&gt; ​&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HorizonForbiddenWest?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HorizonForbiddenWest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/bRP3kToGji"&gt;pic.twitter.com/bRP3kToGji&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Guerrilla (@Guerrilla) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Guerrilla/status/1430611047308677123?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y5g7oE"&gt;Companies outside of PlayStation Studios have also had some of their PS5-exclusives delayed — Arkane’s &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; (a timed exclusive for the platform) has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373588/bethesda-deathloop-ps5-delayed-date"&gt;pushed back to September 2021&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Ghostwire: Tokyo &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373588/bethesda-deathloop-ps5-delayed-date"&gt;also won’t see a release until 2022&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uxb56J"&gt;At this point, the PlayStation 5 still has relatively few games that really take advantage of its next-gen hardware, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523093/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-ps5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408468/returnal-ps5-dualsense-3d-audio"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the delays stacking up, it seems like this may still be the case come holiday season of this year. How much that will affect console sales, though, is hard to tell — Sony has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597784/sony-ps5-playstation-5-sales"&gt;already sold 10 million PS5s&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re still hard to get due to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368552/global-chip-shortage-end-tsmc-samsung-ps5-supply-demand-intel"&gt;ongoing silicon shortage&lt;/a&gt;. The good news for those who haven’t managed to snag a PS5 yet is that, when it comes out in February, &lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22455008/horizon-forbidden-west-gameplay-ps5-sony-state-of-play"&gt;will be available on the PS4 as well&lt;/a&gt;. The studio says preorders will start on September 2nd and that more info will be coming next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mG5dUy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Horizon Zero Dawn’s newest update unlocks 60fps on PS5","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641595/horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-update-ps5-1-53"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22602306/horizon-forbidden-west-playstation-delay-2022-february"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22602306/horizon-forbidden-west-playstation-delay-2022-february</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T15:26:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T15:26:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Horizon Zero Dawn’s newest update unlocks 60fps on PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y_LTu3Pot32Uw2kUKTCGsfpXb6k=/53x0:794x494/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775391/horizon_zero_dawn_screenshot_01_pc_campaign_en_us_01jul20.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from &lt;/em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BqMBXA"&gt;Sony has released a new update for &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; enabling 60fps on PS5. The game was previously locked to 30fps on Sony’s newest console, so this update should help the game feel that much smoother. A &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague has confirmed that the update, 1.53, is available to download and install now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jBXQNH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XWgwFc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; is the latest game to get a 60fps boost on the PS5 — Sony has slowly been adding higher frame rates for some of its biggest PS4 hits since the PS5 was released. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22443868/the-last-of-us-part-2-ps5-patch-update-60fps"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt; got one in May&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260829/god-of-war-2018-ps5-patch-free-update-playstation"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; got one in February&lt;/a&gt;, and Sucker Punch &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SuckerPunchProd/status/1314641549406265346"&gt;added a 60fps option for &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that was available when the PS5 launched in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VaS4gc"&gt;Sony also announced that its sequel to &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22455008/horizon-forbidden-west-gameplay-ps5-sony-state-of-play"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, will be released on &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/08/25/horizon-forbidden-west-arrives-on-february-18-2022/"&gt;February 18th, 2022, on PS4 and PS5&lt;/a&gt;. Previously, the developers had been targeting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465232/god-of-war-ragnorok-ps5-ps4-delay-2022"&gt;a holiday 2021 launch&lt;/a&gt; for the game, but &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Jason Schreier reported in July that &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-30/playstation-video-game-horizon-forbidden-west-delayed-to-2022"&gt;the game had been delayed&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641595/horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-update-ps5-1-53"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641595/horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-update-ps5-1-53</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T14:53:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T14:53:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft announces $549 Halo-themed Xbox Series X console</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XSFySXKNyOOCoEu5SoDRDot3Mw8=/68x0:1049x654/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775214/xboxconsole.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="w5f8iS"&gt;Microsoft’s first custom &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-branded Xbox Series X console will arrive on November 15th. The $549.99 console includes dark metallic paneling, gold accents, and a star pattern to match the &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; universe. It even powers on and off with custom &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-themed sounds, and Microsoft has changed the top fan section of the Xbox Series X from a green color to blue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1mPWFy"&gt;The console bundle will also include a custom &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-branded controller that matches the console, and Microsoft says this will be a very limited edition that will be &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fxbox-series-x-halo-infinite-limited-edition-bundle%2F8rpm8t9ck0p6" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for preorder from Microsoft’s site today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JEG-q33AZBinDco78szkH34v1Ug=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805320/Halo_gamescom_Inline1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Halo-themed Xbox Series X console.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CmQ8q3"&gt;This is the first custom Xbox Series X console, but Microsoft has previously launched many custom Xbox consoles. A limited edition &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/17/17989078/taco-bell-xbox-one-x-console-contest-microsoft"&gt;Taco Bell Xbox&lt;/a&gt; included the famous ring when you powered on the console, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/20/16175552/xbox-one-s-minecraft-limited-edition-leak"&gt;special &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; Xbox One S&lt;/a&gt; looked like it had come straight out of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8FfrqQ"&gt;Alongside a custom &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-branded console, Microsoft is also launching a &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-themed Xbox Elite 2 controller. It’s designed to match the metallic green found on Master Chief’s armor, and it even has a custom case and D-pad. The Halo Infinite Limited Edition Elite Series 2 controller will also be available on November 15th, priced at $199.99. Preorders for the &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-themed Xbox Elite 2 controller &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fxbox-elite-wireless-controller-series-2-halo-infinite-limited-edition%2F90z8k1dbj8zd" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;begin today at Microsoft’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yKOHWIeryOdvCGxIl4XYtZxim2s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805322/Halo_gamescom_Inline2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Halo-themed Xbox Elite 2 controller.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T14:45:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T14:45:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Persona 5’s Morgana is coming to Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BIjoygDu2PZv4V8qAVBIYKMjCWE=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775194/morganamonkeyball.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morgana can’t catch a break&lt;/em&gt; | Sega&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IK7v0b"&gt;In an effort to build up excitement for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22530302/super-monkey-ball-banana-mania-remaster-three-games"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that’s releasing on October 5th, 2021, Sega has been plucking characters from its roster of games, past and present. Not only will &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22631024/yakuza-kazuma-kiryu-super-monkey-ball-banana-mania"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Kazuma Kiryu&lt;/a&gt; serve as an unlockable character, Morgana from &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt; will appear as post-launch content on November 2nd, except it’ll cost $4.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUWu4f"&gt;Morgana plays a pivotal role in &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;, serving as the gutsy feline sidekick to the protagonist and your rag-tag team of Phantom Thieves. In &lt;em&gt;Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania&lt;/em&gt;, Morgana will collect chests instead of bananas. Sadly, there’s no mention of &lt;em&gt;Persona&lt;/em&gt;-themed stages or music mentioned in the press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s5FTon"&gt;Sega is really wringing out its IP to include characters that’ll appeal to as many people as possible. So far, Sega has confirmed that Beat from &lt;em&gt;Jet Set Radio &lt;/em&gt;and Sonic and Tails will join the squad of monkeys, along with the aforementioned Kiryu and Morgana. That’s a potent amount of fan service. But I’m not sold until we get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/6/20850674/yoot-saito-interview-seaman-sega-dreamcast-ai-20th-anniversary"&gt;Seaman&lt;/a&gt; in the game. Thankfully, Sega is promising that “more iconic additions” will be announced soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3A9whS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania&lt;/em&gt; will be available on October 5th, 2021 on all consoles for $39.99, or on Steam for $29.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tfgovd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641160/persona-5-morgana-super-monkey-ball-banana-mania-dlc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641160/persona-5-morgana-super-monkey-ball-banana-mania-dlc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-25T14:36:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-25T14:36:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Midnight Suns is a new Marvel tactics RPG from XCOM studio Firaxis</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lPl_rrKfK8lS9-yGU1J-f5WgDxk=/276x0:2298x1348/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69775155/Screen_Shot_2021_08_25_at_2.14.11_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XWtHmV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://midnightsuns.2k.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel’s Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a newly revealed tactical RPG from Firaxis Games that was just announced at Gamescom’s opening night event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UQJ6SS"&gt;The game is said to take place in the “darker side of the Marvel Universe,” and it will have players take on the role of a new hero, The Hunter (which Firaxis created with Marvel). In &lt;em&gt;Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt;, you’ll team up with classic heroes like Iron Man, Wolverine, Ghost Rider, Blade, Captain America, and Captain Marvel as part of the &lt;a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Midnight_Sons_(Earth-616)"&gt;Midnight Suns superhero team&lt;/a&gt; to battle a supernatural foe: Lilith. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lPFajmSOHyE2oNrbSJja4nOVxJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22805244/Screen_Shot_2021_08_25_at_2.16.46_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ob0KEX"&gt;There’s not much information on the actual gameplay yet — although, given Firaxis’ work on the rebooted &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; series and the fact that &lt;em&gt;Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt; will be a tactical RPG, it seems like players should expect some sort of superheroic spin on its &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; formula here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0nrHC"&gt;Fans won’t have to wait long for more information: a gameplay reveal is planned for September 1st, and &lt;em&gt;Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt; will be released on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X / S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, Steam, and the Epic Games Store in March 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jI7tR9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641590/midnight-suns-marvel-tactics-rpg-xcom-firaxis-trailer-release-date-gamescom"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641590/midnight-suns-marvel-tactics-rpg-xcom-firaxis-trailer-release-date-gamescom</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
