<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-30T13:25:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T13:25:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T13:25:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>The leader of Facebook’s stalled cryptocurrency project is leaving the company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YonDYUvPbrczzZXLjPCt1Gn0JIg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210622/VRG_ILLO_3512_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="srWKj5"&gt;Facebook cryptocurrency chief David Marcus announced today that he’s leaving the company. The former PayPal executive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/9/5794548/david-marcus-leaves-paypal-to-lead-facebook-messaging"&gt;joined Facebook in 2014 to run Messenge&lt;/a&gt;r but eventually took over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/18/18682290/facebook-libra-cryptocurrency-visa-mastercard-digital-currency-calibra-wallet-announce"&gt;plans to launch a new cryptocurrency and wallet&lt;/a&gt;, known at the time as Libra and Calibra, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="wDnHMv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Novi VP of product Stephane Kasriel will take over&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="37oVzI"&gt;After some pre-Meta &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270437/facebook-calibra-novi-rename-digital-wallet"&gt;name changes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734487/facebook-novi-digital-wallet-pilot-program-payments-diem-cryptocurrency"&gt;the digital wallet launched with a small pilot in October under the name Novi&lt;/a&gt; but only in two countries (the US and Guatemala) and support for a single form of crypto, the Paxos stablecoin. The currency that spurred so much ire from regulators and politicians around the world, now called Diem, has yet to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SETRW1"&gt;In posts &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/davidm/posts/10166264804120195"&gt;on his Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter, Marcus says, “While there’s still so much to do right on the heels of hitting an important milestone with Novi launching — and I remain as passionate as ever about the need for change in our payments and financial systems — my entrepreneurial DNA has been nudging me for too many mornings in a row to continue ignoring it.” He announced that Novi VP of product Stephane Kasriel, previously an early PayPal employee and the CEO of Upwork, will take over the leadership of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kuX005"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;While there’s still so much to do right on the heels of launching Novi — and I remain as passionate as ever about the need for change in our payments and financial systems — my entrepreneurial DNA has been nudging me for too many mornings in a row to continue ignoring it. (2/7)&lt;/p&gt;— David Marcus (@davidmarcus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1465740042215645194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="DFvdYY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"‘I don’t think you should launch Libra at all,’ congresswoman tells Facebook","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/17/20697803/facebook-libra-cryptocurrency-regulation-launch-david-marcus"},{"title":"Facebook’s cryptocurrency Libra, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/26/18716326/facebook-libra-cryptocurrency-blockchain-irs-starbucks"},{"title":"Zuckerberg claims it’s not about the money, while explaining how Libra will make money ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/23/20928995/mark-zuckerberg-congressional-testimony-facebook-libra-money-profit-cryptocurrency"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oPZpYc"&gt;Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/davidm/posts/10166264804120195?comment_id=10166264837945195"&gt;commented&lt;/a&gt; on the Facebook post, saying, “I’ve learned so much working with you and I’m so grateful for everything you’ve done for this place. We wouldn’t have taken such a big swing at Diem without your leadership and I’m grateful you’ve made Meta a place where we make those big bets. You’ve built a great team, and while I’ll miss working with you, I’m looking forward to working with Stephane to lead the team going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2YIsAw"&gt;As recently as October, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735171/facebook-novi-diem-libra-calibra-cryptocurrency-digital-wallet-zuckerberg-senate"&gt;politicians were openly calling&lt;/a&gt; for Facebook to drop its cryptocurrency plans. At that time, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1450447443250728962"&gt;Marcus said&lt;/a&gt;, “I do want to be clear that our support for Diem hasn’t changed and we intend to launch Novi with Diem once it receives regulatory approval and goes live. We care about interoperability and we want to do it right.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4T75Zw"&gt;What his departure means for the project overall is unclear, as well as how it fits in with Zuckerberg’s metaverse vision for the future. His departure also comes one day after fellow cryptocurrency proponent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808979/twitter-jack-dorsey-steps-back-platformer"&gt;Jack Dorsey stepped down from his position as the CEO of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It seems unlikely that either one will be done with Web3 projects any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0biIYv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I am so honored for the opportunity to lead the awesome &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/novi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@novi&lt;/a&gt; team, and look forward to continuing to build products and services that allow more access for people and businesses to the financial system and digital economy.&lt;/p&gt;— Stephane Kasriel (@skasriel) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/skasriel/status/1465747314371227650?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810220/facebook-crypto-david-marcus-novi-diem-meta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810220/facebook-crypto-david-marcus-novi-diem-meta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T13:17:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T13:17:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>This browser extension shows how many brands on Amazon are actually just Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vh5PpgA_XSN5jvuccGV-mEsk5qE=/132x0:1551x946/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210554/amazon_brand_detector_3200x1800_1_1682x946.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vZtTJO"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/11/29/introducing-amazon-brand-detector"&gt;new browser extension&lt;/a&gt; promises to show you which products in your Amazon search results are sold by brands that are either owned by or are exclusive to Amazon, giving you a better idea of who’s selling what you’re buying. It’s called Amazon Brand Detector, and it uses a list of Amazon brands created by &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;, along with filters and other techniques (&lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/10/14/how-we-analyzed-amazons-treatment-of-its-brands-in-search-results#identifying-amazons-brands-and-exclusives"&gt;detailed here&lt;/a&gt;) to detect and highlight products that are a part of Amazon’s Our Brands program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y1N2Pq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Markup &lt;/em&gt;created this extension after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727842/amazon-in-house-brands-search-rankings"&gt;its investigation&lt;/a&gt; into how Amazon ranks its in-house brands in search results and says the tool (available for &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/amazon-brand-detector/hjkifponoamdhhgdfodkbaabajhdgbob"&gt;Chrome-like browsers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/amazon-brands/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;) is designed to make searches more transparent. When we tested it, it obviously highlighted Amazon Basics and Essentials products, but it also drew attention to results that were otherwise indistinguishable from ones not affiliated with Amazon: a dog leash labeled as being made by Panykoo, socks by Teebulen, a sweater by Ofeefan. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8P9XUMfaDwzA-kYrKjw2pY_4jXk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051477/Screen_Shot_2021_11_29_at_17.00.46.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the products highlighted are obviously affiliated with Amazon, some less so.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M0Pi3x597KvZPS-HgxBiysyJdLQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051456/Screen_Shot_2021_11_29_at_15.05.13.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Markup&lt;em&gt; says the tool may miss some Amazon-sold products, and I found that to be true.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1UjEpS"&gt;While Amazon marked some of those results as “featured from our brands,” that wasn’t the case for all of them. That advisory text is also small and grey, making it easy to miss if you’re casually browsing (especially since there may not be any notice of the affiliation on the actual product page), and it didn’t show up on every result the tool highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eYGmHShLkrDm2I2xQk4z4kSqN94=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051406/Screen_Shot_2021_11_29_at_16.14.54.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Without the tool’s highlighting, it would be easy to miss the “featured from our brands” message on these socks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5fx8g9"&gt;Amazon isn’t necessarily shadowy about these brands: it &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=17728530011"&gt;has a page that lists&lt;/a&gt; its “private and select exclusive brands,” many of which have legit-sounding names: Happy Belly, Wag, Nature’s Wonder. Some are private labels owned by Amazon, where &lt;a href="https://sell.amazon.com/programs/our-brands"&gt;some are “curated selections”&lt;/a&gt; sold exclusively on Amazon but not necessarily operated by the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJXSLV"&gt;Clicking through to the store pages, there’s a spectrum of Amazon branding. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/59E20785-D133-47A4-B2C8-2FF309221217"&gt;Basic Care&lt;/a&gt; has a large Amazon logo right at the top, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/stoneandbeam"&gt;Stone and Beam&lt;/a&gt; notes that its products are “exclusively on Amazon,” and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/rivet"&gt;Rivet’s&lt;/a&gt; product names are prefixed with “Amazon Brand.” Meanwhile, Amazon’s branding doesn’t appear on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/E55B6B6E-F82E-4622-B1A0-9186F2853B45"&gt;the Goodthreads page&lt;/a&gt; unless you watch to the end of a video titled “Fall 2021.” Most Goodthreads products will have the phrase “An Amazon Brand” somewhere on the page, but it’s not always prominent. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UCAsI-QHd1nhc2EAalDoRMD9S8U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051488/Screen_Shot_2021_11_29_at_17.06.40.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon has a page that lists some, but not all, of its brands, with links to their store pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JW3YSM"&gt;The page also doesn’t contain all of Amazon’s brands — there are letter-soup brand names highlighted by Amazon Brand Detector like Weeso and other brands like Daily Ritual, which showed up often in search results. Despite “An Amazon brand” being listed as a feature of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Daily-Ritual-Womens-Mock-Neck-Sweater/dp/B07DKF5P5D?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Daily Ritual sweater&lt;/a&gt; that showed up in my search results, that brand isn’t on Amazon’s “Our Brands” page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rL2M8O"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/amazons-new-competitive-advantage-putting-its-own-products-first"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, traditional grocery stores have long had their own private-label brands, though stores like Kroger and even Walmart are operating on a somewhat smaller scale — items are more hidden on the third page of search results than they are on the bottom level of a shelf. And, as an advisor to third-party Amazon sellers told &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt;, Amazon’s brands take up space in the coveted first page of search results that could go to other brands (some of which may have more positive reviews or higher sales numbers). Amazon denied favoring its brands in search results, though &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/10/14/amazon-puts-its-own-brands-first-above-better-rated-products"&gt;has an in-depth investigation&lt;/a&gt; into how the company weights its results.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mtv4M62OxcdEoVMVgxeLhepBoeQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23051499/Screen_Shot_2021_11_29_at_17.12.28.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowing which products are sold by Amazon may or many not affect your buying decision, but it’s still interesting to see the results.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SXJ1kY"&gt;For some customers, it may not matter who’s selling the products, as long as they’re decent. But if you’re the kind of person who likes to know where the things you buy are coming from (or who doesn’t want to give Amazon more money than necessary), it could be worth installing the Amazon Brand Detector extension. At the very least, the results may end up being interesting — there were a few times during testing when I went, “Huh... I wouldn’t have guessed that was from Amazon.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EjYQrr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; says the extension “does not collect any data” and that it should be compatible with other extensions, such as ones that look for fake product reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22808835/amazon-brand-detector-browser-extension-markup-basics-essentials-private-labels"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22808835/amazon-brand-detector-browser-extension-markup-basics-essentials-private-labels</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T13:07:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T13:07:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Levels Health review: optimize your fitness with a $400 glucose tracker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2bgv3bDWKDTi93bUQawIf5tf110=/0x333:4000x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210526/20211026_132108.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The key to the Levels Health system is a device that constantly monitors glucose levels in your bloodstream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Real-time glucose tracking for fitness-based purposes is here, but it’ll cost you&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Eqexk9"&gt;“What is that thing on your shoulder?” has been the question I’ve been asked most frequently for the last month. Understandably so. For the last 30 days, just barely peeking out from under the sleeve of my T-shirts, there has been a big black sticker. It’s round, about two inches in diameter, and it looks like a high-end Band-Aid. But that sticker is just a cover. Under it is a smaller plastic disk, with a little thread that is actually sticking into my body and analyzing my ever-changing blood-sugar levels. It’s the closest I’ve ever been to cyborg status. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHsWK0"&gt;Levels Health is a new product and service — currently in late-stage beta but gettable by the public — designed to monitor your body’s glucose response to different stimuli, like exercise and stress and especially the foods you eat. It’s sort of like a Fitbit for your metabolic health, and it currently costs a hefty $400 for the one-month program. It’s aimed toward athletes and the health-conscious who are looking for everything from optimum performance to simply staying healthy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="63u9hx"&gt;Glucose monitoring devices like these are traditionally used by diabetics, who need to know their blood sugar levels and when to administer insulin or treat for low blood sugar. But Levels is marketing itself as a wellness product for anyone to use and isn’t making any diagnostic claims. “Levels is currently a general health and wellness program not intended to diagnose, manage, or treat any health conditions,” says Dr. Casey Means, the company’s co-founder and chief medical officer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wrNsTr"&gt;But let’s back up a little and talk about glucose itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvGNTO"&gt;You might think of glucose as the primary building block for energy inside your body. Your digestive process breaks down the foods you eat (especially the carbohydrates, but fats and proteins, too) and converts much of it into glucose, which it puts into your bloodstream. When that happens, your pancreas gets a signal to release insulin, which is a hormone that allows the cells in your body to take up the glucose and use it as energy (every cell in your body uses glucose).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X4D2p7"&gt;The problem is that there can be too much of a good thing. When there’s too much glucose in your blood, it sort of overwhelms your system. Your muscles can’t take it all up, and bad things start to happen. It may get stored in fat cells as triglycerides. It may damage your liver, brain, and other systems. Big doses of glucose can also cause your pancreas to make too much insulin, which can lead to something known as “insulin resistance,” where your cells start ignoring the insulin and take up less and less glucose over time, which means more and more glucose stays in your blood. This can lead to a whole host of medical problems, including type-2 diabetes, heart disease, obesity, and potentially things like cancer, Alzheimer’s, reproductive issues, fatigue, brain fog, and much more. According to &lt;a href="https://www.unc.edu/posts/2018/11/28/only-12-percent-of-american-adults-are-metabolically-healthy-carolina-study-finds/"&gt;a 2018 study from UNC at Chapel Hill&lt;/a&gt;, only about 12 percent of Americans are metabolically healthy, which is a frighteningly low number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mc1tFkFAWLjcA67j3-M506pGVIQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23032252/20211026_142234.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brent Rose for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The glucose monitor has a probe that inserts into your arm. It’s surprisingly painless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lmxyRE"&gt;This is all a fairly high-level breakdown. If you want to get into the nitty-gritty, Levels wrote what it calls its &lt;a href="https://www.levelshealth.com/blog/the-ultimate-guide-to-metabolic-fitness"&gt;Ultimate Guide to Metabolic Fitness&lt;/a&gt;, which is a fascinating read and goes into more detail than I can here. The TL;DR version is this: High spikes in your glucose levels are bad, but every body is different, and there isn’t a one-size-fits-all solution that works for humans. What causes a spike in me may not cause a spike in you. We may all respond differently to the same exact foods, exercise, or sleep routines, and while some rules of thumb may hold somewhat constant, the only way to know for sure is to experiment and track the results, which finally brings us back to the thingy on my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofvLJ5"&gt;The disk that’s stuck to me is a continuous glucose monitor (CGM). These products themselves aren’t super new, and Levels doesn’t actually make this one. Instead, it works with a product called the &lt;a href="https://www.freestyle.abbott/us-en/home.html"&gt;Freestyle Libre&lt;/a&gt;, made by Abbott. The gadget accounts for much of the cost of the Levels program. Each one lasts for 14 days, so you have to swap them halfway through. The disk-shaped sensor comes embedded in a larger, round plastic stamp. You try to find an out-of-the-way spot on the back of your arm, ideally in the little pocket between your triceps and deltoid, and you clean the area with an included alcohol pad. Then, you put the stamp on your arm and depress it until you hear a loud click. In that click, the device actually sticks you with a little pin, which is instantly withdrawn and replaced with a little, flexible, quarter-inch thread, which is about the thickness of a single bristle on a hairbrush. Levels promises that it’s completely painless, and indeed it was. I literally could not feel it at all, either during or after.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VB2-Pcoer66HRVFD-HmMtBLSl0k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23032257/20211026_132430.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brent Rose for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A plastic tool is used to mount the monitor to your arm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XzlJvs"&gt;Once you remove the plastic stamp, you’ve got this little white disk stuck to you. You slap the larger, black adhesive circle over it just to give it some added protection, and you’re good to go. It’s completely sweat-proof and waterproof (I ran, swam, surfed with it and never had any issues), and you’ll largely forget it’s there at all. The sensor logs a sample every minute and transfers all of the data over to your phone when you scan it. To do that, you simply touch the back of your phone to the sensor. It has an NFC radio, and it transfers all of the data points collected since your last scan over to the Levels app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9Stim"&gt;That app is where you spend most of your time. That’s where you log all of your food and exercise. You simply write in what you ate and when you ate it, or you can take a photo of it if that’s easier. You don’t need to be too specific (i.e., you’re not counting calories, ingredients, or macros); you just enter in enough information so you remember what you had. You can also log events like meditation, sex, or moments of acute stress. Whatever you want, really — you can see how your body responds. Levels recommends you keep your glucose levels between 70 and 110 mg/dL. The ADA says you can go up to 140 mg/dL, but once you cross the 140 line, you’re classified as “pre-diabetic,” so Levels wants you to stay well clear of that and in the “optimal” zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sqfVO3"&gt;The name of the game is avoiding glucose spikes and dips. The app shows you a graph of all your data points, and you want to see a nice, smooth curve after meals. Levels also rates each logged item from zero to 10 (with 10 being the best), so you can easily interpret your results. I logged nearly everything I ate and every minute of exercise for a month, and I was genuinely surprised by the way my body responded to certain things. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Whors0o-zO5pHW13LisL3lgQxzU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23052728/meal_impact_3up.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Brent Rose / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Levels app tells you exactly how each meal or activity impacted your glucose levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="I8PdTX"&gt;For instance, there’s this one protein bar that I’ve been eating for years that is high-protein and low carbohydrate, etc. I was shocked that it made my glucose spike aggressively. Levels gave it a 2. It turns out that my body doesn’t mind some sugar alcohols, but other types of sugar alcohols cause a strong reaction. Thankfully, my regular breakfast of eggs with salad and coffee came in at a 10, but if I added a bowl of oatmeal to it, my score dropped down to a 3. Chicken tenders were fine with a savory barbecue sauce, but if I switched to my favorite (a sweet one), it dropped all the way down to a 0. Damn. Potatoes seemed to be one of the worst offenders for causing me spikes, which was heartbreaking, but sweet potato fries were less bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6AzyX"&gt;One of the biggest takeaways for me was how I could mitigate the negative impact of one thing by adding something else. For example, instead of eating that protein bar that gave me a 2 by itself, if I ate it with some jerky and almonds, it got upgraded to a 6. Dinner would frequently cause me to spike, but dinner with a walk immediately afterward improved my numbers significantly because my muscles used up some of that excess glucose in my blood. A cocktail then going to bed was bad, but a cocktail then going to bed with someone else… not so bad! You’re also given a score for each day and week as a whole, from 0 to 100, with 100 being the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vuQuhq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Being active after a meal often mitigated the spike in glucose levels from the food&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VokyP0"&gt;Levels suggests you don’t make any changes during the first week, so you can see what happens with your normal habits. For weeks two and three, they suggest you start experimenting with different foods to see how your body responds to different things. For week four, it’s recommended that you try to implement your learnings and go for the lowest score possible. Everything you log takes about two hours before you can see your score (because your body doesn’t respond to food or exercise immediately), but then you can see everything in the app. Levels also emails you daily and weekly reports and, finally, one big report at the end of your one-month journey that has 14 pages of granular info broken down into easy-to-understand charts and graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WapVTK"&gt;While the device itself doesn’t hurt at all, it must be said that there are some pain points. For starters, Levels is currently using a two-app solution. You have to download the sensor’s app (called LibreLink) and set up an account on it; then, you tell that app to share info with the Levels app. Once everything is set up and linked, you don’t really need to deal with LibreLink again, but Levels acknowledges that the onboarding process isn’t ideal, and it’s working on a better solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N2KZ6D"&gt;A larger issue is that the sensor itself can only store eight hours’ worth of data points. That means that if you don’t remember to scan it right before you go to bed and again right when you wake up, then you’ll have some gaps in your data. Not ideal, especially if you’re one of those lucky people who actually gets eight-plus hours of sleep (tell me what it’s like?). Levels is working on compatibility with another continuous glucose monitor that has Bluetooth so it could constantly push updates to your phone in the background, but no word yet on if or when that option will be available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wLDyxn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The sensor can only hold eight hours worth of data, so you have to remember to sync it often with the app&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fYNJv3"&gt;Levels could go further in clarifying what your numbers mean, especially toward the beginning. Right now, the way the app is set up, you don’t get a ton of information or advice to go along with your data. The company has written a lot of blogs that help explain the ins and outs of the science behind this, but it would be nice if it were better integrated into the app and if there was more built-in coaching as you went. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDAHZT"&gt;Lastly, there’s the price. $400 for a month is steep. For that, you could buy a very solid multisport watch with GPS (or an Apple Watch) that would last you for years and track a ton of different metrics and activities. Of course, the data you get from Levels is unique in the pantheon of fitness trackers, but it would be easier to take the leap if the cost wasn’t so exorbitant. Its price certainly supports the argument that fitness tech really &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785163/digital-health-physical-activity-inequity"&gt;only benefits the wealthy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y38EkoX66U9S_-TBP64HxXObM04=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23032250/20211019_175926.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brent Rose for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An adhesive, waterproof sticker helps protect the monitor as you wear it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rNMDTv"&gt;Ultimately, I enjoyed my experience with Levels, and I can see it being a useful tool for athletes who want to learn how to fuel properly for their unique body chemistry and for people who have concerns about their metabolic fitness. I didn’t lose any weight in the month I did it, but that’s because glucose levels are just one part of the picture. Levels works with Apple Health and Google Fit to automatically import activities, but part of me thought it would be nice if it could integrate with a calorie tracking system like MyFitnessPal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hTgqNL"&gt;After some thought, though, I came around to believe that it might be best to take a month to simply learn how your body responds to different foods and activities and then integrate those learnings into your diet and exercise plan going forward. That’s something I’m already doing in the days since I took the tracker off. Where I used to just snack on an apple, now I’m more likely to pair it with some yogurt or cheese because I know it won’t spike my glucose as much, which will be better for my long-term health and may help prevent an energy crash a few hours later. That really is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="HabFgC"&gt;Levels is targeting a full launch either at the end of 2021 or the beginning of 2022. It’s currently in a semi-closed beta, and it has more than 100,000 people on the waiting list, but if you use &lt;a href="https://www.levelshealth.com/join?partner=THEVERGE"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;, you should be able to skip the line, and most people will get their tracker kit within two weeks of ordering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wooa9G"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Brent Rose for The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="PZhjwa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10894432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22794594/levels-health-glucose-fitness-tracker-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22794594/levels-health-glucose-fitness-tracker-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brent Rose</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T12:37:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T12:37:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>GTA Trilogy’s next big patch fixes spelling errors, rain, and CJ’s face covering the camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2NmW2lm8cm5KaFOoLOajYU16awU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210326/afa2de9642866521f4d2.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The patch apparently fixes some problems with rain.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Rockstar&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qkh7CF"&gt;Rockstar’s next Title Update for &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy – The Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; looks to address a huge list of issues with the buggy remasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jiLYjS"&gt;The game has had a rough launch, and many of the fixes appear to clean up some of the more meme-worthy problems with the games. A lot of the fixes are &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-trilogy-pours-rain-so-hard-it-s-nearly-unplayable-1848048162"&gt;about rain&lt;/a&gt;. Many spelling errors have apparently been fixed. I spotted two fixes for “a hole in the game world” in &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: Vice City – The Definitive Edition. &lt;/em&gt;There are also two fixes for CJ’s face obscuring the camera in &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas – The Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt;, which (sadly) may address the absolutely incredible bug &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/glassbottommeg/status/1459238099955838979"&gt;shown in this video&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MVZgMM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I've changed my mind, the GTA remasters are perfect.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(this is looking backwards while in first person, on the quadbike) &lt;a href="https://t.co/JEB0SC7y3V"&gt;pic.twitter.com/JEB0SC7y3V&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Megan Fox (   OUT NOW) (@glassbottommeg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/glassbottommeg/status/1459238099955838979?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NBnMPA"&gt;The patch also brings “stability improvements,” fixes some textures, and adds a cinematic camera mode. You can read the &lt;a href="https://support.rockstargames.com/articles/4411612846867/Grand-Theft-Auto-The-Trilogy-The-Definitive-Edition-Title-Update-Notes-1-03-PlayStation-5-PlayStation-4-Xbox-Series-X-S-Xbox-One-PC"&gt;full list of fixes for Title Update 1.03 on Rockstar’s website&lt;/a&gt;. Rockstar says the update is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarSupport/status/1465699042193657871"&gt;now available&lt;/a&gt; on PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X / S, Xbox One, and PC and that it will be available for the Nintendo Switch “in the coming days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pD1dlF"&gt;Rockstar &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791656/rockstar-gta-trilogy-remaster-mess-re-list-original-titles-pc"&gt;apologized for the rocky launch&lt;/a&gt; a little over a week after the game’s November 11th release date. “The updated versions of these classic games did not launch in a state that meets our own standards of quality, or the standards our fans have come to expect,” &lt;a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/393o373751k48k/a-note-from-the-rockstar-games-team-re-grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-th?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=o_social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=gta-trilogy_announcement_update-20211119"&gt;the company said&lt;/a&gt;. “We have ongoing plans to address the technical issues and to improve each game going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pchdrb"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mWXTxp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809948/gta-trilogy-patch-title-update-1-03-fixes-spelling-errors-rain-cjs-face"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809948/gta-trilogy-patch-title-update-1-03-fixes-spelling-errors-rain-cjs-face</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T12:35:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T12:35:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>BMW shows off its new XM hybrid concept vehicle </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AV-31RvvRb5yJGke7Hl_MUWdejk=/14x0:2264x1500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210312/P90445512_lowRes_bmw_concept_xm_11_21.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The BMW Concept XM  | BMW&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KaZadT"&gt;BMW has revealed a new concept plug-in hybrid electric vehicle, the first in its M class to get an electric motor, the company announced. The BMW XM will go into production at the company’s Spartanburg, South Carolina, plant beginning in late 2022, the company said in a &lt;a href="https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0357372EN/the-bmw-concept-xm-%E2%80%93-power-and-luxury-beyond-all-conventions"&gt;news release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4X7ZbH"&gt;The concept BMW XM has a V8 engine combined with an electric motor to provide 750 horsepower and 737 foot-pounds of torque. BMW spokesman Jay Hanson clarified in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that while the production version of the XM will have a V8 engine paired with a plug-in hybrid system, “horsepower and torque figures should be considered preliminary at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGD18Z"&gt;The company said the unusual front-end design, with two large nostril-shaped openings, shows off a new direction for its future luxury vehicles that includes an illuminated version of its black kidney grille. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oX2hkc32wfvlNDFPfIPrMUh0U48=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23052561/bmw_grille.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: BMW&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The grille of the BMW XM shows off a new front-end design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ogwfy"&gt;The interior features “vintage-look leather,” with a curved display that combines the instrument panel and infotainment display into a single design, Hanson said. BMW M CEO Franciscus van Meel said in a statement that the concept XM “represents a complete re-imagining of the high-performance vehicle segment.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A9IOOS-cQQDI7xMjej692QYouxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23052559/bmw_interior.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: BMW&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The interior of the BMW XM concept vehicle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hxg4cf"&gt;The company didn’t provide details about how much the vehicle will cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hNTItd"&gt;While the XM isn’t an all-electric vehicle, BMW is moving toward an electrified future: the company said earlier this year that it expects 50 percent of its new vehicles to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335807/bmw-i4-sedan-ev-m-performance-range-photos"&gt;fully electric by 2030&lt;/a&gt;. It’s developing all-electric versions of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/28/21345464/bmw-5-7-series-x1-electric-car-ev-plug-in"&gt;5 Series and 7 Series sedans&lt;/a&gt; and its X1 SUV. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21324114/bmw-ix3-electric-suv-range-specs-price-china-europe"&gt;the iX3 will only be available in Europe and China&lt;/a&gt;, not the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DXHaQZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArticleBody-InlineImage-106981867"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809724/bmw-new-xm-hybrid-concept-electric-vehicle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809724/bmw-new-xm-hybrid-concept-electric-vehicle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T12:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T12:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s genre slate for 2022 includes The Sandman and The Witcher: Blood Origin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E9nB8ADGffqZzfUIhKn9hguQ5eY=/209x0:892x455/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210274/Screen_Shot_2021_11_30_at_9.58.20_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8qIY2S"&gt;Netflix still has some big releases in store this year — including &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; and the second season of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; — but the streaming service is also looking forward to its 2022 lineup. Today, the company released its slate for genre shows and movies coming next year, and while we knew some of them (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/6/22765226/stranger-things-4-netflix-trailer-eleven-netflix-release-date"&gt;last month, Netflix revealed that &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things 4&lt;/em&gt; would be coming out next summer&lt;/a&gt;), there were also some new confirmations. Most notably, both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/25/22688895/netflix-sandman-video-neil-gaiman-comic-tudum-dream"&gt;the live-action adaptation of Neil Gaiman’s &lt;em&gt;The Sandman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565149/michelle-yeoh-netflix-the-witcher-blood-origin-sword-elves"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; spinoff &lt;em&gt;Blood Origin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will debut on the streaming service in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LTzJ28"&gt;Outside of those heavy hitters, there are also plenty of shows returning — &lt;em&gt;Alice in Borderland’s&lt;/em&gt; season 2, &lt;em&gt;Locke &amp;amp; Key&lt;/em&gt; season 3, &lt;em&gt;The Umbrella Academy&lt;/em&gt; season 3 — along with gaming adaptations, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22466235/netflix-the-cuphead-show-geeked-week-teaser-wayne-brady-king-dice"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cuphead Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21403849/netflix-resident-evil-tv-series-original-live-action-announcement"&gt;a live-action &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt; series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18650396/magic-the-gathering-directors-netflix-avengers-series-russo-brothers"&gt;an animated &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; show&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21303233/cyberpunk-2077-anime-edgerunners-netflix-studio-trigger-2022-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk: Edgerunners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the acclaimed Studio Trigger. Rounding out the selection are some horror titles, including vampire hunting romance &lt;em&gt;First Kill&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Midnight Club&lt;/em&gt;, the latest series from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683761/midnight-mass-review-netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Midnight Mass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21508362/haunting-of-bly-manor-review-netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haunting of Bly Manor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; creator Mike Flanagan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rwDj7A"&gt;Most of the releases don’t have specific dates attached to them yet, but here’s the full list of genre stories coming to Netflix in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cjmh8i"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Archive 81 &lt;/em&gt;(January 14th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YCkjRx"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;In From the Cold &lt;/em&gt;(January 28th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gRRoAN"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Raising Dion &lt;/em&gt;season 2 (February 1st)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NHOpa2"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Vikings: Valhalla &lt;/em&gt;(February 25th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6oOVca"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Alice in Borderland&lt;/em&gt; season 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WZfxOq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of Us Are Dead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zanbQ8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Army of the Dead: Lost Vegas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TIvE1a"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cuphead Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NUOsPL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk: Edgerunners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="67YTN6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;First Kill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FOGREX"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Locke &amp;amp; Key&lt;/em&gt; season 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EIV5BA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lLTMQp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Midnight Club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9cKM8n"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Foir2q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sandman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0qiPhr"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stranger Things 4 &lt;/em&gt;(summer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wt841l"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Umbrella Academy&lt;/em&gt; season 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T6rvYE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher: Blood Origin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809629/netflix-2022-genre-lineup-witcher-cyberpunk-stranger-things-sandman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809629/netflix-2022-genre-lineup-witcher-cyberpunk-stranger-things-sandman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T12:22:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T12:22:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Square Enix warns players that servers might struggle with FFXIV’s next big expansion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MZO-pTyN2Bf84tRVWu-D34l_JMI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70210241/FFXIV_PUB_DIGITAL_FANFESTIVAL_2021_13.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vaSn6Z"&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV Endwalker&lt;/em&gt; launching in early access this week and officially on December 7th, &lt;a href="https://na.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/topics/detail/1f70135439286fa66209cd21c10e73ebb986a6ee"&gt;Square Enix is warning players&lt;/a&gt; that they might face the longest log-in queues and wait times the game has ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ylbdrr"&gt;In a blog post, Square Enix stated that while it has optimized servers in anticipation of heavy traffic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22777216/global-chip-supply-chain-shortage-holidays-christmas-shopping"&gt;the global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; has prevented the addition of new servers that would help alleviate congestion problems. As such, players can expect to wait longer than normal to log into game servers, visit new &lt;em&gt;Endwalker&lt;/em&gt; specific areas, and experience instanced content-like duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLdsDi"&gt;Square Enix also offered tips that players can use to ensure their &lt;em&gt;Endwalker&lt;/em&gt; experience is the best it can be. If players are experiencing higher log-in queues for their home server, they can choose to temporarily play on another, less-crowded server within their data center. Also, since new character creation is disabled for congested worlds, Square Enix suggested players interested in making new characters create them now before the &lt;em&gt;Endwalker&lt;/em&gt; rush or during off-hours post-launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S8Oq8E"&gt;Interest in&lt;em&gt; Final Fantasy XIV &lt;/em&gt;reached an all-time high this summer, aided by an exodus of dissatisfied &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; players, popular streamers giving the MMO airtime, and &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/the-critically-acclaimed-mmorpg"&gt;a clever meme&lt;/a&gt; extolling the virtues of &lt;em&gt;FFXIV&lt;/em&gt;’s free trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zvnymG"&gt;Even with Square Enix beefing up their existing servers and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770249/final-fantasy-xiv-endwalker-expansion-delayed-two-weeks"&gt;delaying the game by two weeks&lt;/a&gt; to ensure stability, &lt;em&gt;Endwalker&lt;/em&gt; is shaping up to be the biggest launch in &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt; history.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809776/ff14-endwalker-square-enix-log-in-queues-extended-wait-times"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809776/ff14-endwalker-square-enix-log-in-queues-extended-wait-times</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T11:45:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T11:45:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk says Raptor engine production is a ‘disaster’ that puts SpaceX at risk of bankruptcy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="GERMANY-US-POLITICS-ELECTION-ECONOMY-TESLA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Ka-0U8FEprHWoRy6f5TPfBfCfI=/0x127:3678x2579/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70209996/1234651136.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by PATRICK PLEUL/POOL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m6e0X8"&gt;On Black Friday, SpaceX CEO Elon Musk sent an anxious email to his company’s employees, urging them to work over the weekend on SpaceX’s Raptor engine line and describing the production situation as a “crisis.” In the email, a copy of which was obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Musk argued that the company faces a “genuine risk of bankruptcy” if production doesn’t increase to support a high flight rate of the company’s new Starship rocket next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Ynuqw"&gt;The Raptor is SpaceX’s massive methane engine that will be used to propel the company’s next-generation launch system, called Starship. SpaceX plans to use Starship to take people to deep space, and in April, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387887/elon-musk-spacex-win-nasa-lunar-lander-contract-artemis"&gt;NASA awarded SpaceX a $2.9 billion contract&lt;/a&gt; to develop Starship as a lunar lander to transport astronauts to the Moon’s surface as early as 2025. SpaceX has been hard at work developing and testing Starship prototypes at the company’s test site in Boca Chica, Texas, though the company has yet to launch the vehicle to orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lz1hCU"&gt;SpaceX is currently hoping to conduct Starship’s first orbital launch in either January or February of 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=da3iF2Np51A"&gt;according to a presentation given by Musk to the National Academies of Sciences&lt;/a&gt; on November 17th. However, according to Musk’s email, SpaceX needs to launch Starship at least once every two weeks next year to keep the company afloat. And apparently, Raptor engine development isn’t on track at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MV7AoL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I will be on the Raptor line all night and through the weekend”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XcPkSE"&gt;In the email, first reported by &lt;a href="https://spaceexplored.com/2021/11/29/spacex-raptor-crisis/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;SpaceExplored&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/30/elon-musk-to-spacex-starships-raptor-engine-crisis-risks-bankruptcy.html"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, Musk claimed that after key senior management departed the company, SpaceX personnel looked deeper into issues surrounding Raptor production and found them to “be far more severe than was reported.” Two vice presidents, one of whom worked on Raptor engine development, recently left the company, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/22/elon-musks-spacex-leadership-shakes-up-as-two-vps-depart.html"&gt;CNBC reported this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iwiesf"&gt;“I was going to take this weekend off, as my first weekend off in a long time, but instead I will be on the Raptor line all night and through the weekend,” Musk wrote in the email. He also urged employees to come in for an “all hands on deck” situation unless they had critical family matters or could not “physically return to Hawthorne,” the location of SpaceX’s headquarters in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2jm4JO"&gt;While Starship will ultimately be used to transport people to deep space, Musk also stressed the vehicle’s role in launching the company’s next-generation Starlink satellites. Starlink is SpaceX’s ambitious initiative to launch a mega-constellation of nearly 12,000 satellites to provide broadband Internet coverage to users all over the Earth. So far, SpaceX has launched more than 1,800 Starlink satellites and is currently serving roughly 140,000 users in more than 20 countries, &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/spacexs-starlink-now-serves-140000-users"&gt;according to a presentation SpaceX gave to the Federal Communication Commission&lt;/a&gt; on November 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="dXG5Uq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“we need all hands on deck to recover from what is, quite frankly, a disaster”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RI5vmx"&gt;However, SpaceX has only launched the first version of its Starlink satellites, known as Version 1 or V1. Most of those satellites don’t have lasers allowing them to communicate with one another, though recent launches have included this capability. Eventually, SpaceX plans to launch its Version 2 or V2 satellites, which are much more massive and will include laser communication. And per his email, Musk claims that Starship is the only rocket that can launch these larger satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3RoONB"&gt;“Falcon has neither the volume *nor* the mass to orbit needed for satellite V2,” Musk wrote, adding that “Satellite V1 by itself is financially weak, whereas V2 is strong.” SpaceX filed an amendment with the FCC in August, proposing changes to its satellites with plans to launch them on Starship. In the email, Musk also noted that SpaceX will be ramping up production of its user dishes, which customers must buy in order to tap into the Starlink V2 satellites. Musk says the terminals will be useless unless the new satellites are ready to “handle the bandwidth demand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="asaEvA"&gt;It’s hard to know for sure if SpaceX is truly in dire straights. SpaceX did not respond to a request for a comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. But this isn’t the first time Musk has called on his employees to rally and work long hours or risk bankruptcy. In 2018, Musk claimed that his other company, Tesla, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/elon-musk-tesla-death-bleeding-cash-a7928b06-3aae-43d7-bdde-5b9c41ef298f.html"&gt;came “within single-digit weeks” of collapse&lt;/a&gt; over problems with the production of the Model 3. Since then, Tesla has rebounded and &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/10/25/investing/tesla-stock-trillion-dollar-market-cap/index.html"&gt;recently surpassed a $1 trillion valuation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tyOx6O"&gt;Read the entire email from Musk below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ydKGRZ"&gt;Unfortunately, the Raptor production crisis is much worse than it seemed a few weeks ago. As we have dug into the issues following exiting prior senior management, they have unfortunately turned out to be far more severe than was reported. There is no way to sugarcoat this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JExavu"&gt;I was going to take this weekend off, as my first weekend off in a long time, but instead I will be on the Raptor line all night and through the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p23ENW"&gt;Unless you have critical family matters or cannot physically return to Hawthorne, we need all hands on deck to recover from what is, quite frankly, a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDTumg"&gt;The consequences for SpaceX if we can’t get enough reliable Raptors made is that we then can’t fly Starship, which means we then can’t fly Starlink Satellite V2 (Falcon has neither the volume *nor* the mass to orbit needed for satellite V2). Satellite V1 by itself is financially weak, whereas V2 is strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qdL8ew"&gt;In addition, we are spooling up terminal production to several million units per year, which will consume massive capital, assuming that satellite V2 will be on orbit to handle the bandwidth demand. These terminals will be useless otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mVgli"&gt;What it comes down to is that we face genuine risk of bankruptcy if we cannot achieve a Starship flight rate of at least once every two weeks next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="huUjHh"&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tkI1gB"&gt;Elon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="qJhW4A"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809720/elon-musk-spacex-raptor-engine-crisis-bankruptcy-starship"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809720/elon-musk-spacex-raptor-engine-crisis-bankruptcy-starship</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T11:31:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T11:31:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter bans posting pictures of ‘private individuals’ against their wishes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SSFy60dTRIg5tnLlJ8TWAY0C1KM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70209925/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C51KuI"&gt;Twitter will now let private individuals request takedowns of pictures or videos featuring them. The company announced the change this morning, extending an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/7/18255238/twitter-report-tweets-personal-information-more-options-specific"&gt;existing ban&lt;/a&gt; on private information to cover media. It’s aimed at preventing harassment or invasions of privacy and includes exceptions for posts that are “shared in the public interest or add value to public discourse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shEQgN"&gt;“Sharing personal media, such as images or videos, can potentially violate a person’s privacy, and may lead to emotional or physical harm,” reads a &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/private-information-policy-update"&gt;Twitter Safety blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing the change. “The misuse of private media can affect everyone, but can have a disproportionate effect on women, activists, dissidents, and members of minority communities.” Twitter will evaluate complaints by the subject of a picture or video — or someone representing them — according to its larger &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/personal-information"&gt;private information policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XDaVdX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Sharing personal media, such as images or videos, can potentially violate a person’s privacy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="euuGXh"&gt;The rule potentially covers all “media of private individuals without the permission of the person(s) depicted,” but the blog post describes several scenarios where Twitter wouldn’t remove that media. As implied, it’s not applicable to people who are public figures, a category that typically includes politicians, celebrities, and other well-known people. Twitter will also take other context into consideration, as well as existing rules like a ban on nonconsensual sexual imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WoAT9b"&gt;“We recognize that there are instances where account holders may share images or videos of private individuals in an effort to help someone involved in a crisis situation, such as in the aftermath of a violent event, or as part of a newsworthy event due to public interest value, and this might outweigh the safety risks to a person,” the post says. It may also leave media online if it’s being covered by traditional news outlets. And it will consider “if a particular image and the accompanying tweet text adds value to the public discourse, is being shared in public interest, or is relevant to the community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="igW3zq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Beginning today, we will not allow the sharing of private media, such as images or videos of private individuals without their consent. Publishing people's private info is also prohibited under the policy, as is threatening or incentivizing others to do so.&lt;a href="https://t.co/7EXvXdwegG"&gt;https://t.co/7EXvXdwegG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Safety (@TwitterSafety) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1465683094581792771?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oAX0Dx"&gt;The goal is to remove pictures or videos that are fueling online harassment campaigns, although, in practice, its implementation will likely depend on moderators judging the nuance of a particular situation. It’s unclear, for instance, how Twitter might have ruled on a 2020 Twitter video depicting a white woman calling police on a Black man — an incident that was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/14/nyregion/central-park-amy-cooper-christian-racism.html"&gt;widely reported in mainstream outlets&lt;/a&gt; but only following a viral Twitter video and which featured two private figures but echoed a larger existing conversation about racism and policing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GcOXla"&gt;Twitter spokesperson Trenton Kennedy says moderators will heavily weigh the circumstances of a given post. “We’re going to evaluate things in the context in which they’re shared, so I would encourage folks not to draw too many conclusions from past instances or hypotheticals,” Kennedy told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The policy will also require a first-person report requesting a takedown, not just a general complaint that a private figure’s image was posted. And Twitter moderators will consider whether the post was shared publicly on other social networks, not just traditional media outlets. “The general rule around our private information policy is that if this is available and easily accessible off of Twitter, we’re not going to take action on it on Twitter,” said Kennedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSCvHd"&gt;This change comes a day after a high-profile shakeup at Twitter, as longtime CEO Jack Dorsey was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;replaced by former CTO Parag Agrawal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809746/twitter-ban-personal-information-private-media-photo-videos-harassment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809746/twitter-ban-personal-information-private-media-photo-videos-harassment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-30T11:23:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-30T11:23:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google engineers claim they were fired for following its ‘don’t be evil’ policy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YZkG-kJJQ0_312-YsbLNUSX8iSo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70209865/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5D4ct7"&gt;Three ex-Google employees claim that Google has a contractual obligation to abide by its well-known “don’t be evil” policy, and they are suing the company for allegedly terminating them for calling out Google’s “evil” doings, via &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/11/29/1059821677/google-dont-be-evil-lawsuit"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="P3SnwA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Don’t be evil” has been a part of Google’s Code of Conduct since the early 2000s&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3VYDi1"&gt;The former workers Sophie Waldman, Rebecca Rivers, and Paul Duke were fired  — in addition to a fourth employee, Laurence Berland — in November 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/11/25/20982649/google-fired-rebecca-rivers-employee-questioned-work-customs-and-border-protection"&gt;for allegedly violating the company’s data security policies&lt;/a&gt;, however, they claim they didn’t leak any confidential information. Earlier this year, the acting head of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421969/google-illegally-firing-three-workers-nlrb-president-biden"&gt;National Labor Relations Board said that Google “arguably violated”&lt;/a&gt; US labor laws by firing the three employees, alleging that Google terminated the employees in retaliation for their activism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m1HLcJ"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21119310-google_complaint_filed"&gt;the lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; filed in the state of California, the group accuses Google of partaking in “evil,” and subsequently punishing them for calling the company out on it. The lawsuit states that at the time Waldman, Rivers, and Duke were hired by Google, they all signed a contract that included the “don’t be evil” rule. So when the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/14/20805432/google-employees-petition-protest-customs-border-cloud-computing-contract"&gt;employees questioned and petitioned against&lt;/a&gt; Google’s controversial cloud computing contract with the Trump administration’s Customs and Border Patrol in 2019, they believed that they were in accordance with their contracts, citing the potential instances of human rights abuses at the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h6aKQ2"&gt;“Don’t be evil” has been a part of Google’s Code of Conduct since the early 2000s. Although Google’s parent company, Alphabet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/3/9445453/google-dont-be-evil-replaced-in-alphabet"&gt;replaced it with “do the right thing” in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, the phrase is still alive and well in &lt;a href="https://abc.xyz/investor/other/google-code-of-conduct/"&gt;Google’s most recent Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;, stating: “And remember… don’t be evil, and if you see something that you think isn’t right — speak up!”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809577/google-employees-sue-dont-be-evil-policy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809577/google-employees-sue-dont-be-evil-policy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
