<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-02T21:10:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T21:10:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T21:10:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>For Apple TV Plus to succeed, it has to be everywhere — even Android TV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LCCa0KZN32lwitIK2S2LLzcnmV8=/128x0:1505x918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69380653/Apple_introduces_apple_tv_plus_03252019_big.jpg.large_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple TV Plus logo.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VKzcOk"&gt;This week, Apple brought its Apple TV app to many new Android TV devices — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462960/apple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available"&gt;not just the Nvidia Shield&lt;/a&gt;. And Apple was smart to widen that support — the expiration date for free trials of Apple TV Plus is swiftly approaching, with many customers about to see their subscriptions end July 1st. That gives Apple a month to win over Android TV users by letting them watch flagship shows like the earnest and delightful &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; on the big screen, a show &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;whose second season &lt;/a&gt;will premiere near the end of July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zz9VYe"&gt;The rollout of the Apple TV app to Android TV OS devices started Monday at 8AM PT, a Google spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. As a caveat, the Google spokesperson clarified that support does not extend to third-party operator set-top boxes, so, for example, devices like AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21160860/att-tv-now-available-android-tv-google-assistant-streaming"&gt;Android TV set-top box&lt;/a&gt; probably won’t get Apple TV anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1vnhvI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The rollout does not extend to third-party operator set-top boxes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUmHPI"&gt;That Apple’s finally made its streaming app available across Android TV devices isn’t much of a shocker. The app was previously made available on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287905/apple-tv-app-now-available-chromecast-google-tv"&gt;non-Apple devices&lt;/a&gt; like the Chromecast with Google TV and the PlayStation 5, and it’s been on Roku and Fire TV devices since 2019. Some Sony TVs running Android TV and other Vizio models running SmartCast OS additionally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/14/21516418/apple-tv-sony-android-now-available-software-update"&gt;received support&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/apple-tv-arrives-on-vizio-smartcast-tvs-1845006293"&gt;for the app&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rNTqHY"&gt;But it’s also not entirely shocking for a company banking heavily on its services offerings. Apple seems to have figured out somewhere along the way that it needed to play nice with other device makers if it wanted to grow Apple TV Plus subscriptions in any meaningful way. With some &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/apple-services-revenue-tops-16-9-billion-4175371/"&gt;660 million paid subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; across its services as of April, Apple TV Plus’ &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1136261/number-of-apple-tv-plus-subscribers-us/"&gt;estimated 40 million&lt;/a&gt; U.S. subscribers is a small but certainly not insignificant slice of that pie — but that figure could quickly change come July when those users will have to decide whether Apple’s shows are worth paying for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GeoJ1w"&gt;Apple launched its service back in 2019 with an astonishingly meager lineup of originals. Sure, they were high-caliber productions with big-name talent and directors at the helm. And sure, some of them were even good! (M. Night Shyamalan’s bizarre psychological thriller &lt;em&gt;Servant&lt;/em&gt; is one such example.) But Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"&gt;extended its lengthy free trials&lt;/a&gt; of the service that it offered to users who purchased its devices, and that trial period is very nearly about to end for some of the earliest users to hop on the freebie train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TqZDcA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple is about to face a subscriber reckoning&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RrhWAa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; — which Tim Cook has &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/apple-services-revenue-tops-16-9-billion-4175371/"&gt;cited as being a critical success&lt;/a&gt; for the platform — will, again, release its second season toward the end of next month. But for some Apple users, their free trials to Apple TV Plus end July 1st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8ywqr"&gt;In other words, Apple’s dangling a content carrot in front of its most loyal users in hopes that they’ll stick around and hand over their money. But with so many other services available at present, it’s unclear whether that’ll be enough to make them stay. In fact, research MoffettNathanson &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/apple-tv-plus-freeloader-problem-percent-free-1234890385/"&gt;estimated earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; that nearly 30 percent of Apple TV Plus subscribers did not plan to resubscribe following their trial periods. While $5 per month isn’t too much for a premium service comparatively speaking, it does start to add up when people are counting all the subscriptions they fork out money for each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qBijHS"&gt;Because Apple’s entire plan for the service is to be a hub for either its own in-house productions — or exclusively attained feature films like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/19/21264009/tom-hanks-greyhound-apple-tv-plus-streaming-sony-pictures-pandemic"&gt;Tom Hanks’ &lt;em&gt;Greyhound&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — that means the company has some catching up to do to reach anything close to the library scale of most of its peers, particularly considering it’s about to start making people pay for the service. Making it available across Android TV devices hooked up in users’ homes is a good way to prepare for this change. Plus, especially accounting for the pandemic, who on earth wants to watch an entire feature film on a palm-sized iPhone when they can watch it on the biggest screen in their home instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MjWM4U"&gt;It’s almost as if Apple realized that &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/apple-never-made-imessage-for-android-to-lock-in-ios-us-1846650480"&gt;doing things the Apple way&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t going to be a successful model for competing in the streaming wars. And while the service is late to the party in terms of accessibility across platforms — it has taken far too long for this app to arrive on more Android TV devices, in my opinion — it was a necessary move for Apple TV Plus’s success in the long run. As long-trialed subscribers discover they’ll suddenly need to pay for Apple’s content, the churn is going to burn.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465825/apple-tv-app-android-tv-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465825/apple-tv-app-android-tv-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T20:40:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T20:40:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Your next laptop may come with a cryptominer, courtesy of Norton</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lsCmzfIHvSEXsYogjo2Csm9Lc7M=/0x0:1024x683/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69380550/norton_crypto.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Norton&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EuE0J6"&gt;Ethereum mining is coming to perhaps an unexpected place: Norton 360, the antivirus software that many readers will know from setting up new computers for their parents (&lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/cryptocurrency/norton-360-antivirus-now-lets-you-mine-ethereum-cryptocurrency/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;BleepingComputer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). In &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210602005361/en/"&gt;its press release&lt;/a&gt;, Norton claims its brand is a perfect fit: people looking to mine crypto won’t have to dig through the dark, scary parts of the web, where they could possibly find “unvetted code.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v2ZGUl"&gt;The company also says that it’ll store users’ crypto wallets in the cloud, with its own Norton Wallet. As far as actually using their gains, a Norton spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; there will be a button that allows users to “pull money into Coinbase.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2krHr"&gt;Until now, Norton claims, people who wanted to mine had to disable their security software to do it, which made things harder for them. While that somewhat seems like a problem that could at least in part be caused by Norton 360 itself, Norton does have a point that using software that comes pre-installed on your computer is easier than having to figure out mining for yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zmCcDx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Think Kindle with Special Offers, except it’s taxing your computer’s GPU&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n0QrYh"&gt;But is that really what we want? Putting aside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"&gt;environmental concerns&lt;/a&gt; of thousands of new miners, and the potential unexpected tax implications that &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/cryptocurrency/norton-360-antivirus-now-lets-you-mine-ethereum-cryptocurrency/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BleepingComputer&lt;/em&gt; brings up&lt;/a&gt; (not that those are things that should be ignored), the idea of having mining software included in a program that comes with people’s computers seems like a slippery slope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3iVbgC"&gt;It’s easy to imagine a company, not necessarily Norton, offering cheaper or even free computers, if you just turn your unused computing cycles into a recurring source of profit for the bloatware makers subsidizing your purchase. Think Kindle with Special Offers, except instead of ads you’re taxing your computer’s GPU and sucking back electricity when you’re not using it (or, in the case of really shady manufacturers, when you are). Norton may be opening a door here that’s hard to close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U6qjYh"&gt;While Norton specifically calls out Ethereum in its blog post, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/02/investing/nortonlifelock-crypto-mining-ethereum/index.html"&gt;it told &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it was considering letting people mine other “reputable crypto currencies” later on. The company’s letting in early adopters on Thursday, and hopes to roll it out to everyone “in the coming weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/6/2/22465862/norton-360-crypto-mining-ethereum-coinbase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/6/2/22465862/norton-360-crypto-mining-ethereum-coinbase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T20:13:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T20:13:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>NASA will send two missions to Venus for the first time in over 30 years</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/akQ1ZAqmTFDavloFUN6Pei5pPpQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69380471/Venus_NewlyProcessedView.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mu0DvE"&gt;The agency has picked two new robotic missions to explore the hot hell-world of Venus, Earth’s neighbor and the second planet from the Sun, administrator Bill Nelson announced on Wednesday. The two missions, DAVINCI+ and VERITAS, were among four competing proposals under the latest round of NASA’s Discovery Program, which manages smaller planetary exploration missions with a slim budget of roughly $500 million each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x0vEeA"&gt;“These two sister missions both aim to understand how Venus became an inferno-like world capable of melting lead at the surface,” Nelson said during his first “State of NASA” address at the agency’s headquarters in Washington, DC on Wednesday. “They will offer the entire science community a chance to investigate a planet we haven’t been to in more than 30 years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MjFHwp"&gt;DAVINCI+, slated to launch around 2029, will mark the first US-led mission into the atmosphere of Venus since 1978, when NASA’s second Pioneer mission plunged into Venusian clouds for scientific study. The spacecraft will fly by Venus twice to snap close-up photos of the planet’s surface before tossing a robotic probe into its thick atmosphere to measure its gasses and other elements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hDJ0yvDEx9IY0KOTPD7HUopaDis=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22326866/wispr_venus_image__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;NASA/Johns Hopkins APL/Naval Research Laboratory/Guillermo Stenborg and Brendan Gallagher&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An image of Venus captured by NASA’s Parker Solar Probe last summer showing the planet’s mysterious nightside and revealing a surprisingly clear view of its surface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wVHd6w"&gt;Interest in Venus &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21438514/venus-future-exploration-spacecraft-flagship-missions-nasa-phosphine-detection"&gt;spiked&lt;/a&gt; last year during NASA’s review of the four missions, when a separate international team of researchers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21428796/venus-gas-life-sign-discovery-phosphine-biosignature"&gt;published findings that the noxious gas, phosphine&lt;/a&gt;, was possibly floating in the clouds of Venus — an intriguing theory that hinted at the first signs of off-world life, as phosphine is known to be made primarily by living organisms. But other researchers disputed the team’s findings, leaving the phosphine theory open-ended. DAVINCI+’s plunge through Venus’ atmosphere could decisively settle that mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JvhKl3"&gt;When the research was published, NASA’s previous administrator, Jim Bridenstine, said “it’s time to prioritize Venus.” NASA’s science associate administrator, Thomas Zurbuchen, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that although the two probes could help confirm the phosphine research, they were picked for their scientific value, proposed timeline, and other factors independent of the phosphine findings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0NzcXf"&gt;The second mission, VERITAS, is a probe slated to launch around 2028, just before DAVINCI+. It’ll orbit Venus and map its surface much like NASA’s Magellan probe did for four years beginning in 1990, but with a much sharper focus that will give scientists a better picture of the planet’s geological history. It’ll use a synthetic aperture radar and track surface elevations to “create 3D reconstructions of topography and confirm whether processes such as plate tectonics and volcanism are still active on Venus,” NASA &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-2-missions-to-study-lost-habitable-world-of-venus"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dPdh75"&gt;Another camera on VERITAS will be sensitive to a wavelength that could spot signs of water vapor in Venus’ atmosphere, which, if detected, could hint that active volcanoes had been degassing on the planet’s surface sometime long ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mcXdhp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Venus is closer to the Sun, it’s a hot house now, but once upon a time it might’ve been different”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="87tbEt"&gt;Taken together, the two missions make clear that NASA is finally going all in on Venus, a spicy-hot planet long sidelined by other, more scientifically popular planets like Mars. The two Discovery-class missions that competed with DAVINCI+ and VERITAS were TRIDENT, which would’ve studied Neptune’s icy moon Triton, and the Io Volcano Observer (IVO), which would’ve studied the tidal forces on Jupiter’s moon Io. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G6Y2H0"&gt;The twin missions to Venus aim to confront the possibility that the planet was once habitable. “Venus is closer to the Sun, it’s a hot house now, but once upon a time it might’ve been different,” NASA’s Discovery program head Thomas Wagner tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;Studying the planet’s atmosphere up close could give scientists clues on how it evolved over time to allow Venus to become the hell world it is today, with surface temperatures of around 900 degrees Fahrenheit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DWPI8G"&gt;The missions could also help scientists learn how to look at exoplanets, distant planets in other solar systems. Though hot and unlivable, Venus sits in the Goldilocks zone of our solar system, a term scientists use to characterize the position of exoplanets whose distances from the Sun sit in just the right spot to foster life. Venus, Wagner says, could be a model, right next to Earth, to help us understand exoplanets farther away. The planet’s distance from our Sun also raises equally intriguing questions about why Venus turned into the hell-world it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5YI08D"&gt;“Since Venus is in the goldilocks zone, we want to know what the heck went on on Venus,” Wagner says.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465588/nasa-mission-to-venus-davinci-veritas-discovery-program"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465588/nasa-mission-to-venus-davinci-veritas-discovery-program</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T18:46:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T18:46:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple asks staff to return to office three days a week starting in early September </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lLQ2WHLpEs-9flnsbZB5C7U9Hn8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69380177/acastro_190322_1777_apple_streaming_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q0JJHI"&gt;Apple employees are being asked to return to the office three days a week starting in early September. Tim Cook sent out an email Wednesday informing staff of the change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PODrP"&gt;“For all that we’ve been able to achieve while many of us have been separated, the truth is that there has been something essential missing from this past year: each other,” he said. “Video conference calling has narrowed the distance between us, to be sure, but there are things it simply cannot replicate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sgrpkz"&gt;Cook said that most employees will be asked to come in to the office on Mondays, Tuesdays, and Thursdays, with the option of working remotely on Wednesdays and Fridays. Teams that need to work in-person will return four to five days a week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mnaG3Q"&gt;Employees also have the chance to work remotely for up to two weeks a year, “to be closer to family and loved ones, find a change of scenery, manage unexpected travel, or a different reason all your own,” according to the letter. Managers need to approve remote work requests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aLkk8F"&gt;The change is not entirely unexpected for Apple staff. While employees have worked remotely during the coronavirus pandemic, the company famously discouraged working from home prior to 2020. In December, Tim Cook told employees they could be asked to come back to the office as early as June, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-29/apple-encourages-staff-to-get-vaccinated-offers-paid-time-off?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xbt1dK"&gt;Apple’s stance on remote work, while getting more relaxed, is still conservative compared to the other tech giants. In May, Google announced that &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/05/google-relaxes-remote-work-plan-will-let-20percent-of-employees-telecommute.html"&gt;20 percent of its workforce would be able to work from home permanently&lt;/a&gt;. Mark Zuckerberg has said that remote work “is the future,” and told Facebook employees they can all work from home forever, so long as they get their manager’s approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYLBVR"&gt;In the letter Wednesday, Cook also encouraged all employees to get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZawd9"&gt;“For now, let me simply say that I look forward to seeing your faces,” he said in closing. “I know I’m not alone in missing the hum of activity, the energy, creativity and collaboration of our in-person meetings and the sense of community we’ve all built.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1Ly2l"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T17:16:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T17:16:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>You probably shouldn’t eat cicadas if you’re allergic to shellfish</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Five cicadas hanging out on some lush green leaves. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pcaduiW0DQhAPdf_AewOnROwIdM=/0x0:4511x3007/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69379630/1321221870.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Magicicada periodical cicadas, members of Brood X, cluster on a plant at Fairland Recreational Park June 01, 2021 in Burtonsville, Maryland.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pWLEhs"&gt;Brood X is back and ready for action. After a 17 year nap, the cicadas of the Eastern US have emerged to scream, mate, and perhaps pick up a fungus that turns them into “&lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-this-zombie-fungus-turns-cicadas-into-horror-movie-sex-bots/"&gt;horror movie sex bots.&lt;/a&gt;” While some people have been dreading the return of the screeching multitudes, others have eagerly awaited the brood with tasty &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/eating-cicadas-brood-x/"&gt;bug recipes in hand&lt;/a&gt;. But before you run to the nearest cicada cookout, be aware that you’ll probably want to avoid these crunchy morsels if you have a shellfish allergy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h1kgWn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yep! We have to say it!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Don't eat &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/cicadas?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#cicadas&lt;/a&gt; if you're allergic to seafood as these insects share a family relation to shrimp and lobsters. &lt;a href="https://t.co/UBg7CwrObN"&gt;https://t.co/UBg7CwrObN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/3qn7czNg53"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3qn7czNg53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— U.S. FDA (@US_FDA) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/US_FDA/status/1400135267269414914?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5fT2Ld"&gt;If you’re allergic to shellfish, it’s entirely possible that you’ll have a reaction to eating certain insects. After all, what are shrimps and lobsters but bugs of the sea? Seriously, in the colonial era lobsters were only food &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/lobsters-were-once-only-fed-to-poor-people-and-prisoner-1612356919"&gt;for poor and incarcerated people&lt;/a&gt;, because they were seen as bottom-dwelling roaches rather than a delicacy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CgLdul"&gt;Like their ocean-based cousins, cicadas are arthropods. Their bodies contain similar proteins, which is what the body overreacts to in an allergic response. Their chitinous exoskeletons can also irritate your (&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22445929/dogs-eating-cicadas-brood-x-fish-bait-birds"&gt;or your pet’s&lt;/a&gt;) gut in larger quantities, even if you’re not allergic. But generally, insects are a perfectly good source of nutrition that are eaten around the world and might be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/science/2019/10/8/20835352/cricket-farms-edible-insect-snacks-farming-food-security-robots"&gt;the future of food&lt;/a&gt;. So if you’ve never had a problem with seafood, go ahead and chow down &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/kidspost/cicadas-inspire-works-of-art/2021/05/28/fe2cc04e-b7e4-11eb-a6b1-81296da0339b_story.html"&gt;while the buffet is still open&lt;/a&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465606/cicadas-shellfish-allergy-brood-x"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465606/cicadas-shellfish-allergy-brood-x</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T16:53:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T16:53:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s newest euphemism for overworked employees is ‘industrial athlete’ </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8XpOwZys4hDJaucPMFW0ED904y0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69379529/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IseoFD"&gt;Amazon tells its warehouse employees to think of themselves not as overworked cogs in an enormous, soul-crushing machine, but&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;as “industrial athletes,” and to prepare their bodies for that experience like someone training for a sporting event, according to &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/epnvp7/amazon-calls-warehouse-workers-industrial-athletes-in-leaked-wellness-pamphlet"&gt;a pamphlet obtained by &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The comparison is a troubling euphemism for a company whose workers have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463132/amazon-injury-rate-warehouses-osha-data-report"&gt;almost double the amount of serious injuries&lt;/a&gt; as the rest of the warehousing industry and who reportedly are often &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/3/22365330/amazon-apology-pee-bottles-worker-warehouse-union-pocan"&gt;unable to take bathroom breaks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDtIcu"&gt;The pamphlet tells employees that some of them will walk up to 13 miles throughout the course of the day, burning an average of 400 calories an hour. It also suggests all sorts of ways to help workers prepare for the athlete life, including changes to their diets and sleep schedules and making sure they’re not dehydrated throughout the day by keeping an eye on the color of their urine. It also suggests that employees buy shoes “at the end of the day when [their] feet are swollen” to avoid tightness and blisters&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— advice that will be familiar to distance runners or multi-day hikers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="radXV6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon’s 2020 injury rates are an improvement from years past&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z16BCe"&gt;One thing Amazon doesn’t bring up is that athletes train &lt;em&gt;for an event&lt;/em&gt; with a definite end date. Athletes aren’t competing day in and day out, and they have time to rest and recuperate in between. The comparison becomes even more ridiculous when you look at what a pro athlete’s day is actually like: significant time is spent warming up to avoid injuries, practice may be only a few hours out of the day (read: not in eight or 10-hour shifts), there’s time made for rest or &lt;a href="https://www.runnersworld.com/advanced/a26964907/a-day-in-the-life-of-one-of-the-nations-fastest-milers/"&gt;even naps&lt;/a&gt;, and significant effort is spent on nutrition. It’s safe to say that most Amazon warehouse workers don’t have &lt;a href="https://www.joe.co.uk/sport/day-in-the-life-professional-footballer-210911"&gt;professional nutritionists and / or chefs&lt;/a&gt; taking care of their dietary needs. If an employee wanted to make up the calories they might expect to burn in a given shift, they would have to eat almost 40 apples, or over 1,000 baby carrots if they were assigned one of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266369/amazon-ten-hour-overnight-shifts-warehouse-workers"&gt;the company’s 10-hour “megacycles.”&lt;/a&gt; Amazon does say that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210517005300/en/From-Body-Mechanics-to-Mindfulness-Amazon-Launches-Employee-Designed-Health-and-Safety-Program-called-WorkingWell-Across-U.S.-Operations"&gt;trying to provide workers with healthy snacks&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s not exactly reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IVNqqe"&gt;Unlike actual athletes — who have a lifetime of physical experience that allows them to train and compete at a high level — many Amazon workers have no background in doing highly physical work. It’s little wonder then that reports continue to find Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463132/amazon-injury-rate-warehouses-osha-data-report"&gt;comparatively high injury rates&lt;/a&gt;: Amazon’s warehouse workers had almost double the number of serious injuries compared to other warehouse workers in 2020, which is actually a “marked” improvement compared to the numbers from 2017, 2018, and 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLB3Dv"&gt;Amazon told &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; that it had immediately removed the pamphlet after it was created, but the worker who provided it said it had been around since November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sEuP7n"&gt;If Amazon wants its workers to think of themselves as “athletes,” the solution isn’t wellness programs or pushing employees to check the color of their pee. Instead, it should let them work at a reasonable pace and provide them with support and personnel to keep them healthy. Trainers don’t seek to extract the maximum value from an athlete only to discard them if they’re hurt. In the case of a worker who spoke to &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;, though, he said out of all the Amazon employees he had to consult during the process of recovering from a workplace injury, only one person even asked how he was feeling. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465357/amazon-industrial-athlete-warehouse-worker-wellness-pamphlet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465357/amazon-industrial-athlete-warehouse-worker-wellness-pamphlet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T16:42:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T16:42:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>If you play Fortnite right now, you might get abducted by aliens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RpAp0v24MTBr8M1zgixeUG0s2Hc=/16x0:978x641/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69379422/fortnite.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A promotional image for &lt;/em&gt;Fortnite’s&lt;em&gt; next season.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CGD5Or"&gt;If you hop into a game of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; right now, you might get teleported across the map by a mysterious laser beam that appears out of the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eGNxRz"&gt;Yes, seriously. Watch it happen &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lIHjp-TgGDI"&gt;in this video&lt;/a&gt; from streamer Ali “SypherPK” Hassan, which I’ve also embedded below at the right timestamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lc4ogm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lIHjp-TgGDI?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=431&amp;amp;start=431" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tNM0zk"&gt;While it’s hard to tell exactly where the laser beam is coming from, it’s hard to think that it isn’t coming from some kind of UFO or alien... thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Igtbu2"&gt;The abductions started happening in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; Tuesday evening, just one week before the game’s next season &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/what-to-do-before-fortnite-chapter-2-season-6-ends-and-7-starts"&gt;begins on June 8th&lt;/a&gt;. And a few other hints seem to indicate that Chapter 2 Season 7 could be alien-themed in some way, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QUkxEb"&gt;Check out &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iFireMonkey/status/1400142779670577157"&gt;this video teaser&lt;/a&gt; that apparently is on TikTok, for example, which features the tagline “they’re coming” and mysterious alien-like sounds (headphone warning, the sound is a little harsh):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="emuxJI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Chapter 2 - Season 7 teaser videos are starting to be posted as ads on TikTok, Facebook, Instagram, and YouTube.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Video VIA: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Christo61905189?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Christo61905189&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/NLMphmHeU9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NLMphmHeU9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— iFireMonkey (@iFireMonkey) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iFireMonkey/status/1400142779670577157?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LGBwCd"&gt;And you can see an image that’s similar to what’s in that TikTok ad on &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/home"&gt;Epic Games’ &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TII9xxMtfZjoVAStvp_AjQ_bHDI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22555516/Screen_Shot_2021_06_02_at_1.02.10_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DhBfzM"&gt;It’s also not out of the ordinary for Epic to change things up at the end of a season. In May 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/4/18529463/fortnite-unvaulting-volcano-eruption-tilted-towers-destroyed-season-9"&gt;a volcano erupted&lt;/a&gt; and destroyed Tilted Towers, one of the most beloved spots on the map. And last June, a mysterious device blew up the island’s central landmark and transformed the ever-present storm &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/15/21291458/fortnite-device-event-agency-explosion-water-storm"&gt;into a wall of water&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PrVJfc"&gt;So far, these new abductions don’t seem to have quite the map-shifting impact that those changes did — but with a few days left in the season, who knows what else Epic might have up its sleeve?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465577/fortnite-epic-games-ufos-aliens-abducted-teaser-season-7"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465577/fortnite-epic-games-ufos-aliens-abducted-teaser-season-7</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T16:34:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T16:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Apple Card outage has been resolved after five hours</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q4n0npO9Hc_laGzjqgNIRTMSivI=/201x0:2349x1432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69377427/Screen_Shot_2019_03_26_at_1.49.46_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QPBOUA"&gt;The Apple Card experienced an outage on Wednesday that reportedly affected users’ ability to make payments, manage their cards, and see recent transactions, according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fsupport%2Fsystemstatus%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F2%2F22465000%2Fapple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s status page&lt;/a&gt;. Interruption in service appears to have started at 6:17AM PT today and lasted for a little over five hours, ending at 12:19PM PT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2J5kgD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277417/apple-pay-credit-card-announcement-goldman-sachs-event-2019"&gt;Apple’s credit card solution&lt;/a&gt; is managed almost entirely through the built-in Wallet app in iOS, where users can pay off their credit card bill, see recent transactions, and make payments through Apple Pay. Apple said that all users were affected by today’s outage, but it wasn’t clear if every user experienced all of the possible issues the company reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jd8AY4"&gt;My colleague Mitchell Clark was able to pay off a portion of their bill and see the transaction show up in the Wallet app during the outage, so it’s possible the issues were slowly fixed over time, or never as widespread as Apple warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCZcu2"&gt;Apple never provided comment on the actual size or scope of the problem, but the status page says the issues is resolved, and you should be able to use your card like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w1n6ui"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 2nd, 2:25PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information about Apple Card usage and updated the duration of the outage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB8vd6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 2nd, 4:34PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added that the outage has ended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465000/apple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465000/apple-card-outage-cant-make-payments-recent-transactions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T15:59:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T15:59:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will stop testing most employees for weed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kvYxUHolEbO9Dnh-aHrjV2O9nUA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69379145/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UfFDai"&gt;Amazon is relaxing its policy around employees using weed, according to &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/operations/update-on-our-vision-to-be-earths-best-employer-and-earths-safest-place-to-work"&gt;a new blog post&lt;/a&gt;, and will no longer enforce marijuana drug tests for any employee who isn’t also regulated by the Department of Transportation, like a delivery driver. In the past, Amazon used positive tests as a reason to disqualify applicants during the hiring process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fVQkua"&gt;Dave Clark, Amazon’s CEO of worldwide consumer, announced the change as part of the company’s goal to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22386992/amazon-is-finally-realizing-it-has-a-labor-problem"&gt;“Earth’s Best Employer,”&lt;/a&gt; a strategy that so far has been characterized by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440385/amazon-workingwell-worker-health-guided-meditaiton"&gt;new programs&lt;/a&gt; like WorkingWell that seem to view employees as things that need to be maintained and trained, rather than people who should be treated fairly. Still, as weed is legalized for recreational and medicinal use state by state &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/4/12/22371929/marijuana-legalization-new-mexico-virginia-new-york-biden"&gt;across the US&lt;/a&gt;, acknowledging that the average employee probably uses marijuana in the same casual way people drink alcohol is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dIdQxQ"&gt;Clark also announced that Amazon’s policy team will be “actively supporting” the reintroduced Marijuana Opportunity Reinvestment and Expungement Act of 2021 (&lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/3884"&gt;MORE Act&lt;/a&gt;) which seeks to legalize weed at the federal level, along with expunging the criminal records of people who were arrested for marijuana possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ScvNVg"&gt;In a statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; Kassandra Frederique, executive director of the Drug Policy Alliance, supported Amazon’s change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="y87v3c"&gt;We implore Amazon and other employers to let this be the starting point and not the goal post. This change can and should be the catalyst to a much larger move—ending drug testing for all drugs—that would ensure a more just and equitable future for millions of people, especially Black, Brown and Indigenous communities who have been disproportionately impacted by these policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="k37r2m"&gt;However helpful Amazon’s tweaks to its employee policies are, they’re still not as good as actual representation for its workers. Luckily, in the fallout of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374540/amazon-union-vote-outcome-bessemer-alabama-rwdsu-bhm1"&gt;union drive&lt;/a&gt; in Alabama, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22445940/amazon-union-nlrb-hearing-mailbox-bessemer"&gt;that’s possibly still on its way, too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7d1tgV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t179fD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0VKhQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465331/amazon-weed-policy-dot-more-act"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465331/amazon-weed-policy-dot-more-act</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T14:51:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T14:51:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMC is giving free popcorn away to meme stonk investors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Burbank Exteriors And Landmarks - 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3bbvln3lxtli5isHtUekMKtcG3c=/0x74:3100x2141/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69378775/1231701895.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by AaronP/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="X73aOx"&gt;Look, when the internet learns a new trick — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;like it did in January, with GameStop&lt;/a&gt; — it’s a pretty safe bet that people will play the trick again. So AMC is through the roof right now: it touched $72.62, a 91 percent increase from its open and an all-time high. That’s because AMC has embraced the trolls, and now the stock price is going &lt;em&gt;brrr&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvcXNt"&gt;AMC &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1411579/000110465921075395/tm2117897d3_defa14a.htm"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that it was creating AMC Investor Connect, “an innovative, proactive communication initiative that will put AMC in direct communication with its extraordinary base of enthusiastic and passionate individual shareholders to keep them up to date about important company information and to provide them with special offers.” This represents “a groundbreaking new approach” to communicating with retail investors, the company says. It’s a shame they didn’t put a bunch of rocket emojis in the announcement — after all, there’s no need to be coy. We all know exactly who AMC is speaking to, and if they sign up today, they’re getting free popcorn. &lt;em&gt;I can’t make this shit up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="am9aGt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;lol nothing matters money is made up&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GtdiwP"&gt;This is also, essentially, the opposite of what GameStop did, which was &lt;em&gt;say absolutely nothing&lt;/em&gt;. You got the sense that maybe the exec team was nervous that anything they said might potentially be securities fraud. AMC, though, they’ve elected to really embrace the whole meme thing. I’m hoping there are more announcements where they get meme-ier. Like, retail investors get a free Lego rocket in the fourth quarter or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DzsKg2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/editorials/meme-insider/weekend-meme-roundup-explaining-the-lingo-and-memes-of-wallstreetbets-and-the-gamestop-stock-surge"&gt;The apes&lt;/a&gt; of r/WallStreetBets have been good to AMC. The in-person theater company had been suffering due to the coronavirus — but the r/WallStreetBets excitement in January  &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/1411579/000110465921008352/tm213880d2_8k.htm"&gt;essentially wiped out $600 million of debt by&lt;/a&gt; letting the holders convert them into stock. Meme enthusiasm essentially &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/02/02/amc-wallstreetbets-stock-debt/"&gt;saved the company&lt;/a&gt;. (AMC &lt;a href="https://investor.amctheatres.com/newsroom/news-details/2021/AMC-Raises-917-Million-of-Fresh-Investment-Capital-Since-Mid-December-of-2020/default.aspx"&gt;also issued new stock&lt;/a&gt; because why not. “Apes together strong,” as they say at WallStreetBets!) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vZE7T1"&gt;A lot of the meme stocks are shooting up again. CNBC even has a “meme stock” graphic now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="“Meme Stocks” chart from CNBC" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t7VLgJRWTeHQQ9weHhVVpzWnQ1A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22555337/E24_NrSWYAAhODE.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ooooh, a CNBC graphic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="d0S1WN"&gt;Meme trading didn’t originate with stocks — it’s a strategy jump. You know what trades heavily on memes? Cryptocurrency! (You remember “HODL,” right?) And you know what makes you go &lt;em&gt;lol nothing matters money is made up&lt;/em&gt;? Also cryptocurrency! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXfc8z"&gt;It was probably inevitable that traders would bring cryptocurrency’s nihilistic insights to the broader market. This real question is what the finance normals plan to do about it. Like, you can make cute little risk models and fill out your Excel spreadsheets, but how do you take into account the possibility that a roving band of irony-poisoned redditors &lt;em&gt;can blow you up at any minute?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7p55tk"&gt;You could say, “Hey, this is bull-market exuberance.” You could also say, “Hey, interest rates are effectively zero right now so there’s a lot of money sloshing around.” Those things are true and they help. But what the internet learned in January is that it can meme stocks into going up, and some people will make money when that happens, and there’s nothing anyone can do to stop it. It &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2021-01-26/will-wallstreetbets-face-sec-scrutiny-after-gamestop-rally-kke9fpzq"&gt;may not even be fraud&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;because no one is lying.&lt;/em&gt; This started somewhere, and that &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-08-06/crypto-pumps-are-just-for-fun?sref=M8H6LjUF"&gt;somewhere was cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, when you bring this strategy to the broader market, you can also potentially fuck over a bunch of big, serious companies, which makes the trolling &lt;em&gt;even more fun&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kvotj1"&gt;Anyway, I hope the AMC investors enjoy their popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465198/amc-meme-stock-popcorn-wsb"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465198/amc-meme-stock-popcorn-wsb</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
