<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-24T11:05:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T11:05:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T11:05:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Guillermo del Toro’s Pinocchio is finally a real wooden boy in first teaser</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Director Guillermo del Toro and a model of his new take on Pinocchio." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y5xdDLHW_WVsDoSRJeow1hCDdxU=/671x361:2930x1867/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70425824/GDTPinocchioPortrait.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CwDwlH"&gt;After years of being trapped in different circles of development hell, co-director &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/16/22677646/nightmare-alley-guillermo-del-toro-teaser-noir"&gt;Guillermo del Toro’&lt;/a&gt;s long-awaited take on &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio &lt;/em&gt;is finally happening, and the stop-motion feature’s first teaser trailer is here to introduce the world to the story’s minuscule moral center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ChzW0v"&gt;Set during Benito Mussolini’s fascist reign over Italy in the 1930s, del Toro’s &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio &lt;/em&gt;once again tells the tale of a wooden puppet who suddenly comes to life, much to his woodcarver “father’s” surprise. Unlike some of the other &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio &lt;/em&gt;tellings you may be familiar with, though, this film’s Pinocchio (Gregory Mann) quickly gets into the sorts of cruel mischief that put him at odds with Geppetto (David Bradley), who loves his son but can’t help but see that he isn’t exactly what one would call a “nice” child. Though this &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio &lt;/em&gt;presumes you’re probably familiar with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167323/disney-live-action-adaptations-plus-streaming-pinocchio-peter-pan-wendy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; parts of this fairytale&lt;/a&gt; as a whole, Sebastian J. Cricket (Ewan McGregor) makes clear in the teaser trailer that there’s more to be said, and he plans to be the one to say it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="juLqT1"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yo02mwsWbAI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kTukbW"&gt;Short as the teaser is, it’s got just enough detail to give you a sense of how &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio&lt;/em&gt;’s more enchanting, playful moments might feel and sound. But what’s still not quite clear is how the film will dance between its fairytale elements and the dark real-world history woven into the narrative. &lt;em&gt;Pinocchio &lt;/em&gt;is co-directed by Mark Gustafson and written by del Toro and Patrick McHale. The film also stars David Bradley, Tilda Swinton, Christoph Waltz, Finn Wolfhard, Cate Blanchett, John Turturro, Ron Perlman, Tim Blake Nelson, and Burn Gorman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c3K6iI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pinocchio&lt;/em&gt; is set to hit Netflix sometime this December.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898792/guillermo-del-toto-pinocchio-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898792/guillermo-del-toto-pinocchio-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T11:01:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T11:01:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google sued by DC and three states for ‘deceptive’ Android location tracking</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7kQ1_-NJyQ7dkqZGCJ3IG6XmCA0=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70425814/acastro_181130_1777_google_bias_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dVZNdX"&gt;The attorneys general of three states and the District of Columbia are &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191075/DCv.Google_1_24_22_.pdf"&gt;suing Google&lt;/a&gt; for the allegedly deceptive collection of location data on Android. The complaints, which build on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/27/21272625/arizona-ag-sues-google-location-tracking-android-allegations"&gt;a 2020 lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; filed by the Arizona Attorney General, allege that Google’s “complex web” of settings obfuscated whether users were sharing their location at a given moment. Furthermore, they allege Google pushed Android users with “repeated nudging, misleading pressure tactics, and evasive and deceptive descriptions” to share more information either “inadvertently or out of frustration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Li42HM"&gt;“Google falsely led consumers to believe that changing their account and device settings would allow customers to protect their privacy and control what personal data the company could access,” said DC Attorney General Karl Racine in a statement. “The truth is that contrary to Google’s representations it continues to systematically surveil customers and profit from customer data.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4oY1o1"&gt;Racine’s suit, filed today, accuses Google of violating DC’s Consumer Protection Procedures Act. State attorneys general from Washington, Texas, and Indiana are also filing similar suits in their own jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vokGOu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://oag.dc.gov/sites/default/files/2022-01/DCv.Google%281-24-22%29.pdf"&gt;The DC complaint&lt;/a&gt; claims that Google’s settings “purport to give consumers control over the location data Google collects and uses. But Google’s misleading, ambiguous, and incomplete descriptions of these settings all but guarantee that consumers will not understand when their location is collected and retained by Google or for what purposes.” Like the earlier lawsuit from Arizona Attorney General Mark Brnovich, the DC suit draws heavily on &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/north-america-science-technology-business-ap-top-news-828aefab64d4411bac257a07c1af0ecb"&gt;a 2018 &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; that found “many Google services on Android devices and iPhones store your location data even if you’ve used a privacy setting that says it will prevent Google from doing so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vaulnv"&gt;Reached for comment, Google denied the claims in the suit, pointing to recent changes like the ability to auto-delete location history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IdDUKW"&gt;“The attorneys general are bringing a case based on inaccurate claims and outdated assertions about our settings,” said Google policy spokesperson José Castañeda. “We have always built privacy features into our products and provided robust controls for location data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mrv2R9"&gt;An Arizona judge, meanwhile, dealt a blow to the Arizona lawsuit last week by &lt;a href="https://www.azmirror.com/2021/01/26/judge-denies-ags-demand-for-summary-judgment-in-google-fraud-case/"&gt;denying a request&lt;/a&gt; for summary judgment, saying there wasn’t strong enough evidence that Google had actually misled consumers. The judge recommended the case move forward with a jury trial to resolve “a myriad of factual issues,” a path that Brnovich indicated he will pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898760/google-dc-washington-texas-indiana-attorneys-general-lawsuit-location-data-tracking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898760/google-dc-washington-texas-indiana-attorneys-general-lawsuit-location-data-tracking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T09:59:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T09:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Win a mystery bag from The Verge chock-full of free tech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/id4RsASm4n1FqtFEO2QjlzZO9QE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70425518/akrales_211105_4862_0044.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t0NOo1"&gt;Did you think the season of giving was over? Not at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;! Not only are we continuing to give you a heads-up regarding discounts and sales on the latest gadgets, but we have another mystery bag stuffed full of freebies to give away to one lucky reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G7oCXZ"&gt;This time, we’ve filled an Alienware M17 Elite Backpack (&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/alienware-m15-m17-elite-backpack-17-for-the-mobile-gamer/apd/aa352186" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;which typically retails for $99.99&lt;/a&gt;) with a whole bunch of goodies. In total, the combined value of the bag and its contents is about $623. We’d be remiss to keep all of these gadgets to ourselves, so we’re offering them to one of you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jlv6J0MD84cvnzpHx9-VB6csgxg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22995766/akrales_211105_4862_0051.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C7jM4Z"&gt;Just where did we get all this stuff? Well, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is always trying out and reviewing the latest tech, and sometimes we end up with some leftover items that need a good home. And what better way to find that home than to give it away to one of our lovely readers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3SMNOo"&gt;To enter, sign up for our &lt;em&gt;Verge Deals&lt;/em&gt; newsletter using the widget below. You can also receive an additional entry by following &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VergeDeals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge Deals&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter (@VergeDeals)&lt;/a&gt;. The sweepstakes will begin at 10AM ET today, January 24th, and run through 10AM ET on Monday, February 28th. Best of luck to all of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UEZoDp"&gt;
&lt;div id="vsscript_104567_384319"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async="" type="text/javascript" src="https://app.viralsweep.com/vsa-widget-798eff-104567.js?sid=104567_384319"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FGAKhB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NO PURCHASE NECESSARY. VOID WHERE PROHIBITED BY LAW.&lt;/strong&gt; Sweepstakes begins at 10:00am ET on 01/14/2022 and ends at 10:00am ET on 02/28/2022. Open to legal residents of the 50 U.S. states and Washington D.C., of legal age of majority and have access to the internet, and a valid email address. Odds of winning depend on number of eligible entries received. Subject to Official Rules, additional eligibility restrictions apply. Official Rules, which govern, can be here: &lt;a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/terms-and-policies.voxmedia.com/OfficialRulesTheVergeMysteryBagGiveaway2022020.pdf"&gt;Official Rules&lt;/a&gt;. Sponsor &lt;a href="https://www.voxmedia.com/legal/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;Sponsor: Vox Media, LLC, 1201 Connecticut Ave., 12th Floor, Washington DC 20036&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22881792/tech-bag-sweepstakes-mystery-gear-entry-rules-january-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22881792/tech-bag-sweepstakes-mystery-gear-entry-rules-january-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T08:01:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T08:01:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Panasonic will reportedly start mass producing next-gen Tesla batteries in 2023</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UI3t00wA4vjKoliMEv-aQ8wL4wQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70425140/acastro_180524_1777_tesla_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="x4fWTA"&gt;Panasonic is due to start mass producing next-generation lithium-ion batteries for Tesla with five times the energy capacity of existing models as early as 2023, according to &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Automobiles/Panasonic-to-start-producing-new-Tesla-batteries-in-2023"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although the batteries are being manufactured primarily for Tesla, a Panasonic executive didn’t rule out supplying them to other companies in a &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Editor-s-Picks/Interview/Panasonic-moves-toward-mass-production-of-Tesla-s-next-gen-batteries"&gt;November interview&lt;/a&gt;. The new batteries promise to boost the range of electric cars, and make them more affordable to produce and sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lmcicz"&gt;In a statement &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/panasonic-invest-700-million-produce-new-batteries-evs-nikkei-2022-01-24/"&gt;given to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Panasonic declined to confirm &lt;em&gt;Nikkei’s &lt;/em&gt;report. “We are studying various options for mass production, including a test production line we are establishing this business year,” the company said. “We don’t, however, have anything to announce at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rkdFU7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nikkei &lt;/em&gt;reports that the larger, higher-capacity batteries —  which are known as 4680 battery cells because they measure 46mm x 80mm in size — could increase the range of electric vehicles by around 20 percent, while Tesla itself has mentioned a 16 percent range increase. They could take a car like its flagship Model S and increase its range from 650km (around 404 miles) to 750km (around 465 miles), according to &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt;. Panasonic is reportedly expanding its Wakayama, Japan plant to mass produce the new batteries, and previously &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tesla-supplier-shows-off-more-powerful-battery-11635144493?reflink=desktopwebshare_twitter"&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that test production is due to start in March 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="o6PeaY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tesla also hopes to produce the batteries in-house&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhShJd"&gt;The next-generation battery cells were detailed by Tesla at a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21449238/tesla-electric-car-battery-tabless-cells-day-elon-musk"&gt;high profile event in September 2020&lt;/a&gt;. As well as their higher storage capacity, the company’s CEO Elon Musk said the cells are six times more powerful, and reduce cost per kWh by 14 percent (batteries are estimated to make up 30 percent of the cost of an electric vehicle). Lower prices and improved range are the sorts of improvements that are key to making electric cars more desirable, as &lt;em&gt;Nikkei &lt;/em&gt;notes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CGcH4B"&gt;The focus of Tesla’s 2020 event was on the company’s attempts to produce the batteries in-house, to reduce potential disruptions from relying on external suppliers like Panasonic. But in a series of tweets posted ahead of the event, Musk said the company would continue to buy battery cells from other companies. “We intend to increase, not reduce battery cell purchases from Panasonic, LG &amp;amp; CATL,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1308149191684710400"&gt;Musk tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, adding that Tesla would be unlikely to achieve high-volume production of the cells until 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBBCuP"&gt;During more recent earnings calls, Musk has reiterated that he expects Tesla’s in-house production of the 4680 cells to start in 2022, and that the first vehicles equipped with these cells will ship the same year. In an &lt;a href="https://www.teslarati.com/tesla-tsla-q1-2021-earnings-call-live-blog/"&gt;April 2021 earnings call&lt;/a&gt;, Musk indicated the company was 12 to 18 months away from mass production of the new cells. However, in July he cautioned that “prototype production is easy, but high-volume production is hard,” &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tesla-supplier-shows-off-more-powerful-battery-11635144493?reflink=desktopwebshare_twitter"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="blXCDB"&gt;The status of Tesla’s new battery cells is likely to be mentioned at the company’s upcoming earnings call on Wednesday, January 26th, when Musk has also said he would share an official “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1466800941269667841"&gt;product roadmap update&lt;/a&gt;” for the Cybertruck following reports of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website"&gt;delay to early 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898666/panasonic-4680-tesla-battery-mass-production-2023"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898666/panasonic-4680-tesla-battery-mass-production-2023</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T06:21:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T06:21:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boeing sinks more money into electric air taxi project it’s co-developing with Kitty Hawk</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Nj6IAQHFK8UewkiLfP8hjZ6tx4=/1172x0:8204x4688/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70424855/Wisk_Aero_Media_Kit_Primary_Image_HD.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="O1wbGS"&gt;Wisk Aero, the electric air taxi startup, raised $450 million from Boeing in a new funding round that it claims will make it “one of the most well-funded [advanced air mobility] companies in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DHHiaO"&gt;In its announcement, Wisk highlights the fact that its “a privately-backed AAM leader,” setting up a contrast with a slate of similar startups that have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358027/lilium-flying-taxi-evtol-spac-electric-aviation-gm-engle"&gt;gone public&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298957/joby-aviation-public-evtol-electric-aircraft-spac-hoffman"&gt;recent months&lt;/a&gt; by merging with special purpose acquisition companies, also known as SPACs or “blank check” companies. Wisk Aero was formed in 2019 as a joint venture between Boeing and Kitty Hawk, the flying taxi company bankrolled by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/19/17586878/larry-page-flying-car-opener-kitty-hawk-cora"&gt;Google co-founder Larry Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z79u1L"&gt;Wisk says it will use the new funds to undertake a period of rapid growth, adding new employees to its current workforce of approximately 350 people and kicking off a manufacturing process that it says will result in a full-scale, commercially operational air taxi business within the next five years. Once that happens, the company predicts that it will conduct 14 million flights annually in around 20 major markets around the globe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZGGh7D"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the company predicts that it will conduct 14 million flights annually&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1aFb8"&gt;Of course, all of this is contingent on the US Federal Aviation Administration and other government regulators giving Wisk the approval it needs to legally carry passengers. So far, the FAA has not certified any electric vertical takeoff and landing (eVTOL) aircraft for commercial operation. Experts have said that it can take a minimum of five years — and likely longer — for regulators to certify that these new types of aircraft are safe enough for passengers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JkJjZO"&gt;Electric air taxis, sometimes misidentified as “flying cars,” are essentially small helicopters without the noisy, polluting gas motors. A number of startups have emerged in recent years with prototype aircraft that are electric-powered, able to carry a handful of passengers, and intended for short flights within a city or regionally. Analysts predict that the flying taxi market could grow to $150 billion in revenue by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oC2fug"&gt;Wisk hasn’t let the lack of regulatory approval get in the way of its business dealings. In addition to the newest founding announcement, the company made a deal last year with helicopter tourism-turned-urban mobility company Blade to &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/05/boeing-backed-start-up-wisk-inks-first-deal-to-operate-air-taxis-in-the-us.html"&gt;own and operate a fleet of 30 aircraft on its network&lt;/a&gt;. Wisk also has a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/4/21122341/wisk-flying-taxi-kitty-hawk-boeing-cora-new-zealand"&gt;signed deal with the government of New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; to conduct a flying taxi trial using its all-electric, self-flying aircraft Cora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxcQGu"&gt;Its aim is for Cora to one day provide a flying taxi service that can reportedly be summoned with an app. The plan is for the vehicle to not have a pilot on board; instead, it will be flown mainly by autopilot systems, with supervision from a human pilot situated remotely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qcoqwl"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22369921/wisk-sues-archer-trade-secrets-theft-flying-taxi"&gt;Wisk accused rival eVTOL company Archer&lt;/a&gt; of stealing dozens of its design secrets, sparking a lawsuit and a subsequent federal investigation into the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22865280/boeing-wisk-aero-funding-evtol-air-taxi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22865280/boeing-wisk-aero-funding-evtol-air-taxi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T06:02:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T06:02:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Recreational drones banned in United Arab Emirates after oil facility attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="3d robotics solo drone" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xoZ2JRKqUKapVNU14cY-jldNp28=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70424843/best-drone-phantom-3dr-.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wLMpEl"&gt;The United Arab Emirates (UAE) has banned the flying of consumer drones by hobbyists. The news comes after a suspected drone attack hit an oil facility and airport in the country’s capital, Abu Dhabi, last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9QGq3i"&gt;The ban was &lt;a href="https://www.moi.gov.ae/en/media.center/News/012222n01.aspx"&gt;announced by the Ministry of the Interior on Saturday&lt;/a&gt; and also applies to light aircraft like gliders. The ministry did not mention the recent attacks in its statement, but referenced “misuse spotted recently,” incidents of drone pilots “trespassing into areas where these types of activities are prohibited,” and a need to “ensure the safety of lives and property.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UEK1yc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The attack involved ‘ballistic missiles and explosive-laden drones’&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bQKMSw"&gt;The recent attack on the oil facility and airport in Abu Dhabi reportedly involved both “ballistic missiles and explosive-laden drones,” &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-dubai-united-arab-emirates-abu-dhabi-yemen-8bdefdf900ce46a6fd6c7bc685bf838a"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;APNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, though it’s not clear from reports what the size and model of these drones were. The attacks were claimed by the Islamist, Iran-backed Houthi rebel group, which currently controls large portions of nearby Yemen and is fighting a coalition of forces supported by Arab countries including the UAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RI8cw6"&gt;Houthi rebels have previously used &lt;a href="https://english.alarabiya.net/News/gulf/2021/02/10/Terrorism-White-House-condemns-Houthi-attack-on-Saudi-Arabia-s-Abha-airport"&gt;small drones&lt;/a&gt; in a number of attacks on Arab nations in recent years, including in the UAE and &lt;a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/saudi-arabian-oil-facility-struck-in-drone-attack/"&gt;Saudi Arabia&lt;/a&gt;. But last week’s strike represents a escalation in tension. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-60082786"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BBC News&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; it’s the first time the UAE has officially acknowledged such attacks, and it’s the first time they’ve been fatal — killing three and wounding six. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwiiIB"&gt;The UAE withdrew its forces from Yemen in 2019, but continues to supply and train local militia opposed to the Houthi. The country is keen to present itself as a bastion of stability in the region, and has been shifting diplomatic relations in recent years, including with Iran. In such a context, deadly strikes by drones and missiles are particularly unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YPbHsu"&gt;A ban on recreational drone use may then help the UAE keep tighter control of its skies. &lt;em&gt;APNews&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-dubai-middle-east-abu-dhabi-yemen-75425bbfc0d5e2d07d882d7bb123c8f2"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that the country already restricted flights in residential areas and near airports. The country’s ministry of the interior says that exceptions may be made for “work contracts or commercial or advertising projects that rely on filming using drones,” if those involved have attained “the necessary exceptions and permits.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898614/united-arab-emirates-uae-ban-recreational-drone-attack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898614/united-arab-emirates-uae-ban-recreational-drone-attack</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T04:25:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T04:25:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Yakuza director announces new studio after leaving Sega</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HLLoJoXtzz2RU6QF7es3siO90bU=/80x0:944x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70424766/ss_02_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jkuAdY"&gt;Toshihiro Nagoshi, former chief creative officer at Sega, where he led development of the &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; series as general director of Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio, has announced his next move. He’s started up his own studio, simply titled &lt;a href="https://nagoshistudio.com"&gt;Nagoshi Studio&lt;/a&gt;, which is being wholly funded by Chinese internet and gaming company NetEase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkVd6e"&gt;Nagoshi announced his departure from Sega last October, but today’s news also follows &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-30/china-s-netease-in-talks-to-hire-creator-of-sega-yakuza-series"&gt;a report from Bloomberg back in August&lt;/a&gt; that named NetEase as his prospective future partner. Masayoshi Yokoyama, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321087/yakuza-like-a-dragon-story-interview-masayoshi-yokoyama"&gt;who &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; interviewed last year&lt;/a&gt; about his work on the most recent &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; game &lt;em&gt;Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;, is the new head of Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio and is currently working on the next game in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="muJL1B"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Yakuza’s lead writer on how Like a Dragon reinvents the series","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22321087/yakuza-like-a-dragon-story-interview-masayoshi-yokoyama"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tunrVY"&gt;Nagoshi Studio will be headquartered in Tokyo and has hired several former long-time Sega employees and &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; contributors. The list includes producer Daisuke Sato, artist Kazuki Hosokawa, programmer Koji Tokieda, designer Masao Shirosaki, engineer Mitsunori Fujimoto, artist Naoki Someya, director Taichi Ushioda, and artist Toshihiro Ando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0ftvD"&gt;In an &lt;a href="https://www.famitsu.com/news/202201/24248030.html"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Japanese games magazine &lt;em&gt;Famitsu&lt;/em&gt;, Nagoshi goes into some detail about why he chose to leave Sega and join up with NetEase. He says he felt like doing something different and expresses a desire to create games that appeal more outside of Japan, while noting that the studio’s focus will still remain on Japan for the time being. Nagoshi says that going independent will allow his team to develop games without having to consider Sega’s wider business plan and budget, and believes that NetEase is serious about prioritizing the new studio’s creative freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898579/toshihiro-nagoshi-studio-yakuza-series-netease-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898579/toshihiro-nagoshi-studio-yakuza-series-netease-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-23T18:03:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-23T18:03:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Plaid, the service used by Venmo, Acorns, Robinhood, and more, may owe you some money</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BE9Bj_3KNEgsgUlZ7SKuR13vll8=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70423809/1227801650.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Venmo is just one of the many apps that uses Plaid to link your bank account. | Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UKc6EB"&gt;If you’ve connected your bank account to financial apps like Robinhood, Acorns, Venmo, American Express, Coinbase, and Credit Karma, you may be entitled to some cash, according to a report by &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90715125/plaid-might-owe-you-money-if-you-use-any-of-these-banking-or-financial-apps"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fast Company&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8OfHKh"&gt;Plaid, the financial service these apps (and &lt;a href="https://plaid.com/company/"&gt;5,500 others&lt;/a&gt;) use to link your bank account, has &lt;a href="https://www.plaidsettlement.com/index.php"&gt;settled a class-action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; accusing the company of collecting more financial data from users than necessary. The suit also alleges Plaid obtained users’ bank login information “through its user interface, known as ‘Plaid Link,’ which had the look and feel of the user’s own bank account login screen.” In reality, users were inputting their information “directly to Plaid.” Plaid denies these claims and says it was transparent with its customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1MLbeE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Plaid has been ordered to pay $58 million to affected users&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eY8I7h"&gt;Plaid will pay $58 million to affected users, but unfortunately for us, payouts might be slim — &lt;a href="https://plaid.com/blog/leading-fintechs-join-the-plaid-network/"&gt;the company says millions&lt;/a&gt; of people have interacted with its service, which means more money to split up. You may qualify to receive a claim if you’re a US resident who has connected a bank account to an app between January 1st, 2013 and November 19th, 2021. If you’re unsure whether an app you use (or have used) is affected, you can search for specific financial apps on the &lt;a href="https://www.plaidsettlement.com/search.php"&gt;settlement’s site&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to the aforementioned apps, some other popular apps that Plaid powers include Chime, Mint, Betterment, and NerdWallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6K7BXy"&gt;You might’ve already received an email alerting you about the class action lawsuit, and if you have, make sure to &lt;a href="https://www.plaidsettlement.com/submit-claim.php"&gt;submit your claim&lt;/a&gt; by April 28th, 2022. If you didn’t receive an email but think you’ve been affected, you can still file a claim by heading to the same page and hitting the “Click Here” button. From here, you’ll have to fill out a form with your name and address, as well as a list of apps you linked your bank account to. You can find additional details about the settlement on &lt;a href="https://www.plaidsettlement.com/frequently-asked-questions.php"&gt;its FAQ page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22898009/plaid-financial-venmo-acorns-robinhood-class-action-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22898009/plaid-financial-venmo-acorns-robinhood-class-action-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-23T16:05:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-23T16:05:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung Galaxy S22 European price leak suggests a base Ultra model with less RAM</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D9sHrw3Udt7MJDg7K9rph2pgsRI=/15x0:1065x700/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70423539/s22U.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1476660792527306754" target="_blank"&gt;evleaks (Twitter)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="id__l2h9sz0gz0o"&gt;Potential European pricing information for the upcoming Samsung Galaxy S22 series has been released by reliable leaker Roland Quandt, as reported by &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-s22-series-could-be-more-expensive-than-s21/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung appears to have carried over its prices from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"&gt;the previous S21 lineup&lt;/a&gt;, with the only inconsistency being an equally-priced S22 Ultra model that supposedly comes with less RAM than its S21 predecessor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BigvRp"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Whoever said S22 series was to be cheaper, didn't think of Covid, parts shortages and inflation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Actual official EURO prices:&lt;br&gt;S22 8/128GB = 849&lt;br&gt;S22 8/256GB = 899&lt;br&gt;S22+ 8/128GB = 1049&lt;br&gt;S22+ 8/256GB = 1099&lt;br&gt;S22 Ultra 8/128GB = 1249&lt;br&gt;S22 Ultra 12/256GB = 1349&lt;br&gt;S22 Ultra 12/512GB = 1449 &lt;a href="https://t.co/QRnfrhkzTz"&gt;pic.twitter.com/QRnfrhkzTz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Roland Quandt (@rquandt) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rquandt/status/1484689280425414661?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 22, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uShSWX"&gt;Quandt claims the S22 will start at 849€ (~$963), the S22 Plus will set you back 1,049€ (~$1,190), and the base S22 Ultra will cost 1,249€ (~$1,417). It looks like all the base models in the series come with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage — the standard S22 and S22 Plus have a higher-priced option for 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, while the S22 Ultra offers two additional tiers that have 12GB of RAM with either 256GB or 512GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibYYwo"&gt;These prices are identical to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22202864/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-specs-leak"&gt;those of the S21 devices&lt;/a&gt;, but as pointed out by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;, Quandt’s leak indicates the base S22 Ultra may come with just 8GB of RAM instead of the 12GB that the base S21 Ultra has. Despite this, the S22 Ultra may still be the same price as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;the S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; — a 100€ premium will get you the extra 4GB you’re missing out on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pta8hD"&gt;You &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893756/samsung-galaxy-s22-2022-preorders"&gt;can preorder a Galaxy S22 device&lt;/a&gt; before it’s even announced at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893640/samsung-unpacked-february-2022-galaxy-s22-ultra"&gt;Samsung’s February Unpacked&lt;/a&gt; event, which will give you a $50 credit towards your purchase. As &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; points out, US pricing information for the devices &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chunvn8888/status/1480953702177406979"&gt;leaked earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, with the base S22 allegedly starting at $899, the S22 Plus costing $1,099, and the S22 Ultra priced at $1,299. If these prices are true, this would mean a $100 increase across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u2DsEy"&gt;There’s been plenty of leaked information about the S22 series floating around the internet, painting a near-complete picture of what the lineup could look like. Previous leaks show us an S22 Ultra that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/30/22860479/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-leak-official-image-note-design"&gt;resembles the reportedly discontinued Note&lt;/a&gt; (complete with a stylus), while another gives us an early glimpse of what appears to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22870027/samsung-s22-series-unofficial-dummy-leak-design-camera-specs"&gt;all three S22 dummy units in an unboxing video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22897808/samsung-galaxy-s22-european-price-leaks-rumors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22897808/samsung-galaxy-s22-european-price-leaks-rumors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-23T12:47:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-23T12:47:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple extends in-app purchase exemption for online group and event apps yet again</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U44rZ18U7g6Ed8AyBm48Lyz0L4g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70423063/acastro_210831_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vxW3Oj"&gt;Apple has extended its deadline requiring online group and event apps to comply with the company’s in-app purchase policy once again, as announced in a post on &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=i71db0mv&amp;amp;1642879522"&gt;the company’s developer’s blog&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/22/apple-delays-app-store-rules/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Apps in this category can now use alternate payment options until June 30th, allowing them to skirt &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21445923/platform-fees-apps-games-business-marketplace-apple-google"&gt;Apple’s 15 to 30 percent cut&lt;/a&gt; the company takes out of in-app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zTRWcL"&gt;“In 2020, we chose to support apps and developers that needed to adapt services from in-person to digital as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic,” Apple writes in the post. “Given the recent resurgence of COVID and its continued impact on in-person services, we’ve extended the most recent deadline.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="z270vJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple first deferred its rule targeting group event apps in November 2020&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Of0dJM"&gt;Apple introduced &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=xqk627qu"&gt;changes to its in-app purchase policy&lt;/a&gt; in September 2020, clarifying apps that provide “one-to-few and one-to-many realtime experiences,” such as online classes and virtual group events, must process payments through in-app purchases. However, the company changed its rules to permit “person-to-person experiences” consisting of just two people, like medical consultations or real-estate tours, to use other payment methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eU45TI"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/25/21455598/facebook-paid-events-apple-ios-30-percent-fees-waived"&gt;facing criticism&lt;/a&gt; for charging event platforms a commission in the midst of a pandemic, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21595040/apple-developer-in-app-purchase-deadline-online-classes-events"&gt;decided to defer its rule targeting group event apps&lt;/a&gt; in November 2020 and later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398338/apple-iap-classes-events-deadline-december-2021-2022"&gt;extended the reprieve until December 31st, 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22896736/apple-in-app-purchase-exemption-deadline-online-group-services-extended"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/23/22896736/apple-in-app-purchase-exemption-deadline-online-group-services-extended</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
