<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-27T16:20:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T16:20:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T16:20:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft reports weaker Surface and Windows revenue amid global chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HZ4EAHZA_j8H6FO9N3HKitPmXuk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640865/acastro_180507_1777_microsoft_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SASbT5"&gt;Microsoft posted the fourth quarter of its fiscal 2021 &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2FInvestor%2Fearnings%2FFY-2021-Q4%2Fpress-release-webcast" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;financial results today&lt;/a&gt;, reporting revenue of $46.2 billion and a net income of $16.5 billion. Revenue is up 21 percent, and net income has increased by 47 percent. While cloud and Office services have boosted Microsoft’s revenues, it’s clear that the global chip shortage is taking its toll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cLzMY"&gt;With the PC market experiencing its first big growth in 10 years earlier this year, there were some signs recently that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575037/pc-market-q2-growth-slowing-chip-shortage-covid-demand"&gt;laptop and PC sales could be starting to slow again&lt;/a&gt; amid a global chip shortage. Microsoft’s Windows results this quarter reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-QssjzH62OYRWTUFKaGD0FaYJJM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22329299/twarren_210223_4439_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has been on sale for six months now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="37iTxZ"&gt;Windows OEM revenue has declined by three percent, in what Microsoft blames on “supply chain constraints. Windows non-pro OEM revenue also declined four percent, with Windows OEM Pro revenue also down, by 2 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="szUfXb"&gt;Windows commercial products and cloud services revenue has increased 20 percent, though. This includes businesses opting for Microsoft 365, with multi-year agreements and reflects the company’s push towards its bundling of Office and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UvFA8U"&gt;Microsoft is now planning to boost the PC market with the introduction of Windows 11, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22553666/microsoft-windows-11-october-20th-release-date-hint-rumor"&gt;expected to ship&lt;/a&gt; on new devices in October. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557060/microsoft-windows-11-hands-on-preview"&gt;Windows 11 is a visual overhaul&lt;/a&gt; to the operating system, with a new Start menu, updated design, and an overall simplification of Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZLzp2"&gt;This recent quarter is also the first time we’ve seen the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22392778/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-15-inch-review"&gt;Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; combined with sales of the Surface Pro 7 Plus affect overall Surface revenue at Microsoft. Surface revenue has decreased by 20 percent this quarter, “driven by supply constraints” and a strong quarter of Surface sales in the year prior.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cCKi9LX4Iwnl0-ncuhnhaM_cb_k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22012258/vpavic_4275_20201030_0028.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s new Xbox Series consoles are now three quarters into sales.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="E2Qop6"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Series X and Series S consoles are now on their third quarter of sales, after helping grow hardware revenue in recent months. Hardware revenue is up again, as expected, by 172 percent. Microsoft’s overall gaming revenue is up by 11 percent, but Xbox content and services revenue has declined by four percent. Microsoft mentions growth in Xbox Game Pass subscriptions and first-party titles offsetting declines from third-party title revenue during a strong quarter in the year prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDtt5k"&gt;Microsoft has not disclosed new Game Pass subscriber numbers, after the company revealed it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250795/xbox-game-pass-subscribers-growth-microsoft"&gt;18 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt; back in January. Microsoft had been regularly revealing Xbox Game Pass numbers over the past year, but it has now gone two quarters without any updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r0P1YL"&gt;While Microsoft’s Windows and Surface businesses took a hit this quarter, cloud services, Office, and LinkedIn have all seen impressive revenue growth. Office commercial revenue is up 20 percent, and Office consumer revenue up 18 percent. Overall Microsoft 365 consumer subscribers has also jumped to 51.9 million, a 22 percent increase year-over-year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="idakjV"&gt;Server and cloud services revenue grew 34 percent this quarter, with Azure alone up 51 percent. Overall revenue for Microsoft’s Intelligent Cloud business was $17.4 billion, 37 percent of Microsoft’s total revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qco7Fw"&gt;LinkedIn continues to grow well for Microsoft, too. LinkedIn revenue is up 46 percent year-over-year, thanks to stronger advertising demand after a dip during the early stages of the pandemic last year. Microsoft says LinkedIn sessions have grown 30 percent, “with record engagement.” Search advertising revenue is also up 53 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYnTCa"&gt;Microsoft will now hold an earnings call at 5:30PM ET / 3:30PM PT, and we’ll update this article with any relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596578/microsoft-q4-2021-earnings-revenue-xbox-cloud-services-surface-gaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596578/microsoft-q4-2021-earnings-revenue-xbox-cloud-services-surface-gaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T16:06:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T16:06:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 9 Pro review: a refined, niche flagship</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Fast charging and elegant software offset a so-so camera&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="KqtAyf"&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro is a legitimate flagship phone that is genuinely competitive with the best Android phones on the market — at least from a features and quality perspective. Yet in terms of market and mind share, it’s still destined to be a niche device for a small group of enthusiasts looking for a specific kind of elegance in their Android device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hAjS4O"&gt;And that’s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q0Ns9M"&gt;If you live in the US and you’re buying an Android phone, chances are very high that you’ll end up with a Samsung Galaxy phone. Samsung has the carrier relationships, quality, and marketing that have led directly to market share. LG, Motorola, and even &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/vendor-market-share/mobile/united-states-of-america"&gt;sell more phones here than OnePlus does&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4shcPS"&gt;But after nearly seven years and dozens of phones, OnePlus has established itself as a brand that can make great phones that are serious alternatives to the mainstream. The $1069 OnePlus 9 Pro (the only option in North America, other parts of the world have access to a slightly less expensive model) achieves that goal with only a handful of notable compromises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I2jYBg"&gt;OnePlus’ flagship phones always come with a laundry list of top-of-the-line specs, but what makes the OnePlus 9 Pro good isn’t the numbers; it’s how well those specs translate into one of the best experiences you can get using Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AHu1Vy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 9 review: semi-pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"},{"title":"This $159 OnePlus Watch is OnePlus’ first smartwatch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22334322/oneplus-watch-smartwatch-features-price-specs-battery"},{"title":"OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro announced with Hasselblad-branded cameras ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22340406/oneplus-9-phone-price-release-date-availability"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="hpoEZD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10406462"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro has an elegant design, but won’t support 5G on all networks" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NjdZe-bk4k4KgMTns8qChqCoZ-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388892/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0068.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro has an elegant design but won’t support 5G on all networks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bQiCrq"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro hardware design and 5G support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="rZIXVc"&gt;The hardware design on the OnePlus 9 Pro is the most seamless, elegant phone that the company has designed to date. It is, of course, big. It has a 6.7-inch screen that goes from edge to edge in a body that’s narrow enough to make it just barely usable for me in one hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3MZ4NI"&gt;What I can’t help but notice is how far OnePlus has come in build quality. The glass on the front and back curves into the aluminum rail on the edges with no seams at all. It’s well-balanced, beautiful, and solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Top: OnePlus 9 Pro; bottom: Galaxy S20 Plus. Both phones have similarly curved glass and molded aluminum rails." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sTvlAj6Darv2g-R9N0QJ9O44UZk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389264/oneplus9progalaxys20plus.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top: OnePlus 9 Pro. Bottom: Galaxy S20 Plus. Both phones have similarly curved glass and molded aluminum rails.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="It has a three-stage ringer switch" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hAp70uBpGGWtFpcHUizuZRTE4QI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388880/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0054_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It has a three-stage ringer switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QYWqZR"&gt;It’s also the spitting image of a Galaxy S20 Plus. Shift a couple of buttons around, move the selfie camera to the middle, and swap out the logo, and it’s the same design. I get that there are only so many ways to sandwich curved glass and aluminum together, but it’s uncanny. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lSjJvc"&gt;To be fair, OnePlus does keep some of its identity in the three-stage ringer switch, which easily lets you toggle between a ringer, vibration, and fully silent. It may still be my favorite feature on OnePlus phones, and I remain baffled as to why more Android phone makers don’t adopt a physical ringer switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LVSttu"&gt;Speaking of vibration, the haptics on the OnePlus 9 Pro aren’t sloppy at all, unlike many Android phones. Unfortunately, the trade-off is that they aren’t very strong; I often can’t feel it vibrate in my pocket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n6vr0E"&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro has the top-tier Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 processor, which is paired with eight gigs of RAM on the 128GB model. Unfortunately, this configuration isn’t sold in North America — OnePlus originally expected to make it available, but later said that supply constraints led it to offer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577770/oneplus-base-9-pro-north-america-us-canada"&gt;only the more expensive version&lt;/a&gt; with 256GB of storage and 12GB of RAM. There’s no microSD card slot for storage expansion in either model. What you get is what you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EMXoXr"&gt;It supports both Sub-6 and millimeter-wave (mmWave) styles of 5G, but there’s a significant caveat: the phone supports it, but OnePlus has only managed to land 5G certification from its carrier partner, T-Mobile. If you buy it unlocked, as of now, it will only work with T-Mobile’s 5G network. Everything else will be LTE. AT&amp;amp;T 5G support doesn’t appear to be in the cards at all, and as for Verizon, OnePlus says that it “continues to work with Verizon to certify both the 9 and 9 Pro on its 5G network.” Later, on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22353052/oneplus-9-pro-verizon-5g-network-certified"&gt;March 26th, Verizon announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would support 5G on the OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OnePlus’ wireless warp charger can fully charge the phone in under 45 minutes" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gyFkyRjI2k4qCPN085Bz4kQTDBU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388875/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0047.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus’ wireless warp charger can fully charge the phone in under 45 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="w5puLi"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro battery and charging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="zfl3AK"&gt;For OnePlus, the standout spec is its proprietary charging technology. There’s a 65W charger included in the box, and it can charge up the phone ridiculously fast. The phone’s 4,500mAh battery is actually split in two, which helps further speed charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The 65W charger comes in the box (pictured with the regular OnePlus 9)." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bYtldbablBg79ONjjiRExDVLu8E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388874/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0044.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 65W charger comes in the box (pictured with the regular OnePlus 9).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DJcrVY"&gt;If you like, you can spend an additional $69 on OnePlus’ new Warp Charge 50 wireless charger. It charges at 25W, but since the battery is split, it’s essentially the same as charging at 50W, wirelessly. It also works if you set the phone on the charger in landscape mode. With the phone fully dead, it charged completely in 45 minutes. With ambient mode in Google Assistant on, it took a bit longer — but it was still wicked fast compared to other wireless chargers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1P12A6"&gt;That 4,500mAh battery was enough to get me through a full day and a half of moderately heavy usage. However, OnePlus phones do tend to be a little more variable in their battery life depending on use. Spending a day shooting 4K video and pushing the processor with games meant I could kill it with less than four hours of screen-on time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2fG6qV"&gt;So while the battery life might not be best in class, the way OnePlus has built its ecosystem for charging means I’m able to top off faster than I can with other phones — provided I use OnePlus’ proprietary chargers, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro has an LTPO OLED screen, which can help with battery life" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B5cHhLu_Wn4xSxFlJ9pZp5KWWUk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388890/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0066.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro has an LTPO OLED screen, which can help with battery life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X8qQlG"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="OAFOOG"&gt;After wireless charging, the next standout spec on the OnePlus 9 Pro is that 6.7-inch screen. Like Samsung, OnePlus has switched over to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251977/samsung-display-ltpo-display-power-efficient-panel-galaxy-s21-ultra-debut"&gt;an LTPO style of OLED&lt;/a&gt;, which can be more power efficient and allows the company to have more control over the refresh rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vQ9Qor"&gt;The screen can go all the way from 120Hz on down to 1Hz, depending on what’s happening on the display. OnePlus has branded the touch response rate on the screen as “Hyper Touch,” clocked at 360Hz for certain games, and though I am dubious it makes that big a difference for gamers, OnePlus says it could. More consequential is the screen resolution: 1440 x 3216 at 525ppi. You can leave it at that high resolution and have the high refresh rate screen going at the same time. Doing so probably hits battery life, but to me, the point of this max-spec phone is to max the specs, so I didn’t turn down the resolution or the refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yI05D4"&gt;Those are the specs on the screen, but it’s the experience that matters. And again, I think OnePlus has done a remarkable job here. Something about the tuning of the animations in OxygenOS makes this phone feel just a little bit smoother than even Samsung phones. I also appreciate the color tuning — although it’s not as subdued as an iPhone or even a Pixel, it’s more restrained than Samsung’s default settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The whole camera system on the OnePlus 9 Pro is solid, but has room to improve" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SBNXzq7K6YNBtQHo8bKFRoCNvZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388879/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0053_Edit_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The whole camera system on the OnePlus 9 Pro is solid but has room to improve.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0avD9X"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="bt7aQC"&gt;Without delving into a lot of history, I will just point out that until very recently, camera quality has been the main downfall for OnePlus phones. It’s a particularly bad way to fall down, too, because often, the clearest and simplest way to compare phones that otherwise look and perform nearly equivalently is to look at the photos they take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="95RI9o"&gt;OnePlus knows all of this and wants to position the OnePlus 9 Pro as a heads-up competitor — or at least a viable alternative — to the very best Samsung and even Apple have to offer. So it did a thing a lot of challenger brands do: called in a ringer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="G9j19S"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Hasselblad partnership is only about color tuning and interface design this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Xt3br"&gt;That ringer is Hasselblad, which OnePlus is partnering with to improve its camera results. It will be a multiyear effort, and it’s far from guaranteed it’ll be a fruitful partnership. In fact, most of these sorts of deals don’t really do anything notable when it comes to the camera’s quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vhWaA4"&gt;This year, Hasselblad’s participation with OnePlus’ development process amounted to helping the company tune the colors from the camera and lending a bit of its interface to the camera’s Pro mode. Oh, and most importantly for OnePlus, Hasselblad allowed its logo to be stamped next to the lenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QOkITZ"&gt;I do think there’s some credit due to this color-tuning influence. In the same way that other smartphone brands have a “look” to their photos, I think OnePlus is developing its own. iPhone photos are generally flat and neutral, tending to the warm side of color; Pixel photos contrasty and blue; and Samsung photos have the vibrancy slider set to max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OnePlus 9 Pro: indoor with mixed lighting handles color well" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AsREolMsK8SMr90RWIWvZnhRREM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389337/17_LE2125_IMG_20210313_111817.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro: indoor with mixed lighting handles color well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OnePlus tends to ramp up blue colors, which is usually fine but can sometimes get the camera into trouble" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6FOH5Nw3MjM6-pT0VtzW7ay7do8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389338/20_LE2125_IMG_20210313_113526.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus tends to ramp up blue colors, which is usually fine but can sometimes get the camera into trouble.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OnePlus does a good job not adding too much vibrancy when it’s not there in the first place" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XaIF0PK3g-pGh0OMJy-SxrBH9XU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389336/15_LE2125_IMG_20210313_110553.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus does a good job of not adding too much vibrancy when it’s not there in the first place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vFHBSJ"&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro’s image output lands mostly in the middle. It tends toward blue, and it definitely lifts up shadows to create more even lighting. Its photos are more striking but less accurate than what you’ll get out of an iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5yYysn"&gt;The camera system is good, but it can’t quite match the quality you get from an iPhone 12 Pro Max or Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra — both of which cost more than the OnePlus 9 Pro. It handles a variety of conditions quite well, but sometimes I just had to take an extra beat to compose my shot. It let me better judge what the viewfinder was showing and, honestly, gave me time to try the shot again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ps0XCc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10406526"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GnGiG3"&gt;As usual with smartphone cameras, I think the difference comes down to software. I like the colors the 9 Pro produces, but sometimes it just tries too hard and whiffs. Similarly, OnePlus seems to want to bring a little of that Pixel contrast magic to bear but instead just oversharpens. And lightening shadows is sometimes laudable, but not when it adds completely unnecessary and distracting image noise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The camera can try too hard to brighten shadows, introducing noise" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CF7YOM7t6e5tB0A06yC8faoLao4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389355/18_LE2125_IMG_20210313_112304.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The camera can try too hard to brighten shadows, introducing noise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The camera oversharpens sometimes, too. Take a look at the fringing around the runners on the lake in this ultrawide shot" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gDooOLmKNWq0aQR0K3UtcKZlt6Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389354/06_LE2125_IMG_20210311_160459.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The camera oversharpens sometimes, too. Take a look at the fringing around the runners on the lake in this ultrawide shot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jmns55"&gt;The main camera uses a new 48-megapixel Sony sensor with OIS, though when I pressed OnePlus to tell me what exactly that sensor brings to the table, I didn’t really get a clear answer. You can shoot 12-bit RAW images in the Pro mode (which is two bits more than last year, if you’re keeping count). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noaYb1"&gt;That’s all nice, but the interface on Pro mode is what gets me. You can clearly see what’s set to manual and what’s in auto mode. It’s simple and easy to use, too. Best of all is focus peaking, which draws little lines over the part of the image that’s in focus. It is a lot clearer and more fun to use than the tap-to-focus you need to use on other phones. (You can do that here, too, of course.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1qMoum"&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro’s other cameras include a big, 50-megapixel ultrawide with a sensor that’s quite a lot nicer than the usual step-down sensors ultrawides get stuck with. I loved using it right up until it went haywire with sharpening. OnePlus put in a custom lens to help with distortion at the edges, and it works as well or better than pure software fixes at keeping straight lines from bowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sGBpJb"&gt;The telephoto camera is 3.3x, and it’s not anything special at that zoom level. Beyond it, digital zoom is kind of a mess. It gets pantsed by the S21 Ultra with its periscope-style lens. There’s also a monochrome camera that serves only as a helper for the rest of the system, but I suspect it’s not doing anything especially important. OnePlus did drop the gimmicky and pointless “color filter” camera from last year’s 8 Pro this time around. It will probably drop the monochrome camera next year, if I had to guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="exkR3H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10406545"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TReqrH"&gt;OnePlus’ software-focused Nightscape mode works really well for capturing nighttime shots, although to my tastes, it over-brightens the image. Portrait mode is a mixed bag; heads often look artificially cut out from the blurry background. Again, I can get good shots, but portrait mode was often one of those situations where I needed to try the shot a second time. The selfie camera is passable in good light but falls down fast in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DkqOPE"&gt;Unfortunately, video is equally messy. The OnePlus 9 Pro will let you shoot up to 8K 30 or 4K 120, but neither looked good. In fact, regular old 4K 30 has that overprocessed and oversharpened look you see so often from smartphones. The big new feature is improved HDR for backlit subjects, but the effect is minimal at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uC8chD"&gt;That’s a whole pile of critical takes compared to phones that cost more than this phone. But despite the price difference, I think the OnePlus 9 Pro’s camera should be held to as high a standard as possible — it’s a flagship phone. It can sometimes hang with the best of the best, and that’s a win. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pLQs9q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10406554"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can put all your widgets in a drop-down menu instead of on your home screen." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vp8Inx-tnSjKoH9h7Te9rzY7t28=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388878/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0052_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can put all your widgets in a drop-down menu instead of on your home screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZN4UWi"&gt;OnePlus 9 Pro performance and OxygenOS 11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="iYZu5Q"&gt;Even though the camera is often the main differentiator for an Android phone, it’s not necessarily everybody’s highest priority. When I’m not pixel-peeping photos, the OnePlus 9 Pro is the best Android phone I’ve used so far this year. The performance is great. I’m especially impressed with the optical in-screen fingerprint sensor, which is super fast and doesn’t seem to be thrown by weird lighting conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lHyiSQ"&gt;OnePlus’ version of Android is called OxygenOS, and it’s now at version 11. The company has borrowed Samsung’s idea of shifting content down to meet your thumb and added in support for an always-on ambient display. The animations feel smooth, and OnePlus has learned its lesson about how annoying it can be to have apps close in the background too often. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="bWqNDM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;OnePlus has a more elegant version of Android than Samsung&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eOb2Eg"&gt;OnePlus has committed to two major OS updates and three years of bimonthly security updates, which puts it ahead of brands like LG but behind Samsung and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpxgUZ"&gt;You can customize a few things like the font and icons, too. My favorite customization is an ambient display mode that displays a colorful bar that shows how often you’ve been using your phone throughout the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iXAAvg"&gt;One feature borrowed from Apple and / or Microsoft is the ability to put your widgets into a separate panel so they’re not littering your main home screen, accessible via a quick swipe down. I love it, but I wish it wasn’t mapped to the same thing other Android phones use to quickly bring down notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIRq8d"&gt;Mostly, though, OxygenOS just feels &lt;em&gt;chill&lt;/em&gt;, especially compared to Samsung. OnePlus isn’t pushing its own ecosystem of apps and services (though with a new OnePlus Watch coming, perhaps that may change). It’s also not festooning its own apps with advertisements, unlike Samsung. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="waqTIv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10406439"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OxygenOS 11 is smooth and less annoying than other versions of Android" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4zOem1ImZLqI374F-y8Shw2hqF4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388899/vpavic_4481_20210311_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OxygenOS 11 is smooth and less annoying than other versions of Android.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 Pro (top) and OnePlus 9" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_UfNp20O_8zgIzOiysC0tStFCjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388886/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0061_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro (top) and OnePlus 9.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 9 has a slightly smaller screen" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7cetFjAfrRKtYErNsip_4ScK7t4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388898/bfarsace_4481_20210317_0077_Edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 9 (right) has a slightly smaller screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="p8uB5Z"&gt;The OnePlus 9 Pro is not a “flagship killer.” It’s a flagship. Although it still costs a little less than its top-tier competitors, it nevertheless is a pricey phone that makes a lot of promises. Mostly, it delivers on them. Even though a tiny fraction of customers buy OnePlus phones compared to Apple and Samsung, the company has built a track record long enough to deserve its status as an established brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="GhSKH3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The regular OnePlus 9 is a fine choice for most people&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NA5uRY"&gt;If you’re considering one of the new OnePlus phones, I am actually hard-pressed to make the case for the OnePlus 9 Pro over the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;regular OnePlus 9, which Allison Johnson reviewed.&lt;/a&gt; The regular OnePlus 9 is $240 less, and the things you lose are mostly the nice-to-haves that justify the Pro’s existence: fast wireless charging, OIS, a telephoto lens, mmWave 5G, and the slightly larger screen. The cheaper OnePlus 9 lacks telephoto, but its other cameras take photos that are nearly equivalent to the pro. It has a high refresh rate screen, fast wired charging, wireless charging (though it’s not as fast), and most importantly, a nice OnePlus software experience with great performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="mMX9ur"&gt;The reason to opt for the 9 Pro over the regular 9 is in some ways the same reason you’d opt for a OnePlus phone over a Samsung phone in the first place: it’s just a little nicer and a little different than what everybody else has in their pocket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iuxd2s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 26th, 2021 5pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22353052/oneplus-9-pro-verizon-5g-network-certified"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verizon announced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; it would support 5G on the OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro and OnePlus confirmed they will not work on AT&amp;amp;T’s 5G network. The review has been updated to note the new information. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWkLOE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 27th, 2021 4pm ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus has stated that despite its original intention to do so, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577770/oneplus-base-9-pro-north-america-us-canada"&gt;&lt;em&gt;it won’t sell the base model OnePlus 9 Pro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; in North America.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22344840/oneplus-9-pro-review-price-camera-screen-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T16:05:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T16:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter hires the team behind news summary app Brief</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1WMbizYXZud_MuVY7qqIP8Gr8LI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640738/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6rqHiN"&gt;Twitter will be bringing on the team building &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/apple-store/id1475186118?mt=8"&gt;Brief, an app that summarizes news&lt;/a&gt;, the company announced Tuesday. The Brief team, which consists of four people, will work on projects that support features like Spaces and Explore, a Twitter spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0mkEB"&gt;Twitter declined to share details on the terms of the deal, but the spokesperson said that Twitter isn’t buying the Brief business; this is more of an acquihire, as it’s only bringing in the team that worked on the app. The Brief app will be wound down on July 31st, and subscribers will see a notification starting Tuesday about the impending change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JftBHr"&gt;The Brief acquihire continues Twitter’s recent trend of acquisitions and talent pickups for news features. The company bought Scroll, a subscription service that removes ads from news sites, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22417852/twitter-buying-scroll-subscription-service-news-revue-newsletter"&gt;in May&lt;/a&gt;, and said at the time the service would become “a meaningful addition to our subscriptions work.” That hasn’t materialized just yet, though; the Twitter Blue subscription product launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22464291/twitter-blue-subscription-service-canada-australia-undo-reader-mode"&gt;in June in Canada and Australia&lt;/a&gt;, and while it had a reader mode to help you more easily read threads, a Scroll-like feature isn’t part of the product right now. Twitter also bought &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250156/twitter-revue-newsletter-acquisition-email-service"&gt;newsletter service Revue in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596202/twitter-brief-app-news-summary-acquihire"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596202/twitter-brief-app-news-summary-acquihire</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:59:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:59:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is testing notices that tell you if your account is suspended or locked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IhbHj23zuOpPMtmM-Jp8p0HeYHo=/250x0:2950x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640684/E7UeDY7XMAEZChB.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter’s new banners informing users their account has been suspended or locked.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QGt12C"&gt;Twitter is testing new notices that tell you if your account has been suspended or locked and has been put in read-only mode for violating Twitter’s rules. The notices, announced Tuesday, will show up as a banner at the top of your feed. They are in testing across a small percentage of Twitter users on iOS, Android, and the web, a Twitter spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWLuVG"&gt;The company is testing this feature after getting feedback from users that they realized they were suspended or locked and in read-only mode only after trying to tweet or follow new accounts, the Twitter spokesperson says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OHWQIq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Knowing where your account stands is important. We’re testing a new way of letting you know — right when you log in. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If your account is locked or suspended, some of you will start seeing a banner making that clear. &lt;a href="https://t.co/fOP53keghz"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fOP53keghz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1420074309998063619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dqv6gh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1420074309998063619"&gt;The new notices&lt;/a&gt; spell out your status and provide some additional guidance for those who are locked or suspended. If you’ve been permanently suspended, you can submit an appeal, according to one notice, and if your account has been locked, that notice says most accounts get full access back in a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iLuGNv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596615/twitter-notice-banner-suspended-locked-testing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596615/twitter-notice-banner-suspended-locked-testing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:42:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:42:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s controversial Safari redesign is now optional in the latest iPadOS 15 beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r2NTqG0Wv4fNyv2F5EnuN3SpDB4=/0x38:2388x1630/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640581/Polygon.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s current tab design squashes tabs and the search window into a single row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wNRznX"&gt;Apple has started trickling out its fourth iOS and iPadOS 15 betas, taking additional steps back from the bold, and somewhat ill-advised &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;reimagining of Safari it debuted at WWDC 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Now the “compact” tab experience in nu-Safari is entirely optional, and the more traditional separate row of tabs that were &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/14/macos-monterey-beta-3-brings-redesigned-safari-tab-interface-to-address-complaints/"&gt;reintroduced in the third macOS Monterey beta&lt;/a&gt; are heading to iPads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abz55u"&gt;Like in macOS Monterey (and every version of Apple’s desktop OS in recent history), tabs will once again live in their own separate row by default, alleviating some of the crowding that made Apple’s initial compact redesign annoying. The tab experience is now also controlled via a toggle in the Settings app, so if you’re committed to Apple’s original vision, you can enable it with a tap. You can see how the new settings option looks &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1420072648822951937"&gt;in this screenshot shared by Federico Viticci&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8oeYhdOpJD7nTm-832P-ao4o9gU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22743862/E7Uci5YWQAgdOaW.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Federico Viticci&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabs now live in their own dedicated row by default in the fourth beta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qM7Hck0QkrDPh71La9fp3p4IHj0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22743788/E7Uci5VXsAIUWGc.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Federico Viticci&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Safari tab options in Settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OFYAZB"&gt;On iOS 15, the fourth beta also includes the return of the dedicated Reload button, one-tap access to Safari’s Reader mode, and a Share button, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/27/whats-new-in-ios-15-beta-4-safari-changes-focus-tweaks-and-more/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hj0pvY"&gt;These kinds of changes are what beta tests are for, and this all could entirely change again before the fall, but it is somewhat notable that this is the second major tweak &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577475/apple-safari-macos-monterey-ios-15-developer-beta-3-change-design"&gt;Apple’s made to the new Safari&lt;/a&gt;. The company’s dealt with criticism over its design changes in the past (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/apple/2013/6/10/4416726/the-design-of-ios-7-simply-confusing"&gt;like iOS 7’s flat UI&lt;/a&gt;) but making tabs “normal” again by default does seem to suggest that on at least one element of the new Safari, Apple knows it got it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596478/apple-ios-15-beta-safari-tabs-compact-optional"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596478/apple-ios-15-beta-safari-tabs-compact-optional</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:35:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:35:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>CDC reinstitutes mask recommendations for some vaccinated people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Og6RtwKRIetQMQc19-jubMkD6h8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640536/acastro_200512_1777_faceMask_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5KSipX"&gt;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention issued new recommendations today that people who are vaccinated against COVID-19 should wear masks in public, indoor settings in areas with high rates of disease. The CDC also said that students, teachers, and staffers should wear masks in school, even if they’re vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9nl9Jw"&gt;The American Academy of Pediatrics issued &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/all-children-should-wear-masks-school-fall-even-if-vaccinated-n1274358?cid=sm_npd_nn_tw_ma"&gt;similar recommendations&lt;/a&gt; for schools earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNYJ5D"&gt;The announcements are a reversal of the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434645/vaccines-masks-social-distancing-cdc-covid"&gt;May guidance&lt;/a&gt; that fully vaccinated people did not need to wear masks in most situations. At that point, cases counts were falling around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SS8b8D"&gt;Now, the highly contagious Delta variant is spreading around the country and cases are surging in most areas, particularly places with low vaccination rates. COVID-19 vaccines are highly effective at preventing serious cases of the disease and death. But they’re not perfect, and some people who are fully vaccinated can still be infected with the virus. Data from the US and other countries shows that, in rare cases, people who are vaccinated and are infected can get sick and pass the virus to others, CDC Director Rochelle Walensky said in a press briefing today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iSlmfB"&gt;“We thought it was important for people to understand that they can still infect someone. That is important in the case, for example, of vaccinated, individuals who might be going to visit an immunocompromised family member, we wanted to make sure that they have precautions necessary,” Walensky said. Still, “the vast majority of transmission occurring is occurring through unvaccinated individuals,” she said in today’s briefing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noFYe5"&gt;Some places, like Los Angeles County, &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-07-18/la-county-indoor-masks-will-people-follow-rule"&gt;already reinstated mask mandates&lt;/a&gt; for everyone, regardless of vaccination status.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnFnSi"&gt;The CDC did not move more quickly to reinstate mask recommendations because it was worried about appearing to “flip-flop” on the issue, a senior Biden administration official &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/07/27/cdc-masks-guidance-indoors/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Masks have been a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588755/covid-mask-guidance-bad-delta-surge"&gt;chaotic, charged issue&lt;/a&gt; since the beginning of the pandemic, and people have been frustrated by shifting guidelines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o3ZCHb"&gt;Experts say the latest adjustment is an important call in the face of the Delta surge. The recommendations, though, aren’t mandates — it’s up to state and local governments to implement and enforce masking rules. At this point in the pandemic, after officials promised that the end was in sight, getting people to put masks back on &lt;a href="https://www.ksdk.com/article/news/health/coronavirus/local-municipalities-push-back-on-mask-mandate-wildwood-ellisville-chesterfield/63-be7e05f1-c66c-4e38-a2a3-6bd2b4ebd246"&gt;might be a challenge&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22595945/cdc-mask-recommendations-vaccinated-delta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22595945/cdc-mask-recommendations-vaccinated-delta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:31:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:31:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>If you’ve been waiting to play Resident Evil Village on PC, Capcom’s fixed it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fP0UMwViQwtgPB2elRf6VRn9uNU=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640522/RE_Village_Sept_Screens_09.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rK4C6W"&gt;If you bought &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; on PC but put off playing it due to horrible performance issues, you may be in luck. Over three months after the port’s release, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RE_Games/status/1417288163610005506"&gt;Capcom has released an update&lt;/a&gt; to fix performance issues related to DRM and, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-resident-evil-village-pc-is-fixed-but-players-deserve-more"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it appears to have resolved the larger performance issue, too. Before the patch, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-resident-evil-village-pc-is-fixed-but-players-deserve-more"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; frame rates tanking from over 100fps to around 30fps in certain scenes, making the PC version of the game significantly worse to play than the console version. The update also includes support for AMD’s upscaling tech to help improve your frame rates even more, if you’ve &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/technologies/radeon-software-fidelityfx-super-resolution"&gt;got a supported graphics card&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTrIkg"&gt;The problems, which may have been caused by DRM (though Capcom has not confirmed this) were noted both by &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-resident-evil-villages-pc-port-is-disappointing-and-needs-work"&gt;outlets like &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and a good number of &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1196590/Resident_Evil_Village/#app_reviews_hash"&gt;reviewers on the game’s Steam page&lt;/a&gt; (though it is worth noting that the game does still have “Overwhelmingly Positive” Steam reviews overall). Some players noted hitches, stutters, and fps drops, mainly in combat when either killing an enemy or taking damage. &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-resident-evil-village-cracked-performance-beats-official-code"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; noted&lt;/a&gt;, these aren’t exactly ideal times for your game’s performance to tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uR6FzZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;An important update for Resident Evil Village players on Steam:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- FidelityFX Super Resolution (FSR) from AMD is now supported. FSR supports higher frame rates on PC for an improved gaming experience.&lt;br&gt;- Adjustments have been made to optimize the anti-piracy technology.&lt;/p&gt;— Resident Evil (@RE_Games) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RE_Games/status/1417288163610005506?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fW4EbP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;People who actually paid for the PC port were getting a worse experience than pirates&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LU1G8Y"&gt;Worse for Capcom was that the pirated version of the game actually ran significantly better, according to &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-resident-evil-village-cracked-performance-beats-official-code"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt;. A patch &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-village-pirate-says-cracked-release-fixes-1847266974"&gt;released by a pirate who goes by Empress&lt;/a&gt; meant to remove the game’s DRM also reportedly fixed the performance issues, meaning that people who paid for the PC port were getting a worse experience than both pirates and console players. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J5IdTN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NgZewSIXawQ"&gt;has a comparison&lt;/a&gt; between the pre-patch, patched, and pirated versions, which you can watch down below. It provides a good look at what the issues were for those of us who hadn’t had the misfortune of playing the DRM-hampered version — to my eye, the stutters are so noticeable that it almost seems like an intentional effect (similar to how &lt;em&gt;Cuphead&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vaZi9hJbaeA?t=60"&gt;pauses for a split second&lt;/a&gt; after you parry off an attack). Shooting zombies with a shotgun causes the whole game to freeze before the muzzle flash is even off the screen, and encountering one of the game’s Maidens turns the game into a slideshow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PbeC7T"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NgZewSIXawQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="biuJ2E"&gt;The update also added support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545441/amd-dlss-fidelityfx-super-resolution-fsr-supersampling-tests-benchmarks"&gt;AMD’s FidelityFX Super Resolution technology&lt;/a&gt;, which allows users to maintain playable frame rates while running at higher resolutions. The tech achieves this by rendering the game at a lower resolution, then upscaling to your desired resolution, similarly to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22463608/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3080-ti-review-test-benchmarks"&gt;Nvidia’s DLSS&lt;/a&gt;, though the two technologies achieve this through very different means. Nvidia’s version uses AI that’s powered by special hardware included in its newer GPUs, where AMD’s tech &lt;a href="https://gpuopen.com/fidelityfx-superresolution/"&gt;algorithmically upscales frames&lt;/a&gt; that have been anti-aliased. &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt; also does a deep dive on FSR’s effect on &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt;’s frame rate and image quality in the video above.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596290/capcom-resident-evil-village-pc-patch-drm-patch-performance-issues"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596290/capcom-resident-evil-village-pc-patch-drm-patch-performance-issues</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:18:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:18:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile CEO Mike Sievert will deliver CES keynote as the Uncarrier moves mainstream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S7LTQS6vVCjV-lBWgtrHMw7oUEQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640464/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile crafted an underdog image for itself, but its recent moves have looked a lot more mainstream.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6lzkqZ"&gt;Lately, T-Mobile has been looking less and less like the Un-carrier it styled itself as in the past, and much more like A Carrier. To that end, the company made a couple of announcements today: a new 5G coverage milestone, and that CEO Mike Sievert will be delivering a CES keynote in a spot recently occupied by Verizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IO0Tci"&gt;The Consumer Technology Association and T-Mobile made the keynote announcement today, with (you guessed it) 5G as the topic of the hour. It’s been the topic of that particular keynote slot in a couple of recent years, with Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg whipping up the 5G hype machine and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;covering roughly the same talking points&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 and earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJys7T"&gt;Sievert will take the microphone from Vestberg at the start of what’s likely to be a pivotal year for 5G in the US. Verizon will be starting to deploy the C-band spectrum in which it has invested heavily. No doubt, Sievert hopes to shine the spotlight on T-Mobile’s relative spectrum advantage, thanks to its Sprint acquisition last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OQPZl1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile aims to cover 200 million people with ultra capacity 5G by the end of 2021&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wjmiNG"&gt;He’ll also highlight milestones like the one T-Mobile announced today: 305 million people are covered by the company’s slower “extended range” 5G and 165 million covered by its faster, mid-band “ultra capacity” 5G network. With a little less than half a year to go, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Fthe-current-state-of-5g&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F27%2F22596307%2Ft-mobile-ceo-mike-sievert-ces-keynote-5g" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile is driving toward its goal to cover 200 million people&lt;/a&gt; with ultra capacity 5G by the end of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JKDWXS"&gt;In contrast, Verizon, which has to wait for current tenants to clear off its new C-band spectrum, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/verizon-announces-c-band-auction-results" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;expects to cover 100 million people&lt;/a&gt; with mid-band 5G in early 2022. Sievert probably &lt;em&gt;won’t&lt;/em&gt; discuss &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587790/t-mobile-sprint-acquisition-dish-promises"&gt;the network’s bare-minimum efforts to uphold its merger commitments and help position Dish as a competitor&lt;/a&gt;, even though the deal is responsible for delivering T-Mobile its valuable mid-band spectrum and its relative “lead” in 5G, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ngTHLj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sievert probably &lt;em&gt;won’t&lt;/em&gt; discuss the network’s merger commitments to help position Dish as a competitor&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K3yMrl"&gt;T-Mobile is eagerly seizing the moment as Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T work to get C-band deployed, but the more time it spends in the spotlight, the harder it will be to maintain its cool, underdog image. In the meantime, we can definitely expect to see less red and a lot more magenta on consumer tech’s biggest stage early next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596307/t-mobile-ceo-mike-sievert-ces-keynote-5g"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596307/t-mobile-ceo-mike-sievert-ces-keynote-5g</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T15:03:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T15:03:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram Reels can now be twice as long</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dPk7B0-rrYTKj9bBoLuRsb3GUGs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640372/akrales_200423_3988_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="12Y4Gb"&gt;Instagram Reels can now be up to one minute long, double the previous 30-second time limit. Instagram initially debuted Reels with a brief 15-second time cap, then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452278/instagram-reels-update-longer-videos-length-trim-edit"&gt;quickly doubled it&lt;/a&gt; just a month later. Reels is now nearly a year old, so it seems it’s time for an update again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZF73s"&gt;Until recently, TikTok also capped videos at 60 seconds long, and it’s with that time constraint that the platform really blew up. So it’s probably wise that Instagram is expanding its short video limit to give creators a little more space to work with. TikTok’s longer limits were better for cooking videos, storytelling, and plenty more, and they still maintained the app’s quick-flipping pace of programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3hOG7"&gt;TikTok recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558856/tiktok-videos-three-minutes-length"&gt;expanded its limit to three minutes&lt;/a&gt; for all creators, so it’s probably a matter of time before Instagram nudges its cap even further. Instagram has yet to share in detail how well Reels is doing, but Instagram’s leader, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238513/instagram-adam-mosseri-reels-decoder-interview-podcast"&gt;Adam Mosseri, said in January&lt;/a&gt; that “we have to be honest that TikTok is ahead.” For what it’s worth, I saw a ripped Instagram Reels video on TikTok for the first time recently, so that’s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4yYHFQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Reels. up to 60 secs. starting today. &lt;a href="https://t.co/pKWIqtoXU2"&gt;pic.twitter.com/pKWIqtoXU2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Instagram (@instagram) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/instagram/status/1420038313772150785?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596530/instagram-reels-60-seconds-time-extension"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596530/instagram-reels-60-seconds-time-extension</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-27T14:56:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T14:56:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Olympic athletes are competing on an urban heat island</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Land surface temperatures in Tokyo show that it’s an urban heat island." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9ICIkLNKorE2S9PydIj_d3tHwJc=/0x33:720x513/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69640309/tokyo_oli_2019229_lst.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Land surface temperatures in Tokyo show that it’s an urban heat island. | NASA Earth Observatory images by&amp;nbsp;Joshua Stevens, using Landsat data from the&amp;nbsp;U.S. Geological Survey.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OFU5RK"&gt;Nearly unbearable heat and humidity have made competing at the Tokyo Olympics rough — but the urban sprawl of the city is making things even worse. An insidious phenomenon called the “&lt;a href="https://scied.ucar.edu/learning-zone/climate-change-impacts/urban-heat-islands"&gt;urban heat island effect&lt;/a&gt;” shows up in stark temperature maps of the area put together by NASA. Because Tokyo is an urban heat island, it traps heat, making conditions worse for athletes and residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQ5Q92"&gt;The forecast is bad enough on its own. This could be the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583913/summer-olympics-danger-zone-extreme-heat-tokyo"&gt;hottest Olympic games on record&lt;/a&gt;. Air temperatures have already hit 34 degrees Celsius (93 degrees Fahrenheit) since the start of the games. Temperatures will dip a little bit today as a &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-seemingly-cursed-tokyo-olympics-are-now-in-the-path-1847359708"&gt;tropical storm rolls by&lt;/a&gt; — but once that passes, the mercury is &lt;a href="https://www.data.jma.go.jp/tokyo2020/#lang=eng"&gt;expected&lt;/a&gt; to climb back up to sweltering temperatures throughout the rest of the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DXHaQx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tokyo’s asphalt and big buildings trap heat&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8pw7LP"&gt;Compounding the problem, Tokyo’s asphalt and big buildings trap heat. That can make cities &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/heatislands/learn-about-heat-islands"&gt;several degrees warmer than nearby areas&lt;/a&gt; with less urban development and more greenery. (Plants can cool a neighborhood down &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/heatislands/using-trees-and-vegetation-reduce-heat-islands"&gt;through evapotranspiration&lt;/a&gt;, a process similar to how sweat helps a person cool down.) So big cities like Tokyo essentially become “heat islands” surrounded by cooler neighbors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLLTmZ"&gt;Scientists can see this from space. NASA’s satellites specifically tracked &lt;a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/global-maps/MOD_LSTD_M"&gt;land surface temperatures&lt;/a&gt;, which can show how dark, impervious surfaces in cities hold on to heat. They also re-emit that heat, and that warmth can actually &lt;a href="https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/user-guides/sentinel-3-slstr/applications/land-monitoring/land-surface-temperature"&gt;influence the weather&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UC9liS"&gt;The images below show how much hotter Tokyo is compared to forested areas. NASA took the images in August 2019, on a day with similar weather to what athletes are enduring during the Olympics. The agency wasn’t able to get more recent images because of cloud cover this summer (the dark blue patch on the map of land surface temperatures is a cloud), but NASA says the change from cooler rural areas to the hotter city depicted on the map should be the same this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="B2zipx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10671974"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="llegLY"&gt;Athletes can even feel the urban heat island effect on a more micro level. “It’s very hot but also humid. The hardcourts absorb the heat, it stays trapped in there,” tennis player Novak Djokovic said on July 24th, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/sports/tennis-swiatek-makes-quick-start-tokyo-heat-takes-toll-2021-07-24/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. Archer Svetlana Gomboeva was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com./lifestyle/sports/olympics-archery-russian-archer-passes-out-under-tokyos-scorching-heat-2021-07-23/"&gt;treated for heat exhaustion&lt;/a&gt; the day before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tB4rhF"&gt;Climate change makes the urban heat island effect worse, NASA points out in its &lt;a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/148616/heating-up-in-tokyo"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; accompanying the satellite imagery. Since 1900, temperatures in Tokyo have risen by roughly 2.86 degrees Celsius (5.14 degrees Fahrenheit). That’s almost three times as high as the global average for warming, NASA says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rgTY8X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hot summer days are even hotter for many Americans of color ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452777/hot-summer-weather-race-urban-heat-island-us-cities"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9iWKRk"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GZrEFb"&gt; Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="M3u1MT"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Taking NYC’s temperature with a thermal camera|102812" data-volume-uuid="5d6810c5f" data-volume-id="102812" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-900" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596152/athletes-tokyo-2020-olympics-urban-heat-island"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596152/athletes-tokyo-2020-olympics-urban-heat-island</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
