<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-15T12:06:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:06:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:06:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>People aren’t missing their second COVID-19 vaccine dose, CDC data says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-HEALTH-VIRUS-VACCINE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENGF95RLZTyZL-dg2PDUVgCjrho=/0x65:5284x3588/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968384/1231700282.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Caballero-Reynolds / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="beB7vy"&gt;Nearly everyone who got their first dose of a two-shot COVID-19 vaccine got their second dose within the recommended window, according to &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7011e2.htm?s_cid=mm7011e2_e&amp;amp;ACSTrackingID=USCDC_921-DM51989&amp;amp;ACSTrackingLabel=MMWR%20Early%20Release%20-%20Vol.%2070%2C%20March%2015%2C%202021&amp;amp;deliveryName=USCDC_921-DM51989"&gt;new data&lt;/a&gt; from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HOoAbx"&gt;During the first two months of the United States COVID-19 vaccination campaign, around 12 million people got their first dose and were also scheduled for their second dose. The second dose is supposed to be given three weeks after the first for the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine and four weeks for the Moderna vaccine (with a few days’ buffer on each side). In that group, 88 percent of people had their second shot on schedule. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCqsHn"&gt;Around 9 percent of people who had their first shot between December 14th and February 14th had not yet received their second dose but were still within 42 days from their first dose. The CDC says that when a delay is unavoidable, people can wait that long. Three percent of people were outside of the 42-day window and had missed the dose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="379OT5"&gt;To look at those numbers in a different way, the CDC also looked at everyone who’d received a &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; dose during those two months to see how many people received it within the recommended period. Over 95 percent of people were on schedule. Just under 3 percent of people were late (but within the 42-day window), and 1.5 percent of people had their second injection early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7wwh7f"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Over 95 percent of people were on schedule&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uUDySe"&gt;Such high numbers of people getting their second dose — and getting it on time — are reassuring, the CDC wrote in its report. The Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna vaccines may have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163146/covid-vaccine-fda-review-safe-effective-time-pfizer-biontech"&gt;some protection&lt;/a&gt; with just one dose, but a single dose wasn’t part of the clinical trials, and it’s not clear how long that protection might last. The second shot &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21587664/pfizer-moderna-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-two-doses-shots"&gt;boosts the immune system&lt;/a&gt; and gives people the full benefits of the vaccines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGFiTt"&gt;When the COVID-19 vaccines were developed and authorized, experts worried about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;challenges&lt;/a&gt; of a two-shot series. They were concerned they would struggle to bring people back in for a second shot. In other multidose vaccines, like the HPV vaccine and the shingles vaccine, there’s &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/coronavirus-covid-19/issue-brief/what-does-a-multi-dose-series-mean-for-the-covid-19-vaccination-effort/"&gt;a drop-off&lt;/a&gt;. Around a quarter of people who get their first shingles shot don’t get a second, and only around half of people finish a three-shot HPV vaccine series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aDrKfM"&gt;Despite the low numbers of people missing a second dose, CDC director Rochelle Walensky said the agency is still hoping to close even the small gap. “CDC is working across the government and with state and local partners to identify and address barriers to getting both doses,” she said during a press briefing today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9ZMnN"&gt;States and health organizations have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;high- and low-tech strategies&lt;/a&gt; to get people back in for the correct second dose. Many central state immunization registries can notify doctors and patients when people are due for a second dose. So can electronic health records. Everyone who gets a COVID-19 vaccine also gets a card that tells them when their second dose should be, and which vaccine they got. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTvA7G"&gt;The CDC data shows that those methods seem to be working. It’s consistent with anecdotal reports from immunizers. “I am not hearing major challenges with bringing people back in,” Claire Hannan, the executive director of the Association of Immunization Managers, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in February. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TzAmvQ"&gt;However, the CDC noted in its report that most people who received the COVID-19 vaccine during the first two months they were available were health care workers and residents in long-term care facilities because they were the first to be eligible. Those groups may be more likely to stick to the schedule because they could get vaccinated where they work or live. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJT3Bh"&gt;The CDC report also says that 90,484 people got the first dose of one vaccine and the second dose of another — 0.2 percent of the total. The agency &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/covid-19/info-by-product/clinical-considerations.html"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna vaccines should not be mixed except in the most exceptional circumstances when a second dose of the same brand is not available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h44ltA"&gt;Over &lt;a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations"&gt;37 million people&lt;/a&gt; in the United States are now fully vaccinated, either through two doses of the Pfizer / BioNTech or Moderna vaccine or one dose of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315138/covid-vaccine-single-shot-johnson-distribution"&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine&lt;/a&gt;, which only takes one shot. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331619/covid-vaccine-second-dose-cdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331619/covid-vaccine-second-dose-cdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:05:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:05:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cruise acquires Voyage in another autonomous vehicle merger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X9G40bFen5UdxbHqSVMsVZFlDoM=/319x0:3777x2305/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968378/Ewh6OQ3UcAAUIjy.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PfPYz0"&gt;Cruise, a majority-owned subsidiary of General Motors, will acquire self-driving startup Voyage in another major autonomous vehicle merger. The announcement came less than a week after news first surfaced that the two companies were in talks about an acquisition. The terms of the deal were not disclosed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4F2u5v"&gt;Cruise mainly operates its autonomous vehicles in dense, urban settings like downtown San Francisco, while Voyage oversees a fleet of low-speed autonomous vehicles providing trips to residents of several &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/10/16874410/voyage-self-driving-cars-villages-florida-retirement-communities"&gt;retirement communities&lt;/a&gt;. Both companies have tested their vehicles without a safety driver behind the wheel and aspire to launch full-fledged commercial robot taxi services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5NMOjP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The self-driving industry is consolidating”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ysUpK1"&gt;“The self-driving industry is consolidating, and the leaders of a trillion-dollar market are fast emerging,” Voyage CEO Oliver Cameron said &lt;a href="https://news.voyage.auto/voyage-acquired-by-cruise-d5f76011032f"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “After being intimately involved with the AV industry for the last five years, I can say with certainty that Cruise — with its advanced self-driving technology, unique auto-maker partnerships, and all-electric purpose-built vehicle with no human controls — is poised to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; clear leader.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ON1hzq"&gt;Voyage is a spinoff from Udacity, an online learning service that offers courses in driverless technology. Cameron headed the startup’s open-source self-driving project before launching his own venture. Sebastian Thrun, Udacity’s chairman and one of the founders of Google’s self-driving car project, was briefly chairman of Voyage before a conflict forced him to step down. The company operates a fleet of self-driving cars in two retirement communities, one near San Jose, California, and the other north of Orlando, Florida, both called The Villages. But Voyage doesn’t want to be seen as the exclusive AV service for senior citizens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWO6IB"&gt;“I think sometimes people think Voyage is all about just low speed, zero to 25 mile-an-hour autonomy,” Cameron said in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/12/20862659/voyage-self-driving-startup-funding-oliver-cameron"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. “We’re not. We’re going to expand our capabilities over time, to zero to 35 [mph], to zero to 55 [mph], to zero to 65 [mph]. And one day we’ll connect all the roadways in the US with a Level 4 self-driving car. But we’re not going to say that’ll be delivered next year. And we’re not going to wait to build a business before that’s ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rdm8U5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think sometimes people think Voyage is all about just low speed, zero to 25 mile-an-hour autonomy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F1TYLI"&gt;Cruise is certainly one of the best capitalized autonomous vehicle companies in the world. In 2018, it secured both a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/31/17412716/gm-cruise-self-driving-car-softbank-investment"&gt;$2.25 billion investment from the SoftBank&lt;/a&gt; Vision Fund and a $2 billion investment from Honda. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18535194/gm-cruise-self-driving-car-investment-valuation"&gt;Cruise landed a $1.15 billion investment&lt;/a&gt; from GM, SoftBank, Honda, and T. Rowe Price Group, which put the company’s valuation at $19 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNEUhy"&gt;There have been a rash of mergers in the world of autonomous vehicles over the past few years: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/26/21304111/amazon-zoox-acquisition-self-driving-car-autonomous-vehicles-startup-robotaxi-bi-directional-vehicle"&gt;Amazon acquired Zoox&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;Aurora absorbed Uber’s autonomous vehicle division&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18758820/drive-ai-self-driving-startup-shutting-down-apple"&gt;Apple bought distressed startup Drive.ai&lt;/a&gt; and was (at one point) considering a tie-up with Hyundai; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/13/14906304/intel-mobileye-acquisition-self-driving-cars"&gt;Intel bought Mobileye&lt;/a&gt;; and Delphi acquired nuTonomy and became Aptiv, which then joined with Hyundai to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362322/hyundai-aptiv-motional-autonomous-vehicle-joint-venture"&gt;become Motional&lt;/a&gt;. The AV industry has gotten smaller as target dates for mass adoption of autonomous vehicles gets further away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ENHHrR"&gt;Cruise recently began testing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165597/cruise-driverless-test-san-francisco-self-driving-level-4"&gt;fully driverless vehicles in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, but the company still doesn’t allow non-employees to ride in its vehicles. Cruise had planned to launch a commercial taxi service in 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707242/cruise-gm-self-driving-taxi-launch-delay-2019"&gt;but failed to do so&lt;/a&gt;, and it has yet to publicly commit to a new date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3z0Tjz"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21075977/cruise-driverless-car-gm-no-steering-wheel-pedals-ev-exclusive-first-look"&gt;Cruise unveiled the Cruise Origin&lt;/a&gt;, a fully driverless prototype vehicle without a steering wheel, pedals, or any controls typically associated with human driving. The vehicle, which will go into production at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519358/gm-factory-zero-detroit-hamtramck-electric-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;GM’s Detroit-Hamtramck plant&lt;/a&gt;, is built to be shared by multiple passengers — though it remains to be seen how much appetite there is for shared vehicles in a post-COVID world. Cruise recently unveiled a new set of safety protocols intended to keep people socially distant during trips and the vehicle sanitized between fares.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331794/cruise-acquires-voyage-self-driving-car-merger"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331794/cruise-acquires-voyage-self-driving-car-merger</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T11:15:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T11:15:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the biggest announcements from Volkswagen’s battery event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtNDNts9qhH3ZXNNba-ifqK4fDM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967900/akrales_200915_4161_0071.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L5DmnU"&gt;Volkswagen Group unveiled a massive push to drive down the cost of producing batteries for its electric vehicles in the hopes of speeding the transition away from gas-powered cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NEZVvc"&gt;The automaker, which is the second largest in the world based on sales, said it would reduce the costs of producing its batteries by up to 50 percent, build multiple battery factories around the world, expand its network of charging stations, and eventually transition to solid-state technology that would cut costs and boost efficiency. The ultimate goal is to make electric cars with longer ranges and quicker charging times — two of the biggest barriers to mass EV adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TzXehC"&gt;The race for huge improvements in battery technology is one of the most expensive and hotly contested on the planet right now. Practically every automaker is betting that electric vehicles will be the future, with some of the largest countries (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452825/california-ban-combustion-gas-vehicles-cars-2035"&gt;largest auto markets&lt;/a&gt;) in the world moving to phase out gas-powered cars and trucks. To ensure that shift, batteries need to be more powerful, last longer, and be cheaper to make in order to entice enough customers to make the switch from gas to electric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oG2jgp"&gt;“Our transformation will be fast, it will be unprecedented,” said VW Group CEO Herbert Diess. “The transformation will be bigger than anything the industry has seen in the last century.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tqjWS3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Our transformation will be fast, it will be unprecedented”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6tMMeV"&gt;The automaker’s nearly two-hour “Power Day” was widely seen as an echo of Tesla’s recent “Battery Day” event. Both automakers touched on issues around battery chemistry, supply chain, production, and charging as a way to make electric vehicles more affordable and attractive to a wider swath of customers. Here are the biggest announcements from VW’s Power Day event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MMTNyX"&gt;Unified battery cells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="b7gpYB"&gt;Starting in 2023, VW plans to roll out a new unified prismatic cell design of its batteries that will be installed across the automaker’s brands. The goal is to have this unified cell design powering up to 80 percent of VW’s electric vehicles by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gnJpMX"&gt;Thomas Schmall, Volkswagen Group Board Member for Technology, said the goal was to drive down the cost of battery production below $100 per kWh, which most experts believe will make EVs roughly the same price as gas-powered vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yb7Hhi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A picture of the unified cell. &lt;a href="https://t.co/OusTHdgwB8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OusTHdgwB8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jordi Sastre (@jordi_sastr3) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jordi_sastr3/status/1371444247178584068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h8XKMl"&gt;The price per kilowatt-hour (kWh) is the unit of energy most commonly used to measure the capacity of the battery packs in modern electric vehicles. Those prices have been falling dramatically over the last decade, from $1,100 / kWh in 2010 to $156 / kWh in 2019, a drop of 87 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyZoVU"&gt;“We aim to reduce the cost and complexity of the battery and at the same time increase its range and performance,” Schmall said. “This will finally make e-mobility affordable and the dominant drive technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyuGQ9"&gt;VW hopes to drive the cost down even further with more efficient production and a robust recycling process. The automaker aims to “gradually” reduce battery costs in the entry-level segment by up to 50 percent and in the volume segment by up to 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="udof4L"&gt;Volkswagen “gigafactories”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oFPjJy"&gt;One way Volkswagen plans to boost production of battery-powered vehicles is through a massive expansion of its manufacturing footprint. The automaker plans to have six battery cell production plants operating in Europe by 2030, which it will build alone or with partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1IjLg"&gt;The first two plants will be in Salzgitter, Germany, and Skelleftea, Sweden; a third plant will be established either in Spain, Portugal, or France; and the fourth factory will be based in Eastern Europe. The plants will have a production capacity of 240 gigawatt-hours a year, Schmall said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuo1Nk"&gt;On the same day as VW’s event, Swedish battery maker Northvolt said it had received an order from the automaker worth $14 billion. Northvolt will also sell its share in joint-venture Northvolt Zwei to Volkswagen. The Swedish company has said it plans to increase its market share in Europe to 25 percent by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="UCbMoT"&gt;Charging expansion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="COuuIV"&gt;Volkswagen said it intends to have 18,000 public fast-charging points in operation in Europe by 2025, a fivefold increase over the current state of EV charging in the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJSUJK"&gt;This will be accomplished through a series of strategic partnerships that were announced today. VW said it would team up with oil giant BP and top European utilities Enel and Iberdrola to expand electric vehicle charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dP583O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;18,000 public fast-charging points in Europe by 2025&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LpvAua"&gt;With BP, Volkswagen said it wants to establish about 8,000 fast-charging points throughout Europe, with most of the stations concentrated in Germany and the UK. The fast-chargers with a charging capacity of 150 kW will be installed at a total of 4,000 BP and ARAL fuel stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKpgNh"&gt;In partnership with Spain’s Iberdrola, Volkswagen will cover main traffic routes across that country. In Italy, Volkswagen will work with Enel to establish fast-charging stations along major highways and in urban areas. The automaker plans to spend about €400 million to expand its European EV charging network by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VOMDqZ"&gt;The company also said it would have 17,000 public fast-charging stations in China and was on track to reach 800 stations in the US through its Electrify America subsidiary by the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="t124AQ"&gt;Two-way charging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tYZGl5"&gt;Starting in 2022, vehicles built on VW’s modular MEB electric vehicle platform will support bidirectional, or two-way, charging. “This will allow green electricity from the solar energy system to be stored in the vehicle and fed back into the home network if needed,” the company said. “Not only will customers be more independent of the public power grid, they will also save money and reduce CO2 emissions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12vT74"&gt;VW plans to offer a range of products to enable this, including a home energy storage system and a mobile EV charger that is unconnected from the grid. This will enable car owners to “become their own utility,” the company claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dt6u0y"&gt;The company also unveiled an adorable EV charger robot intended for fleet owners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WjFxSR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Is this a robotic EV charger? &lt;a href="https://t.co/FiZTYo1Xg3"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FiZTYo1Xg3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jordi Sastre (@jordi_sastr3) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jordi_sastr3/status/1371449999482105857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fpBkJr"&gt;Why now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hzMx8T"&gt;Volkswagen will need to boost its battery expertise and secure its supply chain if it is to deliver on its bold promise of making electric vehicles 50 percent of its sales in the US by 2030. The company recently unveiled a &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a35741685/vw-to-build-ev-trinity-2026/"&gt;concept sedan called Trinity&lt;/a&gt; that it promised would feature “high range” and “short charging time” by 2026. The automaker’s mass-manufactured modular electric vehicle platform, or “MEB,” will serve as the foundation for this massive shift. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W5ZcZp"&gt;Volkswagen announced the MEB platform in 2018 as part of its multibillion-dollar push into electric vehicles. It consists of a modular battery pack that can scale to fit differently sized vehicles, a motor, and other electronics — basically all of the technical underpinnings required to make an electric vehicle move. All of Volkswagen’s upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21288572/volkswagen-id3-ev-delay-software-vw-herbert-diess"&gt;ID-branded electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt; are being built on the MEB platform, and it will also power certain vehicles from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21316580/audi-q4-etron-sportback-suv-2021-volkswagen-meb"&gt;Volkswagen Group brands like Audi&lt;/a&gt;, Seat, and Skoda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgAIBB"&gt;Volkswagen &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/volkswagen-share-meb-electric-car-platform/"&gt;has said it plans to sell access to MEB&lt;/a&gt;, an idea that already attracted Ford, which is going to build a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/12/20690722/ford-vw-alliance-self-driving-argo-investment-valuation"&gt;commercial vehicle powered by the German automaker’s platform&lt;/a&gt;. But it is also open to partnering with startups. The first attempt, with Germany’s e.Go Mobile, fell apart after the &lt;a href="https://www.electrive.com/2020/06/22/vw-will-not-produce-the-id-buggy/"&gt;small startup became insolvent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ac8i9k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The race for huge improvements in battery technology is one of the most expensive and hotly contested on the planet right now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4o7kTi"&gt;VW, which is the second largest automaker in the world based on volume, just released its first pair of long-range EVs, the Europe-only ID 3 hatchback and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22302883/vw-id4-review-volkswagen-ev-specs-range-photos-video"&gt;the ID 4 compact SUV&lt;/a&gt;, which just started making deliveries in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPu74d"&gt;Initially, the ID 4’s battery pack, which is comprised of 288 pouch cells in 12 modules, will be produced by South Korea’s LG Chem. But once ID 4 production shifts to Chattanooga, Tennessee, in 2022, the batteries will be &lt;a href="https://www.timesfreepress.com/news/breakingnews/story/2020/jun/26/sk-innovation-plans-940-million-expansion-georgia/526225/"&gt;supplied by SK Innovation&lt;/a&gt;, another South Korean company that recently opened a $2 billion factory nearby VW’s plant there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9fY5Yg"&gt;Before the event, reports surfaced that VW would be pivoting away from its main battery supplier, South Korea’s LG Chem, and was turning to China’s CATL, &lt;a href="https://www.autonews.com/technology/vw-switch-ev-battery-type-leaving-supply-deals-doubt-report-says"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Automotive News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;citing South Korea’s &lt;em&gt;Money Today&lt;/em&gt; online news site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5VZLD"&gt;VW also has contracts with two other major battery producers, Samsung and CATL. And the company is backing a startup based in San Jose, California, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22158573/quantumscape-solid-state-battery-ev-range-charge-vw"&gt;QuantumScape&lt;/a&gt;, which is working on more energy-efficient solid-state batteries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qnzYYn"&gt;QuantumScape says its solid-state batteries will represent a significant improvement over conventional lithium-ion batteries, enabling electric vehicles that can travel 80 percent further than an EV with a traditional battery. They retain more than 80 percent of their capacity after 800 charging cycles, they’re noncombustible, and they’ll have volumetric energy density of more than 1,000 watt-hours per liter at the cell level, which is nearly double the density of top-rate commercial lithium-ion packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7HBt3n"&gt;VW called solid-state batteries “the end game.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22325813/vw-volkswagen-power-day-battery-electric-car-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22325813/vw-volkswagen-power-day-battery-electric-car-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T11:15:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T11:15:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch GDC’s digital showcase</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o1yZD2-vl_peGa0fwEVrdpS4rcI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967896/acastro_200302_1777_GDC_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LKuc9L"&gt;The 2021 Game Developers Conference will be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22290109/gdc-digital-only-masterclass-showcase-2021"&gt;entirely digital&lt;/a&gt; this year. Organizers scrapped a previous plan that would have incorporated in-person events, opting instead to split the traditionally weeklong event into three parts. &lt;a href="https://showcase.gdconf.com/?MCAID=77FB1CFE532B22840A490D45@AdobeOrg"&gt;GDC Showcase&lt;/a&gt;, a mix of old and new lectures, kicks off this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNXop4"&gt;A full schedule is available on GDC’s official site for talks running March 15th-19th. The Showcase is free to all attendees but requires &lt;a href="https://gdconf.com/showcase?MCAID=77FB1CFE532B22840A490D45AdobeOrg"&gt;registration&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to popular talks from previous years, like Leighton Gray’s &lt;a href="https://showcase.gdconf.com/session/dream-daddies-and-fearful-fathers-how-indies-can-cope-with-being-terminally-online/878688"&gt;“terminally online” presentation&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Dream Daddy&lt;/em&gt;’s success, there will also be several live Q&amp;amp;As. Obsidian Entertainment’s Carrie Patel, PlayStation Studio’s Gavin Moore, and Yacht Club’s David D’Angelo will answer questions about their work and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mIUrNt"&gt;GDC Masterclass, virtual workshops for developers, took place March 4th and 5th. This year’s biggest event, a weeklong slate of multitrack events focused on education and business, is set to take place July 19th-23rd. The Independent Games Festival and Game Developers Choice Awards are set for July 21st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ViTxjP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yWpyzQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZuCdf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22319702/gdc-digital-showcase-how-to-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22319702/gdc-digital-showcase-how-to-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T10:22:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T10:22:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s new beta driver unlocks RTX 3060 Ethereum cryptocurrency mining</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AE_BPflkqyhAubLJI2g46LLBDxM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967573/acastro_180529_1777_nvidia_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LhdJQL"&gt;Nvidia implemented a special system to reduce the hash rate of Ethereum mining on its new RTX 3060 graphics card last month. It was supposed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289154/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency"&gt;limit mining performance by around 50 percent&lt;/a&gt;, but multiple reports now claim cryptominers have bypassed the protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6c9rT"&gt;Japanese site &lt;a href="https://pc.watch.impress.co.jp/docs/news/yajiuma/1312/085/index.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PC Watch &lt;/em&gt;first revealed&lt;/a&gt; that Nvidia’s protections can be bypassed without needing to modify a driver or BIOS. &lt;a href="https://www.computerbase.de/2021-03/mining-bremse-geforce-rtx-3060-umgehbar-eth-hashrate/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ComputerBase&lt;/em&gt; has since confirmed&lt;/a&gt; PC Watch’s report and revealed that Nvidia’s latest &lt;a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda/wsl/download"&gt;470.05 beta driver&lt;/a&gt; is automatically unlocking performance for most RTX 3060 owners. Andreas Schilling, an editor at &lt;em&gt;Hardwareluxx&lt;/em&gt;, has also &lt;a href="https://www.hardwareluxx.de/index.php/news/hardware/grafikkarten/55694-ethereum-mining-bremse-der-geforce-rtx-3060-umgangen-update.html"&gt;backed up these findings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Lce21i"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A variety of RTX 3060 cards seem to be working with this beta driver&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Qxu8T"&gt;The beta driver appears to unlock Ethereum mining performance across a variety of RTX 3060 cards, which was likely not what Nvidia had planned for its test drivers. The 470.05 driver is designed for developers to test the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) performance and new features like OpenCL 3.0 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIY2kC"&gt;Nvidia originally restricted RTX 3060 mining performance in an attempt to steer cryptominers away from purchasing the cards. Nvidia is offering a new Cryptocurrency Mining Processor (CMP) for Ethereum miners instead. The beta driver bypass of Ethereum mining performance will certainly make the cards more attractive to cryptominers now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GypUvN"&gt;Nvidia seemed confident in its software restrictions to nerf RTX 3060 mining performance. “It’s not just a driver thing,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bdelrizzo/status/1362619264423747590"&gt;said Bryan Del Rizzo&lt;/a&gt;, Nvidia’s head of communications, last month. “There is a secure handshake between the driver, the RTX 3060 silicon, and the BIOS (firmware) that prevents removal of the hash rate limiter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4qp60x"&gt;We’ve reached out to Nvidia to comment on this new beta driver, and we’ll update you accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331537/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-cryptocurrency-mining"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331537/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-cryptocurrency-mining</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T10:19:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T10:19:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon expands gamification program that encourages warehouse employees to work harder</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/30jhdeL4gdh1lEtMatbAxZZeE5s=/0x0:5789x3859/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967565/1177531269.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Philippe Lopez/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vl5TGk"&gt;Amazon is expanding an existing program that gamifies warehouse work to encourage its fulfillment center employees to improve their efficiency and compete against others for digital rewards like virtual pets, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/amazon-expands-effort-to-gamify-warehouse-work"&gt;new report from &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The program is called FC Games, and it includes as many as six arcade-style mini-games that can be played only by completing warehouse tasks in the workplace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Smbu2R"&gt;It’s been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/22/18635272/amazon-warehouse-working-conditions-gamification-video-games"&gt;known since at least 2019&lt;/a&gt; that Amazon uses gamification in the form of workstation games to try to incentivize employees to improve productivity, but &lt;em&gt;The Information &lt;/em&gt;reports that Amazon is now expanding those methods to warehouses in at least 20 states throughout the country. Many of the games tend to be simple virtual representations of how fast the worker is completing a task. One, called MissionRacer, moves a car around a track while a picking employee sorts products into appropriate boxes, as reported by &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/21/missionracer-how-amazon-turned-tedium-warehouse-work-into-game/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;at the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="neFAoq"&gt;“Employees have told us they enjoy having the option to join in these workstation games, and we’re excited to be taking their feedback and expanding the program to even more buildings throughout our network,” Kent Hollenbeck, an Amazon spokesperson, tells &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;. “Even with this expansion, the program remains completely optional for employees; they can switch in or out of different games depending on their preference, can play anonymously, or not play at all—the choice is theirs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="uA1zhk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon uses mini-games at its warehouse workstations to improve productivity&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xdVjFo"&gt;Some employees quoted in the report say the games are popular because they can help cut down on the tediousness and repetition of a nearly half-day warehouse shift. Others fear it’s one step toward an even more sinister and dystopian metrics system designed to track employees and encourage them to work as hard and fast as possible. (The image of humans measured through gamification metrics conjures the infamous season 1 episode, “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EqTyZoupc1w"&gt;Fifteen Million Merits&lt;/a&gt;,” of the British science fiction show &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUjdun"&gt;The rewards earned by playing the workstation games can be turned in for virtual pets, including penguins and dinosaurs, according to &lt;em&gt;The Information, &lt;/em&gt;although it’s not clear these pets have any value or whether they can be changed for anything. Another of Amazon’s mini-games is called Tamazilla, a play on the popular Bandai digital pet product Tamagotchi, while others are more competitive and pit employees’ scores against workers at other warehouses around the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dCRI2q"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;reported in 2019, some employees have used FC Games performance to ask for more so-called swag bucks, a proprietary Amazon currency that can be exchanged for company merchandise like T-shirts and water bottles. &lt;em&gt;The Information &lt;/em&gt;report also says that during busy holiday rushes, warehouse employees can win pricey consumer electronics, like game consoles or an Apple Watch, by performing well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sJ7x3d"&gt;But the games themselves are not designed to reward employees with tangible, real-world benefits, the report says, and are instead ways for Amazon to help measure and encourage productivity as warehouse work becomes increasingly more tedious. The company is in the years-long process of automating many elements of warehouse work using robotics. The ultimate goal is ostensibly to eliminate the most repetitive and dangerous jobs. Yet, the result of this hybrid workplace in the interim is that humans are being forced into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/27/21155254/automation-robots-unemployment-jobs-vs-human-google-amazon"&gt;more specialized, often rote roles that involve less movement and more repetition&lt;/a&gt; with an increasing focus on metrics that gauge work performance like one measures the effectiveness of a robot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx2AV2"&gt;In many cases, robots fetch items and bring them to humans to sort, and Amazon has not shied away from its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18526092/amazon-warehouse-robotics-automation-ai-10-years-away"&gt;ambitions to automate large swaths of its warehouse work&lt;/a&gt; in the future. Yet, Amazon warehouses with automation have been shown to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493752/amazon-warehouses-robots-higher-injury-rates-report-reveal"&gt;actually have higher injury rates than those that rely entirely on humans&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331502/amazon-warehouse-gamification-program-expand-fc-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331502/amazon-warehouse-gamification-program-expand-fc-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s Xbox Wireless Headset is a mic-drop moment</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The best budget-friendly headset for Xbox cuts very few corners&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="18Tu1w"&gt;Microsoft’s new $99 Xbox Wireless headset isn’t perfect, but it’s the best attempt at being an Xbox gaming headset and an everyday set of wireless headphones I’ve tried yet. It’s compatible with the Xbox Wireless protocol, making it easy to pair with any Xbox One or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"&gt;S&lt;/a&gt; console. It’s also compatible with Bluetooth (version 4.2, SBC codec), and better yet, it can connect through both protocols simultaneously. So you can take a call or have audio from any app come through from a phone, tablet, or a PC mixed in with the sound coming from your Xbox console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pym0p3"&gt;This is far from the first gaming headset to do this, or even do it well. Microsoft’s latest headset just stands out as being particularly impressive for the number of things it gets right for $99. Its design is stellar, a logical fit in the company’s headphone lineup. Next to the Series X, it looks the part with a touch of glossy green detailing around the ear cup dials, covered in matte black plastic. The little holes in the recessed areas between the faux leather ear pads and the dials seem to be there just for cosmetic reasons, but it looks fantastic nevertheless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="roexZK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10387161"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DS9nuI"&gt;Crucially, these are comfortable, even though my head size nearly pushes them to their size limits. The sidearms require two hands to make adjustments, which I like. There’s no worry that they’ll resize just from being moved around. And while I wish this model had a bungee-style headband and swiveling ear cups like most SteelSeries headsets, not having these features didn’t equate to comfort issues here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S24wqX"&gt;In addition to how the headset looks, its functionality is similar to the Surface Headphones, with twistable dials on the outside of each ear cup for adjusting elements of the audio. Unlike the company’s more premium headphones, there’s no active noise cancellation here (I’d complain, but they’re $99), though the passive noise isolation is better than average for this price. The left dial acts as a chat and game audio mixer, so you can tune your playmates down a bit during a dialogue-heavy cutscene or vice versa. I appreciate that Microsoft put it front and center. On the other dial is the volume control. Twist to increase or decrease, nice and simple — no buttons necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EROyPAjGtRSmBN7ajrHrigTdHDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363677/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The green button pulls double duty, serving as the pairing and power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rR2bCiXK85_7eHXSsFkqe3vX1XM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363685/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s an LED on the mic facing your, well, face, indicating when the mic is active.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JOKh5H"&gt;Over on the right ear cup, there’s a USB-C port for charging. Microsoft includes a USB-C to USB Type-A cable to charge it, but you’ll get all of the same headset features if you plug into a Windows 10 machine with your own USB-C to USB-C cable. That’s not the case when plugged into a MacBook Pro, which won’t work over a wired connection with the headset. You can still connect to a macOS device and use the headset over Bluetooth, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="x8eeqr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming headsets to buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ZDpKTn"&gt;There are only two buttons on the headset: one to manually mute the bendable microphone (an LED on the inner section of the boom microphone angled toward your face is illuminated when the mic is hot), and another that serves as the all-in-one pairing and power button, both of which reside on the left ear cup. Most gaming headsets require days of continued use to fully learn their respective button layouts, but this one’s dead simple. I would have taken one more button if it served as a multifunction button to control my device over Bluetooth, but Microsoft has limited the headset to just two buttons. There’s no way to independently control, say, a phone outside of just adjusting the volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DQuG3"&gt;The sound performance from this headset is better than I expected. During my tests, I listened to Spotify, and the music sounded good enough to stick with this headset instead of automatically reaching for my Sony 1000XM3s. People with a knack for stellar audio quality will find quibbles, like that the sound can come off as muddled at times, and the soundstage isn’t as expansive as you’d find in a more expensive set of headphones. But again, these are $99 and meant for gaming first. And for that price, I’m pleased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sBzN4vGCvi7BGhEN7LcMNTAb2BA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363680/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both rotating ear cups have instructions that are simple to digest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GY3ej0-CJ8y6kU-hFgduDuUtJE8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363679/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These charge via USB-C, and they also work wired via USB-C to a Windows 10 PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0H4eYZ"&gt;Hopping over to gaming, I instantly booted up &lt;em&gt;Doom (2016)&lt;/em&gt; on the Series X. The soundtrack and all of the various hellish sound effects have an adequate amount of crunch and punch, and I was head-banging to the music while I played. It sounded as it was intended to sound, though, again, the same nitpicks apply here as they do for music. When there’s a lot happening in the mid and high frequencies, the sound can lack clarity if you’re listening closely. I didn’t notice that as much in &lt;em&gt;Yakuza: Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;, for instance. This headset works with the Dolby Atmos (Microsoft is giving buyers a trial of Dolby Atmos with purchase that will last until the end of September) and DTS: X paid apps available for Xbox and PC, which might enhance the sound. But for the purposes of this review, I tested just the out-of-the-box experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WPZibO"&gt;The battery life and range are competitive with other gaming headsets I’ve tested in this price range. Microsoft claims 15 hours per charge, and both times I ran the non-replaceable battery down during testing, it lasted for about that long. I was able to roam about my studio apartment, straying about 25 feet or so from the Xbox without experiencing any drop-outs. It started cutting out when the signal had to go through multiple walls, but that’s to be expected. As for charge speeds, Microsoft says it can gain three hours of use out of a 15-minute charge. In case you were wondering, you can use the Xbox Wireless headset while it’s being charged, but obviously, it’ll then take longer to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/63xjlEdwqD8mjoxazoDqKAxAb9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363684/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The polyurethane leather-covered pads are comfortable and deliver good noise isolation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bcvxJXSwhCMLDRLEHUuKJNtdXCw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363678/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A closer look at the left ear cup shows the instructions for the chat / game audio mixer and the pairing button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j7JrXM"&gt;To give you a sense of how this headset handles connections, I first paired the Xbox Wireless headset to my PC with Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/633495/10014?prodsku=6253924&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-xbox-wireless-adapter-for-windows-10-black%2F6253924.p%3FskuId%3D6253924&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;USB Wireless Adapter&lt;/a&gt; (not included with this headset, but it operates on the same Xbox Wireless protocol as the consoles) for music and to take some video calls. Pairing the headset required pressing and holding the pair button for four seconds and doing the same to the Wireless Adapter. To use them on the Xbox Series X, I had to run through the same process. Frustratingly, the headset can’t handle juggling between two previously paired devices that use the Xbox Wireless protocol, so I had to manually re-pair it when I wanted to hop between my PC and the Xbox. I don’t want to overblow this issue, though. Microsoft’s pairing process for Xbox accessories is very simple. This won’t be a problem at all if you connect to your PC via Bluetooth (as I imagine most people will) since the headset can connect to both concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GelArV"&gt;If you’re someone who’s likely to lean heavily on the concurrent wireless connection feature, I like that this headset automatically lowers the audio streaming from the Xbox Wireless protocol device when a call is incoming so you can hear it. You can adjust the volume of just your Bluetooth device with its own controls, but not from the headset itself. Cranking the volume with the dial makes it louder for both devices you’re connected to.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O-v7S22yTaHIXYd7Bvr3MNtHJ6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363752/xboxconfigureheadset.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xbox Accessories app on PC and Xbox lets you fine-tune adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8dvEqO"&gt;The level of customization this headset allows is also impressive for the price. Through the Xbox Accessories app for Windows 10 or Xbox, you can adjust the equalizer (movie, music, game, heavy bass, and speech are the presets, or make your own) and boost the bass. Additionally, there’s an auto-mute feature that can mute noises happening in your surroundings. There are three levels (low, medium, and high), and Microsoft says each step up will increase how aggressively the mic mutes things that aren’t your voice. During a video call, it seemed to work as intended, if not better than I expected. The person on the other end said that my speech wasn’t getting cut off, which is something that can happen with these kinds of features, and that happenings in the background weren’t noticeable. Of course, the effectiveness of this auto-mute feature can vary depending on your household situation. If you’re skeptical, it’s easy enough to just tap the mute button to avoid potential embarrassment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TvmKPc"&gt;Two other small but cool features in the Xbox Accessories app let you tweak how bright the mute light is, making it easier to see in your peripheral vision. You can also customize the level of mic monitoring or how much outside sound is fed through the mics and then funneled into your ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uf3qSh"&gt;Up until now, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21545683/razer-kaira-pro-xbox-wireless-gaming-headset-series-x-s-one-pc-microsoft-usb-c"&gt;$150 Razer Kaira Pro&lt;/a&gt; was the Xbox-specific headset I told people to get because it’s comfortable, and it supports Bluetooth in addition to the Xbox Wireless protocol. Microsoft’s new Xbox Wireless headset is well ahead of that model in terms of design, ease of use, and functionality — all in a more affordable package. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Ns40bYUPWPFJ4BkU9iA5JBW-x0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363686/cfaulkner_210311_4469_00010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If it fits my head and can also fit around the Series X, it should fit you fine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="WgEl04"&gt;If Microsoft is to be judged compared to Sony on how well it designed a headset to accompany its latest consoles — as it inevitably will be — this one handily edges out the Pulse 3D even though they’re the same price. Sony’s model is comfortable and looks equally dashing next to the console it was made for, and it has a 3.5mm headphone jack and 3D Audio support in its court. But it’s tough to compete with the Bluetooth support and button-lite design built into Microsoft’s model. I would have loved it if a USB dongle was included for more support with devices, like the Nintendo Switch. But by design, it can’t connect to other gaming consoles. Microsoft is keeping this one in the family. If you’re in the family, though, you’re in for a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q0gB5f"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T09:51:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T09:51:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>The climate controversy swirling around NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Mining the Worlds Second-most-valuable Cryptocurrency at Evobits I.T SRL" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pYHPVLhq3tTH1RH7-zFCYi3pbMA=/0x1:6000x4001/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967401/1230723200.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mining rigs mine Ethereum and Zilliqa cryptocurrencies at the Evobits crypto farm in Cluj-Napoca, Romania, on January 22nd, 2021.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;There’s a case for more sustainable crypto art, but it’s hotly contested&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="R78yQv"&gt;Famed auction house &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million"&gt;Christie’s just sold its first &lt;/a&gt;“purely digital piece of art” for a whopping $69 million. For that price, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327594/metakovan-beeple-highest-auction-price-69-million-nft"&gt;buyer&lt;/a&gt; got a digital file of a collage of 5,000 images and a complex legacy of greenhouse gas emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="M9HWTH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An “ecological nightmare pyramid scheme” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iUiXvi"&gt;Individual pieces of crypto art, non-fungible tokens (NFTs), are at least partially responsible for the millions of tons of planet-heating carbon dioxide emissions generated by the cryptocurrencies used to buy and sell them. Some artists — including those who have already benefited from the craze — think it’s a problem that can be easily solved. Others think the proposed solutions are a pipe dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y2sKhv"&gt;ArtStation, an online marketplace for digital artists, &lt;a href="https://magazine.artstation.com/2021/03/a-statement-from-artstation/"&gt;canceled&lt;/a&gt; its plans to launch a platform for NFTs within hours after getting a lot of backlash from people who think dealing in crypto art is environmentally unethical. Artists called NFTs an “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/willowsquest/status/1369403180266700801?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1369403180266700801%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fcointelegraph.com%2Fnews%2Fecological-nightmare-backlash-forces-artstation-to-drop-nft-plans"&gt;ecological nightmare pyramid scheme&lt;/a&gt;” and ArtStation’s plans to offset emissions a “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pcsegal/status/1369080757789024265"&gt;scam&lt;/a&gt;” on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="exWOQ1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;ArtStation going into NFT and saying “but don’t worry! We’ll pay for carbon offsets” is the equivalent of setting a house on fire then placing a single potted plant on the burned property as “compensation”&lt;/p&gt;— BleachedRainbows (@Bleeeach) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Bleeeach/status/1369089764700217349?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e4yHDa"&gt;Digital artist Mike Winkelmann, who goes by the name Beeple, is a believer in a more sustainable future for NFTs. His work “Everydays: The First 5000 Days” was the one that got the eye-popping $69 million bid at Christie’s. Moving forward, he says his artwork will be carbon “neutral” or “negative,” meaning he’ll be able to completely offset emissions from his NFTs by investing in renewable energy, conservation projects, or technology that sucks CO2 out of the atmosphere. “I think you’re gonna see a lot of other artists do the same,” Beeple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. But for now, there are still greenhouse gas emissions associated with his NFTs. It costs about $5,000 to offset the emissions from one of his collections, he says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vdGvh6"&gt;The dirty world of NFTs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ihd2iZ"&gt;An NFT is a unique cryptocurrency token that can take the form of pretty much anything digital — art, a GIF, or even Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22316320/jack-dorsey-original-tweet-nft-cent-valuables"&gt;first tweet&lt;/a&gt;. (For a more detailed look at what an NFT actually is, check out this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;breakdown&lt;/a&gt;.) There have been some initial estimates of how much power an NFT uses up and, consequently, how much planet-heating pollution that generates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iwuSJD"&gt;Take “Space Cat,” an NFT that’s basically a GIF of a cat in a rocket heading to the Moon. Space Cat’s carbon footprint is equivalent to an EU resident’s electricity usage for two months, according to the website &lt;a href="http://cryptoart.wtf/"&gt;cryptoart.wtf&lt;/a&gt;. That website used to let people click through the estimated greenhouse gas emissions associated with individual NFTs until creator Memo Akten took it down on March 12th. Akten, a digital artist, had analyzed 18,000 NFTs and found that the average NFT has a carbon footprint somewhat lower than Space Cat’s but still equivalent to more than a month’s worth of electricity for a person living in the EU. Those numbers were shocking to some people. But then Akten saw that the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/memotv/status/1369594107488829441"&gt;website had been used to wrongly attribute an NFT marketplace’s emissions&lt;/a&gt; to a single NFT. He took the site offline after he discovered that it “has been used as a tool for abuse and harassment,” according to a note posted on the site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="OG9O4z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G4pnTh"&gt;Since the crypto art craze is pretty new, none of the data that’s out there so far has been reviewed by outside experts. And Akten admits in a blog about his methodology that the analysis was intentionally “&lt;a href="https://memoakten.medium.com/the-unreasonable-ecological-cost-of-cryptoart-2221d3eb2053"&gt;one-sided&lt;/a&gt;.” But here’s why there’s probably a hell of a lot of greenhouse gas emissions tied to NFTs: they’re largely bought and sold in marketplaces like Nifty Gateway and SuperRare that use the cryptocurrency Ethereum. Ethereum, like most major cryptocurrencies, is built on a system called “proof of work” that is incredibly energy hungry. There’s a fee associated with making a transaction on Ethereum — and, ironically, that fee is called “gas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fPtEPD"&gt;Proof of work acts as a sort of security system for cryptocurrencies like Ethereum and bitcoin since there’s no third party, like a bank, that oversees transactions. To keep financial records secure, the system forces people to solve complex puzzles using energy-guzzling machines. Solving the puzzles lets users, or “miners,” add a new “block” of verified transactions to a decentralized ledger called the blockchain. The miner then gets new tokens or transaction fees as a reward. The process is incredibly energy inefficient &lt;em&gt;on purpose&lt;/em&gt;. The idea is that using up inordinate amounts of electricity — and probably paying a lot for it — makes it less profitable for someone to muck up the ledger. As a result, Ethereum uses about as much electricity as the entire country of &lt;a href="https://digiconomist.net/ethereum-energy-consumption"&gt;Libya&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hSKumz"&gt;Airlines and Ethereum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="EGWKvN"&gt;When someone makes, buys, or sells an NFT using Ethereum, they’re responsible for some of the emissions generated by those miners. What’s still up for debate is whether NFTs are significantly increasing emissions from Ethereum or if they’re just taking on responsibility for emissions that would have been generated by miners anyway. Without NFTs, miners would still be plugging away at puzzles and polluting. And NFTs are still a relatively small portion of all Ethereum transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="WamsVi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Figuring out the culpability of NFTs is a little like calculating your share of emissions from a commercial plane flight&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0FpZSO"&gt;Figuring out the culpability of NFTs is a little like calculating your share of emissions from a commercial plane flight, according to Joseph Pallant, founder of the nonprofit Blockchain for Climate Foundation. If you’re on the plane, you’re obviously responsible for a portion of its emissions. But if you hadn’t bought the ticket, the plane probably would have taken off with other passengers and polluted the same amount anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OEVASW"&gt;Individual behavior becomes a bigger problem, though, when it drives trends. If enough people decide to start flying who weren’t planning to before, an airline might decide to operate more flights — which means more emissions overall. “Many NFT transactions send a stronger economic signal to the miners which may lead to increased emissions,” Susanne Köhler, a PhD fellow who researches sustainable blockchain technologies at Denmark’s Aalborg University, said in an email. If NFTs significantly push up the value of Ethereum, miners might try to cash in by upping how many machines they use. More machines generally mean more pollution. (And even if new machines are better at solving puzzles, making them more energy-efficient, proof-of-work puzzles are designed to get progressively more difficult. Again, the system was designed to keep things inefficient.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AbodRc"&gt;Alternatives to Ethereum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PCtPDH"&gt;There are other strategies for keeping a blockchain secure that might not be as hard on the planet. The most popular alternative to proof of work is a system called “proof of stake.” NBA’s Top Shot, the marketplace where basketball fans can buy NBA highlights as NFTs, operates on the Flow blockchain, which is an example of an arguably more centralized blockchain running on the proof-of-stake model. This system still requires users to have some kind of skin in the game to dissuade bad behavior. But instead of having to pay for huge amounts of electricity to enter the game, they instead have to lock up some of their own cryptocurrency tokens in the network to “prove” they’ve got a “stake” in keeping the ledger accurate. If they get caught doing anything fishy, they’ll be penalized by losing those tokens. That gets rid of the need for computers to solve complex puzzles, which, in turn, gets rid of emissions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Q39r3n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Electricity consumption will literally over a day or overnight drop to almost zero”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r5SOFU"&gt;Ethereum has said for years that it will eventually switch to proof of stake. That’s what crypto art optimists are hoping for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZYhpw"&gt;“That would essentially mean that Ethereum’s electricity consumption will literally over a day or overnight drop to almost zero,” says Michel Rauchs, a research affiliate at the Cambridge Centre for Alternative Finance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnIVak"&gt;The problem is that people have been waiting for years for Ethereum to make the change, and some are skeptical that it ever will. First, Ethereum will have to convince everyone that proof of stake is the way to go. Otherwise, the whole system could collapse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeNfO4"&gt;“If not everyone agrees to that change, you’re going to be in a situation where the network just falls apart,” says economist Alex de Vries. “It can literally break into multiple chains if not everyone runs the same software. That’s the downside of trying to upgrade public blockchains like Ethereum.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DSB0px"&gt;Private blockchains do exist, and some, like Flow, are completely devoted to NFT transactions, allowing them to sidestep some of the issues with cryptocurrencies like Ethereum. But those kinds of blockchains move away from what cryptocurrencies were supposed to do in the first place, which is create a decentralized network where anyone can make transactions without the oversight of a single institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FVCQf6"&gt;There are other ways to bring down emissions from NFTs and keep a more decentralized proof-of-work network. One potential solution is to build out another “layer” on top of the existing blockchain. Working on this second layer can save energy because transactions happen “off-chain” — away from the energy-intensive proof-of-work process. For example, two people who want to trade NFTs might open up their own “channel” on the second layer where they can make a virtually unlimited number of transactions. Once they’re done doing business, they can settle up the net result of their transactions back on the blockchain, where it can be added to the verified ledger via the proof-of-work process. You’re essentially bundling or netting a whole bunch of transactions into just a few that need to take place on the inefficient blockchain, which ultimately saves energy. The bitcoin Lightning Network, launched in 2018, is an early example of a “second layer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="8Vyd88"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Renewable energy isn’t a perfect solution&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jaIiuz"&gt;Then there’s the most straightforward solution to the emissions problem of NFTs: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/21/16806772/bitcoin-cryptocurrency-energy-consumption-renewables-climate-change"&gt;clean energy&lt;/a&gt;. If more cryptocurrency machines run on clean energy, emissions go down. This is starting to happen, but there’s still not a clear picture of how much cryptocurrencies are mined using renewables. For bitcoin, in particular, for which there’s the most research, the estimates vary wildly — from 35 to 80 percent. Some experts, like de Vries, have &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S254243511930087X"&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; that relying on renewable energy isn’t a perfect solution for proof-of-work cryptocurrencies either. If mining for tokens continues to be extremely energy intensive, it will continue to put pressure on electricity grids and eat up renewable energy that could otherwise go toward something arguably more urgent — like heating or lighting homes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EqHxZa"&gt;Leaner, Greener NFTs? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hHPuII"&gt;While people try to hash out the kinks in all of these proposed solutions, the climate crisis grows more dire every day. Against the very real backdrop of climate-related disasters, there will still be people who &lt;a href="https://everestpipkin.medium.com/but-the-environmental-issues-with-cryptoart-1128ef72e6a3"&gt;refuse to participate&lt;/a&gt; at all in a system that they think is inherently harmful and environmentally destructive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yIiizj"&gt;On the &lt;a href="http://cryptoart.wtf/"&gt;now-defunct page of cryptoart.wtf&lt;/a&gt;, a note points readers to GitHub pages and essays that guide people through carbon footprint calculations and current thinking on the topic. “CryptoArt is a tiny part of global emissions,” the note reads. “Our actions in this space is a reflection of the mindset that we need in our efforts for larger-scale systemic change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="I1k76v"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Potential fixes to the NFT climate pollution problem are in the works&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Svi17x"&gt;All of the potential fixes to the climate pollution problem of NFTs are in the works to varying degrees, but they haven’t been widely adopted yet. Still, a lot of artists — and even some environmentalists — are optimistic about crypto art. “I think in the next year, year and a half, the emissions will be a non-issue,” says Blockchain for Climate Foundation’s Pallant.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xt23Qd"&gt;Ultimately, artists are the ones pushing the most for change. If marketplaces for NFTs don’t start to meet their demands, artists could start minting their NFTs on &lt;a href="https://github.com/memo/eco-nft"&gt;marketplaces using cleaner cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;. There’s already an &lt;a href="https://www.artnome.com/greennfts"&gt;artist-led effort&lt;/a&gt; to raise money to reward people who can figure out new ways to make crypto art more sustainable. Anyone who wants to support those artists by buying their work can migrate along with them to less polluting platforms — or maybe just buy a physical copy of their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VKF3WO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elizabeth Lopatto and Jacob Kastrenakes contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="mGUCwq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 15th, 12:05PM: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was updated to include the term for a fee associated with making a transaction on Ethereum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T09:27:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T09:27:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s high-end WH-1000XM4 headphones are back down to their lowest price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo of Sony’s 1000XM4 noise-canceling headphones on someone’s head." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QMc7VWIaWPGntHqVXcO4VyCqI78=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967310/IMG_0625-1.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C01LHi"&gt;If you have high standards for sound quality, comfort, and features, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356313/sony-1000xm4-noise-canceling-headphones-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Sony’s WH-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; noise-canceling headphones are probably already high up on your wishlist — if you don’t already own them. They’re featured today because you can get $72 off their normal $350 cost, bringing them down to $278. For context, they haven’t been cheaper than this (though, around Black Friday, retailers were throwing in a $25 gift card with purchase). Visually, they’re very similar to their predecessor, the XM3, but these have a sensor that can automatically pause or resume music when you put them on, and they can handle two Bluetooth connections simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KMVrlr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361616"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S9uMq8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20947669/razer-wireless-basilisk-gaming-pc-mouse-ultimate-x-hyperspeed-battery-life-price"&gt;Razer’s Basilisk Ultimate&lt;/a&gt; is the go-to wireless mouse if you’re a Razer fan, and if you want a mouse that has a lot of customizable features, as well as an included charging dock. It’s on sale &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1734965877637475564#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;right now at Best Buy for $100&lt;/a&gt;, which is $70 off its original price. This one has a removable sniper button, and the sensitivity of its scroll wheel can be adjusted underneath the mouse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qzU3LF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10392735"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BT8fCt"&gt;APC’s 850VA/450W UPS battery backup is discounted today at Amazon. Normally $108, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/APC-Protector-BE850G2-Back-UPS-Uninterruptible/dp/B085JJZDFK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its current price of $75&lt;/a&gt; is its most affordable on record, according to data from price aggregator CamelCamelCamel. This kind of gadget is handy if you want to keep phones and tablets charged during a power outage. Additionally, if your home is prone to power flickers, you can plug modems, routers, and other small things you might heavily rely on to stay connected throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AdEnm6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10392749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="qcHeBW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/15/22331445/sony-wh1000xm4-headphones-razer-basilisk-gaming-mouse-apc-battery-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/15/22331445/sony-wh1000xm4-headphones-razer-basilisk-gaming-mouse-apc-battery-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tinder will soon let you run a background check on a potential date</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w3LxRYT3sscSJkivSQMJoA03Bq4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967123/acastro_180822_1777_tinder_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U3ifBV"&gt;Tinder and other Match Group-owned apps are going to let their users run background checks on possible dates. The company announced an investment in Garbo, a nonprofit that looks to allow people to run background checks with only their first name and phone number or full name. The investment, of which Match didn’t disclose the amount, will help make the group’s tech available to Match’s users, starting with the company’s most popular app: Tinder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n4Ai7Q"&gt;This means Tinder users will be able to vet their dates with details like their arrest record or history of violence. That could dramatically affect who finds success on the app and who doesn’t. Garbo says it collects “public records and reports of violence or abuse, including arrests, convictions, restraining orders, harassment, and other violent crimes,” and its website says it accepts manually submitted “police report(s), order(s) of protection / restraining orders, and other legal documents that report abuse, harassment, or other crimes.” (That manual function isn’t currently live, however.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Twgl3B"&gt;Notably, in a blog post &lt;a href="https://medium.com/garbo/update-to-garbos-database-policy-to-create-a-more-equitable-background-check-da94028ad715"&gt;published last month&lt;/a&gt;, Garbo said it won’t publicize drug possession charges in order to take an “active stance toward equity.” It cites research about the disproportionate percentage of Black people who are arrested for drug charges compared to white people. The company also says drug-related offenses don’t meaningfully predict “gender-based violence,” which is what the brand is primarily concerned with preventing. Garbo also doesn’t disclose traffic violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j76F4q"&gt;The background checks on Tinder won’t be free, but Match is working with Garbo to figure out how to price them so they’re accessible to most users. It’s unclear whether this will be an a la carte feature or one tied to the brand’s subscription tiers. The team will begin testing and building out capabilities for Garbo on Tinder in the coming months, and once Garbo is integrated into Tinder, other Match Group US brands, which include OkCupid, Hinge, and Match, could follow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mtmvoq"&gt;Garbo’s tool isn’t live yet, so we can’t test its accuracy, but this could upend how anonymous people feel on a dating app, particularly on Tinder, which has consistently deemphasized personal details like a last name and full bio on profiles. Match won’t share its users’ data with Garbo, but users can run a background check so long as they get their date’s last name or phone number, which they likely would want to share anyway if they plan on moving forward with dating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nf651Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ji7rG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22327854/match-group-garbo-tinder-background-check-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22327854/match-group-garbo-tinder-background-check-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
