<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-10T14:04:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T14:04:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T14:04:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber discriminates against people with disabilities, new DOJ lawsuit alleges</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v5WCcTIzQFzaJWh5uWeZAs9EBLE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70123274/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fWObmA"&gt;Uber discriminates against people with disabilities by charging them a “wait time” fee while entering the vehicle, according to a new lawsuit filed by the US Justice Department against the ride-hailing company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xa9oqJ"&gt;These extra fees have “harmed many passengers and potential passengers with disabilities throughout the country,” some of whom may be entitled to monetary damages, the department said. The lawsuit, which was filed in the US District Court for Northern California, alleges that Uber is in violation of Title III of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), which prohibits discrimination by private transportation companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZzFsgJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Passengers would incur the fee two minutes after their Uber car arrives at their pickup location&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8oqEpI"&gt;According to the Justice Department, Uber instituted a wait time fee in a number of cities starting in April 2016, eventually expanding the policy nationwide. Passengers would incur the fee two minutes after their Uber car arrives at their pickup location and were charged until the car begins its trip. Passengers with disabilities, such as those who use a wheelchair or a walker, often need more time to get into the car than passengers without disabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baXH6R"&gt;“People with disabilities deserve equal access to all areas of community life, including the private transportation services provided by companies like Uber,” said Assistant Attorney General Kristen Clarke for the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-uber-overcharging-people-disabilities"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. Clarke said the goal of the lawsuit is to send a “powerful message that Uber cannot penalize passengers with disabilities simply because they need more time to get into a car.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HuFsEO"&gt;A spokesperson for Uber did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Wnuah"&gt;Uber has a fairly abysmal record when it comes to serving its passengers with disabilities. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/28/15888508/uber-equal-rights-center-lawsuit-wheelchair-accessibility-uberx"&gt;The company was sued by disability advocates&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, in which it was accused of denying equal access to people who use wheelchairs and violating the ADA. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/23/17384600/uber-lyft-wheelchair-accessible-fail-nyc-report"&gt;A report detailed&lt;/a&gt; excessively long wait times for wheelchair-accessible vehicles (WAV) in New York City. And Uber sued New York City to block the implementation of a new rule requiring ride-hailing companies to make wheelchair-accessible service a part of their operations. (The company and the city later &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/states/new-york/city-hall/story/2018/06/13/new-york-city-and-uber-reach-settlement-on-wheelchair-accessibility-466459"&gt;agreed to a settlement&lt;/a&gt; exempting Uber and Lyft from the WAV requirement.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0VOkCN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber has a fairly abysmal record when it comes to serving its passengers with disabilities&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xrlDxd"&gt;Uber has also faced civil action over its poor record serving customers with disabilities. A lawsuit &lt;a href="https://www.inquirer.com/transportation/uber-ride-share-wheelchair-access-disabled-suit-allegheny-pittsburgh-20190614.html"&gt;filed in Pennsylvania in 2019&lt;/a&gt; accused the company of failing to ensure that people in wheelchairs receive equal service from the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6CEIM"&gt;A federal lawsuit obviously raises the legal stakes for Uber. The Justice Department is not only seeking monetary damages for affected passengers but also a court order forcing the company to comply with the ADA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6QSyLG"&gt;The lawsuit references a 52-year-old woman from Miami with a spinal injury who uses a motorized wheelchair, detailing how it would take on average five minutes or longer for her to board an Uber vehicle. The woman noticed that she was incurring fees for the added time but was denied a refund from Uber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bnt1V5"&gt;The woman, who is only referred to as “Passenger A,” “felt angry and upset that Uber has charged her wait time fees for her daily rides to her rehabilitation appointments,” the &lt;a href="https://www.ada.gov/uber_comp.pdf"&gt;lawsuit states&lt;/a&gt;. “Uber’s refusal to refund her money or to change its wait time fee policy makes Passenger A feel like a second-class citizen.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774771/uber-disabled-discrimination-lawsuit-justice-department"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774771/uber-disabled-discrimination-lawsuit-justice-department</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:27:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:27:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11 is making it easier to share your screen in Microsoft Teams and other video calls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8pyOMePO74E8d32_DTdfmVFNsfo=/0x0:1332x888/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70123056/Share_any_window_zoomZoom2X.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams share buttons will appear in Windows 11 soon.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3GFgBI"&gt;Microsoft is adding a useful new Microsoft Teams integration into Windows 11 soon. The software maker has started testing a feature in Windows 11 that will allow Teams users to hover over open windows on the taskbar and quickly share the window content on a Microsoft Teams call. It will make screen sharing a lot easier for Teams and other communication apps on Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dtp59a"&gt;Microsoft is testing this initially with Microsoft Teams for work or school rather than the built-in consumer version of Teams in Windows 11. “This means not everyone will see this right away with their Teams calls,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/11/10/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22499/"&gt;says Amanda Langowski&lt;/a&gt;, head of Microsoft’s Windows Insider program. “We plan to bring this to Chat from Microsoft Teams (Microsoft Teams for home) later.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vDxRoH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Zoom, Slack, and others will be free to add this integration&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xQ2SPB"&gt;The good news is that this won’t be limited to Microsoft Teams, either. “Other communications applications can also add this capability to their applications,” explains Langowski. “The capability to share your meeting call applies only to your current meeting call.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1TTVdV"&gt;That means apps like Slack or Zoom could build this functionality into their apps and make it a lot easier for Windows 11 users to share what’s on their screen during video calls. It’s not clear exactly when Microsoft will deliver this functionality in Windows 11, but it’s likely to appear in early 2022, given the timing of testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9Zd3R"&gt;Microsoft is also only testing this with a subset of Windows Insiders, so having the Dev Channel builds of Windows 11 installed doesn’t guarantee you’ll be able to test it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774730/microsoft-windows-11-teams-integration-sharing-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774730/microsoft-windows-11-teams-integration-sharing-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:26:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:26:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>DoorDash will acquire European delivery company Wolt as it builds a global platform</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0F6mQRVns4lSCeGZ_UOm-LGKbwo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70123040/acastro_190724_1777_doordash_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1neYDT"&gt;DoorDash has agreed to acquire the food delivery company Wolt for €7 billion (about $8.1 billion) with plans to expand its reach to Europe (via &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/doordash-to-acquire-food-delivery-company-wolt/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href="https://wolt.com/en/about"&gt;Founded in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, Wolt is a Finland-based company that contracts out couriers to deliver takeout, groceries, and other goods to customers in 23 countries mainly throughout Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KYLmul"&gt;Both &lt;a href="https://ir.doordash.com/news/news-details/2021/DoorDash-Joins-Forces-with-Wolt/default.aspx"&gt;DoorDash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.wolt.com/hq/2021/11/09/wolt-joins-forces-with-doordash/"&gt;Wolt&lt;/a&gt; announced the all-stock transaction in separate blog posts, confirming a move that will bring DoorDash to Europe for the first time. Currently, DoorDash is only available in cities across the US, Canada, Japan, and Australia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IJrzo0"&gt;“By joining forces, we believe we will accelerate our product development, bring greater focus to each of our markets, and improve the value we provide to consumers, merchants, as well as Dashers and couriers around the world,” says Tony Xu, the co-founder and CEO of DoorDash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MO7VeG"&gt;All of Wolt’s 4,000 employees will remain active under DoorDash, including Wolt co-founder and CEO Miki Kuusi, who will serve as the head of DoorDash International. The deal is set to officially close in the second half of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0aB53T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;DoorDash has eaten up smaller companies in the past&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nODVE8"&gt;Along with announcing its acquisition of Wolt, DoorDash also released its &lt;a href="https://ir.doordash.com/financials/quarterly-results/default.aspx"&gt;third-quarter earnings for 2021&lt;/a&gt;. DoorDash’s revenue grew 45 percent year over year to $1.3 billion, quite a leap from $879 million in 2020. Its total number of orders also grew 44 percent year over year from 236 million to 347 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wu0SC1"&gt;DoorDash has eaten up smaller companies in the past, acquiring &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/1/20750755/doordash-caviar-acquisition-square-food-delivery-apps"&gt;food delivery service Caviar&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 and buying out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272746/doordash-chowbotics-acquisition-salad-robot"&gt;robot salad-making company Chowbotics&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/21/20826327/doordash-acquires-scotty-labs-autonomous-vehicle-remote-control-startup"&gt;DoorDash also acquired Scotty Labs&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 — a startup that builds remote-controlled vehicles — to work toward &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21563716/doordash-ipo-profit-pandemic-food-delivery-drones"&gt;its dream of autonomous deliveries&lt;/a&gt;. In 2017, DoorDash tried out humanless deliveries with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/18/14300054/food-delivery-robots-postmates-doordash-us-launch"&gt;semi-autonomous six-wheeled robots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166660/gm-cruise-doordash-test-self-driving-food-delivery"&gt;partnered with GM&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 to deliver food with an autonomous vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="frBuOA"&gt;It looks like DoorDash is still focusing on its human couriers — for now at least. Earlier this month, DoorDash rolled out a set of features, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763690/doordash-safety-button-delivery-worker-rights-accountability-adt-911"&gt;called SafeDash, a safety button that puts couriers in contact with ADT&lt;/a&gt; (or lets them call 911 through ADT) during an emergency. However, some argue that having an app that calls 911 for you probably isn’t more helpful than simply calling 911 yourself and suggest systemic changes to keep couriers safe like allowing them to decline dangerous routes without the threat of a penalty.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774485/doordash-acquires-wolt-stock-europe-international"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774485/doordash-acquires-wolt-stock-europe-international</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:19:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:19:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rivian goes public in one of the biggest IPOs ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n8k55W2Y7ME6-g842TXKjZEed7c=/0x0:2880x1920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70123010/2022_Rivian_R1T_17.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mFyrrP"&gt;Electric vehicle startup Rivian is now a publicly traded company after executing one of the biggest initial public offerings in history. Rivian shares started trading on the Nasdaq stock exchange Wednesday at around $78 per share. That gave Rivian an overall valuation of nearly $80 billion and helped it net $12 billion in fresh cash, despite the fact that it only just recently started to make and ship its first electric pickup trucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nEODrf"&gt;It’s the sixth-largest IPO ever on a US stock exchange, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-09/ev-maker-rivian-is-said-to-guide-ipo-price-above-top-of-range?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s hard to imagine the company picking a better time to debut. Tesla has generated an incredible amount of interest in electric vehicles &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;is now one of the most highly valued companies in the world. The public markets have also been on an outrageous run over the last few years — a run that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744728/money-fandom-cryptocurrency-retail-trades-stocks"&gt;supercharged over the last 18 months by an influx of retail traders&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22194330/ev-startups-tesla-success-2020-electric-vehicles-spac-public"&gt;boom in electric vehicle companies going public&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NwLg6W"&gt;Rivian, which has a steady CEO and founder and relatively modest goals for the next few years, could be a good test of all that hype. It has received a little more than 55,000 preorders for its pricey electric pickup truck (the R1T) and SUV (the R1S) and has said it won’t be able to deliver all of those until the end of 2023. Where other EV startups went public with big promises of near-term growth, Rivian has been very conservative in the few estimates it’s offered for what the next few years look like and has instead emphasized that it will be largely focused on making vans for Amazon, which owns about 20 percent of the startup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hAn7ER"&gt;And yet, shares of Rivian jumped to $106 as they began trading on the Nasdaq exchange Wednesday and climbed from there, lifting the company’s valuation well over $100 billion — higher than all other automakers on the planet, save for Tesla, Toyota, Volkswagen, and China’s BYD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tm4AkV"&gt;Rivian’s eye-watering valuation will likely reinforce lazy comparisons to Tesla, despite the fact that the startup is beginning production at a time when there’s an observable desire for electric vehicles — which wasn’t the case when Tesla started out, to put it mildly. And while many will likely view Rivian’s valuation as a prime example of how hot the stock market is, at least one legacy automaker has already tried to make the case that it’s justified: General Motors CEO Mary Barra said Wednesday that Rivian’s valuation proves that older automakers are “so undervalued.” (GM nearly had a deal in place to become a major investor in Rivian in 2019 before the startup backed out and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768373/go-read-this-gm-deal-ford-rivian-fell-apart"&gt;took on money from its crosstown rival, Ford&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Umjbsy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Rivian’s IPO filing reveals Amazon’s prime influence","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22711196/rivian-s-1-ipo-amazon-ford-r1t-electric-pickup-truck"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zY6Zwr"&gt;Either way, the splashy debut is sure to draw a lot of attention to the startup and its electric vehicles. It has also provided Rivian with a crucial windfall, as it needs a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of money to grow — and survive — in the notoriously cash-hungry automotive business. Rivian lost $994 million in the first six months of 2021 alone and has said in regulatory filings that it expects to spend another $8 billion by the end of 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PLcfm1"&gt;The startup wants to make as many as 1 million vehicles per year by 2030 and says it will have all three different vehicles in production by the end of this year. It plans to sell non-delivery versions of its van &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22765853/rivian-fleet-sales-amazon-exclusivity-van-r1t-r1s"&gt;to other customers within the next two years&lt;/a&gt;. It’s even searching for a location to build a second factory in addition to the one it operates in Normal, Illinois. And it’s already carrying a staff of nearly 10,000 employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JKTP6e"&gt;Originally founded in 2009, Rivian spent nearly a decade operating in stealth mode. CEO and founder RJ Scaringe initially wanted to make an electric sports car more or less similar to the Tesla Roadster. But he nixed that plan along the way and shifted the company toward developing an electric pickup truck and an SUV. The R1T and R1S, as they’re respectively called, made their debut at the 2018 LA Auto Show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="k89tAY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Rivian’s R1T electric pickup truck took me to the top of the mountain","url":"https://www.theverge.com/transportation/2021/9/28/22697309/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-test-drive-off-roading-camp-tested"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Nx8cZI"&gt;Rivian’s profile started to take off shortly after. In early 2019, it announced a $700 million funding round led by Amazon and then a $500 million investment from Ford. Later that year, Amazon announced it was helping Rivian develop an electric delivery van and that it was ordering 100,000 of them from the startup, marking what would be the largest single purchase of electric vehicles in history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCd6ye"&gt;Now, with its pickup trucks starting to hit the road and the van and SUV soon to follow, Rivian has become something that is still rare in the industry: a publicly traded EV company with actual vehicles to sell. That’s something that startups like Faraday Future, Canoo, Fisker Inc., Lordstown Motors, and Nikola — which all went public within the last year-and-a-half — are still months away from being able to say.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774403/rivian-ipo-debut-evs-12-billion-amazon-tesla-valuation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774403/rivian-ipo-debut-evs-12-billion-amazon-tesla-valuation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:12:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:12:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lego is now letting you preorder unofficial sets, including an epic Lego store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-8VvRE_tQGyvDTYWxxnMsztQNQo=/0x50:1200x850/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122964/lego_store_bricklink.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zuliKf"&gt;What do a Lego store, a beautiful abandoned windmill, a retro bowling alley, a miniature aquarium, and a pair of Venetian houses have in common? They’ve all just become incredibly limited edition Lego sets &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/introducing.page"&gt;that you can preorder from the Lego company itself&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TSeXpV"&gt;They started out as candidates for Lego’s Ideas program, got rejected, and now, they’ve been crowdfunded back to life by fans like you through a separate competition &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/blogs/a4ae09b6-0d4c-4307-9da8-3ee9f3d368d6/post/7e027d01-6ec9-473c-b6b0-db8f92bbe5af"&gt;called the BrickLink Designer Program&lt;/a&gt; that gives creators 10 percent of the proceeds for their work. That means you have a short window of opportunity to snap up these unofficial official sets for yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0u2kXr"&gt;And if you’ll allow me to indulge myself, they are &lt;em&gt;glorious&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvaIKm"&gt;Atop this post, you’ll spot the &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/designer-sets-for-adult-fans-of-lego/215728/Modular-LEGO-Store"&gt;$179.99 Modular Lego Store&lt;/a&gt;, originally submitted to Lego’s Ideas program &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/43f98d99-0b4d-4a89-99ad-0291c7b4e8e9"&gt;way back in 2016&lt;/a&gt; and nearly sold out as I write these words. Click to zoom in for a closer look:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FL0YHgCxt5YwFtCzIyxL1frL9eo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002702/lego_store_modular_bricklink.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3YzjES7T7vc3s0IjxZPvMYekUlE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002724/lego_store_modular_bricklink_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vx54wc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/designer-sets-for-adult-fans-of-lego/215752/Mountain-Windmill"&gt;$179.99 Mountain Windmill&lt;/a&gt;, a more recent design originally submitted to Lego Ideas &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/f966f364-7cee-44ad-8870-6d7ff1cfe053"&gt;in February 2020&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U9YVYO-uSJYBFXvxT8_o3WKrFG4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002722/lego_bricklink_designer_1.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yh9Le8LM5hu1vbMepyTW7-4hQok=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002725/lego_bricklink_designer_1__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xoQ57V"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/designer-sets-for-adult-fans-of-lego/215741/Retro-Bowling-Alley"&gt;$229.99 Retro Bowling Alley&lt;/a&gt;, originally &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/d34c928c-a013-49cb-b9d3-13cbbc5aa304"&gt;from 2018&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GhAzoOEB4yWB-DihyE0M_As0tH0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002730/lego_bricklink_designer_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W2OAamaY6ltwVQmxqPND8bc5wZY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002731/lego_bricklink_designer_1__1_.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2kMSi59HrX2mavRM9HyIHEjPQe0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002732/lego_bricklink_designer_1__2_.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P0oupm"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/designer-sets-for-adult-fans-of-lego/215680/Venetian-Houses"&gt;$289.99 Venetian Houses&lt;/a&gt;, originally submitted &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/e84c35d2-8c8b-4b51-8ee2-6b2f0d243cf3"&gt;way back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/avQ2wMjgY-WlwRsxZuIq4qbRMrU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002740/lego_bricklink_designer_1__2_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sbfHg3Uvwy2NCuuqJNYKybVz770=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002741/lego_bricklink_designer_1__3_.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8PrNaN"&gt;Lastly, the one I can actually afford right now (and did, in fact, order): the &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/v3/designer-program/designer-sets-for-adult-fans-of-lego/215751/Clockwork-Aquarium"&gt;$64.99 Clockwork Aquarium&lt;/a&gt;, with its clever modular undersea diorama backgrounds and a crank to make the undersea life swim, jump, and spin. It was originally submitted &lt;a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/fa8f50fa-2267-415d-a0ac-d3b441653bf0"&gt;in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bXEFV3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jjvXr8a8Atw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y6lEuFMR344HFjCQEw1rk0UYZMc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002759/lego_bricklink_designer_1__3_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FQuee8"&gt;Each set is limited to 10,000 preorders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="chLMCs"&gt;A caution: BrickLink (which is owned by Lego as of 2019) does warn that the “final product may vary from image” for each of these sets, and they won’t include paper instruction manuals like the Lego sets you buy at retail. It’s also not clear what their boxes might look like — &lt;a href="https://www.bricklink.com/r3/designer-program/support/main.page"&gt;the company’s FAQ&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t address whether they’ll have official Lego boxes at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MjvkUI"&gt;But they’re definitely fulfilled by Lego itself:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p4ckz6JpNgkKNcH7zIeQNtd6ink=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002767/lego_proof.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orders are fulfilled by Lego’s own storefront, as you can see from my preorder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QoYAJo"&gt;And all of these sets have reached 3,000 preorders and are considered “fully funded,” so they should be good to go. BrickLink estimates each of them should ship around the third quarter of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WCYlPu"&gt;There’ll be a third round of voting for different sets later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774596/lego-ideas-bricklink-designer-program-round-2-preorder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774596/lego-ideas-bricklink-designer-program-round-2-preorder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:12:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:12:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vizio’s profit on ads, subscriptions, and data is double the money it makes selling TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vizio" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sJGP6DZ4xn65FZHlU9OznBD6950=/0x0:1217x811/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122952/vizio_voice.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Vizio&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mf6LSd"&gt;It’s been less than a year since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22308068/vizio-ipo-filing-smartcast-inscape-tvs-soundbars-vzio"&gt;Vizio became a publicly traded company&lt;/a&gt;, and one consequence of that is we know more about its business than ever before. The TV maker &lt;a href="https://investors.vizio.com/news/news-details/2021/VIZIO-HOLDING-CORP.-Reports-Q3-2021-Financial-Results/default.aspx"&gt;released its latest earnings report on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; and revealed that over the last three months, its Platform Plus segment that includes advertising and viewer data had a gross profit of $57.3 million. That’s more than twice the amount of profit it made selling devices like TVs, which was $25.6 million, despite those device sales pulling in considerably more revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="z48v5t"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Most of Vizio’s profit came from advertising&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YFtA3l"&gt;When Vizio filed to go public, it described the difference between the two divisions. While Devices is easy to understand — 4K TVs, soundbars, etc. — Platform Plus is a little more complicated. It counts money made from selling ad placements on its TV homescreens, deals for the buttons on remotes, ads that run on streaming channels, its cut from subscriptions, and viewer data that it tracks and sells as part of the InScape program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yezcv1"&gt;The company says shipments of its TVs fell to 1.4 million in 2021 compared to 2.1 million in 2020, a drop of 36 percent. CEO William Wang told investors on the call that he sees “pretty healthy inventory” going into the holiday season, so anyone planning to pick up a value-priced TV or soundbar should have some decent options available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4X6sr"&gt;That spike in Platform Plus revenue, which shot up 136 percent compared to last year, did a lot to help Vizio make up the difference as profits from TVs dipped compared to last year. Supply chain and logistics problems affecting many companies hit Vizio hard, too, but execs also said the company is working with its third-party partners to help find warehouse and trucking employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L43ZHo"&gt;Where the numbers keep growing is in its number of active SmartCast accounts, which are now over 14 million, and how much money it makes from each user on average. That number has nearly doubled from last year, going from $10.44 to $19.89. On the call with investors and analysts, Vizio execs said 77 percent of that money comes directly from advertising, like the kind that runs on its WatchFree Plus package of streaming channels, a group that recently expanded with content targeting. The next biggest contributor is the money it makes selling Inscape data about what people are watching. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GKVTRJ"&gt;Vizio isn’t the only smart TV maker that’s really in the advertising business — as we noted a couple of years ago, while you probably know Roku for its TV OS and streaming boxes, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/20/17595384/roku-ceo-anthony-wood-ads-hardware-business-interview-business-model"&gt;CEO Anthony Wood is very up front about its true model&lt;/a&gt;. Roku’s most recent report revealed that on average it’s pulling in $40 per month on each user, or more than double what Vizio manages. One way Vizio plans to catch up is by building its own in-app payment system, which chief revenue officer Mike O’Donnell says will roll out to consumers next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KlRJDG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Roku is in the ad business, not the hardware business, says CEO ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/20/17595384/roku-ceo-anthony-wood-ads-hardware-business-interview-business-model"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rddqMl"&gt;A few years ago, Vizio &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/6/14522582/vizio-ftc-lawsuit-tv-viewing-habits-tracking-privacy'"&gt;got in trouble with the FTC for not properly informing customers before they became a part of the tracking program&lt;/a&gt;. It disabled the system on older TVs, paid a couple of million bucks to settle the fine, and moved forward with its new SmartCast tech that focuses on streaming and makes sure new owners get a warning about what they’re opting into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AtBgf3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Most smart TVs are tracking you — Vizio just got caught ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/7/14527360/vizio-smart-tv-tracking-settlement-disable-settings"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fMdubp"&gt;If you have a Vizio TV and all of this is news to you, then you may want to check out the company’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vizio.com%2Fen%2Fterms%2Fprivacy-policy&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F10%2F22773073%2Fvizio-acr-advertising-inscape-data-privacy-q3-2021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;privacy page&lt;/a&gt; for more information. It also will tell you how to disable the Automated Content Recognition (ACR) and data collection tech embedded in its TVs, which is available here. If you prefer to opt out on a SmartCast TV, simply &lt;a href="https://support.vizio.com/s/article/Smart-Interactivity-Broadcast-Interactivity-FAQ-How-to-turn-Smart-Interactivity-Broadcast-Interactivity-on-or-off?language=en_US"&gt;follow these instructions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Z3elKF"&gt;Press the MENU button on your TV’s remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUKNft"&gt;Select System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVuQbj"&gt;Select Reset &amp;amp; Admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sKt8wy"&gt;Highlight Viewing Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w6k5IJ"&gt;Press RIGHT arrow to change setting to Off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22773073/vizio-acr-advertising-inscape-data-privacy-q3-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22773073/vizio-acr-advertising-inscape-data-privacy-q3-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T13:06:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T13:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>2020 was the worst year yet for power outages in the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hurricane Delta Takes Aim At Louisiana’s Gulf Coast" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EY5AFjx9njDsmTt8j6wEwypxsNw=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122915/1228987508.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;LAKE ARTHUR, LA - OCTOBER 09: Roberta Palermo, left, the owner of The Bank Hotel, and a hotel guest, right, check their smartphones in darkness due to power outage at the lobby of The Bank Hotel as Hurricane Delta makes landfall on October 9, 2020 in Lake Arthur, Louisiana. | Photo by Go Nakamura/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9TszQV"&gt;2020 was a record-breaking year for power outages in the United States, according to an Energy Information Administration (EIA) &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=50316"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; published today. Extreme weather is leaving Americans in the dark for longer than it has in the past, a problem that is bound to get worse as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22613531/climate-change-united-nations-report-extreme-weather-ipcc"&gt;climate change fuels even more violent weather.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O2tJ1L"&gt;On average, a person in the US went over eight hours without electricity in 2020. That’s more than twice as long the average American went without power in 2013, the year that the EIA started keeping track. Across the US, outage times varied considerably. Residents of Louisiana, the state with the longest outages, went a full 60 hours, on average, without electricity last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OT5k9S"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A problem that is bound to get worse as climate change fuels even more violent weather&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AW5DrQ"&gt;Major weather events are primarily to blame. 2020 was the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726487/2020-atlantic-hurricane-season-end"&gt;most active&lt;/a&gt; Atlantic hurricane season ever documented, and five hurricanes dealt repeated blows to Louisiana’s grid. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21361751/tropical-storm-isaias-power-outages-tristate-utilities-energy-grid"&gt;Tropical Storm Isaias&lt;/a&gt; knocked out power for about 750,000 customers in Connecticut, another state that suffered way longer outages than the national average. In addition to cyclones, an &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/10/28/928517248/oklahoma-ice-storm-leaves-300-000-without-power"&gt;ice storm&lt;/a&gt; wiped out electricity for 300,000 customers in Oklahoma in October 2020. A derecho in Iowa — the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2020/10/17/iowa-derecho-damage-cost/"&gt;costliest&lt;/a&gt; thunderstorm in US history — damaged a nuclear power plant so badly that it had to be &lt;a href="https://www.powermag.com/derecho-damage-results-in-early-retirement-of-duane-arnold-nuclear-power-plant/"&gt;retired early&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eDRTJS"&gt;Without these extreme events, outages caused by small snags (like pesky wildlife and tree-trimming gone wrong) would have stayed roughly flat at about two hours a year since 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="U.S. Energy Information Administration,&amp;amp;nbsp;Annual Electric Power Industry Report " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dyp6jslsi67ogXeWYnX0hIIBMlA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002274/EIA_outages.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: EIA&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;U.S. Energy Information Administration, &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.eia.gov/electricity/data/eia861/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Annual Electric Power Industry Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xBmB34"&gt;While 2021 isn’t over, this year has already been bad when it comes to power outages. Around &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=49556"&gt;1.2 million customers&lt;/a&gt; lost power across eight states in August and September because of Hurricane Ida. So did more than 4.5 million customers during a sudden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288292/texas-grid-upgrade-disaster-planning-power-outage-energy-crisis"&gt;cold snap in Texas&lt;/a&gt; in February. Lives were lost, too, as residents dealt with weather extremes without air conditioning, heat, or life-saving medical devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BS67Lq"&gt;To keep the lights on in a warming world, America’s aging grid, much of which was built in the middle of the 20th century, needs a serious overhaul. The &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/08/fact-sheet-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal-boosts-clean-energy-jobs-strengthens-resilience-and-advances-environmental-justice/"&gt;bipartisan infrastructure bill&lt;/a&gt; just passed by Congress includes $65 billion to fix up the power grid, including a big investment in new transmission lines to zip renewable energy from far-flung wind and solar farms to homes across the country. Those lines also need to be hardened to withstand storms and fires&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;supercharged by climate change. When Hurricane Ida tore through Louisiana, for example, it knocked out all eight transmission lines that bring electricity into New Orleans — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22650382/new-orleans-lousiana-gas-plant-entergy-power-outage-hurricane-ida-electricity-grid"&gt;leaving residents in the dark&lt;/a&gt; for more than a week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UwC02e"&gt;More money could soon flow towards transforming the US energy system if the $1.75 trillion &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759985/biden-budget-reconciliation-infrastructure-bills-power-grid-climate"&gt;budget reconciliation bill&lt;/a&gt; makes it through a final round of congressional wrangling.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XIGCiqyeYDMlU8BljZi5MZeB0IU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002400/eia_states.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: EIA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6hmoVn"&gt;Renewable energy — particularly solar panels paired with batteries and microgrids — has the potential to make the grid more resilient when disaster does strike. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21403271/virtual-power-plants-california-apartment-buildings-solar-energy"&gt;Home solar systems&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21451642/tesla-ev-electric-vehicle-energy-grid-battery-day-elon-musk"&gt;electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt; can step in to provide backup power during blackouts, for example. Microgrids are one solution that cities like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22735645/new-orleans-east-hurricane-ida-entergy-power-shift"&gt;New Orleans&lt;/a&gt; have already looked into. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fU308V"&gt;Nationwide, President Biden has a &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-sets-2030-greenhouse-gas-pollution-reduction-target-aimed-at-creating-good-paying-union-jobs-and-securing-u-s-leadership-on-clean-energy-technologies/"&gt;goal&lt;/a&gt; of getting to a 100-percent clean energy power sector by 2035. Meeting that target and larger emissions goals could also keep dangerous &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617371/extreme-weather-science-attribution-un-report-climate-change"&gt;weather events from growing even more extreme&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xAFqz6"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="2T0nVg"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Powering a real city with a virtual power plant|95786" data-volume-uuid="e9cbe1c6a" data-volume-id="95786" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-981" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next generation of power plants will be virtual&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g0fxMW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774266/power-outages-worse-united-states-electricity-grid-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774266/power-outages-worse-united-states-electricity-grid-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T12:56:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T12:56:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is launching a dedicated crypto team, part of its push toward decentralization</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B-LFRXVeXtkDX8jNFRP28SWszfs=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122850/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter Crypto is launching | Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yiojJN"&gt;Twitter is building a new division for “all things blockchain at Twitter,” called Twitter Crypto, and has hired Tess Rinearson as the team’s engineering lead to “set the strategy for the future of crypto at (and on) Twitter,” the company said in a release Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W9uhGP"&gt;“First, we’ll be exploring how we can support the growing interest among creators to use decentralized apps to manage virtual goods and currencies, and to support their work and communities,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_tessr/status/1458466734327963648"&gt;Rinearson said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “Looking farther ahead, we’ll be exploring how ideas from crypto communities can help us push the boundaries of what’s possible with identity, community, ownership and more.” She added that her team would be working closely with Bluesky, an independent Twitter-funded effort to create a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/21010856/twitter-jack-dorsey-bluesky-decentralized-social-network-research-moderation"&gt;decentralized social network standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nzWvGI"&gt;Rinearson will work under Twitter chief technology officer Parag Agrawal, and their to-be-hired team will help drive Twitter’s push toward decentralizing social media, the company said. The company says there is “massive and growing interest among creators to use decentralized apps to manage virtual goods and currencies,” and Rinearson will be focused on those issues, “with a long term goal of exploring how ideas from crypto can help us push the boundaries of what’s possible with identity, community and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bzxw85"&gt;In September, Twitter announced it was enabling &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689806/twitter-bitcoin-lightning-tipping-nft-authentication"&gt;creators on its platform to be tipped in Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, and the company says it will explore crypto payments for other features like its Ticketed Spaces, the company said, as “not all people want or are able to accept traditional currencies.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JnTiwP"&gt;Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey, who is also CEO of financial services firm Square, has been a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/21/17147574/twitter-ceo-bitcoin-jack-dorsey-square-interview-currency-10-years"&gt;vocal proponent of cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;, Bitcoin in particular. He displayed a Bitcoin clock &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350705/jack-dorsey-bitcoin-clock-house-hearing-blockclock-mini"&gt;while testifying before Congress&lt;/a&gt; in March and opened a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22579359/jack-dorsey-tbd-open-source-defi-crypto-square-bitcoin"&gt;Bitcoin business unit for Square called TBD&lt;/a&gt; in July.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774501/twitter-crypto-dedicated-team-dorsey-square-decentralization"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774501/twitter-crypto-dedicated-team-dorsey-square-decentralization</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube gives dislikes the thumbs-down, hides public counts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5JAirWZ9ULkKMC5lbId49dI2yKU=/49x0:913x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122512/Exvh5P5WUAg5Nwy.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S3u7bx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/update-to-youtube/"&gt;YouTube has announced&lt;/a&gt; that it’ll be hiding public dislike counts on videos across its site, starting today. The company says the change is to keep smaller creators from being targeted by dislike attacks or harassment, and to promote “respectful interactions between viewers and creators.” The dislike button will still be there, but it’ll be for private feedback, rather than public shaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KSpOFu"&gt;This move isn’t out of the blue. In March, YouTube announced that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358992/youtube-hiding-dislikes-experiment-creator-review-bomb"&gt;experimenting with hiding the public dislike numbers&lt;/a&gt;, and individual creators have long had &lt;a href="https://www.the1janitor.com/blog/2018/11/30/why-i-disable-ratings-on-my-youtube-videos"&gt;the ability to hide ratings on their videos&lt;/a&gt;. But the fact that the dislike counts will be disappearing for everyone (gradually, according to YouTube) is a big deal — viewers are used to being able to see the like-to-dislike ratio as soon as they click on a video and may use that number to decide whether to continue watching. Now, that will no longer be an option, but it could close off a vector for harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DgloWJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Commenting “I just came here to dislike” may be less satisfying when you don’t see a number go up&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KGQZsH"&gt;YouTube says that when it tested hiding dislike numbers, people were less likely to use the button to attack the creator — commenting “I just came here to dislike” was seemingly less satisfying when you don’t actually get to see the number go up. That behavior may still continue to some extent, though, as creators will be able to see the dislike numbers for their own video in YouTube Studio. The company says this still lets well-meaning viewers leave private feedback to content creators or use dislikes to tune the algorithm’s video recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lGq2dz"&gt;Other social networks have given users the option to hide rating metrics, too — Instagram and Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454428/facebook-instagram-hide-like-counts-feature-now-available"&gt;famously let you hide like counts&lt;/a&gt; if you want to avoid the potential social pressure that comes with having your main measure of success on the platform shown to everyone. It’s not exactly a perfect comparison — the number of likes your YouTube video gets will still be public (if you leave public ratings on), and Instagram hasn’t turned off likes site-wide yet, but it shows a growing concern with what data creators have access to versus what data their audiences have access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="to6BTf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;YouTube itself has the most disliked video on YouTube&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NwRna0"&gt;Dislike counts going private could help hide an embarrassing piece of YouTube history: the most disliked video on the entire site is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/13/18137894/youtube-rewind-2018-dislike-shane-dawson-logan-paul-pewdiepie-mkbhd-philip-defranco"&gt;the company’s own Rewind from 2018&lt;/a&gt;. That particular recap video sparked so much ire that YouTube recently announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714550/youtube-rewind-canceled-controversy-creators-annual-recap"&gt;the annual Rewind videos were canceled&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also an argument that not being able to see public dislikes could lead to users watching a video that’s not very good — an insincere apology, perhaps, or informative-looking content that ends up being an ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJzMu8"&gt;Still, YouTube’s argument that it wants to protect smaller creators from dislike mobs or harassment is one that’s hard to argue against. It’s easy to imagine workarounds for some of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/1/18207189/youtube-dislike-attack-mob-review-bomb-creator-insider"&gt;the other ideas it floated to combat that behavior&lt;/a&gt;, which included requiring extra info on why you were disliking the video or graying out the dislike button until you’d watched a certain amount of the video. Instead, people leaving dislikes will be doing so for the creator’s eyes only — and screaming into the void just isn’t the same as publicly booing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22773299/youtube-dislike-button-hide-public-count-numbers-small-creator-protection"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22773299/youtube-dislike-button-hide-public-count-numbers-small-creator-protection</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-10T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Juiced’s new fat-tire electric bike targets a younger generation of riders</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tgbsdCFekeiaTm-KNV2ur7DQVjk=/0x216:5184x3672/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70122548/Copy_of_PB032678.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B9Q8Hz"&gt;Juiced, the San Diego-based electric bike company known for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22537406/juiced-hyperscrambler-2-ebike-moped-price-specs"&gt;extremely fast, extremely heavy, moped-style cruisers&lt;/a&gt;, wants you to know that its newest model, the RipRacer, is “fun-sized.” Not like tiny-Snickers-bars-you-hand-out-at-Halloween-fun-size, but like a smaller frame size for a younger generation of riders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q5Osw6"&gt;Electric bikes are typically marketed and sold to adults, but increasingly, companies are seeing an opportunity around selling bikes to teens and young adults. Juiced is the latest to try its hand at making bikes that are smaller and cheaper than the typical e-bike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Pp28PS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The RipRacer may be fun-sized, but it will no less powerful than Juiced’s other hulking models&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XjMOkW"&gt;The RipRacer may be fun-sized, but it will no less powerful than Juiced’s other hulking models. It will come in two versions: a Class 2 bike with a 52V/10Ah battery capable of speeds up to 20mph or a Class 3 bike with a 52V/15Ah battery and a top speed of 28mph. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KDuyM0kWESpvEyECspm1Bx3Piyc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002383/Copy_of_0Q8A1502.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ppYHcp"&gt;The Bafang 750W rear-hub geared hub motor is similar to the one found on the company’s Scorpion e-bike. Both the Class 2 and Class 3 models will have pedals with cadence sensors (which deliver power based on how fast you pedal), front and rear lights, and hydraulic disc brakes — all standard features on most e-bikes out today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kwMlYp"&gt;For the RipRacer, Juiced has also completely redesigned its battery to be completely water-resistant and to include an integrated Apple AirTag so it never gets lost. The battery has also been reshaped to be easier to handle when removing for charging and will be compatible with a battery docking station that Juiced plans to roll out in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q75wHi"&gt;(Juiced says the docking station will have an inverter for AC power up to 500W, six USB ports, a 12V lighter port, and an LED light. The dock can charge the battery either from AC power or from a solar input.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/14DOVPsiq67sg_HLaarR7PAvfRU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002384/Copy_of_0Q8A1771.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CD-lh0QFcJxR4oh1y45Q0QwSDxY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23002410/Copy_of_PB031390.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ESYiAt"&gt;The low-step frame and motorcycle-style handlebars are styled to fit riders 5’0 to 6’3, the company says. The bike is available in four colors: Baja Blue, Noir, Hi-Viz Yellow, and Mystic Green. The Class 2 bike starts at $1,399, while the Class 3 version will sell for $1,599. Interested customers can reserve one today, and the bikes will start to ship in March 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ijBk2a"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The minimum age requirement in most countries ranges from 14 to 16 years&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Csw9Rk"&gt;The goal in offering a lighter, more nimble, and cheaper e-bike is pretty obvious: younger riders are excited about electric mobility. Of course, some riders are still too young for motorized bikes. The minimum age requirement in most countries ranges from 14 to 16 years, but whether those age limits are actually enforced remains an open question. Shared scooter companies, for example, have struggled to prevent younger riders from using their products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FAfjlN"&gt;In fact, Juiced’s hometown of San Diego is &lt;a href="https://www.nbcsandiego.com/news/local/caught-in-the-act-young-e-bike-riders-breaking-rules-creating-safety-concerns/2695599/"&gt;struggling to keep younger riders safe&lt;/a&gt; amid surging interest in e-bikes. With more customers flocking to e-bikes, many cities are caught flat-footed with out-of-date infrastructure that provides few safe places for people to ride without feeling menaced by cars. If more young people start riding e-bikes, the imperative to build protected bike lanes will grow even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EdPfEj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774217/electric-bike-juiced-ripracer-specs-price-young-riders"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774217/electric-bike-juiced-ripracer-specs-price-young-riders</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
