<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-17T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch is lowering subscription prices — but says streamers will earn more money</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a3t2lTOVOT4HT950rHqBVP2-l64=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69298026/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EfzRyU"&gt;Twitch is announcing a big change to subscription prices — but not for users in the US. Most countries outside of the US will be getting lower prices that will be localized to their specific country, starting with Turkey and Mexico on May 20th. Those lower prices will mean less money for streamers, but Twitch believes they’ll translate to more subscribers and higher earnings in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0PoD0J"&gt;Right now, the most affordable Twitch subscription, which lets fans pay streamers and get perks like custom emotes, currently costs $4.99, a price that is currently translated into local currencies around the world. That translated price can be prohibitively expensive to some Twitch users, however, Mike Minton, Twitch’s VP of monetization, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an interview this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GBZOTM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Making subscriptions more affordable for Twitch’s global audience&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iZv52R"&gt;The upcoming change is intended to make subscriptions more affordable for Twitch’s global audience. And early tests from Twitch seem promising: the company tested localized pricing in Brazil and saw that streamer revenue and total subscriber count “more than doubled,” &lt;a href="https://blog.twitch.tv/2021/05/17/building-global-communities-with-local-subscription-pricing/"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BGRsp"&gt;But Twitch is also preparing for a potential scenario where streamers could see their revenue fall as a result of the price changes, because streamers will need more subscribers — potentially a lot more — just to match their current earnings. If a streamer’s revenue falls below their usual baseline (which Twitch calculates for every streamer) after the localized prices roll out, Twitch will pay that streamer a “revenue adjustment incentive” to help make up the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3B2Zr"&gt;Here is a basic description of how the incentive will work, according to Twitch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="hZCktt"&gt;Twitch will cover 100% of baseline channel and Prime sub revenue (if needed) for three calendar months, including the month of the price change. After that, we will slowly decrease incentive payments by 25% every three months over the following 9 months, totaling a 12-month period of providing revenue adjustment incentives. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1NdWLp"&gt;You can read the full details &lt;a href="http://help.twitch.tv/s/article/local-subscription-pricing"&gt;about the incentive here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNrsYY"&gt;The rollout starts first with Turkey and Mexico, where prices for a subscription will be lowered to 9.90 Turkish lira (the equivalent of $1.20) and 48 pesos (the equivalent of $2.41). Twitch plans to bring localized pricing to “most countries in Asia, Latin America, the Middle East, Africa, and Europe starting in Q3 2021,” according to Twitch’s blog. Localized pricing will carry over to the two more expensive tiers of subscriptions and for gift subscriptions as well. And prices won’t be raised anywhere, just lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wNwD5f"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Prices won’t be raised, just lowered&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XQYTyz"&gt;The changes come as many platforms are looking to give their creators better ways to monetize their followings. Twitter is testing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;a new Tip Jar feature&lt;/a&gt; and will begin rolling out ticketed social audio rooms &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;in the coming months&lt;/a&gt;, and Clubhouse now lets people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22368929/clubhouse-direct-payments-creators-stripe"&gt;pay creators directly&lt;/a&gt; (though not everyone can receive payments yet). While Twitch isn’t announcing any new monetization features today, the lowered subscription prices could lead to more people paying streamers directly.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22431716/twitch-localized-subscription-prices-many-countries-not-us"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22431716/twitch-localized-subscription-prices-many-countries-not-us</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Teams launches for friends and family with free all-day video calling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4hwg3ymhuc2uesnnvB3FxCztGTU=/0x3:660x443/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69298016/microsoftteamspersonal.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nkHMn2"&gt;Microsoft is launching the personal version of Microsoft Teams today. After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21298766/microsoft-teams-personal-launch-preview-accounts"&gt;previewing the service&lt;/a&gt; nearly a year ago, Microsoft Teams is now available for free personal use amongst friends and families. The service itself is almost identical to the Microsoft Teams that businesses use, and it will allow people to chat, video call, and share calendars, locations, and files easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXixZQ"&gt;Microsoft is also continuing to offer everyone free 24-hour video calls that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21579076/microsoft-teams-free-video-calling-web-zoom-competition"&gt;introduced in the preview version&lt;/a&gt; in November. You’ll be able to meet up with up to 300 people in video calls that can last for 24 hours. Microsoft will eventually enforce limits of 60 minutes for group calls of up to 100 people after the pandemic, but keep 24 hours for 1:1 calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TAtbph9awqewKmplaGR_lO5-PWA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519798/Image_1_Together_Mode_GIF.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams’ Together mode feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="B7cHjX"&gt;While the preview initially launched on iOS and Android, Microsoft Teams for personal use now works across the web, mobile, and desktop apps. Microsoft is also allowing Teams personal users to enable its Together mode — a feature that uses AI to segment your face and shoulders and place you together with other people in a virtual space. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189010/skype-together-mode-microsoft-teams-feature"&gt;Skype got this same feature&lt;/a&gt; back in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNan6W"&gt;Speaking of Skype, Microsoft hasn’t announced any plans to replace Skype with Microsoft Teams on the consumer side yet. Microsoft said it was “fully committed to Skype” last year when it launched the preview of this personal version of Microsoft Teams, but the rise of Zoom during the pandemic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21200844/microsoft-skype-zoom-houseparty-coronavirus-pandemic-usage-growth-competition"&gt;certainly highlighted Skype’s irrelevance&lt;/a&gt; amongst consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P4Brin"&gt;As we noted last year, the personal version of Microsoft Teams is part of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21199376/microsoft-365-subscriptions-office-family-safety-app-teams-features-price"&gt;broader effort by Microsoft to remain relevant with consumers&lt;/a&gt; after a series of exits from consumer-friendly services. Microsoft isn’t looking to compete with iMessage, Facebook Messenger, WhatsApp, or other chat apps, but it’s clear Zoom is in the company’s sights after its huge rise with consumers during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsLvTz"&gt;If you’re interested in trying out Microsoft Teams for personal use, you can download the &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1113153706"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.teams"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fmicrosoft-teams%2Fteams-for-home" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;desktop apps&lt;/a&gt;, or simply head to &lt;a href="https://teams.microsoft.com/"&gt;Teams on the web&lt;/a&gt; and avoid downloading anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439924/microsoft-teams-personal-version-launch-available-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439924/microsoft-teams-personal-version-launch-available-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T08:42:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T08:42:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Another report claims Samsung will ditch Tizen for Wear OS with next smartwatch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KyyIibgvawlbLIXaCAlbeSLLhs0=/467x0:5498x3354/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297955/dseifert_200811_4139_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Watch 3 from last year.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CVFizi"&gt;Samsung seems ready to ditch its own Tizen operating system in favor of Google’s Wear OS for its upcoming smartwatches, according to a new &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/exclusive-galaxy-watch-4-feature-wear-os-confirmed/"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The company reportedly has as many as three smartwatches on the way soon, including one with a rotating bezel, and two others with sportier designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTGNC4"&gt;Although Samsung’s smartwatches are often recommended as the best options for Android phone users, the company has opted for its own Tizen operating system over Google’s Wear OS. But rumors of the company’s upcoming switch to Wear OS have been circulating for a couple of months now. Back in February, leaker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1362697174694301700"&gt;IceUniverse said its new watch&lt;/a&gt; would make the switch from Tizen, and in March, &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-android-wear-os/#update1:~:text=Merlot,-%E2%80%9D%20device"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on mentions of “WearOS” discovered in the Galaxy S20’s source code alongside the codename of an unreleased device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zQy3Em"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A new walkie-talkie-style feature is reportedly on the way&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n4KDxV"&gt;Samsung will reportedly pair a new version of One UI with Wear OS so that its new watches are consistent with previous Tizen models, &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt; notes. Other new features include a walkie-talkie feature similar to what the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/4/17428180/walkie-talkie-apple-watch-facetime-audio-wwdc-2028"&gt;Apple Watch already offers&lt;/a&gt; as well as new SmartThings features for Samsung’s smart home ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N7UK3K"&gt;As one of the &lt;a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/global-smartwatch-shipments-market-share/"&gt;biggest smartwatch alternatives&lt;/a&gt; to Apple, Samsung switching to Wear OS would be a big deal for Google’s platform. It could potentially bring a lot more users to Wear OS, which would give developers more of an incentive to build apps for it and address one of the long-standing criticisms of the platform. But this is just one of a litany of issues people have with Wear OS, and my colleague Dieter Bohn recently argued that the platform is “overdue for an overhaul.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HzeXve"&gt;But arguably, Samsung’s own smartwatches are just as in need of a change as Google’s OS. When we reviewed last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21368752/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Galaxy Watch 3&lt;/a&gt;, we said it was a fine product but that it didn’t feel like much of a generational leap over Samsung’s previous wearables. Like Wear OS, Tizen also suffers from a lack of app support, but it’s also saddled with its terrible Bixby voice assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="moeiXt"&gt;There’s no official word on when we might see a Wear OS-equipped Samsung smartwatch release, but &lt;em&gt;SamMobile &lt;/em&gt;speculates that we could see an announcement alongside new foldables in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aqmUlV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439989/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-wear-os-tizen-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439989/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-wear-os-tizen-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The ‘Charlie bit my finger’ video is being auctioned as an NFT — then deleted ‘forever’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-wH4ZMr-zXS9tRpyMcoKRLOO2pM=/52x0:457x270/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297806/hqdefault.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/HDCYT" target="_blank"&gt;Image: HDCYT on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qbpNKC"&gt;The creators of the classic “Charlie bit my finger - again !” video are now auctioning it off as an NFT, but with a twist. At the end of the auction, which will begin on May 22nd, the original video will be deleted from YouTube forever, according to a press release, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_OBlgSz8sSM"&gt;where it currently has over 880 million views&lt;/a&gt;. The auction will kick off on the video’s 14th anniversary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="HTKfSl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sfahRo"&gt;Since NFTs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;exploded onto the cultural landscape&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, we’ve seen plenty of early-to-mid 2000s memes being sold on the blockchain, with many of them fetching higher prices than I would’ve ever have imagined. A non-exhaustive list includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="7ltPvv"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres"&gt;Nyan Cat&lt;/a&gt;: sold for around $590,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9gRWYN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313211/deal-with-it-meme-nft-auction-ryder-ripps"&gt;The Deal with It glasses&lt;/a&gt;: sold for around $23,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VjpOds"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410070/disaster-girl-popular-meme-nft-500000-dollars"&gt;Disaster Girl&lt;/a&gt;: sold for around $500,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rL4ndP"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322131/nyan-cat-creator-nft-memes-memeconomy"&gt;Keyboard Cat&lt;/a&gt;: sold for around $64,400&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="00IY4t"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422993/david-after-dentist-meme-nft-real-life"&gt;David After Dentist&lt;/a&gt;: sold for around $11,500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="vGiLCq"&gt;Seeing these numbers, some people (including myself) have snidely said something along the lines of “why would you pay that much for something that’s not actually scarce? I can see Nyan Cat on the internet whenever I like.” Deleting &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/bvixd4/oc_top_10_most_viewed_youtube_videos_20062019/"&gt;one of the most well-known videos from YouTube&lt;/a&gt; does at least somewhat solve that argument, since whoever ends up with the NFT will actually be able to lay claim to something scarce. That is, assuming the buyer doesn’t just repost the video themselves (and ignoring the re-uploads that currently exist across the internet).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22437088/charlie-bit-my-finger-video-nft-deletion-youtube-auction"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22437088/charlie-bit-my-finger-video-nft-deletion-youtube-auction</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T07:45:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T07:45:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T is merging WarnerMedia with Discovery to create a new media giant</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3nwwjvzHWMzUlHc9E3koBhmR9AU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297791/acastro_180322_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zlmLDs"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/warnermedia_discovery.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; this morning it’s spinning off its media business WarnerMedia and merging it with TV company Discovery, creating a major new player in the media world to compete with firms like Netflix and Disney that are leading the charge in streaming content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vU3vZH"&gt;The deal will bring a lot of familiar names in the TV and film world under one roof. WarnerMedia owns HBO, CNN, Cartoon Network, TBS, TNT, and the Warner Bros. movie studio, which is responsible for such huge franchises as &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;/em&gt;. Discovery operates numerous cable networks, including HGTV, Animal Planet, Food Network, and TLC. Both companies also have their own streaming platforms: HBO Max and Discovery Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i7ZIN8"&gt;The boards of both AT&amp;amp;T and Discovery have approved the deal, but it will still have to be signed off by regulators. The deal is an all-stock transaction, which will see AT&amp;amp;T receive $43 billion in a combination of cash, debt securities, and debt retention on the part of WarnerMedia. AT&amp;amp;T shareholders will receive stock worth 71 percent of the new company, while Discovery’s shareholders will own the remaining 29 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FCsVQa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new company will be home to a huge array of shows and franchises&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cILLMi"&gt;The new company, which has yet to be named, will be led by Discovery chief executive David Zaslav. “It is super exciting to combine such historic brands, world class journalism and iconic franchises under one roof and unlock so much value and opportunity,” said Zaslav in a &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/warnermedia_discovery.html"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. “With a library of cherished IP, dynamite management teams and global expertise in every market in the world, we believe everyone wins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGF784"&gt;The move is a significant U-turn for AT&amp;amp;T, which first &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/23/business/dealbook/att-agrees-to-buy-time-warner-for-more-than-80-billion.html"&gt;struck a deal&lt;/a&gt; to acquire WarnerMedia (then known as TimeWarner) in October 2016 for $85.4 billion. The acquisition was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/20/16655218/att-time-warner-merger-deal-blocked-us-justice-department-lawsuit"&gt;opposed&lt;/a&gt; by the Justice Department, which said it would lead to higher prices for consumers (though some suggested that President Trump’s dislike of Warner property CNN was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/22/17152518/att-time-warner-merger-trial-justice-department"&gt;also a factor&lt;/a&gt;). But after years of wrangling in court, the deal was finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/14/17466518/att-time-warner-acquisition-closes"&gt;approved in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Now, just three years later, it’s being undone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30vpLe"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt;’s Peter Kafka &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/5/16/22439154/warner-media-discovery-hbo-max-att-streaming-netflix-merger"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, the announcement follows something of a trend, as phone companies that tried to make it as media conglomerates divest themselves of unwanted assets. In February, AT&amp;amp;T announced it was &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/25/att-to-spin-off-directv-att-tv-now-and-u-verse-into-new-company.html"&gt;spinning off DirecTV&lt;/a&gt;, with the new firm valued at $16.25 billion (a significant loss of value: AT&amp;amp;T originally &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-directv-fcc-idUSKCN0PY26L20150724"&gt;bought&lt;/a&gt; DirecTV for $48.5 billion). And earlier this month, Verizon announced it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22416854/aol-yahoo-sale-apollo-venetian-hotel-verizon"&gt;sold off AOL and Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;. The companies were bought by a private equity firm for $5 billion, roughly half what Verizon originally paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIvkr1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zJl4t2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439964/at-t-warnermedia-discovery-merger-spin-off"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439964/at-t-warnermedia-discovery-merger-spin-off</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T06:59:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T06:59:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>That’s no moon: veteran Apple designer unveils $1,799 Cell Alpha speaker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S_bRJ21C7WAVca9KUhQQ3v94mbs=/159x0:2180x1347/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297677/DiningRoom_000792_desktop.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cell Alpha.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Syng&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lFPfmf"&gt;Christopher Stringer, an ex-Apple designer who worked on everything from the HomePod to the original iPhone during his 22 year-stint at the company, has unveiled his new startup’s debut speaker. It’s called the &lt;a href="https://syngspace.com/"&gt;Cell Alpha&lt;/a&gt;, a futuristic Death Star-shaped connected speaker with an emphasis on spatial audio. It costs $1,799, or $1,969 if you want the model with a floorstanding base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F6qdbJ"&gt;The Cell Alpha has woofers on its top and bottom arranged into a “force-balanced” configuration. These are paired with three mid-range drivers that are distributed around its equator, where they’re presumably joined by a small thermal exhaust port — the Cell Alpha’s only known weakness. Jokes aside, Stringer’s company Syng claims this three-driver configuration (dubbed “The Triphone”) is able to project sound with “pinpoint accuracy” around a room.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uzLu9B2KxDcht7VtIghWwzvDWzc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519802/LivingRoomProductShot_003338_desktop.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Syng&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two of the floorstanding models.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vjorxx"&gt;Syng is making big claims about the spatial audio capabilities of the Cell Alpha. It’s styling it as the world’s first “Triphonic” speaker, because it offers spatial audio capabilities beyond the stereo audio that’s long been the traditional standard. In practical terms it’s supposed to allow the speaker to fill an entire room with surround sound audio, creating the impression that specific sounds or instruments are coming from distinct areas of the room. There are three microphones built into the speaker’s stand to measure the geometry of the space it’s in, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/6/16976906/apple-homepod-review-smart-speaker"&gt;similar to the HomePod&lt;/a&gt;, which helps it create the impression of surround sound using just a single speaker. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y0wg7Al_mBbaBqgpsrshr8ta2qs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519824/Turntable_000597_desktop.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Syng&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even the model of the speaker with a table stand is hefty.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="j1HjEl"&gt;While Syng says one speaker is capable of offering surround sound, anyone with $5,397 to spend can pair three Cell Alpha speakers together in a single room to get “the fullest expression of Triphonic audio.” According to a report from &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b4a88a13-47c3-4bb4-a627-704fdf0c392b"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Syng hopes to generate revenue from licensing out its audio technology in addition to selling hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIJZse"&gt;In terms of connectivity, Syng says the Cell Alpha supports AirPlay 2 and Spotify Connect over Wi-Fi. Physical connectivity is handled by a pair of USB-C ports, and Syng also says it’s planning on releasing a USB-C to HDMI cable to let the Cell Alpha connect to TVs (it can also output sound from a TV using AirPlay). A companion Syng Space app is available for setup and playback control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KZpH4KPtuY766L97TiFHcO_UYYU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519825/MusicStudioSetup_002481_desktop.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Syng&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;USB-C ports handle physical connectivity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DabCuw"&gt;Syng currently has around 50 employees &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/plaintext-apple-designer-you-never-heard-of-making-noise/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and is reported to have raised $15 million in funding. The &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;’s report last year said these employees include ex-Apple designers and engineers, as well as former Nest, Ring, Nike, and Facebook employees. Others have reportedly joined from the audio companies Harman and Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lRVHZW"&gt;The Cell Alpha is available to purchase now from Syng’s website. As of this writing, shipping is expected in six to eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439925/syng-cell-alpha-wi-fi-speaker-apple-designer-death-star-triphonic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439925/syng-cell-alpha-wi-fi-speaker-apple-designer-death-star-triphonic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T04:27:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T04:27:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple teases major Music announcement as lossless streaming rumors mount</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/114Qih1BN4Gm7ubZptERHIF8OQU=/1x0:1111x740/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297485/msedge_ebejRVkHMS.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of the teaser in Apple Music’s web app.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="http://music.apple.com" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MjXNwG"&gt;Apple is teasing a major Apple Music announcement. “Get ready,” a post in the service’s Browse tab reads, “music is about to change forever.” Tapping the image reveals an animated video, though it just consists of the music streaming service’s logo spinning in place. The teaser, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/05/16/apple-music-about-to-change-forever/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;first reported by MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; is believed to refer to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22436575/apple-music-android-lossless-audio-airpods-3"&gt;Apple Music’s rumored lossless and hi-res music streaming&lt;/a&gt; features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GpuSpB"&gt;A launch of the new higher quality streaming is believed to be imminent after code referencing “Lossless” and “Hi Res Lossless” streaming tiers appeared in the service’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22436575/apple-music-android-lossless-audio-airpods-3"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/05/16/lossless-audio-references-found-in-apple-music-web-app-as-company-teases-special-announcement/"&gt;web apps&lt;/a&gt;. According to code in the Android app, the lossless tier will support music streaming at 24-bit/48Hz (a small step up from regular CD-quality 16-bit/44.1kHz), while the hi-res lossless tier will stream at 24-bit/192 kHz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ScrJRu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/BEsuEUK7tr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/BEsuEUK7tr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— MacRumors.com (@MacRumors) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MacRumors/status/1394046356868771844?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DlFqXh"&gt;Code in the Android app warns that these higher quality tiers will required more storage space and data to stream compared to existing quality. Apple Music’s current high quality tier consumes 6 MB of data for a 3-minute song, but this could rise to 36 MB with lossless, and 145 MB with hi-res lossless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFFxST"&gt;The benefit, of course, should be better sounding audio, similar to what’s already offered by the likes of Tidal, Amazon Music HD, and Deezer. Spotify has also announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;its own lossless HiFi tier&lt;/a&gt; which is due to launch later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oJTpjf"&gt;As well as lossless and hi-res streaming, code snippets also include mentions of “Dolby Audio” and “Dolby Atmos,” &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/05/16/lossless-audio-references-found-in-apple-music-web-app-as-company-teases-special-announcement/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. The speculation is that the AirPods’ Spatial Audio features could be used in conjunction with Dolby’s surround sound technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rAKwbk"&gt;Apple’s teaser doesn’t say when we should expect an official announcement, but some rumors suggest an announcement as early as Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rdpd0a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439885/apple-music-tease-hi-fi-lossless-music-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439885/apple-music-tease-hi-fi-lossless-music-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T04:26:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T04:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sharp’s new flagship phone has a giant 1-inch camera sensor and Leica branding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tr6IWS0pnW4PQD5469hI0pVApoo=/0x0:2090x1393/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297483/sharp.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dP3AC6"&gt;It appears that Leica has found a new mobile camera partner, following Huawei’s sanctions-induced retreat from the international smartphone market. Sharp just announced the &lt;a href="https://jp.sharp/k-tai/aquos-r6/"&gt;Aquos R6&lt;/a&gt; in Japan, and its Leica-branded lens sits in front of what is now the largest camera sensor on any phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxTt8t"&gt;The 20-megapixel 1-inch sensor is similar in specs to what you’d find in Sony’s high-end RX100 compact cameras. It’s only the second 1-inch sensor ever to make its way into a smartphone, and the first to make its way into a phone from an traditional phone manufacturer — Panasonic released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/15/6151671/panasonic-leica-cm1-android-cameraphone"&gt;Android-powered CM1 back in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, but it wasn’t exactly a mainstream device. The closest any current phone gets to a 1-inch sensor is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356128/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-lite-5g-announced-specs"&gt;Xiaomi’s new Mi 11 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;, which has a 1/1.12-inch component behind the lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="waAUWN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Only one rear camera, but it’s a big one&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nQ5jK0"&gt;The f/1.9 “Summicron” lens is also much wider than on other phones’ primary cameras, with an equivalent focal length of 19mm — that’s in ultrawide territory. Oddly, it’s the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; outward-facing camera on the R6, so you’ll need to use digital zoom for more conventional focal lengths. The camera bump also houses an LED flash and a time-of-flight sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8OGUE0"&gt;The Aquos R6’s other big feature is its display, which Sharp calls a Pro IGZO OLED. It’s a 6.6-inch 2,730 x 1,260 panel with a peak brightness of 2,000 nits and a variable refresh rate of 1 to 240Hz. Most Android phones to date haven’t been able to offer OLED displays with truly variable refresh rates that adapt to content in real time — this panel sounds like the most advanced available on any phone right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L183Uj"&gt;Elsewhere the R6’s specs are standard for a 2021 flagship: a Snapdragon 888, 12GB of RAM, 128GB of storage, and a 5,000mAh battery. It’ll go on sale in June in Japan through carriers NTT Docomo and SoftBank. Pricing isn’t yet available.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439883/sharp-aquos-r6-japan-biggest-phone-camera-sensor-1-inch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439883/sharp-aquos-r6-japan-biggest-phone-camera-sensor-1-inch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T02:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T02:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy director’s Paralympics RPG is launching next month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6kVqUYWdXIIbeH2IwwvHMsjO8SQ=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297365/Rie_Ogura.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U9sddg"&gt;The first project from &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt; director Hajime Tabata’s new studio JP Games will finally be released next month, the company has announced. &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt; is a mobile RPG themed around the Paralympic Games, and it’s the first video game ever to carry the official Paralympics license. It was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/12/18307399/pegasus-dream-tour-paralympics-game-hajime-tabata-2020"&gt;initially announced&lt;/a&gt; more than two years ago, but the Tokyo Olympics and Paralympics were postponed due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and there’d been radio silence on the project ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wOELvx"&gt;JP Games describes &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt; as an “avatar RPG” set in Pegasus City. You can create a character based on a selfie from your phone, and train them in various para-sports. The game features illustrated versions of nine real-world para-athletes who compete in sports like javelin, athletics, and wheelchair basketball. Popular Japanese robot cat mascot Doraemon is also included as a guide to Pegasus City.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4bnldgiI3SheBdkRL0Rcz-HbVVY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519669/Rie_Ogura.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Badminton player Rie Ogura, who is featured in &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt;. The athletes are illustrated by Japanese artist Godtail.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="egel4u"&gt;The teaser trailer doesn’t give too much information away about how &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt; will actually play, with very brief glimpses at the in-game action. The style and scope of the game appear to have changed quite a bit since its initial announcement, and Tabata suggests the Games’ delay altered the focus of the project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oISx12"&gt;“The format of &lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt;, which was originally planned to be a “Para-Sports RPG” was switched to that of an “Avatar RPG” in the wake of the global pandemic and the postponement of the Tokyo 2020 Games,” Tabata says in a statement. “This is because I felt that the Tokyo Paralympics, which would be held after the postponement, could allow humanity to overcome their divisions and help bring our spirits together. No matter what the outcome of the Tokyo 2020 Games is, it is my wish that people everywhere will come and receive the positive energy that is abundant inside Pegasus City.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/86ux3cd0xlWhOn5KKD3VaV_OHZk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22519667/PEGASUS_SS_02.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="G8EuoE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pegasus Dream Tour&lt;/em&gt; will be available for iOS and Android on June 24th. It’s a free download with in-app purchases; JP Games says some of the profits will go to the Agitos Foundation, an organization that helps people with disabilities get involved in sports. Pre-launch registration for the game will open today.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439810/paralympics-rpg-pegasus-dream-tour-release-date-hajime-tabata"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439810/paralympics-rpg-pegasus-dream-tour-release-date-hajime-tabata</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-16T23:22:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-16T23:22:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft board members thought Gates should step down after affair with employee: WSJ</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bill Gates during 8th International Conference on Agriculture Statistics in New Delhi" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5EEKWD5O-9QuOUrplRVrJ_NLLcw=/0x0:5440x3627/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69297079/1183210456.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Indraneel Chowdhury/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="s614Xu"&gt;Some of Microsoft’s board members concluded that Bill Gates should step down last year as an investigation was being conducted into an affair with an employee, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/microsoft-directors-decided-bill-gates-needed-to-leave-board-due-to-prior-relationship-with-staffer-11621205803"&gt;report in &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Gates ultimately &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21179214/bill-gates-steps-down-microsoft-board-philanthropy"&gt;resigned from the board in March 2020&lt;/a&gt;, which the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; says was before the investigation had been completed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="epJGgK"&gt;The board reportedly hired a law firm in 2019 to investigate the matter following a Microsoft employee alleging in a letter that she had had a sexual relationship with Gates over many years. The employee, who was an engineer at the company, is said to have asked that Melinda French Gates, who was married to Bill at the time, read her letter, though it’s unclear whether that actually happened. Gates and French Gates &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22418019/bill-melinda-gates-marriage-separation-charity-foundation"&gt;announced their separation&lt;/a&gt; this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZASch"&gt;“Microsoft received a concern in the latter half of 2019 that Bill Gates sought to initiate an intimate relationship with a company employee in the year 2000,” a Microsoft spokesperson said in a statement to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;. “A committee of the Board reviewed the concern, aided by an outside law firm to conduct a thorough investigation. Throughout the investigation, Microsoft provided extensive support to the employee who raised the concern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="N6vhd8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Board members ‘decided it was no longer suitable’ for Gates to remain a director&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QwQEz4"&gt;A spokesperson for Gates denies that his resignation from the board was related to the investigation. “There was an affair almost 20 years ago which ended amicably,” the spokesperson tells the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, adding that his “decision to transition off the board was in no way related to this matter. In fact, he had expressed an interest in spending more time on his philanthropy starting several years earlier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Md1ORp"&gt;But according to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, some board members “decided it was no longer suitable” for Gates to remain a director at Microsoft as more information about the matter was revealed, and Gates stepped down before an official decision could be made. Microsoft had earlier that year pledged to improve the way it handled harassment complaints after several women &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18295647/microsoft-workers-sexual-harassment-stories-internal-email-chain"&gt;shared dozens of their negative experiences at the company on an internal email chain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m8XvEB"&gt;The board also reportedly inquired about Gates’ relationship with Jeffrey Epstein, the convicted sex offender, but “were told the relationship was focused on philanthropy and nothing more.” A &lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/jeffrey-epstein-gave-bill-gates-advice-on-how-to-end-toxic-marriage-sources-say"&gt;report in &lt;em&gt;The Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, however, says Gates met Epstein dozens of times between 2011 and 2014, often seeking counsel about his marriage to French Gates. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/16/business/bill-melinda-gates-divorce-epstein.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; also reports&lt;/a&gt; that Gates said he was unhappy in his marriage while in Epstein’s presence “on at least one occasion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bdYDfo"&gt;Gates’ association with Epstein was a source of concern for Melinda French Gates, who hired divorce lawyers soon after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/12/20911488/bill-gates-foundation-jeffrey-epstein-meetings"&gt;reports of the pair’s interactions&lt;/a&gt; became public, according to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;. French Gates is also said to have been unhappy with how Gates handled a sexual harassment complaint against his money manager Michael Larson. The &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; reports that after the woman who made the claims agreed to a settlement, French Gates called for an independent review of the allegations and the culture at Gates’ investment company. Larson was put on leave but later returned to the job; it’s not known whether the report cleared him.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/16/22439640/bill-gates-microsoft-board-alleged-affair-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/16/22439640/bill-gates-microsoft-board-alleged-affair-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
