<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-12T11:06:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T11:06:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T11:06:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best phone to buy right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPhone 12, Galaxy S21 Ultra, Galaxy S21 Plus, iPhone 12 Mini, Galaxy Z Fold 2, and Pixel 4A 5G" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2xXWN-t57Q2UyqQv662Bj9KonMk=/158x0:1883x1150/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490961/Best_Phone_Grid_2021_2.7.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone 12, Galaxy S21 Ultra, Galaxy S21, iPhone 12 Mini, Galaxy Z Fold 2, and Pixel 4A 5G&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Buying a new phone can be a chore, but we’ve done the work for you&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="OauOjO"&gt;In 2021, buying the best phone means looking for something that should last you a few years. Smartphones’ upgrade cycles are slowing down for a reason: even at lower prices, it’s getting harder and harder to buy a lemon. In other words, you don’t have to spend a huge amount to get something great, as a bunch of great smartphones are available for around $800. It’s harder than ever to decide between everything in that range, but for most people, our pick for the best phone is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple iPhone 12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLLWfM"&gt;Luckily, if you’re looking for a no-compromise smartphone at any price, the choices over a thousand dollars are much clearer. If you like Android, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is incredibly good. And if you want to get the best smartphone on a budget, you can find something really good for under $500 or even under $400. For those recommendations, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2018/7/27/17619088/best-cheap-phone-budget-iphone-android"&gt;check out our guide to budget smartphones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IJpqAH"&gt;A great smartphone will last you for several years (at least), have a great camera, a nice screen, long battery life, and be fast enough to do all the work, social networking, and gaming you want to pack into a day. Believe it or not, all of those things are easier than ever to find in a phone — so picking the best one is often a matter of degrees or preferences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6I7S1w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9527699" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="vcanoT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10326077"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="B7RXQo"&gt;The best phones 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XfQkHu"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuP5JW4ilTFsD1GqJPcjnL_wagE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21973509/vpavic_4243_20201017_0144.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple iPhone 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DK8L4P"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WnjecW"&gt;Best iPhone to buy in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wW82H0"&gt;Apple has released four different variations of the iPhone 12, more than it ever has at one time. Despite all of those choices, the traditional, regular model is still a good pick. The regular iPhone 12, which starts at around $830 for a 64GB model, is the best smartphone for most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VycfOO"&gt;The 12 has the same overall design, the same processor, the same wireless charging, the same Face ID system, the same 5G support, the same front camera, and the same main and wide-angle rear cameras as the pricier 12 Pro but for hundreds of dollars less. On top of all that, it comes in five colors, one more than you can choose from in the Pro models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wUSPTz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The iPhone 12 balances a big screen with manageable size well&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vgfddW"&gt;Compared to the iPhone 12 mini, the iPhone 12 has a noticeably roomier display and a bigger battery — two things that are important to many people. At 6.1 inches, it’s big enough to make watching video and reading text comfortable and engaging, but it isn’t so big that it’s terribly hard to use in one hand or fit in your pocket. Battery life is also very good; you can reliably expect this phone to last all day without needing to charge up before bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3CpBRz"&gt;The 12 gives up the telephoto camera that’s available on the 12 Pro and 12 Pro Max, but that’s something not everyone will miss. The iPhone 12’s camera system is the best you can get in this price range and is excellent at most anything you’d use it for. It also has the ability to shoot Dolby Vision HDR for brighter and more dynamic video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UaJMCS"&gt;Since the 12 has Apple’s latest smartphone processor, the A14 Bionic, it has extremely fast performance and fluid animations. It also has a sleeker, more modern design than the previous iPhone 11 or iPhone XR, which feel frumpy in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4Yr6F"&gt;The base iPhone 12 comes with 64GB of storage, but as usual with an iPhone, it’s not expandable, so we recommend buying the 128GB model for only $50 more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qsBso"&gt;In all, the iPhone 12 is an easy choice for most people: it offers top-level performance, design, and camera features, while providing reliable battery life for less money than other options on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="eK0QNl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra is the most powerful Android phone you can get" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YeqTG9TtdMdfvxPoil_iBKPmKfQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22248903/vpavic_210119_4377_0153.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra is the most powerful Android phone you can get.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2t2EER"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="GxgXJO"&gt;Best Android phone to buy in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KXRoWF"&gt;If neither size nor price is a concern, the best Android phone you can buy right now is the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra. With a big 6.8-inch screen and the best cameras you can get on an Android phone, it’s the no-compromise pick. In some cases, its cameras can even best the iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zc0tSW"&gt;The Galaxy S21 Ultra comes with the latest and best specs you can get on Android. It has the latest Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 processor, which is the fastest you can get on Android. It features support for S Pen styluses if you prefer to use a pen with your phone, although it’s sold separately. The screen has a high refresh rate, which makes scrolling much smoother. It also has a huge battery that will last two days without much effort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNdn1U"&gt;Samsung updated the design of the S21 Ultra, with a metal rail that curves naturally into the camera bump on the back. It is the best-looking big phone you can get right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AOuzp6"&gt;That camera bump houses four cameras: a regular wide-angle with a 108-megapixel sensor, an ultrawide, and two different telephoto lenses. This makes it an incredibly versatile camera system that also has a ton of advanced video features like Pro modes and 8K recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b68lAw"&gt;Starting at $1,199.99, the Galaxy S21 Ultra is a very expensive phone. Thankfully, Samsung phones are discounted early and often. If you are in the market for one, it’s worth looking around for a deal before buying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="IyREhz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy S21 is often available for less than full retail price" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CuDtdwJTwbMBxwvpw_1cGz7AwFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22258914/vpavic_210118_4378_0170.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy S21 is often available for less than full retail price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wFbUhR"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 / S21 Plus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kVG4SO"&gt;Best Android phone to find a deal for&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="bwT4eg"&gt;Although the Samsung Galaxy S21 and S21 Plus don’t post the big numbers the S21 Ultra does, they are still our picks right now for best Android phones under a thousand bucks. The regular Galaxy S21 with a 6.2-inch screen starts at $800 while the Plus version with a 6.7-inch screen starts at $1,000. However, both are frequently discounted with either price drops or bundles, so these are great candidates for hunting down sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7grLVJ"&gt;The Galaxy S21 and S21 Plus are essentially identical phones with three differences: screen size, battery size, and materials. We’ve reviewed the regular Galaxy S21 and found it to be a very competent phone even though you could argue it’s a minor refresh over last year’s Galaxy S20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EbSGE"&gt;However, Samsung refreshed the important part: the processor is the same Snapdragon 888 as the Ultra. That means the Galaxy S21 is super fast and should last more than a couple of years without slowing down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHvvhF"&gt;There are likely more great Android phones coming soon — especially from OnePlus — but right now, the Android phone that strikes the best balance of features and price is the S21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oL8ji7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10326026"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="1sQvkt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10326050"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UZDxTM"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone 12 mini" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7ys0KprJKXc3lDpQZD49h30F65Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22015272/cgartenberg_201105_4276_004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 mini is small enough to be used in one hand by almost anybody.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hvSkHC"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555295/iphone-12-mini-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12 mini&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IZTX1K"&gt;Best small phone in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="n8BP66"&gt;There’s really only one reason to buy an iPhone 12 mini, but it’s an important one: if you want a phone that’s easier to use in one hand or put into a small pocket. The iPhone 12 mini is the only small phone on the market with top-tier features and specs; you don’t have to compromise in performance, build quality, or cameras with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lNVbxg"&gt;Though it’s much smaller in size than the other iPhones released this year, the mini’s 5.4-inch screen is still big enough for text messaging, email, web browsing, apps, video, and games, and if you’re coming from an iPhone 6 / 7 / 8, it will feel quite spacious. But it’s also small enough that most adults, even those with small hands, will be able to comfortably reach all of the screen with their thumb. You won’t need a PopSocket on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Em0efZ"&gt;Otherwise, the mini is the same phone as the iPhone 12: it has the same design, processor, cameras, 5G support, and build quality as the larger model. It’s just smaller and has a smaller price tag, at about $100 less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vYYXqS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215729"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="x5NLwl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12 Pro Max is huge, but it has the best camera system on a smartphone" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/37pUx3JgB0PUKctA6KREwo-rwJI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22022582/bfarsace_201106_4269_002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 Pro Max is huge, but it has the best camera system on a smartphone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="l32PYT"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="FUQpEY"&gt;Best phone for photography and video in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="G0d3Pt"&gt;The iPhone 12 Pro Max has the best camera system you can currently get on a smartphone. Its three rear cameras — standard wide, ultrawide, and telephoto — combine with Apple’s image processing to produce stunning images, even in poor lighting. If camera quality is your most important factor when buying a phone, the 12 Pro Max is where you should be spending your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CCe5L2"&gt;The big difference between the 12 Pro Max and the other iPhone 12 models is found in its main camera sensor. The 12 Pro Max has a physically larger camera sensor that allows it to gather more light and produce better-quality images when in dark or challenging lighting conditions. In addition, the 12 Pro Max has an improved image stabilization system that helps keep your images sharp as light levels drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3IjBeK"&gt;But unless camera quality is all you care about, the 12 Pro Max isn’t the best iPhone for most people. It’s enormous, and the squared sides make it feel even bigger than its spec sheet implies. Most people will be happier with the smaller but still large-screened iPhone 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iXtPZ6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215756"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="7Hu7dH"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Note 20 Ultra" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4tFtN-bEShMB8qsd71536yIE1Bk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21765222/vpavic_200807_4133_0116.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Note 20 Ultra has the battery life you need to go all day long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xyIPT9"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21372109/samsung-galaxy-note-20-ultra-review-camera-price-photos-s-pen-notes"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Note 20 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MPtDpR"&gt;If you want a stylus built into your phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="efDFTK"&gt;If you’re looking for the best phone to go from morning to night with heavy use and last through it all, Samsung’s top-of-the-line Galaxy Note 20 Ultra is the one to get. It has a massive 4,500mAh battery that keeps its enormous 6.9-inch screen going as long as you need it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3wWez"&gt;The Note 20 Ultra is also a high-end phone in every other respect. Its giant screen supports a 120Hz refresh rate for smooth interactions; its triple rear camera system is one of the most advanced you can get; and the Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 Plus processor and 12GB of RAM allow it to perform without a hiccup. In addition, it supports Samsung’s S Pen for stylus input, allowing you to write or doodle on the screen with a pen instead of your finger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S6gOEi"&gt;Although you can now use a stylus with the Galaxy S21 Ultra, it isn’t built into the phone as it is here on the Note 20 Ultra. Depending on Samsung’s plans, this may be the last “Ultra” version of the Note, too — though rumors have been conflicting on that front. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="I5qlMp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="lFEHuO"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The power button on the Pixel 4A 5G is the only playful part of the design" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p1XbfRXPA0CnBX5itOLv1QzYYYI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21956762/akrales_201013_4137_0297.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The power button on the Pixel 4A 5G is the only playful part of the design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="z3SklF"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514296/google-pixel-4a-5g-review-camera-speed-video"&gt;Pixel 4A 5G&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7spKRS"&gt;Best budget phone in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4WMzav"&gt;Google’s Pixel 4A 5G starts at $500 and gets you access to several key features: a big-ish 6.2-inch screen, clean and uncluttered Android software, Google’s excellent Pixel camera, and of course 5G. Although buying a phone &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; to get 5G is a mistake, all things being equal, it’s worth getting 5G if you can in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dwyHDO"&gt;Even though the Pixel camera isn’t the very best you can get anymore, it still is competitive with phones that cost hundreds of dollars more. No other phone at this $500 ($600 on Verizon) price point can match the Pixel’s camera quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1YRQbD"&gt;The Pixel 4A 5G doesn’t have the fastest processor, but it does have a good-looking OLED screen. Just as importantly, it has the promise of getting timely software updates directly from Google. While other Android phones take forever to get the new versions of Android, Google’s get them right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KdXXRK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="LbIFDi"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy S20 FE is still a great phone in 2021" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p5hIuIJkFZYKzgyGYGGqI3b4VAA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21939396/dbohn_201004_4227_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy S20 FE is still a great phone in 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fqlnrb"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21506470/samsung-galaxy-s20-fe-review-camera-processor-price"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S20 FE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hEmpY9"&gt;Best midrange Android phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="eI71VU"&gt;Last year’s Samsung Galaxy S20 FE is a Goldilocks phone. It is much more capable and powerful than budget phones like the Pixel 4A 5G, but it still costs significantly less than the newest flagship phones. Even though it came out in October 2020, it still is a completely competent device with an excellent screen, good cameras, and fairly good battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5nZhS"&gt;The “FE” in the name stands for “Fan Edition,” but the reality is that this is a phone for anybody, not just Samsung fans. To bring the price down from its flagships, Samsung changed the screen resolution to 1080p and simplified the build materials — it has a plastic back. Don’t let that last detail throw you, though, as the plastic back feels quite good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="65JwyR"&gt;The successor to the S20 FE really is the “flagship” Galaxy S21, which has essentially the same camera system as this phone. As we’ve noted with most Samsung phones, the whole game is whether or not you can find a good deal. If the S21 and S20 FE are about the same price, go with the S21. If you can find a great price on the S20 FE, it’ll do right by you as a very solid Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G0OfHQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546311"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ODEAze"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 4A has a rear-mounted fingerprint sensor." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zGSyayDrR2mXPWMiM9i0d_4YCk0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21691996/vpavic_200728_4113_0127.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s PIxel 4A is the best Android phone under $500.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yteQuG"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WMeIkj"&gt;Best Android phone under $500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="cBeDqy"&gt;If you’re on a budget and prefer Android, then the Google Pixel 4A is the obvious choice. It doesn’t have the largest screen or the fastest processor, but it does have a clean version of Android that’s guaranteed to get software updates for at least three years. It only comes in one version: black with 128GB of storage for $349.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tZEqw2"&gt;The Pixel 4A’s main claim to fame is its camera, which can go head-to-head with smartphones that cost $1,500 or more. That’s because Google does so much of the image processing in software — the sensor itself is actually quite old and not very special. It means the Pixel 4A can take night photos, do astrophotography, and has a passable portrait mode. It can’t hang with the iPhone SE for video but beats it for photos every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZsgOa"&gt;The rest of the Pixel 4A’s specs are good but not great. It has a 5.8-inch screen, just enough RAM to keep apps from closing in the background, and a headphone jack. There’s no wireless charging, no fancy face unlock, and the body is made out of plastic instead of something more premium like glass. The Pixel 4A doesn’t even offer any IP water resistance ratings (but a splash of water is probably fine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ftzlw6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sUP4Y7"&gt;But for all that, the Pixel 4A is probably the safest bet if you want to get an Android phone for less than $500. You’ll get better software support and a better camera for $350. Not a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="bozVVC"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtDtkO85MCRRENbxtnPm7guG9-Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21829980/Product_image_14.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 2 is expensive, extravagant, and the easiest way to fit a tablet-sized screen into your pocket.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mre8Bq"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4x700N"&gt;Best folding phone in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JDL8H8"&gt;Folding phones have been around for less than two years and have already seen their share of controversies. But if you are interested in buying one and are willing to pay the hefty price required, there’s really only one model worth considering: Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Mbw2f"&gt;The Fold 2 is Samsung’s second-generation folding phone. Its main premise is this: it is sized like a normal smartphone that fits in your pocket, but it unfolds to reveal a tablet-sized 7.6-inch display on the inside. That inside screen makes everything from reading books to browsing the web to watching video to playing games more enjoyable and immersive. When you’re done using it, just fold it back up and stick it in your pocket just like any other phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nKplTb"&gt;That flexibility is unmatched by any other phone you can buy right now, but it doesn’t come without a significant list of compromises. The Fold 2 is twice as thick when closed compared to normal phones, and its outside screen is much smaller than what you’re probably used to. It is also delicate; there’s no rated dust or water resistance, and its inner screen is more likely to get damaged if you poke it too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rta9KS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215758"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fp3cHb"&gt;But the biggest compromise is its cost: at $2,000, the Fold 2 is literally twice as expensive as other high-end phones. You’re paying a lot for the ability to fold a tablet screen in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xA969T"&gt;If you’re willing to put up with those compromises for an experience that’s unlike anything else, though, the Fold 2 delivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iahfYJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKGbug"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T11:00:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T11:00:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best iPad deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tK0LbEtEShHQh97Hs1ENU1d_fQg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66899976/bking_200322_3945_0023.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Brennan King / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1E6t41"&gt;Deals on Apple’s iPad are more common than you might think. Whether you’re after the affordable iPad, the high-end iPad Pro, or something in between like the iPad Air or iPad Mini, there’s usually some sort of price cut happening somewhere. Of course, it’s difficult to know exactly where you can find those deals unless you’re looking around at all of the major retailers. But that’s what we’re doing each day when we hunt for deals, so let us help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzVhpS"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each of the current iPads available for purchase. Most of the time, there’s some sort of discount happening on a new or refurbished model. When there is a deal we think is worth telling you about, we’ll let you know, along with any info you need to keep it in context. If there isn’t a current deal, we’ll tell you how much the most recent sale price was for, so you’ll know when to take the plunge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLLRFN"&gt;If you need a little help figuring out exactly which iPad is best for you, we’ve got you covered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21280856/apple-ipad-mini-air-pro-comparison-how-to-choose"&gt;with a comparison post featuring all of the latest models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rFr0TF"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad 2020 review: here we go again, again|95745" data-volume-uuid="d243cb26d" data-volume-id="95745" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-520" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hb2n3u"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="q5ZrvP"&gt;This is Apple’s most affordable iPad, usually costing $329 for the model with 32GB of storage or $429 for the 128GB model. Each has a 10.2-inch display and features the A12 Bionic processor, a Touch ID fingerprint sensor, and a Smart Connector for connecting a Smart Keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="T559mJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The new 2020 iPad isn’t enough for Zoom school","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5m6ZrK"&gt;You can currently get the base iPad with 32GB of storage for $299 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J65DST5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-2-inch-iPad-8th-Gen-Wi-Fi-32GB-Gold%2F457916456%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or for $300 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731914581454635364" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s2PEas"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508346"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="pxIjz0"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad mini 2019 review: the best small tablet|63300" data-volume-uuid="e735355f0" data-volume-id="63300" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-216" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fmPtFu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad mini (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MgBOt3"&gt;Apple released a new iPad mini in early 2019, equipped with the same 7.9-inch display and design as previous iterations, but with refreshed internal specs. It has the A12 Bionic processor found in the base iPad, along with Wi-Fi support. Apple makes a 64GB and 256GB model of the iPad mini, with prices set at $400 and $500 respectively. If you want LTE connectivity, the starting price is $530.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="X7SsrD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s new iPad mini is a terrific small tablet with no competition","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="QD0sMe"&gt;Sales on the basic Wi-Fi model are rare, but you can buy the 64GB iPad Mini in gold for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PRD2NQ7/ref=as_li_ss_tl?th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=5338385a3949a01d236ad3cfbdbfb96d&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PRD2NQ7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;384 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1468029-REG%2Fapple_muqy2ll_a_7_9_ipad_mini_early.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21280354%2Fbest-ipad-deals-apple#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$394 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEZSI9"&gt;Amazon also has the 256GB model on sale for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PQ8XKZC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$529 in rose gold&lt;/a&gt;, or for $530 in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07NHN9W4J?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PSK4LGQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PSFYBw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515887"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WfS02T"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad Air (2020) review|96393" data-volume-uuid="6c97cb5b6" data-volume-id="96393" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-282" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="66nPkj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Air (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5sW0N"&gt;The 2020 iPad Air has a slightly larger 10.9-inch display compared to last year’s 10.5-inch display, and features thinner bezels around the display. It has relocated the Touch ID fingerprint sensor to the power button, located on the top of the device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="u6ZCyC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPad Air (2020) review: take it from the Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VGT87b"&gt;Like its predecessor, the fourth-gen iPad Air model comes in 64GB or 256GB storage configurations. The Wi-Fi models start at $599 and $749 respectively, making the starting price slightly more than last year’s models. The model that supports LTE starts at $729. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzykEb"&gt;Amazon currently has the fourth-gen iPad Air 64GB model with Wi-Fi in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J61FCVN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;all colors available for its lowest price ever of $540&lt;/a&gt;. Walmart has the same configuration on sale for $559 if you buy the 64GB iPad Air with Wi-Fi in &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-9-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Green%2F968764839%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-9-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Silver%2F694429303%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wn6zsS"&gt;The 256GB configuration has also been discounted at Amazon; you can get this model for $699 ($50 off) in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J63W44Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6FTH75?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rose gold&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6FVJMX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sky blue&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7jir3Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="nFcTiz"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad Pro (2020) review: beyond the trackpad|75424" data-volume-uuid="a90d1f137" data-volume-id="75424" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-948" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7PfM3l"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Pro (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VbsKiA"&gt;Apple’s 2020 iteration of the iPad Pro looks a lot like the 2018 model, aside from its dual-lens rear camera array. Unlike the less expensive iPad models, the iPad Pro ditches the headphone jack and uses a USB-C port instead of a Lightning port. It also has Face ID to help you unlock the tablet instead of relying on the Touch ID fingerprint sensor; it also has a high refresh display. In fact, the iPad Pro has the most stacked spec sheet of Apple’s entire iPad lineup, which comes at a price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="B73hce"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPad Pro review 2020: small spec bump, big camera bump","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="MHHxDV"&gt;The 11-inch model with 128GB of storage starts at $800; bumping the screen size up to 12.9 inches raises the price to $1,000. Each model supports up to 1TB of storage, with the top-spec models going for $1,299 (11-inch) and $1,499 (12.9-inch). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g8em56"&gt;If you are looking to pick up the 11-inch model at a discounted price, Amazon has the 128GB model with Wi-Fi in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08637NV8M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08631S3BP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt; marked down to $749 and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863358NV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB configuration in space gray only for $846&lt;/a&gt; (coupon applied). If you are okay with spending $1,000 or more, you can get &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863BT4DD?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of storage for $1,044 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (coupon applied). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G5QUP2"&gt;Of course, if you have money to spend and want a ton of storage, you can buy the 11-inch &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08631TDC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB configuration in space gray for only $1,234 (with coupon);&lt;/a&gt; that’s $69 off its usual retail price of $1,299.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eK4A7f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="48UoRv"&gt;If you want a slightly bigger screen, Amazon has the 12.9-inch iPad Pro on sale &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862JF4KR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting at $929&lt;/a&gt; for the base model, which includes 128GB of storage. If you need more storage, you can get the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862HNWGK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB model for &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862HNWGK/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=ffc689de651b8297993943adb5f6d337&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$999&lt;/a&gt; or you can buy the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862JK4BQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB for $1,199&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2My51r"&gt;The 12.9-inch 1TB model with Wi-Fi only is also discounted at Amazon. You can get it in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08637TYPT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray for $1,399&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08631SHQJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,449 for silver&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G0kMgB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:45:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:45:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Google’s mysterious lack of app updates and Apple’s rumored VR headset</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C-zNKVIf4Ehpk17SXvNaoF_hnzE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809630/acastro_210121_1777_google_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vJEcYT"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to discuss this week in &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;headlines&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Here’s what &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, and Adi Robertson focus the episode on this week: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277304/google-ios-apps-out-of-date-update-message"&gt;Google’s mysterious lack of iOS app updates&lt;/a&gt;, the rumors around &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266190/apple-vr-headset-ar-glasses-8k-displays-cameras-hand-tracking-details-report"&gt;an Apple-made VR / AR headset&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269050/sonos-fcc-filing-mini-move-portable-bluetooth-speaker"&gt;gadget headlines&lt;/a&gt; you may have missed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fiuOJp"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/5lPooKzzl16Y4qkzY5c6FC" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xAj2ME"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2LSPE"&gt;This week, users of the iOS versions of Google’s apps &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277304/google-ios-apps-out-of-date-update-message"&gt;were shown a prompt&lt;/a&gt; claiming the software was “out of date” and suggesting updates to the current versions due to security risks. However, Google had not updated their apps yet and haven’t for several weeks now. &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; crew discuss whether this is related to Apple’s new mandatory App Store privacy labels and what leverage Google might be trying to gain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9BCDG"&gt;Also, it’s another week of rumored Apple products. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268091/vergecast-podcast-439-mustang-mach-e-apple-car-tesla-model-s-redesign"&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt;, the podcast dived into the much-rumored Apple Car and the potential manufacturers that would be teaming up with the tech company to make the vehicle. This week, they update which companies have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271748/hyundai-apple-car-talks-stopped-report"&gt;downplayed these rumors&lt;/a&gt;, as well as what other much-rumored product Apple may be developing — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266190/apple-vr-headset-ar-glasses-8k-displays-cameras-hand-tracking-details-report"&gt;a VR headset&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adDoCb"&gt;There’s a whole lot more discussed in this episode — like a glimpse of what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274071/google-android-12-ui-screenshots-privacy-indicator-conversations-widget-leak-rumor"&gt;Android 12 may look like&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22273056/expanscape-aurora-7-seven-screen-laptop"&gt;laptop with seven screens&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276511/north-dakota-senate-bill-2333-apple-google-app-store-antitrust-monopoly"&gt;North Dakota bill&lt;/a&gt; that may force alternative app stores on the iPhone — so listen here or in your preferred podcast player for the full discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="53xleB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279956/google-ios-apps-apple-vr-rumors-vergecast-podcast-440"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279956/google-ios-apps-apple-vr-rumors-vergecast-podcast-440</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:44:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:44:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter CEO partners with Jay-Z on $23M bitcoin development fund</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bitcoin Cryptocurrency Illustration" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pWfoRB6y8dPfF7zmCZ-pIalViLY=/0x3:7360x4910/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809624/1231114549.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by Alain Pitton/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6F5zTa"&gt;Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey and musician Jay-Z have pledged 500 bitcoin (around $23.3 million) toward ₿trust, an endowment to fund bitcoin development, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1360114881978982403"&gt;Dorsey announced on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; today. The CEO said development will initially be focused on teams in Africa and India, but that he and Jay-Z plan to give “zero direction” to the plans. ₿trust is currently looking for three board members, with an application form noting its mission is to “make bitcoin the internet’s currency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2LfjYZ"&gt;Africa and India are two interesting markets in which to focus bitcoin development. As &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/jack-dorsey-and-jay-z-invest-23-6-million-to-fund-bitcoin-development/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, cryptocurrencies have grown increasingly popular throughout the African continent for making cross-border transactions cheaper, and in some cases being resistant to government control. Nigeria is reportedly &lt;a href="https://qz.com/africa/1947769/nigeria-is-the-second-largest-bitcoin-market-after-the-us/"&gt;second only to the US&lt;/a&gt; in terms of the amount of bitcoin traded in the country in the last five years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bDD0BH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;JAY-Z/&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/S_C_?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@S_C_&lt;/a&gt; and I are giving 500 BTC to a new endowment named ₿trust to fund &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; development, initially focused on teams in Africa &amp;amp; India. It‘ll be set up as a blind irrevocable trust, taking zero direction from us. We need 3 board members to start: &lt;a href="https://t.co/L4mRBryMJe"&gt;https://t.co/L4mRBryMJe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— jack (@jack) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1360114881978982403?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hFPx4c"&gt;Meanwhile, the Indian government is currently looking to ban private cryptocurrencies in the country, &lt;a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/intent-on-ban-india-to-give-transition-time-to-crypto-investors-bq-exclusive"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, while also investigating the creation of an official digital currency. &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; notes that cryptocurrency development in the country has been slow, despite its strengths in software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l7Yvvd"&gt;Dorsey has been a longtime supporter of cryptocurrency, and this has been reflected in the actions of his companies. His payments platform company Square has accepted bitcoin as a form of payment since 2014 and announced it had purchased &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21507533/square-50-million-bitcoin-dorsey-cryptocurrency"&gt;$50 million in bitcoin last year&lt;/a&gt; as an investment in cryptocurrency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NRz0tV"&gt;At the time, Square said it believed bitcoin could be the currency of the future and that cryptocurrency is an “instrument of economic empowerment.” Earlier this week, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SquawkCNBC/status/1359501275650547714"&gt;Twitter’s chief financial officer said&lt;/a&gt; the company was looking into how it might pay its employees or vendors in bitcoin in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="18QVLf"&gt;₿trust is the second major bitcoin investment announced this week. On Monday, Tesla said it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272103/tesla-bitcoin-investment-1-5-billion-cryptocurrency-payments"&gt;had invested $1.5 billion&lt;/a&gt; in the cryptocurrency and was hoping to take it as a payment method in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BmLzHL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gi3bbA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22280005/jack-dorsey-jay-z-bitcoin-development-fund-africa-india"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22280005/jack-dorsey-jay-z-bitcoin-development-fund-africa-india</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:41:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:41:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s where you can buy a Nintendo Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SrSHDHNRiQrX7uCuXdtZyYvmZKk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66793958/akrales_190820_3597_0355.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YIrWef"&gt;The Nintendo Switch, like everything else that can lighten the mood during this incredibly tough time, is in short supply. And as soon as retailers like Best Buy, Amazon, and Walmart get it in stock, it quickly sells out. It can be disheartening to miss out on the opportunity to buy a Switch — but fear not! The purpose of this article is to help you do just that without paying more than it would usually cost at retail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BazuMH"&gt;We’re keeping a lookout across the web to find where, when, and how you can buy a Nintendo Switch (the one you can dock to your TV or remove for portable use) or a Switch Lite (the portable-only version of the console) as well as any bundles that seem like good deals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6nOmgX"&gt;Keep in mind that stock — even Switch consoles that are preowned or refurbished — will likely continue to sell out quickly during the pandemic. But we’ll do our best to keep this article up to date with the latest in-stock offers, and we’ll tell you when each offer was posted. When something gets sold out, we’ll try to let you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D0nXc0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 8 best games for your new Nintendo Switch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/25/21012569/nintendo-switch-best-games-2019-pokemon-zelda"},{"title":"The best games of 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/25/21126558/best-games-2020-ps4-ps5-xbox-nintendo-switch-pc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qGGw5PwDrzANZ-regrcl3nOYK_A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19086558/akrales_190820_3597_0150.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Switch Lite is the smaller, portable-only version of the console that comes in a few different color options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lxqTuB"&gt;Where can I buy a Nintendo Switch or Switch Lite right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="guePeD"&gt;Currently, you can buy the Nintendo Switch Mario Red and Blue Edition at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732041273955221131" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-mario-red-38-blue-edition%2F-%2FA-82242753%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. This limited edition Switch includes a screen protector and a carrying case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gG8y3P"&gt;You can buy the limited-edition &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; Nintendo Switch at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732099862554262226" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-animal-crossing-new-horizons-edition%2F11100143.html%3Fcondition%3DNew" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-animal-crossing-new-horizons-edition%2F-%2FA-79494599%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qcOiY9"&gt;Over at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07YMR6NB8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, you can buy an updated Nintendo Switch model with neon and blue Joy-Cons, plus a 64GB SanDisk MicroSD card for $319. You can also get a similar bundle, but with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07YBVJRD7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB MicroSD card for $327 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9fQLQo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732099399409384635" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-gray-joy-con%2F204622.html%3Futm_source%3Dgoogle%26utm_medium%3Dfeeds%26utm_campaign%3Dunpaid_listings" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt; have the Nintendo Switch with gray Joy-Cons for $300. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ueoxw3"&gt;You can buy the updated Nintendo Switch model with red and blue Joy-Cons for $300 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07VGRJDFY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732099443632214646" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-neon-blue-and-neon-red-joy-con%2F11095819.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-with-neon-blue-and-neon-red-joy-con%2F-%2FA-77464001%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZaaYGt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Lite-Coral/dp/B07V4GCFP9/ref=as_li_ss_tl?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=25204d2c5e9e7105ec173ae5b3e28bcc&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732099797003183412" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergedeals&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-turquoise%2F11095775.html%3Futm_expid%3D.cxvp7jeuRNKc9QoJTI6kMQ.0%26utm_referrer%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-lite-gray%2F-%2FA-77419246%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; currently have Nintendo Switch Lite stock available in different colors. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pbWPDc"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergehowto&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fsearch%2F%3Fq%3Dnintendo%2Bswitch%26lang%3Ddefault" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1720139703165212912" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; receive new supplies of the Nintendo Switch and Switch Lite consoles fairly regularly, and it’s a good strategy to keep these pages open so you can quickly add one to your cart when they come back in stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8sjVf7newR4j6lSgYUYAPINU6jo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22298929/SM3DW_Lead.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Nintendo Switch Mario Red &amp;amp; Blue Edition&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o2G175"&gt;If you’re not against buying a preowned or refurbished console, you’ll want to check out &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-gray-joy-con%2F206007.html%3Fgclid%3DCjwKCAiAt9z-BRBCEiwA_bWv-HzeKt4-dsaWdi9G9SGmxFTUUEAxrCA4NxZS0xEWCkIacwTZ_cUKPRoCEYUQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;. Another good place to look is &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-switch/systems.html"&gt;Nintendo’s own online store where it sells refurbished Switch consoles&lt;/a&gt;. Those have been sold out recently, but there’s no telling when it will restock the page with some repaired, refreshed consoles. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/veAGHSQdVpomFEThPomQmjmS1bQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/8070145/jbareham_1492_170228_0275.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can buy games on Switch cartridges or store several digital downloads purchased through the eShop on a microSD card.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8hV7z9"&gt;What accessories do I need to buy for the Nintendo Switch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hgAR00"&gt;Frankly, the Switch comes with everything that you need to get started and have fun. However, a few extra purchases can help you get a little more out of your console, and in some cases, help it weather the wear and tear that it’ll undoubtedly endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sHCpf"&gt;First off, a microSD card will help you extend your Switch’s default 32GB of storage. Amazon, Best Buy, and other retailers regularly sell cards with up to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07SC7BZHR/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;amp;tag=vergehowto-20&amp;amp;linkId=d9d13492d7a2383ae455b1e464853cbe&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;th=1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of storage for around $70&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B074RNRM2B/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergehowto-20&amp;amp;linkId=ebcbe0aae0692190d419f2c892d31718&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;A 400GB microSD card will cost you around $40&lt;/a&gt;, and with each game ranging in download size from 1GB to tens of gigabytes, the card has enough space to store several of them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6yrravQwglpzWOC1tZVT479bwzQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/8028811/jbareham_170221_1475_0010.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nintendo Switch does not include a Pro Controller.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QGdvLy"&gt;Let’s talk quickly about controllers. The Switch Joy-Cons have a somewhat unconventional look. Nevertheless, the Pro Controller is a great alternative to play most Switch games, though some &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Party&lt;/em&gt; titles require the Joy-Cons to play. If you are looking for a Switch Pro controller, Walmart also has the normal &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Pro-Controller-Black%2F55485228&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Switch Pro controller for $59&lt;/a&gt;, knockings $11 off its normal retail price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zmgu8T"&gt;If you are looking to use your Nintendo Switch to also g&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2BZPIqmUqpLcZoV5GVxdxMULT3I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9537475/akrales_171025_2091_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Switch doesn’t include a screen protector, so make that one of the first things you buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UODwlY"&gt;Next up, get a tempered glass screen cover. The display on the Switch and Switch Lite is covered in plastic, and it’s just asking to get scratched as soon as you take it out of the box. Save the heartbreak by getting an affordable, easy-to-apply glass cover at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ulULMw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01N3ASPNV/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergehowto-20&amp;amp;linkId=03e07706174eba9d98e121bd33c717da&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;A two-pack of amFilm tempered glass protectors for the Nintendo Switch is $8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="l1NCcr"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2YZPQpf" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07TCPVHTM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergehowto-20&amp;amp;linkId=40eaf677c94a1341b4ed7beb385dbb06&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; three-pack of amFilm tempered glass protectors for the Switch Lite is $6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="cx5X9k"&gt;If you want to play online with friends, ensure that your saves are backed up in the cloud, and get access to a slate of on-demand games from the original Nintendo console and SNES console era, you’ll want to get a Nintendo Switch Online subscription. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07FV64QLX/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergehowto-20&amp;amp;linkId=e9815cab861c6f59255b7b948189eef3&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s $20 per year for a single user&lt;/a&gt; on a console or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1728487093072266361" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$35 a year for up to eight users on different consoles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21257643/nintendo-switch-lite-how-to-buy-in-stock"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21257643/nintendo-switch-lite-how-to-buy-in-stock</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:16:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:16:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s AirPods Pro are down to $200 at B&amp;H Photo and Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ADVaKJ741skd2nYKH2QlBnCa0F0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68805342/akrales_191030_3763_0446.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XWNZQd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 10:05AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; When this was written, Amazon and Walmart were selling the AirPods Pros for $180. While this deal is no longer available, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722683585155103" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Buy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; are selling the devices at the lower price of $200. Also, be sure to check out our roundup of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;the best AirPods sales at any given time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nolzBn"&gt;When it comes to true wireless earbuds, Apple’s AirPods Pro &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;are possibly the best option out there&lt;/a&gt;. If you have been holding off on buying the AirPods Pro, hoping for a decent price drop, your time has come: Apple’s flagship wireless earbuds are just $200 at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722683585155103" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; right now. That’s $49 off the usual $249 price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLpNMN"&gt;While this is not the lowest price we have seen these earbuds go for, the AirPods Pro rarely gets marked down to anything lower than $190. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hm8acq"&gt;Among other advantages, the AirPods Pro offer a customizable fit that includes three different silicone ear tip sizes, making it easier for them to fit in your ears. The standard AirPods come with a “one size fits most” design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="04LGOU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vDBZb6"&gt;If you’re looking for a pair of AirPods but aren’t interested in the Pro model, Amazon currently has one of the better deals on the regular AirPods. For $110, you can grab &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a second-generation pair with a wired charging case&lt;/a&gt; (coupon applied at checkout). For $50 more, you can pick up a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pair that includes a wireless charging case&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uDyAc8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple AirPods Pro review: perfect fit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"},{"title":"Apple AirPods second-gen review: even more wireless","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="OOOVcw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278616/apple-airpods-pro-wireless-earbuds-deal-amazon-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278616/apple-airpods-pro-wireless-earbuds-deal-amazon-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:16:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:16:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify to let employees keep working remotely and now choose what country they work from</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jpCmHuQMEMTFOBy2bPcKWVFl7ys=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809498/acastro_180213_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="USol59"&gt;Spotify is jumping on the remote work bandwagon in a big way with an &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-02-12/distributed-first-is-the-future-of-work-at-spotify/"&gt;announcement on Friday&lt;/a&gt; that it will let its employees choose where they’d like work, both for their preference of coming into the office or staying mostly at home and their geographic location in the world. Spotify is calling the initiative Work From Anywhere and it describes it as a “new way of collaborating that allows Spotifiers to work from wherever they do their best thinking and creating.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgfdRj"&gt;“Through this distributed-first mentality, we are giving employees the opportunity to elect a Work Mode—whether they’d prefer to work mostly at home or in the office—as well as their geographic location,” the company’s blog post reads. Spotify says it will implement the new options this summer, and the choice of how often, if ever, an employee returns to the office will be decided by the employee in conversations with their manager and team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPWU2S"&gt;As for the freedom to work for Spotify anywhere in the world, the company says it will let employees decide their location “with some limitations to address time zone difficulties, and regional entity laws in the initial rollout of this program,” reads a more &lt;a href="https://hrblog.spotify.com/2021/02/12/introducing-working-from-anywhere/"&gt;in-depth post on the company’s human resources blog&lt;/a&gt;. “If someone chooses a location that is not near a Spotify office, we will support them with a co-working space membership if they want to work from an office.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GqZb9x"&gt;Spotify’s decision comes on the heels of an announcement from Salesforce &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22275304/salesfore-remote-work-9-to-5-workday-is-dead-flex-coronavirus"&gt;earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, in which the cloud computing giant said it would give employees the choice to work mostly from home from now on and also give workers more flexibility around their daily schedules for taking care of children or attending to personal matters. Scores of other major tech companies, include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/facebook/2020/5/21/21265699/facebook-remote-work-shift-workforce-permanent-covid-19-mark-zuckerberg-interview"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21508964/microsoft-remote-work-from-home-covid-19-coronavirus"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, have similarly announced major commitments to remote work and letting employees make their new COVID-era work environments permanent going forward, if they so choose. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279951/spotify-remote-work-from-home-employees-choose-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279951/spotify-remote-work-from-home-employees-choose-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:14:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:14:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s new Mario-themed Switch is available now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bvgRQTxM0NLQWTBSTeifLDgYgTM=/486x0:5736x3500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68808878/SM3DW_Lead.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nintendo Switch Mario Red &amp;amp; Blue Edition | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QwoMeU"&gt;Alongside the release of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Super-Mario-3D-World-Bowsers-Fury/dp/B08H9M7LDY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the Nintendo Switch, several retailers have a Mario Red &amp;amp; Blue Edition Switch game console available for purchase. You can buy one right now at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732041273955221131" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-mario-red-38-blue-edition%2F-%2FA-82242753%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGb5kj"&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/30/21116081/nintendo-animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-unique-joy-con-colors"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;-themed Switch released last year&lt;/a&gt;, this limited-edition console stands out from other models, with the entire Switch and its accompanying accessories based on the outfit typically worn by the mustached plumber. Retailing for $300, the limited-edition Switch features an all-red console, a red dock stand, a pair of red Joy-Cons, a red casing around the screen, and a blue Joy-Con grip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AvudIO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10338949"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1HC5Y2"&gt;Additionally, for $300, the Mario-themed Switch also includes a screen protector and a special carrying case that includes various symbols associated with the &lt;em&gt;Mario&lt;/em&gt; franchise at no additional cost. The Nintendo Switch included with the bundle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/17/20697601/nintendo-switch-new-model-battery-life-improvements"&gt;is the updated model&lt;/a&gt;, which includes two more hours of battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jg2C5x"&gt;If you are planning to buy this console, there are a few things to keep in mind. Firstly, the device does not include a copy of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;, despite both products having the same release date. Secondly, these limited-edition Nintendo Switch consoles tend to sell out quickly, and there’s no telling if and when it will be restocked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LAAGX7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury is the best of Mario in one package","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22274990/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review-nintendo-switch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:13:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:13:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>In WandaVision’s new episode, somebody thinks of the children</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tqUADR4N25dUl1mJgA71HvNaN_E=/219x0:2517x1532/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809465/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.41.02_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vc88pf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is moving closer to its endgame, as SWORD clashes with Wanda, Vision continues to question his reality, and the mystery of who is actually behind the Westview Hex grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cp1IQD"&gt;But as we get closer to getting those answers, &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; has also started to lay the groundwork in this week’s episode for whatever might come next, including hints at a new generation of Marvel superheroes that could pop up in future movies and shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Fucjw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilers ahead for WandaVision’s sixth episode.]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l7XRwj"&gt;Two of a kind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="a8GAlm"&gt;The show may be called &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, but taking the spotlight in this episode are the couple’s children Billy and Tommy, who jump to the forefront of the early 2000s &lt;em&gt;Malcolm in the Middle&lt;/em&gt;-style sitcom of the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LxSkX6"&gt;The twins — born just a few episodes ago — have already aged into preteens and are starting to exhibit their own powers that match their comics counterparts, Wiccan and Speed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dvqNnE"&gt;The comics history of Wanda and Vision’s children is a complex one, to say the least. As my colleague Julia has alluded to in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22243271/wandavision-episode-3-recap-explainer-mephisto-agatha-harkness-tommy-billy-sword"&gt;earlier editions of this column&lt;/a&gt;, Billy and Tommy were originally magical constructs that Wanda managed to bring to life (through a complicated plotline involving fragments of the soul of Mephisto, the Marvel equivalent of Satan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DH1z5U"&gt;While those construct-children were eventually reabsorbed into Mephisto, Billy and Tommy eventually would return in later comics as members of the Young Avengers. But they weren’t quite the same iterations of the characters. Rather, they were “reincarnated” versions: &lt;a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/William_Kaplan_(Earth-616)#Powers_and_Abilities"&gt;William Kaplan&lt;/a&gt;, who adopts the name Wiccan and wields magical powers similar to Wanda, and &lt;a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Thomas_Shepherd_(Earth-616)#Powers_and_Abilities"&gt;Thomas Shepherd&lt;/a&gt;, who bears similar speed powers as Pietro. (He goes by the rather original hero name of “Speed.”) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQRurC"&gt;It’s those versions of the characters that &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is beginning to allude to with its latest episode. Billy’s Halloween costume is a dead ringer for Wiccan’s comic attire, while Tommy’s Quicksilver-like quickness matches the abilities of Speed. Billy’s visions at the end of the episode appear to be hinting at his own magical abilities, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uIdSe9"&gt;That leaves one of the biggest questions surrounding &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, though: are Tommy and Billy &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zsfQNoNpeYRnTk8STxAWmJNCv-4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299791/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.39.07_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nCjfbt"&gt;For the children?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oVEyBV"&gt;The answer may lie in one of the subtler reveals in this week’s episode: what exactly is happening to the hundreds of inhabitants of Westview when Wanda is not around, and — as Vision highlighted last week — where are all the children? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZSMav"&gt;It’s the recast Pietro (who, noticeably, seems to be suspiciously more aware of Wanda’s effect on the town than almost anyone else) who provides the answer. Whether consciously or not, Wanda was working to minimize her rewriting of the town’s inhabitants and the trauma it causes. The town residents’ lives still broadly resemble their own, with the children kept out of the picture until they’re needed. When Wanda and Vision aren’t around, everyone just sort of… stops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hw0pJN"&gt;But given what we know of the Hex’s ability to rewrite reality for anyone who enters, it’s possible that Billy and Tommy aren’t just magical conjurings — they might be real children who have been recast as Wanda and Vision’s kids, similar to the reincarnated versions of the characters in the comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjptcL"&gt;But if Billy and Tommy are just ordinary Westview children, where does their magic and speed come from? &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IWaeio8-Q-Nn9rW1r3_fo-QpR5A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299797/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.39.50_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Yc7UYy"&gt;Full spectrum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KUuImH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; may have an answer to that question, though, through its hinting at the comic book destiny of Monica Rambeau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QKPIZN"&gt;In the comics, Monica Rambeau isn’t just the daughter of Captain Marvel’s best friend; she’s a superhero in her own right, who gains energy-based superpowers as Spectrum after being exposed to extra-dimensional energy. It’s a similar origin to the lab results that Darcy reveals in this week’s episode, where Monica’s cells have begun to change on a molecular level as the only person to face repeated exposure to the Hex’s energy field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxOH0b"&gt;We already know that Wanda and Pietro’s powers came from exposure to the Mind Stone, and that Wanda herself has power enough to rival one of the Infinity Stones at this point. It’s not so hard to make the leap that Wanda’s own magical energy could confer superpowers of her own — powers that could be infusing Monica Rambeau &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;Billy and Tommy, sowing the seeds for a new wave of Marvel heroes. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279920/wandavision-episode-6-billy-tommy-wanda-vision-marvel-disney-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279920/wandavision-episode-6-billy-tommy-wanda-vision-marvel-disney-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:05:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:05:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Switch continues its bestselling streak, but the PS5 is making more money</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZiMJ8mnO0tu-4hYeaccuOmWQ3qc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809435/jbareham_180301_2346_nintendo_switch_0065_mario.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EKHbnw"&gt;The Nintendo Switch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;continues to perform very well&lt;/a&gt;, selling the most units out of any other gaming hardware in the US in January, according to gaming analyst firm The NPD Group. But Sony’s PlayStation 5 still made more money last month, despite a more limited supply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dib2a8"&gt;According to NPD’s January report, the Switch was the bestselling hardware platform in terms of units sold in January — the highest of any platform in that specific month since the Nintendo Wii in 2010. Despite this, Sony’s next-gen console earned the highest dollar sales total for the month of January, breaking the previous record set by the Nintendo Wii in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bPtZS2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are a few reasons why the Switch sold more units but made less money than the PS5&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="De9lcl"&gt;There are a few reasons why the Switch might have sold more units but made less money than the PS5. Most notably, the PS5’s starting price begins at $100 more than the Switch, with the digital-only PS5 retailing for $400 and the disc drive model retailing for $500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94F3UV"&gt;The PS5 has been out for nearly three months yet, just like the Xbox Series X / S, the PS5 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"&gt;has been &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to buy&lt;/a&gt;, with retailers mostly hosting online sales due to severe supply shortages. With no signs of retailers selling the PS5 in stores anytime soon due to the ongoing pandemic, the only way you can buy a PS5 from a retail store is to wait for another wave of PS5 restocks to appear online. But when they do, they typically sell out in minutes, and Sony’s strong numbers for the month suggest it’s going through its stock as fast as possible. NPD’s report makes no mention of Microsoft’s new Xbox consoles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPMLOU"&gt;Nintendo’s console has been impacted by the pandemic, too, as the Switch was a bit difficult to find last spring, but supplies have remained relatively healthy since. The Switch has also seen restocks of the base console and various bundles, including limited-edition ones like the newly released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop"&gt;Mario-themed bundle&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wJJgaO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Nintendo Switch has been the US’s bestselling console for 23 straight months","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"},{"title":"Sony sold 4.5 million PlayStation 5 consoles last year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22263821/sony-earnings-q3-2020-ps5-launch-sales"},{"title":"The true price of a PlayStation 5 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279859/nintendo-switch-lite-ps5-sales-january-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279859/nintendo-switch-lite-ps5-sales-january-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
