<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-18T13:38:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:38:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:38:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces 16-inch MacBook Pro with new ports and design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q3n76A8lOcCeTxI7UKOuQ0M1CsQ=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012026/lcimg_982af7b3_d14a_4a82_8073_a94b6e73fdd5.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="a2xXc9"&gt;Apple has introduced its new 16-inch MacBook Pro, promising an upgrade in both design and performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iyW7Ra"&gt;The chassis has also received a modern redesign. The device is 4.7 pounds and 16.8 mm thick, with a 16.2-inch display. The Touch Bar has been replaced by physical keys, and there’s an HDMI port on the right side in addition to a Thunderbolt 4 port and an SD slot, in addition to a headphone jack and two Thunderbolt 4 ports on the left. It’s the most connectivity we’ve ever seen from a Mac notebook, according to Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AhRU2Y"&gt;The first MacBook Pro 16 debuted in November 2019. It had a very similar design to previous 15-inch MacBook Pros and was powered by Intel’s 9th-Gen processors (which are now two generations old). Reviewers praised its outstanding keyboard and audio, in addition to its power, but moaned about the limited connectivity — there were only two Thunderbolt ports on each side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sS0Fuw"&gt;Apple announced two new processors alongside the 16-inch MacBook Pro: the M1 Pro and the M1 Max, which both have 10 cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlngy4"&gt;The M1 chip that Apple announced last November (which now powers the MacBook Air, the 13-inch MacBook Pro, the Mac Mini, the iPad Pro, and the 2021 iMac) has blown competing offerings out of the water when it comes to processing power, efficiency, and integrated graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OHtxSE"&gt;But customers have been waiting for Apple to release processor workstation machines, including the 16-inch MacBook Pro and a potential successor to the 27-inch iMac. It’s safe to say that many people are eagerly awaiting this MacBook Pro — not just to purchase for themselves but to see whether the M1 Max will take the laptop market by storm in the same way its predecessor did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kyaonQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:38:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:38:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new MacBook Pro has a notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vs_a3EC0lVvh66-mJaX1RihgKao=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012024/lcimg_dbbf28e3_568c_48d1_8c66_10c4149e89fe.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello notch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="koVG91"&gt;Apple is adding a notch on the display of its new MacBook Pro. It’s a cut out that will house the camera system, much like how Apple moved to a notch design for its iPhone X launch in 2017. The surprising addition of the notch comes in the new 14-inch MacBook Pro, equipped with Apple’s new M1 Pro silicon inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPNtvK"&gt;The 14-inch MacBook Pro is completely redesigned, and the bezels have been completely trimmed down thanks to this notch. The bezels at the side at 3.5mm, that’s 24 percent thinner than before, and up top it’s 60 percent thinner. The macOS menu bar now wraps around the camera, and it seems to look a lot better with dark mode enabled so the notch isn’t as noticeable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q8nZA4"&gt;This display is also 120Hz with HDR support, so you do get a big jump in fluidity for the notch. Apple is also adding an SD card slot, HDMI port, and more hardware improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HJkOe8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732912/apple-macbook-pro-notch-display"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732912/apple-macbook-pro-notch-display</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:35:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:35:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces new 14-inch MacBook Pro with a notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W8Gu1yCl8X5f8qVymayXFLwwadY=/121x0:1414x862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012007/1Rm4aV2YiD.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pzYFl7"&gt;Apple has announced a redesigned MacBook Pro, which now includes a 14-inch screen, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;Apple’s new M1 Pro and Max chips&lt;/a&gt;, a notch, and a wider selection of ports in addition to the standard Thunderbolt ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McMzX0"&gt;The redesign is the first major one in Apple’s pro laptop lineup &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13490774/apple-macbook-pro-review-2016-13-inch-laptop"&gt;since 2016&lt;/a&gt;, the year that brought ill-fated butterfly keyboards, the Touch Bar, and Thunderbolt 3 as the standard and only port type (with the exception of a headphone jack, of course). It also marks the return of the mid-size 14-inch screen, which Apple hasn’t put on a laptop since the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBook#iBook_G4_(%22Snow%22)"&gt;2005 iBook G4&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beNUXV"&gt;It’s nice to see Apple more clearly differentiating the smaller MacBook Pros. The lineup has been a bit confusing for the past few years — the two-port MacBook Pro and four-port 13-inch computers were awkwardly lumped together but were pretty different computers with different processors and prices. Now, the screen size difference makes the distinction clear: people looking for portability can get the Air or 13-inch Pro, and the 14-inch Pro exists for those looking for more horsepower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WMgpXS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:20:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:20:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s HomePod Mini gets three new color options</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j-UNdDcp-UybRFWpka5uG0XEIwY=/235x0:2766x1687/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011946/Apple_HomePod_mini_hero_5up_10182021.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s HomePod Mini ... now in color&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0FT5Ir"&gt;With Siri now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22720890/siri-voice-control-ecobee-smart-thermostats"&gt;socializing on other smart speakers&lt;/a&gt;, Apple took to the stage at its October event to announce a new look for its HomePod Mini smart speaker. In addition to white and black (space gray), you will soon be able to pick up a HomePod Mini in yellow, orange, and blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dctHY3"&gt;Apple is catching up with the competition here. Google’s Nest Mini smart speakers have blue and orange options, and there’s also a blue Amazon’s Echo Dot, plus some fun animal-themed colors offered on the Echo Dot Kids edition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ql281U"&gt;Apple’s new, colorful smart speakers cost the same, $99, and will be available in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noxVVm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:18:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:18:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new M1 Pro and M1 Max processors take its in-house Arm-based chips to new heights</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e7BlgsBIEdxifeQl6sj7oGLgHlM=/127x0:1288x774/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011926/Untitled.5.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lzy4HC"&gt;Apple has officially announced its most powerful chips ever: the M1 Pro and M1 Max, souped-up versions of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558095/apple-silicon-m1-chip-arm-macs-soc-charge-power-efficiency-mobile-processor"&gt;the M1 chip&lt;/a&gt; that it debuted last fall and the heart of its new MacBook Pro models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1MyN0q"&gt;The original M1 chip was announced a little less than a year ago as Apple’s first in-house, Arm-based chip for laptops. At launch, it was featured in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;Apple’s revamped MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;13-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;the entry-level Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;, in addition to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22440059/apple-imac-m1-2021-24-review"&gt;2021 iMac&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;iPad Pro refreshes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MulTxQ"&gt;But as good as the M1 chip was, it was only a solution for replacing Intel on Apple’s entry-to-mid level hardware, with its high-end MacBook Pro, iMac, and Mac Mini models (meant for developers, programmers, graphic designers, and other more demanding workloads) all notably still sticking with Intel’s chips for the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2gnb7E3RgMZiuUET43W0Lk7P2Zw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936632/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.16.30_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dLnsCOhvR8rB2XTIDFmtkhLpl-M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936602/lcimg_2d0f1c7f_4824_4e90_b501_7d917bcd4ae2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o8R39h"&gt;The M1 Pro and M1 Max are Apple’s long-awaited answer to that issue: while both are built on the same 5nm process, Apple is promising big jumps in performance here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="REgwYE"&gt;For the M1 Pro, Apple promises 70 percent better CPU performance and twice the graphics performance compared to the M1. While the basic architecture is still the same on the M1 Pro, Apple is upping the hardware here in a big way, with a 10-core CPU that offers eight performance cores and two efficiency cores, along with a 16-core GPU with 2,048 execution units. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HFZK7y"&gt;The new chip also supports more RAM, with configuration options up to 32GB (although, like the M1, memory is still integrated directly into the chip itself, instead of user-upgradable) with 200GB/s memory bandwidth. In total, the M1 Pro has 33.7 billion transistors, roughly twice that number of transistors that the M1 has. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fiLZU7uzSdtjK0cNs59lV7tp9Dk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936603/lcimg_c4568d1b_5f1a_468a_9292_9743a7eadbd3.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dl3qmc"&gt;But Apple isn’t stopping there: it also announced the even &lt;em&gt;more &lt;/em&gt;powerful M1 Max, which has the same 10-core CPU configuration, with eight performance cores and two efficiency cores. But the M1 Max doubles the memory bandwidth (to 400GB/s), RAM (up to 64GB of memory) and GPU (with 32 cores, 4,096 execution units and four times the GPU performance of the original M1.) The M1 Max features 57 billion transistors, making it the largest chip that Apple has made yet. The new chip also means that you can connect up to four external displays to a single device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7ZgZN"&gt;Apple also promised that the new M1 Pro and M1 Max chips offer up to 1.7 times better CPU performance per watt compared to both the regular M1 and unspecified four-core and eight-core PC laptop chips — although the company didn’t give hard numbers, or identify what other chips it was comparing things to, making it difficult to ascertain just how the new chips will hold up in the real world. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T6VF9S7nURce1VWHrkb-6vohvu4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936647/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.21.36_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TPIzkt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:15:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:15:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon threatened with criminal probe over reported search and product discrimination</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9039g-aSabaomSFPbxwUtkQQAGk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011913/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rP8gqo"&gt;House lawmakers are giving Amazon &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__judiciary.house.gov_uploadedfiles_letter-5F-2D-5Famazon-5Fmisrepresentations-5F-2D-5F10.18.21.pdf&amp;amp;d=DwMGaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=0wboxaxDvI2j3I5JR1N_op4UPS4msfrwmjVlLMwAKrc&amp;amp;m=lXKiD4YjMq3QcotpF0kJmWDE_AU13C-t2LO1MLna7t4&amp;amp;s=afDGMeUFUobGwNgRwI3fkGRTqpas0bL7kdkszLx4tHI&amp;amp;e="&gt;one last chance to correct the record&lt;/a&gt; on whether it uses seller data to copy popular third-party products and manipulate marketplace search results in light of recent reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLKVKU"&gt;In the Monday letter addressed to Amazon chief executive Andy Jassy, lawmakers called on the company to provide “exculpatory evidence” to corroborate congressional testimony that directly conflicts with recent reporting regarding the use of third-party seller data. Specifically, lawmakers called out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21347083/jeff-bezos-amazon-tech-antitrust-hearing-jayapal-questioning"&gt;Amazon founder Jeff Bezos for statements&lt;/a&gt; made in a 2020 hearing, claiming that the ecommerce giant “prohibits the use of anonymized data, if related to a single seller, when making decisions to launch private brand products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="krZyj9"&gt;That claim was contradicted by a series of recent reports from &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/amazon-india-rigging/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/10/14/amazon-puts-its-own-brands-first-above-better-rated-products"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which found that Amazon used data from independent sellers to copy popular products and manipulate search results favoring their own house brand items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GBfYXC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“At worst, it demonstrates that they may have lied to Congress.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e21czT"&gt;“At best, this reporting confirms that Amazon’s representatives misled the Committee,” a bipartisan group of House Judiciary Committee lawmakers wrote. “At worst, it demonstrates that they may have lied to Congress.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AM5Cw"&gt;Third-party sellers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21335706/antitrust-hearing-highlights-facebook-google-amazon-apple-congress-testimony"&gt;have accused Amazon of this behavior&lt;/a&gt; for years, and the company’s alleged discriminatory behavior was part of a yearslong House antitrust investigation into the company and other lawmakers last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hHvLzs"&gt;In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on Monday responding to the letter, an Amazon spokesperson said that the company “did not mislead the committee.” The spokesperson reiterated Amazon’s internal policy banning employees from using seller data to make private label products; the same policy Bezos mentioned in his testimony last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpxFgG"&gt;“We investigate any allegations that this policy may have been violated and take appropriate action,” the spokesperson said. “In addition, we design our search experience to feature the items customers will want to purchase, regardless of whether they are offered by Amazon or one of our selling partners.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mL674g"&gt;The lawmakers have given Amazon until November 1st to provide additional evidence supporting these claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYMZf6"&gt;Amazon sent along additional statements specifically addressing each report from last week. Regarding &lt;em&gt;The Markup &lt;/em&gt;story, Amazon pointed out that its house brand ad placements are “clearly labeled to distinguish them from search results,” and that results are tailored to “the customer’s query, the product the customer is shopping for, and whether the customer is shopping on desktop, mobile browser, or in our app.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zs6lPq"&gt;The Amazon spokesperson also went on to say “private label products are a common retail practice, and are good for customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8CCoi"&gt;Last Thursday, a bipartisan group of senators, led by Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN), put out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726897/amazon-apple-google-app-stores-marketplace-antitrust-competition-klobuchar-grassley"&gt;a new bill that would prevent companies&lt;/a&gt; like Amazon, Apple, and Google from using their dominance to disadvantage their competitors. The measure, The American Choice and Innovation Online Act, was approved out of the House Judiciary Committee last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2mitjo"&gt;In response to the bill, an Amazon spokesperson said that the measure would “jeopardize” the company’s ability to run a marketplace for the third-party sellers lawmakers argue the company hurts in search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GkcYv2"&gt;As of publication, the Democrat-led bill has garnered bipartisan support from Republicans like Sen. Cynthia Lummis (WY), Josh Hawley (MO), and Lindsey Graham (SC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUCCbo"&gt;Amazon did not comment on whether it plans to issue new evidence to the committee before the end of the month. In the letter, House lawmakers encouraged the company “to correct the record” while they consider whether to refer the alleged false testimony to the Justice Department “for criminal investigation” if appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d6PISv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7dp9cb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733031/amazon-prime-data-sellers-congress-judiciary-antitrust-klobuchar-cicilline"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733031/amazon-prime-data-sellers-congress-judiciary-antitrust-klobuchar-cicilline</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:15:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:15:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music’s new voice-only plan costs $4.99 per month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UtaG2Kgj_x2SxUy84d3Epf9FIWA=/146x0:1636x993/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011911/25cFLr6.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Music Voice Plan lets you access music through Siri.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g3viTf"&gt;Apple unveiled a new Voice plan for Apple Music during its Unleashed event on Monday that will be $4.99 per month. You can use only your voice and its Siri voice assistant to access all Apple Music content across Apple devices. It will be available later this fall in 17 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="du7pLy"&gt;“Apple Music and Siri are natural partners and already work seamlessly together,” Oliver Schusser, Apple’s vice president of Apple Music and Beats, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-introduces-the-apple-music-voice-plan/"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. And non-subscribers can sign up for a free, seven-day trial without auto-renewal to check out Voice before they commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKcI0d"&gt;Users can subscribe to the plan with Siri by saying, “Hey Siri, start my Apple Music Voice trial,” or by signing up through the Apple Music app. Once subscribed, users can request music to be played across all of their Siri-enabled devices, including HomePod mini, AirPods, iPhone, and when using CarPlay. Voice plan subscribers will have access to hundreds of new stations and playlists and full playback controls, including unlimited song skipping. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eE9bgi"&gt;The plan seems in response to Amazon Music’s Echo plan that’s priced at $3.99/month, which lets you use its Alexa voice assistant to request music via an Echo or Fire TV device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LxGn7V"&gt;Voice plan subscribers will get customized in-app experiences with suggestions based on their preferences and recently played music. There will be a dedicated section called “Just Ask Siri” with tips for how to optimize Siri for Apple Music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IKKtPj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T13:13:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T13:13:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces third-generation AirPods for $179</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NyOewOw7VnmjT0zzEC6Im56oKuQ=/238x0:2659x1614/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011892/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.11.15_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M1fVSZ"&gt;Apple has just introduced its third-generation AirPods, the latest set of the company’s massively popular true wireless earbuds. With a new design that blends aspects of the prior AirPods and AirPods Pro, the third-gen AirPods retain a hard plastic, one-size-fits-most fit in the ear. But the form factor is seeing significant change for the first time since 2016: the new earbuds have much shorter stems than before. Priced at $179, the third-generation AirPods will be available to preorder today and will go on sale next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I4qpkZ"&gt;They’re now water and sweat resistant. Battery life has been extended to 6 hours of continuous listening. With the case, you’ll get a total of 30 hours. The new third-gen AirPods have a redesigned custom driver and adaptive EQ that automatically tunes and optimizes audio output. Apple has carried over the “force sensor” controls of the AirPods Pro, and it also says the new AirPods are compatible with its MagSafe charging system.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NfU0_dIVbgbqzIsF-Y5njJa03SI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936604/Apple_AirPods_3rd_gen_lifestyle_01_10182021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The third-generation AirPods have shorter stems than their predecessors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mLFgKo"&gt;The company is putting a big emphasis on spatial audio and Dolby Atmos music mixes with the new AirPods. They’ll support the same head tracking capabilities as the AirPods Pro and AirPods Max, which also apply when watching video. Already seen by many as the champion of voice call quality, Apple claims to have further improved microphone performance on the latest AirPods. They “feature AAC-ELD, a superior speech codec that offers full HD voice quality, providing clear, natural communication for FaceTime calls.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZ6Tic"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/20/14016568/apple-airpods-wireless-earpods-earbuds-review"&gt;original AirPods&lt;/a&gt; were released in 2016 and were followed by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;a second-gen pair&lt;/a&gt; that added wireless charging and other modest improvements. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; arrived in 2019 with a more traditional in-ear fit with silicone ear tips. Last year, Apple expanded the AirPods line to cover over-ear headphones for the first time with the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features"&gt;the $549 AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tsMQ-2fUlOhjub7vCA_vircYgig=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936579/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.14.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s list of features for the third-generation AirPods.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tbkDkL"&gt;There’s a lot riding on the latest AirPods to sustain the huge popularity of their predecessors. Above all else, the earbuds are well regarded for their ease of use and seamless integration with Apple’s ecosystem of hardware, including the iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch, and Apple TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3CNfp"&gt;But Apple faces more competition than ever before — especially at lower price points. Aside from the latest alternatives from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, Jabra, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, Sony, and others, newer entrants like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22598920/nothing-ear-1-earbuds-review-features-specs"&gt;Nothing&lt;/a&gt; have sought to set themselves apart on design and value with starting prices around $99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jYJgAq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22495680"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Pro event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T12:42:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T12:42:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>NASA’s newly launched Lucy spacecraft is having issues with one of its solar panels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lai31ZuFR6c0DyxiXnoAYhGdLGM=/0x131:3110x2204/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011705/21_00210_lucy_solar_deploy_074.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of Lucy’s solar panels fully deployed before its launch&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Lockheed Martin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="k92NoU"&gt;A robotic spacecraft that NASA just launched to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22711372/nasa-lucy-mission-jupiter-trojan-asteroids-12-years-launch"&gt;explore clusters of asteroids around Jupiter&lt;/a&gt; may be in some slight trouble on its journey through space. The space probe, named Lucy, is &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/lucy/2021/10/17/lucy-spacecraft-healthy-solar-arrays-being-analyzed/"&gt;having issues with one of its two main solar panels&lt;/a&gt;, which are critical for gathering rays from the Sun and generating power for the spacecraft on its 12-year trip through the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8WOopU"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/16/22729626/nasa-launches-lucy-probe-study-jupiter-trojan-asteroids"&gt;launched Lucy early in the morning on Saturday&lt;/a&gt;, October 16th, on top of an Atlas V rocket from Florida. The launch was deemed a success, putting Lucy on its trajectory to reach Jupiter’s asteroids, named the Trojans, by 2027.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="s7dlq4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In the current spacecraft attitude, Lucy can continue to operate.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AB4wFg"&gt;But on Sunday, NASA announced that one of Lucy’s 24-foot-wide solar panels may not be fully latched, according to an update on the agency’s website. It’s unclear what that means for the future of the mission, but NASA says the mission team is working on analyzing the problem and will come up with next steps in the days ahead. In the meantime, both of the solar arrays are producing power and charging the battery, so the latch issue does not seem to be negatively affecting Lucy at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PF_ttE2IkpWqWKyes5fTq3l-Wy8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929031/final_lucy_high_end_render_pira.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Southwest Research Institute&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An artistic rendering of the Lucy spacecraft at a Trojan asteroid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="In1o5M"&gt;“All other subsystems are normal,” NASA says in its statement. “In the current spacecraft attitude, Lucy can continue to operate with no threat to its health and safety.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5BrAn"&gt;However, an improperly latched solar array might be an issue as Lucy makes its way deeper into the Solar System. The spacecraft is slated to visit seven Trojan asteroids, as well as an asteroid in the main Asteroid Belt, and it will swing by Earth up to three times to get a boost from our planet’s gravity. It’s a long road ahead, and generating power from the Sun will be absolutely vital on its journey.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732894/nasa-lucy-spacecraft-solar-panel-latch-problem-jupiter-trojan"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732894/nasa-lucy-spacecraft-solar-panel-latch-problem-jupiter-trojan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T12:42:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T12:42:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Someone unboxed the Pixel 6 early and didn’t bother to turn it on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pixel 6 color choices" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-XfVzGdHxQQaqtli3WLbugSjLuk=/0x22:3170x2135/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011701/pixel_6_phones.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Pixel 6 color choices | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="auC0LN"&gt;Google’s upcoming phones have made early appearances in leaks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/14/20865699/pixel-4-xl-leaked-photos-camera-specs"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/3/17814936/google-pixel-3-xl-leak-found-in-lyft"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/5/3/18527905/pixel-3a-xl-best-buy-leak-6-inch-display-64gb-ram-specs-features"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/3/4691652/did-google-just-leak-the-nexus-5-kitkat-video"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/10/12/3493954/lg-nexus-4-full-review-leaked-ahead-of-announcement"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again, so it’s really no surprise that someone seems to have obtained a retail-boxed Pixel 6 unit ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;the fall launch event tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iG6u53"&gt;In a video posted initially to TikTok, then deleted but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469"&gt;still available on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, @CristianDimboiu takes a literal approach to unboxing by removing the “Sorta Seafoam” green device from its carrier without going any further. You won’t see the screen turn on or see the screen at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dxeipT"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Google Pixel 6 - World First Unboxing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GooglePixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GooglePixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Launch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6Launch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/0z6wttnVp7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0z6wttnVp7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris DB (@CristianDimboiu) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fd2ZyY"&gt;Fortunately, Google apparently ships its new phone upside down so that you can see the camera bar at the back with multiple lenses. It also appears that this phone ships with a cable and USB-C adapter but no charger, so hopefully, new owners will have one handy. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Google’s own preview&lt;/a&gt; revealed that the Pixel 6 Pro adds a telephoto lens to the mix, but more about the hardware performance, display characteristics, and software tweaks will have to wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cmdcuV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Pixel 6: what to expect from Google’s thoroughly pre-announced phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PFB3Oe"&gt;What we know so far about the Pixel 6 family, thanks to retailer leaks over the weekend, is that pricing may have dropped compared to the Pixel 5. If information from Target is correct, then the 128GB Pixel 6 will go on sale for $599, while the 128GB Pixel 6 Pro costs $898.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
