<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-23T15:02:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T15:02:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T15:02:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>We regret to inform you that T-Mobile is selling a 5G-branded gin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LCOhGBVo2e8RQPnT2cd8PGEkZNk=/0x160:3833x2715/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494965/5gin_crop.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile’s 5G-branded gin and ginger beer go on sale tomorrow.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: T-Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FCFBBq"&gt;Whatever the reason, 5G-themed gin is now something that exists in the world, courtesy of T-Mobile. Ostensibly, “Ultra Capacity 5Gin” exists to celebrate a T-Mobile milestone: covering 300 million people with its low-band extended range 5G network and 150 million covered by its better midrange ultra capacity 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pJtDl0"&gt;But maybe it just came down to the company seeing Ryan Reynolds having a good time, selling gin*, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/11/25/20982199/ryan-reynolds-mint-mnvo-t-mobile-ownership-deadpool-detective-pikachu"&gt;enjoying ownership of a wireless company&lt;/a&gt; and it thinking, “Let’s get in on that.” Or perhaps as the Mariners were &lt;a href="https://www.lookoutlanding.com/2021/5/18/22443250/tigers-make-justin-dunn-look-good-mariners-make-spencer-turnbull-historic"&gt;on the receiving end of yet another no-hitter&lt;/a&gt;, some marketing execs out for a night at ol’ T-Mobile Park drowned their sorrows in one too many $20 G&amp;amp;Ts and got to thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2Yo9VQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With notes of pine, citrus, and unfulfilled Sprint acquisition promises&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Giq2mj"&gt;The corporate-branded gin nobody asked for is &lt;a href="https://heritagedistilling.com/"&gt;produced by Heritage Distilling&lt;/a&gt;, the Northwest’s preferred purveyor of flavored vodkas and Seahawks-themed whiskey. There’s a non-alcoholic option, too: Extended Range 5Ginger Beer, made by Jones Soda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cPyy9h"&gt;If this sounds appealing and your home bar would benefit from a gin with “approachable piney notes” and a label with loud magenta branding, then you can &lt;a href="https://t-mobile5gin.com/"&gt;order a bottle for $30 starting tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;. The ginger beer also goes on sale tomorrow at $10 for a six-pack. Just do us a favor if you order some: maybe pour one out for that fourth wireless carrier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;T-Mobile was supposed to help set up&lt;/a&gt; after the Sprint merger?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OfunIO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Technically, Ryan Reynolds &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.diageo.com/en/news-and-media/features/diageo-to-acquire-aviation-gin-and-davos-brands/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;sold his gin company&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; for $610 million last August. Spiritually, he’s still kicking around as part-owner, though.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547222/t-mobile-5g-gin-ginger-beer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547222/t-mobile-5g-gin-ginger-beer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EA continues to spend big on mobile games with $1.4 billion Playdemic acquisition </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Irn2xXyAD4JZUlFd1SuiM4zWFPI=/0x0:1520x1013/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494935/970613582.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MJtKBV"&gt;EA is adding to its roster of mobile game developers &lt;a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Electronic-Arts-Acquires-Playdemic-Makers-of-the-Highly-Successful-Golf-Clash-Mobile-Game-From-Warner-Bros.-Games-and-ATT/default.aspx"&gt;by purchasing Playdemic&lt;/a&gt;, known for &lt;em&gt;Golf Clash&lt;/em&gt;, from WarnerMedia for $1.4 billion. The company says it plans on using Playdemic’s experience to help make future mobile games and that it’s interested in using &lt;em&gt;Golf Clash&lt;/em&gt;’s mechanics with other franchises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJ25s3"&gt;It’s possible that EA could be purchasing Playdemic not only to gain ownership of a successful mobile game (&lt;em&gt;Golf Clash&lt;/em&gt; has over 10 million installs &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playdemic.golf.android&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;on the Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;), but because there’s opportunity for EA to incorporate some of its other series — &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22440408/ea-sports-pga-tour-release-date-course-list-majors"&gt;it makes the PGA golf games&lt;/a&gt; after all, which could tie in well with a mobile golf game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGbdXX"&gt;EA seems to be focusing on mobile gaming recently — it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22273187/ea-glu-mobile-acquisition-kim-kardashian-hollywood"&gt;also purchased mobile developer Glu&lt;/a&gt; in February for $2.1 billion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Tz28y"&gt;WarnerMedia, Playdemic’s former owner, is currently going through a transition, as it’s being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22444031/warnermedia-discovery-merger-hbo-max-streaming-giant"&gt;spun out from under AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; to join with Discovery. &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/electronic_arts.html"&gt;The company says&lt;/a&gt; that it’s divesting from Playdemic as “part of [its] overall strategy to build games based on Warner Bros. storied franchises.” Indeed, if you go to &lt;a href="https://www.warnerbrosgames.com/games"&gt;Warner Bros. Games’ website&lt;/a&gt;, it’s dominated by franchises like Lego, Harry Potter, and Mortal Kombat (with &lt;em&gt;Scribblenauts&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Golf Clash&lt;/em&gt; being the only real exceptions). It also has upcoming games like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22340247/gotham-knights-delay-release-date-2022"&gt;DC universe-based &lt;em&gt;Gotham Knights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. WarnerMedia says the rest of its games will become part of the combined Warner-Discovery company after the deal is settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nHEWk"&gt;Mobile gaming has become a big focus for companies as the market has exploded. EA competitor &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/11/2/9662214/actvision-blizzard-buys-candy-crush-king-5-9-billion"&gt;Activision purchased &lt;em&gt;Candy Crush&lt;/em&gt;-maker King&lt;/a&gt; for $5.9 billion in 2015, and its &lt;a href="https://investor.activision.com/static-files/af35383a-0db9-44de-b0b2-180eac785930"&gt;recent earnings&lt;/a&gt; show that the division is now bringing in more money than Blizzard. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22458279/valorant-mobile-spinoff-riot-games"&gt;Many popular PC and console games&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, and EA’s own &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; have also gotten mobile ports.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547324/ea-golf-clash-playdemic-acquisition-warner-brothers-games-mobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547324/ea-golf-clash-playdemic-acquisition-warner-brothers-games-mobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T14:56:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T14:56:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alien planets have had ‘front-row’ view of Earth for ages, astronomers say</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JUdFAwa9B5882whTM-fnxKq1QGc=/0x43:3600x2443/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494911/ssc2017_01d.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An illustration showing the seven Earth-like planets of Trappist-1, a nearby star system astronomers say will be able to view Earth in transit roughly 1,600 years from now.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / JPL-Caltech / R. Hurt (IPAC)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="byTdFl"&gt;For decades, astronomers have probed the universe for signs of life by watching distant planets glide past their host stars, studying the tiny dips of starlight that give away clues about an exoplanet’s atmosphere. Hundreds of those worlds could bear life. And if there’s life, what’s to say it isn’t looking back at us? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1ng06"&gt;New research published Wednesday entertains that question, finding nearly 2,000 star systems that have had a front-row seat to observe Earth in recent millennia. The study suggests that hypothetical extraterrestrial civilizations in those star systems could’ve been in the right position to watch Earth transit our Sun and look at us the same way we attempt to look at other planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="EoTU4n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The cosmos is dynamic, so the vantage point is not forever — it is gained and lost.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KbVq4b"&gt;A total of 1,715 stars within a range of 326 light-years have been in the right place to spot life on Earth, either currently or sometime around the wee ages of human civilization roughly 5,000 years ago, astronomers from Cornell University and the American Museum of Natural History wrote in a paper published in &lt;em&gt;Nature Astronomy&lt;/em&gt; on Wednesday. The paper, relying on a recently released trove of data on distant stars detected by the European Space Agency’s Gaia spacecraft, indicates 1,402 of those systems can currently see Earth from a finite perspective called the Earth Transit Zone (ETZ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t3vJw5"&gt;“I started to wonder what stars could see us if we change the vantage point... The cosmos is dynamic, so the vantage point is not forever — it is gained and lost,” Lisa Kaltenegger, an associate professor of astronomy at Cornell and a co-author of the paper, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “And I was wondering how long that front row seat to find Earth through the dip in brightness of the star lasts. No one knew.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QEZ2tA"&gt;Witnessing distant planets move around their star is among the primary techniques astronomers use to observe exoplanets. They watch for a “transit” — when an exoplanet’s orbit takes it between its star and Earth — dimming the star’s light ever so slightly. The idea behind the Earth Transit Zone retools that technique to imagine Earth itself as the exoplanet. As star systems swirl around the center of our galaxy, many fall into the position from which Earth’s silhouette can be seen crossing in front of our Sun, just like astronomers see exoplanets “transit” their own stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IC6j9n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Hypothetical aliens “could have identified Earth as a habitable, or even as a living, world long ago”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZyvPtv"&gt;In recent decades, scientists have put themselves in the shoes of imaginary alien astronomers to get a sense of how detectable we are in the universe, a unique “&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1603.00776.pdf"&gt;reciprocal&lt;/a&gt;” perspective in the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI). Some of those studies looked at star systems — many confirmed as exoplanet hosts — that are presently positioned to spot Earth. “If any of these planets host intelligent observers, they could have identified Earth as a habitable, or even as a living, world long ago, and we could be receiving their broadcasts today,” researchers wrote in a separate study published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Astrobiology&lt;/em&gt; in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTk5tF"&gt;But Kaltenegger and Jackie Faherty, an astrophysicist and senior scientist at the American Museum of Natural History, looked backward and forward in time. They found that 313 star systems were previously in the right spot to see Earth photobomb the Sun in the last 5,000 years. Ross 128 b, an Earth-sized exoplanet orbiting one of the closest stars to our Solar System, was in the right spot to see Earth for over two millennia ending at least 900 years ago. Exoplanets in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/22/14674088/7-planet-solar-system-discovered-conditions-for-life-water-nature-nasa"&gt;Trappist-1 solar system&lt;/a&gt;, some 39 light-years away, will be able to see our planet 1,642 years from now. And some exoplanets farther away have been in the ETZ for thousands of years and will remain for thousands more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="742enW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10620891"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0S0qOb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; anyone was living on these exoplanets and &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; that life had mustered the same technology humans currently have, they could have already found Earth. It’s a lot of “ifs” and assumptions, but given the course of human development, we know that it’s at least possible. “Although we cannot infer the time needed for life to start on any exoplanet from Earth’s history, the early signs for life on Earth are encouraging,” Kaltenegger and Faherty’s report says. The star systems closest to Earth generally spend over 1,000 years in the ETZ, the paper says, leaving open “a long timeline for nominal civilizations to identify Earth as an interesting planet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGep6T"&gt;Human-made radio waves that started pinging from Earth roughly 100 years ago have washed over about 75 different star systems, the paper says. Forty-six of those systems are also currently in the ETZ, meaning any exoplanets within those star systems probably offer the best seat in the cosmic theater for detecting life on Earth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ESdrl7"&gt;Meanwhile, humanity is continuing its own exploration of our neighborhood. Projects using the James Webb Space Telescope, a multibillion-dollar observatory now slated to launch to space by the end of the year, will be able to get a closer look at these nearby celestial bodies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mE0GBh"&gt;“We don’t know yet how likely it is to have life on planets or how likely it is that curious technological civilizations evolve from there,” Kaltenegger says. “We don’t know at all if there is life out there in the cosmos, but we are on the verge of finding out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="lQwYpv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How you can help astronomers hunt for undiscovered worlds","url":"https://www.theverge.com/science/22254948/planet-9-discovery-brown-dwarf-nasa-solar-system-astronomy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VtDtM3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QgfJNK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KA72Zl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ef94ef"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22545453/alien-planets-view-earth-astronomers-journal-nature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22545453/alien-planets-view-earth-astronomers-journal-nature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T14:43:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T14:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>To succeed, cloud gaming needs to disappear</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/raAhioVoGdFOS7XHGNSzKw87w08=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494837/acastro_190618_1777_cloud_gaming_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The problem with cloud gaming is you have to think about it&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="EsSyjB"&gt;Google Stadia, Amazon Luna, Nvidia GeForce Now, and more: none of these are cloud gaming’s final form. They had one spectacular window of opportunity to pitch themselves as the next generation of gaming ahead of the PS5 and Xbox Series X, but we’ve yet to see any sign that they’ve made a significant dent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="1IwYtb"&gt;I think it’s because there’s too much friction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DyHdnm"&gt;Before you buy a $60 game for a cloud gaming platform or sign up for a recurring subscription, you might ask yourself: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="JJwFhK"&gt;Will cloud gaming even work for me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ghKVbh"&gt;What if my connection isn’t good enough? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DDWXL4"&gt;What if my home networking gear isn’t good enough?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BG3fOJ"&gt;What if I live too far away from the servers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aHjpFf"&gt;Will this cloud service actually have the games I want to play?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ik0La7"&gt;Will there be enough of them to justify a monthly fee?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hvkmO7"&gt;Will developers bother to port games over?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IuRiZC"&gt;Will they run as well as they would if I just bought a console or PC?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DYb4iI"&gt;Will I need a special controller or dongle to play on TV?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lMI5BA"&gt;Will I go over my data cap?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mVJVIo"&gt;Will I be able to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/12/21252200/google-stadia-cross-play-games-lonely-venue"&gt;play with my friends&lt;/a&gt; who aren’t on this particular cloud platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QOaTzG"&gt;Will I lose access to my games entirely &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/11/21133793/nvidia-geforce-now-no-more-activision-blizzard-games-carriage"&gt;if they lose a distribution deal&lt;/a&gt; or shut down the servers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LhxnHN"&gt;Will I have to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22336600/nvidia-geforce-now-price-tier-cloud-gaming-subscription"&gt;wait in line to play my games&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bIV9lw"&gt;Can I access my existing save files?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vAcbDl"&gt;What about outages?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gp0FQk"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/18/20970297/google-stadia-review-gaming-streaming-cloud-price-specs-features-chrome-pixel"&gt;Are they hiding&lt;/a&gt; how well these games will run?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3JYdIN"&gt;What if this tech company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"&gt;suddenly decides&lt;/a&gt; it no longer wants to be a gaming company, or &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/30/shadow-game-streaming-bankruptcy/"&gt;goes bankrupt&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="yvIEbI"&gt;That’s a lot of uncertainty! But it doesn’t need to be this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tCfU65"&gt;The reason these answers matter is because today’s companies are generally asking you to choose. Is &lt;em&gt;this &lt;/em&gt;where I want to play my games? Should I invest my money in the cloud? It’s a little ridiculous, because the whole point of the cloud is that you can play anywhere at all. You don’t worry about where you’re going to watch your next Netflix movie or YouTube video, do you? You just tap and watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="icWCCo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Maybe the Netflix of games should actually be like Netflix&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zpq7jR"&gt;Someday, with the right business model, that may be how cloud gaming will work as well. You’ll be paying for the content, not the locale. You’ll simply sign up for a Netflix-like subscription filled with games that run on every platform under the sun, and their quality will dynamically adjust to the amount of horsepower you can access at any given moment — much like how the quality of your Netflix stream automatically adjusts when the rest of your household starts hogging the bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qTVuyu"&gt;Sure, games won’t feel &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as good on a phone as with the latest console or gaming PC, but you won’t have to think about whether “local” is better than “cloud.” You’ll get both, perhaps even simultaneously, once companies figure the economics out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oz2i5j"&gt;Games are already starting to work this way. Dynamic frame rates and resolution targets are common on major console and PC games, automatically adjusting a game’s graphics to keep the action smooth. Meanwhile, Microsoft is championing the idea that one copy of a game might be good enough to play across a console, PC, and cloud. Microsoft’s Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription and its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/10/21060771/microsoft-xbox-series-x-exclusive-games-launch-backwards-compatibility"&gt;Xbox Play Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21150594/microsoft-xbox-series-x-backwards-compatibility-support-smart-delivery"&gt;Smart Delivery&lt;/a&gt; initiatives give you digital copies of the latest Microsoft-exclusive games for your Xbox, Windows PC, and cloud for one monthly subscription, often bringing your saves along for the ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="u2ozNq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Game Pass is Microsoft’s true next-gen Xbox","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/24/21336892/microsoft-xbox-series-x-game-pass-event-showcase-future"},{"title":"Xbox boss says Microsoft’s Bethesda deal was all about exclusive games for Game Pass","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325757/microsoft-xbox-bethesda-acquisition-game-pass-exclusive-games-phil-spencer-comment"},{"title":"A first look at Microsoft’s Xbox Cloud Gaming on iOS and the web","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393793/microsoft-xbox-cloud-gaming-xcloud-iphone-ipad-hands-on"},{"title":"Microsoft announces Xbox TV app and its own xCloud streaming stick","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527420/microsoft-xbox-tv-app-streaming-stick-xcloud"},{"title":"Microsoft will build native Xbox games for the cloud, and the woman behind Portal will lead","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22544018/microsoft-xbox-hire-portal-developer-kim-swift-cloud-native-games"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Dv4Ype"&gt;When you launch that next game on your Microsoft Xbox One, you might only get the limited power of that last-gen game console — but switch to an Xbox Series X and you’ll see sharper graphics and higher frame rates (assuming its developers have issued a next-gen patch). You can get even more with a powerful Windows gaming rig. Games&lt;em&gt; scale &lt;/em&gt;to different hardware, just like they have across multiple generations of PC graphics cards for the past two decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JcG1xZ"&gt;Cloud gaming can scale, too. Microsoft has announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536418/microsoft-xbox-series-x-games-on-xbox-one-xcloud-streaming"&gt;older Xboxes like the Xbox One, Xbox One S, and Xbox One X will get xCloud as well&lt;/a&gt;, letting those boxes tap into an Xbox Series X-grade server to play next-gen games like &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a little like sticking a more powerful GPU into your machine. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22544018/microsoft-xbox-hire-portal-developer-kim-swift-cloud-native-games"&gt;Microsoft is also now pursuing native cloud games&lt;/a&gt; that could theoretically harness the power of multiple Xboxes simultaneously, unlocking experiences that might be impossible without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2RFTii"&gt;But cloud gaming could let games scale to your &lt;em&gt;situation&lt;/em&gt; as well, a little like that auto-adjusting Netflix quality I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYu3Gb"&gt;You might find this amusing: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452029/apple-microsoft-xbox-console-streaming-xcloud-app-store-guidelines"&gt;Apple’s App Store rules&lt;/a&gt; currently let you stream games from your own Xbox on your own local network to your iPhone with a dedicated iOS app — but it won’t let you do the exact same thing over the internet from Microsoft’s Xboxes sitting in server racks. Either way, you’re remotely controlling an Xbox over a Wi-Fi connection through the magic window of your phone, playing your games with your Microsoft account, yet Apple doesn’t treat them the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4feiBs"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This week, I dissected Apple's new rules that supposedly allow Microsoft xCloud and Google Stadia onto the the App Store.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Spoiler alert: they don't. &lt;a href="https://t.co/LbdEBAZdBN"&gt;https://t.co/LbdEBAZdBN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sean Hollister (@StarFire2258) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1307040255879442432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9lQYVR"&gt;But Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304762/microsoft-xcloud-app-windows-xbox-touch-controls-gyro-support"&gt;quietly working on a single app that does both&lt;/a&gt;, and it makes a lot of sense. If your phone had the choice of connecting to an Xbox Series X sitting in a server rack, or an Xbox Series X sitting in your house, why wouldn’t that app automatically pick the most powerful and reliable computer to stream those games? Why not stream from your gaming PC as well? Microsoft has let us stream &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/24/20813677/xbox-one-games-streaming-pc-windows-10-how-to"&gt;from Xboxes to Windows PCs&lt;/a&gt; for years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21448979/microsoft-new-xbox-app-mobile-android-remote-play-beta"&gt;added local Xbox streaming to phones&lt;/a&gt;, and there’s technically a way &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/20/20871130/microsoft-xbox-one-pc-wireless-display-app-stream-games-how-to"&gt;to stream from Windows to Xbox, too&lt;/a&gt;, but they’re currently all separate ideas inside separate apps instead of one intelligent auto-switching whole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CwdniE"&gt;That kind of dynamic switching could theoretically help the latency problem, too. Lag is a common reason some gamers reject cloud services, claiming they don’t feel as responsive as pressing a button on a console at home. (That’s often true.) But Amazon started figuring out a way to solve that problem seven years ago: &lt;em&gt;hybrid&lt;/em&gt; cloud games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vvXihl"&gt;In 2014, Amazon prototyped a tower defense game called &lt;em&gt;The Unmaking&lt;/em&gt; that could generate gigantic &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings-&lt;/em&gt;esque armies thanks to the cloud — while still letting you quickly and responsively aim a ballista using an Amazon Fire tablet’s local processing power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="h3qGCm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zGCS45s-2-o?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TRBj5W"&gt;Microsoft knows about hybrid games, too. The company’s &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; can offer stunning photorealistic scenery as you fly around the globe, because much of that data doesn’t live on your PC at all; it takes up 2 petabytes of storage in the cloud. And importantly, you can still play the game without that data; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/B9jTKrQA4O0?t=225"&gt;it just doesn’t look as good&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tdk4Us"&gt;When I fire up a future &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; on my phone, I expect it’ll be a full copy of &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, one that looks and plays like &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; but at drastically reduced quality — until I’m within reach of my Xbox, my Windows computer, or a fast and reliable connection to the cloud. Then, it’ll continue to play like &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;but &lt;/em&gt;with a seamless upgrade to next-gen graphics and the ability to pick up and play on another screen right where I left off. (That last bit is something Google Stadia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/18/20970297/google-stadia-review-gaming-streaming-cloud-price-specs-features-chrome-pixel"&gt;already does&lt;/a&gt; quite well.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iGsZ7P"&gt;I predict that the company which eventually sells me on cloud gaming won’t be selling me on cloud gaming at all. It’ll just be selling me the games I would have bought anyhow, with the added ability to play them wherever I want and with all of my friends, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417560/sony-ps4-cross-play-confidential-documents-epic-games-agreements"&gt;assuming Sony plays ball&lt;/a&gt;. The trick is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161469/nvidia-geforce-now-cloud-gaming-service-developers-controversy-licensing"&gt;making sure you have those games on board&lt;/a&gt;, and that’s where big platform holders like Microsoft have an advantage — they can bake those streaming rights into the agreements developers sign to appear on console. That’s something Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/2/22415712/microsoft-xbox-store-cut-epic-games-court-documents"&gt;was planning to do&lt;/a&gt; and may &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22424596/epic-games-store-sony-playstation-pc-games-steam-competition"&gt;have already started doing&lt;/a&gt;, and something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20952028/steam-valve-code-stadia-xcloud-cloud-gaming-service-competitor-streaming"&gt;we may have spotted Valve doing&lt;/a&gt; a couple years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kC5pgkmB_zy_B9EOhJdfUxPPRgE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22506605/Cuj9cpe.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Microsoft has apparently been requiring xCloud support, according to documents unearthed during the &lt;/em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;em&gt; trial.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S8t5oh"&gt;It’s not the only path forward for cloud gaming, though. Another way to sell gamers cloud gaming (without trying to sell them &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; cloud gaming) is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20993828/sony-playstation-now-cloud-gaming-gaikai-onlive-google-stadia-25th-anniversary"&gt;the way Sony-owned Gaikai originally did&lt;/a&gt;: you use the cloud to provide free game demos you can instantly play in your browser the moment you click an ad, with an option to buy the game or pay for more time when you’re done. Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527461/xbox-xcloud-game-streaming-try-before-download-feature"&gt;has teased “try before you download”&lt;/a&gt; as a feature of xCloud as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j6Qlrd"&gt;I also wonder if someday, some daring developer will release a cloud game without telling anyone it’s actually running on the cloud, later to reveal you’ve been playing on servers all along. It’s not currently feasible in the United States due to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/3/22365753/wow-wideopenwest-internet-cable-data-cap-pizza-excuse"&gt;the tyranny of illegitimate internet data caps&lt;/a&gt;, but perhaps somewhere else. It’d be a PR stunt for the ages, and perhaps it could convince the world once and for all that this tech actually works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="XNVVjx"&gt;The day someone can pull that off, you’ll know cloud gaming’s time has truly come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aPFM9q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTTCtk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547334/cloud-gaming-xbox-xcloud-microsoft-streaming-google-stadia-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547334/cloud-gaming-xbox-xcloud-microsoft-streaming-google-stadia-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T14:22:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T14:22:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hospitals are selling treasure troves of medical data — what could go wrong?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RwUCTGJXR_MF4Sw7XwxVC48sa4k=/0x0:2130x1420/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494737/VRG_ILLO_1777_AK_body_data.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Ana Kova&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Xz8J6t"&gt;Healthcare organizations and hospitals in the United States all sit on treasure troves: a stockpile of patient health data stored as electronic medical records. Those files show what people are sick with, how they were treated, and what happened next. Taken together, they’re hugely valuable resources for medical discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4FOyPw"&gt;Because of certain provisions of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), healthcare organizations are able to put that treasure trove to work. As long as they de-identify the records — removing information like patient names, locations, and phone numbers — they can give or sell the data to partners for research. They don’t need to get consent from patients to do it or even tell them about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SYkyWg"&gt;More and more healthcare groups are taking advantage of those partnerships. The Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minnesota, is working with startups to &lt;a href="https://medcitynews.com/2021/04/mayo-clinic-launches-two-joint-ventures-to-build-commercialize-diagnostic-ai-tools/"&gt;develop algorithms&lt;/a&gt; to diagnose and manage conditions based on health data. Fourteen US health systems &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/02/17/truveta-patient-data-terry-myerson/"&gt;formed a company&lt;/a&gt; to aggregate and sell de-identified data earlier this year. The healthcare company HCA announced a new data deal &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454817/google-hca-patient-data-healthcare-algorithms"&gt;with Google&lt;/a&gt; in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="68XbIP"&gt;There may be benefits to sharing this data — researchers can learn what types of treatments are best for people with certain medical conditions and develop tools to improve care. But there are risks to free-flowing data, says Eric Perakslis, chief science and digital officer at the Duke Clinical Research Institute. He outlined the ways the system could potentially harm patients in a recent &lt;em&gt;New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp2102616"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; with Kenneth Mandl, director of the computational health informatics program at Boston Children’s Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="rdlCFU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You don’t always understand the risks that come with the benefits until later”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ayIyoa"&gt;“I’m a huge advocate for open data,” Perakslis says. “I think it’s very easy to get excited about the benefits. What we know with medical sciences, though, is that you don’t always understand the risks that come with the benefits until later.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5OSqmt"&gt;Perakslis talked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; about what could go wrong and how to protect people from those risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4AqaEH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LrdOHa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When did healthcare organizations start taking advantage of their electronic medical records data in this way? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8j66S"&gt;I want to say it was probably in 2017 or 2018. The thing that really pushed this into overdrive was the rise of privacy-preserving record linkage, which combines records from the same person without identifying them. The technologies are perfectly fine. But it almost makes a lot of people feel like, “Well, if I de-identified the data, I can almost do anything I want.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JQfToJ"&gt;Before those technologies, the only good way to do de-identification was to have a statistician do it. These technologies made it so almost anyone could do it. They’re not expensive. So the technology is ubiquitous, and it’s very easy to make deals and start marketing the data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DnH2II"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is using this data, and what’s it being used for? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7yqhd3"&gt;If you look at ethical research, there are a lot of academic medical centers with great de-identified data sets and large research networks that have been well-monitored and well-designed. What’s happened beyond that is a place like an MRI center or a pharmacy has an agreement with a hospital, but that agreement doesn’t prohibit them from doing anything with that data. If you haven’t explicitly told them they can’t de-identify and sell data, they can. That’s the kind of thing we’d call a data leak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mcOBAH"&gt;So then there are these large data networks that are being formed, where people are putting their data in with other people’s, and then those big networks are trying to sell to pharma or government research labs or places like that. At the end of the day, everyone’s trying to sell to pharma because it’s so lucrative. In fairness, the pharma companies aren’t necessarily looking to do anything less than anything completely ethical, as far as getting data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzAHtk"&gt;I think most healthcare institutions are interested in using data for profit and for research. I don’t think there’s anything wrong with that if you can actually say how you’re returning the benefit back to the core mission of the place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DVq952"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So say I have my health record at a hospital that then decides to sell it to a private company that’s building a health database. It’s de-identified, so my name isn’t on it. In what ways does that put me at risk?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3bcIte"&gt;I’ve always kind of called de-identification a privacy placebo. It works about as well as the thermostat in a hotel room. There’s a lot of ways around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kALccq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’ve always kind of called de-identification a privacy placebo.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sf81ig"&gt;If it’s re-identified and the data is hacked or exposed, there are a few things that could go on. A lot of people will use solely medical data to make fraudulent medical claims, and then what happens is the victim of the identity theft gets all these bills. Your medical record contains financial information, so there’s the financial risk of that. The other thing that can go on is if you had a condition that you didn’t want your family to know about, or your employer or something like that, it could be exposed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ci04is"&gt;We’ve gotten really good at not fixing anything when this happens. Once the data is out, it’s out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aUtS7s"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those are the risks. But what are the benefits? How well can data from health records actually be used to solve health problems?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pUNtfr"&gt;The usefulness of it is absolutely overblown. I think that, at the end of the day, electronic health records have been shown to be pretty good billing systems. While there’s great research done on them, that doesn’t mean the research is easy. It just means more people have taken it on. Good research requires really skilled people to do it. It’s really easy to underestimate the complexity of the problem. I get people calling me all the time with big studies, wondering why we couldn’t just do it using electronic health records data. We can do a lot of research that way, but it isn’t always high-quality research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTu9Z6"&gt;I think there are benefits, it just matters where you’re looking. There are great open-source data initiatives that have just really democratized the ability for smart people everywhere to get access to good-quality data for their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOF30H"&gt;I’m sure people are going to do great things. But I’ve had long conversations with people in this market, and many of them genuinely believe that what they’re doing is going to help patients. But they’re naive, and there will be gaps in their methods that will invalidate the research. It’s the “move fast, break things” mentality, which is wonderful, but please don’t move fast and break things in my daughter’s medical records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TCI29"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there other ways to do better research that also gives patients more protection in the process? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yzn8Vh"&gt;There’s also the traditional medical research establishment that gets patients’ consent and uses the same technology in that consented way. And they get IRB approval. [&lt;em&gt;Note: Institutional Review Boards, or IRBs, do ethics reviews of research that includes human subjects.&lt;/em&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ow646"&gt;That’s done by the government and nonprofits and also pharma. There’s great stuff out there. So I guess the question is: why do we need this whole other thing? If pharma is de-identifying and sharing data where the patients consented for research and it’s overseen by an IRB, if all of that is working, why do we need this other, risky thing? The IRB also looks at the validity of the research. Nobody’s looking at the validity of the research of this off-the-grid stuff that’s going on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icgjFi"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think health institutions or regulatory agencies will adjust anything to block some of these data leaks or prevent some of the risks to patients? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2tdAR"&gt;Something like this is like any other kind of medical harm. An adverse event could be a destroyed credit score. I think there are parts of healthcare that take this very seriously, but I don’t think it’s second nature yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rqB1WP"&gt;That’s partly because the game is always being upped. I think it’s very difficult to stay on the curve, especially in medicine. On one side, you have these speed-of-light tech and cybercrime processes going on, and the other is smart people trying to take care of patients better. And they’re just mismatched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RUNlL"&gt;But I think the industry could help itself a little bit, and be more open, and say that they’ll do more with consent. Or [regulators] could make re-identification of data illegal. Something that actually protects the people who are going to suffer from this. I actually don’t believe there’s anything wrong with the technologies. It’s really more a matter of saying, “If we’re going to do this type of research, how do we ensure we’re protecting the people that might be harmed by it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XcUxeI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547397/medical-records-health-data-hospitals-research"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547397/medical-records-health-data-hospitals-research</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T14:11:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T14:11:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Brave Search is a new alternative to Google built on its own index</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1NJkhn0PqM91Cl6xEP47EzPR6cc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69494691/acastro_200211_3900_Brave_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J9ofkO"&gt;Brave, makers of the privacy-focused Brave browser, &lt;a href="https://brave.com/brave-search-beta/"&gt;launched a new search engine&lt;/a&gt; in public global beta on Tuesday (&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/braves-non-tracking-search-engine-is-now-in-beta/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Brave Search, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/4/18249623/brave-browser-choice-chrome-vivaldi-replacement-chromium"&gt;like the company’s browser&lt;/a&gt;, is meant to be a private and transparent alternative to Google’s offerings that doesn’t turn users into carefully surveilled targets for advertising. It also isn’t dependent on Google’s results — Brave Search uses its own independent index of the web to function. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GnMeoQ"&gt;Using an entirely different index is kind of a big deal. Google obviously dominates the space (to the point of becoming its own verb) and even other popular privacy-focused search &lt;a href="https://help.duckduckgo.com/duckduckgo-help-pages/results/sources/"&gt;alternatives like DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; rely on a mix of results from larger indexes like Microsoft’s Bing and their own web crawlers. Brave claims its search engine will default to its own results, but the company does clarify that for certain kinds of searches where it still isn’t able to produce results with enough relevancy (or enough results at all), it pulls answers from other providers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cMrUfvPYZnHO1cEvCC5d9UFT3MI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22677034/image1_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Brave&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brave Search in the Brave browser. Note the independence metrics on the side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6FiTJi"&gt;To measure how many of the results Brave shows you are truly “independent,” the company is also including a “&lt;a href="https://search.brave.com/help/independence"&gt;search independence metric&lt;/a&gt;” which you can pull up anytime via the menu in the top right corner of Brave Search. After enough searches, Brave is able to calculate what your personal “results independence” percentage is and also display the global results independence percentage for all Brave Search users. It’s not the most informative metric, but Brave does view it as a sort of promise that it will become more and more independent over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8akkcy"&gt;Along with being upfront about its results, Brave also says that it won’t track or profile users, and it claims it won’t use “secret methods or algorithms to bias results.” Brave is actually working &lt;a href="https://brave.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/goggles.pdf"&gt;on a proposal for a community-curated open ranking model&lt;/a&gt; called “Goggles” it hopes to use as an alternative to Google’s algorithm. The model would let users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="XXwKGJ"&gt;Create sets of rules and filters...to define the space which a search engine can pull results from. Instead of a single ranking algorithm, we could have as many as needed, overcoming the biases that a single actor (the search engine) embeds into the results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8w6l50"&gt;Brave plans to make its search engine the default engine for its browser later this year. The engine will remain free to use, with an ad-supported version on the way and a premium ad-free option coming at some point down the line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ovSCqn"&gt;The Brave Search beta is available now in the Brave Browser for desktop, Android, and iOS, and also at &lt;a href="http://search.brave.com"&gt;search.brave.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9yHCVu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547158/brave-search-beta-browser-private-independent-index"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547158/brave-search-beta-browser-private-independent-index</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram tests putting suggested posts ahead of your friends’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jhZQ1HRBOoxiPu5E0R6gNDiA1fA=/246x0:1782x1024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69493833/Recommended_Posts_in_Feed_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y4QryM"&gt;Instagram says reception to its “suggested posts” feature has been so positive that it’s launching a new test: this time, suggested posts will be mixed throughout your primary feed, sometimes ahead of photos and videos from people you follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhtUY8"&gt;The company is testing new controls, too, that’ll allow users to add specific topics as an interest for their suggested posts, as well as the ability to snooze the recommendations for 30 days to hide them from the feed entirely. (You can see what that looks like below.) The feature, which launched last year, has so far offered additional content only after you’ve seen everything the people you follow have shared. This new test will come to a “small number” of users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/37kh4_Tu6vwPoSd-pLDHPUw8GxY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22676856/Recommended_Posts_in_Feed_2.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Instagram&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FH4p2z"&gt;Although this change is only a test for now, it could signal a major shift in how the platform works. Instagram, of course, has an interest in surfacing suggested content to keep people on the app for longer. At the same time, people might prefer to just see the posts from the people they follow, especially if that group is small. (People are still upset the feed is no longer chronological, let alone now including posts from strangers.) That snooze button might end up being highly used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xCcjB2"&gt;This move also feels like part of a bigger trend in which platforms attempt to give users a semblance of control over the algorithm. Earlier this week, Tinder announced a feature where users could swipe only on people with certain interests, for example — a first for the company. Although algorithms are powerful enough to know what people’s interests are and what keeps them engaged, letting people select what they want to see might make them feel more empowered and give them greater understanding into why they see what they do. The app can feel less creepy while also keeping them interested, a win-win for companies.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547045/instagram-suggested-posts-test-algorithm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547045/instagram-suggested-posts-test-algorithm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T12:55:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T12:55:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Foundation will debut on Apple TV Plus in September</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qnd6z3ry89CES0r4LRh6KS9H5VA=/256x0:1792x1024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69493817/apple_foundation.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RZcT9s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; — Apple’s big-budget adaptation of the classic Isaac Asimov books — finally has a release date: it’ll debut on Apple TV Plus sometime this September, according to an email to subscribers &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/23/apple-tv-foundation-series-release-date/"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. An exact release date has yet to be announced, although, presumably, Apple will provide details on that in the coming weeks as the marketing blitz for the show picks up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhBl2L"&gt;The series has been a long time coming. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/11/17223728/apple-foundation-trilogy-isaac-asimov-tv-show-david-goyer-josh-friedman"&gt;first announced &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; back in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, as one of the marque series for the streaming service, and it debuted a trailer for it during its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21295512/apple-tv-plus-foundation-show-trailer-isaac-asimov-wwdc-2020"&gt;WWDC keynote presentation last year&lt;/a&gt;. But due to delays from the COVID-19 pandemic, the show was delayed to late 2021, and Apple hasn’t really shown off any more footage or information since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="O0VuAz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Can ‘Foundation’ bring in viewers to TV Plus?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ou0MW2"&gt;Set to star Jared Harris as Hari Seldon, Lee Pace the Emperor of the Galaxy, and Lou Llobell as Gaal Dornick, the series appears to be starting at the same place Asimov’s series does: with the Galactic Empire still at its height, but with Seldon’s “psychohistory” predicting its downfall, necessitating the creation of the titular Foundation to house mankind’s knowledge during a new dark age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhHrNi"&gt;Since launching in late 2019, Apple’s streaming service has been searching for its must-watch flagship series, a &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones, The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; of a show that gets viewers to pay the service’s monthly cost. And while the service has seen some success from shows like &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show &lt;/em&gt;— two of its earliest debuts — neither series has turned into the kind of massive hit that can drive an entire streaming service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AUN185"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"You may have to actually pay for Apple TV Plus to watch Ted Lasso’s second season","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="50j53b"&gt;So far, the biggest impact of TV Plus has been in the unlikely hero of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;Jason Sudeikis’ sports comedy &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — so much so, in fact, that Apple appears to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"&gt;timing the end of its extended promotional free trial&lt;/a&gt; for day-one TV Plus subscribers just ahead of the show’s upcoming second season. Apple is betting that the show will be the draw to get viewers to start subscribing in earnest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8FIVj"&gt;Apple TV Plus is currently available for $4.99 a month or as part of the company’s Apple One service bundles, which also include iCloud storage, Apple Music, Apple Arcade, and on the highest tier, Apple News Plus and Apple Fitness Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQG4ok"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W899zL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547252/foundation-release-date-apple-tv-plus-september"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547252/foundation-release-date-apple-tv-plus-september</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T12:53:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T12:53:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Marvel’s Avengers bug that showed IP addresses on-screen for PS5 players now fixed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wHYA2w9bTtQXKCZqYHl5ZMk-l5Q=/86x0:1015x619/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69493794/black_widow_headshot.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Widow in &lt;/em&gt;Marvel’s Avengers&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Square Enix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="G8mQDc"&gt;The developers of &lt;em&gt;Marvel’s Avengers&lt;/em&gt; have &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayAvengers/status/1407733073890840580"&gt;released a new patch&lt;/a&gt; that fixes a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545477/marvels-avengers-bug-ip-address-on-screen-square-enix"&gt;bad bug for PS5 players that showed their IP address on-screen&lt;/a&gt;. Having your IP address on display poses a particular problem for streamers and people trying to record gameplay of the game, as your IP address can be used to glean a lot of information about you (such as &lt;a href="https://www.iplocation.net/"&gt;an approximate idea of your location&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tweet-text"&gt;“Patch 1.8b has been published and fixes the issue that was occurring on PS5 where sensitive information was displayed on screen,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayAvengers/status/1407733073890840580"&gt;the developers said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “PS5 players are safe to stream now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwrNFU"&gt;The bug first appeared in the PS5 version of &lt;em&gt;Marvel’s Avengers&lt;/em&gt; on Tuesday following &lt;a href="https://avengers.square-enix-games.com/en-us/news/patch-notes-v1-8-0"&gt;the 1.8 update&lt;/a&gt;, which adds new content and a long list of other bug fixes and improvements. The developers first acknowledged the IP address issue shortly after the original update went live on Tuesday, and they &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayAvengers/status/1407388097319473158"&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt; that players refrain from streaming until it was resolved. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547280/marvels-avengers-ps5-ip-address-bug-patch-1-8b"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547280/marvels-avengers-ps5-ip-address-bug-patch-1-8b</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-23T12:11:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T12:11:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Supreme Court says a school can’t punish a cheerleader for swearing on Snapchat</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Snapchat white ghost logo on a bright yellow background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d1v1JkYZ96uEOi4b8FSy4_MCoqg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69493626/snapChatPattern_BW.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lJ3Yvp"&gt;The Supreme Court says a Pennsylvania school can’t punish a cheerleader for swearing on Snapchat. The 8-1 ruling determined that students’ rights to free expression outweighed the school’s interest in preventing potentially disruptive speech — in this case, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/4/22/22394121/supreme-court-cursing-cheerleader-first-amendment-bl-mahanoy-brandi-levy-student-free-speech-campus"&gt;a snap captioned&lt;/a&gt; “fuck school fuck softball fuck cheer fuck everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZLqsI"&gt;Justice Stephen Breyer &lt;a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/20pdf/20-255_g3bi.pdf"&gt;delivered the majority opinion&lt;/a&gt; this morning, upholding an appeals court decision from the Third Circuit. He said that student Brandi Levy — identified as B.L. in court documents — shouldn’t have been suspended from her cheerleading team for a vulgar post about school sports. “While public schools may have a special interest in regulating some off-campus student speech, the special interests offered by the school are not sufficient to overcome B. L.’s interest in free expression in this case,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="70CBzt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The student’s “pure speech” wasn’t harmful or harassing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FJb0Wp"&gt;Levy had unsuccessfully tried out for varsity cheerleading (as well as a position on a private softball team) and vented about the results on Snapchat, including a follow-up snap that said “Love how me and [another student] get told we need a year of [junior varsity] before we make varsity but that’s doesn’t matter to anyone else.” Another student complained about the snap, and the school issued a one-year suspension because she “used profanity in connection with a school extracurricular activity” on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lrIO4"&gt;Breyer’s ruling notes that Levy posted her message “outside of school hours and away from the school’s campus.” Profanity notwithstanding, the message criticized a decision the school had made. “B. L. uttered the kind of pure speech to which, were she an adult, the First Amendment would provide strong protection,” it says. And while the school cracked down on Levy for posting vulgar language on social media, there was no evidence that it punished students for generally swearing outside the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8qMrdX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Online learning muddies what counts as “on-campus speech”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mpfZyC"&gt;Thanks to a case called &lt;em&gt;Tinker v. Des Moines Independent Community School District&lt;/em&gt;, schools can penalize on-campus speech that “would materially and substantially disrupt the work and discipline of the school,” even if it’s protected by the First Amendment. But the standard for speech in other settings has been historically fuzzier, especially on social media where posts can be viewed anywhere at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkB9ST"&gt;Breyer said the appeals court had ruled too broadly to limit &lt;em&gt;Tinker&lt;/em&gt;, and he affirmed that schools can punish students for some off-campus speech, citing things like bullying and harassment as disruptive speech. His ruling also says the rise of distance learning — fueled by the coronavirus pandemic — has particularly complicated the issue. And the way Levy used social media mattered: her snap was sent to a private circle of friends and fellow students, and she didn’t identify the school or target any particular students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zXT5iq"&gt;Even so, the ruling emphatically supports students who make offensive — but not threatening or concretely harmful — statements online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d3lB5M"&gt;Justice Clarence Thomas was the sole dissenting vote on the case. Thomas, who has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22368045/clarence-thomas-social-media-regulation-knight-v-trump"&gt;argued for legally stopping&lt;/a&gt; social media platforms from banning their users, wrote that schools may have “more authority, not less, to discipline students who transmit speech through social media.” His dissenting opinion states that “because off-campus speech made through social media can be received on campus (and can spread rapidly to countless people), it often will have a greater proximate tendency to harm the school environment than will an off-campus in-person conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547065/supreme-court-mahanoy-school-cheerleading-snapchat-case-ruling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547065/supreme-court-mahanoy-school-cheerleading-snapchat-case-ruling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
