<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>This security researcher fooled an at-home COVID-19 test using a Bluetooth hack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qvBiYR7p7g7U4elz1kP2CFUgDDI=/42x0:1092x700/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70300934/img_product_consumer02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Researchers were able to exploit Ellume’s at-home test.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Ellume&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q1xB3S"&gt;A security researcher was able to change the results of an at-home COVID test and get those results certified by intercepting and modifying Bluetooth traffic from the device before it reached the app. The researcher, Ken Gannon, found the flaw in Ellume’s nasal swab test, which is designed to analyze and transmit data to a companion app which displays and saves the results. According to a press release from F-Secure, the security company Gannon consults for, Ellume has now fixed the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9JqBt3"&gt;The process of falsifying results wasn’t a simple one — according to F-Secure’s writeup, the researcher used a rooted Android device to tap into and analyze the data the tester was sending to the app. From there, Gannon was able to determine how the results were sent, and how their authenticity was verified. Then, he wrote two scripts that were able to successfully change a negative result into a positive one. When he got an email with his results from Ellume, he says, it incorrectly showed he had tested positive. If you’re interested in the technical details, you can &lt;a href="https://labs.f-secure.com/blog/faking-a-positive-covid-test"&gt;read the writeup here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iWnpUY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ellume says it’s followed recommendations to make this type of exploit harder&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BXstvC"&gt;Ellume says it followed F-Secure’s recommendations to do more analysis to ensure that data was accurate, and made changes to the app that should make it harder to analyze its data or take over the data transmission. Gannon told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an email that he didn’t test to see if his research was applicable to the iOS version of the app, and that the goal of his research was “to see if an ‘average person’ can fake a positive/negative COVID test.” He said that, in theory, “a dedicated threat actor could use [his] research to modify the Ellume app to always report a positive / negative result,” which could be installed on a non-rooted phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTYLpU"&gt;While Gannon’s writeup only includes changing negative results to positive ones, he says in F-Secure’s press release that “the process works both ways.” Before Ellume’s patches, Gannon says that “someone with the proper motivation and technical skills could’ve used these flaws to ensure they, or someone they’re working with, gets a negative result every time they’re tested.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a41Vxq"&gt;In theory, a fake certification could be submitted to meet US re-entry requirements. Not only was F-Secure able to get an incorrect result certified, it did so without &lt;a href="https://www.azova.com/testing/ellume/"&gt;a video test supervisor&lt;/a&gt; being able to detect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hgG0gR"&gt;The press release says Ellume is now working on a “verification portal” that will let authorities verify that its at-home tests are authentic, and has gone back to analyze all its previous results for accuracy. Ellume says it found that none of them had been faked. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847222/ellume-at-home-covid-test-bluetooth-android-certification"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847222/ellume-at-home-covid-test-bluetooth-android-certification</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-21T07:33:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-21T07:33:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s big holiday update adds TikTok and playable Sonic the Hedgehog  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Tesla Model 3 interior is displayed with a Sega Genesis game controller sitting under the infotainment screen with a window on the screen showing the game Sonic 1." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_UD039NLuQ9srYlRdeWAJUoMeAQ=/0x168:4032x2856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70300924/IMG_0936.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of the Sonic 1 title screen opened in the Tesla web browser taken prior to its release.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Umar Shakir / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="atniDs"&gt;Tesla’s annual holiday software update for its cars is here, &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/12/20/tesla-releases-big-holiday-update-tiktok-app-ui-changes/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electrek&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. It includes useful driving features like automatic access to a car’s blind spot cameras, as well as fun additions like new games built into Tesla Arcade, TikTok support, and a feature that lets the electric cars “dance to a choreographed light show.” The update’s version number is 2021.44.25, and should be rolling out over the coming days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYQRCp"&gt;The most useful inclusion in the update could be its blind spot camera feature which automatically shows a live camera view of the car’s blind spot whenever a driver activates a turn signal. Tesla CEO Elon Musk indicated the feature was in development &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1281121939600207873"&gt;in July 2020&lt;/a&gt;, but now it’s here to (hopefully) make maneuvers like changing highway lanes a little bit safer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FFLVTm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sure&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1281121939600207873?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n7jDOZ"&gt;Other practical improvements include an easier way to add multiple waypoints to a journey, and simplified controls for accessing a car’s primary controls. It’s also now possible to drag and drop your most frequently used apps to customize the car’s menu bar, and the heaters in the front seats can now regulate temperature based on how hot it is in the car generally.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RezT1V"&gt;Of course, this being Tesla, there are a number of less essential and more fun inclusions in the update. TikTok videos can now be watched directly from the car’s touchscreen via Tesla Theater, and Tesla Arcade has been updated with new games like the original &lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834023/sega-genesis-sonic-1-tesla-arcade"&gt;announced earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Sudoku&lt;/em&gt;. It’s probably best to save these for when the car is stationary, although &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823127/tesla-car-arcade-games-safety-nhtsa"&gt;controversially they’re also playable by passengers&lt;/a&gt; while a vehicle is in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tP4l2c"&gt;Finally there’s “Light Show,” a feature that appears to be coming to all Tesla’s after being shown off on the &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2015/12/23/the-tesla-model-x-flaps-its-wings-with-a-xmas-theme-light-show-video/"&gt;Model X in 2015&lt;/a&gt;. Many thanks to u/Emulsifide for posting a complete record of the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/teslamotors/comments/rl21jd/tesla_20214425/"&gt;update’s changelog to Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847952/tesla-christmas-update-2021-sonic-the-hedgehog-sudoku-blind-spot-cameras"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847952/tesla-christmas-update-2021-sonic-the-hedgehog-sudoku-blind-spot-cameras</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-21T05:01:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-21T05:01:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Xiaomi’s next flagship phone will launch on December 28</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rMEbCSv2RelPcCYZ8OXhUhVNBvA=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70300676/002p2Zyzly1gxl7k7wbp2j61o0280npd02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A teaser poster for the event.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Xiaomi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7GZaaz"&gt;Exactly one year from the launch of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22202973/xiaomi-mi-11-flagship-announced-chinese-variant"&gt;Mi 11&lt;/a&gt;, Xiaomi is set to launch the successor on December 28th, the company has announced via its &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/2202387347/L72AgfN3a?pagetype=profilefeed"&gt;official Weibo account&lt;/a&gt;. The new lineup will be called the Xiaomi 12 series, following the company’s decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639020/xiaomi-mi-brand-ending-mix-4-confirmed"&gt;phase out its Mi branding&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. A teaser poster features Chinese sprinter Su Bingtian, which sets the expectation that the event is likely to be focused on the Chinese market before the Xiaomi flagships make their way to global markets in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NzrwtN"&gt;Xiaomi’s 12 series lineup could include as many as four different devices, &lt;a href="https://gadgets.ndtv.com/mobiles/news/xiaomi-12-12x-pro-series-launch-date-december-28-poster-ultra-specifications-features-2662501"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Gadgets 360&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. These include the Xiaomi 12, the 12 Pro, the 12X, and the 12 Ultra, although it’s possible that not all of them will be announced during the December event (this year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356128/xiaomi-mi-11-ultra-lite-5g-announced-specs"&gt;Mi 11 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t announced until late March, for example). &lt;a href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2021/12/21/xiaomi-12-12x-12-pro-names-launch-date-confirmed/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gizmochina &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that Xiaomi executives have been spotted using the other three phones to post to their Weibo accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vyjIVY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="tl" dir="ltr"&gt;Xiaomi 12 and 12 Pro  coming &lt;a href="https://t.co/HRCYuamab9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/HRCYuamab9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ice universe (@UniverseIce) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1473190043711782912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YrsKej"&gt;There aren’t many official details about the upcoming handsets, but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/leijun/status/1465843044415336449"&gt;Xiaomi has confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that they’ll be powered by Qualcomm’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"&gt;Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor&lt;/a&gt;. Apparent marketing images of the Xiaomi 12 and 12 Pro shared by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1473190043711782912"&gt;leaker @UniverseIce on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; show the phones will feature centrally orientated hole-punch cameras. Other rumored specs of the Xiaomi 12 include a triple rear camera, according to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1471470228089585682"&gt;leaked renders from @OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt;, with a 50-megapixel primary sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W4csX7"&gt;Although Xiaomi’s phones don’t have much of a presence in the US, it’s ranked as the &lt;a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/europe-smartphone-market-q3-2021/"&gt;second biggest smartphone manufacturer in Europe&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/global-smartphone-share/"&gt;second biggest Android manufacturer in the world&lt;/a&gt; behind Samsung. Demand is driven by phones like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310843/xiaomi-mi-11-review-samsung"&gt;Xiaomi Mi 11&lt;/a&gt; which offers comparable specs to Samsung’s flagships at much more affordable prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YFsnAi"&gt;The Xiaomi Mi 11 launched globally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272003/xiaomi-mi-11-international-price-release-date-announcement"&gt;in February this year&lt;/a&gt;, which hopefully means that the international version of the Xiaomi 12 will arrive soon after the December event.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847884/xiaomi-12-launch-event-december-28-china"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22847884/xiaomi-12-launch-event-december-28-china</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T19:55:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T19:55:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Today I learned double-pressing Ctrl can become a powerful Windows 11 shortcut for finding your mouse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/stiu8__CBQWQO_mZJ_OKFW-y5c8=/0x0:4032x2688/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70299798/find_my_mouse_powertoys.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M2ZkAw"&gt;Ever lose your mouse cursor? It’s not hard to do when you’ve sitting in front of multiple monitors or perhaps &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs"&gt;a super-ultrawide&lt;/a&gt; or maybe even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22815110/lg-c1-48-oled-samsung-odyssey-neo-g9-review-monitor-tv#comments"&gt;a monstrous TV&lt;/a&gt; — but Microsoft has an amazing keyboard shortcut that can instantly surface your cursor, and I recently found it purely by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mu9kg"&gt;I was tapping away on my keyboard when all of a sudden my screens dimmed — except for one tiny disc of light. It turns out I’d accidentally double-pressed Ctrl, which triggers the Find My Mouse feature in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752275/microsofts-powertoys-windows-11-ui-video-conference-mute-find-my-mouse-features"&gt;Microsoft’s excellent optional PowerToys&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mdoicl"&gt;Here’s what that looks like up close:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The screen dims except for one tiny disc of light, around the cursor, which I can move with my mouse." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6jQ0G0H4zIk0g0vA_3vuAsKDKfQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23116573/find_my_mouse_2.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find My Mouse in action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4rzX0L"&gt;And here’s a rough idea of what it looks like with my triple-monitor rig:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NWJeHibFFa9ftxwyb5OGXDpj2NE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23116574/find_my_mouse_1.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sorry about the lower quality; I should have turned off HDR video on my phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AyZ8n3"&gt;For something so simple, it’s incredibly effective — the spotlight instantly draws my attention to where my cursor is, the dimming effect makes it perfectly clear where it &lt;em&gt;isn’t. &lt;/em&gt;As someone who used to wildly wag my mouse cursor around to find it across three screens, I’m finding it coming in handy almost every day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6TSBrh"&gt;My only question is: why isn’t this built into Windows 11? For now, you’ll &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/PowerToys/releases/tag/v0.51.1"&gt;have to download and install PowerToys from GitHub&lt;/a&gt; if you want it. I’m a big fan; I’ve used its highly customizable FancyZones window manager to snap windows into perfectly sized positions across my screens for well over a year now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QfYnZr"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rTtGzZYAXgY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Yedbvg"&gt;The Find My Mouse feature doesn’t require any additional setup, as I accidentally discovered myself. As long as PowerToys is up and running at startup, double-tapping Ctrl should do it. &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/powertoys/mouse-utilities"&gt;Microsoft’s support page&lt;/a&gt; does show a few ways to tweak it, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="EnuOgR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft is finally fixing Windows 10 rearranging apps on multiple monitors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407995/microsoft-windows-apps-rearranging-sleep-resume-fix-directx-12"},{"title":"Windows 11 is getting some much-needed taskbar and Start menu improvements","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812258/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-clock-multiple-monitors-start-menu-updates"},{"title":"Microsoft is pushing the Control Panel aside in its latest Windows 11 updates","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841028/microsoft-windows-11-control-panel-changes"},{"title":"The Verge Guide to Windows","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21231636/windows-10-pc-user-guide-how-to-microsoft"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847428/how-to-find-my-mouse-cursor-pointer-windows-11-powertoys-til"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847428/how-to-find-my-mouse-cursor-pointer-windows-11-powertoys-til</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T19:10:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T19:10:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google is turning off the controls for OnHub routers at the end of 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google OnHub router" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rv2LsLBsLak7mC3uObSHRbRPkYA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70299716/onhub-2.0.0.1440961465.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google OnHub router&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8HgXPY"&gt;Google’s insistence on cloud-based controls for its networking products has occasionally caused issues, even though it was supposed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/18/9172523/google-router-announced-onhub"&gt;make life with OnHub routers simple&lt;/a&gt;. Now it will be a reason pushing anyone still using the OnHub to find a replacement by the end of next year when Google’s apps stop allowing owners to change the settings on their devices. An email went out to users, and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/11257354?hl=en"&gt;a support page&lt;/a&gt; revealed the changeover is scheduled for December 19th, 2022 (via &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/12/20/google-is-cutting-off-onhub-router-support-next-year/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Droid-Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14kSge"&gt;When it still seemed unusual for Google and Amazon to make their own hardware, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/26/9211513/a-look-inside-googles-new-onhub-wireless-router"&gt;teamed up with TP-Link&lt;/a&gt; and, eventually, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/27/9621576/google-onhub-router-launched-by-asus"&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt; to build OnHub routers that made a point of blending in seamlessly with the rest of your house. They had slick mobile apps to simplify setup and controls, plus a style that blended in so people were more likely to place them in a central location, which could improve WiFi coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fgZ57q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google OnHub review: Is this the router of the future?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/31/9228739/google-onhub-router-wifi-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="F1HfBC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/11257354?hl=en"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Support:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fs9iMC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before December 19, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGf0tj"&gt;Your OnHub router will continue to work as normal, but won’t receive any new software features or security updates. We recommend you upgrade to a new Wi-Fi setup today. A special discount code has been emailed to OnHub users only, for 40% off Nest Wifi on the Google Store. This promotional code is available for a limited time.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eAJqZB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After December 19, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7YmpaZ"&gt;Your OnHub router will still provide a Wi-Fi signal, but you’ll no longer be able to manage it with the Google Home app. &lt;br&gt;You won’t be able to update things like Wi-Fi network settings, add additional Wifi devices, or run speed tests. &lt;br&gt;Google Assistant features like “Hey Google, pause my Wi-Fi” will stop working.&lt;br&gt;OnHub performance can’t be guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="LKP9P8"&gt;The idea was that by styling them to fit with interior decorations, people would be more likely to place them in a central location, thereby improving Wi-Fi coverage. They even had slick mobile apps to control them so that you didn’t have to dig through ugly menus, but now those apps are gone, with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364381/google-wifi-router-management-home-app-discontinued"&gt;settings merged into Google’s Home app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google Nest Wifi" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nj1irwcy7_W77pM-Gx7C62Vbp0Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19276765/vpavic_191010_3722_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Nest Wifi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LJDpDT"&gt;After the shutdown date, the routers will still work, but you won’t be able to adjust their settings, get any updates, or really do any troubleshooting. For its part, Google is offering owners a 40 percent discount on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20946586/google-nest-wifi-review-mesh-router-price-specs-features"&gt;Nest Wifi&lt;/a&gt; unit, which should knock a fair amount off of pricing that currently &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/config/nest_wifi?hl=en-US"&gt;starts at $149 for a base unit by itself&lt;/a&gt; or $189 for a base and one extender. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTKvYs"&gt;For routers that are several years old by now, at least, that doesn’t feel like an unfair offer to get a replacement that we called “even faster and more capable than before.” Still, it doesn’t change the feeling that buying one of these routers means “owning” it only for so long as Google is willing to provide support. How many of your supposedly smart devices will quickly turn into bricks and electronic waste if someone flips a switch on the back end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kEkxC8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google Nest Wifi review: the smarter mesh router ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20946586/google-nest-wifi-review-mesh-router-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KCGrAi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847277/google-onhub-router-shutdown-2022-nest-wifi-replacement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847277/google-onhub-router-shutdown-2022-nest-wifi-replacement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T18:49:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T18:49:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok’s new Live Studio app allegedly violates OBS’ licensing policy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GmejaV4x628g9yddaDL53TEeSXY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70299625/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ey0dK6"&gt;Live Studio, TikTok’s new livestreaming app for Windows, supposedly uses code from the free livestreaming program Open Broadcaster Software (OBS) (via &lt;a href="http://protocol.com/bulletins/tiktok-obs-gpl-violation"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). This would typically not pose an issue when done properly because OBS is open source — however, TikTok purportedly fails to adhere to OBS’ licensing requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5TG2rO"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Remember yesterday’s news about TikTok releasing a go live platform? Turns out it’s a fork of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OBSProject?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@OBSProject&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shoutout to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HunterAP23?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@HunterAP23&lt;/a&gt; for pointing this out&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;STOP STEALING FROM OBS JESUS &lt;a href="https://t.co/kx8ckK3MXS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/kx8ckK3MXS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Naaackers (@Naaackers) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Naaackers/status/1471494415306788870?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="goTUPL"&gt;The situation unraveled on Twitter after a user posted screenshots of what appears to be Live Studio’s code. The programmer who originally took the screenshots alleges that the app “is an illegal fork of OBS” and also claims that TikTok used OBS and then slapped its own user interface on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MA8YiG"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GlitchedMythos/status/1471520986155659265?s=20"&gt;another user&lt;/a&gt; points out, if TikTok does make use of OBS’ code, the platform is required to make the source code publicly available in accordance with the &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/gpl-2.0.en.html"&gt;GNU General Public License (GPL), version 2&lt;/a&gt;. If TikTok fails to do so, OBS could potentially take legal action against the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iAeeJY"&gt;Ben Torell, the business developer for OBS, later &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dodgepong/status/1471522226520346632"&gt;replied to that tweet&lt;/a&gt; in agreement, but noted that OBS is open to working with TikTok: “We have a commitment to dealing with GPL violations in good faith, and in the case of TikTok/ByteDance we would be happy to have a friendly working relationship with them as long as they comply with the license.” The Trump Media and Technology Group (TMTG) got in trouble for a similar reason in October, as it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752850/mastodon-trump-truth-social-network-open-source-gab-legal-notice"&gt;failed to make the source code for Truth&lt;/a&gt;, Donald Trump’s upcoming social network, publicly available after using the open-source Mastodon to build the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PLG0oB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839213/tiktok-live-studio-desktop-live-streaming-twitch"&gt;TikTok quietly started testing Live Studio&lt;/a&gt; with a small group of users just a few days ago. In its current state, it appears to be a barebones streaming software with the ability to let users broadcast live, whether from a camera, phone, game, or program. TikTok didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yt9aLZ"&gt;Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22788051/streamlabs-quickly-drops-obs-name-called-out"&gt;OBS was involved in a controversy with Streamlabs&lt;/a&gt;, which also happened to unfold on Twitter. OBS admitted that it didn’t give permission for Streamlabs to use OBS in its name, but Streamlabs used it anyway. After popular streamers like Pokimane threatened to stop using and promoting Streamlabs because of the situation, Streamlabs agreed to drop “OBS” from its name.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847213/tiktoks-live-studio-obs-open-source-policy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847213/tiktoks-live-studio-obs-open-source-policy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T17:05:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T17:05:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Matrix Resurrections won’t hit HBO Max until 3AM ET on December 22nd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DL1TKUMhpo8aX8jtePH9iY3GrBs=/471x0:1950x986/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70299184/Screen_Shot_2021_12_06_at_12.22.59_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Exa6EF"&gt;Bad news, &lt;em&gt;Matrix&lt;/em&gt; fans: Warner Bros. isn’t going to be releasing &lt;em&gt;The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; early on HBO Max &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737133/dune-hbo-max-stream-it-early-denis-villenueve"&gt;like it did for &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, the highly anticipated fourth film in &lt;em&gt;The Matrix &lt;/em&gt;franchise will make its streaming debut on December 22nd at 3:01AM ET / 12:01AM PT — meaning you’ll either have to stay up &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; late to catch the movie when it first comes out or (more sensibly) wait until Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HlL6Ni"&gt;The news isn’t entirely surprising given that HBO Max usually releases new episodes and movies at 3:01AM ET (or the equivalent time in other time zones) the date that they come out. Still, the company has broken its pattern a few times when it comes to major HBO Max releases: &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt;, as noted earlier, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737133/dune-hbo-max-stream-it-early-denis-villenueve"&gt;hit the service a few hours ahead&lt;/a&gt; of its October 22nd release date by streaming at 6PM ET the night before, while &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt; got a slightly &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt; release time &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22194171/wonder-woman-1984-soul-bridgerton-christmas-day-release-date-time-streaming"&gt;by debuting at 12PM ET&lt;/a&gt; on Christmas Day last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="huGO1i"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ix7TUGVYIo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lVURx9"&gt;That said, unlike Dune (which also hit theaters the night before its “official” release date), &lt;em&gt;The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t appear to be offering early Tuesday night screenings in theaters either, meaning that no matter whether you’re looking to see the upcoming sequel on the big screen or streamed on your couch, you’ll have to wait until Wednesday, December 22nd rolls around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUmULP"&gt;Practically speaking, though, if you’re looking to remain spoiler-free until you have time to see &lt;em&gt;The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/em&gt;, you might want to try and stay off Twitter on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847124/the-matrix-resurrections-release-date-time-hbo-max-streaming-december-22nd"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22847124/the-matrix-resurrections-release-date-time-hbo-max-streaming-december-22nd</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T16:46:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T16:46:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Meta cracks down on phishing scams that use its trademarks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dunJab9tYwiE9zemMbCfamNPcOE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70299090/acastro_211101_1777_meta_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bqzIt3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/12/taking-legal-action-against-phishing-attacks/"&gt;Meta is taking legal action&lt;/a&gt; against the bad actors who allegedly impersonated Facebook, Messenger, WhatsApp, and Instagram to conduct a phishing scam. The company claims that since 2019, the defendants created over 39,000 websites in an attempt to replicate Meta’s services, subsequently deceiving users and collecting their login information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="datAvp"&gt;In the post on its blog, Meta explains that the defendants used a relay service, Ngrok, to send internet traffic to the phony login pages they created, all while concealing their identity and location. Those who clicked the phishing link were brought to a login page that resembled Facebook, Instagram, Messenger, or WhatsApp. When the user attempted to log in, defendants would collect their victims’ usernames and passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="WdlGJF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Meta blocks and shares phishing URLs so other platforms can also block them”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="24R79K"&gt;Meta noticed that these attacks started ramping up in March of this year and worked with Ngrok to suspend the URLs that the bad actors were using. A copy of the legal complaint obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;shows that Meta’s lawsuit doesn’t just concern phishing attacks — it also raises an issue with copyright infringement. The defendants allegedly used the company’s trademarked logos and names on their fake login pages to mislead users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZuzDXB"&gt;“By creating and disseminating URLs for the Phishing Websites, Defendants falsely represented themselves to be Facebook, Messenger, Instagram, or WhatsApp, without Plaintiffs’ authorization,” the complaint reads. “Plaintiffs were adversely affected by Defendants’ phishing scheme and suffered, without limitation, damage to their brands and reputations, harm to their users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LuvE0b"&gt;In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20904233/instagram-anti-phishing-feature-emails-security"&gt;Instagram introduced a tool&lt;/a&gt; to help combat phishing attacks, which lets you verify that the emails you receive are actually from Instagram. Meta’s brands aren’t the only high-profile companies affected by these scams — in October, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22737580/google-youtube-channel-phishing-campaign-report-malware"&gt;Google reported a large-scale phishing campaign&lt;/a&gt; that attempted to steal creators’ login cookies on YouTube, gaining access to their username and password as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cVpsBf"&gt;“We proactively block and report instances of abuse to the hosting and security community, domain name registrars, privacy/proxy services, and others,” wrote Jessica Romero, Meta’s director of platform enforcement and litigation in the company’s blog post. “And Meta blocks and shares phishing URLs so other platforms can also block them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZCyvk7"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21165321-facebook-phishing-lawsuit/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="facebook-phishing-lawsuit (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22846952/meta-lawsuit-phishing-attacks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22846952/meta-lawsuit-phishing-attacks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T16:10:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T16:10:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cortana would be named Bingo if Steve Ballmer had his way</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cortana Windows Phone 8.1" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DFK0l3MLFteUajVaO7FkWr8FW9A=/0x0:636x424/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70298845/cortanawp811_640.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o54yAL"&gt;Steve Ballmer wanted Microsoft’s Cortana AI to be called “Bingo” so it would be more Microsoft-branded, according to &lt;a href="https://bigbets.substack.com/p/cortana-with-sandeep-paruchuri-big"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Big Bets &lt;/em&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;That’s according to former Microsoft product manager Sandeep Paruchuri, who recounted the story of how Microsoft’s AI assistant got its name to writer&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Alice Newton Rex as part of a deep dive into Cortana’s origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcabL1"&gt;While we’ve gotten a pretty good idea of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/2/5570866/cortana-windows-phone-8-1-digital-assistant"&gt;Microsoft’s ambitious vision for the AI assistant&lt;/a&gt; in the years since it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/20/5430188/microsoft-cortana-personal-digital-assistant-windows-phone-8-1"&gt;leaked&lt;/a&gt; then launched, Paruchuri and Rex gave the inside story of how Cortana was named, pitched to management, and the clash that happened between dreams and reality. Also included are interesting details about how the assistant became one of the main advertising points for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/10/16452162/windows-phone-history-glorious-failure"&gt;doomed Windows Phone platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="75d944"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Cortana was supposed to be a code name, but it stuck&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nOAJ3i"&gt;The article is a good reminder of the fun origin story behind the assistant being branded as “Cortana” — the name was taken from the Halo character (who is also an AI, which isn’t confusing at all) and was only supposed to be used during development. It was actually supposed to be called Alyx, according to Paruchuri, but when the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/6/8/4408798/windows-phone-notification-center-screenshots-leak-rumor"&gt;name leaked&lt;/a&gt;, Halo fans and tech writers were so frenzied that Microsoft decided to officially dub the feature as Cortana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="73HUAf"&gt;While not every part of the AI’s story is as interesting as Ballmer’s idea to name it after Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;-beloved search engine (which he came up with during his handoff of power to current CEO Satya Nadella), &lt;a href="https://bigbets.substack.com/p/cortana-with-sandeep-paruchuri-big"&gt;the newsletter is still an interesting read&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in Cortana’s history or are looking for tips on how not to name your product.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22846906/steve-ballmer-cortana-windows-phone-assistant-name-bingo-alyx-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22846906/steve-ballmer-cortana-windows-phone-assistant-name-bingo-alyx-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-20T16:07:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T16:07:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>The EV revolution’s next big roadblock: access to chargers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Transportation Secretary Buttigieg Highlights New Electric Vehicle Charging Station On Earth Day" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kFKxY5ujJ8Hj15FVs2SryY-8d50=/0x0:7987x5325/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70298803/1232464133.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electric vehicles are displayed before a news conference with White House Climate Adviser Gina McCarthy and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg about the American Jobs Plan and to highlight electric vehicles at Union Station near Capitol Hill on April 22nd, 2021 in Washington, DC.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Drew Angerer / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="14FCNy"&gt;Electric vehicles are set to play a critical role in our clean energy future, but in order for everyone to reap the benefits of EVs, they’ll need access to chargers. While the Build Back Better bill &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2021/12/19/manchin-climate-build-back-better/"&gt;suffered a major setback&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend that could mean significantly less funding for the transition to electric vehicles, there’s still hope that the &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/"&gt;bipartisan infrastructure law&lt;/a&gt; passed in November could bring EV charging infrastructure to places that have been left out until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fak77t"&gt;That could make it easier for drivers from marginalized communities to switch to electric vehicles, while also cleaning up the air in their neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2JfWDa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The way charging stations are spread out now is neither equitable nor convenient&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p2YERa"&gt;The way charging stations are spread out now is neither equitable nor convenient for many low-income communities and neighborhoods of color, experts tell&lt;em&gt; The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; Across the country, the places with the most access to chargers tend to be wealthier and whiter. That’s something the Biden administration could go a long way toward remedying, experts say, as long as it heeds advice that comes directly from those communities. Otherwise, existing disparities could get worse as policymakers hasten efforts to transition to electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pMop36"&gt;“There’s probably not a city that you could look at and say that there is a proliferation of charging infrastructure in these underrepresented communities because the strategy was: let’s place charging infrastructure where EV vehicle registration is,” says Terry Travis, managing partner and co-founder of EVNoire, a consulting group that works toward more diversity and equity in the industry. The profile of an average EV driver, Travis says, is still a white guy who lives in the suburbs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYnxCj"&gt;With the price tag for an EV &lt;a href="https://theicct.org/sites/default/files/publications/EV_cost_2020_2030_20190401.pdf"&gt;expected&lt;/a&gt; to become comparable with gas-powered cars this decade, that could soon change. After EV costs come down, access to charging will be the next biggest hurdle when it comes to replacing gas-powered cars. Today, many EV owners choose to charge up at home in a garage or driveway, but as EV adoption expands beyond individual homeowners to those who rent or live in apartment buildings, public charging infrastructure will become more important. There are only around &lt;a href="https://afdc.energy.gov/fuels/electricity_locations.html#/find/nearest?fuel=ELEC"&gt;46,000 public charging stations&lt;/a&gt; across the country, and very few of them are fast charging stations that can juice up cars in under an hour. The country will need more than 100,000 fast charging stations by the end of the decade, according to one &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822454/power-companies-utilities-ev-fast-charging-network"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="Xa4HDR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The country will need more than 100,000 fast charging stations &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TKbVSq"&gt;In California, which leads the nation in EV adoption, there’s been an uneven rollout of charging stations based on race and income. Census blocks in the state with majority Black and Hispanic residents were “significantly less” likely to have access to a charging station in their area compared to the rest of the state in 2019, according to &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0967070X20309021#!"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; published this year. The same was true for neighborhoods with incomes lower than the median for the state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vg7RnB"&gt;“The part that really surprised me [was] learning that the public funded infrastructure somehow is distributed in a less equitable way” than privately funded charging stations, says Chih-Wei Hsu, who led the study as a researcher at Humboldt State University. This disparity is probably the result of the state not being as thoughtful at the onset about how it designed its programs for funding charging stations, Hsu says. It’s a pitfall the Biden administration will need to avoid now that it’s trying to build out a national charging network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WiiNqW"&gt;The newly adopted infrastructure law includes $7.5 billion for EV charging infrastructure. That includes $5 billion for states and another $2.5 billion for grants prioritizing rural and “disadvantaged” communities. The goal is to build out a network of 500,000 charging stations across the country that is both “convenient and equitable,” &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/"&gt;according to the White House&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oLgS1b"&gt;The administration revealed more detailed &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/"&gt;plans&lt;/a&gt; for charging infrastructure last week when it &lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-and-dot-launch-joint-effort-build-out-nationwide-electric-vehicle-charging-network"&gt;set up&lt;/a&gt; a Joint Office of Energy and Transportation. The administration committed to getting input from “diverse” stakeholders on how to improve the nation’s charging infrastructure. At early meetings, according to the plan, they’ll discuss environmental justice and civil rights as well as partnerships with local governments and tribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eFqV3J"&gt;Saving seats at the table for grassroots advocates will be key to making sure marginalized groups don’t continue to get left out, experts tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. People from marginalized communities will know where to put charging stations that will be the most useful. It can come down to super granular factors like knowing which grocery stores underserved groups are more likely to visit. “When I go to Whole Foods, there’s always a charger,” Hsu says of the organic grocery store. “The clientele at Whole Foods is very different than say, [the supermarket] Vons.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29PcNs"&gt;By early next year, the Biden administration plans to issue guidance to states and cities on how to set up charging stations. “This guidance will look at where we already have EV charging and where we need—or will need—more of it. It will focus on the needs of disadvantaged and rural communities,” the White House &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/"&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt; says. The Federal Highway Commission is also &lt;a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/11/29/2021-25868/development-of-guidance-for-electric-vehicle-charging-infrastructure-deployment"&gt;taking public comment&lt;/a&gt; through January to inform its guidance on charging infrastructure deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qN8BS2"&gt;The biggest investment in climate solutions in the US yet was supposed to come through Democrats’ massive budget reconciliation bill. Iterations of it included billions more to install charging stations, including in &lt;a href="https://energycommerce.house.gov/sites/democrats.energycommerce.house.gov/files/documents/Fact%20Sheet%20on%20E%26C%20Build%20Back%20Better%20Key%20Provisions%20.pdf"&gt;“multi-unit housing structures” and “underserved areas.”&lt;/a&gt; But West Virginia Sen. Joe Manchin has all but strangled that bill to death. Manchin negotiated to cut down climate provisions on behalf of his state’s fossil fuel industry, before saying over the weekend that he’ll block the bill by withholding his tie-breaking vote. That means even more is riding on the implementation of the infrastructure bill that Congress did manage to pass this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4j0iNj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Policies that help underserved communities transition to EVs could address another environmental injustice: air pollution&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="itKh11"&gt;Policies that help underserved communities transition to EVs could address another environmental injustice, too: air pollution. In addition to being responsible for nearly a &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/topics/transport"&gt;quarter&lt;/a&gt; of US greenhouse gas emissions, cars are a big source of pollutants like particulate matter, which &lt;a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/116/13/6001?utm_campaign=Hot%20News&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=89531294&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9xNvMHn1bWk9yKfonfI3tKRFqpBykQxjDPLwQQ8jOWV6x-lOYIn8RzUEdKwvI0RkzvF9opoWwdz4RPe8VAmXGxrue0heNyHVsPkDmeLZHAAcWSn38&amp;amp;utm_content=89531294&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email"&gt;disproportionately affect Americans of color&lt;/a&gt;. A 2019 study found that White residents are exposed to 17 percent less air pollution than their individual actions trigger. Meanwhile, Black and Hispanic people in the US are burdened with about 60 percent more pollutants, on average, than they cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fMrAPL"&gt;“When we think about who these cars are impacting the most, and who emissions are impacting the most: it’s people in my community,” says Kameale Terry, who lives in South Central Los Angeles, a neighborhood with large Hispanic and Black communities. “And we’re not dumb people. We know that these things are health issues, and we want to be a part of the solution.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZmqJFe"&gt;Terry co-founded an app called ChargerHelp! that provides on-demand repair services for electric vehicle charging stations. One problem she sees through her business is a lack of &lt;em&gt;working&lt;/em&gt; charging stations in her neighborhood. Popular places for people to gather, like churches and small businesses, might have gotten initial public funding for a charging station but might not always have the funds to keep it in good condition, she says. Unless the Biden administration starts proactively planning for charger maintenance and repairs, Terry worries that this problem will replicate itself at a national scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LwUmdL"&gt;“What we’re seeing today is that there was no type of operations and maintenance money allocated, and we’re seeing the same thing — really it’s a little bit scary — with the infrastructure bill,” she says. ChargerHelp! trains and hires people, many from Terry’s neighborhood, to fix up charging stations for the companies that manufacture and operate them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cXK80"&gt;Advocates for cleaner transportation also say that the buck can’t stop with electric vehicles alone. Healthier air and a safer climate will still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22600226/bipartisan-infrastructure-plan-ev-charging-climate-change"&gt;rely on investment in public transportation&lt;/a&gt;. “While expanding EV charging stations is important, the ultimate goal should be to reduce emissions and vehicle miles traveled,” Kevin Garcia, transportation planner for New York City Environmental Justice Alliance, says in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8ME9c"&gt;For folks who live in transit deserts without adequate charging infrastructure or even subway stations nearby, climate and equity solutions boil down to more options for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22846965/ev-charging-stations-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-equity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22846965/ev-charging-stations-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-equity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
