<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-19T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-19T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How the pandemic inspired creative uses of technology in 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GEYyUpKLw8iwFwkfRnE3oB9potM=/205x0:1732x1018/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68552676/one_zoom_to_rule_them_all_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Josh Gad’s Reunited Apart brought together the cast of the Lord of the Rings movies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="x5Rmva"&gt;The year that brought us the coronavirus pandemic, murder hornets, and the deaths of Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Alex Trebek is probably one most people won’t be sad to bid adieu. Parents and kids were stuck together during lockdowns, trying to manage remote school and work, and everyone’s feeling good and frayed at this point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ypCje1"&gt;At the start of the pandemic, media was abuzz with the notion that this pandemic and the resulting lockdowns would be a boon for the creative process. Suffering and isolation, the logic goes, beget great works of art and literature: just look at &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/03/broadway-shutdown-could-be-good-theater-coronavirus/607993/"&gt;Shakespeare, who apparently cranked out&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Macbeth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Antony and Cleopatra&lt;/em&gt; while quarantined during an outbreak of bubonic plague. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jvr26F"&gt;While we may not yet know if another Shakespeare found their muse during the current pandemic, plenty of people found their creative spark thanks to technology, with librarians, artists, and even epidemiologists using the tools at hand not just to distract from the tedium of lockdown, but to put forth new approaches to how we learn and connect with each other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="P7hhvl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324558/google-forms-virtual-escape-rooms-librarians-games-puzzles-homeschooling"&gt;Librarians used Google Forms to create virtual escape rooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Harry Potter escape room" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u5EhT5Fc_DG9xnD9QDJtFMvDf04=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20083663/Screen_Shot_2020_07_14_at_3.40.36_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A &lt;/em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;em&gt; escape room starts off by telling players where in the Wizarding World they are.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1bq9Ow"&gt;The easy-to-use format of Google Forms allowed librarians and teachers to create problem-solving exercises for students designed as digital versions of escape rooms. In addition to solving the puzzle of the game, the escape rooms let kids hone their geography, math, and reading comprehension skills, and are built around fun themes that included &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jurassic World&lt;/em&gt;, and Marvel superheroes. Not only did they take away some of the tedium and chaos of online teaching and learning, but the virtual escape rooms were tools for staff development and community building. Brooke Windsor, a librarian in Ontario, put it this way: “We still want to sneak in that learning, broccoli-in-the-brownie style.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2QunsV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/8/21213184/tim-dunk-facetime-photoshoots-wedding-photography-lockdown"&gt;A photographer used FaceTime to create professional-looking portraits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QzOf4M9xG5wUDXAv_tlv_LLK6fc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22178797/facetime_photo_shoots.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://timdunk.com/facetime-photoshoots" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Dunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photographer Tim Dunk helped users create professional-quality photos via iPhone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vcGMKJ"&gt;As big weddings were (mostly) canceled and postponed in 2020, UK wedding photographer Tim Dunk decided he needed another project to keep his creative juices flowing. “I had to deal with the shock and financial implications of [the coronavirus] like any other photographer. It also threw up another challenge: how do we as creatives stay creative?” &lt;a href="https://petapixel.com/2020/04/06/how-to-shoot-portraits-through-facetime/"&gt;Dunk wrote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C7EmLQ"&gt;His solution: FaceTime photo shoots. The photo subject and Dunk connect on FaceTime, and he determines where the light in their house is best for a portrait. Then, using the Live Photo button on the iPhone (sorry, Android users) that lets you take photos during a FaceTime call, he snaps the pictures, then edits them in Lightroom. And £10 from every shoot — he charges £50 for a set of 10 to 15 photos — goes to the &lt;a href="https://www.trusselltrust.org/about/"&gt;Trussell Trust&lt;/a&gt;, a UK-based charitable organization that supports food banks. He’s also created photo books of some of the portraits taken during the project, and he &lt;a href="https://timdunk.com/how-to-shoot-portraits-through-facetime"&gt;penned a how-to&lt;/a&gt; for other photographers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gxcZ1y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2020/jun/26/80s-zoom-reunion-josh-gad-film-giants-lockdown-reunited-apart-frozen-olaf"&gt;Josh Gad created Gen X nostalgia on Zoom by reuniting movie casts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3Q9qns"&gt;Okay, so not all of the movies in Gad’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMCd3u3uQ0DtlDfVU0GlKpQ"&gt;Reunited Apart&lt;/a&gt; YouTube series are from the 1980s, but the casts of &lt;em&gt;Ferris Bueller’s Day Off&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Splash&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Goonies&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/em&gt; meeting on Zoom brought back the faces of some cultural touchstones of the American Gen-X childhood. Each episode benefits a different charitable organization and garners thousands, and in some cases, millions of views. The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l_U0S6x_kCs&amp;amp;ab_channel=JoshGad"&gt;One Zoom to Rule Them All&lt;/a&gt; episode featuring the cast of the &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; drew 5.7 million views and benefited nonprofit organization &lt;a href="https://www.nokidhungry.org/"&gt;No Kid Hungry&lt;/a&gt;. “Everybody is going through the same craziness, trying to operate in a world that’s still very new and complicated, where our sole connection is through the internet,” Gad &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2020/jun/26/80s-zoom-reunion-josh-gad-film-giants-lockdown-reunited-apart-frozen-olaf"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kN0UGS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.teachforamerica.org/stories/creative-ways-teachers-are-using-social-media-during-the-pandemic"&gt;A teacher created science projects on TikTok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="UblerN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@mrs.b.tv/video/6906654550380285190" data-video-id="6906654550380285190" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@mrs.b.tv" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@mrs.b.tv"&gt;@mrs.b.tv&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;An oldie but a goodie! &lt;a title="learnontiktok" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/learnontiktok"&gt;#learnontiktok&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a title="happyholidays" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/happyholidays"&gt;#happyholidays&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="holidaycrafts" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/holidaycrafts"&gt;#holidaycrafts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="scienceexperiments" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/scienceexperiments"&gt;#scienceexperiments&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="scienceathome" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/scienceathome"&gt;#scienceathome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ Christmas Hip Hop 3 - Tini Mc" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/Christmas-Hip-Hop-3-6839817225558296577"&gt;♬ Christmas Hip Hop 3 - Tini Mc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KtRNAT"&gt;If any app is having a moment in 2020, it’s the ubiquitous TikTok — fighting the Trump administration in court and at the same time becoming the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/6/10/21285309/tiktok-2020-user-numbers-revenue-smash-hit-mea-culpa"&gt;most-downloaded app in the world&lt;/a&gt; over the summer. Jacksonville, Florida science teacher Nancy Bullard created a Mrs. B TV on TikTok, dressing like everything from an astronaut to a chicken in the name of science. Bullard guides students through science experiments they can do without parental supervision, so parents working from home can have a bit of a reprieve. The response from students has been overwhelmingly positive, &lt;a href="https://www.cms.k12.nc.us/News/Pages/Mrs.-B-TV-Science-teacher-gets-creative-to-reach-students.aspx"&gt;Bullard said&lt;/a&gt;. “Whether it is the latest dance trend or &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, we have to find our kids on the platforms they’re comfortable with.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ZKBUyo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/2/21545725/fauci-tufts-chart-mood-coronavirus-medicine"&gt;An epidemiologist created a Level of Fauci meme&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/edsj_DahYip5keonamfJOLd9ATU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22007308/fauci_level.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Karen Errichetti&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Fauci’s facial expressions say it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GXvAyI"&gt;During the coronavirus pandemic, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) director Anthony Fauci has become one of its most recognizable faces — and it’s an extremely expressive face that usually conveys what he’s thinking. Epidemiologist Karen Sautter Errichetti needed a way to check in with how her students were coping with... everything... and created an unscientific chart based on the five-part Likert scale, using photos of Fauci on a one to five scale (later expanded to a nine-photo scale) so students could choose their mood for that day. Photos of the NIAID director smiling were the most difficult to find, Errichetti noted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xc18sP"&gt;Word is that Fauci himself has seen the scale, which is not quite the introduction Errichetti envisioned; she and her colleagues consider him a rock star of sorts. “Creating your own memes,” Errichetti told me, “that’s a little bit of your own kind of medicine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1cWUu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22167393/pandemic-tech-tiktok-zoom-facetime-google-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22167393/pandemic-tech-tiktok-zoom-facetime-google-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T23:39:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T23:39:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>DJI says people can still buy and use its drones in US after export ban</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QU36TjV4aUjxzYFa_gLpYe4CYmY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551981/dji_mavic_mini_drone_1412.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4NZ9FI"&gt;DJI says people in the US will still be able to buy and use its drones and other products despite being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188789/dji-ban-commerce-entity-list-drone-china-transaction-blocked"&gt;named to the Commerce Department’s Entity List&lt;/a&gt;. The Chinese drone giant was named to the blacklist on Friday for “enabl[ing] wide-scale human rights abuses within China through abusive genetic collection and analysis or high-technology surveillance” — most likely a reference to how DJI provided &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-03-26/dji-s-drone-supremacy-comes-at-a-price?srnd=economics-vp&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;drones and other technology to the Chinese government to be used in its Muslim detention camps in the Xinjiang province&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2zAs49"&gt;“DJI is disappointed in the U.S. Department of Commerce’s decision. Customers in America can continue to buy and use DJI products normally,” the company said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “DJI remains committed to developing the industry’s most innovative products that define our company and benefit the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBxqDE"&gt;The company declined to provide any more information about what it thinks will happen as a result of being named to the Entity List. Being on the list typically means US companies are banned from exporting technology to blacklisted companies. DJI not only sells products to consumers, but since it is far and away the market leader, its technology is used by all sorts of companies that need drones or handheld cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xCCby"&gt;This is not the first time that access to Chinese drones has been targeted by the US government, usually due to security concerns. The Department of Justice &lt;a href="https://www.ojp.gov/sites/g/files/xyckuh241/files/media/document/ojporderfundingdrones.pdf"&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; the buying of foreign-made drones with agency funds in October, and the Department of the Interior said it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21113533/us-interior-department-chinese-drone-ban-grounding-security-dji"&gt;ground its drone fleet&lt;/a&gt; while it looks into claims of spying and cyberattacks. DJI has pushed back against many of these actions, saying accusations of national security transgressions are unfounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SP4eWM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22190097/dji-blacklist-ban-xinjiang-entity-list-trump"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22190097/dji-blacklist-ban-xinjiang-entity-list-trump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T20:33:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T20:33:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s Microsoft store listing now has a warning for bugs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jReBBxOLhoHEb2TIDudebKw3L_I=/81x286:976x883/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551641/Screen_Shot_2020_12_18_at_5.29.06_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uNTwdT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;’s listing on Microsoft’s digital games store &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fcyberpunk-2077%2FBX3M8L83BBRW%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;now includes&lt;/a&gt; a label warning of potential performance issues on Xbox One. “Users may experience performance issues when playing this game on Xbox One consoles until this game is updated,” the warning reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GoQIYp"&gt;Players have observed numerous bugs and performance issues with &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; since its launch last week, especially on the Xbox One and PlayStation 4. The dissatisfaction led the company to quickly issue a statement suggesting that unhappy players try to get refunds &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173738/cyberpunk-2077-developer-apologizes-base-ps4-xbox-one-performance-issues-refunds"&gt;for the game&lt;/a&gt;. Many players had trouble actually getting refunds, though, given Sony and Microsoft’s typically strict policies for issuing refunds of digital games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dq0cYq"&gt;Since Thursday evening, though, that has changed. Sony began offering full refunds of Cyberpunk 2077 and yanked the game entirely from the PlayStation Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;Thursday night&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft’s response, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189059/microsoft-cyberpunk-2077-refunds-xbox-microsoft-store"&gt;issued Friday morning&lt;/a&gt;, wasn’t as drastic: the company also began offering full refunds of digital sales, but the game remains on the Microsoft Store. At some point Friday, though, a warning label appeared on the game’s listing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2LQpE1"&gt;It’s unclear if Microsoft or CD Projekt Red applied the label. Neither company immediately replied to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9FhXl"&gt;CD Projekt Red has so far released two post-launch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;hotfixes&lt;/a&gt; (with one of those &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189893/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-hotfix-bugs"&gt;hitting Friday evening&lt;/a&gt;) to help improve the game’s performance. There are also two larger patches in the works for January and February that will fix “the most prominent problems” players are seeing on older consoles, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1338390123373801472"&gt;according to the studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189918/cyberpunk-2077-microsoft-store-listing-warning-label"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189918/cyberpunk-2077-microsoft-store-listing-warning-label</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T20:05:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T20:05:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s 1.05 update addresses a laundry list of bugs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SZkVpMSOabIVxyXX2I2EYMi3_VU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551568/screen_gotta_know_where_to_look_en.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OrxH0m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;’s second promised hotfix is out for Xbox and PlayStation platforms. The PC version will follow “soon,” according to developer CD Projekt Red. You can read the extensive list of &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37166/hotfix-1-05"&gt;fixes here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Trvpmn"&gt;While there doesn’t seem to be anything quite as significant as the changes to reduce epilepsy risk made in last week’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;1.04 hotfix&lt;/a&gt;, hopefully this new update will make what has been a very buggy game have a few less issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TRawXT"&gt;The game has been out for a little more than a week, and players have been criticizing the game for its numerous bugs and performance issues, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2077-cyberpunk-2077-how-bad-is-last-gen-performance-and-can-it-be-improved"&gt;particularly on older consoles&lt;/a&gt;. The outcry led to Sony offering full refunds of digital copies of the game and taking the unprecedented step of yanking the game from the PlayStation Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;Thursday night&lt;/a&gt;. As of this writing, the game has not returned to Sony’s storefront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNdap9"&gt;Microsoft is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189059/microsoft-cyberpunk-2077-refunds-xbox-microsoft-store"&gt;offering refunds&lt;/a&gt; for digital versions, though the game remains available for digital purchase. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189322/cyberpunk-2077-refund-cd-projekt-red-ps4-xbox-one"&gt;CD Projekt Red has also vowed&lt;/a&gt; to pay for refunds for retail purchases of the game “out of our own pocket if necessary” if players submit refund requests by December 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4CKWO"&gt;CD Projekt Red &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1338390123373801472"&gt;has committed&lt;/a&gt; to releasing two larger patches to help the game run better in January and February. “Together these should fix the most prominent problems gamers are facing on last-gen consoles,” according to the studio.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189893/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-hotfix-bugs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189893/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-hotfix-bugs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T19:47:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T19:47:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Members of the US Space Force will now be called ‘Guardians’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xRp7xycT_6f3l_4rg9VKepM42ek=/0x0:3600x2400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551473/SpaceForce_Guardians.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: United States Space Force&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bmbVn3"&gt;Members of the United States Space Force &lt;a href="https://www.spaceforce.mil/News/Article/2452593/us-space-force-unveils-name-of-space-professionals/"&gt;will officially be called “Guardians”&lt;/a&gt;, according to an announcement Vice President Mike Pence made at an event celebrating the military branch’s one year anniversary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2xnYN"&gt;The organization traces the name “Guardians” back to an old Air Force Space Command motto from 1983, “Guardians of the High Frontier,” according to &lt;a href="https://www.spaceforce.mil/News/Article/2452593/us-space-force-unveils-name-of-space-professionals/"&gt;a short post on the US Space Force website&lt;/a&gt;. While a distinct entity, Space Force is part of the Air Force per its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/21004914/space-force-military-branch-ndaa-2020-joint-chiefs"&gt;establishment with the National Defense Authorization Act&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rbBF39"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LR2xlbRe6po?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=4946&amp;amp;start=4946" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="frwqxV"&gt;As it exists today, Space Force is mostly a rebrand of Air Force Space Command, but with the authority to make decisions independent from the Air Force. Space Force personnel also mostly come from the Air Force, but there’s been notable transfers — &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/astronaut-mike-hopkins-space-force-7891a73d-33a8-4b3f-8437-72f502ecce37.html"&gt;like astronaut Mike Hopkins&lt;/a&gt; — who’ve joined from other government organizations. Unlike Hopkins’ former employer NASA, Space Force is less concerned with exploring space, than it is controlling it and protecting American assets like satellites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1kw7Qw"&gt;Choosing “Guardians” as an official name comes with some unavoidable (and maybe intended) pop culture associations. There’s Disney’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/24/15394108/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2-review-chris-pratt-marvel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy &lt;/em&gt;franchise&lt;/a&gt;, which introduced Marvel film fans to the “cosmic” side of the Marvel universe. And from the world of video games, Guardians also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/5/16253052/destiny-2-launch-gameplay-preview-impressions"&gt;show up again in &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as undead warriors charged with defending the Last City on Earth from alien enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7PMhtM"&gt;This wouldn’t be the first time that Space Force appeared to be cribbing from pop culture, either. When the organization &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/24/21080812/space-force-new-logo-donald-trump-reveal-design-star-trek"&gt;revealed the official logo&lt;/a&gt;, many pointed out its similarities to the Starfleet emblem used in the television show &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;. The US Space Force later attempted to clarify that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21335338/united-states-space-force-star-trek-delta-symbol-air-force-space-command"&gt;inspired by older Air Force Space Command logos&lt;/a&gt; rather than the hit series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GGSPDx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Oh wow. &lt;a href="https://t.co/uiJfOS1L1H"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uiJfOS1L1H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Miriam Kramer (@mirikramer) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mirikramer/status/1220822476621598720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 24, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ppwkzC"&gt;Whatever the source of the name, you can count on Space Force being a lot more mundane than any of the pop culture we associate with it. It may be a bit of a branding exercise to satisfy the President, but the Biden administration appears to have &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/biden-likely-to-stay-course-on-space-force-and-defense-investments/"&gt;no plans to change course&lt;/a&gt;. With Space Force and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700565/nasa-artemis-moon-return-landing-trump-administration-jim-bridenstine"&gt;recent work to return to the moon&lt;/a&gt;, the US is focusing even more on space heading into the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XgeFq3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zqvnvi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVyuG3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189637/space-force-military-branch-official-name-guardians"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189637/space-force-military-branch-official-name-guardians</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T19:39:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T19:39:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Moderna COVID-19 vaccine second to get FDA sign-off in US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration Of Moderna Logo With A Syringe" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/skJAj8q3qyZFagq2G96SndVcoNg=/0x0:5400x3600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551451/1230124131.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Nicolas Economou/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JSv9D8"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-takes-additional-action-fight-against-covid-19-issuing-emergency-use-authorization-second-covid"&gt;authorized&lt;/a&gt; the COVID-19 vaccine developed by Moderna, which joins the Pfizer and BioNTech product as the second shot available for use in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JuLAx6"&gt;The vaccine &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/144636/download"&gt;can now&lt;/a&gt; be given to adults 18 years of age and older in the US. It was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726554/moderna-covid-vaccine-fda-pfizer-biontech"&gt;94 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; against symptomatic COVID-19 in clinical trials. The Moderna vaccine also protects against cases of severe disease: there were 30 cases of severe disease among trial participants, and all were in the placebo group. Initial data on the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine also indicated that it could protect against severe disease, but data was &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/pfizer-biontech-covid-vaccine-is-first-to-win-u-s-authorization/"&gt;too limited&lt;/a&gt; to reach a definite conclusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XX15W"&gt;“With the availability of two vaccines now for the prevention of COVID-19, the FDA has taken another crucial step in the fight against this global pandemic that is causing vast numbers of hospitalizations and deaths in the United States each day,” said FDA Commissioner Stephen Hahn in a &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-takes-additional-action-fight-against-covid-19-issuing-emergency-use-authorization-second-covid"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwPZ07"&gt;Data presented by Moderna also hints that the vaccine might be able to prevent asymptomatic infection with COVID-19, not just symptomatic disease. In the clinical trial, the company tested every participant for the coronavirus between the first dose and second dose of the vaccine. There were 38 cases without symptoms in the placebo group and 14 in the vaccination group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="w21gv1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Moderna vaccine has less onerous storage requirements than the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UCkqk6"&gt;Like the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine, the Moderna vaccine was made using a gene-based technology. It contains a snippet of the genetic material for the coronavirus spike protein. The snippet instructs the body to build copies of that protein and use those copies to train the immune system to recognize and attack the actual virus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gSMNo1"&gt;Also like the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine, the Moderna vaccine will be available under an Emergency Use Authorization, a designation that lets the FDA sign off on products faster than the normal review process during an emergency like a pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P6BNKt"&gt;The Moderna vaccine has less onerous storage requirements than the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine, which has to be kept at ultracold temperatures — covered in dry ice or in specialized freezers — until it’s ready to be used. Moderna’s can be stored in a refrigerator for &lt;a href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-announces-longer-shelf-life-its-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;up to 30 days&lt;/a&gt;, making it easier to distribute to places without the infrastructure to maintain an ultracold environment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AiNyf8"&gt;“We remain focused on scaling up manufacturing to help us protect as many people as we can from this terrible disease,” Stéphane Bancel, chief executive officer of Moderna, said in a &lt;a href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-announces-fda-authorization-moderna-covid-19-vaccine-us"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5aTDz"&gt;The United States ordered &lt;a href="https://www.fiercepharma.com/pharma/pfizer-shot-supply-rocks-u-s-taps-option-to-secure-100m-more-moderna-covid-19-vaccine-doses"&gt;200 million doses&lt;/a&gt; of the Moderna vaccine, enough to vaccinate 100 million people. The first doses will be distributed to health care workers and residents in long-term care facilities within days. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22185507/moderna-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorized"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22185507/moderna-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorized</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T19:19:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T19:19:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google now offers weekly COVID-19 tests to every US employee</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U4c-ecOnEv26bQgQTm0cCO4rbo0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551383/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oLkkxw"&gt;90,000 Google employees have just received access to free weekly COVID tests. The &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/googles-new-perk-free-weekly-covid-19-testing-for-employees-11608328652"&gt;first reported the news&lt;/a&gt; that every US Google employee (and its subsidiaries, including YouTube) will be eligible to sign up for a free at-home test. This differs from other companies, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/15/amazon-encourages-california-workers-to-get-weekly-covid-tests.html"&gt;like Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which are only offering tests to employees who still have to work in a physical location, like a retail location or warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pz7dNI"&gt;This is apparently something Google employees are interested in, as the vendor’s website crashed after going live. Employees are promised that they’ll receive the test within two to four days of requesting one, and that they’ll get the results back within two days of the lab receiving it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hskzr5"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; report, Google is paying its partner, BioIQ, $50 per test. That comes out to $4.5 million per week when multiplied by 90,000 employees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SE3Dk0"&gt;Of course, the $4.5 million figure is assuming that every employee takes advantage of the offer, though a Google spokesperson said the company is recommending they do. It’s also a very small cost relative to Google’s profit margins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RQIhII"&gt;Google’s spokesperson also told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that interns will be eligible for the program as well, and that it should be expanding to international employees in 2021. The company is hoping that the testing will help reduce the number of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21445706/coronavirus-cdc-test-guidelines-covid-19-asymptomatic-trump"&gt;asymptomatic spreaders&lt;/a&gt; should any of its employees become infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSy78L"&gt;In the early days of the pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/15/21180370/google-testing-website-coronavirus-trump-covid-19-confusion"&gt;President Trump claimed&lt;/a&gt; that Google would create a website and nationwide system for getting access to COVID tests. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21179118/google-coronavirus-testing-screening-website-drive-thru-covid-19"&gt;That was not true&lt;/a&gt;, although an Alphabet division did briefly offer testing in some regions. Google has done other work for the public like creating a contact tracing system with Apple and improving the information it shows on its search results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vri7FB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The original version of this story said that it was a Google site that crashed under the load. It was BioIQ’s site. We regret the errors. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189653/google-employee-covid-testing-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189653/google-employee-covid-testing-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:32:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:32:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Shigeru Miyamoto tours Super Nintendo World theme park in new video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9DxPa4-ZbtR0KPrOHzLL053XmQ=/158x0:1583x950/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551221/Screen_Shot_2020_12_18_at_3.25.43_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iZB6In"&gt;Nintendo’s Shigeru Miyamoto led a video tour of the company’s Mario-themed Super Nintendo World attraction at Universal Studios Japan in Osaka during the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hQaRBOI-9kg"&gt;latest Direct livestream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3k0oy"&gt;The theme park looks to be packed with Mario iconography that will be familiar to Nintendo fans. Even the entrance Mario-themed: you enter the park by walking through a giant pipe that spits you out in the atrium of Princess Peach’s castle that first debuted in &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SDUVFU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A smart wristband lets you interact with elements of the park&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t3s64K"&gt;Miyamoto showed how you can you use a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/13/21064777/super-nintendo-world-mario-theme-park-osaka-japan-wristbands-mobile-app"&gt;special smart wristband&lt;/a&gt;, called the “Power-Up Band,” to interact with different parts of the zone. In one example, he punched a question mark block with the hand wearing the device, and the block made the classic Mario coin-collecting sound. In another moment, Miyamoto hit a POW block near a spinning Koopa shell at the right time to make it bounce up and collect a key coin. The band links to your smartphone so you can track your activities around the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Vf72Y"&gt;Miyamoto also walked through an underground area that had oversized elements to create the illusion of being a smaller Mario, a vast cafe with video screens of Toads making food, and Bowser’s Castle, which is where the AR &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/em&gt;-themed roller coaster is located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XI3Shp"&gt;As a long-time Mario fan, the park looks delightful, and I hope I can experience it for myself someday. Super Nintendo World is scheduled to open &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726093/super-nintendo-world-osaka-japan-opening-date-announced"&gt;on February 4th&lt;/a&gt;. The zone was originally set to open before the 2020 Summer Olympics in Tokyo, but the opening &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21306781/super-nintendo-world-opening-delayed-indefinitely-coronavirus"&gt;was delayed&lt;/a&gt; due to the COVID-19 pandemic (which also pushed back the Olympics). At some point, Universal Studios also plans to open Super Nintendo World zones in Hollywood, California; Orlando, Florida; and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9faf2t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Super Nintendo World opens on February 4th with AR Mario Kart rollercoaster","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726093/super-nintendo-world-osaka-japan-opening-date-announced"},{"title":"Japan’s Super Nintendo World will open in spring 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505457/super-nintendo-world-opening-date-spring-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189601/super-nintendo-world-theme-park-universal-studios-japan-mario-shigeru-miyamoto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189601/super-nintendo-world-theme-park-universal-studios-japan-mario-shigeru-miyamoto</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:20:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:20:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>A Facebook bug exposed Instagram users’ personal email addresses and birthdays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F9rvVWJkc9YoNwD6Uo7Uk0NZrbM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550595/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BUiIHc"&gt;When signing up for an Instagram account, the service promises that your email and birthday won’t be publicly visible. A bug discovered by security researcher Saugat Pokharel, however, made it so that an attacker could easily get that private information. The bug, which was patched after being reported to Facebook, was exploitable by business accounts that were given access to an experimental feature the company was testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Qoi1mI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The attack worked on private accounts, and ones that don’t accept public DMs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0E00Zu"&gt;The attack used Facebook’s Business Suite tool, available to any Facebook business account. The experimental upgrade meant that if a Facebook business account was linked to Instagram and was included in the test group, the Business Suite tool would show additional information about a person alongside any direct message — including their supposedly private email address and birthday. All business users had to do was send a direct message on Instagram to call up the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zMPbB"&gt;Pokharel found that the attack worked on accounts that were set to private and accounts that were set to not accept DMs from the public. If an account did not accept DMs, the user potentially would not receive any notification indicating their profile may have been viewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hs53HU"&gt;An experienced bug hunter, Pokharel also discovered that Instagram &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21368602/instagram-kept-deleted-photos-messages-on-servers-year-bug-fixed"&gt;wasn’t actually deleting deleted posts&lt;/a&gt; back in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTN7La"&gt;In a statement provided to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Facebook spokesperson said that the bug was only accessible for a short period of time, as the experiment was started in October. The company doesn’t disclose how many users were given access to the feature, but it says that it was a “small test,” and that an investigation found no evidence of abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYWByA"&gt;The full text of the statement is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="nCejhA"&gt; A researcher reported an issue where, if someone was a part of a small test we ran in October for business accounts, personal information of the person they were messaging could have been revealed. This issue was resolved quickly, and we discovered no evidence of abuse. Through our Bug Bounty Program we rewarded this researcher for his help in reporting this issue to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4qDXVF"&gt;According to Pokharel, Facebook engineers fixed the issue within a few hours of being notified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JIExn1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 18, 6:20 PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clarified a point in the second paragraph that only accounts that were included in the experiment had access to the information.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189494/facebook-bug-instagram-email-birthdays-messages"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189494/facebook-bug-instagram-email-birthdays-messages</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:00:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:00:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra will have six cameras</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S21" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ncHc-NQdnFXhEsi3BDMXZvmm9qU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551093/41821.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The upcoming Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: WinFuture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Gl5Wyo"&gt;Today, we have another Galaxy S21 leak, which seems to confirm some of the specs that have been floating around, &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,120117.html"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167208/samsung-galaxy-s21-january-14th-launch-india-plus-ultra-s-pen"&gt;Information about&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22187074/samsung-galaxy-s21-leaked-colors-plus-ultra"&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; of Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy S21-series phones have been landing almost daily in the run-up to Samsung’s January event. With this newest leak, we now have a better idea of what to expect — especially in the camera department. In short, the hardware appears to be a big part of Samsung’s plan to take on the highly capable iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEPWZl"&gt;The S21 Ultra will reportedly offer 3x &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; 10x telephoto cameras (72mm and 240mm equivalent focal lengths, respectively), both with optical image stabilization. That’s one additional rear-facing camera compared to the S20 Ultra’s three rear sensors. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dd4YyGk5Sl73FJRSV1V7y9LOCSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22183371/41804.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: WinFuture&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SPua0d"&gt;The S21’s 10x lens will use a folded optic design like that of the S20’s telephoto camera. We expect that Samsung will once again offer hybrid zoom that reaches much farther than that 10x optical range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fSy8aS"&gt;Some other subtle camera updates look to be on the way, too. The main 108-megapixel camera gets a slightly wider 24mm (versus 26mm) equivalent lens. It will also get laser-assisted autofocus: something that the S20 Ultra didn’t offer but the Note 20 Ultra later introduced. And &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; says that despite the main camera sensor’s on-paper similarities to the last generation, this is a new sensor that should offer better image quality than the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TF4xl8"&gt;Samsung will need every advantage to compete with the iPhone 12 Pro Max, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;which we think is the best smartphone camera&lt;/a&gt; on the market today. Historically, Samsung has taken more of a hardware-heavy approach to mobile imaging, increasingly using its own house-made sensors rather than grabbing Sony’s off the shelf, and being early to adopt dual- and triple-lens cameras on its devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Whdfag"&gt;Part of the reason Samsung has leaned so hard into advanced hardware is that its computational photography hasn’t kept up with either Apple or Google. Only recently has it come up to par with features like Night Mode. But now it’s another year, and there’s more work to be done to catch up to the iPhone 12 Pro Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zWQk7y"&gt;Video may prove to be grounds for Samsung to level the playing field with Apple, too. It’s one area where software can only do so much without the right hardware behind it. Samsung has usually had big specs to tout when it comes to video — the S21 Ultra will offer 8K recording to the 12 Pro Max’s 4K — but the proof will be in the footage. Samsung &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-defies-one-size-fits-all-mobile-experiences/"&gt;says it’s committed&lt;/a&gt; to continuing to push its capabilities in this area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jMtF32"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S20 Ultra review: shutter bug","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/27/21155012/samsung-galaxy-s20-ultra-review-5g-screen-camera-space-zoom-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="pXwHna"&gt;There are a few notable non-camera-related details in &lt;em&gt;WinFuture’s&lt;/em&gt; report. These specs confirm a 6.8-inch display with variable refresh rates from one to 120Hz, a battery-saving move also adopted from the Note 20 Ultra. There’s also S Pen support, which will be sold separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGNcHv"&gt;Samsung will also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;follow Apple’s lead&lt;/a&gt; by shipping the S21 devices without wall chargers in the box. The company will probably, like Apple, cite the environmental benefits as the motivation for this change, though cynics among us will note that it’s also beneficial to each company’s bottom line. But the reduction of e-waste is no doubt a good thing, and Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522980/apple-iphone-12-pro-usb-c-lightning-environment-charger-box-electronic-waste"&gt;use of USB-C rather than a proprietary connector&lt;/a&gt; scores it even more environmental bonus points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWjQAx"&gt;There’s no confirmed launch date or pricing yet for the S21 Ultra, though reports point to an announcement on January 14th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189305/samsung-s21-ultra-spec-leak-cameras"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189305/samsung-s21-ultra-spec-leak-cameras</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
