<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-18T14:04:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T14:04:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T14:04:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Photos is adding a locked folder for your private images</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dFnc8br2Z38trrXGVZ3o_51oxg8=/75x0:1176x734/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306573/Screen_Shot_2021_05_18_at_10.46.16_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YTqvDv"&gt;Google is introducing a new feature to Google Photos that lets you hide specific pictures so they won’t show up in your photo feed or in other apps. The feature, called Locked Folder, will put whatever sensitive pictures you’d rather not share behind a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2b6ROx"&gt;In its I/O presentation, Google used the example of parents trying to keep a puppy purchase secret from their kids — though the feature should be useful for any sensitive images that you don’t want to share with others. It’s easy to see how this feature could be useful: who hasn’t handed their phone to someone to show off one or two pictures, then suddenly realized, “Wow, I hope they don’t scroll too far to the left or right”? Locked Folder will help Photos users avoid that fear by keeping whatever sensitive pictures you’ve got on the service out of your main photos feed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gBY8Zf"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;With Locked Folder in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/googlephotos?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@googlephotos&lt;/a&gt;, you can add photos to a passcode protected space and they won’t show up as you scroll through Photos or other apps on your phone. Locked Folder is launching first on Google Pixel, and more Android devices throughout the year. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoogleIO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/yGNoQ8vLdq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yGNoQ8vLdq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Google (@Google) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394710047213633536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MxYKAn"&gt;Google says the feature will launch first on Pixels but will be coming to more Android phones “throughout the year.” Similar features have been available through third-party apps already, and many Samsung users already have access to a &lt;a href="https://www.samsungknox.com/en/solutions/personal-apps/secure-folder"&gt;Secure Folder feature&lt;/a&gt; included on some Galaxy phones.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442416/google-photos-locked-folder-private-hidden-pictures"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442416/google-photos-locked-folder-private-hidden-pictures</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T14:01:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T14:01:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>This is Ford’s electric F-150 pickup truck</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n7GZ5BXDcEQTC2uAlwavjMTfWVg=/0x2:2448x1634/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306561/Screen_Shot_2021_05_18_at_12.54.20_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bm8D58"&gt;Ford has revealed the all-electric F-150 pickup truck one day ahead of schedule. The truck, dubbed F-150 Lightning, was on display Tuesday at Ford’s Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Michigan during a speech from President Biden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBjjlp"&gt;Images from the event show that the F-150 Lightning largely looks like its gas and hybrid counterparts, though the truck has a more modern grille, with an unbroken light bar that stretches from headlight to headlight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yCFQgJ"&gt;The F-150 EV has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441793/ford-f150-lightning-announcement-rumors-specs-details"&gt;years in the making&lt;/a&gt; and is the second mass-market electric vehicle from Ford, following the Mustang Mach-E. The company is set to reveal full pricing, specifications, and other details about the electric pickup truck Wednesday at 9:30PM ET. But the truck is expected to be one of the most powerful F-150s ever made, and it will serve as a huge test of the appetite for an all-electric version of the most popular vehicle in the country.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Igyi4n"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;And there it is. The electric &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Ford?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Ford&lt;/a&gt; F-150 Lightning ahead of comments by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@POTUS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/IF0baIT55w"&gt;pic.twitter.com/IF0baIT55w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Michael Wayland (@MikeWayland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MikeWayland/status/1394709687396966404?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YK3ENU"&gt;Biden used Tuesday’s speech to stump for his infrastructure plan, which is big on electric vehicles, lithium batteries, and EV charging technology. “The future of the auto industry is electric. There’s no turning back,” he said &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wvF3RG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442415/ford-f150-lightning-electric-pickup-truck-first-images"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442415/ford-f150-lightning-electric-pickup-truck-first-images</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:58:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:58:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft confirms Windows 10X is dead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m5sZX9EVzr6v6EHtHRobmWhNh30=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306521/akrales_190930_3649_0349.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KCMKpK"&gt;Microsoft is confirming today that it no longer plans to release Windows 10X. The operating was originally supposed to arrive alongside new dual-screen devices like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/2/20889000/microsoft-surface-neo-windows-10x-hands-on-features-price-photos-release-date"&gt;Surface Neo&lt;/a&gt;, with a more lightweight and simplified interface and features. This was all before the pandemic hit, and Microsoft then decided to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246561/microsoft-windows-10x-single-screens-windows-usage-demand-coronavirus-pandemic"&gt;prioritize Windows 10X for single-screen laptops instead&lt;/a&gt;. Windows 10X is now officially over, and Microsoft is now planning to bring its best bits into Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HZrkQ1"&gt;“Instead of bringing a product called Windows 10X to market in 2021 like we originally intended, we are leveraging learnings from our journey thus far and accelerating the integration of key foundational 10X technology into other parts of Windows and products at the company,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2021/05/18/how-to-get-the-windows-10-may-2021-update/"&gt;confirms John Cable&lt;/a&gt;, head of Windows servicing and delivery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXoXwN"&gt;Some of that has already started appearing in the form of a new app container technology, better voice typing, and a modernized touch keyboard for Windows 10. Microsoft says it will now “continue to invest in areas where the 10X technology” makes sense for both software and hardware in the future. It’s unlikely that we’ll ever see the Surface Neo device now, though.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bcFMPevTNZw1fOQabEDKCqhp0RQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19247635/akrales_190930_3649_0115.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Neo device was supposed to ship with Windows 10X.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xOdae9"&gt;Windows 10X was going to appear in 2021 as more of a Chrome OS competitor, and Microsoft had spent years trying to modernize Windows in an attempt to bring a more lightweight version to market. Windows RT first released alongside the original Surface tablet in 2012, and then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/2/15506378/microsoft-windows-10-s-os-operating-system-announced-features"&gt;Windows 10 S arrived in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. Both failed to simplify Windows, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230554/microsoft-windows-10x-leak-chrome-os-chromebooks-hands-on"&gt;Windows 10X had some promising features&lt;/a&gt; that will now start to appear in Windows 10 instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYju7r"&gt;While Microsoft released a smaller Windows 10 May 2021 Update today, a larger one is planned for October. This next major update includes some big visual changes in the form of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313037/microsoft-windows-10-new-system-icons-ui-overhaul-sun-valley"&gt;new system icons&lt;/a&gt;, File Explorer improvements, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422553/microsoft-windows-95-era-icons-removal-windows-10-update-sun-valley"&gt;end of Windows 95-era icons&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft is also focusing on some key features and additions like fixing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407995/microsoft-windows-apps-rearranging-sleep-resume-fix-directx-12"&gt;rearranging apps issue&lt;/a&gt; on multiple monitors, adding the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336240/microsoft-windows-10-auto-hdr-pc-gaming-directx-11-12"&gt;Xbox Auto HDR feature&lt;/a&gt;, and also improving &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410088/microsoft-windows-10-bluetooth-aac-support-update"&gt;Bluetooth audio support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442421/microsoft-windows-10-x-canceled-official"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442421/microsoft-windows-10-x-canceled-official</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:46:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:46:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android introduces new privacy-friendly sandbox for machine learning data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/38HEhYmYPsERp-7uX04I4K7LJiI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306475/acastro_180507_1777_android_privacy_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1js6w0"&gt;At the I/O developer conference on Tuesday, Google announced a range of new privacy measures, including &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/our-work-keep-you-safe/"&gt;a new partition within Android&lt;/a&gt; to manage machine learning data more securely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L82dgX"&gt;Android’s new Private Compute Core will be a privileged space within the operating system, similar to the partitions used for passwords or sensitive biometric data. But instead of holding credentials, the computing core will hold data for use in machine learning, like the data used for the Smart Reply text message feature or the Now Playing feature for identifying songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lJh8cR"&gt;While neither feature is sensitive in itself, they both draw on sensitive data like personal texts and real-time audio. The partition will make it easier for the operating system to protect that data, while still keeping it available for system-level functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ikl4qw"&gt;“This means that all sensitive audio and language processing happens exclusively on your device and isolated from the network to preserve your privacy,” Google explained in a post announcing the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m5at8W"&gt;Despite the name, the Android Private Compute Core is not a separate hardware chip; the partition exists entirely in software. While that lowers the absolute level of data protection, it should also make the system easier to deploy across a range of devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y6q3Ed"&gt;The new system was announced alongside a range of other privacy features for Android, including a new privacy dashboard and a new setting for approximate location sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xwx3ma"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22200447"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google I/O 2021 live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYBEJ3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcdnRn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22436367/google-io-android-private-computer-core-machine-learning-data-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22436367/google-io-android-private-computer-core-machine-learning-data-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:44:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:44:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google showed off its next-generation AI by talking to Pluto and a paper airplane</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d4VcwRWG7mBH_-lkWSbqjDk185k=/76x0:846x513/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306451/Screen_Shot_2021_05_18_at_6.20.17_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YwHNi5"&gt;Artificial intelligence is a huge part of Google’s business, and at this year’s I/O conference, the company highlighted its work with AI language understanding. The star of the show was an &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/lamda/"&gt;experimental model called LaMDA&lt;/a&gt;, which Google says could one day supercharge the ability of its conversational AI assistants and allow for more natural conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOMWI0"&gt;“It’s really impressive to see how LaMDA can carry on a conversation about any topic,” said Google CEO Sundar Pichai during the presentation. “It’s amazing how sensible and interesting the conversation is. But it’s still early research, so it doesn’t get everything right.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5wC26"&gt;To demonstrate LaMDA’s abilities, the company showed videos of two short conversations conducted with the model. In the first, LaMDA answered questions while pretending to be Pluto, and in the second, it was standing in for a paper airplane. As Pichai noted, the model was able to refer to concrete facts and events throughout the conversation, like the New Horizons probe &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/6/11863004/nasa-new-horizons-pluto-history-interview-video"&gt;that visited Pluto in 2015&lt;/a&gt;. (For some strange reason, both Pichai and LaMDA-Pluto erroneously referred to Pluto as a planet! It is, of course, a dwarf planet.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64vSmh"&gt;You can see the conversations above and below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0U1XvR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Google shows off LaMDA AI language demo by talking to a paper plane &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoogleIO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/8q51rqbbpA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/8q51rqbbpA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— The Verge (@verge) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/verge/status/1394708912843149314?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z7JlXx"&gt;But what’s the point of holding a conversation with a machine? Well, as Pichai noted onstage, so much of Google’s AI work is about retrieving information, whether that’s through translating other languages or understanding what users mean when they search the web. If Google can get AI to understand language better, it can improve its core products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VabcYh"&gt;But it’s definitely hard work. As Pichai noted: “Language is endlessly complex. We use it to tell stories, crack jokes, and share ideas. [...] The richness and flexibility of language make it one of humanity’s greatest tools and one of computer sciences’ greatest challenges.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="veRI98"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22200447"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google I/O 2021 live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442328/google-io-2021-ai-language-model-lamda-pluto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442328/google-io-2021-ai-language-model-lamda-pluto</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:43:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:43:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>It’s about to get easier to change compromised passwords in Chrome for Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6F3o-TWtLjQ1qpx2H9KYCRZGUhE=/124x0:1477x902/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306442/Untitled.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lCqs0g"&gt;Google is adding a feature to its Chrome password manager that allows you to change a compromised password with a few button taps. If its &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95606?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid#:~:text=Get%20alerts%20to%20change%20your%20passwords"&gt;security check feature&lt;/a&gt; finds a password that was potentially leaked, the message will now include a “Change Password” button for supported sites. Tapping that button will automatically take you to the page to change your password on that site and will fill out a new one with a suggested secure password. That password will then, of course, be stored in Chrome’s password manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXULGX"&gt;Google says this feature is partially powered by its Duplex for the web technology, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18531195/google-duplex-web-update-car-rentals-movie-tickets-io-2019"&gt;introduced to help complete tasks like ordering food and buying movie tickets&lt;/a&gt;. Google does say in its blog post, however, that you can interrupt the process at any time if you’d prefer to do some parts manually.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jc3BKKWoGrRsTDAHXSBmUax1W0k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22523116/05_SaferWithGoogle_PasswordAutoChange_OF_v20.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The process can be completed in two button taps for supported sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XvJ4x1"&gt;Similar features can be found in other password managers, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22320467/dashlane-one-click-password-changer-autofill-machine-learning"&gt;such as Dashlane&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s good to see Google adopting it: making it easier to update compromised passwords and save them somewhere securely helps people stay safer online, even after services have been breached. Google says the feature will be rolling out gradually to US users of Chrome for Android but will become more widely available in “the coming months.” Google also announced that the password manager would support importing data from other managers, as well as automatically checking for compromised passwords during its I/O keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442247/google-chrome-password-manager-android-compromised-duplex"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442247/google-chrome-password-manager-android-compromised-duplex</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:35:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:35:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Republicans have a new tool to fight deplatforming: common carriage laws</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Capitol-dome-congress2" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/alA9RK3oKQa1VZ4AX2FVAKLYW9I=/3x0:1022x679/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306368/capdome-2013-3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bOE4uC"&gt;After four years of hearings and publisher complaints, Republicans have gotten awfully quiet about Section 230. Prominent conservatives &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepMattGaetz/status/1390002611349299201?s=20"&gt;may still tweet&lt;/a&gt; in all caps to repeal the law when they’re pissed at Facebook, but it’s no longer the only solution they’re talking about.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhSKtM"&gt;Part of the shift is by necessity. With Democrats in control of Congress, Republicans no longer have a clear path to changing the law, and it’s become clear the two parties want totally different things when it comes to reform (fixing misinformation and blocking censorship, respectively). And while Section 230 works well as a threat against tech companies, actually changing the law is so delicate that it isn’t a particularly good way to keep companies from deplatforming conservatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7jItrV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“People are starting to realize that Section 230 isn’t going to go anywhere anytime soon.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EITBpd"&gt;“People are starting to realize that Section 230 isn’t going to go anywhere anytime soon. We’re just too far apart with the Democrats,” Jon Schweppe, director of policy and government affairs for the American Principles Project said. “I think people are still working on it in hopes of having a Republican supermajority down the road. But that’s just political reality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Sa8HA"&gt;So ever since the inauguration, Republicans have started turning to an unexpected set of tools to protect conservative voices online: common carriage laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6H74rL"&gt;The idea was laid out in detail in April, when Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas issued a &lt;a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/20pdf/20-197_5ie6.pdf"&gt;concurring opinion&lt;/a&gt; as the court declined to hear a case on former President Trump blocking people on Twitter. The case itself was moot for procedural reasons, but Thomas took it as an opportunity to write in support of classifying social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter as “common carriers,” the same classification that net neutrality rules use for telecom providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbjNx9"&gt;“There is a fair argument that some digital platforms are sufficiently akin to common carriers or places of accommodation to be regulated in this manner,” Thomas wrote in his opinion last month. In theory, common carriage would ban platforms from unfairly discriminating against speech, .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sav2kt"&gt;Thomas’s opinion has no legal force, but it was enough to get Republicans in Congress to pay attention. In the wake of the opinion, Sen. Bill Hagerty (R-TN) introduced the 21st Century FREE Speech Act, which combined the usual Section 230 repeal with a new effort classifying social media platforms as common carriers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCwF0J"&gt;“This is more than just a messaging bill or an empty gesture,” Mike Davis from the Internet Accountability Project said in a statement soon after the bill was released last month — although any time someone has to say it’s not an empty gesture, you should probably be skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="wDmKx0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is more than just a messaging bill or an empty gesture”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iJe8rb"&gt;Hagerty is a junior senator and his bill has yet to find much support from other Republicans — but there may be other bills coming. Sen. Roger Wicker (R-MS), the top Republican on the Senate Commerce Committee which has jurisdiction over tech issues, referenced Thomas’s opinion earlier this month in light of a Facebook Oversight Board Decision to uphold the platform’s ban on former President Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EbctXB"&gt;Facebook’s decision to uphold Trump’s ban “illustrates the concentrated control Big Tech exerts over speech and why Congress should act to curb its dominance,” Wicker said in a statement. “Justice Thomas’s recent opinion suggesting that powerful online platforms should be treated as common carriers offers a sound basis for legislation that would bring accountability to this industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vNfx6"&gt;Wicker’s office did not immediately respond to a request for comment regarding any future legislative proposals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJvEoS"&gt;For veterans of the net neutrality fight, this might seem a bit confusing: After a 20 year fight against common carrier rules for telecoms, are Republicans really going to embrace them for Twitter? And many skeptics see it all as just more posturing for the midterms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yCSNkp"&gt;“The Republican Party isn’t interested in governing, or passing legislation,” Berin Szoka, TechFreedom president told me. “It’s all about performance, and then the culture war, and this is the ultimate intersection of those two things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LKNBJG"&gt;But unlike the intricacies of Section 230 reform, these common carrier bills could directly strike at platforms’ power to ban conservatives — is the one issue nearly everyone in the caucus can unite behind. Conservatives are furious over the recent Oversight Board decision affirming Facebook’s Trump ban, and eager to do something to push back. With offshoots like Parler and Frank flailing, big government regulation might be the best option they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4jPcT6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22442359/republican-common-carrier-social-media-facebook-trump-ban-antitrust-section-230"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22442359/republican-common-carrier-social-media-facebook-trump-ban-antitrust-section-230</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:12:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:12:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Workspace turns to ‘smart chips’ to weave Docs, Tasks, and Meet together</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B7KthskGN98BSu3kfvGBbeqWYM0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306187/acastro_051821_4589_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The @ mention is the key to Google’s Office competitor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UYxUeC"&gt;Google is launching a slate of new features for its Workspace productivity suite today, starting with new “smart chips” that connect Google Docs to other products. Just like you can tag people with an @ symbol, starting today, you can use it to specialize links inside docs that hook up other files or meetings. They’re part of what Google is calling the “smart canvas,” a new initiative that promises to increase the cadence of product improvements for Workspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1wyfN"&gt;The idea behind the smart canvas is similar to workplace productivity suite dreams that reach as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenDoc"&gt;far back as OpenDoc in the ’90s&lt;/a&gt;: having smaller bits of information like charts, text, and images become more modular and interconnected. It’s not dissimilar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/19/21260005/microsoft-office-fluid-web-document-features-build"&gt;Microsoft’s Fluid Office document project&lt;/a&gt;, which launched last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UURtgD"&gt;Ultimately, Google is working to make every single part of its Workspace suite of apps interconnected. You’ll be able to start a Meet video chat directly within Docs or share your Doc directly into a Meet call with a button in the doc. All of that integration will be useful, but it also has the benefit (for Google) of perhaps enticing users away from using competing products like Zoom or Slack and instead using Google’s cohesive suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ffTjhQ"&gt;There is a smattering of other small updates: emoji reactions in Google Docs in addition to traditional comments, a new timeline view in Google Sheets for improved project management, and best of all: a new “pageless” view in Google Docs that does away with the assumption that your document is meant for an 8.5 x 11 piece of paper. It dynamically resizes the doc to the size of your web browser the way a web app ought to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAuyOz"&gt;Finally, Google is adding some “assisted writing” features to Google Docs, which will range from warning you about offensive language, wordiness, or noninclusive language. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKiYKS"&gt;Taken together, it’s a grab bag of updates, but the thing to keep an eye on going forward is the smart canvas function, which is built on a new framework for Workspace apps that could accelerate development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f36wDO8moXwPw0J4URGbCbpbczo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520920/chips.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2VK9s8"&gt;Smart chips and templates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="N3UJUH"&gt;Starting with Google Docs, smart canvas will make it easier to dynamically insert smart objects — called chips — that are linked to other parts of Google’s office suite. Google is starting small, though. At first, the smart chips will only connect with other documents, contacts, and meetings. Hovering over one of them will pop up a box with relevant information you can interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wwrf8v"&gt;To insert a chip, Google is relying on an interaction model you’re probably already familiar with: the @ tag. Type an @ symbol into Google Docs, and it’ll pop up a menu that will list a bunch of those elements, and you can type to narrow it down to the thing you want to include. Hit enter, and it will make a smart chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="leoUoo"&gt;“We don’t want you to have to learn a new affordance,” says Erika Trautman, director, Google Workspace. “This is something that people know how to use and millions of people use it every day.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="DBMA71"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Smart chips are a new way to live the old OpenDoc dream&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9wFp_P5eTsQQOcH1nb7uMKtxXZM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520926/chip2.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gDoNNU"&gt;If you link to another document or sheet, you can scroll through that document inline in the resizeable hover box — and it should work with lots of different document types in Google Drive, including Microsoft Office docs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vMi3xc"&gt;The smart chips do more than simply link out or create hover boxes, too. The @ symbol can bring up custom templates for things like project management tables, complete with voting and task tracking. If you select a meeting template, it will auto-populate smart tags for the attendees and any files attached to the calendar invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbJFsr"&gt;You can also create task lists inside a Google Doc and then assign them to a contact — and if they choose, those tasks will auto-sync with Google Tasks (which, by the way, is still not getting its own website and only lives in a sidebar in other Google apps for some reason). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SibiLc"&gt;Google says that smart chips will also come to Google Sheets “in the coming months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OmTQ9mh5bQBY8CUWE3yvMpXzjK0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520931/pageless.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4VsbS3"&gt;Pageless view, timelines, and other features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="66z3ER"&gt;There is a smattering of other features being announced today alongside smart chips, many of which will probably have a more immediate impact on many people’s day-to-day work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ejgGYW"&gt;The pageless format in Google Docs is wildly overdue, especially considering how simple it is. It just does away with the wholly unnecessary concept of a “page break” and also makes the text flow smoothly no matter the width of the browser window. It’s arriving just in time for the 11th anniversary of Ethan Marcotte’s &lt;a href="https://alistapart.com/article/responsive-web-design/"&gt;seminal Responsive Web Design article&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="59B97k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Finally, a responsive layout for Google Docs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WyyHBy"&gt;If you use Google Sheets to track projects, there is a new timeline view that can be used to track multiple overlapping tasks. Sheets will also &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; get a little smarter about auto-suggesting formulas when you drag a mouse across cells — as well as offer better troubleshooting for broken ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4zjSYL"&gt;There are also a bunch of integrations with Google Meet coming. Docs, Sheets, and Slides will let you present from them directly into a meeting without mucking about with screen-sharing options. Later this fall, all three will integrate Meet directly, so you can start a meeting directly within a document tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Iy-I9_22gQlvpIZC7Gwy-mCdTMk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520932/Sheets_Timeline_View.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SBuJLKRbb7BG-ixY1bGnoGFG7lg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520937/Assisted_analysis_formula_suggestions.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1vtHiZN-BjgT_EnsqIuSzPULMKE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520940/Assisted_writing_word_warnings.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z5CdXG"&gt;Docs is also getting some new options that are either wonderful, infuriating, or perhaps a bit of both. Instead of leaving comments, you’ll soon have the option to just put an emoji reaction on a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XZP6vq"&gt;Last but not least, add one more squiggly underline to go along with red for misspellings and green for grammar: purple for style. Google Docs will be able to make suggestions about different kinds of writing style issues ranging from the genuinely important (suggesting inclusive language like “delivery person” for “mailman”) to patronizing (suggesting “to” for “in order to”) to the downright Victorian (underlining swear words). It’s similar to &lt;a href="https://www.grammarly.com/"&gt;Grammarly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/microsoft-editor-spelling/gpaiobkfhnonedkhhfjpmhdalgeoebfa?hl=en"&gt;Microsoft Editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0gJgsSG00I0uZEuhqtJPM-4JEj8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520942/Table_Checklist_Chips.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FxKxRK"&gt;Workspace and the web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="OoUJqS"&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/05/Google-Docs-Canvas-Based-Rendering-Update.html"&gt;Google put up a blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing that “Google Docs will now use canvas based rendering: this may impact some Chrome extensions.” That “canvas” is different from the smart canvas we’ve been discussing. I regret to inform you that we must now briefly discuss web standards, but it’s relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H4ZBCu"&gt;At a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canvas_element"&gt;very high level&lt;/a&gt;, canvas is an element you can put into any HTML page, and as the name suggests, it is an empty space you can use to display more complex things — like stuff built with scripts. Essentially, it sits on top of web technology, but — depending on who you ask — it isn’t &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; web technology. It’s a technique for putting code on a webpage that doesn’t necessarily use the stuff you might think of as the code that makes up most of the web like HTML, CSS, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIycFC"&gt;I bring this up because it &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/steveklabnik/status/1392540892746104840"&gt;caused a bit of a stir&lt;/a&gt; in the web community last week. One refrain is that Google is one of the greatest champions of the web and puts significant engineering resources into web technologies — and if Workspace isn’t using them for core features, that’s a bad sign at best and harmful to the development of the web at worst. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="mE4LXy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google is committed to the web as Workspace’s main platform, but it’s evolving&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UqqUvU"&gt;Google insists that the switchover from more traditional web code to canvas is unrelated to today’s announcements, but Trautman admits that the “shift in technology is part of what’s allowing us to innovate and bring these new affordances forward.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kgpAGi"&gt;At the same time, Javier Soltero, VP and GM of Google Workspace, emphasizes that Google — and the Workspaces team, in particular — contributes quite a bit to the web: “We are fiercely committed in steering the path of innovation around the web. [...] These standards are really important to us. And this approach is, to us, an opportunity for us to showcase what you can do through these apps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPgukQ"&gt;It’s unclear what third-party Workspace plugins or what Chrome extensions may break in the future, but that’s true of any web app, whatever technology it’s built on. Google does say that its smart chip system &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be open to other companies. “We do not want this to be a walled garden. It will be extensible,” Trautman says. “We have third party partnerships underway.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LmVBR"&gt;Ultimately, the most important question may not be whether Google is using traditional web technologies, but whether Google Workspace will continue to be a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/24/15681958/what-is-web-definition"&gt;real web app&lt;/a&gt; instead of just a Chrome app. For that to be true, it needs to be broadly compatible across many desktop and mobile browsers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DJm7b9"&gt;The answer to that question turns out to be fairly complicated because web standards are complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8W5ZEY"&gt;Google says Blink-based desktop browsers (including Chrome and Edge) should fully support all of the features mentioned here. WebKit (Safari) and Gecko (Firefox) desktop browsers should support everything except some of the Meet features like opening a videoconference from within Docs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDompL"&gt;Google officially supports “view mode” for mobile web browsers (though the iPad can present itself as a desktop browser and work). In general, Google wants to point mobile and iPad users to its native apps. Those apps will support many smart canvas features like smart chips, tasks integration, and the responsive pageless layout — but miss out on others like templates and the purple assisted writing squiggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V3u5YNzutB3f-5UyGvNpKHp3JzM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520946/Present_to_Meet_from_Docs.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BCZix2"&gt;A coherent product roadmap. At Google. Really!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ip4ptS"&gt;Google Workspace was on a tear in 2020, adding new features and rebranding itself from G Suite (the name you probably still associate with Docs, Sheets, and Meet products). Many of the developments were necessary (and overdue) improvements for both Meet and Chat, two vital collaboration tools for remote work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4sicsD"&gt;The pandemic surely put more priority and resources behind those features, but what was remarkable about them wasn’t what they did, but how they seemed to be part of a larger plan instead of just being haphazardly added as they occurred to a Google engineer. Even Google Chat, the Slack competitor that is the ultimate inheritor of Google’s fractured message app fiascos over the last decade, seems to have a coherent product direction these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qcvq5W"&gt;It’s happened under the leadership of Soltero, who came to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/1/17067130/microsoft-outlook-cortana-boss-javier-soltero"&gt;Google from Microsoft in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. He came to Microsoft as part of its acquisition of Accompli, an email client so good it ultimately became Outlook for Mobile. Now in charge of Workspace and Google’s communication apps, Soltero is methodically working his team toward a new vision for Workspace. The vision seems to be more influenced by trendy productivity apps like Notion than by Microsoft Office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="YcxDP9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Development on Workspace has accelerated in the past year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AAa1d4"&gt;In fact, in speaking to Trautman or Soltero, asking even simple questions like how a Docs smart chip could create a Google Task leads quickly to heady discussions around product design and the future of collaborative work. “We want all of that to be under the hood and completely invisible,” Trautman says. “We want that behavior to, from a user perspective, to know what you intended and to do what you intended.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZ85fS"&gt;“The technical complexity [...] isn’t as important as the sense of restraint and predictability you have to deliver to users,” Soltero adds. For Google, it was a conscious choice to start with Docs and build from there, rather than create an entirely new product or system for collaboration. It’s trying to meet users where they already are and build on that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5T7b5Q"&gt;There are limits to that approach, but it definitely makes the new features more approachable. The Workspace team is deliberately trying to help users build new habits organically rather than foist an entirely new framework for understanding how productivity software could work on them. &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/"&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;, to cite that example again, is incredibly rich and powerful if you’re able to dive into that system and spend the time it takes to learn it, but Workspace is a giant product with a giant user base that can’t get there right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6PjRH"&gt;As for some future system that actually presents all of these interconnections, tasks, and documents in a new dashboard? Soltero says: “I don’t want to spoil the rest of our roadmap,” but “there are many examples of decisions you could make to aggregate these things and the decision about whether you create yet another surface… I think restraint actually is not only the right call, but it is more characteristic of what has made Google successful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="MuiwLY"&gt;In other words, if you were hoping this new interconnected and collaborative smart canvas portends the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/4/30/2989189/google-wave-shutdown"&gt;return of Google Wave&lt;/a&gt;, it does not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NPetRp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEBRQr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440226/google-workspace-smart-canvas-features-docs-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440226/google-workspace-smart-canvas-features-docs-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T13:04:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T13:04:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 10 May 2021 Update now available, designed to improve remote work</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_LyvnU46guYxeE2SQn8auZ9t9PA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306134/acastro_180504_1777_microsoft_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jxh23A"&gt;Microsoft’s next major Windows 10 update is starting to roll out to devices today. The Windows 10 May 2021 Update focuses on improving remote work scenarios, with changes like being able to use multiple Windows Hello cameras on a single machine. That’s particularly useful for Surface devices that owners might want to connect to a monitor with an additional webcam while working from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WG4RcD"&gt;Here are the full new features of the Windows 10 May 2021 Update (version 21H1):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vpjo57"&gt;Windows Hello multicamera support to set the default as the external camera when both external and internal Windows Hello cameras are present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nGUMwO"&gt;Windows Defender Application Guard performance improvements including optimizing document opening scenario times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ac1Wit"&gt;Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) Group Policy Service (GPSVC) updating performance improvement to support remote work scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="GbwDB3"&gt;Microsoft typically delivers a big major update of Windows 10 during the springtime, with a smaller one in the fall. The company has reversed that cadence for 2021, so the update that will likely arrive in October will be full of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZZv87"&gt;The next major update will include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313037/microsoft-windows-10-new-system-icons-ui-overhaul-sun-valley"&gt;new system icons&lt;/a&gt;, File Explorer improvements, and even the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422553/microsoft-windows-95-era-icons-removal-windows-10-update-sun-valley"&gt;end of Windows 95-era icons&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft has some even broader visual changes arriving in Windows 10, as part of a “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212817/microsoft-windows-10-visual-changes-update-sun-valley-2021"&gt;sweeping visual rejuvenation of Windows&lt;/a&gt;.” The October update will also fix the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407995/microsoft-windows-apps-rearranging-sleep-resume-fix-directx-12"&gt;rearranging apps issue&lt;/a&gt; on multiple monitors, add the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336240/microsoft-windows-10-auto-hdr-pc-gaming-directx-11-12"&gt;Xbox Auto HDR feature&lt;/a&gt;, and even improve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410088/microsoft-windows-10-bluetooth-aac-support-update"&gt;Bluetooth audio support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BSiPCp"&gt;Today’s May 2021 Update is so small that you’ll barely even notice it install. Microsoft has been using a special enablement package so that the features are simply hidden on your Windows 10 PC right now, and this update switches them on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYtpoS"&gt;As always, the Windows 10 May 2021 Update will be available on Windows Update, but if you don’t see it yet, it’s because Microsoft is rolling this out in waves to ensure there are no compatibility issues. If you’re feeling brave, Microsoft does let people force the update through its &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware-download%2Fwindows10" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;installation media tool right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442134/microsoft-windows-10-may-2021-update-remote-work-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442134/microsoft-windows-10-may-2021-update-remote-work-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-18T12:57:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-18T12:57:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>One of NASA’s Solar Orbiter tools caught its first video of a coronal mass ejection</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Uh5QFmjI_S2z2TRl26-8yNZuSc=/0x109:800x642/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69306028/fig1_solohi_optimized_gif.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;ESA &amp;amp; NASA/Solar Orbiter/SoloHI team/NRL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ial5Zi"&gt;One of the instruments aboard Solar Orbiter, a probe built by the European Space Agency (ESA) and NASA, caught its first video of a coronal mass ejection while whizzing around the other side of the Sun in February. Solar Orbiter, which launched in early 2020, has detected these massive bursts of energy in the past, but the explosion captured in February this year was an exciting first for NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8LtzY"&gt;NASA built the Solar Orbiter Heliospheric Imager, or the SoloHI instrument for the Solar Orbiter. It recently captured an energetic gust of solar plasma jetting from the star’s surface as the spacecraft was meandering around the Sun. Scientists didn’t expect the spacecraft to beam back any exciting images at this point — data is slow to reach Earth from such a far distance, and Solar Orbiter’s main mission doesn’t kick off until November.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xZZzpFCqLf85lHI4y-DjW_xFRj8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22522754/fig1_solohi_optimized_gif.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;ESA &amp;amp; NASA/Solar Orbiter/SoloHI team/NRL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The first coronal mass ejection captured by the Solar Orbiter’s Solar Orbiter Heliospheric Imager (SoloHI).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wLdV7r"&gt;But SoloHI delivered the goods anyway, as it came out from behind the Sun and reentered Earth’s line of sight, beaming back what NASA called a “happy accident.” Two other instruments aboard the Solar Orbiter, the Extreme Ultraviolet Imager (EUI) and the Metis coronagraph, may have captured different views of the coronal mass ejection around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D9SUKz"&gt;Scientists are still piecing together the images from the different instruments to get a clear picture of what was going on near the Sun that day. Around the same time that SoloHi recorded its &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2021/a-new-space-instrument-captures-its-first-solar-eruption"&gt;first detection of a coronal mass ejection&lt;/a&gt;, EUI and METIS detected &lt;a href="http://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Solar_Orbiter/Solar_Orbiter_images_first_coronal_mass_ejections"&gt;a pair of coronal mass ejections&lt;/a&gt;. Other solar-focused spacecraft also captured images and video of the eruptions that day.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J8Rvp2wVQEIX7IYTVtpZys8uIIg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22522803/RESIZED_fig2_stereo_a_cor2_cme.2021_05_18_15_14_35.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;NASA/STEREO/COR2&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The same coronal mass ejection Solar Orbiter’s SoloHI instrument observed, captured by NASA’s Solar Terrestrial Relations Observatory-A — one of two spacecraft launched in  2006.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="542SFz"&gt;Coronal mass ejections are lively bursts of plasma that send geomagnetic shockwaves across the solar system. The bigger ones that cross paths with Earth can wreak havoc on satellites in space, potentially disrupting radio transmissions or (for really rare and massive ones) knocking power grids offline. The plasma emitted from these ejections pummel Earth’s protective magnetosphere and slide around into its polar regions, clashing with the atmosphere and giving rise to the Northern and Southern Lights, or aurora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uEoq4x"&gt;Solar Orbiter’s main mission is to study the Sun up-close, helping scientists understand the causes of solar wind and how it affects Earth. The minivan-sized craft, coming as close as 26 million miles from the Sun, is among the closest human-made objects to probe the star. It’s second only to NASA’s Parker Solar Probe which is designed to get even closer, zipping around the Sun at a distance of just 3.8 million miles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OzvEMe"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WzC4QUhywOw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zbk88v"&gt;In July last year, Solar Orbiter’s Extreme Ultraviolet Imager nabbed some high-resolution shots of what scientists dubbed “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326014/esa-nasa-solar-orbiter-images-flares-campfires-sun-close-distance"&gt;campfires&lt;/a&gt;” — tiny surface explosions more formally called nanoflares.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441894/nasa-esa-solar-orbiter-video-sun-coronal-mass-ejections"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441894/nasa-esa-solar-orbiter-video-sun-coronal-mass-ejections</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
