<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-04T12:36:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:36:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:36:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon and AT&amp;T delay crucial 5G expansion over aircraft interference concerns</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SKhuTLlvOCWA4ClbJtBF3P9odDs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70094027/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MR2uYu"&gt;Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T are delaying the rollout of their wider 5G networks after the Federal Aviation Administration warned that the new wireless technology could interfere with the safety systems of some aircraft, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/at-t-verizon-to-delay-5g-rollout-over-faas-airplane-safety-concerns-11636039555"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBNlyf"&gt;The two companies planned to light up new 5G networks that use so-called “C-band” frequencies on December 5th. That rollout will now be delayed until at least January 5th, the companies said Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jQLr73"&gt;Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T still currently offer ultra-fast 5G connectivity in specific areas using high-band millimeter-wave technology and much slower 5G over low-band frequencies. But the two companies have been banking on using the C-band — which covers midrange frequencies with good-to-great speed — to dramatically expand access to 5G across the country. The two companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;collectively spent nearly $70 billion earlier this year to gain access to a bunch of C-band spectrum&lt;/a&gt; that was up for auction. T-Mobile, the other major player in the wireless market, already has a lot of mid-band spectrum that doesn’t operate in the C-band (though it will in a few years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="inoXgW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T need this spectrum to keep pace with T-Mobile&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k7AlJO"&gt;The aviation industry has voiced concerns over C-band interference for a while now. In an &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/faa-has-deep-concern-about-5g-network-plan-aviation-safety-letter-2021-10-29/"&gt;August meeting&lt;/a&gt; with the Federal Communications Commission, for instance, industry reps said that “major disruptions to use of the National Airspace System can be expected” with the rollout of C-band 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BDKp1g"&gt;Those concerns &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/us-faa-warns-potential-interference-new-5g-technology-2021-11-02/"&gt;came to a head this week&lt;/a&gt; when the FAA released a “&lt;a href="https://rgl.faa.gov/Regulatory_and_Guidance_Library/rgSAIB.nsf/(LookupSAIBs)/AIR-21-18?OpenDocument"&gt;special information bulletin&lt;/a&gt;” about potential interference issues with safety equipment that relies on radio altimeters. While the agency said that there have been no documented incidents of “harmful interference” in other countries to date, it nonetheless warned aircraft operators that they “should be prepared for the possibility that interference from 5G transmitters and other technology could cause certain safety equipment to malfunction, requiring them to take mitigating action that could affect flight operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5QOcq"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T said Thursday that it is working with the FAA and FCC to better understand the aviation industry’s concerns. “It is critical that these discussions be informed by the science and the data,” the company said in a statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “That is the only path to enabling experts and engineers to assess whether any legitimate co-existence issues exist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bfFHfJ"&gt;The major wireless trade group, the CTIA, said last week that companies should be able to use C-band 5G “without causing harmful interference to aviation equipment,” &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/faa-has-deep-concern-about-5g-network-plan-aviation-safety-letter-2021-10-29/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The group pointed to the many successful C-band deployments in other countries as evidence. “Any delay in activating this spectrum risks America’s competitiveness,” the group wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>League of Legends’ Jinx is coming to Fortnite to promote a Netflix show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s9FVl25QYql8eUOJKmIx8G0dOBs=/20x0:1640x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093987/18BR_Jinx_Arcane_LoadingScreen_1920x1080_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jinx in &lt;/em&gt;Fortnite&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Epic Games and Riot Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NaIG1F"&gt;One of the biggest games in the world is getting a character from one of the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; biggest games in the world. &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;’&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Jinx&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;a star of the upcoming Netflix series &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;, is the latest gaming character to join &lt;em&gt;Fortnite. &lt;/em&gt;You’ll be able to buy her skin in the &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; item shop starting Thursday at 8PM ET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Lm4aF6"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We can’t wait to see Arcane Jinx jump off the Battle Bus! Welcome to the Island  ️&lt;a href="https://t.co/GaubLR1wsM"&gt;https://t.co/GaubLR1wsM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/E55PShBHbE"&gt;pic.twitter.com/E55PShBHbE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite (@FortniteGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1456297574164537345?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n4ON2p"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22242696/fortnite-predator-marketing-brands-cross-promotion"&gt;no stranger to crossovers&lt;/a&gt;, and over the past several months, developer Epic Games has added a lot of gaming superstars, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22151470/fortnite-god-of-war-kratos-skin-now-available"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Kratos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166187/fortnite-master-chief-halo-the-walking-dead-the-game-awards"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;’s Master Chief&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381590/horizon-zero-dawn-aloy-fortnite"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;’s Aloy&lt;/a&gt;, and even four characters from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291805/chun-li-ryu-fortnite-street-fighter-mortal-kombat"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608624/fortnite-street-fighter-guile-cammy-are-coming-to-fortnite"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fighter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Jinx arrives in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; just two days ahead of the November 6th premiere of &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; developer Riot Games is promoting with a &lt;a href="https://www.riotgames.com/en/news/welcome-to-riotx-arcane"&gt;multi-stage marketing tidal wave&lt;/a&gt;. The studio is adding &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;-themed content across its games, and &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; isn’t the only cross-studio collaboration; the hugely successful &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.riotgames.com/en/news/runeterra-enters-pubg-mobile-to-celebrate-riotx-arcane"&gt;will be getting&lt;/a&gt; “&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;-inspired weapons and gear, characters, and map locations” in mid-November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cM8irQ"&gt;Riot Games also announced that &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Teamfight Tactics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Legends of Runeterra&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Valorant &lt;/em&gt;will all be available in the Epic Games Store starting Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JmsvFy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22760266/league-of-legends-jinx-fortnite-netflix-arcane"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22760266/league-of-legends-jinx-fortnite-netflix-arcane</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:24:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:24:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Blue Origin loses lawsuit against federal government over NASA’s human lunar lander contracts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mNNEIC7plHd3BMgzxHQeUNH9dkk=/0x0:900x600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093956/blue_origin_blue_moon_lander_reveal_web.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nMfIlO"&gt;Jeff Bezos’ spaceflight venture Blue Origin has &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.uscfc.44185/gov.uscourts.uscfc.44185.74.0.pdf"&gt;lost out on its lawsuit against NASA&lt;/a&gt; over a contract to build the space agency’s next human lunar lander. The judgement puts an end to Blue Origin’s monthslong quest to receive government funding to develop the company’s lander, called Blue Moon, for NASA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iFhxwD"&gt;Judge Richard Hertling, who oversaw the federal court case, issued a short ruling today, noting that Blue Origin’s motion for judgement had been denied. The opinion has not been issued publicly yet. All the parties involved will propose which parts they want redacted before the opinion is released openly on November 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KWDTTD"&gt;Blue Origin had hoped to be involved in NASA’s ambitious plan to return humans to the Moon, an initiative called the Artemis program. To achieve this goal, NASA is working with various companies in the space industry to build rockets and spacecraft that would help send the first woman and the first person of color to the lunar surface. A critical part of that plan entails building a privately made lunar lander that can safely carry people to and from the lunar dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kQv5sE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;NASA surprised everyone by awarding just one contract to SpaceX&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Vp5DRQ"&gt;Prior to giving out contracts for the lunar lander, NASA publicly hinted that it would select two companies to build these vehicles as a way to have redundancy and some competition. The agency eventually narrowed down the selection to three finalist companies, including Blue Origin, SpaceX, and a company called Dynetics. Then in April, NASA surprised everyone by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387887/elon-musk-spacex-win-nasa-lunar-lander-contract-artemis"&gt;awarding just one contract to SpaceX&lt;/a&gt;, which asked for $2.9 billion to develop the company’s monster Starship spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PFas6T"&gt;NASA attributed its decision to select one company instead of two to a lack of funding for its lunar lander program. NASA had requested $3.2 billion for its human lunar lander program for this year, but Congress only gave the space agency $850 million, about a quarter of what NASA had hoped for. Meanwhile, NASA has been striving to reach the lunar surface as early as 2024, an incredibly ambitious deadline that seems all but impossible with the budget shortfall. Given the lack of funding, NASA opted to stick with the company that proposed the cheapest option. Blue Origin requested $5.9 billion &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/9/18550258/blue-origin-moon-lunar-lander-jeff-bezos-space"&gt;for its Blue Moon concept&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="vbO0X1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Blue Origin has pulled out all the stops to somehow reverse the decision&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UTtnMe"&gt;Since losing out on the contract, Blue Origin has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22457893/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-nasa-spacex-senate-competition-bill-nasa-moon-lander"&gt;pulled out all the stops&lt;/a&gt; to somehow reverse the decision. Initially, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22404528/nasa-bezo-blue-origin-protest-spacex-contract"&gt;the company protested through the Government Accountability Office&lt;/a&gt; (GAO), but the GAO ultimately denied Blue Origin’s request. It also rejected a similar protest from Dynetics. The GAO argued that NASA “reserved the right to make multiple awards, a single award, or no award at all,” &lt;a href="https://www.gao.gov/press-release/statement-blue-origin-dynetics-decision"&gt;according to the office’s statement on its decision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMV2HO"&gt;Then this summer, Bezos wrote a letter to NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, proposing to build Blue Moon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594038/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-nasa-lunar-lander-2-billion"&gt;for a discount of $2 billion&lt;/a&gt; over the next two years to bridge the “funding shortfall.” The extra money would have been provided by Bezos himself, who is currently the second wealthiest person in the world. However, NASA wasn’t swayed by the offer. As a last-ditch effort, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22623022/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-sue-nasa-lawsuit-hls-lunar-lander"&gt;Blue Origin sued in federal court&lt;/a&gt; to have the decision reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rwgTEi"&gt;NASA argued that Blue Origin “gambled” with its bid for the lunar lander program, which it ultimately lost. The company “made an assumption about the Agency’s [lunar lander] budget, built its proposal with this figure in mind, and also separately made a calculated bet that if NASA could not afford Blue Origin’s initially-proposed price, the Agency would select Blue Origin for award and engage in post-selection negotiations to allow Blue Origin to lower its price. All of these assumptions were incorrect,” NASA attorneys wrote in legal filings dated May 26th and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22689729/blue-origin-moon-lunar-lander-price-nasa-hls-foia"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; through a Freedom of Information Act request&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tpFg2U"&gt;In response to today’s ruling, NASA noted that there will be opportunities in the future for companies to work on the Artemis program. “In addition to this contract, NASA continues working with multiple American companies to bolster competition and commercial readiness for crewed transportation to the lunar surface,” NASA said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “There will be forthcoming opportunities for companies to partner with NASA in establishing a long-term human presence at the Moon under the agency’s Artemis program, including a call in 2022 to U.S. industry for recurring crewed lunar landing services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BCHYyq"&gt;Both Blue Origin’s protest with the GAO and its lawsuit wound up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632990/spacex-lunar-lander-contract-paused-blue-origin-nasa-lawsuit"&gt;temporarily halting NASA’s contract with SpaceX&lt;/a&gt;. Now that the final decision has been made, NASA says that work will resume under SpaceX’s contract. On Twitter, SpaceX CEO Elon Musk made a joke about the ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X6irdZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/deqktTvS3U"&gt;pic.twitter.com/deqktTvS3U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1456275627221393409?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g6mce5"&gt;In response to today’s ruling, Blue Origin said it looks forward to continuing to work with NASA on potential future contracts. “Our lawsuit with the Court of Federal Claims highlighted the important safety issues with the Human Landing System procurement process that must still be addressed,” the company wrote in an emailed statement. “Returning astronauts safely to the Moon through NASA’s public-private partnership model requires an unprejudiced procurement process alongside sound policy that incorporates redundant systems and promotes competition. Blue Origin remains deeply committed to the success of the Artemis program, and we have a broad base of activity on multiple contracts with NASA to achieve the United States’ goal to return to the Moon to stay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJhpfc"&gt;It’s also possible that NASA could award future contracts to Blue Origin and Dynetics, depending on the funding the agency receives in the future. Former NASA Administrator Jim Bridenstine testified before the Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee that he thinks the agency should have at least two lunar lander providers. The Senate Appropriation Committee’s draft budget bill for NASA issued in October would also direct NASA to pick a second provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qggfdi"&gt;Earlier this year, Administrator Nelson had requested an extra $5.4 billion for NASA’s human lunar lander program, with the aim of getting the money through President Biden’s proposed infrastructure policy. “I think at the end of the day, after all the shouting is over, after all the pushing and tugging, a lot of which has nothing to do with NASA, you will see that NASA will have the funds that it needs,” he said, &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/nelson-remains-confident-on-nasa-funding-for-artemis/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Space News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. However, after multiple revisions to Biden’s Build Back Better Act, &lt;a href="https://rules.house.gov/sites/democrats.rules.house.gov/files/Section_by_Section_BBB.pdf"&gt;the latest version of the bill&lt;/a&gt; would only provide an extra $1.1 billion for NASA, mostly aimed at repairing and modernizing the agency’s facilities and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lX4XAR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 4th, 12:45PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was updated to include a statement and information from NASA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vk8SjT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wi7oI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeZwSi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763384/blue-origin-lawsuit-nasa-spacex-lost-human-lunar-lander-artemis"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763384/blue-origin-lawsuit-nasa-spacex-lost-human-lunar-lander-artemis</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:15:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:15:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best wireless earbuds to buy right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qIqT6EMRepUea5ztPgjCClI6hqM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67005648/DSCF4089_Edited.11.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Sony holds on to the top spot, and the Powerbeats Pro have been finally been toppled&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="BaOA2o"&gt;It’s hard to buy a bad pair of wireless earbuds these days. The market has come a long way since the early era of true wireless earbuds when we had to deal with mediocre sound quality and unreliable performance, all for the sake of ditching wires. Things are much different now. After several product generations of learned lessons, companies like Sony, Apple, Samsung, and others are releasing their most impressive earbuds yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H0HzJg"&gt;You can get phenomenal noise cancellation and sound quality in the premium tier of earbuds if you’re willing to spend big. But those aren’t always the most important criteria for everyone: maybe you’re looking for the perfect fitness earbuds or for a set that works just as well for Zoom calls as for playing your favorite playlists and podcasts. Tech companies are increasingly making their earbuds &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22627099/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-apple-airpods-pro-ecosystem-lock-in-features-companion-app"&gt;work best with their own products&lt;/a&gt; through exclusive features and functionality, so that’s another thing to consider as you shop around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lVXiJ0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600158"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pqS6dl"&gt;In terms of overall excellence, the best wireless earbuds you can get are Sony’s WF-1000XM4. They’ve got an unbeatable combo of top-notch active noise cancellation, wonderfully detailed audio, and long-lasting battery life. But we’ve also got a number of other picks based on other factors that you might rank higher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="pNy3BT"&gt;The best wireless earbuds in 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="zlQO6t"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lSw46_F71FYZ50eLPQxU31hsJGw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644193/DSCF4085_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sony’s WF-1000XM4 are the best overall wireless earbuds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tmCflo"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mSCWfZ"&gt;Best overall wireless earbuds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="iRpJZT"&gt;Though they come at a hefty price, the best overall wireless earbuds you can buy are Sony’s WF-1000XM4. They offer superb, warm, detailed sound quality and top-tier active noise cancellation. And their impressive battery life can stretch to eight hours of continuous listening with noise cancellation turned on, enough to outlast all of Sony’s top competition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHOmBh"&gt;The WF-1000XM4s have a premium, matte black (or light gray) design with stylish rose gold accents. Most earbuds come with standard silicone ear tips, but Sony includes foam-style tips that expand in your ears to create an excellent seal that, together with the noise cancellation, do an impressive job at hushing the outside world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="de0Fag"&gt;On Android phones, the 1000XM4s support Sony’s LDAC codec for higher-quality music playback. But even when used on other platforms, they’re up there with the very best audio-focused premium earbuds like Sennheiser’s Momentum True Wireless 2 — with much better noise cancellation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T49ehN"&gt;The only thing preventing the 1000XM4 from being the perfect set of wireless earbuds is their lack of multipoint / two simultaneous Bluetooth connections. They’re also on the larger side compared to some of the competition. But with their best-in-class mix of features (including bonuses like 360 Reality Audio support), improved voice call performance, and impressive battery endurance, you can’t do much better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="z7gyVY"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lx1n1-UXCTGwKwbgPg4-95FUU5g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22854826/DSCF5585_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Jabra Elite 3 are the best wireless earbuds under $100.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DOsyHK"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;Jabra Elite 3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wRf3xs"&gt;Best earbuds under $100&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xyCMjr"&gt;Sometimes all you need are the fundamentals, and that’s where Jabra’s Elite 3 earbuds manage to rise above the crowded field of sub-$100 competition. Their sound puts some emphasis on the bass but still manages to come through nicely balanced overall with very good clarity for this price range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Fs6sYM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844228"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F63F5J"&gt;The earbuds last for up to seven hours of continuous playback, and the compact case holds three additional charges. Their large physical buttons are easy to use, and the earbuds are rated IP55 for dust and water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdhZzT"&gt;The Elite 3s lack the multipoint feature that Jabra has long been known for — that’s the main sacrifice you make for the price — but in an improvement from past models, either earbud can be used standalone in mono mode. And they’re extremely comfortable to wear for long stretches. You don’t get features like active noise cancellation or wireless charging (though Jabra does include a so-so transparency mode), but the Elite 3s perform reliably with a strong Bluetooth signal. They’re a terrific value for the money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hWu3Jv"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ds_HnWvvgrCsv6J7sKcYODjSnto=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21946559/IMG_0720-1.0.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bose’s QuietComfort Earbuds have the best noise cancellation you’ll find in any earbuds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EGS3sY"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507552/bose-quietcomfort-earbuds-review-best-noise-cancellation"&gt;Bose QuietComfort Earbuds&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AGqjBz"&gt;Best noise-canceling earbuds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0TWUxd"&gt;Bose’s QuietComfort Earbuds are neck and neck with Sony when it comes to the effectiveness of their active noise cancellation — and probably a hair better. Like their main rival, the QC Earbuds have a fit and finish that exudes quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Aar5Ga"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386455"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zicZdh"&gt;With Bose’s mobile app, you can dial in the level of noise cancellation that’s perfect for the environment you’re in. Their charging case is a bit chunky, but it supports wireless charging. The QC Earbuds also handle voice calls better than most, so that’s another plus in exchange for their pricey cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="iU0gjj"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rqULYd7Vneck60NRlyx1aucD5Hc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22973267/DSCF6021_Edited_2.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Beats Fit Pro are the best earbuds for running and working out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Phouot"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple"&gt;Beats Fit Pro&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MJaN1M"&gt;Best earbuds for working out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xk3ZRx"&gt;The long-reigning champ of fitness earbuds, the Powerbeats Pro, have finally been defeated. And fittingly, they’ve been outdone by Beats’ latest earbuds. The Beats Fit Pro trade the ear hooks of the Powerbeats for a new wing tip design that keeps them securely locked in your ears during even the most vigorous workouts. As a result, these earbuds have a much smaller form factor — and their carrying case is mercifully far more manageable. The way these earbuds magnetically latch into the case also means you don’t have to worry about one or both buds failing to charge in the case, which was a common annoyance with the Powerbeats Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XPJTnP"&gt;Unlike the Powerbeats Pro, the Fit Pros include active noise cancellation. And they’re on par with the AirPods Pro in that department, so you’ll be able to exercise without distraction. When you do want to stay alert to your surroundings, the transparency mode is also as natural-sounding and clear as on the AirPod Pros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8NgG5q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844241"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sfx8aI"&gt;The earbuds are rated IPX4 for water resistance. While that’s not as robust as some other fitness-focused buds, it should be sufficient to survive sweat and outdoor runs in various conditions. The Fit Pros have easy-to-use physical button controls, and although they lack the dedicated volume rocker of the Powerbeats Pro, you’ve got the option to remap a long-press of each earbud to adjust volume instead of toggling noise cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W7gkOl"&gt;If you’re an iPhone owner, the Fit Pros offer Apple-only features like dynamic head tracking for spatial audio, auto device switching, Find My integration, and more. For Android users, Beats has an app that will let you adjust settings and see the battery status of the earbuds and case, among other functions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UrdVrj"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uPyp1tAFu7ySzKQN1zzQF9Y5QPI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19336099/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro remain the best earbuds for people who own several of the company’s other devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5DaumO"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;Apple AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DkEuTL"&gt;Best earbuds for Apple fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lLBDNk"&gt;For those invested in Apple’s ecosystem, the AirPods Pro offer an appealing mix of powerful noise cancellation, good-enough sound quality, and an array of features that make them the ideal companion to the company’s other devices. They’re also the only AirPods that come with different sizes of ear tips for a customizable fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kqPPhS"&gt;The AirPods Pro have a compact case that supports wireless charging. Setting them up is as simple as holding the open case near your iPhone. The earbuds are lightweight and fit snugly in most ears. Their force sensor pinch controls are easy to get down, and they rank among the very best wireless earbuds when it comes to voice call quality. Their ANC can’t match Bose or Sony but is enough to quiet your surroundings a fair amount, and the transparency mode almost makes it feel like you’re not wearing earbuds at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pqRzuC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mxfus6"&gt;Where the AirPods stand out is with their Apple-only features like head tracking for spatial audio, automatic pairing with all of your Apple iCloud devices, auto device switching, extensive Find My support, and so on. They also support audio sharing, and if you’ve got an Apple TV and need to keep things quiet in the living room or bedroom, you can use the AirPods for private listening. The AirPods Pro are pretty standard in other areas like sound quality and battery life, but their deep intertwining with Apple’s world is reason enough to give them serious consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9rJ372"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VKKynJBCoA04Zi7RagNuJaU9rdo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22775336/IMG_1106_Edited_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’ve got a Samsung Galaxy smartphone, the Galaxy Buds 2 are the best earbuds to go along with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q3cBQl"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5YAL6G"&gt;Best earbuds for Samsung fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="FuVr9O"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds 2 are so good that there’s little reason to shell out more money for the Galaxy Buds Pro. They’ve got a small, discreet design that won’t stick out of your ears like other buds. They sit more comfortably over long stretches of time than the company’s Pro buds. And the Buds 2 produce balanced, vibrant sound that’s quite close to the sound signature of the Pros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q9Ybgn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844268"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2LdugR"&gt;If there’s one downside, it’s the below-average IPX2 water resistance, which makes them less than ideal for workouts or getting caught in the rain. The Buds Pro have a more worry-free IPX7 rating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="j12RRo"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M6h63DEaW6azn8uU-w15vHQCU8M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22800050/DSCF4677_Edited.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus Buds Pro are the best earbuds if you’re a loyal OnePlus customer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9LHtPH"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637548/oneplus-buds-pro-review-specs-price-features"&gt;OnePlus Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aYIRNs"&gt;Best earbuds for OnePlus fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pJYhX6"&gt;OnePlus has come a long way since its original OnePlus Buds. The OnePlus Buds Pro are the company’s most refined earbuds yet, with a sleek stemmed design that’s right on par in comfort with Apple’s AirPods Pro. There’s no denying that these are AirPod clones, but their noise cancellation is slightly even better than Apple’s, and there’s a satisfactory transparency mode to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NawWim"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yaWD39"&gt;The controls are pretty much an exact copy of the AirPods Pro squeeze gestures, but OnePlus manages to best Apple at durability: these are rated IP55 for dust and water resistance. Voice call performance is also above most earbuds that cost the same $150 as the OnePlus Buds Pro. For that price, you also get wireless charging in the case. And when it comes to calls, the OnePlus Buds Pro are among the very best performers out there with clear voice reproduction and excellent background noise cancellation so others can hear you perfectly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="FIJ8K9"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WK-mSuFuVOg5iUNkHQdRI1SwPYA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953803/IMG_0044.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirPods 3 are the best earbuds for voice calls and sound much better than their predecessors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MMWh6V"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;Apple AirPods (third generation)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zUT2zw"&gt;Best earbuds for voice calls on iPhone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2Yu1aA"&gt;Apple’s third-generation AirPods have a new design with shorter stems than the original model. But even with their mics now being farther from your mouth, they still perform very well on calls — and there are bigger improvements to sound quality and fit / comfort that make upgrading to the so-called AirPods 3 worthwhile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J0qCuz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844500"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lZKllk"&gt;Apple has also added new features that were previously exclusive to the AirPods Pro, like head tracking spatial audio and deeper Find My integration for hunting down your misplaced buds. And the case is now optimized to work with Apple’s MagSafe wireless charging system. The AirPods still have a one-size-fits-most hard plastic form factor, so you’ll want to try them before buying to make sure they’re the right match for your ears. But if they are, these are Apple’s best regular AirPods yet by a wide margin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="P3VBkm"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3YM-r4tDPLQ584Vl5aHVf9vvqpQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236517/bfarsace_210114_4372_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Buds Pro are the best earbuds for voice call on Android.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6kvmL6"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rEED6p"&gt;Best earbuds for voice calls on Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="8OHWyv"&gt;Okay, so maybe there’s one not-insignificant reason to get the “Pro” Galaxy Buds instead of the Galaxy Buds 2: they’re fantastic at handling voice calls. The Galaxy Buds Pro hardware includes a windshield chamber that helps prevent distortion and annoying wind noise if you’re taking a call outside. And if you watch &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eVIuRJ-2P-s&amp;amp;t=1s"&gt;our video review&lt;/a&gt; of the Galaxy Buds 2, you’ll hear that it actually works quite well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4BKuAJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844513"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cXdPCx"&gt;Noise cancellation on the Galaxy Buds Pro is slightly better than the Buds 2, and they also include bonus tricks like 360 audio and a voice detect feature that drops the volume and activates transparency mode if you start speaking to someone nearby. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9ct7ND"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Mbuxj5OdJvZId3pvKYdYSwxyzc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792478/DSCF4633_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Razer’s Hammerhead True Wireless earbuds have flashy RGB lighting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PcGTEM"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22632338/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-earbuds-2nd-gen-review"&gt;Razer Hammerhead True Wireless (2021)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6ic0rB"&gt;Best earbuds for mobile gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PG68TP"&gt;The Hammerhead True Wireless earbuds have decent sound quality and active noise cancellation for their price. But likely, what’s equally as important to avid mobile gamers is their low latency gaming mode that cuts response time down to 60ms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2TSOzc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844522"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KcYx9m"&gt;And then there’s the Chroma. Unlike the first-gen Hammerhead True Wireless, these ones have fully customizable RGB lights on each earbud. It’s an eye-catching effect, though it does eat into battery life a little. Razer’s mobile app for the earbuds allows for control remapping and extensive EQ adjustment. The Hammerhead True Wireless earbuds are average in metrics like battery life, and their transparency mode is merely passable, but if you’re big on Razer gear, now you can flash the brand while playing your favorite mobile games at the coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="KVAIqq"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fpQT7CfT9FwmZzy0mKv08NvJYdA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22747060/DSCF4365_20Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nothing Ear 1s have a very cool look, but they can be buggy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9AzthM"&gt;11. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22598920/nothing-ear-1-earbuds-review-features-specs"&gt;Nothing Ear 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nhE8Ll"&gt;Best earbuds for standout style&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0pKVp1"&gt;Though they can be buggier than we’d like, and their noise cancellation is run of the mill, there’s no denying that the first earbuds from Nothing have a unique look. With their semi-translucent design and unique charging case, the Ear 1 earbuds will catch some attention when lined up with earbuds from more established brands. And at $99, you don’t have to break the bank for that added style — and maybe that price will make it easier to overlook the areas where Nothing came up short with its debut pair of earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7fqCtb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844531"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="xiUBQ2"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a1OfV5rzbzKb1R-s-3DuQUVa0P4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21993704/DSCF2216.0.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The UE Fits can mold to the contours of your ear for a perfect fit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tbqWHp"&gt;12. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21537150/ue-fits-review-wireless-earbuds-review-custom-fit-ear-tips"&gt;UE Fits&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MAbkyl"&gt;Best earbuds for a perfect fit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0VNbge"&gt;They mold to the shape of your ears in 60 seconds. That’s really all that needs saying for you to know why the UE Fits surpass all other wireless earbuds at nailing the right fit. Short of visiting an audiologist and having custom IEMs made, you’re not going to do much better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X9garq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386604"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZfliz"&gt;But the Fits are really only worth it if you often struggle with keeping other earbuds in your ears. If you’ve exhausted all options (including trying memory foam tips), then definitely give these a try. The molding sensation — the tips warm up in your ears as they adapt their shape — is certainly unlike anything you’ll get from other earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSR2yw"&gt;Related: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kwcWJO"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="2021 Airpods|104501" data-volume-uuid="1a50839d4" data-volume-id="104501" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-834" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:10:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:10:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elden Ring debuts 15 minutes of new gameplay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2q712_Eyq3uR7K2TuPwF33CBYH8=/124x0:1539x943/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093879/eldenring.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mPXEyw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732651/from-software-elden-ring-release-date-delayed"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the newest &lt;em&gt;Souls&lt;/em&gt; game from FromSoftware, was featured in a livestream event showing off 15 minutes of new footage — the biggest chunk of gameplay we’ve seen yet. The preview debuted some exciting, never-before-seen features like item crafting and a very detailed world map while also giving us a glimpse of what’s sure to be a crowd favorite — the spirit horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CxHl8l"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JldMvQMO_5U?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qkpzy8"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt; footage was from a PC build, showing off impressive visuals from the world known as the Lands Between. Instead of bonfires or lanterns, sites of grace are now where Tarnished can rest and replenish their health. Occasionally, touching a site of grace will spawn a beacon that can guide players to their next objective, which will definitely come in handy for such a seemingly large and expansive world.  To help travel through the world, you’re given a spirit horse, which was my favorite part of the demo. I hope we’ll have the opportunity to bond with our spirit horse ala Roach from &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;. It is unknown if you can pet the spirit horsey, but I understand you can feed it, fight on it, and use it to vault off spirit springs and fly through the air to reach elevated areas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k3DAMmQqah9Cx9z3RUcU7p5syxM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22985824/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Bandai Namco&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PQ0t7V"&gt;Epona, eat your heart out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uUDSup"&gt;The demo previewed the co-op system, calling in a fierce-looking barbarian lady to assist with a boss. For those who wish to play offline to avoid a potential invasion, you can summon spirits for a short time to help you take down a pack of enemies. According to the video, there are different types of spirits, allowing you to mix and match your spirit parties to find one that best suits your playstyle. For those of us (me, I mean me) who have a hard time with some of the more difficult elements of &lt;em&gt;Souls&lt;/em&gt; games, this spirit helper system is sure to come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBdN3q"&gt;The preview didn’t go too in-depth about what kind of story &lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt; tells, although we did meet a woman with a tattooed eye named Melina who apparently wants to offer us an accord. We also saw one of the game’s bosses, Godric the Golden, who, as the self-styled king of all things golden with a prancing lion on his axe, could be a long-lost &lt;a href="https://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/House_Lannister"&gt;Lannister&lt;/a&gt; and a whiff of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22643950/elden-ring-preview-fromsoftware-george-rr-martin"&gt;George R. R. Martin’s influence&lt;/a&gt; on the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1UrwF"&gt;The preview ended with a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LBKJKl195C0"&gt;brand new trailer&lt;/a&gt; and the reveal of the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/puUJhaBJdF8"&gt;Collector’s and Premium Collector’s edition&lt;/a&gt; of the game (which was spoiled earlier in the day by commercials on Twitch). Pre-orders are available now, with Premium edition buyers getting a sweet-ass 1:1 replica of the winged helmet Malenia, Blade of Miquella, wears. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DXekqU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Secure your path to the Lands Between.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Pre-order the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ELDENRING?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ELDENRING&lt;/a&gt; Collector’s Edition: &lt;a href="https://t.co/oooEiDSP1X"&gt;https://t.co/oooEiDSP1X&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/RZJB8fO1PC"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RZJB8fO1PC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ELDEN RING (@ELDENRING) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ELDENRING/status/1456263714311704576?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tpakk2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt; hits PlayStation, Xbox, and PC on February 22nd, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763258/elden-ring-new-gameplay-demo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763258/elden-ring-new-gameplay-demo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best iPhone gaming controller now works with Android phones — but you’ll need a cable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BackBone One" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QFs2R-z4LZgDMsyD2XzPePSTR2A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093769/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WaILkA"&gt;Last year, a small company called Backbone Labs released arguably the best iPhone gaming controller on the market right now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"&gt;the Backbone One&lt;/a&gt;. Starting Thursday, you’ll be able to use that controller with many more devices — including Android phones — though it won’t work exactly as you might expect &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; requires a new Backbone Plus subscription to set it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w6FqOo"&gt;Here’s how using the controller with other devices works. The Backbone One is designed to let you slot in an iPhone in landscape mode to a Lightning port on the right side of the controller. To use the Backbone One with a non-iPhone device, you can’t plop it into the controller since it requires plugging into that Lightning port. Instead, you have to pick what type of device you want to connect it to in the Backbone app settings menu and then hook up the device to the controller with a Lightning-to-USB cable. (The Backbone One has a Lightning port to plug the cable into.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cD5hov"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Playing Crossy Road Castle on my MacBook Air worked great&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U5LsZG"&gt;I tested the feature out by connecting the Backbone One to my M1 MacBook Air to play &lt;em&gt;Crossy Road Castle. &lt;/em&gt;It worked great, and I had no trouble traversing dangerous platforms as a tiny voxel chicken. I wasn’t able to test the Backbone One with an Android device, but if it works as well as it did with my Mac, it should be a perfectly capable gaming controller. If you unsubscribe from Backbone Plus, your Backbone One controller will still work with your iPhone and the last non-iPhone device you had it configured for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJBP9Q"&gt;The Backbone Plus subscription comes with a lot more benefits than just letting you use the controller with other devices. One impressive feature is that you’ll be able to stream to Twitch right from the Backbone app. That means you’ll be able to easily stream yourself playing your favorite mobile game or even a PlayStation or Xbox game over console streaming. In a test I did, the video on my Twitch stream was pretty laggy, but that might just be due to my network, and I didn’t see any performance issues with my iPhone 12 Mini while the broadcast was going.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EHfLIqnbMtM1wIk58ncHhyFJ4s0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22984103/TwitchStreaming.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Backbone Labs&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Backbone One’s orange button is surrounded by a purple ring while you’re streaming on Twitch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ItjjfI"&gt;Backbone is also adding some new video recording features in its subscription. You’ll be able to record at 1080p and 60fps on iOS 15 devices, up from 30fps, and there’s a new Smart Record option that lets you hold down the capture button to record the last 15 seconds of your game. The app’s useful catalog of games, videos, highlights, and more also now shows information from many different gaming services instead of just native iOS games, and search has been improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Cy2dZ"&gt;With Backbone Plus, you’ll be able to use all of the app’s software features. New Backbone users will be given a free year of the service, and if you opt to renew, it’ll cost $49 per year. If you choose not to subscribe, you’ll still be able to use the Backbone One as an iPhone gaming controller, and the app will still install software updates to the controller, but you won’t be able to take advantage of the other software features offered with the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8O5BrL"&gt;And current Backbone players are in luck. Every Backbone user who has made an account before Thursday will be given a free lifetime membership to Backbone Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="MKyS7M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Backbone One is a stunning controller that turns your iPhone into a more capable gaming device","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22753567/backbone-one-plus-iphone-gaming-controller-android-phones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22753567/backbone-one-plus-iphone-gaming-controller-android-phones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T11:50:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T11:50:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Merry Cringemas, here is a bad trailer for a worse movie about Nintendo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w_axpXq8uuam5PjuFZvUA5vXQjo=/0x0:711x474/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093698/msedge_B54BE3Bbsp.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: HBO Max&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y5zYsC"&gt;Warner Bros. may be putting a solid contender in the annual competition for the worst Christmas movie if the official trailer for &lt;em&gt;8-Bit Christmas&lt;/em&gt; is anything to go by. Picture the kid from &lt;em&gt;Jingle All The Way &lt;/em&gt;having to embark upon a wacky adventure to find &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt; the perfect toy for Christmas, told through a &lt;em&gt;How I Met Your Mother&lt;/em&gt;-style framing device, and you’re pretty much there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eBUtjb"&gt;The trailer sees Neil Patrick Harris narrating a story from one of his childhood winters, in which he and a group of friends compete to win an original NES for Christmas. After all, what could be more festive than a brand-new video game console? And no global chip shortages in sight! Bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fLOJMR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;No global chip shortages in sight&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R5bOqG"&gt;As far as I’m concerned, outside of a small handful of bonafide classics like &lt;em&gt;It’s a Wonderful Life&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Elf&lt;/em&gt; (and no, I will not be engaging with the “is &lt;em&gt;Die Hard&lt;/em&gt; a Christmas movie?” discourse), films focused on Christmas are uniformly terrible. But isn’t that the point? I don’t think anyone is looking for a cinematic masterpiece when December 25th rolls around. They’re looking for the vaguest of background noise to draw their attention away from the gnawing sensation that they &lt;em&gt;just might &lt;/em&gt;have overdone it on the food. Or maybe that’s just me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1lqVq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;8-Bit Christmas&lt;/em&gt; is streaming on HBO Max starting November 24th. If you’d like to get into the festive spirit early, please enjoy this short clip of a child &lt;em&gt;loosing his goddamn mind &lt;/em&gt;opening a Nintendo 64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xhGXVt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 75%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pFlcqWQVVuU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763449/8-bit-christmas-trailer-neil-patrick-harris-hbo-max-movie"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763449/8-bit-christmas-trailer-neil-patrick-harris-hbo-max-movie</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T11:01:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T11:01:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is working on a more user-friendly way to find files in Drive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YDI14ueZShyo9kG_sFgJ33nLa8g=/0x0:800x533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093358/Screenshot_2021_11_04_144152.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uSa9YZ"&gt;Google is preparing to beta test new search filters in Google Drive, which will hopefully make it easier to find the exact file you’re looking for. Dubbed “search chips,” the feature adds a line of filters to the top of the Drive interface, letting you limit your search by things like file type, last modification date, or which other users are associated with a specific file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hC5Iv"&gt;Google Drive already has some search filtering options, but they’re relatively basic and hidden in a sub-menu in the search bar. In contrast, the new search chips are presented front and center, and they look set to offer a wider range of filtering options. A similar feature was introduced in Gmail &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2020/02/gmail-search-chips-ga.html"&gt;early last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x3ApmP"&gt;If you’d like to try out the new Drive search chips beta, Google is directing interested users toward &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdAt17W4xOOtCQesdFcCv301YAUBGirv1dkafdXucYeJUgR8A/viewform"&gt;this sign-up form&lt;/a&gt;. Search chips will eventually be available to all Google Workspace users, including G Suite Basic and Business customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763374/google-drive-search-chips-filters-beta-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763374/google-drive-search-chips-filters-beta-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T11:00:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T11:00:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>The FDA’s crackdown on unproven stem cell therapies isn’t working</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="human stem cell - Ryddragyn (wikimedia commons)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5KCiImcfgHj7dxPpWGBtxEpQ5ac=/0x43:1024x726/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093354/1024px-Humanstemcell.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A human stem cell.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ePkPlg"&gt;In 2019, the Food and Drug Administration won &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/10/health/stem-cells-fda.html"&gt;a major victory&lt;/a&gt; when a judge shut down a clinic in Florida claiming to treat everything from back problems to heart diseases with stem cells. The decision was additional juice for the FDA to regulate the growing industry, which sells risky, unproven stem cell procedures as cure-alls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxwuXW"&gt;But despite the high-profile success in Florida, the problem has gotten worse. There are more than four times as many businesses in the United States advertising unproven stem cell therapies now than there were four years ago, according to &lt;a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2021.10.008"&gt;an analysis&lt;/a&gt; published today in the journal &lt;em&gt;Cell Stem Cell &lt;/em&gt;that used online searches and Google Maps to find clinics. That’s despite a common perception that there’s been an FDA crackdown on the clinics offering these procedures, says study author Leigh Turner, a professor of health, society and behavior at the University of California, Irvine. As Turner sees it, with nearly 1,500 businesses operating 2,754 stem cell treatment clinics&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in the US in March 2021,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;whatever warnings regulators have issued to try and rein in the industry aren’t working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8lITk"&gt;“It kind of raises the question, is there really meaningful regulatory oversight at all?” Turner says. “There is on the books, but in reality, does it exist?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JbC0CQ"&gt;Stem cell therapy, a broad term covering any treatments that use specialized cells that can morph into any cell type, has some real, evidence-based applications. Stem cells are used to treat some blood cancers, for example. There are efforts to develop stem cell-based treatments for conditions like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/29/12059618/als-spinal-cord-stem-cell-injection-surgery-trial"&gt;amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&lt;/a&gt;, and stem cells from patients in need of an organ transplant have been used to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/4/30/4286776/hannah-warren-first-child-bioengineered-windpipe-transplant"&gt;bioengineer one&lt;/a&gt;, lowering the risk of rejection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AFyO0A"&gt;But most of the other ways people try to use stem cells are unproven, experimental, and risky. Medical practitioners selling these treatments claim the cells, which are usually taken from patients’ own fat or from donated umbilical cords, can treat everything from joint pain to degenerative eye conditions. There isn’t evidence to back up those claims, and the supposed treatments aren’t FDA-approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Anu2Av"&gt;And the products have a dubious safety record. People have &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/miracle-cures-or-modern-quackery-stem-cell-clinics-multiply-with-heartbreaking-results-for-some-patients/2018/04/29/80cbcee8-26e1-11e8-874b-d517e912f125_story.html"&gt;gone blind&lt;/a&gt; after receiving unregulated stem cell treatments. Non-FDA-approved treatments have also been linked to &lt;a href="https://jasn.asnjournals.org/content/21/7/1218.long"&gt;kidney failure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/67/wr/mm6750a5.htm?s_cid=mm6750a5_w#T1_down"&gt;bacterial infections&lt;/a&gt;. Unproven and potentially dangerous therapies have become so prevalent that in 2019, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/6/20853185/google-stop-ads-unproven-experimental-medical-techniques-stem-cell-therapy-moderation"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; it would ban ads for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfFyVD"&gt;Many of the clinics promoting stem cell therapies argue that repurposing someone’s own cells does not qualify as a new drug product, meaning they don’t need FDA approval. But the FDA says the cells are processed and manipulated enough that they become a biological drug product that the agency has to oversee — an interpretation that was affirmed by the 2019 case in Florida. In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/10/health/stem-cells-fda.html"&gt;winning the case&lt;/a&gt; to shut down the Florida clinic, over the last few years, the agency has &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/vaccines-blood-biologics/enforcement-actions-cber/bimoteam-biologicsinternet-surveillanceother"&gt;sent letters&lt;/a&gt; to dozens of businesses warning them that the stem cells they use need approval before they’re marketed. The Federal Trade Commission and states attorneys general have also &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/cases-proceedings/182-3125/stem-cell-institute-america-llc"&gt;sued clinics&lt;/a&gt; over deceptive advertisements for claiming they can treat diseases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFMprs"&gt;These high-profile actions haven’t stopped the clinics from proliferating. There were only 351 businesses selling unproven stem cell therapies in the US in 2016 when Turner first investigated the matter. Now, according to his updated analysis, there are around 700 claiming to treat orthopedic injuries alone. Nearly 100 businesses say they can use stem cells to treat erectile dysfunction, and 23 say they use stem cells for autism spectrum disorder — and that they administer them to children. Most clinics included in the analysis didn’t list prices, but of those that did, the average cost was $5,118. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NdcIAe"&gt;Turner thinks the spike in businesses offering stem cell therapies might be because the practice became normalized over the past few years, even as federal agencies tried to crack down. In addition to stem cell clinics, the businesses advertising stem cell therapies included chiropractors’ offices, sports medicine clinics, and other medical or quasi-medical practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6Feps"&gt;“There seems to be a kind of move that’s taking place where it’s not just a kind of a couple of rogue clinicians who are way over the edge,” he says. “It’s much more run-of-the-mill: podiatrists, chiropractors, and naturopaths have moved into this space.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JBAa3W"&gt;Stem cell treatments are profitable. The barriers to entry are low, and there’s a steady supply of people who are suffering from conditions that standard medicine doesn’t have good answers for. People with spinal cord injuries or chronic pain can be targets for businesses claiming they can cure these problems. And the rise in the number of businesses offering the treatments even in the face of FDA action shows that the odds of someone facing consequences are, on the whole, fairly low. It’s a risk many businesses appear willing to take. “I think some people see this as it’s an opportunity to make a lot of money,” Turner says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JhPgJX"&gt;That could continue as long as the regulatory landscape stays the same. Experts have been waiting for the other shoe to drop for years, Turner says. But instead, things have gone in the opposite direction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baQLWE"&gt;The FDA did not respond to a request for comment by publication. It’s not clear whether the agency will respond more decisively in the next five years or if the market for these products will continue to spiral, Turner says. “I do find myself wondering — when you have a marketplace this large that isn’t well regulated, can you ever get it under control?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsJcJK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22761580/stem-cell-clinics-fda-oversight"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22761580/stem-cell-clinics-fda-oversight</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Astronomers call for a massive new space telescope to find the next Earth</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A9ptDhaZnTiVGhIqYcY74Pq-aWM=/0x0:3825x2550/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70093334/kepler186f_artistconcept_2.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An artistic rendering of a potential Earth-like exoplanet&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Laying the groundwork for the next few decades of astrophysics&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="DMVe82"&gt;American astronomers are calling for the development of a whole new suite of grandiose space telescopes that will be able to peer into the atmospheres of planets beyond our Solar System, listen to black holes ringing as they form throughout the Universe, and look back in time to when galaxies first emerged. It’s all part of an ambitious long-term strategy to create the next generation of tools to study the most distant reaches of space, with the hopes of launching these spacecraft throughout the 2030s and the 2040s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0BDTVG"&gt;Astronomers laid out their vision for this future in a report known as the Decadal Survey on Astronomy and Astrophysics, released today by the National Academies of Sciences. Compiled every 10 years after extensive meetings and debate, the survey is essentially a wishlist, detailing the highest priority missions astronomers would like NASA to build in the coming decade. Decadal surveys of the past have led to the formation of some of NASA’s most enterprising missions, such as the Hubble Space Telescope currently in orbit around the Earth, and the James Webb Space Telescope, or JWST, which is set to launch into deep space before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5YzIca"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Decadal team rose to the challenge.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UOwq7s"&gt;Typically in their report, astronomers will provide a list of missions they’d most like to see move forward, ranked in order of priority. This year, the recommendations are a little different. Similar to past surveys, the new survey recommends building one big “flagship” space telescope—a behemoth that can see infrared, optical, and ultraviolet light in the atmospheres of planets that are 10 billion times fainter than the stars they orbit, searching for signs of life. But the report also recommends developing two smaller telescopes—one that sees X-rays and one that sees in far-infrared—almost simultaneously while investing in various ground-based telescopes and space missions already in development. They’re calling this pipeline the “&lt;a href="https://www.greatobservatories.org/"&gt;Great Observatories&lt;/a&gt; Mission and Technology Maturation Program,” and it would result in multiple spacecraft being built together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7YtxTc"&gt;That way, in several decades’ time, astronomers will have an entire fleet of new space telescopes providing the most comprehensive picture ever of the distance Universe. Many in the science community are thrilled about that idea. “The Decadal team rose to the challenge,” Heidi Hammel, the vice president for science at Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy, a consortium of academic institutions that operate major telescopes, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an email. “They laid out the awesome science, and they made bold choices, both for ground-based and space-based facilities. I am so happy right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jIhvsX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Search for Another Earth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UMlCko"&gt;The biggest goal laid out in the Decadal Survey — and the priority of its flagship space telescope — is finding and cataloging worlds beyond our Solar System. The first of these distant planets, known as exoplanets, were only discovered in the early 1990s. Since then, astronomers have cataloged thousands more, completely transforming our understanding of the cosmos. Now that we know exoplanets are common, scientists are on the hunt for one — or more — that might be home to alien life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8XZUn"&gt;The problem is that studying exoplanets is unbelievably difficult. These worlds are extremely far away, typically orbiting very bright stars that overwhelm them in light and wash them out. That prevents astronomers from seeing exoplanets directly. Instead, scientists must &lt;em&gt;infer&lt;/em&gt; their presence, either by staring at a distant star and waiting for it to dim ever so slightly — a sign that a tiny world is passing in front of it, blocking its light — or measuring how distant stars wobble due to the gravitational pull of a nearby planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="tHNmgf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We want to discover Earths. We want to discover habitable worlds.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p6r03x"&gt;But just knowing an exoplanet exists is not enough to answer the ultimate question: are we alone? Astronomers are desperate to peer into the atmospheres of these distant worlds to see if they might resemble our own. The pinnacle of exoplanet discovery would be to find an exoplanet with just the right gases in its atmosphere, parked in a Sun-like star’s habitable zone — a spot where it’s not too hot and not too cold, allowing water to pool on the planet’s surface. But we’ll never find that if we’re stuck watching stars as they dim and shake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r7fmI2"&gt;With a giant space telescope that sports a 20-foot (6-meter) dish that can see in bright types of light, astronomers believe they’ll be able to finally see an abundance of exoplanets directly, including the ones that are just too faint to look at now. That way, we might be able to find Earth’s twin and perhaps even confirm the existence of life on it. “We focus our specifics around the scientific achievements that we want to see happen,” Keivan Stassun, a professor of physics and astronomy at Vanderbilt and one of the committee members who wrote the new Decadal Survey, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We want to discover Earths. We want to discover habitable worlds. That is a specific scientific priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kSMDTYKdtl8lwz_do8a8cttjmiI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22985303/Starshade_Artist_s_Concept_2_PIA20911.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA/JPL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An artistic rendering of what the HabEx telescope could look like&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N8l3Gt"&gt;To design this new giant telescope, engineers will likely draw from two proposed observatory ideas that have already been sketched out in detail. Before completing the decadal survey, four teams of scientists came up with four different proposals for space telescopes, providing a framework for what future flagship missions could look like. Two of the four teams, LUVOIR and HabEx, proposed telescopes that could search for habitable worlds. HabEx called for a bold plan to build a starshade, which would fly in front of the telescope and block out light from distant stars, making their exoplanets easier to see. LUVOIR called for a monster space telescope that looked a bit like NASA’s upcoming JWST spacecraft, upgraded to the extreme. HabEx’s proposed budget hovered between $8 and $10.5 billion, according to the new survey, while LUVOIR’s was a whopping $17 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BoUV8l"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It is the best possible outcome I could have hoped for”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MNEQiu"&gt;The decadal survey doesn’t recommend building either HabEx or LUVOIR specifically. The report notes that HABEx wasn’t quite ambitious enough in scope and that LUVOIR was a bit over the top in terms of budget. Instead, the report simply lays out what the astronomy community wants these telescopes to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;, which should help inform their final design. The researchers who worked on these projects are pretty happy about the decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ZNDiX"&gt;“It’s absolutely amazing,” Scott Gaudi, a professor of astronomy at Ohio State University and co-community chair for the HabEx study, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It is the best possible outcome I could have hoped for, not just for me, but also for all the people that worked on these large mission concepts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZSfpGk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than One Great Observatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1H7IWI"&gt;Searching for habitable worlds isn’t the astronomy community’s only goal for the next 10 years. It also wants to learn more about the densest objects in our Universe, like black holes and neutron stars, and the cataclysmic events that give rise to them. Astronomers also want to be able to peer inside distant galaxies right as they’re forming to learn more about how they evolve and birth millions of new stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z-hLefnI2r6RrYIPcW_JzXPluK0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22985307/PIA16695_orig.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An artistic rendering of a black hole, surrounded by a swirling disc of hot gas and plasma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RjQNzM"&gt;It’s a lot to accomplish, which is why the decadal survey calls for more than just one new spacecraft. The authors say that the addition of an X-ray telescope and a far-infrared telescope will be the best way to achieve all of these tasks. In order to get everything they want, the report’s authors propose that mission planners get started on development of the big exoplanet-hunting telescope right away, sketching out the exact technologies they’ll need to start building the spacecraft. If that process goes well over the next five years, then it’ll be time to begin designing the X-ray telescope and the far-infrared telescope. All of these vehicles can then be developed and built around the same time. The two smaller telescopes would cost between $3 and $5 billion and launch in the 2030s, while the larger telescope would cost roughly $11 billion and launch in the mid-2040s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1NbN9"&gt;It feels like a bold plan, especially since space telescopes typically go over budget. NASA’s next big space telescope, the JWST, was originally supposed to launch as early as 2007 and cost less than $1 billion. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/1/17627560/james-webb-space-telescope-cost-estimate-nasa-northrop-grumman"&gt;Now, it’s set to launch this December, and its overall budget has ballooned to $9.7 billion&lt;/a&gt;. Another space observatory that NASA is currently working on, the Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope (formerly called WFIRST), also struggled with rising costs, so much so that the Trump administration tried to cancel the project. Both of these telescopes were considered the highest priority missions in previous decadal surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="YgNM7E"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When things take a long time, they are expensive”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DY3VHR"&gt;The committee that penned the decadal report claims it’s making these recommendations with those lessons learned. For one, it argues that many of the technologies that were needed for JWST to work simply did not exist when the telescope was envisioned. “Doing that invention and technological maturation and testing and engineering — that just took a long time,” Stassun says. “And when things take a long time, they are expensive.” He’s hopeful that by getting started on the large telescope’s blueprints now, astronomers won’t be as blindsided by the technologies they’ll need to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxfDtI"&gt;Stassun also argues that the staggered development approach will allow mission planners to do check-ins from time to time to see how things are progressing. If one mission is ballooning out of control, then it can be paused or tweaked while the others stay in development. That way, there isn’t one mission that sucks up all the energy — and money — in the room the way that JWST did. Most of NASA’s astrophysics budget was dedicated to JWST during its most crucial development years, making it harder for small projects to get significant funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hhYOQk9QAweEwXW5ck1URTK0aRQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22985309/right.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA/Chris Gunn&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;NASA’s JWST spacecraft, ahead of its launch this December&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DFQMZl"&gt;It might be a hard sell to Congress, which ultimately determines NASA’s budget and has been critical of JWST’s ballooning costs. But scientists are optimistic. NASA’s science budget &lt;em&gt;has &lt;/em&gt;increased over the last few decades&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and Gaudi thinks people will be inspired by what these future telescopes could tell us. “We have come to Congress and the American people saying, ‘Look, this is fantastic science that can answer the huge questions that are going to inspire generations to come,’” Gaudi says. “And it requires a modest increase in astrophysics development budget. I think we can make that case.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oUHyl"&gt;“NASA looks forward to reviewing the recommendations in detail and appreciates the steering committee and panels for their dedicated work to deliver this report,” the space agency wrote in a statement following the report’s release. “The survey will inform a compelling new chapter in astrophysics science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qsMaSa"&gt;The decadal survey calls for more than just &lt;em&gt;building&lt;/em&gt; telescopes. The authors want to ensure that the people who are working on these projects are being protected. The report calls for a diversity and inclusion strategy for these missions, one that would make harassment and discrimination a form of scientific misconduct — a potentially career-ending move. And they also want the mission teams to be more mindful of how their work impacts indigenous communities and the environment. For instance, the authors suggest astronomers embrace remote conferencing long-term to decrease their carbon emissions from flying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BbaXH5"&gt;There’s a long road ahead to turn these dreams into reality. But for now, astronomers are excited for what looks like a&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;bright future. “We stand at the threshold of a new golden era of discovery, both on the ground and in space: might we actually find evidence for life on another planet?” Hammel says. “This report — true to its name — lays out robust pathways to answer this question, and we can be the generation that answers it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="5Yfo0o"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 4th, 11:30AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article updated with quote from NASA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22761537/space-telescope-astronomy-decadal-survey-astrophysics-habitable-planets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22761537/space-telescope-astronomy-decadal-survey-astrophysics-habitable-planets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
