<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-11T20:56:29-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T20:56:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T20:56:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ubiquiti, maker of prosumer routers and access points, has had a data breach</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uakJkN-cvYQweiw7PE4mwoRk7Pw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653361/acastro_170629_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N9l1Ly"&gt;Ubiquiti, the company I bought networking gear from because I wanted Wi-Fi that’s totally under my control, now tells me something may not have been under my control after all: my basic account information. According to an email it’s sending out to users today, a “third party cloud provider” was accessed by an unauthorized user, and that provider might possibly have some of our data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="thJmnw"&gt;While the company says it isn’t hasn’t found any evidence that our user data has been accessed, it also “cannot be certain that user data has not been exposed”. The potential data at risk will be familiar if you’ve received these kinds of emails before: names, emails, phone numbers, addresses, and (encrypted, hopefully unreadable) passwords. You’ll want to change your password now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="reeNsw"&gt;It doesn’t sound like that bad a breach as breaches go, but it’s annoying news to hear from a company that prides itself on giving users control. If I had wanted my data on someone else’s server, I might have picked a router that gave me some benefit for it, like plug-and-play setup. The database of customer info, it seems, is hard to get away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5FXzYl"&gt;The full email text, which can also be &lt;a href="https://community.ui.com/questions/Account-Notification/96467115-49b5-4dd6-9517-f8cdbf6906f3"&gt;viewed on the Ubiquiti forums&lt;/a&gt;, is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="C1huiT"&gt;We recently became aware of unauthorized access to certain of our information technology systems hosted by a third party cloud provider. We have no indication that there has been unauthorized activity with respect to any user’s account.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We are not currently aware of evidence of access to any databases that host user data, but we cannot be certain that user data has not been exposed. This data may include your name, email address, and the one-way encrypted password to your account (in technical terms, the passwords are hashed and salted). The data may also include your address and phone number if you have provided that to us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As a precaution, we encourage you to change your password. We recommend that you also change your password on any website where you use the same user ID or password. Finally, we recommend that you enable two-factor authentication on your Ubiquiti accounts if you have not already done so.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We apologize for, and deeply regret, any inconvenience this may cause you. We take the security of your information very seriously and appreciate your continued trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you,&lt;br&gt;Ubiquiti Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bSH3ES"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22226061/ubiquiti-data-breach-email-third-party-unathorized-access"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22226061/ubiquiti-data-breach-email-third-party-unathorized-access</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T20:12:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T20:12:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Salesforce says it has taken action against the RNC, but won’t say how</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Trump Supporters Hold “Stop The Steal” Rally In DC Amid Ratification Of Presidential Election" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qDxQ-EHGGqV2EZ_ZfOgVAbXKaAg=/0x0:7200x4800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653217/1294967493.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e1gtPE"&gt;Salesforce has “taken action” to stop the Republication National Committee (RNC) from sending emails that could incite violence, though the company won’t say what that action is. The RNC is using ExactTarget, a Salesforce tool, for campaign emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx5h5o"&gt;The move, first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkdmdv/salesforce-takes-action-to-prevent-rnc-emails-from-inciting-violence"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; comes after the Trump campaign sent an email urging supporters to “step up RIGHT NOW” and “defend the integrity of this Election” shortly before the breach of the US Capitol on January 6th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5qTElO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The enterprise software company declined to elaborate on what action it has taken&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k5axVT"&gt;Salesforce confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it hasn’t dropped the RNC as a client. “The Republican National Committee has been a long-standing customer, predating the current Administration,” a spokesperson said. “We have taken action to prevent its use of our services in any way that could lead to violence.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPy8sL"&gt;The enterprise software company declined to elaborate on what action it has taken and whether the mysterious measure would affect the Trump campaign, as well as the RNC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cj6KmW"&gt;Before the attack, the Trump campaign sent emails saying the election was rigged and the results needed to be overturned. The campaign sent 569 emails between November 3rd and January 6th, including four emails the morning of the breach, &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xexZmN"&gt;Each email asked supporters to donate money to the campaign. While it’s not known how big the ExactTarget email list was, in 2018, the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/13/us/politics/trump-political-data.html"&gt;Trump campaign reportedly had contact information for 20 million supporters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uORcD5"&gt;The RNC told &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; that it had ‘independently’ decided to stop its digital fundraising efforts on January 6th. The following day, another email service — Campaign Monitor — suspended the Trump campaign’s account. That alone would make it harder for the campaign to raise money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iAep0k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We can’t know for sure, because Salesforce won’t answer our questions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0csf3M"&gt;Social media platforms are also taking action against Trump in the wake of the attacks in DC. On January 7th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218725/facebook-trump-ban-extended-capitol-riot-insurrection-block"&gt;Facebook blocked the president indefinitely&lt;/a&gt;, and at least until Joe Biden’s inauguration. The following day, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22218753/twitter-bans-trump-permanently-realdonaldtrump"&gt;Twitter permanently banned Trump’s account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cs9J6Z"&gt;The news from Salesforce isn’t quite so decisive. Perhaps, like Campaign Monitor, the company is making it more difficult for Trump to fundraise. We can’t know for sure, because Salesforce won’t answer our questions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xtf6be"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CWj5e1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYLMl7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NMKnOA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225936/salesforce-stop-rnc-sending-emails-incite-violence"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225936/salesforce-stop-rnc-sending-emails-incite-violence</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T19:55:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T19:55:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Some monster scraped Trump’s name into this poor manatee’s back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xXAH84Qo8PbmmlU3XWRSXhQMrC4=/102x0:1598x997/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653127/5ffc72b6af600.image.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Citrus County Chronicle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uS2QuH"&gt;Last week was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221669/what-just-happened-this-week-trump-social-media-capitol-twitter-facebook-parler"&gt;a cacophony of horrible Trump-related news&lt;/a&gt;, but this is the one that hit home hardest for me: a manatee with his name scraped into its back was found in the headwaters of Florida’s Homosassa river (&lt;a href="https://www.chronicleonline.com/news/local/federal-officials-seek-information-on-manatee-harassment/article_c84a3b66-5423-11eb-93b6-1bf69750167f.html"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Citrus County Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). At the moment it’s unclear whether the animal was actually injured, or if the name was just scraped into the algae on its back, but it’s a crime either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gy90Yo"&gt;While US Fish and Wildlife officials told the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; that they “[could not] comment on a current, ongoing investigation”, they’re asking anyone who may have information about who did this to reach out to the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. The Center for Biological Diversity &lt;a href="https://biologicaldiversity.org/w/news/press-releases/5000-reward-offered-for-info-on-trump-carved-into-florida-manatees-back-2021-01-11/"&gt;is also offering a $5,000 reward&lt;/a&gt; for information that leads to a conviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RmTGu"&gt;An investigation could be difficult, though — manatees are, of course, live creatures, and while this particular one was found near a local swimming spot called Blue Hole, it’ll be hard to figure out where the manatee was when someone did this to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7rrUi7"&gt;If the person is caught, however, it won’t be good news for them. Manatees &lt;a href="https://myfwc.com/wildlifehabitats/wildlife/manatee/"&gt;are classified as threatened&lt;/a&gt;, and are therefore fall under the federal Endangered Species Protection Act. If someone is found to have criminally harassed a manatee, they could be facing up to a $50,000 fine, a year in jail, or both. Even just chasing a manatee while it’s swimming is considered harassment, so imagine scraping something into one’s back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjLBUy"&gt;I lived in Florida for 15 years, and was on the water a lot. If there’s one thing that’s extraordinarily clear, it’s that you &lt;em&gt;should not&lt;/em&gt; mess with the manatees. There are signs on every public dock telling boaters to watch out for manatees, and every natural science museum I went to had an exhibit on how manatees were threatened by motorboats and human activity. I vividly remember camping trips where rangers told us that we had to stop swimming in Manatee Springs because, surprise, there were manatees there, and they were not to be disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FY0559"&gt;Getting to see them up close was a literally awesome experience, and it provided the one good piece of news that I can give you: manatees are tough creatures, and I’ve seen many swimming around with scars from boat propellers. Despite someone being so thoughtless as to scrape anything into its back, it should hopefully be okay. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225867/manatee-harassed-with-trumps-name"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225867/manatee-harassed-with-trumps-name</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:25:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:25:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Only one person showed up to the pro-Trump protest outside Twitter’s San Francisco HQ</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GZm6SDx-Q8bGaID_348OK8S6298=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652818/vpavic_210111_4366_0039.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rare pro-Trump protester Rebecca Brooks came to show her discontent toward Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey who is “silencing conservative voices.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;30 police officers were there to monitor the scene&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="JrPhIK"&gt;It’s the second week of 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221669/what-just-happened-this-week-trump-social-media-capitol-twitter-facebook-parler"&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt; began with an insurrection, siege of the US Capitol building, and rejection of democracy, and it ended with all major social media companies banning the one-time impeached 45th president of the United States, Donald J. Trump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yymacB"&gt;One of those companies was Twitter. On the Donald.win forum, Trump supporters announced a plan to show their discontent by protesting in front of the San Francisco headquarters earlier today. The building was empty, with Twitter employees working from home to prevent the spread of COVID-19, but there was still a heavy police presence to protect against mob violence. What happened instead was a fairly quiet event, with just a single pro-Trump protester in evidence — and two counter-protesters there to applaud Twitter’s decision to deplatform the outgoing president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h8LylWd4kUwQH_LOaoYGZ10FDw4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228551/vpavic_210111_4366_0056.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter’s headquarters on Market St. in San Francisco was barricaded with fences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fdY8vHXmAP0GJPNhO2eHUsTtS-U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228547/vpavic_210111_4366_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moderate police presence at the Twitter headquarters in downtown San Francisco.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wrDUvZs2bXdw-2vM8CPmUWVLcpU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228548/vpavic_210111_4366_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ray Blanco was one of the two anti-Trump protesters who showed up on Monday morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dQxFOSlCF_vI5eCHWuCXQznjjMc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228558/vpavic_210111_4366_0151.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press and protesters mostly cleared out by 11:30AM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ee9MdBKRUP_WNN0RxFjgtwWjzUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228553/vpavic_210111_4366_0063.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approximately 30 police officers were standing near the entrance awaiting protesters since early in the morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j0IZTsM8M4ZEANnlST5Wf6ltd7o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228560/vpavic_210111_4366_0219.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Police officers lined up since early in the morning expecting a protest to start at 8AM local time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/085e_YfZaMKrsSaduuVjilzeMxc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228557/vpavic_210111_4366_0140.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katherine King is happy with the actions Twitter took, but only wishes they came sooner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sUjZmlPsb13Bd22A_Kkwd_aRC8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228559/vpavic_210111_4366_0165.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Police vans parked in the alley behind the Twitter headquarters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aSvicE8I30ddVOIWMakhR2mHOgQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228564/vpavic_210111_4366_0245.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riot gear was left unused during the pro-Trump protest near Twitter’s headquarters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YJzUqtR94I5tzPI9fVeIT052xU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228566/vpavic_210111_4366_0278.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graffiti on the wall wasn’t related to the protest, but was sprayed on the night before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B9q2eH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225721/twitter-protest-san-francisco-trump-stopthesteal-deplatforming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225721/twitter-protest-san-francisco-trump-stopthesteal-deplatforming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vjeran Pavic</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:04:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:04:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony promises streaming quality nearly as good as 4K Blu-ray on Bravia Core movie service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xFgWHD7ft8cVShIB782neCN1o5Y=/174x0:1269x730/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652657/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_5.34.08_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YZTEu6"&gt;Sony’s new line of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218693/sony-tv-lineup-8k-4k-z9j-a90j-a80j-x95j-x90j-ces-2021"&gt;Bravia XR television sets&lt;/a&gt; will allow customers to watch and stream movies at some of the highest quality available in the consumer market through its new Bravia Core platform, according to the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CFDnzU"&gt;Bravia XR owners will be able to choose from a number of Sony Pictures titles and watch them using Sony’s “Pure Stream” technology, which achieves “near lossless” ultra high-definition, Blu-ray disc quality, according to Sony. Pure Stream also allows for streaming of up to 80 megabits per second. To compare, most streaming services recommend maintaining an internet speed &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/columnist/2017/12/10/youre-buying-4-k-tv-how-much-internet-bandwidth-do-you-need/933989001/"&gt;between 15 and 25 megabits per second&lt;/a&gt; to achieve proper 4K Ultra HD streaming quality. If Sony’s numbers are accurate, that’s better than a lot of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6B5a91"&gt;The platform comes preloaded on all new Bravia XR models (MASTER Series Z9J 8K LED, MASTER Series A90J and A80J OLED, and X95J and X90J 4K LED) and effectively uses a voucher system. Depending on the model that someone purchases, they’re given a number of credits. Those credits can be cashed in for a number of new titles. It’s unclear if people can keep those titles after they’re purchased with the credits, but &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has reached out to Sony for more information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pXVZNI"&gt;On the streaming front, Sony’s website states that customers can stream a number of titles “anytime and as many times as you like, in up to 4K HDR quality,” but there are limits to this, too. Time periods for streaming availability are depending on the Bravia XR model purchased, according to the site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BpIp5E"&gt;Bravia Core isn’t going to replace Netflix, but it seems like it was specifically designed to show customers the ultimate capabilities of their new TV set. Kind of like when you buy a TV with true 4K HDR capabilities, and you play the best 4K YouTube channels to try to see the difference between your new set and that old clunker you just tossed. Bravia XR TVs also have “the largest IMAX Enhanced movie collection,” according to Sony. It’s unclear exactly how many movies that works out to, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RaqRQE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225768/sony-bravia-core-movie-platform-service-xr-television-quality-stream"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225768/sony-bravia-core-movie-platform-service-xr-television-quality-stream</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:01:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:01:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>PopSockets are going MagSafe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oqLxpCKYCBBhu2JRX1hanIDgQxw=/0x20:552x388/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652647/1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: PopSockets&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iUXKXO"&gt;PopSockets is announcing that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/popsockets-unveils-innovation-at-ces-2021-including-magsafe-solutions-301205556.html"&gt;making its iconic phone holders compatible with MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;. When Apple announced that accessories would be able to attach to the iPhone 12 with MagSafe, many people immediately thought of PopSockets — including &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/popsockets-is-working-on-magsafe-compatible-iphone-accessories/"&gt;the company itself&lt;/a&gt;, which announced it was working on adding compatibility. Now, it’s finally at the point where it’s putting out an announcement and a release window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keD1sS"&gt;PopSockets is planning on bringing MagSafe to quite a few of its products, but first, of course, is the famous &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.popsockets.com%2Fshop%2Fpopgrip&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F11%2F22225701%2Fpopsockets-magsafe-accessory#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PopGrip&lt;/a&gt;. Now, if you want to charge your phone wirelessly, you won’t have to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21048205/popsockets-poppower-home-wireless-charger-popgrip-ces-2020"&gt;buy PopSockets’ specialized wireless charger&lt;/a&gt;. The MagSafe version will have a larger base than many PopSockets users may be used to, which is probably to provide space for the “no-slip” rubber bottom. Hopefully, that will keep the PopSocket from sliding off when going in and out of your pocket, like Apple’s own MagSafe wallet is somewhat infamous for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wm7Iga"&gt;Speaking of wallets, PopSockets is also announcing a magnetic version of its PopWallet Plus, which is essentially a wallet with a PopSocket built in. Like Apple’s version, it will include a shield meant to protect any cards that are liable to get erased by magnets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CRW3XF"&gt;In addition, PopSockets is unveiling two mounts that will use MagSafe: one for home (dubbed “Multi-Surface) and one for the car. The company notes that the new PopGrips will work with existing PopSocket mounts, but the new mounts will work magnetically, though it’s not clear if they’ll also use the PopSocket as an extra mechanical grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PiGw4z"&gt;The press announcement had some other notable products, including an antimicrobial version of the PopGrip (it’s a sign of the times), and a multitool PopGrip that’s a collaboration with famed knifesmith SOG. The PopGrip and PopWallet Plus for MagSafe are slated to launch in spring of 2021, and the PopMounts should be coming in the summer. No word has been released on pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225701/popsockets-magsafe-accessory"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225701/popsockets-magsafe-accessory</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:00:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:00:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mode aims high for the perfect puff of weed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q3hG-tA3EM0WUJz6dBrScf9HbXo=/0x55:1292x916/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652641/Mode_smart_cannabis_dosing.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Mode says its smart cannabis device lets you control your dosage | Mode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u4yswc"&gt;For people who use cannabis for medicinal purposes, such as pain management, anxiety, and sleep, vaping the drug can be a bit of a trial-and-error process since you can’t be totally sure of the exact dose you’re getting like you can with a standard edible or pill. The makers of the Mode smart cannabis device say it solves the dosing problem, using a high-res pressure sensor to determine how much a user is inhaling and a prediction algorithm that determines how many micromilligrams a user is getting per puff based on the cartridge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qG4j8t"&gt;The company says it’s run hundreds of cannabis cartridges through its testing machines to identify each one’s unique characteristics, and the device has an accuracy rate of over 75 percent even without letting the app know which cartridge you’re using. (It’s in the high 80 percent range for known cartridges, the company claims.) Mode is compatible with thousands of standard 510 threaded cannabis cartridges, and it can be locked manually or remotely with the companion app. The company says the algorithm is still improving, and you'll be able to download a new version to the device over Bluetooth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQIa9b"&gt;People treat many different medical conditions with cannabis, some using different varieties to treat more than one condition. For example, a user may need a different dose — and likely a different blend — of cannabis to treat anxiety during the day than they would use as a sleep aid at night. That’s why being able to fine-tune the number of milligrams would come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="okYNO6"&gt;“This is not just another vape device you’re hitting and blowing out clouds all day,” Mode co-founder Izzy Kirsch said in a demonstration over Zoom during the Consumer Electronics Show. “You can get a milligram pill, so to speak, and go on with your day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1BiIdd"&gt;So let’s say you’re using cannabis for sleep and you know what dosage you want. Put your cartridge into the Mode device, set it to a dosage between 1 and 5 milligrams, and inhale. The device turns off its heater and vibrates, giving haptic feedback, when you’ve reached your desired dosage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dAPKA1"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/493919648?byline=0&amp;amp;badge=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;title=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="laT267"&gt;Mode co-founder Mark Wagner said during the CES demo that the company is software-oriented, so rather than building a special sensor to measure dosage, it’s working on fine-tuning the algorithm, which was developed in part by a former data science lead at Jawbone. In addition to a pressure sensor, Mode has temperature, motion, and orientation sensors that help create the ideal dose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyLpjF"&gt;The device also has a mobile app that lets users track their dosage over time, which is helpful information if you’re testing out a new strain or if you decide your dosage is too strong or too weak. The device bases its measurements on the cartridge manufacturer’s information. For people buying cartridges at a dispensary where the product is a known quantity, the Mode device relying on manufacturer info seems reasonable. However, it’s worth noting that black market and counterfeit cartridges may not provide the same level of accurate info (&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/potential-culprits-in-mystery-lung-illnesses-black-market-vaping-products/2019/09/24/cb5b708e-d98d-11e9-ac63-3016711543fe_story.html"&gt;and can potentially lead to serious illness&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPOUZT"&gt;In the relatively new medical cannabis marketplace, patients can end up going through a lot of trial and error finding a strain and a cartridge that gives them the amount they need — even the batteries used with standard cannabis cartridges can vary wildly in how they deliver your dosage. So a device that gives more user control over how much you’re consuming is a welcome addition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcqxtu"&gt;Mode says its device is made with medical-grade materials, including a tear-resistant silicone air passageway that goes all the way from the bottom of the device through to the cartridge, separate from all its electronics except for the pressure sensor. It uses high-grade stainless steel on the heat shield in the tube, and the outer case is raw ABS plastic; the company says it’s staying away from paint, which can lead to emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L72fYu"&gt;Mode uses USB-C charging, with a 385mAh custom battery. It can provide between a week and two weeks of battery life for a user taking 5 to 20mg per day, “not someone who’s continually crushing through cartridges,” Kirsch notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fcQeYV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://mode.co/"&gt;Mode is available for preorder&lt;/a&gt; and will retail for $100 when it’s available later this year. The company's targeting early summer. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225548/mode-smart-cannabis-device-dosing-algorithm-ces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225548/mode-smart-cannabis-device-dosing-algorithm-ces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T17:36:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T17:36:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>This is Sony’s Airpeak drone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UqFe78AufnuR1UYSVgFW5lFhj9c=/93x0:1041x632/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652448/bandicam_2021_01_11_17_16_20_402.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M9Pu8i"&gt;Sony is getting into the drone business, with the company showing off a brief first look at its new &lt;a href="https://www.sony.net/SonyInfo/airpeak/"&gt;Airpeak&lt;/a&gt; drone at CES 2021. The new drone is said to be the smallest drone capable of carrying an Alpha camera and is designed for video content creation and professional photography. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ok_mLDXXJA5zF09OWrlMiCH5E8o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228821/bandicam_2021_01_11_17_16_20_990.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aPqK74"&gt;There are very few concrete details about the new drone system right now, although Sony mentioned that it’s been exploring using the drones to film landscape and city shots. It showcased the Airpeak working as a chase camera for footage of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/8/21056404/sony-vision-s-electric-concept-prototype-first-look-ces-2020"&gt;Vision-S concept car&lt;/a&gt; from last CES. The model shown off at CES 2021 is a quadcopter design and features two landing gear extensions that retract upward during flight (so as not to spoil your footage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="H8xPPJ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HzwuAxSc5Jo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9reHJI"&gt;While Sony hasn’t dabbled in drones before, its cameras are among the best in the industry — so much so that market leader DJI already offers camera mounts for Sony Alpha products. And the idea of Sony bringing that expertise to bear with bespoke drone-focused products is certainly an intriguing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vR1Lah"&gt;Sony had originally announced the &lt;a href="https://www.sony.net/SonyInfo/News/Press/202011/20-091E/"&gt;Airpeak brand in late 2020&lt;/a&gt;, with a planned “spring 2021” release window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jKc8Az"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o_XWbHuwsfw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225758/sony-airpeak-drone-alpha-photography-cameras-ces-2021-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225758/sony-airpeak-drone-alpha-photography-cameras-ces-2021-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T17:32:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T17:32:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>iBuyPower’s compact Revolt 3 MK3 PC case packs in a handle and lots of ventilation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Revolt 3 MK3 will come in black or white." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_iMc8eRpgXNqj97bn8-TbiOI7Dk=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652415/revolt3mk3hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;iBuyPower&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H4HNL3"&gt;iBuyPower announced a new 18.34-liter small form factor PC case at CES 2021 called the Revolt 3 MK3. I’m not sure what I find so enthralling about it, but it’s the kind of case I’d find myself staring at for an embarrassing amount of time if I were in the market to upgrade my build. (Maybe I am, &lt;em&gt;after all.&lt;/em&gt;) If you’re a fan of minimalist cases like me, with next to no added LEDs, you might find yourself under the spell of this case, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GawHR1"&gt;Okay, I also really like its top-mounted handle. It’s not like I move my PC around a lot, though it would make it far easier and safer to carry this around when I need to give it a deep cleaning or swap some of the tech inside. Beyond the handle’s utility, it reminds me of the Nintendo GameCube — if the handle were attached to a chassis that’s far more refined than that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/olafurw/status/1166267668414046208"&gt;console’s actual devkit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Revolt 3 MK3 will come in black or white." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bVW_7d1JcMnDyH3h82kDfOX43yY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228743/revolt3mk3hero.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: iBuyPower&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MIqeb8"&gt;This case design isn’t entirely original. The &lt;a href="https://lian-li.com/product/pc-tu150/"&gt;Lian Li TU150&lt;/a&gt; is a beloved small form factor (mini ITX) option for people who want a small PC with a handle on top, and it’s not like there aren’t other solid choices that arrive sans handle (Velocity Micro, Silverstone, and Sliger, to name a few). The Revolt 3 MK3’s huge amount of ventilation gives it a unique look. Beyond how it looks, each side of the machine can be removed for cleaning, and to make cable management easier to manage. The Revolt 3 MK3’s retractable headphone hook is a thoughtful feature, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="616Pfl"&gt;You’ll be able to purchase this case sometime in the second quarter of the year filled with some pre-selected components from iBuyPower, including a 700W 80 Plus Gold SFX-L power supply that’s &lt;em&gt;just &lt;/em&gt;below the suggested 750W for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21435926/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3080-review"&gt;Nvidia RTX 3080&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21571414/amd-radeon-rx-6800-xt-review"&gt;AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT&lt;/a&gt; and cards below in both AMD and Nvidia’s field should be covered with this power supply for the pre-built crowd. At launch, the company hasn’t actually shared what other specs you’ll be able to have crammed in. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iBuyPower Revolt 3 MK3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P8sbysQ3DC8CSqkfAFlnZs72o5M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228749/revoltmk3exploded.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: iBuyPower&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An exploded view of the Revolt 3 MK3 shows that it’s likely very good at catching dust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yU9eJE"&gt;Alternatively, you’ll have the option to purchase just the case alone in black or white (it supports swappable parts so you can mix white and black how you please), and you can fit an ITX motherboard inside with all of the components you desire. It can actually fit GPUs as big as Nvidia’s RTX 3090, so you can make yourself a powerful machine in this case if you have the right power supply. The company hasn’t shared a price for the case by itself. &lt;a href="https://www.ibuypower.com/gaming-pcs/signatures/revolt-series"&gt;You can find even more specs for the case on iBuyPower’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225562/ibuypowers-revolt-3-mk3-pc-case-itx-handle-small-form-factor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225562/ibuypowers-revolt-3-mk3-pc-case-itx-handle-small-form-factor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T17:16:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T17:16:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vuzix’s new microLED smart glasses look like tech you’d actually want to wear on your face</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g0S-Oi3F3Kd66zBBoPvBM2ey5mc=/151x0:1747x1064/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652338/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_4.24.00_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Vuzix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mj8mck"&gt;Wearable tech and augmented reality provider Vuzix is back at CES 2021 with another pair of its smart glasses, this time with a new advancement. The latest pair is powered by microLED technology, thanks to a &lt;a href="https://ir.vuzix.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1853/vuzix-confirms-that-it-has-entered-into-a-joint"&gt;partnership with the Chinese firm Jade Bird Display&lt;/a&gt;. MicroLED displays have emerged in recent years as viable alternatives to OLED screens, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166062/samsung-110-inch-microled-4k-tv-announced-features"&gt;driving advancements mostly in the television space&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9Rj02"&gt;Yet, the tech in this context allows for ultra small but powerful display projectors to be fitted into both sides of the smart glasses, which, to Vuzix’s credit, look pretty close to something you’d be comfortable wearing out in public on a daily basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWfkrX"&gt;Combined with Vuzix’s waveguide tech and its display engine optics for mapping the image onto the inside of the glass, the result is an impressive-looking gadget that can project a stereoscopic monochrome or color image onto both lenses at a variety of pixel densities and resolutions, depending on the software requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EvkMiKMeC_db5ukM9dcrR5tTlNM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228701/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_4.32.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Vuzix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Similar to Google Glass, Vuzix’s smart glasses are more heads-up displays than true augmented reality devices and are designed to mirror information from a paired smartphone. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vSf9DD"&gt;There are a few other bells and whistles with this device. Vuzix says the device will support Wi-Fi and optional LTE as well as stereo speakers and noise-canceling microphones. There will also be Android and iOS-supported gesture-based touch controls, presumably for controlling companion mobile apps using just the sides of the smart glasses. Unlike Vuzix’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166018/vuzix-blade-ar-consumer-version-available-pricing-release-date-features-ces-2019"&gt;previous $1,000 Blade model&lt;/a&gt;, this new version doesn’t have an official product name or a price yet, though the company is aiming for a summer release date, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/vuzixs-new-microled-powered-smart-glasses-will-arrive-this-summer/"&gt;reports &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VwUgTK"&gt;Of course, given the nature of the virtual CES this year, we haven’t been able to try these smart glasses as we normally would on the show floor, so we can’t say much about the quality of the image, the comfort or design of the frames, or any of the software support. But Vuzix isn’t really targeting the consumer market with a Google Glass-style device, which would necessarily warrant getting an early, hands-on impression of how well they work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dlGSmJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Vuzix’s glasses look impressive, but we’re unable to try them out for ourselves right now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6VnqY4"&gt;Vuzix’s smart glasses, which are more in the realm of heads-up displays than true AR, are aimed more toward the enterprise, especially after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/5/7493439/intel-buys-stake-in-google-glass-rival-vuzix"&gt;Intel acquired a 30 percent stake in the Rochester, New York-based company&lt;/a&gt; back in 2015. The shift toward workplace-focused AR and VR products has been accelerated by slow adoption of consumer-geared headsets and glasses as well as an overall lack of breakthrough advancements in the fundamental tech that would facilitate an iPhone-style moment for the field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nk7Bw4"&gt;That’s why we’ve seen and heard so little about Microsoft’s HoloLens, the second-generation Google Glass, and Magic Leap’s AR goggles in the years since those gadgets made their splashy debuts, all while Facebook quietly continues pumping money into Oculus and remaining one of the very few large tech companies still actively engaged in VR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZk5if"&gt;The tepid consumer reception to AR and VR products hasn’t stopped some bigger names from trying their hand at consumer smart glasses. Amazon has since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22197463/amazon-echo-frames-review-alexa"&gt;entered the smart glasses market with its Echo Frames&lt;/a&gt;, and Facebook is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439929/facebook-ar-smart-glasses-ray-ban-announcement"&gt;working on its first pair&lt;/a&gt; in partnership with Ray-Ban. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/19/21296674/apple-vr-ar-headset-glasses-external-hub-jony-ive-bloomberg-go-read-this"&gt;rumors continue to percolate&lt;/a&gt; around Apple’s plans to release an AR headset or a pair of smart glasses (or both) sometime in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225605/vuzix-microled-smart-glasses-next-gen-ar-heads-up-display-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225605/vuzix-microled-smart-glasses-next-gen-ar-heads-up-display-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
