<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-01T12:55:24-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T12:55:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T12:55:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Renewables see record growth in 2021, but supply chain problems loom </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Solar and Wind Farms in Qinghai Province as China Expands Clean Energy Access" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IcqChoxXGr6GYCS9h8DZ9fERQB8=/430x0:5035x3070/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215386/1235228776.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photovoltaic modules at a solar power plant near Golmud, Qinghai province, China, on Saturday, Sept. 11, 2021. | Qilai Shen/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rwOgJM"&gt;2021 is on course to break a global record for renewable energy growth, according to the International Energy Agency’s latest &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/renewables-2021"&gt;Renewables Market Report.&lt;/a&gt; That’s despite skyrocketing commodity prices, which could bog down the transition to clean energy in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ykcPoC"&gt;With 290 GW in additional capacity expected to be commissioned by the end of the year, 2021 will smash the record for renewable electricity growth that was just set last year. This year’s additions even outpace a forecast that the International Energy Agency (IEA) made in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430465/renewable-energy-solar-wind-iea-2020-exceptional-growth"&gt;spring&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Att8pA"&gt;“Exceptionally high growth” would be the “new normal” for renewable sources of electricity, the IEA &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/renewable-energy-market-update-2021"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; at the time. Solar energy, in particular, was on track to take the crown as the “new king of electricity,” the IEA said in its October 2020 &lt;a href="https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/a72d8abf-de08-4385-8711-b8a062d6124a/WEO2020.pdf"&gt;World Energy Outlook report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="nN9EtM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Solar continued to dominate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qbJVI4"&gt;Solar continued to dominate in 2021, with an expected record growth of nearly 160 GW. It made up more than half of all the renewable energy capacity added this year, a trend that the IEA thinks will continue over the next five. Renewables will likely make up 95 percent of new power capacity globally through 2026, according to the new report. The IEA also predicts explosive growth for offshore wind capacity, which could more than triple over the same time period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hcMiAj"&gt;By 2026, the IEA says, the amount of renewable electricity capacity globally will likely be equivalent to today’s fossil fuel and nuclear energy capacity combined. That’s a huge shift. In 2020, renewable energy only made up &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/global-energy-review-2021/renewables"&gt;29 percent&lt;/a&gt; of electricity generation globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NpF05L"&gt;Still, there are some dark clouds in the IEA’s new forecast for renewables. Soaring prices for commodities, shipping, and energy all threaten the previously rosy outlook for renewable energy. The cost of polysilicon used to make solar panels has more than quadrupled since the start of 2020, according to the IEA. Investment costs for utility-scale onshore wind and solar farms have risen 25 percent compared to 2019. That could delay the completion of new renewable energy projects that have already been contracted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xs0ajU"&gt;More than half of the new utility-scale solar projects already planned for 2022 could face delays or cancellation because of larger price tags for materials and shipping, according to a separate &lt;a href="https://www.rystadenergy.com/newsevents/news/press-releases/most-of-2022s-solar-PV-projects-risk-delay-or-cancelation-due-to-soaring-material-and-shipping-costs/"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Rystad Energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JAFV6k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The transition to renewable energy needs to speed up significantly to meet the scale of the climate crisis&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3c8ytx"&gt;If commodity prices stay high over the next year, it could erase three to five years of gains&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;solar and wind have made, respectively, when it comes to affordability. A dramatic price drop for photovoltaic modules over the past few decades has fueled solar’s success. &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/charts/evolution-of-solar-pv-module-cost-by-data-source-1970-2020"&gt;Costs fell&lt;/a&gt; from $30 per watt in 1980 to $0.20 per watt for solar energy in 2020. By last year, solar was already the &lt;a href="https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/a72d8abf-de08-4385-8711-b8a062d6124a/WEO2020.pdf"&gt;cheapest source of electricity&lt;/a&gt; in most parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bIJZKi"&gt;Renewables haven’t fallen too far behind, however, because costs are rising for all forms of energy. “The high commodity and energy prices we are seeing today pose new challenges for the renewable industry, but elevated fossil fuel prices also make renewables even more competitive,” IEA executive director Fatih Birol said in a &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/news/renewable-electricity-growth-is-accelerating-faster-than-ever-worldwide-supporting-the-emergence-of-the-new-global-energy-economy"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oFyf6P"&gt;Still, the transition to renewable energy needs to speed up significantly to meet the scale of the climate crisis. Greenhouse gas emissions from burning fossil fuels need to virtually disappear by the middle of the century to avoid catastrophic climate change, according to a huge body of &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/chapter/spm/"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;. To make that happen, new renewable power capacity needs to grow at nearly twice the rate the IEA foresees over the next five years, the agency says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="pAAz9j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fossil fuels are forecast to dry up, but not soon enough ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724258/fossil-fuels-forecast-climate-change-international-energy-agency"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="EVgXFi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Biden administration gives offshore wind farms a big boost ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22725234/biden-offshore-wind-boost-united-states-coastlines"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="9cYLfA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Rising electricity demand is keeping coal alive ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641178/global-power-sector-emissions-rise-pandemic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="HvhxUM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CVlux6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTu9FY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a1s81J"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yrTN54"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811869/renewable-energy-electricity-record-growth-2021-supply-chain-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811869/renewable-energy-electricity-record-growth-2021-supply-chain-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T12:48:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T12:48:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify Wrapped 2021 is here to take over your social media</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Spotify Wrapped 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KswJpE7orzWXqd1hpuu52f7VTY0=/0x131:1216x942/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215366/PR_2021_Minutes.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Spotify Wrapped 2021 | Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u1KAT4"&gt;Spotify &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-12-01/the-wait-is-over-your-spotify-2021-wrapped-is-here/"&gt;has released its eagerly anticipated&lt;/a&gt; Wrapped experience revealing the most listened to artists and albums for (most of) 2021. This year, it’s adding even more social media-friendly features that help you share your favorite music with a customized movie, aura, or playing cards. Naturally, you can share Spotify’s auto-created images on your timeline and, for the first time, directly to TikTok. It’s sure to spark discussions with friends and provide valuable marketing for Spotify that competitors like Apple and YouTube can’t seem to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUsBKX"&gt;Here’s how to find your Spotify 2021 Wrapped experience. To get all of the interactive features, you’ll need to open the Spotify mobile app — it’s not available on the desktop or web version. If you’re on an iPhone or Android device, just &lt;a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/wrapped/"&gt;click this link&lt;/a&gt; and it should open the correct page inside the app. If you’re not seeing it yet, try refreshing the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jltz5g"&gt;If you don’t have Spotify or aren’t seeing it yet, these are some of the new features it’s added in 2021 to promote sharing: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLOJRP"&gt;The Movie feature gives you selected songs for your biopic formatted for your opening credits theme, the moment of reflection, the dance-off, or the big game. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature 2021 the movie" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nQdoibudIa5PFHmDxDtlxudgBJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055547/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.25_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new 2021: The Movie feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zN4Hxg"&gt;Spotify users can also get a visualization of their audio aura based on their top two music moods. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature audio aura" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/clHxQVlyD--Vhxxz3Sa3g8ho1tY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055536/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.18_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new audio aura feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yifiwY"&gt;Spotify also released a data-based game that you can play and share with your friends called  Playing Cards. In the style of two truths and a lie, players can look at statements about another user’s listening history and guess which one is a lie. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Three phones showing Spotify Wrapped’s new feature playing cards" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5GIpeq6msDmeYiI-0cqU3PGSgZQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055538/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_9.44.32_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s new Playing Cards feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qKYhzT"&gt;Spotify is also using Wrapped to expand the blend feature that was released this year by letting users blend their Spotify Wrapped and share the results on social media. Also available is Spotify’s 2021 Wrapped hub, which includes both personalized and editorially curated content and playlists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcsNUw"&gt;Other than TikTok, Wrapped cards are directly shareable to Snapchat, Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUWieq"&gt;So what about people who don’t use Spotify? Apple Music users like me can’t enjoy Spotify Wrapped, but we have access to &lt;a href="https://music.apple.com/replay"&gt;Apple Music Replay&lt;/a&gt; which includes a compilation of a user’s most played songs and lists most listened to artists and albums, plus an option to listen to playlists dating back to 2015. Of course, if you’re seeking your own unique version of today’s Wrapped interactive experience, then 2021 is just another year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20997218/spotify-wrapped-year-end-decade-review-apple-music-streaming-audio-service"&gt;reminding you of what you’re missing&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MB3MSI"&gt;Other music streaming services like YouTube Music and Tidal have released their own versions to commemorate a user’s listening history. &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/30/youtube-music-2021-recap/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out that some YouTube Music subscribers &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/30/youtube-music-2021-recap/"&gt;have spotted a 2021 Recap&lt;/a&gt; that includes playlists and stats. Tidal &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tidal-releases-my-2020-rewind-for-members-to-look-back-at-their-year-in-music-301182905.html"&gt;released its My 2020 Rewind&lt;/a&gt; feature last year on December 1st but has yet to release an updated 2021 version. As far as other streaming services, they might be waiting until the end of December to take a look back on the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google announces grab bag of new Android features for the end of 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6BEbICX3NxjzrHkzkVfR1s_xC7k=/118x0:1398x853/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215130/Untitled__4_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fijamA"&gt;Google has a bevy of new features coming soon to Android, including new widgets for YouTube Music, Google Play Books, and Google Photos; new Android Auto features; and updates for Google Assistant and Google Photos. The company detailed the new features &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-december-2021/"&gt;in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="To5aJQ"&gt;The biggest car-based addition is that from today Pixel 6, Pixel 6 Pro, and Samsung Galaxy S21 owners will be able to use their phones as a car key with “compatible BMW vehicles” in select countries. Google announced it was working on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22436410/google-android-auto-os-pixel-phone-key-io"&gt;car key feature for Android 12 in May&lt;/a&gt;, specifically citing BMW as one of the manufacturers with which it would work. Google says the feature will be available “on all BMW 2020 &amp;amp; 2022 model year vehicles,” and that it hopes to add more compatible vehicles in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UOhnTM"&gt;Other new Android Auto features that are coming soon include an option to have the car-friendly interface automatically launch when an Android phone is connected to the vehicle, a new play button on the homescreen to start music playback with a “single tap,” a new search icon to quickly find music, and new smart reply options for text messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3mc6gD"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Hp-lGxwPUnI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mGZMUU"&gt;New widgets are also coming to the Android phone screen for the YouTube Music, Google Play Books, and Google Photos apps. The music widget offers playback controls and access to recently played tracks, while the books widget gives shortcuts to your library. There’s also a new Google Photos widget rolling out next week that can be set to specifically show pictures of select people and pets from your library. As well as a new widget, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/12/20860938/google-photos-memories-prints-cvs-walmart-canvas"&gt;Google Photos’ Memories feature&lt;/a&gt; will also start showing curated photos and videos of events like New Years Eve within the standard photo grid interface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U1JHuV"&gt;Google’s “Family Bell” feature, its alarm-like reminder system that can be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21353207/google-assistant-smart-display-speakers-family-new-features-homeschool"&gt;broadcast from smart speakers and displays&lt;/a&gt;, is also being updated to work on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PqesWX"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6CiQEfiZv9s?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JquKdK"&gt;Finally, Google has also provided an update on the rollout of its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679379/android-11-auto-reset-permissions-android-6"&gt;permissions-reset feature on older Android phones&lt;/a&gt;, which automatically turns off permissions for apps you haven’t used in a while. The feature is already available for devices running Android 11 and above but will now expand to devices running Android 6 and up “starting next month,” the company says, indicating a January rollout. It previously said the expansion would begin rolling out in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gxWC3A"&gt;As is typical with these kinds of feature drops from Google, these new options are releasing in a variety of different timeframes, ranging from “today” for the BMW car key feature to the “coming months” for the Android Auto voice search and smart replies features.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811617/google-android-auto-widgets-assistant-family-bell-updates-december-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811617/google-android-auto-widgets-assistant-family-bell-updates-december-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:38:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:38:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>General Motors announces it will build a new cathode plant in North America </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Biden Visits General Motors’ Factory Zero Electric Vehicle Factory" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zHX-FwaeOomro4dr_EX80GCEynU=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215016/1236631423.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eWzdSt"&gt;General Motors announced that it will construct a new cathode factory in North America for its electric vehicle batteries. The factory, which will be built under a joint venture with South Korea’s Posco Chemical, will process cathode active material (CAM), which represents about 40 percent of the cost of an EV battery cell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1CBNii"&gt;Much like the rest of the auto industry, GM is racing to boost its EV offerings, vowing to spend $27 billion on the development and production of 30 new electric vehicles by 2025. To accomplish this enormous feat, the company is trying to get a stronger grasp on its supply chain, which includes battery manufacturing. The company has said it will spend over $4 billion on the construction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313251/gm-ev-second-battery-factory-lg-chem-tennessee"&gt;two battery factories&lt;/a&gt; in North America in partnership with South Korea’s LG Chem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="L76B7n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Much like the rest of the auto industry, GM is racing to boost its EV offerings&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AKb1TD"&gt;The new cathode facility will supply battery materials to the two factories that are currently under construction: the Ultium Cells facilities in Lordstown, Ohio, and Spring Hill, Tennessee. GM is also planning to build two more cell facilities by mid-decade, the company has said. GM did not disclose the location of the new cathode facility but said it would be open by 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xE7P6r"&gt;The majority of EV battery cathodes are made with NCM — nickel, cobalt, and magnesium. The Ultium batteries will add aluminum — so NCMA — and reduce the cobalt content by 70 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KgbpcW"&gt;Cobalt is &lt;a href="http://batteryuniversity.com/learn/article/bu_310_cobalt"&gt;a key component of batteries&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s also the most expensive material in the battery and &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/business/batteries/congo-cobalt-mining-for-lithium-ion-battery/"&gt;mined under conditions that often violate human rights&lt;/a&gt;, leading it to be called the “blood diamond of batteries.” As a result, GM and other companies, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21451678/tesla-new-cathode-plant-north-america-battery-day"&gt;like Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, are rushing to create a cobalt-free battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j6jbsv"&gt;“We would like to get out of cobalt altogether and have a zero cobalt situation,” said Doug Parks, GM’s executive vice president focused on global product development, purchasing and supply chain. “We’re going to start with old Ultium NCMA chemistry, and then we will we will advance as we go forward as quickly as possible to improve either the performance or the cost of the battery cell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Pcjta"&gt;This is the latest announcement from GM regarding its efforts to boost its EV production through vertical integration. The company also recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559718/gm-lithium-ctr-ev-battery-investment-salton-sea"&gt;struck a deal to source lithium&lt;/a&gt;, a key ingredient in electric-car batteries, from geothermal deposits in the US. And it’s building a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709389/gm-wallace-battery-center-ev-ultium-research"&gt;new 300,000-square-foot battery research facility&lt;/a&gt; in Michigan to help it realize its mission of building electric vehicle batteries that are longer-lasting, quicker to charge, and more sustainable for the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811902/general-motors-cathode-factory-ev-battery-posco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811902/general-motors-cathode-factory-ev-battery-posco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:38:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:38:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Barnes &amp; Noble announces new Nook GlowLight 4, says it cares for real this time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HxyWTAGOKs4lK0uhXBA9TG-gHDQ=/166x0:1266x733/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215009/nook.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MA5vv4"&gt;Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has once again remembered that it ostensibly wants to sell e-readers and has announced the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.barnesandnoble.com%2Fw%2Fnook-glowlight-4-barnes-noble%2F1140326110%3Fean%3D9780594149293&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811857%2Fbarnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nook GlowLight 4&lt;/a&gt;, a $149 e-reader that offers a refreshed design, more onboard storage, and USB-C charging to the company’s lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNEnTl"&gt;The last dedicated Nook e-reader, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/11/1/16591594/nook-glowlight-3-ereader-eink-barnes-and-noble"&gt;the GlowLight 3&lt;/a&gt;, was announced 49 months ago (to the day) on November 1st, 2017, although Barnes &amp;amp; Noble did give the Nook brand a shot in the arm earlier this year with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22340588/barnes-and-noble-new-nook-10-hd-tablet-lenovo-price-release-date-ebooks"&gt;new, Lenovo-made budget tablet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Uay09"&gt;The new GlowLight 4 doesn’t appear to move the needle much compared to the 2017 model, though. The display is an identical six-inch, 300ppi e-paper display with an integrated backlight and adjustable color temperature functionality, although the company has slimmed down the bezels and overall size of the new model. Battery life has been increased, with up to 50 days off a single charge (up from a month on the old model). And the onboard storage has been quadrupled from 8GB to 32GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QEtH4U"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The first new Nook e-reader in 49 months&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QUGAs4"&gt;Those new upgrades also come with an unfortunate $30 price increase, with the Nook GlowLight 4 costing $149, up from the already expensive $119 that the GlowLight 3 went for. Adding insult to injury is the fact that Barnes &amp;amp; Noble isn’t adding back more important features like waterproofing or more premium materials. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ulNr9kw-E73kv-wP_v-L40l7SbE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055570/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_11.14.25_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: Barnes &amp;amp; Noble&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nook GlowLight 3 (left) and the new GlowLight 4 (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HWRDBy"&gt;It’s something that’s especially puzzling given that Barnes &amp;amp; Noble was one of the first companies to add both of those features with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/21/9582252/barnes-and-noble-nook-glowlight-plus-waterproof-ereader"&gt;2015 GlowLight Plus&lt;/a&gt;, which offered a sleek aluminum design long before Amazon did with its Oasis. The Nook was also waterproof years before Amazon and Kobo would make that the standard across most of their product lineups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XVO0DR"&gt;And given the $149 price tag, the GlowLight 4 is a pretty hard sell. It’s pricier than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22745670/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2021-review-usb-c-signature-edition-display-e-reader-books"&gt;Amazon’s new Paperwhite model&lt;/a&gt;, which starts at $139 (when not on one of its frequent holiday sales) and has a bigger display, waterproofing, and a larger ebook storefront. And it matches up poorly against Kobo’s Libra line, too, which has a $159 starting price but adds a bigger and better display, waterproofing, and easier access to borrowed library books. The only real benefit that the GlowLight 4 offers is physical page turn buttons, making it the cheapest major e-reader to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2IxeAK"&gt;That said, it seems like the GlowLight 4 might just be the tip of the Nook iceberg. “Barnes &amp;amp; Noble is now investing significantly in our Nook line of products,” Barnes &amp;amp; Noble CEO James Daunt promised in an accompanying press release, noting plans to “reinvigorate Nook in the coming months and years.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUdETa"&gt;And while Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has a long way to go before it catches up to Kobo or Amazon, getting a third competitive player in the e-reader space would be a good thing — even if Barnes &amp;amp; Noble is only slightly less of a monolithic corporation than, say, Amazon or Rakuten (which owns Kobo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WV1sI0"&gt;The Nook GlowLight 4 is set to go on sale on Barnes &amp;amp; Noble’s website and in stores in one week on December 8th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811857/barnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811857/barnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:33:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:33:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hawkeye’s trick USB arrow is in desperate need of a dongle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U2x_zNEgCO6adRsPVaHeJThDEhQ=/714x0:3126x1608/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214997/CMB2460_103_comp_v091.1035.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5JdlCD"&gt;In the third episode of &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt;, Kate Bishop (Hailee Steinfeld) does something very unexpected: she requests a USB dongle in the midst of a battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGiCIL"&gt;The highlight of the episode is a scene where Kate and her reluctant mentor, Clint Barton (Jeremy Renner), are fighting their way through the Tracksuit Mafia amidst some hectic New York City traffic. While Clint drives, Kate goes through his collection of trick arrows. Most are the kind of comic book goofiness you’d expect: one arrow creates a bubbling purple foam; another becomes destructively huge. Later, though, Clint hands Kate something much less useful in a fight: an arrow with a USB-A port on the end. “God, I hope he’s got a dongle to make this useful,” Kate quips afterward. (It turns out to not be very useful.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2EWi16"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hawkeye starts out strong because it doesn’t take itself too seriously","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22796664/hawkeye-early-review-disney-plus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BY1rY0FAoZ0__32UL5Y2BZiaXsk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055481/FFh3uZGWYAIJZ8F.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_n2R97ByHi8jbSBOxl2-wFL3uE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055482/FFh3ucsWUAUGY6m.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PCKgCv"&gt;This isn’t the first time we’ve seen a trick arrow designed to interface with computers. In the original &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; movie, Hawkeye had an arrow that could hack a very specific and proprietary port on a flying Helicarrier. But the new episode of the show makes it clear that there are much more mundane arrows as well. Unfortunately, given the surprising amount of characters who use a USB C-equipped Pixel phone in &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye,&lt;/em&gt; the superhero is going to have to update his arsenal soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811932/hawkeye-usb-arrow-dongle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811932/hawkeye-usb-arrow-dongle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:19:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:19:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>What’s the best student laptop? We asked students</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BVcaADlGztrbR5iNL_kFd3rebG0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67232292/akrales_200421_3975_0080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 is one of the best laptops for high school and college students.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tsQK0e"&gt;Shopping for a laptop can be stressful — doubly stressful if you or your children will be learning online for the first time. Kids of different ages have a range of different laptop use cases and different needs. And as the choices for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; evolve, so do students’ needs. So I spoke to some experts on the subject: students themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9ZW8b"&gt;My recommendations here are meant to accommodate a variety of preferences and price ranges. But they’re a jumping-off point rather than an exhaustive list: every student is different. Before making a decision, you’ll want to make sure you read reviews and try out devices yourself if you can. I’ll do my best to keep this article up to date with items that are in stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lxqTuB"&gt;Best laptop for students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside id="7m4BUq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best laptop you can buy ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"},{"title":"The best Chromebooks to buy in 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4lsvuf2NE7Upsw5uiVfjINO_Jhk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19315989/vpavic_191023_3755_0159.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s Pixelbook Go has solid battery life and a rippled base that’s easy to grip, making it a good choice for kids.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uaaUWw"&gt;Best laptop for elementary school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wdF0Hl"&gt;For younger students, a touchscreen device is easier to use than a keyboard and touchpad, says Michelle Glogovac. Glogovac’s five-year-old son uses an iPad for Webex meetings with his kindergarten class. He’s gotten the hang of it; Glogovac says he’s already learned how to mute and unmute himself, “a skill that many adults aren’t familiar with.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qEF087"&gt;That said, it may be worth investing in a keyboard case if you go the tablet route. Glogovac has to type her son’s meeting codes and passwords for him, which can be cumbersome on the iPad’s flat screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wxdcbE"&gt;As kids get older, their best laptop choice will vary depending on their needs. As a parent, it’s important that you and your child are in sync about how they intend to use it and the size of the programs they want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8sTP9p"&gt;Kristin Wallace purchased a budget HP laptop for her daughter, Bella, but didn’t realize how quickly the nine-year-old would fill up 32GB of storage. “It is really slow and has no space for games. I need a computer with more storage space,” said Bella, who uses the laptop to Zoom with friends and take virtual guitar lessons and math enrichment classes. Wallace plans to buy Bella a better device in the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rwTXVL"&gt;Audio quality is an important consideration for kids’ laptops. Lisa Mitchell, an elementary library media specialist, says her students use their devices to watch YouTube videos in addition to their online classes. Battery life is also a plus, even for distance learners who may not be far from a wall outlet. Bella likes to use her laptop all around the house and doesn’t want to bring the cord with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FaeV8B"&gt;Durability is also worth paying for, according to Mitchell. If you’re using a tablet, get a protective case. “If a reasonably-priced insurance or replacement policy is available, it’s usually worth the extra expense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlnxQa"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mWvFvV"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08F62DV1Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Fire HD 10 Kids Editio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-New-Fire-HD-8-Kids-Edition-Tablet/dp/B07WDDT3G5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;n&lt;/a&gt; ($199): a colorful, fast tablet with kid-friendly content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nE2JTN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lenovo.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Flaptops%2Flenovo%2Fstudent-chromebooks%2FLenovo-CT-X636%2Fp%2FZZICZCTCT1X&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21369381%2Fbest-student-laptops-school-high-college" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt; ($229): a tiny 10-inch Chromebook with a detachable keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yxGd1j"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1068592/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-10-2" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple 10.2-inch iPad&lt;/a&gt; ($329): a great budget tablet that supports the Apple Pencil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ATavfg"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Go-2%2F8PT3S2VJMDR6%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfbt-p1c%26selectedColor%3D%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Surface Go 2&lt;/a&gt; ($299): a solid Windows tablet with a built-in kickstand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GB06L3"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1741208806862135658" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google Pixelbook Go&lt;/a&gt; ($599): a sturdy touchscreen Chromebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Lenovo Chromebook Duet" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M79QGj6leDzJdmoI3tnqqQRv7Cc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19978535/mchin_200512_4018_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lenovo’s Chromebook Duet is just $289, but it can run plenty of tabs and apps with no problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dE2ANJ"&gt;Best laptop for middle school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="r5kOKS"&gt;The middle school students I spoke to don’t use their laptops for much more than web-based schoolwork and browsing. Don’t be too concerned about power — prioritize a machine that’s comfortable and easy for your child to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9OvOd"&gt;“We just got the most basic Chromebook and it is totally perfect,” says Gabrielle Hartley, an &lt;a href="http://gabriellehartley.com/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;attorney&lt;/a&gt; and mother of three children. “The most basic Chromebook serves all the needs of the basic middle schooler.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A user types on the Acer Chromebook Spin 713." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0hMEh9WTjBjXAQF5Bh8xq8l2ng0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21698818/mchin_181029_4126_0017.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chromebooks, like this one from Acer, are a good choice for students who use Google Classroom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fP2U74"&gt;Hartley’s son Max, who is in eighth grade, agrees. “I would really like a gaming PC or gaming laptop that can plug into a monitor and run video games with 120fps, but I really don’t need that,” Max says. “Most eighth graders aren’t going to be running any video games on their laptops or any software that requires a lot of power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WpOfaD"&gt;Max mostly uses his laptop for Google Classroom applications, including Gmail, Slides, Google Docs, and Google Sheets. They’re very easy to use on his device, which he describes as “a run-of-the-mill Samsung Chromebook.” That said, if your child is starting middle school this year, it could be worth checking with their teachers to see what operating system is most compatible with their workflow. Caspian Fischer Odén, a ninth grader from Sweden, told me he has trouble with his Chromebook because his school has blocked downloading apps from the Google Play Store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9eUtDq"&gt;Even kids with more demanding hobbies think a budget device can get the job done. Sam Hickman, an eighth grader from the UK who uses his laptop for photo and video editing, says, “For most middle schoolers, any processor developed within the last two years will be able to handle any tasks they can throw at it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4fFLe"&gt;So, what &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;worth paying for? A comfortable keyboard, several students told me. Many middle school kids aren’t used to typing for long periods of time. You should also look for a device that’s compact and easy for them to carry around, particularly if they’re preparing for in-person school. Shoot for an 11- to 13-inch model — certainly nothing larger than 15 inches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RnWLQu"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="y39J7M"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-chromebook-x360-14a-ca0000-%25282v972av%2529" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Chromebook x360&lt;/a&gt; ($259): an affordable Chromebook with great battery life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fJzJXL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hxVB3yKL" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo Flex 3 Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; ($329): a small but sturdy laptop made for students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JfExfj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lenovo-Flagship-Education-Touchscreen-Quad-Core/dp/B07Q478DHY/ref=sr_1_3?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Lenovo+300e+Chromebook&amp;amp;qid=1597705015&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo 300e&lt;/a&gt; ($349): a durable 2-in-1 with a stylus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QAiiVc"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2F1TS-000X-01365%3FDescription%3Dacer%2520aspire%25205%26cm_re%3Dacer_aspire%25205-_-1TS-000X-01365-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Aspire 5&lt;/a&gt; ($459): a portable option for kids who need a 15-inch screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T0amM0"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-Go%2F94FC0BDGQ7WV%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfbt-h1c%26selectedColor%3D86888a%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Surface Laptop Go&lt;/a&gt; ($499): an attractive, light Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Surface Laptop 4 15-inch seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JJpWTgsxAQaEUzKsbaT80APyQdE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22456007/mchin_20190710_4532_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Laptop 4 is a capable, no-nonsense laptop — just what many high schoolers want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SKuVFA"&gt;Best laptop for high school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OHE9ce"&gt;High schoolers’ laptop needs can vary based on their interests, but most don’t need powerful machines with lots of bells and whistles — especially if they come with glitches or serious downsides that could interfere with schoolwork. Miles Riehle, a student at Laguna Beach High School, has a high-end Surface Pro 7 but finds it overwhelming. “There is so much other stuff that I don’t use very often,” he said. “Something simpler might be a little more straightforward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="toVK5y"&gt;The best operating system may depend on what your child is used to. Aryan Nambiar, a student at Barrington High School in Illinois, has an iMac at home and enjoys using an iPad for his schoolwork. Riehle says he would prefer a Chromebook because he has an Android phone and often uses Google services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taD6O0"&gt;But almost every student I spoke to agreed that the most important feature of a high school laptop is portability. Kids attending in-person classes may be carrying their device around for much of the day with a stack of other books. Look for a 13- or 14-inch screen, or a lighter 15- to 17-inch model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9koeX"&gt;Students also recommend something sturdy. “Most high schoolers I’ve seen will throw their laptop in their bag without too much care,” says Moses Buckwalter, a student at Penn Manor High School. Backpacks can be jostled in the hallway as well. Kids can also run into trouble at home. “Anything can happen,” says Aadit Agrawal, a high school student from India. “My own brother scratched my laptop with his nails.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wo7j0d"&gt;Battery life is another key feature. “It can be a real struggle to find a place to charge while in class,” says Cas Heemskerk, a sophomore from the Netherlands. Unlike college students, many high schoolers don’t have frequent breaks to juice up their devices, so try to find something that can last a full day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SMbdD6"&gt;Many students recommend a touchscreen with stylus support. Nambiar uses the feature for his biology class, where he does a lot of visual modeling. “The touchscreen is always a bonus for drawing diagrams, whereas if you’re using a laptop it’d be a whole process to submit a diagram you drew,” Nambiar says. Riehle uses a Surface Pen to fill out school forms and annotate PDFs. Agrawal finds it useful to take notes on the same screen as his online lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z7t3Wu"&gt;Depending on the broadband situation in your area, you may also want a laptop with multiple connectivity options. Agrawal’s online classes are sometimes interrupted by powercuts, so he recommends an LTE model. Matej Plavevski, a junior at Yahya Kemal College in North Macedonia, recommends looking for an Ethernet port in case slower connections disrupt meetings. That’s hard to find on smaller laptops, but there’s a slew of affordable dongles and docks to consider. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hUtx7H"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XJHuOW"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?sharedid=verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FAcer-Spin-513-Qualcomm-4GB-64GB-Chromebook-13-3-Full-HD-IPS-Multi-Touch-Corning-Gorilla-Glass-Display-Qualcomm-Snapdragon-7c-Compute-Platform-4GB-LPD%2F973209903%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_QMfy1TTJJxyLWB-wUx0Mo36KUkB28lyFUWu0zo0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_64065%26clickid%3DQMfy1TTJJxyLWB-wUx0Mo36KUkB28lyFUWu0zo0%26sharedid%3Ds1621611404093icm1a52402%26affiliates_ad_id%3D568844%26campaign_id%3D9383" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 513&lt;/a&gt; ($349): a convertible Chromebook with all-day battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dQPInK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1068592/7613?subId1=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-air" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple iPad Air&lt;/a&gt; ($599): a powerful tablet with a great screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ohIlqp"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hqZQdAk1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt; ($699): a fantastic Chromebook that’s not too pricey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7PDjaF"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-12839518?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fxps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; ($1,219): a solid clamshell Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ezk6BY"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-4%2F946627FB12T1%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfrequentlyboughttogetherlaptop4%26selectedColor%3D9A9CA3%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; ($699): an excellent, light laptop that’s comfortable to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: HP Envy x360 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-3n_PDQBp_EOIUDusfA7A_LYGZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20069599/mchin_200705_4086_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For college students seeking an affordable laptop, HP’s Envy x360 performs just as well as some expensive competitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QKVW4e"&gt;Best laptop for college &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sqoQtB"&gt;College kids are justified in spending a bit more money than other age groups. Some (especially in STEM courses) can expect to do some fairly demanding work. Assad Abid, an electrical engineering undergrad from Pakistan, needs to run simulation software for his assignments. Aakash Chandra, a student at New Horizon College of Engineering in India, does a lot of coding, in addition to creative work in Premiere Pro and Photoshop, and gaming. Students also noted that it’s worthwhile to pay for a laptop that will last for a few years after graduation. That means you won’t have to worry about finding and financing your next device until you’re (hopefully) settled into a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNtiDo"&gt;But among high-end, capable devices there’s still a wide range of options. Students stressed that a college laptop should be light. Expect to bring it between classes, meals, meetings, the library, and other locations on campus. “It’s a boon that I can carry my laptop as well as some notebooks without feeling like I’m carrying too much for six hours a day,” says Haseeb Waseem, a senior at Villanova University. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ntrjko32oDlmo53mASwptA-kbCI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19897864/mchin_200413_3971_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 has a variety of configurations. Students with light workloads may prefer the base model, while gamers and creatives can add a GPU.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gsQLLb"&gt;Another universally-lauded feature: battery life. Waseem, who uses an HP Spectre, says the all-day juice gives him “the flexibility to study in a bunch of different locations, and even outside.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PevA8"&gt;Speakers and webcams are often overlooked, even in top-end devices. But students say it’s worth looking for good ones if you’re starting college this year. Though many college students are now back to in-person classes, some will still be meeting with clubs and attending events online. Waseem isn’t satisfied with his laptop’s audio and picture quality, which he says has made it difficult to pay attention in class and to engage with other students.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MqglEH"&gt;Many students will need to invest more in areas tailored to their interests and schoolwork needs. Chandra’s dream laptop would include a stylus and touchscreen for his creative work as well as a high-end GPU. Waseem, who uses his laptop for a hodgepodge of activities, including streaming, coding, social media, video chatting, and Microsoft Office work, would prefer to prioritize a large screen to keep track of his multitasking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1fkTF"&gt;Check out: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VTZaIC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1617646-REG%2Facer_nx_a4kaa_003_swift_3_i7_1165g7_8gb.html%3F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21369381%2Fbest-student-laptops-school-high-college" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt; ($849): a super light laptop that performs well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pSvCeK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hoyEJXSp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt; ($749): a fast and stylish 2-in-1 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eaAcQA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-12839518?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fxps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; ($1,219): a solid clamshell Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NPYIS2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-4%2F946627FB12T1%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfrequentlyboughttogetherlaptop4%26selectedColor%3D9A9CA3%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; ($699): an excellent, light laptop that’s comfortable to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Bfwtvt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeBestLaptops080621&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-spectre-x360-laptop-14t-ea000-touch-1q881av-1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt; ($949): a premium convertible with standout battery life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jabra Elite 7 Pro review: something’s missing</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Jabra’s latest earbuds impress on voice quality but arrive without the company’s signature feature&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UDC7Dj"&gt;Jabra has managed to carve out a strong reputation for its true wireless earbuds over the past several years, even as the competition from larger companies continues to get better. But the company recently decided to shake things up and overhauled its lineup by introducing three new models at once. The $199.99 Elite 7 Pro are the company’s new premium buds, with the $179.99 Elite 7 Active offering the same core features and sound with tweaks that make them a better fit for workouts. At the entry level, you’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;the Elite 3&lt;/a&gt; that I reviewed in September, a no-frills set of earbuds that nail the basics for $80. The higher-end Elite 7s have better sound, active noise cancellation, wireless charging, and more extensive water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uamjMp"&gt;But at least initially, they’ve also sacrificed something that’s always been a standout feature of Jabra earbuds: multipoint Bluetooth support. It’s still somewhat rare to find buds that can connect to two devices at once, which allows you to seamlessly take phone calls while listening to music or watching a video on your laptop, for example. Jabra has consistently offered multipoint with its previous Elite 65t, 75t, and 85t earbuds. However, the Elite 7 Pro and Elite 7 Active are both launching without this important functionality; Jabra’s website says multipoint will be added via firmware update sometime in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLjmuR"&gt;With that selling point still MIA, the Elite 7 Pros lack any big draw that might lure people away from the competition. They’ve got a nicer design than previous Jabra buds and excellent voice call quality, but those are things available in buds from Apple and Samsung and don’t really separate the Jabras from the pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0K0wc6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10896381"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="piSnKF"&gt;The Elite 7 Pros have a more stylish, refined design compared to all past Jabra buds. The in-your-face microphone holes are gone, and the clicky button with the Jabra logo is now teardrop-shaped and takes up the entire outer surface, so you’ll have no trouble finding it with your finger. The curves of this matured design also make the earbuds easier to grab out of the charging case and less prone to accidental drops when you’re handling them. The case has a USB-C port on the front, which is unusual, but not a downside in practice. It also supports Qi wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VG4LirOhxJQxDDtarPlLPKWwyIk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055360/IMG_0119_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The charging case’s USB-C port is on the front.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w5FweD"&gt;Unfortunately, the Elite 7 Pros and their ear tips aren’t as good of a match for my ears as the older 75t and 65t buds were. Something about the fit just isn’t doing it for me. When the earbuds are fully inserted into my ears, the sound can be thin and passive noise isolation suffers, so the ambient noise in my local coffee shop can get distracting. I get the best bass response and audio quality with these earbuds by stopping short of putting them all the way in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tiEfihfVd_manPnKxiTZhPV71TY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055330/IMG_0114_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Jabra Elite 7 Pros are rated IP57 against dust and water.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="091Hu9"&gt;In that sweet spot, the Elite 7 Pros have rich audio with ample bass — though I still think the older 75t buds hit harder in this regard. But the mix here is a lot cleaner. Listening through Taylor Swift’s remake of &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;, the earbuds were detailed and had nice warmth to them on acoustic tracks. I wasn’t blown away by their soundstage, but the overall balance makes up for that some. The vocals on Amanda Shires’ “Home To Me” were crisp and stood out beautifully from the rest of the mix. But the new Nathaniel Rateliff &amp;amp; The Night Sweats album &lt;em&gt;The Future&lt;/em&gt; didn’t sound as rockingly big and powerful as on the 75t buds, which feel like they still carry more weight and oomph in their sound signature at the cost of accuracy. Unsurprisingly, Jabra is also outdone by the upper echelon of earbuds like the Sony 1000XM4s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="If2qYp"&gt;Jabra still has room for improvement when it comes to active noise cancellation, however. At their price point, the 7 Pros disappoint in this category and don’t get rid of as much background noise as I expected. The company says its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Elite 85t earbuds&lt;/a&gt; continue to offer the best ANC performance of the whole lineup. But the HearThrough transparency mode also trails the AirPods Pro and Bose with a less natural sound&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RwqFnBFT1IIOOsoaSXK_f9k4dDw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055332/IMG_0117_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds have round ear tips instead of the oval-shaped tips from the Elite 85t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VcEn4sG65yezWwXSHZf6f7sNK3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055334/IMG_0118_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The button on each earbud is easy to find and click with your finger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WMOslU"&gt;Ears are all different, so I can’t ding Jabra too badly for these not being perfect for me. An XL set of ear tips would’ve helped, though. If you’ve got smaller ears and found the company’s older buds uncomfortable or bulky, these might be an improvement and not the regression they’ve been in my case. Jabra says it used data from 62,000 ear scans to design the earbuds’ shape and gel tips, but even after all that, the fit is just off for me. Maybe aftermarket tips can help. Either way, I’m glad Jabra has gone back to round ear tips instead of the oval-shaped tips from the Elite 85t buds that don’t always stay in my ears well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="0zinMQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10896386"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q9uPIf"&gt;It’s always worth highlighting how many features Jabra crams into the earbuds’ companion smartphone app on Android and iOS. You get extensive EQ customization, settings, remappable controls, an audio test to tailor the sound profile to your hearing, and extras like soundscapes (white noise, thunderstorm, etc.) meant to help you relax. You can also set up different moments for the various points of your day with personalized levels of noise cancellation and transparency for each environment. It’s about as full-featured as earbud apps get. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rUWd0u"&gt;One nice advancement with Jabra’s latest Elite buds is that you can now use either one independently; it used to be that only the right earbud could be used by itself, but now you’re free to use the left one independently, too. Battery life is rated at up to eight hours of straight music playback and 30 including case recharges. Those are both only slight improvements from the 7.5 hours and 28 hours that Jabra said the Elite 75t earbuds could achieve. The dust and water resistance rating has also gone up from IP55 to IP57.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ofsVp87xLNgf2FCslThwICPktLw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055354/IMG_0116_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new earbuds have a sleeker design than Jabra’s past efforts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f7mRkg"&gt;From Jabra’s perspective, the standout feature of the Elite 7 Pros — and what separates them from the Active model — is voice call performance. The company has reworked its algorithms to do a better job at canceling wind and other disruptive sounds, and it also added bone conduction tech to the mix. This makes the voice pickup sensors automatically activate when they sense vibrations in your jawbone. These tweaks have resulted in excellent voice quality for both phone calls and Zoom or Microsoft Teams conferencing that ranks among the best next to Apple’s AirPods. It’s especially impressive outside, where wind is effectively hushed. If multipoint does actually come along in January, these might well become the best option for multitasking between work and your music playlists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GrEGVl"&gt;But in their current state, Jabra’s Elite 7 Pro earbuds aren’t an essential upgrade compared to the 75t, which have way more thump to their sound and can already handle multipoint Bluetooth connections. In my own case, the older buds also fit much better, but &lt;a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/headphone-reviews/jabra-elite-7-pro-review/"&gt;other reviews&lt;/a&gt; (including from early buyers) suggest that the 7 Pros are working just fine for many ears out there. Jabra has made legitimate improvements to voice calling, so if that’s an important factor for you, they’re worth a look. But in any case, I’d wait until January before buying to make sure Jabra comes through on its promise of adding multipoint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="K9aY9r"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22811826/jabra-elite-7-pro-earbuds-review-features-multipoint"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22811826/jabra-elite-7-pro-earbuds-review-features-multipoint</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:08:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:08:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>CVS Pharmacy’s Spoken Rx prescription labels are now available at all locations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Prescription medication frames the CVS Corp. logo in this photo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ekOW8edNw6Lv2txZYZjJTgTmkas=/0x57:3333x2279/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214893/94603799.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;All CVS Pharmacy locations in the US now offer Spoken Rx prescription labels for blind and vision-impaired patients.  | Photo by Victoria Arocho/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Up45ew"&gt;CVS Pharmacy is expanding its Spoken Rx audio prescription labels to be available in all its pharmacies, after a trial run last year. The feature, developed as part of a collaboration with the American Council of the Blind, is part of the CVS Pharmacy mobile app and can read prescription information — like dosage and directions — aloud in English or Spanish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4xNpa"&gt;To use the spoken labels, CVS Pharmacy patients register for a CVS account, download the smartphone app, and enroll in Spoken Rx. The patient’s future prescription labels will then be tagged with an RFID label. The enrollment process can be done over the phone or in person at a CVS pharmacy. When the patient holds the prescription bottle four inches from their smartphone, the app scans the prescription bottle’s RFID label and reads out the information. CVS also has options for Braille and large-print labels on prescription bottles available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1f4P8t9KLeVqwVInUgoeS0JYTIY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055428/spoken_rx_cvs.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CVS&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The CVS Pharmacy app includes Spoken Rx, which lets users hear their prescription labels read aloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tJuogY"&gt;Matt Blanchette, manager of retail communications for CVS Pharmacy said for those who don’t have a smartphone, CVS can provide a separate, standalone speaker device on request, at no cost to the patient. The Spoken Rx app only reads prescription labels from CVS Pharmacy, and Blanchette said there are no plans to expand the feature to include labels from other pharmacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sQ6619"&gt;Eric Bridges, executive director of the American Council of the Blind, called the feature a positive step. “Spoken Rx allows for a greater level of privacy, safety and independence for blind and visually impaired customers,” Bridges said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncNtOS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809859/cvs-pharmacy-spoken-rx-prescription-labels-blind-vision-impaired-accessibility"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809859/cvs-pharmacy-spoken-rx-prescription-labels-blind-vision-impaired-accessibility</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit is adding new real-time features, including a live upvote count</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6CdqdUqnnAkKEYafS_Sk3N6A8WE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214806/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Wsgsdk"&gt;Reddit is introducing some big changes on Wednesday by adding new real-time features. Perhaps the biggest update is that the number of upvotes, downvotes, and comments will go up or down as they happen. That could give you a more accurate idea of the popularity of a post as you’re reading it, but I could also see people hitting an upvote or downvote in response to seeing others do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zt9G1r"&gt;Another change is that Reddit will show the number of people reading a post when there are five or more people looking at it. Reddit won’t just show who’s reading, though; it’s also introducing a typing indicator that will pop up when two or more users are typing a comment. And when new top-level comments come in, Reddit will show a new pill-shaped notification. When you tap that notification, the comments on a post will be sorted by new so you can view what’s been added most recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDoLIO"&gt;You can get an idea of how the new features work in this GIF:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oq5hW7l85SwXFoxetlBvorLMvNY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053930/ezgif_6_f30ba41cd9a7.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U0tcRt"&gt;The new features are rolling out globally across desktop and mobile starting Wednesday, but they’ll only be available on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/2/17190244/reddit-redesign-begins-rolling-out"&gt;newer Reddit design&lt;/a&gt;. If you use old Reddit, you won’t have access to them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810850/reddit-real-time-live-upvote-reading-typing-indicator-comment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810850/reddit-real-time-live-upvote-reading-typing-indicator-comment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
