<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-22T14:34:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T14:34:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T14:34:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook offered to license its network and code to avoid antitrust action</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/elpqpBnAy8HXGF3XTYLl5PhDsVU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567988/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hLrADP"&gt;In the wake of the groundbreaking Federal Trade Commission lawsuit against Facebook, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/22/facebook-antitrust-lobbying-settlement/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; is reporting&lt;/a&gt; new details of the company’s negotiations with regulators in the run-up to the case, including an unusual offer to license its code and network to competitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NBIP75"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting, Facebook was willing to significantly alter its business practices in order to avoid litigation, including one measure “allow[ing] another firm or developer to license access to its powerful code — and its users’ intricate web of relationships — so that they could more easily create their own version of a social network.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIY6dX"&gt;Ultimately, the FTC declined Facebook’s offer, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;filing an antitrust complaint&lt;/a&gt; against the company on December 9th. The lawsuit alleges that Facebook used its platform power to stifle competitors, and it seeks to unwind the acquisitions of WhatsApp and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gxeDd"&gt;It’s not clear what a platform-licensing arrangement would look like in practice, but it’s a tantalizing proposition for some tech reformers, particularly thinkers like &lt;a href="https://www.publicknowledge.org/assets/uploads/documents/Case_for_the_Digital_Platform_Act_Harold_Feld_2019.pdf"&gt;Harold Feld&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/08/tim-wu-interview-internet-classic-party-went-sour-attention-merchants"&gt;Tim Wu&lt;/a&gt; who have looked for ways to make it easier for users to switch platforms. This kind of licensing deal would allow upstarts like TikTok to buy access to many of Facebook’s most powerful tools — but it’s unclear whether it would produce meaningful competition for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YFOd9n"&gt;Facebook is also facing new scrutiny over an alleged deal with Google to coordinate ad networks. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-facebook-agreed-to-team-up-against-possible-antitrust-action-draft-lawsuit-says-11608612219"&gt;A new report from &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Monday night expanded on details of an ad network arrangement between the two companies, as detailed in a case brought against Google by the Texas attorney general. According to the complaint, the arrangement guaranteed Facebook would win a particular percentage of bids on the company’s auction site, potentially constituting collusion between the two companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49kqbU"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting, the deal was explicitly promoted by Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg who told CEO Mark Zuckerberg the arrangement was “a big deal strategically.” Facebook executives were also given detailed and explicit instructions on how to avoid antitrust infractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tC0xlr"&gt;Both companies deny the allegation, although much of the state’s evidence has yet to be presented. “AG Paxton’s ad tech claims are inaccurate,” a Google representative told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We don’t manipulate the auction and Facebook’s participation in Open Bidding doesn’t prevent the company from participating in header bidding or any other similar auction.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195259/facebook-code-license-ftc-antitrust-google-deal-sandberg"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195259/facebook-code-license-ftc-antitrust-google-deal-sandberg</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T14:19:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T14:19:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watch Nicolas Cage shout expletives in History of Swear Words trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nicolas Cage reading a book about swearing" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mEnD7reXexsS7Q87iF-FZ2oEwss=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567053/AAAABYWdj2lusZ4ZYb3V7kXS9jUgMKPh5ukTVTxnLgepEjDsv83xu1bkHhJ_lhD1C_2wymfEFHvL5j_7MN_x4bFGPglr7JA6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ePzJM3"&gt;If you’ve ever wondered how profanity actually became profane, Nicolas Cage is here to help you out. The actor is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zySHepF04c&amp;amp;t=45s"&gt;no stranger to swearing&lt;/a&gt;, but in Netflix’s upcoming show &lt;em&gt;History of Swear Words &lt;/em&gt;he’ll be doing it in a more educational way. Though, if the trailer’s indicative of what the show is going to be like, it’ll still be&lt;em&gt; very&lt;/em&gt; entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QzUPZv"&gt;It opens with Cage standing up and just screaming “fuck,” likely a reference to him doing pretty much &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ve88BGz0nPc"&gt;the exact same thing&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Deadfall&lt;/em&gt;. It only gets better from there, explaining the myth that the expletive is an acronym (standing for Fornication Under Consent of the King), and delving into how swear words are understood by the people using and hearing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="N7g8Fg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The show will include celebrity interviews and, of course, a lot of swearing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QLyUKd"&gt;As someone who’s always been interested in how regular words came to be (TED-Ed has a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWbu2Kh1S6Q&amp;amp;list=PLJicmE8fK0EjR_iVOzgiJfvRuDPqKlPQt"&gt;great series called &lt;em&gt;Mysteries of Vernacular&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;if that’s an interest you share), it’s exciting to see a bigger production that goes into the etymology and social implications of swearing. Especially since it seems like it will also be going into the backlash to swearing — the trailer includes a part talking about those Parental Advisory stickers from back when CDs were a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uyj8tl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;History of Swear Words&lt;/em&gt; isn’t the only production Nicolas Cage has been involved with recently — if you can think back to the beginning of this decade-long year, you may remember Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21202720/tiger-king-documentary-review-netflix-joe-exotic"&gt;taking the internet by storm&lt;/a&gt;. Well, there’s going to be a scripted dramatized adaptation of it coming to Amazon, and &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/amazon-lands-nicolas-cage-led-joe-exotic-drama"&gt;of course Cage will be playing Joe Exotic&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment, it’s unclear when that will be coming out, but I don’t think it’s the kind of show that will fly under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4sZMN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;History of Swear Words&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;though&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; is coming to Netflix on January 5th. It &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/nicolas-cage-history-of-swear-words-netflix-1234849387/"&gt;will be six episodes long&lt;/a&gt; and include Cage interviewing various celebrities and etymologists (people who study words), including Open Mike Eagle, Nick Offerman, and Sarah Silverman. It will also, of course, include a lot of swearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vk1zsl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original version of this story claimed that the trailer implied the word “fuck” is an acronym, when the scene is in fact debunking the myth. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195341/nicholas-cage-history-of-swear-words-netflix-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195341/nicholas-cage-history-of-swear-words-netflix-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T14:06:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T14:06:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>New ‘felony streaming’ measure is aimed at piracy services, not Twitch streamers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-POLITICS-HEARING-BANKING" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T1NHKOnCEC6e4pejDMhXKMi2j7Y=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567803/1229890894.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by AL DRAGO/POOL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7gXrIH"&gt;Yes, Congress approved a new bill Monday that would classify illegal streaming as a felony offense, but the feds won’t be going after your favorite Twitch streamers, YouTubers, or their subscribers. They’re more interested in services dedicated to streaming pirated content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ir5jYQ"&gt;Monday night, Congress approved &lt;a href="https://t.co/Tot32uXo3a?amp=1"&gt;an over $2 trillion government&lt;/a&gt; spending and coronavirus relief package that included a handful of controversial copyright and trademark measures. A felony streaming bill, authored by Sen. Thom Tillis (R-NC), was included as part of that massive package. The news circulated all across the internet; in a &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr-esq/the-covid-19-stimulus-bill-would-make-illegal-streaming-a-felony"&gt;poorly headlined &lt;em&gt;Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;article, tweets, and YouTube videos. Quickly, content creators and their fans grew increasingly concerned that the bill could threaten their livelihoods or their favorite means of entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEn8JQ"&gt;But according to a press release from Tillis’ office and statements made by tech advocacy groups like Public Knowledge, streamers and their fans have no cause for alarm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79Uq7E"&gt;“As a general matter, we do not see the need for further criminal penalties for copyright infringement,” Meredith Rose, senior policy counsel at Public Knowledge, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.publicknowledge.org/press-release/public-knowledge-responds-to-senator-tillis-felony-streaming-copyright-proposal/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month. “However, this bill is narrowly tailored and avoids criminalizing users, who may do nothing more than click on a link, or upload a file. It also does not criminalize streamers who may include unlicensed works as part of their streams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xfmXR6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It also does not criminalize streamers who may include unlicensed works as part of their streams”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CafsyX"&gt;The text of the bill affirms this reading. On its fourth page, &lt;a href="https://www.tillis.senate.gov/2020/12/bipartisan-legislation-led-by-tillis-and-leahy-to-fight-illegal-streaming-by-criminal-organizations-to-be-signed-into-law"&gt;the bill outlines&lt;/a&gt; what would qualify as felony behavior under the law. Currently, streaming unlicensed content is a misdemeanor offense. Previously, organizations like the NFL would sue sites like NFLBite that recast games, but if approved, the Tillis measures would open the door for the FBI to pursue those website owners under threat of prison time. But while the penalties and enforcement are both stepping up, the bill wouldn’t change what’s legal and what’s not. More importantly, there’s nothing in the text of the bill that suggests platforms’ moderation of everyday copyright violations would need to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cjiikh"&gt;Here’s &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/covid-relief-bill-still-includes-felony-streaming-act-1845929782"&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt; from Tillis’ office describing the purpose of the legislation: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="FghP3u"&gt;The Protecting Lawful Streaming Act will apply only to commercial, for-profit streaming piracy services. The law will not sweep in normal practices by online service providers, good faith business disputes, noncommercial activities, or in any way impact individuals who access pirated streams or unwittingly stream unauthorized copies of copyrighted works. Individuals who might use pirate streaming services will not be affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fqIRyY"&gt;Still, it’s totally understandable that YouTubers and streamers would freak out about a bill whose final text was released only days before it was approved. Social video platforms haven’t done the best job in the past with copyright, Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) claims, and strikes. YouTube’s algorithm frequently flags content as violating copyright even when it doesn’t. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/26/21037763/youtube-copyright-claim-studios-update-automatic-trim-tool-studios"&gt;For a long time&lt;/a&gt;, copyright owners like Universal were able to claim videos without expressly stating where the copyrighted material appeared in the content. Copyright is messy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iog8Af"&gt;On December 16th, Twitch addressed this proposal in its town hall, saying that the company did not expect the bill to affect its platform or its users. YouTube did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3qy95f"&gt;That doesn’t mean copyright activists can rest easy. The multitrillion-dollar package did include a copyright measure that civil liberties activists fear could have dramatic consequences. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Tot32uXo3a?amp=1"&gt;The CASE Act&lt;/a&gt; was also approved in the package and would create a quasi-judicial copyright claims court within the Copyright Office. Copyright holders could be awarded up to $30,000 in damages if they find their creative work being shared online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Um2tAb"&gt;There’s also more bad copyright news coming from Sen. Tillis in the next congressional term. The senator is planning to offer up additional copyright changes next year that have already spooked the tech and creative industries. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BrendanBordelon/status/1341399864287096839?s=20"&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday that Tillis has been circulating a draft proposal of a bill that would completely reform the DMCA. The bill would include a “&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/01/notice-and-stay-down-really-filter-everything"&gt;notice-and-staydown&lt;/a&gt;” provision that could make copyright bots, like YouTube’s Content ID, stricter. &lt;em&gt;National Journal&lt;/em&gt; said that Tillis’ office would limit this provision to “complete or near-complete works” and would focus on larger enterprises rather than small platforms or creators. Still, current copyright-striking tech has been hit-or-miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlX3NZ"&gt;“This proposal [the incoming DMCA reform] would result in massive legal uncertainties for small businesses, startups and new creators; hurt competition and consumer choice for the next generation of platforms like TikTok and Parler; and lead to significant overblocking of everyday content on the platforms that Americans use every day to work, communicate and have fun,” said Joshua Lamel, executive director of the Re:Create Coalition, in a &lt;a href="https://www.recreatecoalition.org/press_release/recreate-statement-on-proposal-to-undo-the-dmca-would-fundamentally-end-online-creativity-as-we-know-it/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tuPIb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvCTCb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195658/felony-streaming-tillis-youtube-twitch-content-creator-copyright-dmca"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195658/felony-streaming-tillis-youtube-twitch-content-creator-copyright-dmca</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T13:57:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T13:57:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>The stimulus bill will phase out ‘super’ greenhouse gases</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A worker on a rooftop installing air conditioning at a hotel on Ocean Drive" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PPF-Ih0B-K_JRFMOZMrCVA-zFM8=/0x0:3800x2533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567675/814536358.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A worker on a rooftop installing air conditioning at a hotel. | Photo by: Jeffrey Greenberg/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tUnlYb"&gt;Congress’s $900 billion stimulus bill includes some unexpected climate provisions, including new restrictions that will change the way Americans cool their homes and refrigerate their groceries. The new measures will phase out hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs) used in air conditioning and refrigeration, “super” greenhouse gases that are thousands of times more potent than carbon dioxide in their climate impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5wpg9"&gt;The goal of the provision is to cut the production and import of HFCs by 85 percent by 2035. Under the new provision, that goal will be federal policy and the EPA will have the power to implement new restrictions on manufacturers and importers in order to meet it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pPpCXC"&gt;Those measures will bring the US in line with an important climate agreement that it had previously refused to ratify, the Kigali amendment to the Montreal Protocol. With the US on board, the phasing out of HFCs is expected to help the world avoid an additional half a degree Celsius of warming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="L9qBBn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“One of the most significant pieces of climate legislation”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bN3IOu"&gt;Preventing half a degree of warming makes a huge difference for the planet’s future. The world has heated up by just over one degree Celsius since the preindustrial era, which has already led to more devastating &lt;a href="https://www.gfdl.noaa.gov/global-warming-and-hurricanes/"&gt;hurricanes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2912/satellite-data-record-shows-climate-changes-impact-on-fires/"&gt;wildfires&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/climateandhealth/pubs/climatechangeandextremeheatevents.pdf"&gt;heat waves&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why policymakers and environmental groups have praised the relief package as one of the most important steps the US has taken to date in combating climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qihqj4"&gt;“This is one of the most significant pieces of climate legislation that Congress has passed in its history,” Andrew Steer, president and CEO of the nonprofit World Resources Institute, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.wri.org/news/2020/12/statement-congress-passes-major-stimulus-package-significant-provisions-climate-change"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. “Much more needs to be done, but this legislation should put wind in the sails of the incoming Biden-Harris administration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2YpdhO"&gt;Rising temperatures have created a conundrum for city planners concerned about climate change. Recent urban development has happened alongside hotter weather, especially in the Global South — and that’s created &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/14/16290934/india-air-conditioner-cooler-design-climate-change-cept-symphony"&gt;greater reliance on air conditioning&lt;/a&gt;. More air conditioning has come with more planet-heating HFCs that add to the climate crisis. It’s a vicious cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtjFy4"&gt;“The need for more energy efficient air conditioning is so vital to the future of both emissions [and] the reality of what we’re building,” says Ian Hamilton, an associate professor at the University College London, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22178481/buildings-greenhouse-gas-emissions-climate-change-united-nations-report"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week&lt;/a&gt;. “Those lovely, great big glassy towers in hot parts of the world rely so heavily on air conditioning for them to be comfortable, livable.” Hamilton was the lead coordinating author of a recently published &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22178481/buildings-greenhouse-gas-emissions-climate-change-united-nations-report"&gt;UN report&lt;/a&gt; that showed that emissions from buildings reached a record high in 2019, in part because of air conditioning units that suck up a lot of power and leak HFCs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Lmzp7x"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is a big deal for our economy and our planet.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4HMBFQ"&gt;Luckily, there are &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/clima/policies/f-gas/alternatives_en"&gt;alternatives&lt;/a&gt; to HFCs that aren’t as bad for the planet. The industries that make these alternatives already employ 593,000 US workers, according to Senator Tom Carper (D-DE). The new mandate to phase out HFCs could create 150,000 more jobs in the US and increase American manufacturing by $39 billion over seven years, his office says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uv4gyr"&gt;“This is a big deal for our economy and our planet,” Carper said in an emailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXjQFp"&gt;The relief package also includes about $35 billion for clean energy, including $4 billion in research and development funding for wind, solar, geothermal, and hydropower. There’s also $6 billion earmarked for emerging technologies that can draw down carbon dioxide emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KBmY4"&gt;Additionally, the bill will extend important tax credits for renewables and carbon capture technologies, including a tax credit for power plants and other polluting facilities that find ways to capture and store their planet-heating emissions. There’s similarly an extension of production and investment tax credits for solar and wind. President Donald Trump is expected to sign the bill today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V8B8dG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7sVB5c"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195522/stimulus-bill-phase-out-hfcs-super-greenhouse-gas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195522/stimulus-bill-phase-out-hfcs-super-greenhouse-gas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T13:25:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T13:25:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Driving the XC40 Recharge, Volvo’s first electric crossover with native Android Auto</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h6alNtYuzFbe55L1Xe_mHs5YZyo=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567373/ahawkins_201221_4352_6514.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Volvo’s first EV is an impressive blend of Swedish ingenuity and electric performance&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="4rUWG8"&gt;There’s been an avalanche of new electric vehicles announced in the past year and a half, ranging from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429319/lucid-motors-air-electric-sedan-price-specs-range-reveal"&gt;luxurious&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/5/21502032/volkswagen-id4-electric-suv-first-drive-vw"&gt;practical&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;garish&lt;/a&gt;. So you’d be forgiven if you forgot about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/16/20915841/volvo-xc40-recharge-electric-suv-specs-miles-range-reveal"&gt;Volvo XC40 Recharge&lt;/a&gt;, a great compact SUV with a terrible name. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vizyM6"&gt;I won’t judge Volvo too harshly for its name choice. The Swedish automaker wanted to convey the simple message that this was a familiar vehicle with a new powertrain. And “XC40 Recharge” certainly gets that point across. That said, it’s an uninspiring name for what is arguably a fantastic EV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="rBLTxs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;an uninspiring name for what is arguably a fantastic EV&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k0fzF4"&gt;I got a chance to drive Volvo’s first all-electric vehicle around northwestern New Jersey for around two hours on a recent Friday. The roads were freshly plowed, the sky was a cloudless blue, and the XC40 Recharge was an able and attractive partner for my jaunt through the snowy woods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8t3jfK"&gt;I already had an inkling of what to expect with the XC40 Recharge, having driven its sister EV, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;the Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt;, earlier in the year. Like the Polestar 2, the XC40 Recharge is built on Volvo’s Compact Modular Architecture (CMA), an advanced vehicle platform co-developed within the Geely Group, Volvo’s parent company, which already powers the plug-in hybrid version of the XC40. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLK4EK"&gt;The XC40 Recharge also comes with Android Automotive, the native version of Google’s Android Auto operating system. This voice-activated system can control everything from navigation (“Hey Google, take me home”) to music (“Hey Google, play some Swedish death metal”) to heating and air conditioning (“Hey Google, turn on my seat warmer”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FM0UczG6kXBbHHJvuKfz8WefiBc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22189074/ahawkins_201221_4352_6471.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Q8E1sVY4FcdwuQorla8FoFVZdE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22189077/ahawkins_201221_4352_6480.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pm8wKL"&gt;Having already driven the Polestar 2, I was familiar with Android Automotive. But it was no less revelatory than the first time. There’s something immensely satisfying about using my voice to control all the in-car minutiae rather than fumble around on a touchscreen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIRKnF"&gt;It’s also uniquely tailored to running the infotainment system in an electric vehicle. When you ask Google to navigate you to a certain location, the Android-powered operating system will take into account your battery levels and incorporate charging stations that are available along the way. That should go a long way toward quelling any range anxiety you may have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="J7bCU9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s something immensely satisfying about using my voice to control all the in-car minutiae&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9tg6bB"&gt;From the outside, the XC40 Recharge looks (surprise!) exactly like the gas-powered XC40, but with a smooth grille and no tailpipes. There are familiar touches, like the “Thor’s hammer” front headlights that are common across Volvo’s lineup. But the XC40 Recharge is delightfully nondescript. It looks like a typical Volvo with a few futuristic flourishes. I received no second glances from passersby and was able to blend into my environment, which typically isn’t the case with a new EV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MM0Tz2"&gt;The XC40 Recharge has a key — a chunky-looking fob that fortunately is immediately made irrelevant because this is a car that can be turned on using only your phone. Once seated, you only need to close the door, press the brake pedal, and click the gear shift to the desired direction in order to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSVQfv"&gt;The 400-volt battery, made by South Korea’s LG Chem and located in the floor of the vehicle, has the capacity of 78kWh (75kWh of which is usable) — on par with other electric crossovers like the Tesla Model Y and the Volkswagen ID 4. But the XC40 Recharge will only get a little more than 200 miles of range per charge, which is significantly less than those other compact SUV EVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhDPcX"&gt;I didn’t have enough time with the car to test out the range nor the charging experience, but Volvo says drivers can expect to get a lot of power pumped back into the battery thanks to the XC40 Recharge’s regenerative brakes, especially while using one-pedal driving. The battery charges to 80 percent of its capacity in 40 minutes on a DC fast-charger system, the automaker claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p9w564eEFNYSTiO75nBgXdsZcbI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22189079/ahawkins_201221_4352_6489.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r8-H4VurqgRLRYRDOHG87VHYqG4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22189078/ahawkins_201221_4352_6484.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hJlohv"&gt;It’s surprisingly sporty for a compact SUV. The two 150kW motors in the front and rear axle put out 402 horsepower, 486 foot-pounds, and 330 Newton-meters of torque, giving the XC40 Recharge that familiar zippiness down any straightaway. It will do 0 to 60mph in 4.7 seconds, a couple of tenths slower than the Polestar 2. I actually found the acceleration to be more impressive than the 333 hp &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175017/ford-mustang-mach-e-electric-suv-first-drive-specs-review"&gt;Ford Mustang Mach-E&lt;/a&gt;, which I had the chance to drive only a few days prior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrwumH"&gt;What a world to live in, where an electric Volvo somehow feels more powerful than an EV named after Ford’s iconic pony car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0cR43"&gt;Unlike the Mach-E, though, Volvo only has one driving mode, which speaks to the commitment to simplicity. If one-pedal driving isn’t to your liking, you can toggle through a couple of screens to turn it off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xfUyfA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;What a world to live in, where an electric Volvo somehow feels more powerful than an EV named after Ford’s iconic pony car!&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xd6YbT"&gt;Inside, the 12.3-inch digital instrument cluster behind the steering wheel comes in three modes, including a minimalist “calm” mode with only crucial information, “navi” for full-screen maps and navigation, and “car centric” for help using the car’s driver assist function. The ability to view full-screen maps in the “navi” setting is a definite upgrade over previous Volvo vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UJzvMr"&gt;I appreciated Volvo’s decision to eschew the oversized main touchscreen in favor of a more modest 9.3-inch display. The screen is divided into four quadrants, or “tiles,” which is similar to other Volvos running the automaker’s Sensus operating system. The difference here is the XC40 Recharge’s display is powered internally by Android.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w6BIgf"&gt;Again, shouts to Volvo for having the prescience to team up with Google for its first electric vehicles. The inclusion of Android Automotive gives the XC40 Recharge a definite advantage over other electric crossovers in its price range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D46pVKE1aNNTbAr4tMHTpc0lcXw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22189082/ahawkins_201221_4352_6522.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="orIXST"&gt;Not only is it easy to use, but it should reduce driver distraction as well. Being able to toggle between the directions, temperature, and Spotify while keeping my eyes on a road made me a better driver and reduced the likelihood that I’d swerve or let my attention wander. Smartphones and digital infotainment systems that invite a lot of scrolling or tapping are obvious distractions, and tech companies need to come up with better ways to mitigate that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YMaiPC"&gt;It’s also demonstrably better than non-native Android Auto, which just mirrors your smartphone’s display on the main infotainment screen. &lt;a href="https://www.iamroadsmart.com/campaign-pages/end-customer-campaigns/infotainment"&gt;A recent study&lt;/a&gt; found that despite their simplified controls, drivers who are using Android Auto to select music are more distracted than drivers under the influence of marijuana or alcohol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="eqtgl7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s an extension of Volvo’s reputation for safety&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2vbySg"&gt;It’s an extension of Volvo’s reputation for safety, which encompasses other aspects of the XC40 Recharge’s design. The battery pack, for example, is encased in a neon orange aluminum case that Volvo is calling “a safety cage.” Embedded in the middle of the car’s body, the safety cage creates a built-in crumple zone around the battery. Leave it to Volvo to put as much thought into keeping passengers safe as it does its drivetrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ymwEfe"&gt;Volvo kicked off production of the XC40 Recharge in October, almost a full year after the vehicle was first introduced, and customers will start taking delivery before the end of the year. Volvo’s suggested price is $53,990 (not including the $7,500 federal tax credit), which isn’t cheap, but feels right for the XC40 Recharge’s impressive blend of Swedish ingenuity, crossover utility, and electric performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="4HMQRA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195499/volvo-xc40-recharge-ev-suv-first-drive-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195499/volvo-xc40-recharge-ev-suv-first-drive-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T13:06:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T13:06:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>GameStop will reportedly accept Cyberpunk 2077 returns, even if you’ve opened the game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zE5JUuAHYKPvpTJ88MBTYBedKdQ=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567225/Cyberpunk2077_Power_in_your_hands_RGB_en.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mphfBE"&gt;GameStop reportedly sent a memo to employees telling them to accept returns of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, even in the event the physical game box has already been opened, according &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/source-gamestop-now-accepting-returns-of-defective-c-1845930739"&gt;to &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/patrickklepek/status/1341134244437962753"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; reporter Patrick Klepek&lt;/a&gt;. GameStop’s &lt;a href="https://care.gamestop.com/store-return-policy"&gt;return policy&lt;/a&gt; typically doesn’t let you return opened games, but GameStop seems to be making an exception for &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; after its buggy launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kR4sbw"&gt;You can return PlayStation 4 and Xbox One versions of game within 30 days of purchase to get a refund, reports &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;. GameStop didn’t reply to a request for comment, but employees at GameStops in Chicago and Houston confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; by phone that their stores were accepting returns of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g310zr"&gt;Other retailers have also offered refunds of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. Best Buy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189238/best-buy-cyberpunk-2077-returns-cd-projekt-red-refund-xbox-one-ps4"&gt;accepted physical returns&lt;/a&gt; of the game until December 21st, and the game’s developer, CD Projekt Red, also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189322/cyberpunk-2077-refund-cd-projekt-red-ps4-xbox-one"&gt;promised refunds&lt;/a&gt; for retail copies of the game “out of our own pocket if necessary” if players submitted a refund request by December 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rcnHmE"&gt;Sony is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;offering refunds&lt;/a&gt; of the digital version of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; bought through the PlayStation Store, and it has even taken the extraordinary step of delisting it “until further notice.” Microsoft is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189059/microsoft-cyberpunk-2077-refunds-xbox-microsoft-store"&gt;offering refunds&lt;/a&gt; of digital copies of the game from the Microsoft Store, though players can still buy it. However, there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189918/cyberpunk-2077-microsoft-store-listing-warning-label"&gt;is a warning&lt;/a&gt; on the game’s listing noting that players “may experience performance issues” on Xbox One until the game is updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dhIGHL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Best Buy is accepting Cyberpunk 2077 returns through December 21st, even if you played it","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189238/best-buy-cyberpunk-2077-returns-cd-projekt-red-refund-xbox-one-ps4"},{"title":"CD Projekt Red promises Cyberpunk 2077 refunds ‘out of our own pocket if necessary’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189322/cyberpunk-2077-refund-cd-projekt-red-ps4-xbox-one"},{"title":"Sony is pulling Cyberpunk 2077 from the PlayStation Store and offering full refunds","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"},{"title":"Microsoft offers Cyberpunk 2077 refunds for all digital sales, but it’s not pulling the game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189059/microsoft-cyberpunk-2077-refunds-xbox-microsoft-store"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195420/gamestop-cyberpunk-2077-returns-even-if-opened"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195420/gamestop-cyberpunk-2077-returns-even-if-opened</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T12:47:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T12:47:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>‘Toss a Coin to your Witcher’ is even catchier broken down into different languages </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Witcher" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NsZ4hChfh5X4nwO4y5oCcB0cKD4=/0x3:6016x4014/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68567072/GRADED_Witcher_101_Unit_04997_RT.f3gcqwb7f.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="k6v6rS"&gt;Remember this time last year, when everyday didn’t bring with it a new horror and people just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21026537/the-witcher-netflix-review-henry-cavill"&gt;wanted to talk about &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Well, now a new video from Netflix is trying to bring back some of that energy, piecing together lyrics from the show’s breakout song, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/12/30/21042791/netflix-toss-a-coin-to-your-witcher-song-hit-streaming-spotify-apple-music-why"&gt;“Toss a Coin to your Witcher,”&lt;/a&gt; all sung in different languages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c7SqkW"&gt;In the video, the song jumps between languages, starting with English before leading into Polish, Turkish, Spanish, Portuguese, German, and more. It’s incredibly charming, with all the different Jaskiers coming together to remind various townspeople and locals to toss a coin to their Witcher. It’s the holiday season; not tipping at least 20 percent, especially in areas with heavy snowfall and grotesque monsters that demand a Witcher to slay them, is simply unacceptable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajH5mo"&gt;Look, I’m a sucker for these types of videos. Remember when Disney released a version of “Into the Unknown” from &lt;em&gt;Frozen 2 &lt;/em&gt;that &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/12/13/21020823/frozen-2-into-the-unknown-languages-multilingual-versions"&gt;consisted of 29 different languages&lt;/a&gt;? So much better than the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jp-CVYGEsjg"&gt;Panic! At The Disco cover&lt;/a&gt; (which I, unfortunately, also loved because I’m a sucker for a pop punk band that inspires nostalgia). Disney also brought a number of different actresses to the 2020 Oscars to perform “Into the Unknown” &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWtEPuP1YH4"&gt;alongside star Idina Menzel&lt;/a&gt; in their own languages, and it was wonderful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="biwUhb"&gt;There is one warning I should include, though: if you listen to the version of “Toss a Coin to your Witcher” above, be prepared to have it stuck in your head all day. I’m currently listening to my favorite version of the song that was released last December! I’ll share it below as a holiday treat for us all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="W7NKWE"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PDtu2r8mYIw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZB3MiY"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195317/witcher-toss-a-coin-song-languages-netflix-henry-cavill"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195317/witcher-toss-a-coin-song-languages-netflix-henry-cavill</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T12:30:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T12:30:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Let Tree.fm give you a hug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Winter at Rosa Khutor mountain resort in Russia" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4n8QucQZ9LuCQTL5DEIU8ih_JOw=/0x0:4939x3293/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68566862/1230260630.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dmitry Feoktistov / TASS via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8c578n"&gt;“Trees have a curious relationship to the subject of the present moment,” &lt;a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/pilgrim-at-tinker-creek-annie-dillard?variant=32129313832994"&gt;she said&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hj32q1"&gt;So I gaze on the present,&lt;br&gt;which is neither here nor there,&lt;br&gt;watching time scatter in the breeze,&lt;br&gt;propagating nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kwbijf"&gt;But in the forest, this is hope.&lt;br&gt;I close my eyes to hear the birds&lt;br&gt;who keep time with the trees:&lt;br&gt;canaries in the eternal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5rAm1t"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tree.fm/"&gt;Join me and listen?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22195383/tree-fm-forest-radio"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22195383/tree-fm-forest-radio</id>
    <author>
      <name>T.C. Sottek</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T11:25:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T11:25:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can now play Microsoft’s Flight Simulator in VR</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Microsoft Flight Simulator" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/olH1WtD2ptychuiWURMZH1WjXM4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68566403/DayandNight.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8y3Wiw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; has always been about making you feel like a pilot, but you’ve never been able to experience it in VR — until today. &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/12/22/microsoft-flight-simulator-virtual-reality-update-available-now/"&gt;With today’s free update&lt;/a&gt;, Asobo Studio has added support for &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-pc-vr-release-date-quest-2-link/"&gt;OpenXR-compatible headsets&lt;/a&gt;, which include Windows Mixed Reality headsets as well as the Valve Index, HTC Vive, and the Oculus Rift and Oculus Quest (if you use &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/oculus-link-usb-2-0-tether-quest-charging-cable/"&gt;a Link cable&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z6C8NU"&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/07/30/microsoft-flight-simulator-steam-track-ir-and-vr-support/"&gt;originally announced&lt;/a&gt; that the VR feature would be coming first to the HP Reverb G2. This latest update includes support for most Windows Mixed Reality headsets, Oculus, Valve, and HTC headsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLpIGR"&gt;Before, if you wanted to feel like you were &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; in an airplane while playing &lt;em&gt;Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;, it would take a lot of computer monitors and some carpentry skills. Even then, you could only make your surroundings look like the cockpit of a single model of airplane. Now all you’ll need is a VR headset — oh, and a powerful computer to run it at a resolution that’s passable for screens an inch from your eyes. When Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21499518/microsoft-flight-simulator-vr-closed-open-beta-test-sign-up"&gt;ran a beta test of the feature&lt;/a&gt;, an i5-8400 or Ryzen 5 1500X paired with a GTX 1080 &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-vr-support-closed-beta/"&gt;were listed as the &lt;em&gt;minimum &lt;/em&gt;specs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XdsX6l"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dtfx_rF16Yc?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bVhhlu"&gt;The update is also giving the world &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-snow/"&gt;a winter makeover&lt;/a&gt;, adding snow and ice to the variety of weather conditions in the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21403769/hurricane-laura-microsoft-flight-simulator"&gt;real-time weather simulation&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/12/17/microsoft-flight-simulator-is-fastest-growing-entry-in-the-series-with-over-2-million-players-to-date/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; by the head of &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;, the game will now “add real-time snow and true-to-life ice coverage to the entire planet.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1jfKRm"&gt;Currently, flying over the North Pole in the game &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/travel/article/microsoft-flight-simulator-2020-tips-hacks/index.html"&gt;gets a bit weird&lt;/a&gt;, not least of which because it’s all water with no ice. As you would imagine, in real life that region &lt;a href="https://www.nesdis.noaa.gov/content/noaa-shares-first-new-view-north-pole-earth-day"&gt;is often very icy&lt;/a&gt;, so it’ll be interesting to see if the new weather conditions will make this area more true to life. In fact, let’s go see for ourselves. We’ll be departing as soon as everyone turns their phones off. And the runway clears. And, of course, we’ve got to de-ice the wings now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWXAwT"&gt;If you’re interested in trying out VR, the default keyboard shortcut for turning it on is Ctrl+Tab. If you’re using a customized keyboard mapping, you’ll have to check in the settings, where there will be a new VR tab. There’s a full FAQ &lt;a href="https://forums.flightsimulator.com/t/read-first-vr-faq/336918"&gt;for VR mode on the Flight Simulator forum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SVQ7IW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft Flight Simulator is coming to next-gen Xbox consoles next summer","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168892/microsoft-flight-simulator-xbox-release-date-announced"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6yjAmM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 22, 12:54 PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added a link to the FAQ on the Flight Simulator forum with instructions on how to get into VR mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22194274/microsoft-flight-simulator-update-vr-xbox-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22194274/microsoft-flight-simulator-update-vr-xbox-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-22T11:11:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T11:11:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram creators were promised a $500 sponsorship but ended up with $40 face scrubbers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aE9mTm5jNvytgL9YKCNfxJ1nYfw=/0x400:2400x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68566290/Photo_12_12_2020__15_13_52__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Lauren Clitheroe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T7P1It"&gt;All of the women tell the same story of how they were scammed. A company called The SkinGlo emailed them with &lt;a href="https://theskinglo.com/pages/partnership-terms-conditions"&gt;a tempting deal&lt;/a&gt;: it was looking for content to fill its Instagram feed, and its team had chosen them to help. In exchange for five photos of them using The SkinGlo’s electric face scrubber — even photos taken just from their phones — they’d receive €450, or about $525 USD. They could even watermark the images and only send over a clean file once they got paid. It seemed like a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zgIHJJ"&gt;There was one small catch, though. The women would have to buy the company’s face scrubber themselves, with a 50 percent off discount code, bringing the total to €40, or about $48.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fKlGtP"&gt;Although that stipulation was slightly odd, the company still seemed trustworthy, the women say. It has a &lt;a href="https://theskinglo.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; that’s basic but colorful and clean. Its Instagram page has over 12K followers, and at one point, it was filled with tons of positive comments on its posts. One woman says the page even talked about a partnership with ASOS, a popular apparel retailer, and linked out to its page. Seven women tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; they bought the scrubber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BePD0U"&gt;That’s when the company ghosted. After taking and sending photos, none of the women heard from The SkinGlo again. Nothing’s been posted to its account since October, and all comments are disabled. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; messaged seven women who confirmed they weren’t paid, although the scam’s scale is unclear, as is how the company found their accounts. We’ve reached out to The SkinGlo for comment and haven’t heard back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HPIEVo"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eXC-JpoyPrk?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VYfB2d"&gt;From these seven women, the company made over €200 and sold seven pieces of inventory without having to pay for marketing, advertising, or comped products. All the people behind SkinGlo had to do was send some emails and correspond a few times with the women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dNVTsN"&gt;“The fact that they’re asking for payment, it’s just a way to guarantee that they’re getting money in their pockets rather than supporting the creative side of doing the work for them, really,” says Lauren Clitheroe, a photographer who made &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eXC-JpoyPrk"&gt;a YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; about what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9e3MZL"&gt;This scam did a couple of things right to convince the women to press the buy button. For one, a person claiming to work in The SkinGlo’s PR department emailed everyone instead of relying on DM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6WqS2B"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIn5nNepAIX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="13" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:16px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIn5nNepAIX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 19% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"&gt;&lt;svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding-top: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: auto;"&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIn5nNepAIX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by  Rachel Gross  (@riizzyray)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BmGysx"&gt;“The email looked very professional,” says Rachel Gross, an online creator who got duped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rCWXG"&gt;The company also sent over a link to a webpage that detailed “partnership terms and conditions” and emailed a contract that didn’t have to be signed. The company told the women that buying the product and letting the team know was equivalent to signing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UpD6IO"&gt;“I said, ‘Okay, if there is a contract that makes me feel a lot better because I know it’s a legal thing,’” says Clitheroe. “They have to stand by what they’re saying, or at least so I thought.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WMUfbl"&gt;Another creator, Kristen McCleary, says her husband read over the contract and flagged some concerning clauses, including one that said the contract was beholden to the laws of Malta. But she figured $50 wasn’t too much to gamble to make over $500. The company eventually ghosted her, without even receiving the photos she took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z19jwf"&gt;“It was definitely a scam, and I’ve not emailed them,” she said. “And I’m certainly not threatening a lawsuit for 50 bucks in international, Malta law, whatever that is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Lma2W4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIlhqy7FJ-v/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="13" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:16px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIlhqy7FJ-v/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 19% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"&gt;&lt;svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding-top: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: auto;"&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIlhqy7FJ-v/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by 1 Black LA Makeup Artist   ‍  (@itsvagabondbeauty)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Nwt2xp"&gt;The scam could have been worse, of course, but the women also lost hours of their time shooting and editing photos, as well as money and pride. Clitheroe says even more so than that, the company preyed on people during an especially tough year, which is unforgivable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nklj2t"&gt;“Myself and my husband, we both lost our jobs at the beginning of this year, right as the pandemic started, so we were struggling a little bit for a few months,” she says. “There will be people in that same boat because of the pandemic, and it’s taking advantage of people in a desperate situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OSDwih"&gt;Multiple women have posted about the scam on their accounts, where others then chime in that the same thing happened to them. There are nearly 20 reports on &lt;a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/theskinglo.com"&gt;Trustpilot&lt;/a&gt;, a website that collects user reviews, warning people not to collaborate with the brand. One poster, from yesterday, says they almost agreed to order the product but thought again after reading the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ySbbW"&gt;Gross says seeing the other women who were tricked made her feel slightly better. Generally, though, the takeaway for her is to not be tempted into promoting brands she doesn’t already love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pcLa51"&gt;“I promised myself a long time ago that I would not post about products that I don’t like or personally believe in - I will not be bought,” &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CIn5nNepAIX/"&gt;she wrote&lt;/a&gt; in a post about the experience. “And I let myself down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZeila"&gt;Although, as she also notes, the scrubber wasn’t so bad and felt nice on her face, and the photos she took didn’t go to waste. She still got a nice post out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22195081/the-skin-glo-skinglo-instagram-scam-creator-influencer-skin-care"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22195081/the-skin-glo-skinglo-instagram-scam-creator-influencer-skin-care</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
