<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-04T18:34:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T18:34:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T18:34:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Locked out and totally down: Facebook’s scramble to fix a massive outage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K7m-20zYszke0f6MiKESYTZYClI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950350/acastro_170329_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vo6zhu"&gt;A prolonged, global outage of Facebook’s apps sent the company’s engineers scrambling to fix the issue at one of its data centers in California, according to two people familiar with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CrorXh"&gt;The outage, which began around 11:40AM ET on Monday, brought down all of Facebook’s apps — including Instagram and WhatsApp — globally, affecting billions of users and millions of advertisers. Inside Facebook, the outage also broke nearly all of the internal systems that employees use to communicate and work. As of 6PM ET, it appears that most of the services are back online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8vO2I"&gt;Several employees told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; they resorted to talking through their work-provided Outlook email accounts since Facebook mainly runs on an internal version of the social network that is currently not accessible. While employees could email each other, they can’t send or receive emails from external addresses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ifKzix"&gt;Since Facebook requires employees to log in with their work accounts to access tools such as Google Docs and Zoom, those services also weren’t working, leading some employees to use alternative services like Apple’s FaceTime and Discord. Employees who were already authenticated with non-Facebook tools like Google Docs before the outage began, still had access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XNRypQ"&gt;Facebook has yet to detail the cause of the outage internally or externally, though outside experts are saying it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708989/instagram-facebook-outage-messenger-whatsapp-error"&gt;relates to the company’s networking architecture&lt;/a&gt; suddenly going offline. Facebook engineers were sent to one of its main US data centers in California to try and fix the problem, meaning the fix couldn’t be done remotely. “We understand how disruptive this is to everyone,” CTO Mike Schroepfer said in an email to employees that was seen by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LqF6qF"&gt;Further complicating matters, the outage broke the ability for some employees to access company buildings and conference rooms with their badges, according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/04/technology/facebook-down.html"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, which first reported that engineers were being dispatched to the data center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="diBOxl"&gt;A Facebook spokesperson pointed to a tweet by Schroepfer saying the company was experiencing “networking issues” and that employees “are working as fast as possible to debug and restore” its systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IezK1N"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;*Sincere* apologies to everyone impacted by outages of Facebook powered services right now.  We are experiencing networking issues and teams are working as fast as possible to debug and restore as fast as possible&lt;/p&gt;— Mike Schroepfer (@schrep) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/schrep/status/1445114730151043073?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4B9425"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 6:33PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Noted that the outage is ending as Facebook and its other services are coming back online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709575/facebook-outage-instagram-whatsapp"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709575/facebook-outage-instagram-whatsapp</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T18:31:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T18:31:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin has a new demo, and it’s awesome</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nJ0tgZ6YgXzko2zHyZQG6xpLu1o=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950702/02_bmp_jpgcopy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Square Enix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PvjZUG"&gt;Square Enix released&lt;em&gt; Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://square-enix-games.com/sopffo/en-us/#trialversion"&gt;second demo&lt;/a&gt;, showing off a little bit more of what we can expect from the action-oriented &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; spinoff. The demo gets... interesting. In one cutscene, Jack, the main character, peaced out after a boss fight in hilarious fashion. Players shared the cutscene all over social media with an air of alarmed confusion, but I am here to state for the record that if &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; is going to be like that moment, this game is going to kick so much ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hazmmF"&gt;When &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22532295/final-fantasy-origins-square-enix-team-ninja-trailer-e3-2021"&gt;was first announced&lt;/a&gt;, fans were a bit surprised since the game is being developed by Team Ninja of &lt;em&gt;Dead or Alive&lt;/em&gt; fame. Team Ninja is also behind the &lt;em&gt;Dynasty Warriors&lt;/em&gt;-ification of franchises like &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem, &lt;/em&gt;as well as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metroid:_Other_M"&gt;the most controversial &lt;em&gt;Metroid &lt;/em&gt;game&lt;/a&gt;. From its pedigreed developer, whatever form &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; was going to take, it was going to be unlike anything the franchise had ever seen — and that’s a good thing. The &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; series has been around for almost 35 years, and it’s refreshing to see Square Enix continue to try new things. Square Enix has done new and weird things with its IP (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689462/nintendo-direct-september-2021-trailers-announcements"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chocobo GP&lt;/em&gt; anyone?&lt;/a&gt;), but I’d argue a spinoff action game hasn’t been seen since the likes of 2006’s &lt;em&gt;Dirge of Cerberus&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vtHmv6"&gt;That’s the vibe I get playing &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; — like it’s Square Enix’s attempt to relitigate the merits of &lt;em&gt;Dirge of Cerberus&lt;/em&gt; while adding a dash of &lt;em&gt;Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice&lt;/em&gt; for flavor. There’s a break gauge that functions almost like &lt;em&gt;Sekiro&lt;/em&gt;’s posture gauge — depleting it makes enemies vulnerable to special finishers, but you are similarly vulnerable if your break gauge depletes. In a growing market of Soulslike games, &lt;em&gt;Strangers In Paradise&lt;/em&gt; fits. While not being quite as hard as the famously difficult From Software games, &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; asks a little bit more critical thinking from its players. You cannot spam attacks like you can in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21207441/final-fantasy-7-remake-ff7-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and expect to walk out alive. And once you get the hang of changing combos and switching jobs, the combat is pretty cool. There’s also a relentless gloominess present in &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise &lt;/em&gt;that was in &lt;em&gt;Dirge of Cerberus&lt;/em&gt;. But unlike &lt;em&gt;Dirge&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; seems to be self-aware of its edgelordiness to comedic effect. Take the gameplay clip that’s gone viral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8QtBvJ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lWUwqF947rA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="12OmvU"&gt;This &lt;em&gt;rules&lt;/em&gt;. There is something so relatable to Jack — not Squall, not Cloud, not Lighting, but... &lt;em&gt;Jack&lt;/em&gt; — essentially throwing up deuces and making his exit while sick tunes blare from his earbuds. In this one moment, Jack became the millennial &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; protagonist. He’s masked up, pissed off, and finds himself outnumbered and outgunned on a seemingly futile quest to defeat an oppressive and eternal evil while toothy assholes block his path. No, seriously — one way you progress through a zone is by destroying what are essentially tooth-ringed, pulsing butthole monsters. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/__TVqgK3waK7Sml-5b3CXvQi5Xc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22901108/FA4wpCgX0AQ8oJp.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Square Enix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;That’s a butthole&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LIKSG9"&gt;Is this just a poorly conceived monster idea or a well-crafted meditation on the kind of people who block humanity’s progress? You be the judge. I know the conversation around &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin&lt;/em&gt; centers on a cutscene people might interpret as cringe, but that cringe accompanies a demo that’s weirdly compelling and a great new direction for the seminal franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sXTLss"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin &lt;/em&gt;releases on PlayStation, Xbox, and PC March 18, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p99jvl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDaRKE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709720/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-demo-playstation-square-enix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709720/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-demo-playstation-square-enix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T18:07:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T18:07:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is back online after a massive outage that also took down Instagram, WhatsApp, Messenger, and Oculus</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dG0Qx5icf91JlXCq-1SEPtG9q6w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69948694/acastro_180720_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yQnrks"&gt;Just as Facebook’s Antigone Davis was live on CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;defending the company over a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"&gt;whistleblower’s accusations&lt;/a&gt; and its handling of research data &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701445/facebook-instagram-mental-health-research-pdfs-documents"&gt;suggesting Instagram is harmful to teens&lt;/a&gt;, its entire network of services suddenly went offline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dpmd6V"&gt;The outage started just before noon ET and took nearly six hours &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709654/instagram-facebook-outage-whatsapp-oculus"&gt;before it was resolved&lt;/a&gt;. This is the worst outage for Facebook since a 2019 incident &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18265185/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-outage-2019-return-back"&gt;took its site offline for more than 24 hours&lt;/a&gt;, as the downtime &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18265002/facebook-instagram-outage-ad-revenue-lost"&gt;hit hardest on the small businesses and creators who rely on these services&lt;/a&gt; for their income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jC6Rko"&gt;After failing all tests for most of the day, a test of ISP DNS servers via &lt;a href="http://DNSchecker.org"&gt;DNSchecker.org&lt;/a&gt; showed most of them successfully finding a route to &lt;a href="http://Facebook.com"&gt;Facebook.com&lt;/a&gt; at 5:30PM ET. A few minutes later, we were able to start using Facebook and Instagram normally, however, it may take time for the DNS fixes to reach everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="edlDtv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook engineers were dispatched to the company’s U.S. data centers to try and fix the problem&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e7AlIx"&gt;On Twitter, Facebook communications exec Andy Stone &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1445058088436908045"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;, “We’re aware that some people are having trouble accessing our apps and products. We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible, and we apologize for any inconvenience.” Mike Schroepfer, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688510/facebook-cto-andrew-boz-bosworth-chief-technology-officer"&gt;who will step down from his post as CTO next year&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/schrep/status/1445114730151043073"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “We are experiencing networking issues and teams are working as fast as possible to debug and restore as fast as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BdUNeh"&gt;Inside Facebook, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709575/facebook-outage-instagram-whatsapp"&gt;the outage has broken nearly all of the internal systems employees use to communicate and work&lt;/a&gt;. Several employees told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;they resorted to talking through their work-provided Outlook email accounts, though employees can’t receive emails from external addresses. Employees who were logged into work tools such as Google Docs and Zoom before the outage can still use those, but any employee who needs to login with their work email was blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ht1q2C"&gt;Facebook engineers have been sent to the company’s U.S. data centers to try and fix the problem, according to two people familiar with the situation. That meant the outage, already Facebook’s most severe in years could be further prolonged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="l3G5TB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Is Facebook down right now? This global outage is tough on everyone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709123/facebook-outage-down-detector-cloudflare"},{"title":"Twitter is up, Facebook is down, and Jack Dorsey is laughing ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/10/4/22709235/twitter-jack-dorsey-dunk-facebook-outage-dns"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="x5968t"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;*Sincere* apologies to everyone impacted by outages of Facebook powered services right now.  We are experiencing networking issues and teams are working as fast as possible to debug and restore as fast as possible&lt;/p&gt;— Mike Schroepfer (@schrep) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/schrep/status/1445114730151043073?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CmqBiE"&gt;A peek at &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/facebook/"&gt;Down Detector&lt;/a&gt; (or your Twitter feed) reveals the problems were widespread. While it’s unclear exactly why the platforms were unreachable for so many people, their DNS records show that, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702876/slack-is-down-outage-morning-disruption-work-chat"&gt;like last week’s Slack outage&lt;/a&gt;, the problem is apparently DNS (&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/WmRbmf5"&gt;it’s always DNS&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXykPn"&gt;Cloudflare senior vice president Dane Knecht &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dok2001/status/1445056572703625218"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook’s border gateway protocol routes — &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/security/glossary/what-is-bgp/"&gt;BGP&lt;/a&gt; helps networks pick the best path to deliver internet traffic — were suddenly “withdrawn from the internet.” While some have speculated about hackers, or an internal protest over last night’s whistleblower report, there isn’t any information yet to suggest anything malicious is to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jijz8O"&gt;&lt;a href="http://Instagram.com"&gt;Instagram.com&lt;/a&gt; was flashing a 5xx Server Error message, while the Facebook site merely told us that something went wrong. The problem also affected its virtual reality arm, Oculus. Users could load games they already have installed, and the browser works, but social features or installing new games didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JhSAXC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 3:37PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added additional information about the outage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtXsyU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 4:15PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from Facebook CTO Mike Schroepfer, along with internal Facebook updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JQ06Jm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 5PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Noted outage is still ongoing, added information about the 2019 outage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zNGZJ3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 5:35PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;DNS updates suggest Facebook is closing in on a solution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Av16YP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th, 6:08PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://Facebook.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is back online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708989/instagram-facebook-outage-messenger-whatsapp-error"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708989/instagram-facebook-outage-messenger-whatsapp-error</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T17:49:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T17:49:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is coming back after a six-hour outage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bO6n6A12PstmdlZ_bKNj5QNRsfE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950524/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KZnXEX"&gt;Facebook is back online after a six-hour outage due to DNS routing problems. The outage &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708989/instagram-facebook-outage-messenger-whatsapp-error"&gt;took down Instagram, Whatsapp, Messenger, and Oculus VR as well&lt;/a&gt;. For some, those services are back online now; however, after a DNS issue like this, it could take hours for everything to work properly on every network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="egDXnz"&gt;The outage started just before noon ET on Monday. It was the most significant outage for Facebook since a 2019 incident &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18265185/facebook-instagram-whatsapp-outage-2019-return-back"&gt;took its site offline for more than 24 hours&lt;/a&gt;. Journalist Brian Krebs &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/briankrebs/status/1445147230244061184?s=21"&gt;cites a trusted source&lt;/a&gt; who told him the incident didn’t have any malicious origins. Instead, they said it started with a routine BGP update that went wrong, wiping out the DNS routing information that Facebook needs so that other networks can find its sites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GKbjdv"&gt;However, the problem meant remote users could access the network to use it, and the people on site didn’t have the network access necessary to repair things. This mirrors an anonymous account of the issue posted earlier to Reddit (and quickly deleted), which cited pandemic protocols as a reason fewer people were on location than usual, slowing restoration efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e7AlIx"&gt;On Twitter, Facebook communications exec Andy Stone &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1445058088436908045"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, “We’re aware that some people are having trouble accessing our apps and products. We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible, and we apologize for any inconvenience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8vO2I"&gt;Inside Facebook, the outage broke internal systems as well, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709575/facebook-outage-instagram-whatsapp"&gt;leaving employees unable to get into offices and communicate easily with each other&lt;/a&gt;. Some told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; they were using work-provided Outlook email accounts, allowing Facebook workers to email each other but unable to send or receive emails from external addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOp2Id"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709654/instagram-facebook-outage-whatsapp-oculus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709654/instagram-facebook-outage-whatsapp-oculus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T17:26:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T17:26:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Epic Games Store is getting better achievements next week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0_A5Tm8lstuErs6McU3iy6xbrK8=/158x0:1760x1068/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950422/Screen_Shot_2021_10_04_at_4.50.08_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KLFXTJ"&gt;The Epic Games Store is taking a bit step towards further competing with more established PC game stores like Steam next week with a &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/news/epic-games-achievements-are-launching-next-week"&gt;proper achievement system&lt;/a&gt; (called, of course, “Epic Achievements”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BoTX9E"&gt;To start, Epic Achievements will only be available on a few games, including &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pillars of Eternity&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kena&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Zombie Army 4&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake Remastered. &lt;/em&gt;Achievements will be broken up into four levels: Bronze (which award 5-45 XP), Silver (50-95 XP), Gold (100-200 XP), and Platinum (which is awarded upon achieving 1000 XP in a game and awards players with an additional 250 XP on their profiles).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F8JjjF7Xl43NpZ7MVSRFOyZtNF8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900962/Screen_Shot_2021_10_04_at_5.00.25_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JzQehS"&gt;Games that are updated to support Epic Achievements will now show those achievements on the game’s page in the store, in addition to player’s libraries, where they’ll be able to track progress and see how far they’ve progressed towards a particular challenge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h6RaJu"&gt;Right now, accumulating experience points doesn’t actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything, however, beyond giving players a sense of pride and accomplishment; Epic promises that it’ll be adding “new social features and player rewards” centered on achievements later this year, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kfyoKy"&gt;The Epic Games Store has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EpicGames/status/1288520483147833346"&gt;technically offered achievements&lt;/a&gt; for over a year when it started testing what the company called “an early version of the feature,” but the coming launch next week promises a more comprehensive system that will span games, allowing players to gain experience on a platform-wide level, similar to Xbox’s Gamerscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ltpJem"&gt;Legacy achievements already in games will stick around as “developer achievements” that exist solely at the discretion of the developer, although developers will have the option to convert existing developer achievements over Epic Achievements if they wish (which will also maintain player progress). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709465/epic-games-store-achievements-feature-xp-social"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709465/epic-games-store-achievements-feature-xp-social</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T17:23:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T17:23:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s Google partnership now includes an ‘exclusive’ cloud storage plan</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K3IOnO6iMCZa3k03V7fnxzghcqk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950406/ajohnson_210813_4713_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0u1gtV"&gt;T-Mobile and Google &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fun-carrier%2Ft-mobile-google-one&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F4%2F22709452%2Ft-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;have announced&lt;/a&gt; they’re offering an “exclusive” plan with 500GB of Google One cloud storage for T-Mobile customers starting October 12th. The plan will cost $5 per month, the latest addition in an ongoing partnership between the search giant and the mobile carrier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXle9c"&gt;Google offers Google One plans &lt;a href="https://one.google.com/about/plans"&gt;in a variety of sizes&lt;/a&gt; but, up until this point, didn’t have a 500GB tier, jumping from 200GB for $2.99 per month straight to 2TB for $9.99 per month. Anyone with a Google account gets 15GB for free, but T-Mobile’s offer could work as a nice middle ground if you’ve started to store more of your files in Google Drive and Google Photos. T-Mobile also says the plan can be shared with up to five other people, whether or not they have T-Mobile accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cvvIHL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile and Google started collaborating earlier this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IsXeoD"&gt;T-Mobile and Google first announced their partnership &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356918/t-mobile-google-android-services-rcs-youtube-tv-pixel-storage-backup"&gt;at the end of March this year&lt;/a&gt; for a set of still undisclosed financial terms. T-Mobile agreed to support Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/12/18137937/rcs-rich-communication-service-messaging-explainer-what-is-google-chat"&gt;messaging standard of choice, RCS&lt;/a&gt;, offer Google’s Android Messages as the default messaging app, and push YouTube TV and YouTube Premium through a variety of different deals. At the time, neither company included a deal to push Google One as T-Mobile’s official backup method for Android phones. But lo and behold, on October 12th, T-Mobile will now have an option for that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="btQTKt"&gt;Customers can sign up for the Google One deal through T-Mobile. The company says it’ll offer a 30-day free trial before it starts charging $5 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709452/t-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709452/t-mobile-google-one-cloud-storage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T16:28:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T16:28:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to upgrade to Windows 11 without waiting in line</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cy_Rk8Cy4tPRNKRGbxc6XTPI6-Q=/8x0:2552x1696/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950095/twarren__windows11main_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Au8ANT"&gt;Windows 11 is now available and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22472519"&gt;will be rolling out to millions of PCs worldwide&lt;/a&gt;. But, as with any new OS rollout, it’s not going to happen overnight, and many Windows users will be waiting for a while until that magic upgrade notice appears. Don’t want to wait? You don’t have to — you can, with just a little effort, download and install the new version of Windows right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZ2ul9"&gt;Keep in mind, though, that unlike previous versions of Windows, you may not be invited to install Windows 11 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/microsoft/22544171/microsoft-windows-11-system-requirements-hardware"&gt;if your machine isn’t considered up to its standard&lt;/a&gt;. That doesn’t mean that you can’t install the new OS — Microsoft has said if you have an older machine, you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22644194/microsoft-windows-11-minimum-system-requirements-processors-changes"&gt;will be able to access Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, but you’ll have to download an ISO file of Windows 11 and install the OS manually. (However, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/28/22646035/microsoft-windows-11-iso-workaround-no-update-guarantee"&gt;you may not get automatic updates&lt;/a&gt; — you may have to install a new ISO each time instead.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sud2Gv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Planning to upgrade to Windows 11? A checklist before you do ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/e/22469447"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jTOlnX"&gt;Now that the update is rolling out, you can check to see if it’s arrived at your machine by going to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Windows Update.” If you haven’t gotten the upgrade yet, and you want to see if your machine is considered good enough for Windows 11, you can download Microsoft’s PC Health App (&lt;a href="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;), which should tell you whether your machine qualifies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3yY15r"&gt;If it does, and you don’t want to wait, here’s how to install Windows 11:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Installation Assistant should make it easy to install Windows 11." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0TTu4TrRsXt1oVjO2263ZuaTAuY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900873/image__2_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Installation Assistant should make it easy to install Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2gCP5o"&gt;Go to the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware-download%2Fwindows11" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Windows 11 software download page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RYIUWp"&gt;If you want to do it the easy way, use the Windows 11 Installation Assistant; just click “Download Now” and follow the instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6GQT1Q"&gt;You can also create a bootable USB or DVD by selecting “Create Windows 11 Installation Media.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ekKNCO"&gt;And finally, you can download a disk image (ISO) for either bootable media or a virtual machine install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="V9owEb"&gt;Follow the directions, and you should be good for an immediate install of Windows 11. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="KH7st5"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5yFC8T"&gt; Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="9C7frw"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Windows 11|104128" data-volume-uuid="65d6e1f88" data-volume-id="104128" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-809" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vPKz2t"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22683953/windows-11-upgrade-how-to-download-install"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22683953/windows-11-upgrade-how-to-download-install</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T16:08:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T16:08:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Acer’s new 17.3-inch Nitro 5 seems like a lot of bang for your buck</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Acer Nitro 5" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6FB0zkfgmoZFW41fzSa0IgUOlVY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950036/acernitro52021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Acer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4lW9aZ"&gt;Acer has refreshed its Nitro 5 lineup of entry-level gaming laptops for the second half of 2021, and its new 17.3-inch model launching in mid-October seems particularly impressive given its $1,199.99 price. Its 1080p display has a 144Hz refresh rate, and it comes equipped with an 11th Gen Intel Core i7 processor and Nvidia’s RTX 3050 Ti graphics chip. (Acer hasn’t specified the CPU model or what the maximum graphics power of the GPU will be.) Other specs include 16GB of DDR4 RAM and a 1TB SSD. That sounds like a solid gaming laptop to me, so long as you’re not expecting too much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TndUFB"&gt;If you want something smaller, Acer also has a 15.6-inch version coming in mid-October for $769.99. It also has a 144Hz refresh rate screen, but as you might have guessed with the $400 price difference, there’s more than just size that gets a reduction here. It has an 11th Gen Intel Core i5 processor, 8GB of DDR4 RAM, a 256GB SSD, and on the graphics side of things, it features the Nvidia GTX 1650. This should still be able to do some light gaming, but it’ll likely be a more compromised experience than what the 17.3-inch can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4b8cYw"&gt;Both models have an ethernet port and a Thunderbolt 4 port, in addition to three USB-A ports, HDMI out, a 3.5mm jack, and a Kensington slot.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Acer Nitro 5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UplLxr5Tks_TB1acuud3oK0YZus=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900721/acernitro52021_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Acer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nitro 5 charges via the barrel plug port on its side instead of its rear, where it was located on the previous iteration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dPNhAV"&gt;Acer gave the latest Nitro 5 just a couple of minor design adjustments that make it stand out a bit compared &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22218681/acer-nitro-5-gaming-laptop-intel-11th-tiger-lake-h35-amd-ryzen-rtx-3080-qhd-release-date-price"&gt;to the early 2021 model&lt;/a&gt;. It still has a red and black colorway with edges that taper off, along with a full-size keyboard. The barrel plug charger now plugs in along the right side of the laptop instead of its back, and parts of its lid and chassis appear to have a grippier texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADumaN"&gt;If you just got the Nitro 5 or a similar gaming laptop earlier this year, these upgrades don’t seem like must-haves. But if you’re in the market for a 17.3-inch machine, Acer’s latest seems like a fantastic value.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709358/acer-17-3-inch-nitro-5-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3050-ti-price-specs-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709358/acer-17-3-inch-nitro-5-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3050-ti-price-specs-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T16:03:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T16:03:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Planning to upgrade to Windows 11? A checklist before you do</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7dQzx-iJ-i2TCh7CjJLQSsm_Nnc=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950018/RWF5uB.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="irnYQM"&gt;I don’t know what else to call it: the Windows 11 upgrade situation is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22643275/windows-11-upgrade-system-requirements-pc-health-check"&gt;confusing mess&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on when your PC was built, which components you chose, and how it was configured, there’s a decent chance &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686457/windows-11-health-check-compatible-supported-cpu-old-pc-waiver"&gt;Microsoft will try to scare you away&lt;/a&gt; from installing the free upgrade, which is available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709166/microsoft-windows-11-release-download-available"&gt;a day early today&lt;/a&gt;. Millions of people will likely be told their systems are incompatible, and Microsoft is reserving the right to withhold security updates if you install on older systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Qo3G58"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Windows 11 review: a familiar home that’s still being renovated","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"},{"title":"Microsoft releases Windows 11 a day early","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709166/microsoft-windows-11-release-download-available"},{"title":"How to upgrade from Windows 10 to Windows 11 for free","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708478/microsoft-windows-11-upgrade-free-os-how-to-download"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vSQV72"&gt;But as far as we can tell, Windows 11 is largely Windows 10 with a fresh coat of paint, and there’s a strong chance your Windows 10 computer will run Windows 11 just fine. Do we recommend it? &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22705148/windows-11-upgrade-beta-release-preview-impressions"&gt;Not necessarily&lt;/a&gt;, but this article might help you figure out whether your PC is ready for the ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dVF2jQ"&gt;Here’s a basic checklist of what you’ll likely need, and how you might satisfy each requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SxPe7Y"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fwindows%2Fwindows-11-specifications" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Basic system requirements&lt;/a&gt;: 1GHz dual-core CPU, 4GB RAM, 64GB storage, UEFI motherboard, TPM 2.0, DX12 graphics, 720p display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Yhe225"&gt;UEFI must be enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1yRTmS"&gt;TPM must be enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lWA1Kb"&gt;Secure Boot must be enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ck1udY"&gt;Processor must be on Microsoft’s approved list if you want an in-place upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4UMd0W"&gt;64GB of free space if you want to dual-boot Windows 11 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="AxWX2C"&gt;Before we go any further, why not give Microsoft’s official PC Health Check tool a try? (&lt;a href="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp"&gt;Direct download here&lt;/a&gt;.) If you pass, you’re probably already fine. Just wait for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708478/microsoft-windows-11-upgrade-free-os-how-to-download"&gt;the official Windows Update&lt;/a&gt; and you should be good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VR16st"&gt;But if not, your first steps should probably be to turn on your TPM and Secure Boot setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gbnrAM"&gt;How to turn on TPM &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NdzwVU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security"&gt;As we discussed in June&lt;/a&gt;, you probably already have a Trusted Platform Module (TPM) in your PC, built into your desktop or laptop motherboard or your CPU. (If you don’t, there are &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/how-to/bypass-windows-11-tpm-requirement"&gt;hacky ways around it&lt;/a&gt;, but let’s start by saying you do.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OHvrC4"&gt;It’s possible that Windows will see your TPM, and you can easily check by either running that aforementioned PC Health Check tool or hitting &lt;strong&gt;Win + R&lt;/strong&gt;, typing &lt;strong&gt;tpm.msc&lt;/strong&gt; into the window that appears, and hitting &lt;strong&gt;enter&lt;/strong&gt; to see what kind of TPM might be there and if it’s “ready for use.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NBWccK"&gt;If it’s not, don’t give up yet! It might just be disabled in your BIOS and you’ll need to go hunting for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="6tDdN0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10788546"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ErByTU"&gt;Once you’re in the BIOS, the TPM setting goes by a wide variety of names. (My desktop motherboard called it “Intel PTT” (Platform Trust Technology), but it might be an “AMD PSP fTPM” or simply a “Security Device.”) If you don’t see an obvious place to check, &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/enable-tpm-2-0-on-your-pc-1fd5a332-360d-4f46-a1e7-ae6b0c90645c"&gt;Microsoft suggests&lt;/a&gt; looking for a sub-menu called “Advanced,” “Security,” or “Trusted Computing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f1Uuzr"&gt;Oh, and depending on your BIOS, you may need to use your keyboard’s arrow keys to move and possibly even the PG UP / PG DOWN buttons to turn things on and off again. (Apologies if you know this, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684730/students-file-folder-directory-structure-education-gen-z"&gt;it’s no longer safe to assume&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vVfylh"&gt;Got it? Great! But don’t leave the BIOS just yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZPzRx"&gt;If you only have a TPM 1.2 module, not TPM 2.0, you still aren’t out of luck: Microsoft will let you modify a registry key in Windows to allow upgrades “if you acknowledge and understand the risks.” If so, hit &lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt;, type &lt;strong&gt;regedit&lt;/strong&gt;, search for “&lt;strong&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\Setup\MoSetup”&lt;/strong&gt; find the &lt;strong&gt;AllowUpgradesWithUnsupportedTPMOrCPU&lt;/strong&gt; key, and set its value to &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sn3iJ2"&gt;How to turn on Secure Boot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="k5kxCB"&gt;Once you’re in your motherboard’s BIOS, you should likely also be able to locate a sub-menu for Secure Boot. It might be buried in a “Security,” “Boot,” or “Authentication” tab. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wYqRLS"&gt;Flick it to “Enabled,” if it isn’t already. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lZTGnAC2_3MreCK-C35cBW0a2ss=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900233/secure_boot_uefi.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Secure Boot is easy to find in a modern Dell laptop’s UEFI, less so with a random desktop motherboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ec2SZn"&gt;If you’d like to check whether Secure Boot is already enabled from Windows (perhaps saving yourself a trip to the BIOS), there are a couple of ways to do that, too: in addition to Microsoft’s PC Health Check tool (&lt;a href="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp"&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt;), you can hit &lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt; and type in &lt;strong&gt;System Information&lt;/strong&gt;, and launch that app to see a variety of things, including Secure Boot toggle status and your current BIOS mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ktB4Y7"&gt;I can’t turn on Secure Boot, and I’m not sure I have UEFI at all. &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UCv3nr"&gt;Unless your PC is very old, you probably have the &lt;em&gt;option&lt;/em&gt; of a UEFI BIOS, but you might not actually be using it right now. You might be on a “legacy” BIOS that uses MBR (Master Boot Record)-partitioned drives instead of the modern GPT (GUID Partition Table) standard that Windows requires for UEFI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="trsA7X"&gt;If that sounded like a load of alphabet soup, you may want to stop here! &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/deployment/mbr-to-gpt"&gt;Microsoft does have an MBR to GPT conversion tool&lt;/a&gt;, but messing with partition tables fundamentally puts the data on your drive at risk. That tool didn’t work for one &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer, who went on to use a different method that wound up wiping his entire partition. (Sorry, Cam!) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vuZiwf"&gt;If you don’t care about your data, you might as well do a clean install of Windows 11. And if you DO care about that data, why not try out a dual-boot of Windows 11 instead? Besides, those may be your only easy options if your CPU is too old.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XgZS0-DPfpISCUaa_A6vvlq4C9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900459/windows_11_windows_11_cpu_not_supported.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7YywH3"&gt;“The processor isn’t supported for this version of Windows.” Help!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NFVzua"&gt;While there are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; hacky ways to get around Microsoft’s restrictions — one &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; writer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22705148/windows-11-upgrade-beta-release-preview-impressions"&gt;tricked the Windows 11 updater&lt;/a&gt; using a Frankenstein-esque combination of old and new ISOs — the company is generally not allowing PCs with older CPUs to install Windows 11 over their existing Windows 10 operating system and keep existing settings and files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXczRD"&gt;That means you’ll generally need to create a new drive partition or overwrite an existing one, and it makes dual-boot particularly enticing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EL86oK"&gt;You can find Microsoft’s official lists of supported processors at these links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XDOh3r"&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/design/minimum/supported/windows-11-supported-intel-processors"&gt;Supported Intel CPUs for Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T0eRkH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/design/minimum/supported/windows-11-supported-amd-processors"&gt;Supported AMD CPUs for Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HuE6fY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/design/minimum/supported/windows-11-supported-qualcomm-processors"&gt;Supported Qualcomm SoCs for Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="GUuBYM"&gt;Generally, Intel 8th Gen or newer CPUs are supported, as are AMD Ryzen 2000 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KFFaJc"&gt;How to dual boot Windows 11 or clean install the OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2ZyG6y"&gt;Whether you’re starting from scratch or just dipping a toe in the water with a dual-boot, the process should be roughly the same: you’ll need to free up some space, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware-download%2Fwindows11" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;download the Windows 11 ISO or tool&lt;/a&gt;, burn it to a bootable drive, and use it to install Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5NoxG2"&gt;For a dual-boot, you don’t need a second drive inside your PC — you can simply shrink your existing partition with Microsoft’s Disk Management tool. Hit &lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt;, begin typing in &lt;strong&gt;“Create and format hard disk partitions” &lt;/strong&gt;and hit enter to launch it. Make sure your drive has plenty of space, then &lt;strong&gt;right-click &lt;/strong&gt;and pick &lt;strong&gt;Shrink Volume.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll want to shrink it by at least 65,536MB (64GB) so there’s enough room for Windows 11 — I gave my laptop install 128GB (131,072MB) just to be safe. You can’t shrink more than you have, though, and you may want to leave some space for your current OS to breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jfR6k2P6krUtkfgvPLEkeTIIPAs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900501/shrink_volume_windows.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Shrink Volume option in Disk Management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="I5BoFG"&gt;To actually install that ISO, all you need is a USB external drive — an 8GB USB 3.0 key should work just fine — and a piece of software to burn it to disk. Microsoft has its own Media Creation Tool which we’ll link to soon, and I’m a big fan &lt;a href="https://rufus.ie/en/"&gt;of Rufus&lt;/a&gt; to burn my bootable USB drives using downloadable ISOs as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AfJ5s6"&gt;Power users might want to try &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/AveYo/c74dc774a8fb81a332b5d65613187b15"&gt;AveYo’s Universal MediaCreationTool&lt;/a&gt;, which may be able to download the image and bypass TPM for you, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o3oZzS"&gt;If all goes well, you’ll reboot your computer with that USB key plugged in to start the process. You may need to press a key like F12 while your system’s booting up and manually select your external drive, if it doesn’t automatically load. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hrOJxC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Choose wisely&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Oaef0p"&gt;Now, be careful to pick the right place to install Windows 11 — if you shrunk your drive to make room for a dual-boot, you’ll tell Windows to install in the unallocated space, and if you’re overwriting an existing drive for a clean install (file loss ahoy!) you’ll pick that drive instead. For a desktop with multiple drives, you may want to power off and unplug the extra ones before choosing where to install. It’s all too easy to press the wrong button and wipe out data, and we’d hate for that to happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IG5ZJW"&gt;Once you’ve got a dual-boot, it’s not too hard to switch between the two operating systems. Hit the &lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt; key to pull up the Start menu, type &lt;strong&gt;UEFI &lt;/strong&gt;and pick &lt;strong&gt;Change advanced startup options&lt;/strong&gt;, then select &lt;strong&gt;Restart now&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you boot back into the advanced startup menu, pick &lt;strong&gt;Use another operating system&lt;/strong&gt; and it’ll present you with your choice of OS.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22705406/windows-11-upgrade-checklist-cpu-tpm-secure-boot-dual-iso-clean-install"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22705406/windows-11-upgrade-checklist-cpu-tpm-secure-boot-dual-iso-clean-install</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T16:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T16:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to upgrade from Windows 10 to Windows 11 for free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uzNam0rUjlKPWc7cKiq0isySy7k=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69950003/Hero_Bloom_Logo.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9wVf6N"&gt;Microsoft’s free Windows 11 upgrade from Windows 10 is now rolling out. Microsoft is starting to offer the free upgrade to new devices that are still shipping with Windows 10, before making the OS available to other eligible existing hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P7Weaa"&gt;Not every existing PC running Windows 10 will be able to upgrade to Windows 11, though. Windows 11 will require Intel 8th Gen Coffee Lake or Zen 2 CPUs and up, TPM 2.0 (Trusted Platform Module) support, 4GB of RAM, and 64GB of storage. That leaves millions of PCs unable to officially upgrade to Windows 11, although there will be unsupported workarounds if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WyffW3"&gt;Microsoft is also gradually rolling out Windows 11, so the free upgrade won’t be offered to all existing PCs that are officially supported just yet. All existing and eligible PCs should be offered the Windows 11 upgrade by mid-2022, according to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSb2Yi"&gt;Here’s how to get Windows 11 today, if you have a new PC that just shipped with Windows 10 or a device that’s allowed to upgrade to Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mJBZ9N"&gt;Check that your PC is officially supported through &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fwindows%2Fwindows-11%23pchealthcheck" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s PC Health Check app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DglUmP"&gt;Back up all of your important documents, apps, and data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fbhhWh"&gt;On your Windows 10 PC, head into Settings &amp;gt; Update &amp;amp; Security &amp;gt; Windows Update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="y4Vfqf"&gt;Check for updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cVPP14"&gt;If the free Windows 11 upgrade is available, you’ll see an option to download and install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q2_h6JYY4O4vgsw-hU9fq1RRQpM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22899489/CnD4YoV.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Windows 11 upgrade prompt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="d4H5Jc"&gt;Click download and install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Q0ZnPX"&gt;Follow the on-screen prompts and configure Windows 11 settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="O2tuEY"&gt;If you don’t see the free Windows 11 upgrade, and your PC is supported, then you might be able to avoid the wait using Microsoft’s new Installation Assistant. We have a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22447994"&gt;guide here for skipping the line to upgrade to Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8PHrSv"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LArwcI"&gt; Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="x7IYrG"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Windows 11|104128" data-volume-uuid="65d6e1f88" data-volume-id="104128" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-90" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22708478/microsoft-windows-11-upgrade-free-os-how-to-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22708478/microsoft-windows-11-upgrade-free-os-how-to-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
