<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-09T11:41:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:41:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:41:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to swap your Xbox Series X controller’s connection between your Xbox and a phone or PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/09xdB7K6TvjUTi4VINJvpbiDswc=/9x0:2631x1748/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68793088/twarren_xboxseriesxcontroller_VLS_3616_2_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aoX8xz"&gt;Over the past couple of months, I’ve been playing a lot of games on my Xbox Series X, and following the release of the iOS 14.5 beta, which added support for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260671/ios-14-5-ps5-dualsense-xbox-series-x-controller-support"&gt;Xbox Series X controller&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been itching to stream my games from my console to my iPhone. However, I dreaded having to pair my controller with my phone — I figured that it might be a hassle, and I wasn’t sure how easy it would be to sync my controller between the two devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Og0eBt"&gt;Turns out, it’s a smooth process to sync the controller to my iPhone. Better yet, it’s easy to swap the controller’s connection back and forth between my iPhone and my Xbox Series X. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7FVnY5"&gt;Here’s how you set everything up: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="CnwFpW"&gt;First, you have to pair your Xbox Series X controller with your phone or PC. Activate sync mode on your controller by pressing and holding the sync button on the back, which is just above the USB-C port. After a couple seconds, the Xbox logo on the controller will flash rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IdKrIv"&gt;Then, on the device you’re trying to sync the controller with, look for the controller in the Bluetooth settings menu. Select the controller to pair it. (Using iOS 14.5 beta, my Xbox Series X controller first appeared with the name “Accessory,” but once I tapped it, it autofilled to “Xbox Wireless Controller” followed by a combination of letters and numbers.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pG1JT0wUkOxAx4e8EEGOwF-B9-w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21904644/twarren_xboxseriesxcontroller_VLS_3632_2_11.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press and hold the sync button on the back of your controller to pair it with your phone or PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="7icoZM"&gt;Once the controller is connected to your new device, have fun playing some games!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gYalMC"&gt;To use your controller with your Xbox Series X again, double-tap the sync button. The Xbox logo will flash slowly, and then the controller should reconnect with your console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EI8wwM"&gt;To switch the controller back to the other device, hold the sync button. The Xbox logo should flash rapidly for a few seconds, and then it should connect to your device. Double tap the sync button to switch it back to your console. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="lCqfb0"&gt;That’s it! I’ve been really pleased with how easy it is to switch between my console and my iPhone, and I suspect I’ll be playing even more Xbox games away from my console than I originally imagined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BLIAsK"&gt;One thing you should be aware of: this quick-swap functionality only works with the last mobile device or PC that the controller connected with, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmitFlow/status/1358695588838199297"&gt;according to Microsoft’s Timo Wolf&lt;/a&gt;. So if you want to quickly swap between your Xbox Series X and a different device, you’ll need to manually set up your controller with that new device first. And, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmitFlow/status/1358821215650131976"&gt;Wolf says&lt;/a&gt;, this method apparently only works for jumping between your Xbox and another device over Bluetooth — it won’t let you swap between an Xbox and the Xbox Wireless Adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22273528/how-to-xbox-series-x-controller-swap-connection-phone-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22273528/how-to-xbox-series-x-controller-swap-connection-phone-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:40:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:40:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola Moto G Power (2021) review: power over perks</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The G Power’s massive battery lasts for days, but other features have suffered to make way for it&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="N2DVeg"&gt;The Motorola Moto G Power is a $200 phone that does exactly what it claims — powers you through multiple days of use — but don’t expect any other bells or whistles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WilRjv"&gt;Battery is this phone’s whole deal. Its 5,000mAh battery is about as big as they come right now; it’s the same capacity you’ll find in top-of-the-line devices like the Galaxy S21 Ultra. Rather than making a more well-rounded phone, Motorola has pared back features here and there — a low-res screen, a slower processor — and gone all-in on its headline feature. Cheaper components allow Motorola to sell a $200 version of this phone, and they’re also less power-hungry, making the absolute most of that massive battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27KtjE"&gt;This device bears the same name as its predecessor from last year, but it differs in a few key ways. Rather than offering one model, this year the G Power is offered in the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Battery-Unlocked-Motorola-Camera-Silver/dp/B08NWDMR9N?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;aforementioned $200 variant&lt;/a&gt; with 3GB of RAM and a paltry 32GB of storage. There is also a 4GB RAM / 64GB storage option available for $250 (I tested the 32GB version). This year’s models drop the ultrawide camera and gain a slightly larger screen — 6.6-inch compared to 6.4-inch — with a lower 720p resolution than last year’s 1080p. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y6TH6s"&gt;If you choose to buy the Moto G Power, it will hold up its end of the bargain. The question is whether you can live with the significant sacrifices Motorola has made to get the biggest possible battery into the most affordable phone it could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qQXgVP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10333144"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-brPctpoFkMIqYPDnfvL1B3Wmck=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290841/ajohnson_210205_4399_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 6.6-inch display offers a relatively low resolution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TNamvm"&gt;Moto G Power screen and performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="PChwmX"&gt;The Moto G Power has a 6.6-inch LCD with 720p resolution. That’s not much resolution to stretch across a fairly large screen, and it shows. Images aren’t quite as sharp as they could be, and the screen overall looks a little dim and washed out to me. The phone itself is on the big side, though I find it a bit more comfortable to use one-handed than the slightly larger &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22255202/motorola-one-5g-ace-review"&gt;6.7-inch Motorola One 5G Ace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="9ku8bj"&gt;The G Power uses a Snapdragon 662 processor, and I felt the difference between this and the performance from a 700-series step-up chipset. It’s an extra beat slower jumping between apps and opening the camera. It requires more time to capture and process images in Portrait and Night Vision modes than the Ace does with the same main camera sensor. And heavier tasks like jumping in and out of Google Maps navigation shows noticeable stuttering. That said, you’ll be hard-pressed to find substantially better performance at the $200 price point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RKyNWiILXnlRn8Rg89S4p3h9bfc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290843/ajohnson_210205_4399_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto G Power offers biometric unlocking by way of a fingerprint sensor on the power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rlQMbm"&gt;Bottom line, the Power handles day-to-day tasks, plays videos, and navigates adequately. I just felt myself noticing the delays as I was using the phone, which over the course of a day added up to a less than satisfying experience. But for a $200 phone, it gets the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G6ESar"&gt;The G Power offers expandable storage by way of a microSD card slot, which feels necessary here. On the 32GB version I tested, 14GB of that storage is already occupied by Android 10 files. That’s simply not enough in 2021. You can pay $50 more for the 64GB model, but that also feels like spending too much to get too little. If you buy this phone, budget for a microSD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUGhmK"&gt;Motorola will offer an upgrade to Android 11 and says it will provide security updates for the G Power until January 2023. By then, years of updates will probably be slowing the phone down even more anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="14HxdS"&gt;Moto G Power battery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="oFQ9yX"&gt;The Moto G Power delivers on its headline feature. I started on Monday with a fully charged battery. I watched an episode of &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt;, you know, for testing. I navigated across town and back. I scrolled through Instagram... a lot. Email, web browsing, rinse and repeat; by day three of moderate use, I was only down to 40 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hnXkSG"&gt;Even after a trip outside of the house with a lot of picture-taking, I’m going on day four with a battery at 26 percent with just under six hours of screen-on time. I have charged my personal phone at least three times during this time span. We’ve been through roughly 12 news cycles. I myself have aged at least two years. But the Moto G Power carries on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ESF7d9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I have charged my personal phone at least three times during this time span&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lYzJ1P"&gt;No doubt the slightly slower processor and low-powered screen help boost those numbers. I left the screen at its default brightness while I tested it, which is just a little dimmer than I’d prefer. It certainly doesn’t look &lt;em&gt;overly &lt;/em&gt;bright at its maximum setting, so an additional hit on battery life is something to take into account if you like a bright screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NJsxN"&gt;Bear in mind that I spent a good chunk of that time at home on Wi-Fi, which is easier on the battery. During non-pandemic times, I would have spent more time out of the house on cell data. And six hours of screentime doesn’t exactly make me a power user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nia2QJ"&gt;If you do spend more time on data and do more power-hungry tasks like watch a lot of videos, you’d probably be looking at more like two full days. In any case, Motorola’s claim of up to three days of battery life is entirely reasonable, and you might do even better than that if you spend the bulk of your time on Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wmtbxb979it3GBV4NpdMOLpuSkw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290839/ajohnson_210205_4399_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cameras on the Moto G Power include a standard wide, ultrawide, and a depth sensor for portrait mode photos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eIrKqL"&gt;Moto G Power Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="gk9Doj"&gt;The G Power offers a 48-megapixel main camera that produces 12-megapixel images, a 2-megapixel macro camera, and a depth sensor to help create portrait mode photos. There’s also an 8-megapixel selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vXgBlW"&gt;The G Power uses the same main camera as the One 5G Ace, and similarly it takes nice photos in good light. It judges exposure well and captures plenty of detail, especially with close subjects. When its AI recognizes a scene like a landscape, colors look appropriately vibrant, but otherwise it tends toward flat, washed-out colors. In less good lighting conditions, things get a little messier where noise reduction smears a lot of detail. In high-contrast scenes where the camera has brightened shadows, there’s a fair amount of noise and / or noise reduction visible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Zw3ol7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10322645"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gYLMCB"&gt;As with the Ace, Night Vision tends to produce a washed-out looking image and in this case, it requires both you and your subject to hold still for several seconds. There’s some noticeable shutter lag in all photo modes — enough to make you wonder for a split second if you actually tapped the shutter button — and the display is laggy when panning around in portrait mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnOGxD"&gt;This camera is just okay, and that’s fine for a $200 phone. The Moto G Power doesn’t have the processing power to pull off more sophisticated HDR or low light photography — for that you’d need to step up to the $350 Pixel 4A. It also won’t be able to keep up with fast subjects, or even slow-moving subjects in low light, but that’s often a struggle for phones priced well above $200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6hqir7WeU1PEDah-vnyS6jq-17w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290838/ajohnson_210205_4399_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G Power makes good on its promise of multiday battery life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="PL6gw6"&gt;If you’re on a strict budget and long battery life is a necessity, then look no further than the Moto G Power. However, I hesitate to recommend it to someone who doesn’t meet that description. You will be making sacrifices in order to get that $200 price and multiday battery life. The base storage is way too anemic and the speed is noticeably pokey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5KJid"&gt;If you have some flexibility in your budget, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;$300 OnePlus N10 5G&lt;/a&gt; is a great upgrade pick with a better processor and camera. A bit more than that would get you a Pixel 4A with an excellent camera and a well-supported device with better longevity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="GD1Vfm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Be aware of its limitations and pack a little patience&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="sdfsHk"&gt;If $200 is the limit of your budget, the G Power is a fine pick — more so because there are few other options at this price. In addition to its dayslong battery life, it has a better processor than the $100-150 competition and you’re unlikely to find a substantially better screen or camera at this price. Just be aware of its limitations and pack a little patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="87xZ8z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="KmktRK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10333151"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:40:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:40:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony patent hints at Back Button Attachment for the PS5’s DualSense controller</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/39cvnJkxD6iGRHV9z8TXAuIU1x4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68793082/vpavic_4278_20201030_0150.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Aty8Qj"&gt;Sony may be working on a version of its Back Button Attachment for the PlayStation 5’s DualSense controller, according to a &lt;a href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2021021362&amp;amp;tab=PCTBIBLIO"&gt;patent filing&lt;/a&gt; published earlier this month. The filing, &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-may-be-working-on-a-back-button-attachment-for-ps5s-dualsense-controller?sf137897364=1"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;IGN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, shows off an accessory identical in appearance to the existing DualShock 4 Back Button Attachment, describing the product as an add-on with buttons that “may be mapped to controller buttons using customized button mapping pre-sets.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qmuCrc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21064320/sony-ps4-dualshock-4-back-button-attachment-review-gaming-pro-controller"&gt;Back Button Attachment&lt;/a&gt;, announced in late 2019, is Sony’s low-cost alternative to a proper pro controller. It costs just $30 and adds programmable buttons to the underside of the DualShock 4 that let you remap crucial functions reserved for, say, the X or O buttons. In turn, this lets you trigger the associated in-game actions without removing your thumbs on the joystick. In a smart move, Sony opted for smooth grip-like buttons that don’t float off the controller unlike the more popular floating paddle design, which meant they’re less prone to snapping off. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xs-ZXzfOFyFkLbHuB1eNDWZNjU0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22292190/LXAffSFxfgF4GUgDplAft2i42e_dFI0ja8wG_pHjj_F3vN6dsZhlxfCJdfnzGJT7JKH4gTUnugLQyrDKnQ9_skNu4y8ZE4IHIyo0jOe5NTBYPhQUmN2_LI5nsGBVXQfNER_03U95FydJ0Rl3SmW7GlNLZqGJvqftwbzWNp3pyoc__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LBNtYk"&gt;Extra programmable buttons can provide a noticeable advantage when playing high-stakes competitive games. Prior to the Back Button Attachment, PlayStation fans had to rely on third-party manufacturers like Scuf for programmable back paddles and other pro controller features like customizable thumbsticks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNSHB8"&gt;Although some fans may have wanted the PS5 controller to ship with removable back paddles, Sony didn’t end up doing that when the DualSense was unveiled last year and launched with the new console in November. And due to the shape of the device, the existing Back Button Attachment does not work on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w2Dn8H"&gt;So it stands to reason Sony would develop an upgraded version for the DualSense, but it’s anyone’s guess when we might see that translate from a patent filing into a real consumer product. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274499/sony-ps5-dualsense-back-button-attachment-patent-filing-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274499/sony-ps5-dualsense-back-button-attachment-patent-filing-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:35:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:35:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Razer Hammerhead True Wireless Pro review: good sound at the wrong price</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Razer’s second set of true wireless earbuds nail fit and audio but fall flat elsewhere&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="epf36V"&gt;Razer’s Hammerhead True Wireless Pro earbuds are a major improvement over the company’s first pair of true wireless earbuds. They’ve switched from an open-air design to a sealed fit; have better sound, thanks to that decision (and a partnership with THX); and they offer adequate active noise cancellation. Razer has thrown in a generous heap of ear tips (including Comply foam), and there’s also a low-latency gaming mode to keep the earbuds in sync with your mobile gaming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sx3tZE"&gt;But the main stumbling block with Razer’s new earbuds is price. At $200, the Hammerhead True Wireless Pros face a tough mix of competition — and we’ve reached a point where many of those alternatives have moved beyond the core basics of fit, sound quality, and ANC to offer more unique features. In Apple’s case, that’s Spatial Audio. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;For Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, it’s the clever new speech detection feature that enables ambient sound as soon as you start talking. Jabra’s earbuds can pair with two devices at once. Razer doesn’t really have anything to match these perks (unless you’re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; enthused about that gaming mode), and the result is earbuds that are perfectly satisfactory but fail to stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uMcCsm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10332736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EMtiGl"&gt;From a design standpoint, the Hammerhead True Wireless Pros are your typical stem-style earbuds. They’re a good deal larger than the AirPods Pro and less curvy, but the matte black finish ups the sleek factor. No, the Razer logo on the outside doesn’t light up. That’s the area where you’ll tap (or hold) to access the various gesture controls, which proved responsive in my tests, can be customized to your liking, and cover all functionality except for volume. Below this on each stem is a mic used for active noise cancellation; the mics that work for calls are positioned at the bottom of the stems for optimal voice pickup. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lTlkOcJiv5OFvHMVSYg0qrHLzy4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22289627/DSCF2722_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to a plethora of included ear tips, it’s easy to find a good, comfortable fit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vEPhA6"&gt;Razer packages &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; sets of ear tips in the box: there’s standard silicone (S, M, L) and a grippier version (S, M, L) that’s meant for active use cases like running. You’ll also find a medium set of Comply foam tips that, in my case, made for a terrific seal. I ended up keeping those on all the time. Razer definitely gets props for doing everything it can to help customers find the right fit, when many other earbud makers continue to phone it in with just three sets of tips. The Hammerhead True Wireless Pros are IPX4-rated for sweat resistance, making them suitable for general workouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RZYGKe"&gt;Razer has packed 10mm drivers into these earbuds, and they’ve gone through THX certification to “present a rich, balanced sound stage for all your movies, music, and gaming.” I can’t speak to the rigors of THX’s process, but the Hammerhead True Wireless Pros do sound articulate, well-balanced, and have some extra bass to spare if you want to dial up that part of the audio. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xPxcINgDnDXDbsG7eQsKHo9Xxsg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22292099/razerapp.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Razer’s mobile app lets you adjust EQ and customize the controls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HS1lAd"&gt;Speaking of which, Razer’s mobile app lets you fully customize the EQ to your preference or choose from presets. The default “THX” mode is where I stayed, but it’s nice that you’ve got full control over the whole EQ range. The Hammerhead True Wireless Pros can deftly hop between genres without ever meeting something they can’t handle. Codec support covers the standard AAC and SBC, with no Apt-X on the Android side. Like many other earbuds, these will automatically pause music if you remove one from your ear and resume when it’s put back in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2GOv0ldB_GTQuuwoIukmzwJldjM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290351/DSCF3038_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The case is compact but lacks wireless charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BI_KrtzLU2MkdJwL9bTRuCyiVpA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22292035/DSCF3036_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The buds sit securely in the case whether you’re using silicone or Comply foam tips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eP5c5U"&gt;Unfortunately, the active noise cancellation doesn’t live up to that impressive sound quality. The Hammerhead True Wireless Pros approach ANC in the same way as other premium earbuds, producing anti-noise to counter the ambient sounds around you. But Razer’s ANC is very average: it’s efficient at hushing the constant, low-level hums and whirring you get in many rooms or office spaces, but it doesn’t live up to other earbuds at this price level. The Jabra Elite 85t and Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro best Razer here, and they’re soundly defeated by more expensive options like the Bose QuietComfort Earbuds and AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dbcSmf"&gt;If anything, it feels like the passive isolation I get, thanks to the Comply tips, does the most work at blocking outside noise. Razer’s transparency / ambient mode also sounds digitized compared to the best of what’s out there, and the voice microphones are passable but nothing to write home about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SSDaXRyCgwOpGPmTn-2tT9KvSs0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22289619/DSCF2719_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hammerhead True Wireless Pro earbuds use a familiar elongated stem design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TnbfBNqC69DBqRpqEAssFsuLK5k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22289655/DSCF2711.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Razer offers a TPU case for your case with an optional carabiner. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cMbbgu"&gt;So then we’re left with that special gaming mode feature, which Razer says reduces Bluetooth latency to 60 milliseconds. That should help keep up with the action in fast-moving mobile game titles, and it seemed to do the trick just fine in my experience. But the company also notes that gaming mode will drain the battery faster, and that’s an area where these earbuds already struggle. The Hammerhead True Wireless Pros advertise up to four hours of continuous listening, which is definitely on the low end and below competitors like Jabra (5.5 hours), Samsung (five hours), and Sony (six hours). The well-built carrying case has enough juice for you to reach 20 hours of total playback, but it lacks wireless charging. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/slf2-HM5YX4bhwJGOuY8aEgbdN8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22289666/DSCF2716_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hammerhead True Wireless Pros are rated IPX4 for sweat resistance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="dJ8hGf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10334033"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RhXAFv"&gt;Gaming mode might be a boon if you spend hours playing &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, but I didn’t find any obvious sync issues with more casual games when the earbuds were on their normal setting. It just doesn’t go far enough in helping justify the $200 cost of Razer’s Hammerhead True Wireless Pros — especially when competitors offer more advantageous tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gh_-EiPhpR1DFvtTm2UPhM3SeJ8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22292064/DSCF3032_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These earbuds would be much more compelling at a lower price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="AoQIBh"&gt;Razer’s Hammerhead True Wireless Pros would be among my top recommendations at $150 or below. They sound quite good across all sorts of music, Razer goes above and beyond with ear tips, and I didn’t mention other bonuses like a two-year warranty. They’re a big improvement over the original Hammerhead True Wireless buds. But they’re outshined in the $200 category that they live in right now. Middle-of-the-road ANC and battery life on the short side drag them down to a point where it’s hard to reconcile performance and cost. A price cut would put Razer’s second-generation true wireless earbuds in a much better place and help them shine for the qualities they &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; deliver. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bAzHJK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IXfix4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9xm1ih"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22272549/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-pro-review-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22272549/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-pro-review-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:15:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:15:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>The UAE reaches Mars for the first time with its Hope probe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4zOczOYOgNB-n3fiIKnyAjvu3Ns=/0x0:2234x1489/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68792948/Knowledge_transfer_BackSide.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;UAE’s Hope probe sits in a clean room before launch.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bu1snQ"&gt;A probe from the United Arab Emirates successfully reached Mars on Tuesday, earning the country a spot in a small group of spacefaring powers that have sent spacecraft to study the fourth planet from the Sun. The UAE hopes the mission will yield key discoveries on Martian weather patterns and catalyze a new science and technology sector as it looks to wean its economy from oil dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldD1av"&gt;Hope carried out an intricate and fully automatic maneuver called a Mars Orbit Insertion (MOI) on time at 10:30AM ET, mission engineers said. This maneuver slams the brakes on the spacecraft’s final leg of its journey, slowing Hope’s cruising speed of 75,000 mph down to 11,000 mph by firing all six of its Delta-V thrusters for 27 minutes. The deceleration allowed Hope to get swept up in a “capture orbit” around Mars, officially reaching the Red Planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SsF4hj"&gt;Mission control didn’t have confirmation of a successful MOI burn until 11:14AM ET because of a 22-minute roundtrip communications delay through NASA’s Deep Space Network. Manual, real-time control is impossible, so Hope has been programmed to carry out these orbital dances on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KVRxd3"&gt;As expected, the Hope mission team briefly lost contact with the probe as it flew around the far side of Mars, cutting off radio signals for about 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bDwfud"&gt;For mission managers at the Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Center in Dubai, Hope’s arrival at Mars was a nerve-racking climax in the UAE’s first mission to deep space. The spacecraft traveled 300 million miles after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/19/21330417/uae-hope-spacecraft-emirates-mars-mission-launch-success"&gt;launching&lt;/a&gt; from Japan’s Tanegashima Space Center last July, as Earth and Mars aligned in their orbits around the Sun. It’s also the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266752/uae-china-nasa-mars-missions"&gt;first of three&lt;/a&gt; Mars spacecraft visiting the planet this month, with a Chinese spacecraft arriving tomorrow and NASA’s Perseverance rover following next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mVd8yp"&gt;With a successful injection into Mars’ orbit, the spacecraft is on track to spend two years capturing global snapshots of the planet to better understand its atmosphere and weather changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYncIp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274189/uae-mars-hope-probe-spacecraft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274189/uae-mars-hope-probe-spacecraft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:06:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:06:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s every game coming to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ctg6U9v5jr9RrXkzgL82pqnQOXQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67735830/vpavic_4261_20201023_0084.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;For the early adopters of next-gen hardware&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="cyuvuR"&gt;Just over two months after their release, the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S continue to be some of the most desirable gadgets in the world. While it’s still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"&gt;very difficult&lt;/a&gt; to get your hands on a new console, those lucky enough to own one can enjoy something unprecedented in modern gaming history. For the first time, next-gen console owners can take their existing library — whether it’s physical, digital, or a mix of the two — and bring it to a next-gen platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNh3ro"&gt;That gives consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play and what performance benefits are worthwhile enough to upgrade. And technologies like cross-platform play and now even cross-generation support will allow people to still play with their friends, even if they don’t upgrade to the latest gaming hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5uXjX1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Giving consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CveWHl"&gt;Yes, both consoles arrived within seven years of the last generation of console hardware. And while it’s likely within the first year of both consoles’ lifespan that many of the hottest titles may launch on last- and current-gen simultaneously, there’s still a good chunk of games that will be exclusive titles playable only a PS5 or Xbox Series X / S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u79IWA"&gt;Besides 4K, the solid-state drives, and other spec changes, Microsoft and Sony have pledged to support close to every title in the existing console platforms’ libraries. Every Xbox, Xbox 360, and Xbox One game currently playable on existing Xbox One hardware (minus Kinect games) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326805/xbox-series-x-xbox-one-game-support-backward-compatible-feature-kinect"&gt;will be playable on the Series X / S&lt;/a&gt;, while Sony is supporting a “vast majority” of PS4 games, totaling &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440748/ps5-playstation-5-99-percent-backward-compatible-ps4-games-jim-ryan"&gt;more than 4,000 titles&lt;/a&gt;. With both consoles early into their lifespan, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163921/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-old-games-next-gen-consoles"&gt;easy for many to return to older games&lt;/a&gt; to help fill the gap in between long wait periods for more titles to be added to each console’s library. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dwgnjo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new consoles let you take a majority of your existing libraries with you&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUlnZM"&gt;This changes the calculus a bit with regard to buying a new console. No longer do you have to abandon what you were playing on your old device and start anew. And thanks to some genuinely consumer-friendly initiatives like Xbox Smart Delivery and similar upgrade programs, plenty of the games we own now or are planning to buy in the next couple of months will not only work on the new platforms, but in most cases, they’ll also come with free upgrades from the standard PS4 and Xbox One versions. Sony also introduced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/28/21538383/sony-playstation-plus-collection-available-games-november-free-bugsnax"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection&lt;/a&gt;, a library of PS4 games available for free with its online subscription service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lmWX6y"&gt;That leaves us with one big issue: how do you know what new games are coming out for which platforms and when? There’s also the painstaking process of parsing whether a game company is giving out a free next-gen upgrade of a cross-gen title, charging a little extra, or releasing a next-gen-only game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsrpjD"&gt;2021 is packed full of new releases and full optimizations of cross-gen games that should further pad out what’s available to play on your new system of choice. We’ve compiled the list below to help you understand every game coming out during the first year of the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GM3UJT"&gt;This excludes games without release dates that may have been previously announced — like &lt;em&gt;Elder Scrolls VI &lt;/em&gt;and the &lt;em&gt;Fable &lt;/em&gt;reboot, for example — and any games that were released for either console in 2020, including launch titles. We’ve also chosen only to list release dates for games where the publisher has chosen a concrete date with both day and month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="hTe555"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:9552771"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4tQEqz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 4th, 2020, 12:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added that &lt;/em&gt;ARK: Survival Evolved&lt;em&gt; recently released an Xbox Series X enhancement update that will be available to new console owners on launch day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rC6OMy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version of this post incorrectly stated &lt;/em&gt;Haven &lt;em&gt;would be a PS5-only release and that &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder &lt;em&gt;would be Xbox Series-only at launch. Those are incorrect; Haven is also coming to Xbox Series X and Xbox One and as part of Game Pass at launch, and &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;is slated for PS5 mid-November. We regret the errors. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qPYdhq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 15th, 2021, 5PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add additional titles releasing in 2021 and update any games that may have been delayed into this year. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yywDTp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n76LJk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>3D audio could be the next big podcast trend</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sX20FFvPnBAXmc9XKL2JcT0uVvI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68792815/akrales_191106_3774_0085.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FkEN6S"&gt;Companies looking to make a name in podcasting have mostly done so by spending lots of money on flashy names, big acquisitions, and valuable content libraries. But increasingly, the audio itself, and the recording techniques used to capture it, are becoming the selling point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74afZ1"&gt;Today, iHeart Media announced that it’s investing in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/2/12/8021733/3d-audio-3dio-binaural-immersive-vr-sound-times-square-new-york"&gt;binaural audio&lt;/a&gt;, also known as 3D audio, which effectively places listeners in the room of a recording and makes them feel like it’s happening around them. Listening to a show in 3D audio sounds like you’re in the scene and hearing things exactly as you would in real life because the microphones are often shaped &lt;a href="https://www.fullcompass.com/prod/027605-neumann-ku-100-dummy-head-binaural-stereo-microphone?dfw_tracker=36058-027605&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA34OBBhCcARIsAG32uvOk4Ktki16Z5S-MbAPDcJcRa4EnBjshSEmAWZLVre5UfFYmeJ4es0MaAtVHEALw_wcB"&gt;like a human head&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://reverb.com/item/32682447-3dio-fs-binaural-microphone-ex-vat?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_campaign=11253364499&amp;amp;utm_content=campaignid=11253364499_adgroupid=110438597997_productpartitionid=966842144580=merchantid=321731946_productid=32682447_keyword=_device=c_adposition=_matchtype=_creative=469851967394&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA34OBBhCcARIsAG32uvOf83_uhC9Qj38JrJBJ-n_DJNEfp336l55yAcQkKr4JXKkQNlvI0CcaAn2GEALw_wcB"&gt;pair of ears&lt;/a&gt;. This means the sounds hit your ears as they would normally, a zooming car, for example, might be louder in your right ear and then move to your left as it passes, slowly fading from your right. (&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s audio director Andrew Marino published a ton of 3D audio clips &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/2018/7/12/17032058/headphones-sennheiser-ambeo-smart-headset-review-binaural-3d-audio"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you want some examples.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5C24pN"&gt;iHeart is launching an entire slate of shows dedicated to the technique, under the name &lt;a href="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/1119-iheart-3d-audio-77097007/"&gt;iHeart 3D Audio&lt;/a&gt;. It will feature programs made with Blumhouse Television as well as podcast creator and producer Aaron Mahnke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYdapg"&gt;The company has built three studios specifically equipped to handle 3D audio recording and employs a team of 12 producers who are trained in capturing binaural audio. By the end of 2021, iHeart plans to have 10 to 12 series produced with the technology, says Conal Byrne, president of the iHeartPodcast Network. The team also plans to host live radio events because iHeart owns hundreds of US radio stations, during which it’ll encourage listeners to don a pair of headphones to enjoy the binaural experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DSQ5rR"&gt;“I think a lot more should be in 3D audio than is,” Byrne says. “And so as we look across the slate of shows we have from A-to-Z, across 2021, most of those, there’s a 3D audio version that’s probably better than what [we’re] doing normally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nXmBgO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;iHeart now has three binaural audio-equipped studios&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3cr7d"&gt;Byrne sees the form as a tool for storytelling, sure, but also as a new way for sponsors to send a message — and another way for iHeart to differentiate itself from all the companies looking for brand partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhRHdY"&gt;“I think 3D audio to make a new kind of a 30-60-two minute ad could really kind of — I’m not going to suggest will reinvent podcast advertising — but could definitely push it further toward immersion,” he says. “So we’re going to offer that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="231yP2"&gt;iHeart isn’t the only network to harness 3D audio, and creators have been doing so for years. Indie network &lt;a href="https://www.theparagoncollective.com/"&gt;Paragon Collective&lt;/a&gt; has used the technology for some of its narrative shows as well, including &lt;em&gt;The Oyster&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Darkest Night.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1lZrP"&gt;“What I really like about 3D audio is it just sucks people in, so where I’ll use it a lot now is when a character’s whispering to another one, so you can get in their head, or it makes a huge difference when you’re using these sound effects on 3D audio and the user’s in the middle of the room,” says Alex Aldea, founder and CEO of Paragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5uaYv0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;3D audio isn’t new technology — creators have been using it for years&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RsgJOT"&gt;Binaural could become more popular than ever for a few reasons. For one, it’s more immersive, which is good for getting people to listen and stick through a podcast. It’s also compatible with any pair of headphones, meaning listeners don’t need special equipment or software to enjoy it. And finally, narrative podcasts are booming with many networks looking to gain an audience for their shows and a way to differentiate themselves. If you try 3D audio and love it, you might look for more shows like it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kK8hzz"&gt;Another network, QCODE, which makes narrative shows with big-name stars, is looking to take the next step in podcast audio and create surround-sound experiences. The company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; it’s been mixing its shows in Dolby Atmos. Crucially, no major podcast apps support the standard yet, despite companies like Apple supporting it on their hardware devices, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;, the HomePod, and Apple TV 4K. QCODE is essentially preparing for a day when podcast app makers are ready to support the standard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JyaKsG"&gt;“Creating these environments and this experience is  going to be a really new thing, and a really positive one for this type of storytelling,” says Rob Herting, CEO at QCODE. “It’s not to say that it’s a replacement for good storytelling, and you can’t think of it like a gimmick, but I think when used well, it can be really, really impactful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y8ki4u"&gt;Podcasts are increasingly becoming IP machines, or a way to make a story come to life and sell a potential film or TV adaptation. Surround sound and 3D audio are just the next steps in that journey to keep listeners tuned in and make podcasts seem even closer to the experience of watching something on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22273072/podcast-audio-3d-dolby-atmos-iheart-qcode"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22273072/podcast-audio-3d-dolby-atmos-iheart-qcode</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T10:50:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T10:50:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this Bloomberg story on how Tim Cook turned Apple into a $2.3 trillion powerhouse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Key Speakers At 2019 Dreamforce Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nqN3TEeX9S3C5UOfrEmz2dcA6JI=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68792737/1183490758.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uzis5m"&gt;Much has been said and written over the years about the post-Steve Jobs era of Apple and whether CEO Tim Cook’s operations-heavy approach to running the iPhone maker has proved more or less successful than Jobs’ at times cutthroat dealmaking and his obsessive, detail-oriented product development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNhZI5"&gt;It’s hard to argue now that Cook hasn’t taken Apple to all-new heights — the company is more valuable than it’s ever been, and the wondrous success of the iPhone over the last decade has allowed Apple to build hugely successful secondary businesses around the Apple Watch, AirPods, the iPad, and much more. But how exactly Cook, a logistics expert with deep ties to Asia and a much more measured temperament than his former boss, pulled this off is still a topic of debate — and the focus of a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-09/this-is-how-tim-cook-transformed-apple-aapl-after-steve-jobs?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;great new &lt;em&gt;Businessweek&lt;/em&gt; story from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman and Austin Carr&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5UrwZ"&gt;In “Apple Is the $2.3 Trillion Fortress That Tim Cook Built,” Gurman and Carr recount how Cook managed the tricky balancing act of keeping Apple a thriving business throughout the aggressively anti-China Trump presidency and amid the ongoing coronavirus pandemic. The piece also raises the important question of how Cook will manage Apple under a Democratic president and within a much more adversarial regulatory environment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LITaky"&gt;It’s a great examination of Cook’s leadership style and one we don’t often hear about, as Apple still goes to great lengths to keep the conversation surrounding the company focused on new products. There are great anecdotes about Cook’s relationship with Foxconn founder Terry Gou, a relationship instrumental to Apple’s unprecedented overseas manufacturing ambitions that transformed the company into what it is today, and Cook’s masterful handling of the Trump White House and the former president’s obsession with optics. Go read the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-09/this-is-how-tim-cook-transformed-apple-aapl-after-steve-jobs?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;story from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22274333/apple-tim-cook-china-bloomberg-steve-jobs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22274333/apple-tim-cook-china-bloomberg-steve-jobs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T10:30:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T10:30:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>What’s on your desk, Becca Farsace?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JjvDlaRaLaDwnMOd39KsdPkhquw=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67563965/bfarsace_200924_4210_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Trees, pandas, earbuds, and Abe Lincoln&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="Jbyn5q"&gt;Many people who used to commute to an office every day have passed the six-month mark as remote workers, and we are now working from home offices, dining room tables, desks set up in the corners of bedrooms, or living room sofas. The folks here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; are no different, and we thought it might be interesting to talk to some of our co-workers and find out how they’re coping with roommates, kids, spouses, and other distractions — not to mention having to find a place in their homes to double as workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K0uP3F"&gt;For this article, we talk to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; video director Becca Farsace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="55789S"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re one of The Verge’s video directors — what exactly do you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cjWDp0"&gt;I am! How friggin’ cool is that? I drink a whole lot of coffee while simultaneously filming, hosting, and editing videos about technology for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. It’s truly a dream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DRybao"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could we start by talking about the space? That’s a nice little nook you have.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4uGXX"&gt;When I was apartment hunting, the first thing I would look for was a space that this desk could fit in. This desk means a lot to me, so there was no way I was leaving it behind, but more on that later. In my current apartment, this is the only wall long enough to fit this six-foot-long slab of a tree, so I really didn’t have much of a choice. But it ended up working out well with a really nice view out to the yard on one side and Abe Lincoln on the other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FbriPN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That desk is beautiful! I was wondering if you’d made it yourself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsKBDW"&gt;Oh heck, yeah! I am always looking for ways to bring more natural elements into my home. The inspiration came from those really beautiful, long dining room tables you see in fancy log cabins. But I knew I would never have the space for that in a tiny Brooklyn apartment, and I also knew I couldn’t afford one of those. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="InUw45"&gt;So I went to the &lt;a href="https://www.bigreuse.org/"&gt;Big Reuse, my favorite secondhand store&lt;/a&gt; here in Brooklyn, where they sell unfinished, large pieces of wood, and decided I would make a desk out of one of these pieces instead. My partner at the time and I didn’t have too much money to spend, so we picked out a piece of wood that had a large crack in it, and was therefore discounted. We borrowed one of the Big Reuse’s rolling carts, and we rolled this beautiful six-foot-long piece of trunk home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The desk was made out of a large, unfinished piece of wood." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IpigeRQzdMeyXDL4JHsKBgYG84c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919214/bfarsace_200923_4210_0043.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Metal pipes were used to create the legs." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MaP3XIxRRVXPbPyVkef5xUEx5LY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919216/bfarsace_200923_4210_0038.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A workspace created by found objects." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hlfpFNaD8PPzIDhHCm7z3OANTTU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919211/bfarsace_200923_4210_0058.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A workspace created by found objects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WR4A7i"&gt;We then played Legos with metal pipes &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lowes.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21456362%2Fremote-work-desk-setup-video-director-home-office-tech#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on the floor of Lowes&lt;/a&gt; to create the legs. Everything about building this desk was a challenge, and there is certainly so much more to the story — like having to glue the crack together because I dropped the piece of wood in the backyard literally as soon as we got it home. But every day I get to work on the insides of a tree and at a desk that I made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taduFE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cool! Now tell me about your tech.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vyvG16"&gt;Oh man, where do I begin? Since I am reviewing products, I have a lot of tech coming and going, often multiple pieces of one type of tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuRysb"&gt;I have the most earbuds though, and I am constantly switching between them so that I can really understand what works best when and for what. For example, as I’m writing this it’s 11:30AM, and already today I have used &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21400695/google-pixel-buds-2-2020-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;Pixel Buds&lt;/a&gt; on a walk, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt; on a video call, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356260/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-review-wireless-earbuds-beans-design-specs-price"&gt;Galaxy Beans (Galaxy Buds Live)&lt;/a&gt; when I was making coffee. Those three are my daily drivers and all live on my desk when I’m not using them. (I have learned if they don’t have a home they will get lost.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="fdSnNO"&gt;
&lt;div id="P8Pb7z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502839" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="R17vLX"&gt;
&lt;div id="a9hy2j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503020" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="6zsCBB"&gt;
&lt;p id="ClCnID"&gt;When the Vox office shut down for COVID-19, I agreed to do every supercut (that’s a video where we cut down live events to only the most important information for our viewers). But only if I could take home &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161358/mac-pro-review-apple-display-xdr-adobe-hardware-software-price-video"&gt;Mac Pro&lt;/a&gt; (a 3.2GHz 16-core Intel Xeon W processor, two Radeon Pro Vega II graphics cards, 96GB of RAM, and a 1TB SSD) and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"&gt;Pro Display XDR&lt;/a&gt;. And if I’m being honest, I’m going to be really sad when I have to go back to my late-2013 iMac. (I foresee a large update coming to that because I simply don’t know how I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; go back.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="1qD5dT"&gt;
&lt;div id="ogxSjV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10332578" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0SjHHk"&gt;
&lt;div id="PURbwV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10332742" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="2H5PvS"&gt;
&lt;p id="r5Zi5G"&gt;Anyhow, the Pro Display doesn’t have a webcam or a mic, so for video calls and working away from my desk, I have a 15-inch 2016 MacBook Pro with an i7 Intel processor, 16GB of RAM, and Radeon Pro 460 graphics card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hP3ZTH"&gt;I have a 500GB Samsung SDD that I use for the projects I am currently working on and three other hard disk drives I back everything up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sbV1r"&gt;There is also almost always a camera I am reviewing on my desk, along with its lenses or mods. When this was written in October 2020, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437419/gopro-hero-9-review"&gt;GoPro Hero9&lt;/a&gt; and Sony a7C were sitting up here with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="TyjRdf"&gt;
&lt;div id="fl6Ba0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10332746" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="jpQC5W"&gt;
&lt;div id="Zi46Tv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10332759" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8yd3Te"&gt;
&lt;p id="lDPO7i"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s a great setup you have in that filing cabinet. How did you do it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KrmmH1"&gt;I have so many cords and dongles and just small pieces! So a filing cabinet just made sense to me: a large container that doesn’t need to be treated delicately and provides maximum storage. I also love the industrial look of filing cabinets, and they are easy and cheap to thrift. The blue dividers inside are a funnier story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9ghww"&gt;I really hate buying anything new and am a huge fan of upcycling. Which has led me to the very abundant dumpsters in NYC. (My parents get so mad when I tell people I dumpster dive — sorry, Mom!) There are large warehouses by my apartment that house many small businesses, and when COVID-19 started, sadly, many of them went out of business, which led to whole offices being dumped into dumpsters and driven away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6xYT4"&gt;The best dumpster was from a clothing company that was really going for that Brooklyn outdoorsman vibe. They had tons of buttons and zippers and pieces of fabric, and along with all of those things, they had many, many dividers. I found those blue dividers deep in that dumpster before I even had the filing cabinet, but absolutely had an organization problem. Ugh, that was a great dumpster. (To be clear, I do not recommend diving into just any dumpster. There can be hella glass and pests that you really don’t want to come in contact with, but all of that is for another post.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A homemade standing desk" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CcAsA0yvL0CJ2UFEaEg-7PsLVJU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919232/bfarsace_200923_4210_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A homemade standing desk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Fp4MfN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That laptop looks like it’s about to fall off. Do you ever lose tech to the floor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYBuA6"&gt;You know, I don’t lose as much to the floor as you might think — knock on wood. I have broken enough tech to really make sure it is secure before I leave it. Plus, this is a standing desk, so a fall from this can truly be deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xL2OZH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like me, your desk is littered with little toys and other tchotchkes. I count offhand: Must Go Hard water bottle, Little Panda, the rock pile, the plant, a troll doll, and more. Are there any that have stories that you could tell?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybJ6Se"&gt;Play is extremely important to me. It is what inspires me, it is a large form of therapy for me, and it really informs my style. So I like to fill my desk with things to play with. These objects are constantly rotating but currently I have two favorites: the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/HmiL-U-Stealing-Automatic-Speaking-Creative/dp/B07WJ1G3KD/ref=sr_1_5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Little Panda piggy bank&lt;/a&gt; and the rocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HT843J"&gt;The “Little Panda” comes out of the box and says “Hello!” when you put a coin on the white button, then he snatches the coin and says “Thank you!” A really close friend gave it to me too, so besides the fun it provides, I think of her when I use it, which always makes me smile. I keep a pile of coins next to him, it’s seriously so cute and fun! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PLKd7s"&gt;Then, the rocks, I just move around in my hands endlessly. I would classify them as a “tinker toy” but also a subtle way to keep me close to nature and keep me grounded. I just love this Earth so much and am beyond grateful for the beauty it provides, so the rocks keep me close to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="sgUcpc"&gt;
&lt;div id="SUL5sS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10332769" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Xz2tSO"&gt;
&lt;p id="qpH3Nc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is that a portrait of Lincoln on your wall?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzFoLL"&gt;Oh yeah, good ole Abe always watching over me. Most of the things I surround myself with have emotional value, but he was just a classic thrift find. I saw him and just knew I needed to see that every day. It’s actually a replica of Lincoln’s portrait that hangs in the White House. The funny part is I brought him home and put him on a hook that a previous tenant had hung and he just fit so perfectly. It truly feels like he was meant to be there. And I named my Wi-Fi after him because he is right above the router. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The “Little Panda”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kT9hvLyT3Nzugo2mQ4cGWqNKftE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919229/bfarsace_200923_4210_0012.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Rocks make for a natural Tinker Toy" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U-zXYa9ja_gYgyUVIYzwt8EvVeE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919227/bfarsace_200923_4210_0013.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Toys, notes, photos, and other stuff" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Uty5W6Pk2pIIK0AxbRxXAMqDce8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21919224/bfarsace_200923_4210_0019.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toys, notes, photos, and other stuff.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oOSXMZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you keep the world out while you’re working — or do you need to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XWUWv6"&gt;If I’m being honest, I’m not great at keeping the world out. There are simply so many fun things in my home I could be messing with, but I know this about myself and actively set boundaries and rules to stay focused. A timer has become my greatest friend and worst enemy. I usually set the timer in one- or two-hour increments during which I cannot leave my desk or stop working until the time runs out. Quite literally, I need to chain myself to my desk, but I have found that once I get into a flow I don’t have trouble staying in it, I just need to get into that flow first. And tying myself to things gets me flowing with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ty1Cfd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you’d like to change or add to the current setup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JQckRk"&gt;I have been wanting a stool with a back for awhile now. I stand 75 percent of my day, but when I do sit I find my stool to not be very comfy, and I think I would be a bit more productive if I was more comfortable in that 15 percent of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwK73V"&gt;I also have this piece of wall that has nothing on it above and to the left of my monitor. I try to let walls decorate themselves with things that naturally find their way into my life, like Abe, but this has been white for a few months now, and it’s starting to bother me. Whatever it ends up being, I know it can’t be too big or it will make the wall feel small, and I know that it can’t be in a beefy frame that might compete with Abe. I think about this at least once a day and have been eyeing &lt;a href="https://oxfordpennant.com/"&gt;Oxford Pennant’s website&lt;/a&gt; for awhile now… Suggestions are welcome!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O10lW8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything we haven’t covered that you’d like to tell us about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7sge07"&gt;I just wanna say thank you to everyone reading this. I feel so grateful for being able to wake up and create every day, and without everyone tuning in I simply wouldn’t be able to do that. It’s weird times man, but the support I have received from y’all has really been such a source of light. Okay! That’s all. Sappy Becca out. Be well, buds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3Oyjkk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What’s on your desk, Kaitlin Hatton?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21409065/remote-work-desk-setup-from-home-office-tech"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xEwj3V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 9th, 2021, 10:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on October 1st, 2020; the prices have been updated. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1cEpb"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21456362/remote-work-desk-setup-video-director-home-office-tech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21456362/remote-work-desk-setup-video-director-home-office-tech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-09T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Visible customers can now get 5G and use eSIMs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tRPr7-QCR4o6Q49AO015tkRUWKE=/128x0:1508x920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68792395/1_SmzBzHMl2wygmhoz_KWrGg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;eSIM makes it possible to activate your device with a new carrier without waiting for a physical SIM card. | Image: Visible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Nyx3bQ"&gt;Visible, the Verizon-owned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/24/18195784/verizon-visible-carrier-selling-devices-iphone-galaxy"&gt;MVNO&lt;/a&gt;, is adding some new services that make using it just a bit more like subscribing to one of the big wireless carriers. Starting today, Visible now supports activating service via eSIM. It only works with recent, compatible iPhones, but Visible says it will add support for Android devices soon. The company also is offering 5G service (with limits) and free calling and messaging to Canada and Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kgbEQY"&gt;Visible customers’ access to Verizon’s 5G network has some important fine print: both Nationwide and Ultra Wideband are included, but data speeds will be capped at 200Mbps. Direct carrier subscribers (AKA Verizon customers) also have priority on the fastest data speeds during times of congestion. That’s par for the course for MVNOs. While they can offer competitively priced plans, they’re commonly subject to limitations like speed reductions for heavy data users and streaming video at 480p only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5U9XB2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Both Nationwide and Ultra Wideband are included, but data speeds will be capped at 200Mbps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NFKaiv"&gt;eSIM support makes a lot of sense with Visible’s all-digital ethos: customers with compatible phones can switch to Visible without waiting for a physical SIM card to be mailed. By opting for an embedded rather than removable SIM card, eSIM technology makes it easier to switch carriers using an existing device. That’s very appealing to MVNOs trying to compete with the big carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gKrSSV"&gt;Many MVNOs don’t support eSIM yet, but more are coming this year. H2o Wireless and Pure Talk &lt;a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/wireless/2-prepaid-brands-offer-esim-a-sign-mvnos-are-ready-to-tap-technology"&gt;will both offer eSIM support sometime this quarter&lt;/a&gt;. But while it makes initially signing on with a new carrier easier, eSIM presents its own drawbacks, including a more complicated process when switching to a new phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJvfLi"&gt;Visible’s announcement today also includes news about its Party Pay plans, which allow customers to share plan costs while maintaining separate accounts and billing. Previously capped at four people, these plans can now include an unlimited number of lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9iVAw5"&gt;Finally, Visible will no longer charge for calls and texts between the mainland US and Canada, Mexico, US Virgin Islands, and Puerto Rico. It’s increasingly the norm for US carriers to include calling and SMS from the US to neighboring regions without an extra fee or at low monthly flat rate. All of these features (except for upcoming Android eSIM support) are available starting today.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22269306/visible-5g-esim-verizon-mvno"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22269306/visible-5g-esim-verizon-mvno</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
