<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-11T14:45:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T14:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T14:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Matter could bring universal casting that actually works</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hSjLQu7b-61QZ8vRbvaiJ56pc5g=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70249408/verge_IMG_8670_2040pxl.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;This Amazon-led casting standard for TVs could challenge Apple AirPlay and Google Cast &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="eU6aaf"&gt;The new smart home standard Matter is making a lot of grand promises, chief among them are fixing the interoperability mess the smart home is currently in and making Apple, Samsung, Google, and Amazon talk to each other. Big jobs. But it’s also tackling one of the other pain points in the connected home: TV control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bm1PBy"&gt;One part of the new connectivity protocol is a specification for televisions and streaming video players. This means that Matter could become yet another way to control content in our homes. But, with its promise of platform agnosticism, Matter’s TV spec has the potential to replace proprietary casting systems, like Apple’s AirPlay or Google’s Cast, and finally free our TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m2niZc"&gt;Matter TV, as we’ll call it for wont of an official name, will allow control of a television’s core functions — volume up / down, changing the channel, controlling inputs and outputs, and switching between HDMI ports. “But importantly, you can also do casting,” Chris DeCenzo, Principal Software Development Engineer at Amazon Lab126, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oENWS1"&gt;“This is an area with at least five proprietary protocols today,” he says. “The result is a complete opportunity loss for everyone.” Not to mention major headaches for users as they grapple with which voice assistant can get this content and which remote will control that streaming stick. Amazon is leading the effort to define the specification for Matter — unsurprising, as it is currently the only large player without a proprietary way to cast content from a smartphone to a TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sv-CBjF74efHYHqQaY3CTpNuA3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13262367/jbareham_180726_2773_0087.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Controlling our smart TVs can feel anything but smart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1AsPEc"&gt;“Control of media is one of the most popular use cases for Alexa,” says DeCenzo, who told me Amazon is working with the different industry leaders in the fields of smart TVs, streaming video players, and content providers to help them adopt Matter. The goal is so that “customers can have a consistent way to use voice control and to launch their favorite content on those screens,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0NyUx"&gt;While the Matter TV specification doesn’t explicitly call out voice control, the idea here is standardization. One protocol for all device communication, everything will talk to everything else using the same language, no &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt; who made it. Ultimately, this means you will be able to use your control interface of choice (a voice assistant, remote control, or smartphone / tablet app) with all your streaming content devices and apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="7HxJWF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With its promise of platform agnosticism, Matter could finally free our TVs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rguZA0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623275/matter-interoperable-smart-home-standard-delay-2022-project-chip-csa"&gt;When Matter arrives in 2022&lt;/a&gt;, the Matter TV specification will use app-to-app communication, at least until the TVs and streaming video players become Matter enabled. The spec supports casting from a Matter client (e.g., a remote, a smart speaker, or a phone app) to an app running on a Matter-enabled TV or video player device, explains DeCenzo. It also supports URL-based casting, which means a Matter client can cast to a TV even when there’s no app for that client, if the TV supports Dynamic Adaptive Streaming (DASH, an international standard for streaming) or HLS DRM streams (HLS is a video streaming protocol developed by Apple and widely supported across Android devices and browsers). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tus8PG"&gt;The capability could go beyond just entertainment and be used to enable smart home notifications, says Chris LaPré of the &lt;a href="https://csa-iot.org/"&gt;Connectivity Standards Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, the organization that oversees the new standard. For example, it could cast a message from your connected doorbell to your smart TV, notifying you that someone is at the door. It could potentially show you the video feed, too, something of a workaround for including video feeds in Matter, since cameras are not part of the first device rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ietivWcwo5KkGDZsTA4bL1fY9k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074285/f7484de0_fd1a_11eb_8eb4_4d8ac557fa35.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CSA / Matter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matter-enabled devices will have the Matter logo on them to indicate they’re compatible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="to2vl9"&gt;Intriguingly, LaPré posited that the specification could allow for the use of context when delivering these messages, such as notifying you from the smart speaker in the room you are in that your laundry is done. “It can be about casting anything, smart home notifications, local video — all it needs is a URL to pull content from,” says LaPré. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hntmBy"&gt;The technology here is not system-level specific, as with Apple’s AirPlay. It appears to be more akin to Google’s Cast, where apps will need to build support for it, at least initially. But like AirPlay, and as with all Matter communications, it’s entirely local. Communication from device to device uses Matter as the channel. At launch, Matter will use ethernet, Wi-Fi, and Thread as its communication protocols. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s30Vfu"&gt;The requirement for the app makers — such as Hulu and Netflix, who aren’t currently members of the CSA — to build Matter support could make this something of a non-starter initially. Beyond Amazon and its Prime Video and Google with YouTube, few of the major streaming content providers are part of the CSA, and the app developer will initially need to add Matter support to both the app in the phone or casting device (for example, a smart speaker, laptop, or smartphone) and the app in the receiving device (TV, streaming stick, smart display). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCw2XM"&gt;“You can have communication directly from the Prime Video app on my phone to the Prime Video app that’s on the TV,” explains DeCenzo. Going forward, according to LaPré, the streaming video players and TVs will have Matter built into the devices themselves, and at this point the apps in the receiving device won’t need to be Matter-enabled. It seems likely Amazon will enable Matter on its Fire TV devices, and the company has already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761340/amazon-matter-smart-home-standard"&gt;committed to upgrading all its smart speakers to support Matter&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung, TCL, Panasonic, Toshiba, and LG are all involved with Matter, as are Apple and Google. Also, streaming video player maker Roku is part of the Matter TV working group. However, according to the list of companies on the &lt;a href="https://buildwithmatter.com/"&gt;Matter website&lt;/a&gt;, Vizio and Sony are two notable hardware players that are not yet signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="JleYxe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is a consistent way to use voice control to launch content on any screen&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BcAKqp"&gt;The main goal, however, is part of Matter’s overarching promise: avoiding manufacturer lock-in. People should be able to buy whichever device they choose and it should be able to talk to all the other connected devices in their home, regardless of who made it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xjqOY9"&gt;For example, if both were Matter-enabled you should be able to control an LG TV from a Samsung smartphone, and that LG TV should be able to receive a message from a Miele smart washer that the laundry is done. But, and this is a big but, nothing in the overall Matter spec is a requirement. A company that is on board with Matter as a whole is under no obligation to adopt a certain device specification that they don’t need or want to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LEcMbI"&gt;This means that Apple and Google do not have to adopt the Matter TV specification if they don’t want to (but if they do, they have to adopt it all, including casting). LaPré says both companies have “blessed this” as part of the spec (Matter is governed by members of the CSA who vote on the specifications). Whether they will adopt it remains to be seen. But if Amazon does, which seems like a good bet, it should mean you can use Matter to cast from your Amazon Prime app on your iPhone to your Amazon Prime app on your Apple TV or Google Chromecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W1CPHb"&gt;I reached out to both Google and Apple about this specification and how it would impact their current offerings. Both companies have committed to supporting Matter in their respective smart home ecosystems and both are members of the CSA. Kevin Po of Google said in an email that “Google Assistant will support Matter (eg. on/off, play/pause, app launch etc.) at parity with our current Works With Assistant offering.” Apple did not comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="5nr5N9"&gt;Po went on to reiterate that Google Cast remains Google’s preferred method for sending media via apps and voice to Chromecasts, speakers, and displays. As, we can only assume at this stage, will Airplay be Apple’s “preferred method.” But what your preferred method will be could very soon involve a lot more choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wKv5qW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Thursday, December 9th, 1:20PM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added that if a company chooses to adopt the Matter TV spec, it will need to adopt all of it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34SCdf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Saturday, December 11th, 2:45PM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;A previous version of this article stated that according to the list of companies on the Matter website, Roku and Toshiba were not part of Matter. The CSA reached out to say its website is out of date and Toshiba and Roku are now members. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824559/matter-tv-streaming-devices-smart-home-casting-protocol-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824559/matter-tv-streaming-devices-smart-home-casting-protocol-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T13:29:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T13:29:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s app tracking transparency feature isn’t an instant privacy button</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BRtHG6ikFWC0DwMOxhTVOAhRjuI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70259172/FB_ATT_Prompt.001.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ByQJj0"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/69396795-f6e1-4624-95d8-121e4e5d7839"&gt;report from the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; acts as a reminder of what Apple’s App Tracking Transparency settings do and do not do to protect your privacy (&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/12/apple-reaches-quiet-truce-over-iphone-privacy-changes/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). While asking apps to not track you does keep them from collecting and selling data tied to your personal advertising identity, it doesn’t keep developers from collecting any information about you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AAawK0"&gt;The feature, introduced in iOS 14.5, is meant to prevent app-makers from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;tracking what you do and selling that information to advertisers&lt;/a&gt;. Companies like Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/2/22415824/facebook-instagram-notice-ios-apps-free-privacy-tracking"&gt;cried foul when it was introduced&lt;/a&gt;, saying that it would hurt their ability to show targeted, personalized ads, and therefore hurt businesses that relied on those ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="k1GJHu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why Apple’s new privacy feature is such a big deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9G2ObX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Companies have turned to aggregated and anonymized data, which still comes from individuals&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WDIM97"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;, though, developers have taken Apple’s rules to mean that they’re allowed to target ads at cohorts, or groups that people are put into without needing to have unique IDs assigned. The report says that developers like Snap, Inc. have continued collecting some data, including from those who have asked them not to track them, with the justification that anything that could be tied to an individual user would be anonymized and grouped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EfnW4L"&gt;It’s a similar concept to FLoC, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358287/privacy-ads-google-chrome-floc-cookies-cookiepocalypse-finger-printing"&gt;Google’s plan for a post-third-party cookie internet&lt;/a&gt;, where individuals are assigned labels describing what kind of things they might buy instead of being tracked individually. Ads can still be targeted, without advertisers having to keep track of everything everyone does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6RCvaE"&gt;Some developers &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/12/10/more-details-emerge-on-how-snap-facebook-and-others-are-skirting-app-tracking-transparency/"&gt;have admitted&lt;/a&gt;, though, that they also try to make predictions about what users do after seeing ads based on info they receive from ad companies. The &lt;em&gt;Financial Times &lt;/em&gt;also says that some personalized data, like IP address, location, and screen size, still makes its way to advertisers, to help ensure that ads fit properly and show up in the right language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tFJlqH"&gt;According to the report, Facebook and many other companies are planning on selling ads using aggregated or anonymized data. While Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22745381/facebook-reality-labs-10-billion-metaverse"&gt;partially blamed Apple’s policies&lt;/a&gt; for it missing its earnings goals last quarter, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;it’s estimated&lt;/a&gt; that the ads affected by the rules only made up 5 percent of its annual ad revenue. In other words, Apple’s ad tracking permissions were never going to destroy Facebook’s ad business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="77cmgb"&gt;None of this is to say that there are no privacy benefits to hitting the “Ask app not to track” button — a previous &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; investigation found that Snap, Inc, Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/31/22756135/apple-app-tracking-transparency-policy-snapchat-facebook-twitter-youtube-lose-10-billion"&gt;lost $10 billion combined after the feature was implemented&lt;/a&gt;, so there was obviously a market for ads driven by that data. But it’s good to remember that even Apple, a company that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22179721/apple-defends-upcoming-privacy-changes-standing-up-for-users-facebook-data"&gt;prides itself on “standing up” for its users&lt;/a&gt;, can’t stop companies from collecting your data with a single switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="z2xR9j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to&amp;amp;nbsp;use the iOS app tracking blocker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22403523/ios-14-5-tracking-consent-app-transparency-how-to"},{"title":"Keep it Locked","url":"https://www.theverge.com/c/22796344/cybersecurity-how-to-protect-hacked-account"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22828713/apple-app-tracking-transparancy-psa-privacy-ads-cohorts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22828713/apple-app-tracking-transparancy-psa-privacy-ads-cohorts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T13:19:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T13:19:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Multiple deaths confirmed after tornado hits Amazon warehouse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TOPSHOT-US-CLIMATE-STORM" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7hnzDLWGzRXJlYCKzwGPWR13nak=/201x0:3800x2399/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70259136/1237160688.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by TIM VIZER/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GjXXNX"&gt;An Amazon warehouse in Edwardsville, Illinois collapsed following a bout of severe weather and tornados that ripped across the Midwest and South on Friday night. According to a report from &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/injuries-reported-after-roof-collapse-amazon-warehouse-illinois-ap-2021-12-11/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, at least two deaths have been confirmed, and a number of workers are still unaccounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lV7Daf"&gt;&lt;a href="http://facebook.com/collinsvilleEMA/posts/269327955226516"&gt;A post&lt;/a&gt; on Illinois’ Collinsville Emergency Management Agency’s Facebook page called the collapse a “mass casualty” incident. It &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo?fbid=269627795196532&amp;amp;set=a.222212819938030"&gt;later posted&lt;/a&gt; an update with a photo of the event’s aftermath, showing a large portion of the warehouse completely torn away by the storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="W83334"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Workers killed in Amazon warehouse collapse following severe weather in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/edwardsville?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#edwardsville&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/amazon?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/stlwx?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#stlwx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/tornado?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#tornado&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/q9HTdgEJFa"&gt;https://t.co/q9HTdgEJFa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— FOX2now (@FOX2now) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FOX2now/status/1469634191616884739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b6wNxM"&gt;During a press conference this morning, police chief Mike Fillback told reporters that authorities have had trouble finding out “how many people we actually had at that facility at the time because it’s not a set staff.” Amazon management was at the scene to help create a list of staff members who are accounted for, however, Fillback notes that it’s still difficult to determine how many people remain trapped inside the collapsed building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZ0gxx"&gt;Around 30 people reportedly made it out of the facility safely. While some were transported by bus to a safe area and reunited with family, others were able to leave the scene on their own (via &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/least-one-person-dead-severe-weather-event-illinois-amazon-warehouse-rcna8464"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). It remains unclear how many people were originally in the building, but Fillback estimates it might’ve been around 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VcgDJ3"&gt;“The safety and well-being of our employees and partners is our top priority right now,” Amazon spokesperson Richard Rocha said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’re assessing the situation and will share additional information when it’s available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Qo8WF"&gt;Illinois wasn’t the only state affected by the severe storms. According to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1469683523447664642?s=20"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 70 fatalities are expected in Kentucky, while one was killed after a possible tornado hit a nursing home in Arkansas. President Joe Biden sent out a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1469683523447664642"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; this morning, stating that the administration is “working with Governors to ensure they have what they need as the search for survivors and damage assessments continue.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829363/amazon-warehouse-tornado-collapse-edwardsville-illinois"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829363/amazon-warehouse-tornado-collapse-edwardsville-illinois</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T13:12:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T13:12:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Keanu Reeves doesn’t get the NFT hype either</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Keanu Reeves owns crypto, but thinks the concept of NFTs is just funny" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z_055E3UddArVQ1cZv7zrUkx4qA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70259116/vpavic_211203_4921_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keanu Reeves owns crypto, but thinks the concept of NFTs is just funny&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gXbcjo"&gt;By now, you’ve probably heard of NFTs enough to have an opinion about them, and, as it turns out, so has Keanu Reeves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uyi9m0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Keanu Reeves doesn’t get the NFT hype either. Watch our full interview here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ea0NInhtBO"&gt;https://t.co/ea0NInhtBO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/UuUNFMtfmf"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UuUNFMtfmf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— The Verge (@verge) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/verge/status/1469718270236413956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="ga7dzp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z3PH5p"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22825102/keanu-reeves-carrie-anne-moss-interview-matrix-awakens-epic-games"&gt;our interview&lt;/a&gt; with him and fellow &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; icon Carrie-Ann Moss, Alex Heath asked the actors about their feelings on cryptocurrency, NFT collectibles, and the concept of digital scarcity. Keanu — described in &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/8/16/20694479/keanu-reeves-in-2019-revival-memes-history-explained"&gt;this 2019 &lt;em&gt;Vox &lt;/em&gt;profile of his Keanaissance&lt;/a&gt; as a “relatable geek” — had, of course, a relatable response (tweeted earlier by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dz/status/1469424767488962570"&gt;David Zhou&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfFYnp"&gt;He laughed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0rp9r"&gt;And not just a little either, as the idea of digital trinkets conveying ownership even though the actual content remains, as he says, “easily reproduced” is enough to have Neo himself bent over at the waist. When he recovered, he asked Moss if they’re getting a cut from the sales, so maybe he’ll take it more seriously once someone tweets relentlessly at him about the glorious potential of smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LNmvS"&gt;It’s not like Reeves doesn’t know about the blockchain, as he also said he owns cryptocurrency that a friend bought for him. However, he is all about HODLing and isn’t actively trading any of it yet. You can find out more about their thoughts on the metaverse, explaining &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; to teens who don’t think living in a wholly digital reality is a scary idea, and Warner Bros.’ missed videogame opportunities in the nearly 19-minute interview &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22825102/keanu-reeves-carrie-anne-moss-interview-matrix-awakens-epic-games"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AU5NzU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I don't think you understand digital scarcity, Mr. Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;— Nathan    (@ScamShamUnfairo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ScamShamUnfairo/status/1469451728248442880?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="5yXXt0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Matrix Awakens didn’t blow my mind, but it convinced me next-gen gaming is nigh ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22828860/the-matrix-awakens-ps5-xbox-series-x-free-next-gen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829383/matrix-nft-keanu-reeves-interview-carrie-ann-moss"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829383/matrix-nft-keanu-reeves-interview-carrie-ann-moss</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T11:16:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T11:16:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watch these Excel pros duke it out in a financial modeling competition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_DFU__nC20qPtQ-2upfp5_3dIZ4=/0x0:2415x1610/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258817/ms_excel_modeling_competition.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Diarmuid Early competes in the second round of the Financial Modeling World Cup. | Image: Financial Modeling World Cup | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y4ae0qpB2r0" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OjGqL4"&gt;Microsoft is sponsoring an esports competition with prizes totaling $10,000. The game? Well, it’s not exactly a game — it’s Microsoft Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LUUsGj"&gt;Every year, the top Microsoft Excel users (&lt;em&gt;players?&lt;/em&gt;) from around the world face off in the Financial Modeling World Cup (FMWC) (via &lt;a href="https://www.pcworld.com/article/559001/the-future-of-esports-is-microsoft-excel-and-its-on-espn.html/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PCWorld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The qualifying rounds already took place, leaving just eight Excel masters to compete for the FMWC crown. The quarter-finals, semifinals, and final round all take place today at 12PM ET via a YouTube livestream and the ESPN app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ut7X0M"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NSU11kxxJvc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2WNMCh"&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.fmworldcup.com/rules/"&gt;FMWC rules&lt;/a&gt;, competitors are presented with a one to five-page long case study during each round. Case studies contain real-world problems, along with six to 15 questions that vary in complexity — the more complex a question, the more points are awarded to the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibfXLD"&gt;Participants will, of course, have to use their financial modeling skills to determine the answer to each question. The sample cases on the &lt;a href="https://www.fmworldcup.com/sample-cases/"&gt;FMWC site&lt;/a&gt; can give you a glimpse of what kinds of problems these Excel pros solve have to solve, some of which they may encounter during a typical workday, and others, dubbed “freestyle,” might have a more unusual subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1v02fp"&gt;And if you never thought you’d get amped up over an Excel tournament, think again.  Surprisingly enough, watching a livestream of the FMWC feels just as exciting as watching your typical esports event, complete with announcers, live commentary, and a scoreboard. It even has a &lt;a href="https://smash.gg/tournament/fmwc-open/event/last-128-last-64-round/brackets/1017600/1602399"&gt;bracket system&lt;/a&gt; to track the progress of the competition, as well as a &lt;a href="https://www.fmworldcup.com/rankings/"&gt;ranking system&lt;/a&gt; — appropriately made with an Excel spreadsheet — with Diarmuid Early of New York at the top of the global leaderboard, followed by Anup Agarwal of India, and Andrew Ngai of England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XPVRjr"&gt;The FMWC isn’t the only competition of its kind, either — the &lt;a href="https://www.moschampionship.com/"&gt;Microsoft Office Specialist World Championship&lt;/a&gt; covers the entire Office suite, including Excel, Word, and PowerPoint, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/16/16152310/microsoft-office-specialist-mos-world-championship-2017"&gt;challenges students to become the “Microsoft Champion.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="E5uJXp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How an Excel TikToker manifested her way to making six figures a day","url":"https://www.moschampionship.com/"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829228/excel-pros-financial-modeling-world-cup"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829228/excel-pros-financial-modeling-world-cup</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T10:16:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T10:16:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Blue Origin launches Michael Strahan, Laura Shepard Churchley and others to space and back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QS5mYhFz7IhQjM5idIar_A4DwX4=/275x0:2563x1525/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258688/blue_origin_liftoff.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Blue Origin via &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MpaiuDg_DN4" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f4qZMk"&gt;This morning, space tourism venture Blue Shepard successfully launched its third crew of passengers to space and back on the company’s New Shepard rocket, the first time a group of six people has flown together on the vehicle. The crew included GMA host Michael Strahan and Laura Shepard Churchley, the eldest daughter of Alan Shepard — the first American in space and the namesake for the New Shepard rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MzeEVv"&gt;New Shepard lifted off just after 10AM ET on Saturday morning from Blue Origin’s launch facility in Van Horn, Texas. The entire flight lasted just over 10 minutes from liftoff to touch down. Riding inside a crew capsule on top of the New Shepard rocket, the six-person crew climbed to an altitude of 351,225 feet, or more than 66 miles above the Earth, what is considered to be above the boundary to space. After experiencing a few minutes of weightlessness, the capsule carrying the crew touched down on the Texas desert floor, while the New Shepard booster successfully landed upright on a landing pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LgoaeX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Before today’s launch, Blue Origin had only flown crews of four to space&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wzhpfs"&gt;Also included in today’s crew were Evan Dick, an engineer and investor, as well as Lane Bess, the founder of Bess Ventures and Advisory. Bess brought along his son, Cameron Bess, making them the first father and child duo to ride to space together. The final crew member was Dylan Taylor, the CEO of Voyager space and active investor in the space industry. These four were all paying customers for this flight, while Strahan and Churchley were “honored guests.” Blue Origin did not disclose how much each person paid for their seat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ei6PIfKUPiSfaCYn3LkC-Za6pvQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23080942/blue_origin_tminus_2.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blue Origin via &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MpaiuDg_DN4" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bBKVfW"&gt;Once back on the ground, Strahan described the sight of the Earth from the capsule to a group of people that included Blue Origin founder Jeff Bezos. Then someone asked him if the planet was around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Goo7y"&gt;“Okay, Kyrie Irving,” Strahan replied. Irving, a basketball player for the Boston Celtics, once proclaimed &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/08/movies/kyrie-irving-nba-celtics-earth.html"&gt;he believed the Earth was flat&lt;/a&gt;, though &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/nba/story/_/id/24863899/kyrie-irving-boston-celtics-apologizes-saying-earth-flat"&gt;he has since said he was “sorry” about saying that publicly&lt;/a&gt;. In response to Strahan’s joke, Bezos shouted out, “Flat Earther!” Strahan also said he wanted to do the flight again, but Bezos joked he’d have to pay for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="X7QH6O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Strahan said he wanted to do the flight again, but Bezos joked he’d have to pay for the next one&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GerbPI"&gt;Churchley talked to Bezos about her experience compared to the one her father had back in 1961, when he flew to suborbital space on a Mercury-Redstone rocket. “Gosh he didn’t even get to enjoy what I’m going to get enjoy,” Churchley said about her thoughts ahead of the flight. “He was working!” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ytAnmj"&gt;Before today’s launch, Blue Origin had only flown crews of four to space on New Shepard. The company’s first crewed launch in July famously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;launched Bezos&lt;/a&gt;, as well as legendary female aviator Wally Funk. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724058/blue-origin-william-shatner-new-shepard-flight-success"&gt;The second flight in October included actor William Shatner&lt;/a&gt;, best known for playing Captain James Kirk on the TV show Star Trek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WF0eqc"&gt;All six of the passengers on today’s flight should receive their commercial astronaut wings from the Federal Aviation Administration, which has historically given the small pins to people who fly above 50 miles. However, this week the FAA announced it would be ending this practice by the end of the year, citing the advent of the commercial space tourism era. Moving forward, it will now list all future spacefarers who fly above 50 miles on the agency’s website instead. That means the six people on today’s flight may be the last fliers to receive the FAA’s wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHfO51"&gt;Today’s flight comes after the FAA says it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827900/blue-origin-new-shepard-launch-michael-strahan-faa-investigation-watch-live"&gt;closed an investigation into Blue Origin’s safety culture&lt;/a&gt;. The FAA initially opened an investigation in October, after 21 former and current employees at the company penned an essay, accusing Blue Origin of culture rife with sexual harassment and safety concerns. However, the FAA tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it found “no specific safety issues” after looking into the claims.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829232/blue-origin-new-shepard-michael-strahan-six-crew-success"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829232/blue-origin-new-shepard-michael-strahan-six-crew-success</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s Invasion feels like the first chapter of a sci-fi epic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UBT6IX4NQ20qtGe-IsN-TpUjf4I=/482x0:3359x1918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258618/Invasion_Photo_011006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9n9RgM"&gt;The first season of &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; on Apple TV Plus feels a little incomplete. Across its 10 episodes, which chart a handful of humans grappling with an alien invasion, the story slowly teases out the reality of what’s happening. There are hints here and there — a haunting artificial voice, a mysterious alien-killing weapon, a kid with seizures that may or may not show the future — but the biggest reveal of all doesn’t even happen until the very last shot in the final episode. It still managed to pull me in — but that pull has a lot to do with potential. Rather than standing on its own, the initial season of &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; feels like the first chapter of a much grander science fiction epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="83ezo3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22740520/invasion-review-apple-tv-plus"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; gets off to a slow start&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike most stories about an alien invasion, which tend to focus on the alien part, &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; lingers on human trauma. Early on, there’s barely even a mention of the invading extraterrestrials. Instead,&lt;em&gt; Invasion&lt;/em&gt;’s global story tracks a handful of different threads spread across the world, which ultimately end up loosely connected. Each has some tie to the otherworldly events: there’s a young boy in London who is prone to seizures that may be connected to the invasion; a family from Long Island that’s struggling with infidelity and also happens to possibly have a weapon that can kill the aliens; a space engineer in Japan who seems to be the only one able to communicate with them; and an American soldier who is separated from his squad in Afghanistan after what appears to be an attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tDs0Zv"&gt;The show does a great job of making you care about these characters, mostly because you spend so much time with them. You understand why the engineer is working tirelessly to find a stranded astronaut after lots of long, heartfelt scenes revealing their secret relationship. Likewise, while the soldier comes across as a jerk initially, his slowly revealed backstory ultimately turns him into a sympathetic figure. There’s lots of great character development going on, but it also requires patience since it takes quite a while to get to the actual aliens. For the first half of the season, it’s mostly just hints that there’s something going on beyond a natural disaster of some kind.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iTc2-wBP-YFwG77benxDHPBkg08=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23079599/Invasion_Photo_011001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pzxnjQ"&gt;This all means that when the aliens do finally appear, it’s a huge deal. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776188/invasion-apple-tv-plus-episode-6-aliens"&gt;The reveal is great&lt;/a&gt; and neatly changes the tone of the show. From then on, &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; becomes something different, balancing out its character drama (which never fully goes away, thankfully) with some intriguing alien mysteries and the flat-out horror of dealing with the invaders. There’s a terrifying scene in a secluded house, where a family tries to sneak away from one of the spiked blob creatures; later, we see the soldier making his way through a war-torn hospital amidst an infestation as if this was a first-person &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt; game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vgcp5a"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You never get much in the way of answers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AXaQXi"&gt;What you don’t get are much in the way of answers. There are some small revelations, like when you learn that the London teen had visions of the invasion before it happened or when it appears that the Japanese researcher discovers how the aliens communicate. But nothing is ever clear. Even when it seems like the aliens have been defeated, the show throws another twist at you. This isn’t necessarily a bad thing. Mystery is important, and those unknowns are part of what has kept me coming back. But the result is that season 1 doesn’t feel like a complete story, with its own distinct arc. It’s 10 episodes of setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZ9WrR"&gt;The good news is that Apple revealed earlier this week that &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; is coming back for a second season, with co-creator Simon Kinberg saying they would be “expanding our universe in the most intimate and epic ways.” And after a full season of setting things up, I’m anxious to see where it’s finally going.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22828386/invasion-season-1-review-apple-tv-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22828386/invasion-season-1-review-apple-tv-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s latest AirPods are selling for just $140 at Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5TrE5Uxh3_92cAbphTpiq9WQOFg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258564/IMG_0044.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m_9003484103508200907J9So2B"&gt;Things have chilled out considerably this week, both in terms of how cold it has become in parts of the US and how few deals there are compared to the hectic Black Friday and Cyber Monday extravaganza. However, that’s not to say there aren’t some fantastic offers happening both in-store and online. We’ll be keeping a close eye on deals in the next few weeks to make sure you get what you’re looking for ahead of the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bF0hQ1"&gt;Alright, let’s get to the deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pfojO4"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1BGXAl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Save $40 on the third-gen AirPods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="U9bNqV"&gt;I can’t remember the last time an Apple product was discounted so swiftly. That’s what is happening to the third-gen AirPods, which debuted at $179, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;but are now just $139.99&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon (the correct price will reflect at checkout). While they resemble the AirPods Pro with their shorter stems, the latest AirPods lack active noise cancellation, and they rest in your ear instead of fitting snugly via the Pro’s included silicon tips. Those differences may not matter to some people, and if you’re one of those people, check out this deal before it expires. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="R0uTdG"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FEUW7o0SLmMH0yrqGsPtZ6aOk0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22013076/vpavic_201103_4275_0252.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2v7Dm0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08G9J44ZN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can find the Xbox Series S in stock right now at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UQ7j2j"&gt;While its bigger, more powerful $499.99 Xbox Series X sibling is tough to find, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08G9J44ZN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the $299.99 Xbox Series S&lt;/a&gt; is comparatively bountiful. At the time of publishing, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08G9J44ZN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is selling stock for the MSRP price&lt;/a&gt;, and for Prime members, you’ll have a shot at getting &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09H73LTM6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the special edition console for $299.99&lt;/a&gt; that includes in-game currency for both &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="xmC4Qw"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="v4LyXM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDeals121121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fomen-by-hp-laptop-16-c0035nr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP’s powerful 16-inch Omen gaming laptop is a bargain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pvk6SZ"&gt;Presumably for a limited time, HP is offering a fairly capable configuration of its Omen 16 gaming laptop &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDeals121121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fomen-by-hp-laptop-16-c0035nr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for just $1,304.99&lt;/a&gt; when you use the offer code &lt;strong&gt;WINTER10 &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout (h/t &lt;a href="https://slickdeals.net/f/15492136-hp-omen-16-c0035nr-16-1-fhd-144hz-ryzen-7-5800h-rtx-3070-16gb-ddr4-512gb-pcie-ssd-win11h-1304-99-f-s?src=popular_recombee"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slickdeals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The price is impressive when you consider what’s inside of this laptop. You’re getting a 16.1-inch FHD panel with a 144Hz refresh rate, AMD’s Ryzen 7 5800H processor, 16GB of RAM, a 512GB M.2 PCIe SSD, and most impressively, an RTX 3070 graphics chip with 115W of total graphics power. Most gaming laptops at this price range include the RTX 3060.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vObibn"&gt;
&lt;div id="d1Jasx"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Surface Pro 8 review: the best of both worlds|104127" data-volume-uuid="a87b72033" data-volume-id="104127" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-350" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Z4jB9S"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FE90MS8PN00001&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F11%2F22827785%2Fapple-airpods-third-gen-wireless-earbuds-xbox-series-s-surface-pro-8-gaming-laptop-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The new Surface Pro 8 comes with a Type Cover and extended warranty for just $999&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QfuIGM"&gt;At Buydig, a reputable site that often gets the edge over other retailers by offering extended warranties or Visa gift cards with big-ticket purchases, you can buy a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FE90MS8PN00001&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F11%2F22827785%2Fapple-airpods-third-gen-wireless-earbuds-xbox-series-s-surface-pro-8-gaming-laptop-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new Surface Pro 8 bundle for just $999&lt;/a&gt;. It comes bundled with a Type Cover (usually $100) and an added one-year warranty, giving you two years total of coverage. The Surface Pro 8 on offer is the base configuration (usually $999), with an Intel Core i5 processor, 8GB of RAM, an upgradeable 128GB SSD, as well as a 120Hz refresh rate display. You’re getting about $300 worth of extras at no additional cost. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22709876/microsoft-surface-pro-8-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XssujP"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o_sKHR0__Hya7Zw9Qukpt1ruAIs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20108409/halo_infinite_keyart_primary_horiz_9e788e276ba740e3af6451ef073fd3de.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2MQYzr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeDeals121121&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%3FlaunchStore%3DCFQ7TTC0KHS0%23join" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Get Game Pass so you can play Halo Infinite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="m_9003484103508200907jOxh3U"&gt;If you have a PC or an Xbox, you can (and should) play &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; on the cheap with a Game Pass subscription. For new PC subscribers, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeDeals121121&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%2Fpc-game-pass" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Game Pass costs just $1&lt;/a&gt; for the first three months of service ($9.99 per month after that) and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeDeals121121&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%3FlaunchStore%3DCFQ7TTC0KHS0%23join" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass Ultimate costs $1&lt;/a&gt; for the first month (costing $14.99 monthly afterward). Whichever one you choose, that’s plenty of time to play through the campaign, and to see if its multiplayer component digs its talons into your brain, making you just a little addicted (I’m totally not speaking from personal experience. Nope, not at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eFboGb"&gt;Of course, you don’t need Game Pass to play &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;. You can pay $60 for the game... or on second though, just get Game Pass. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820011/halo-infinite-campaign-review-xbox-series-x"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; campaign review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="C1Drq3"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AK0wY-eE_KIKq1w2fqpMbo1QPd0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23001468/akrales_211109_4870_0263.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wtuMus"&gt;Logitech’s stellar G435 wireless gaming headset is $10 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="m_9003484103508200907XmwQuJ"&gt;$79.99 is a reasonable price to pay for a comfortable, good-sounding wireless headset that offers both 2.4GHz and Bluetooth connectivity. I’m describing the Logitech G435 Lightspeed, a headset that I liked so much I chose it as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"&gt;my favorite wireless headset in our buying guide&lt;/a&gt;. Today, however, you can save $10 on it at a number of retailers, including &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLogitech-G435-LIGHTSPEED-Bluetooth-Wireless-Gaming-Headset-Lightweight-over-ear-headphones-built-in-mics-18h-battery-compatible-Dolby-Atmos-PC-PS4-PS%2F377935551&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDeals121121" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-G435-Wireless-Gaming-Headset/dp/B08R8DT7X6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cga548BGiR3?u1=vergedeals121121" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the price down to $69.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XCQ1R2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10866389"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="qRrF6R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/11/22827785/apple-airpods-third-gen-wireless-earbuds-xbox-series-s-surface-pro-8-gaming-laptop-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/11/22827785/apple-airpods-third-gen-wireless-earbuds-xbox-series-s-surface-pro-8-gaming-laptop-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite’s creators say your wildest stunts are part of the series’ DNA</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9x0XedIxINewcjz94GQOfsIcVlA=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258273/Screen_Shot_2021_12_09_at_3.51.34_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTuber “Mint Blitz” found a way to soar through the air in &lt;/em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SK8beuE0-d0" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Blitz on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3Xnbut"&gt;On Monday, a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MintBlitz/status/1467839509291167744"&gt;jaw-dropping &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; video&lt;/a&gt; kept showing up on my Twitter feed that looked like something out of a &lt;em&gt;Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; speedrun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XCYKUr"&gt;The video, from Australian YouTuber “Mint Blitz,” begins with Master Chief armed with a massive hammer behind a Warthog vehicle. In an impressive sequence taking place over a matter of seconds, Mint Blitz swings the hammer to send the Warthog flying while almost simultaneously using Master Chief’s new grappling hook on the vehicle to slingshot himself into the air like Spider-Man. As he’s soaring high above Zeta Halo’s treetops, he uses the thruster powerup — and then, inexplicably, just keeps flying forward. After 39 seconds in the air, he finally lands, gracefully setting down on top of a tall tower that’s likely supposed to otherwise be inaccessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J7vkya"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This Changes EVERYTHING &lt;a href="https://t.co/j3fIGw4oxA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/j3fIGw4oxA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mint Blitz (@MintBlitz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MintBlitz/status/1467839509291167744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0nxnZX"&gt;Mint Blitz is almost assuredly doing something &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; developer 343 Industries never specifically intended. I can’t imagine that players are supposed to be able to fly straight forward without falling for more than half a minute. But based on a conversation I had with 343 Industries, it seems like the studio is fine with letting players figure out how to do similarly outlandish stunts and doesn’t plan to patch those sorts of things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mP1eUQ"&gt;“It would actually have to be something that causes the game to lock up for us to be wanting to stop it,” 343 Industries associate creative director Paul Crocker tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “I’d love it if someone managed to speedrun the game by using some crazy combination of mechanics to get there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYM4Id"&gt;“Unless it’s brick-blocking player progression or their ability to enjoy the game, we’ll fix it,” adds character director Stephen Dyck. “Those are the types of things we patch. Otherwise, we love seeing that kind of stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6mZZV"&gt;Dyck argues that pushing the boundaries is something that’s “part of &lt;em&gt;Halo’s&lt;/em&gt; DNA.” He gave an example of trying to squeeze a vehicle where you technically aren’t supposed to. “If the player wants to invest time and energy into doing that, and then ultimately they’re successful, and they get the vehicle where they technically weren’t supposed to? Awesome,” he says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jNO1UP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You’re totally able to do that”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="keyGkN"&gt;Crocker shared the story of a time the development team spent two hours trying to get a Ghost (kind of an alien hovercraft speeder) into a certain building. “When they wrote up this huge bug [report] about, ‘I can get a Ghost in, we need to fix this,’ we went, ‘Nope. You’re totally able to do that,’” Crocker said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mLzGrf"&gt;Seeing the things players end up doing also inspires the team for things they make down the line, according to Dyck. “We’ll see interesting things that players are gravitating towards, and we’re like, ‘Cool, yeah, we’ll lean into that one.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkqU1e"&gt;Pushing worlds to their limits can give games extended lives. People are still actively &lt;a href="https://www.speedrun.com/botw#Any"&gt;shaving time off &lt;em&gt;Breath of the Wild &lt;/em&gt;speedruns&lt;/a&gt; more than four and a half years after its original release, for example. And &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; fans have already shown they’re a persistent bunch, having spent seven years trying to get &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/halo-reach-players-spent-seven-years-trying-to-get-into-1823356029"&gt;into a cutscene room in &lt;em&gt;Halo: Reach&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGyVZb"&gt;343 Industries hasn’t said what’s next for &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite’s&lt;/em&gt; campaign, so we don’t know how the next chapter on Zeta Halo may unfold. But while we’re waiting for what’s to come, I’m looking forward to seeing whatever tricks top Mint Blitz’s epic flight across the map — and it seems like 343 will be, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3WzecO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Halo Infinite campaign review: playing the hits","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820011/halo-infinite-campaign-review-xbox-series-x"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="uDLXhQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827053/halo-infinite-developers-wild-stunts-series-dna"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827053/halo-infinite-developers-wild-stunts-series-dna</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-11T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-11T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watch as Blue Origin plans to launch its first crew of six to space, with Michael Strahan on board</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/npkEyZ3FZPeE0PGcB_soFTKl_70=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70258084/blueorigin_ns19_barntour_l_2_1639079187.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4it0ZE"&gt;This morning, Jeff Bezos’ spaceflight company Blue Origin is slated to launch another crew of customers to the edge of space and back. The crew cabin will be a little more crowded than usual: a total of six passengers will ride to space inside Blue Origin’s New Shepard tourist rocket, the largest group the company has ever sent up on one flight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b3kOps"&gt;That makes this flight a bit unusual. The launch also comes after an FAA investigation into the safety of Blue Origin’s rockets came to an inconclusive resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iM4Rtd"&gt;On board are a mixture of celebrity guests and paying spaceflight enthusiasts. Notably, Michael Strahan, a host for &lt;em&gt;Good Morning America&lt;/em&gt; and former NFL rusher for the New York Giants, will be flying, along with Laura Shepard Churchley, the eldest daughter of Alan Shepard, who was the first American in space. Both are considered guests, so they did not pay for their seats. Flying with them are paying customers: Evan Dick, an investor, Lane Bess, the founder of Bess Ventures, and Bess’ son Cameron Bess. Dylan Taylor, a major investor in the spaceflight industry, will round out the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I73rNt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’ll be interesting to see how a crew of six fares&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jJu1NC"&gt;This will be Blue Origin’s third time launching people to the edge of space from the company’s test facility in Van Horn, Texas. For all three of these missions, Blue Origin has made sure to have some kind of star on board. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;The company’s first crewed mission carried Bezos&lt;/a&gt;, as well as legendary female aviator Wally Funk, while the second flight notably &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724058/blue-origin-william-shatner-new-shepard-flight-success"&gt;carried William Shatner&lt;/a&gt;, best known for playing Captain James T. Kirk on &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;. For those first two tourist flights, however, Blue Origin only flew crews of four. Videos from inside the crew cabin showed that the interior &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LpiBhOQrtPo"&gt;got somewhat crowded&lt;/a&gt;, even with such small complements of people. It’ll be interesting to see how a crew of six fares, which is the maximum number of people the capsule is supposed to hold.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FfpbJWpIJkIBWPVm3titShki3GU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23080220/blueorigin_ns19_strahanseatsmiling_l_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blue Origin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michael Strahan training in one of New Shepard’s passenger seats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XFgFOx"&gt;The flight comes just after the Federal Aviation Administration confirms that it closed an investigation into Blue Origin’s safety culture without finding any substantial issues. The FAA, which is responsible for issuing licenses for commercial rocket launches, started looking into the company in early October &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702335/jeff-bezos-employees-essay-blue-origin-toxic-workplace"&gt;after 21 current and former employees at Blue Origin published an essay&lt;/a&gt; alleging a culture of rampant sexual harassment and safety concerns with the company’s rockets. The essay, penned by former Blue Origin head of employee communications Alexandra Abrams, argued that employees are too scared to speak about safety violations over fears of retaliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SUWIGw"&gt;“In the opinion of an engineer who has signed on to this essay, ‘Blue Origin has been lucky that nothing has happened so far,’” the essay stated. “Many of this essay’s authors say they would not fly on a Blue Origin vehicle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="iHV91c"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the FAA found “no specific safety issues” after investigating allegations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0hyVpJ"&gt;When the essay came out, the FAA said it was “reviewing the information.” However, as CNN &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/12/10/tech/blue-origin-safety-review-whistleblower-scn/index.html"&gt;first reported on Friday&lt;/a&gt; and the FAA confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; its investigation is now over. Steven Kulm, a public affairs specialist at the FAA, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that the FAA found “no specific safety issues” after investigating allegations made against the company’s human spaceflight program. When asked for comment, Linda Mills, the vice president for communications at Blue Origin, said, “The FAA statement is accurate.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SRwGHO"&gt;However, in an email obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, FAA representatives explained to Abrams that the agency was unable to conduct a thorough investigation because no additional engineering or safety experts from Blue Origin came forward to discuss issues at the company that were raised in Abrams’ letter. The emails show that FAA investigators put the burden on Abrams to convince her former colleagues to speak up. Abrams passed along key information to the investigators, including email exchanges between Blue Origin employees detailing concerns over capsule recovery operations and a memo crafted by a departing employee about safety concerns. She also got nearly three people to provide written statements, but the individuals ultimately backed out over fears of their identities being disclosed, Abrams tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. In an email to Abrams, the FAA noted that those who came forward could not be guaranteed protection because there are no statutes in place to protect whistleblowers at space companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xt4wes"&gt;A copy of the FAA’s email to Abrams, sent on December 6th, is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="vjrHXW"&gt;It has been several weeks since our last contact with you and although we know you did everything possible to try and persuade members of your group to come forward, no technical experts have reached out to us or provided any specific documentation regarding the safety allegations. We understand that there are no federal “whistleblower protection” statutes protecting employees of commercial space companies from retaliation resulting from reporting safety issues. This is in stark contrast to the extensive protections available to commercial aviation industry whistleblowers. We believe this was an enormous factor in our inability to pursue this investigation further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gSPEBZ"&gt;Following a thorough review of the limited information provided, multiple discussions with you, and consulting the applicable law and regulations, the FAA could not investigate this matter in depth, and thus, could not substantiate the safety concerns described in the document you provided. No further actions can be recommended at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4Lp2xt"&gt;Currently, the commercial space industry benefits from little federal oversight regarding safety, thanks to something called the&lt;a href="https://www.theregreview.org/2015/12/31/rathz-space-commerce-regulation/"&gt; US Commercial Space Launch Competitiveness Act passed in 2015&lt;/a&gt;. The law prohibits the FAA or other federal agencies from placing safety regulations on the commercial space industry until 2023. The impetus for the law was to allow a space industry that’s still in its infancy to continue to grow and innovate without “burdensome” regulations. That means when the FAA issues launch licenses, it is only responsible for making sure that a rocket launch will not harm uninvolved people or property on the ground. The agency cannot dictate rules for how commercial space companies should make their vehicles or operations safer. &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-ends-commercial-space-astronaut-wings-program-will-recognize-individuals-reaching"&gt;Commercial space tourists fly through “informed consent&lt;/a&gt;,” meaning they agree that the trip they are taking is inherently dangerous and risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T4hTr6"&gt;After the original essay was published in October, the company stood by its culture. “Blue Origin has no tolerance for discrimination or harassment of any kind. We provide numerous avenues for employees, including a 24/7 anonymous hotline, and will promptly investigate any new claims of misconduct,” a Blue Origin spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ymMSD1"&gt;To get passengers to the edge of space and back, Blue Origin relies on its New Shepard rocket, a reusable vehicle designed to launch upright from Earth and then land upright back on the ground again. Passengers ride on top of the vehicle inside a crew cabin with reclined seats and large windows. Once the rocket reaches a certain altitude, the cabin separates from the top of the rocket and enters space, allowing the riders to experience a few moments of weightlessness. Both the capsule and the rocket return to Earth; the rocket lands upright, while the capsule touches down gently using parachutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLIh5U"&gt;Typically, New Shepard reaches an altitude of roughly 62 miles up when it flies, which most consider to be above the boundary to space. When today’s passengers return to Earth, all of them should be awarded commercial astronaut wings by the FAA. These wings have historically been given to people who fly above 50 miles on a commercial spacecraft. However, &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-ends-commercial-space-astronaut-wings-program-will-recognize-individuals-reaching"&gt;the FAA announced this week that it will be ending this practice&lt;/a&gt; by the end of the year and will merely list all future commercial tourists and flyers who reach space on the agency’s website. That means this crew may be the last ones to ever get the wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="msNQ9L"&gt;Today’s New Shepard launch is slated for takeoff this morning at 9:45AM ET out of Blue Origin’s launch site in Van Horn. Blue Origin plans to begin live coverage 90 minutes ahead of launch.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827900/blue-origin-new-shepard-launch-michael-strahan-faa-investigation-watch-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827900/blue-origin-new-shepard-launch-michael-strahan-faa-investigation-watch-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
