<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-17T08:57:15-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-17T08:57:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-17T08:57:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Washington state lawmakers vote to phase out gasoline cars by 2030</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Traffic Jam" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xYgvohHa7yyBd88F_EHpQH4WAWg=/0x0:1000x667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69142149/shutterstock_54135052.1419966774.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Traffic Jam&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yojoZs"&gt;Washington state lawmakers have &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22450947/clean_cars_2030.pdf"&gt;passed a measure&lt;/a&gt; that would phase out the sale of gas-powered vehicles starting in 2030. The Clean Cars 2030 initiative passed Thursday as an amendment &lt;a href="http://lawfilesext.leg.wa.gov/biennium/2021-22/Pdf/Amendments/Senate/1287-S2.E%20AMS%20ENGR%20S2584.E.pdf"&gt;to a bill&lt;/a&gt; that requires state utilities prepare for an electric-vehicle future. The bill now awaits Gov. Jay Inslee’s signature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G60dDl"&gt;That’s five years earlier than planned gas vehicle bans in California and Massachusetts, and the first ban on gas cars passed by legislators, rather than by an executive order. The bill passed Washington’s Senate by a vote of 25-23 and a vote of 54-43 in the House. The bill bans the sale, purchase, or registration of non-EVs from model year 2030 and later, and would include vehicles bought in another state and brought into Washington state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6lafAK"&gt;The Clean Cars 2030 measure depends on the state approving a tax on vehicle miles traveled, which would help pay for new transportation infrastructure in the state, according to the bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KT49H7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452825/california-ban-combustion-gas-vehicles-cars-2035"&gt;California Gov. Gavin Newsom signed an order&lt;/a&gt; last September in that would ban the sale of new combustion-engine vehicles in the state starting in 2035, also part of a package of policy changes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. That measure applies to new-vehicle sales in the state, and doesn’t bar Californians from owning gas-powered vehicles. Massachusetts Gov. Charlie Baker unveiled a plan in December to ban new gas-powered cars by 2035 as part of that state’s &lt;a href="https://www.mass.gov/doc/ma-2050-decarbonization-roadmap/download"&gt;2050 Decarbonization Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6R9AC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/17/22389088/washington-state-vote-ban-gasoline-cars-2030-electric"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/17/22389088/washington-state-vote-ban-gasoline-cars-2030-electric</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-17T08:37:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-17T08:37:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter appears to be having a partial outage Saturday morning</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4kJplUrnXfZcq1dnySFKdV5B-A4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69142133/acastro_180827_1777_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tAkjEl"&gt;It looks like problems on Twitter that began Friday night are persisting Saturday morning. People on the east coast of the US were reporting that while the page would load, they were unable to send tweets and DMs. Twitter Support posted a brief message Friday night that it was looking into the matter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uGls8t"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tweets may not be loading for some of you. We’re working on fixing a problem and you’ll be back on the timeline soon.&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1383221595804602370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CLAd58"&gt;Donwndetector, which monitors site outages, &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/twitter/"&gt;showed a massive spike in problems&lt;/a&gt; around 8:25PM ET on Friday. Things seemed to be returning to normal within an hour, but Saturday morning around 8AM ET, it was showing a small uptick in reported problems again. Often these outages are the result of a problem with an intermediary service like Amazon Web Services, but its &lt;a href="https://status.aws.amazon.com/"&gt;dashboard shows all green&lt;/a&gt; as of this writing. And &lt;a href="https://api.twitterstat.us/"&gt;Twitter’s API status&lt;/a&gt; website was showing no problems this morning, either. At least, not yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SgVkDQ"&gt;There’s no official word on what is causing the problems and if it’s still limited to the eastern US. We’ve reached out to Twitter for more information and will update when we know more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r6QPJm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing... &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/17/22388685/twitter-partial-outage-saturday-east-coast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/17/22388685/twitter-partial-outage-saturday-east-coast</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T21:25:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T21:25:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton is fighting a recall request on its treadmill after a child died last month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/evM_OL3GiOeamlcZQpFtCK7EhdE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69141043/akrales_170407_1569_0850.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1AV52L"&gt;Peloton is resisting a request from the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to recall its Tread Plus treadmill, which was &lt;a href="https://support.onepeloton.com/hc/en-us/articles/360058677091-A-Note-from-Peloton-CEO-John-Foley-about-Tread-"&gt;involved with the death of a child last month&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/04/16/peloton-treadmill-injuries-death-cpsc/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; is reporting tonight&lt;/a&gt;. At the time of the incident, the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thestreet.com%2Finvesting%2Fus-consumer-agency-to-investigate-peloton-treadmill-death&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F16%2F22388707%2Fpeloton-fighting-recall-treadmill-child-death" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CPSC issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; that it was investigating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rWjp6m"&gt;The agency is reportedly planning on issuing a consumer alert about the Tread Plus and may do so as early as Saturday, according to officials who spoke to the &lt;em&gt;Post. &lt;/em&gt;One official added that “this doesn’t happen with other treadmills.” The &lt;em&gt;Post’s&lt;/em&gt; sources tell the paper that the CPSC is aware of “‘dozens’ of incidents involving Peloton’s treadmills, some involving pets or exercise balls and many of them resulting in serious injuries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4eLrE6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-18/peloton-ceo-says-accident-with-treadmill-led-to-death-of-child?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; this this past February the &lt;a href="https://www.saferproducts.gov/PublicSearch/Detail?ReportId=3054628"&gt;CPSC received a report&lt;/a&gt; that a three-year-old suffered a ”significant brain injury. He was found to have tread marks on his back matching the slats of the treadmill, neck injury, and petechiae on his face, presumably from occlusion of blood flow.” Peloton commented on the report that the child from that separate incident “is expected to fully recover.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="96Et8p"&gt;Peloton CEO John Foley &lt;a href="https://support.onepeloton.com/hc/en-us/articles/360058677091-A-Note-from-Peloton-CEO-John-Foley-about-Tread-"&gt;noted the death in an open letter&lt;/a&gt; on March 18th, in which he reiterated the safety instructions for Peloton’s Tread Plus exercise treadmill, including “Keep children and pets away from Peloton exercise equipment at all times. Before you begin a workout, double check to make sure that the space around your Peloton exercise equipment is clear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XJcqd6"&gt;“While we are aware of only a small handful of incidents involving the Tread+ where children have been hurt,” Foley wrote, “each one is devastating to all of us at Peloton, and our hearts go out to the families involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QfDmdj"&gt;In a comment to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Peloton spokesperson writes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="3WiKKJ"&gt;We are disappointed that the CPSC is mischaracterizing the situation. The Peloton Tread+ is safe for use at home when operated as directed and in accordance with our warnings and safety instructions. As a reminder, the Tread+ is not for children under 16 and children, pets, and objects need to be kept away from the Tread+ at all times. Peloton is 100% committed to the safety of our Members and we will always be open to working with the CPSC to implement impactful safety measures. When the Tread+ is not in use, Members should continue to follow the safety instructions by storing the safety key, which keeps the Tread+ from operating, away from the Tread+ and out of reach of children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="xFbIVy"&gt;A spokesperson for the company told the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; that it “does not believe a recall is necessary” and further that it didn’t provide more information to the CPSC at the family’s own request — and therefore asked the agency to issue a subpoena. The CPSC reportedly has issued an administrative subpoena that required Peloton to provide regulators the family’s contact information so that it can investigate the incident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MSNKYU"&gt;At issue is whether the accident was a result of a poorly designed product or improper use — Peloton says that not only should children be kept away from the treadmill, but that owners should “store it out of reach of children” when it’s not in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pW1w42"&gt;In October of 2020 &lt;a href="https://www.cpsc.gov/Recalls/2020/peloton-recalls-pr70p-bike-pedals-due-to-laceration-hazard-recall-alert"&gt;Peloton recalled&lt;/a&gt; the PR70P Clip-In Pedals, because they “can break unexpectedly during use, causing laceration injuries.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IKDTLb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388707/peloton-fighting-recall-treadmill-child-death"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388707/peloton-fighting-recall-treadmill-child-death</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T19:50:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T19:50:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Camera footage from wolf’s collar reveals a very good boy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r2ZobcYyv3l8vR2iQg2Zl740xjk=/136x0:1462x884/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140802/Screen_Shot_2021_04_16_at_4.36.49_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XdBpoK"&gt;Have you ever wanted to watch a wolf hunt freshwater fish? Thanks to the Voyageurs Wolf Project from the University of Minnesota, you can see it on YouTube any time you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hKdqn3"&gt;The researchers with the project trapped V089, a lone wolf, sedated him, and then strapped on the Vectronic-Aerospace camera collar. The collar recorded video in 30 second bursts during daylight hours, for a total of 7 minutes a day. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZYgADito0E0jAoMe7RvXSQGiCJM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22450235/Screen_Shot_2021_04_16_at_4.39.19_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The wolf is a regular neckbeard, it turns out&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SbK97l"&gt;The footage is &lt;em&gt;very cool&lt;/em&gt;, though some of it is obscured by V089’s fur. (“The wolf’s beard needed a little trim... lesson learned,” one video caption says.) They found that V089 was clever enough to hunt near a beaver dam, going after fish that were trapped by the obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AMXB5B"&gt;“Up until recently, wolves hunting and killing freshwater fish is something that people didn’t even really know happened,” researcher &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/see-the-first-camera-collar-footage-from-a-wild-wolf-1846702152"&gt;Thomas Gable told &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The Voyageurs Wolf Project documented wolves hunting freshwater fish in one pack a few years ago, but assumed that it was just a weird quirk. “The fact that this wolf started doing this is evidence that it’s not a one-off thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ugYV1x"&gt;Other highlights of the footage include the wolf chewing on a deer bone, tromping through a river, and eating a fish. Who’s a good boy? V089! Who owns the copyright? Probably the Voyageurs Wolf Project, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/13/17235486/monkey-selfie-lawsuit-ninth-circuit-motion-to-dismiss-denied"&gt;unless PETA gets involved&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388609/wolf-collar-camera-fish-voyageurs-minnesota"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388609/wolf-collar-camera-fish-voyageurs-minnesota</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T19:19:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T19:19:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Edward Snowden NFT sells for more than $5.4 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cory Doctorow and Edward Snowden" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PJMHKiKso-YfZUkeRuLWUcSh-qU=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140678/live_2017_05_03_snowden_doctorow_6420.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sarah Stacke / NYPL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CZyzIz"&gt;Today, NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden’s NFT &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/Snowden/stay-free-edward-snowden-2021-24437"&gt;sold for about $5.4 million&lt;/a&gt;, or 2,224 ETH. The NFT is of an artwork that shows an image of Snowden’s face made from pages of a US appeals court decision that ruled the mass surveillance program Snowden exposed had violated US law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZQZ7V"&gt;The image is called “Stay Free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ovZqc"&gt;The profits won’t go to America’s most famous exiled whistleblower, however. Instead, the sale is meant to benefit the Freedom of the Press Foundation, where Snowden is the president. &lt;a href="https://freedom.press/about/board/"&gt;Its board&lt;/a&gt; includes actor John Cusack, whistleblower Daniel Ellsberg, and the writer Glenn Greenwald.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pw0Sqr"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We have a winner, internet friends. I want to extend a very special thanks to everyone who followed this over the last 24 hours, and the deepest gratitude from EVERYONE at our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FreedomofPress?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@FreedomofPress&lt;/a&gt; to those who bid on our charity event. You help us make a better world. Stay free! &lt;a href="https://t.co/A5SJDs5Sjp"&gt;https://t.co/A5SJDs5Sjp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Edward Snowden (@Snowden) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Snowden/status/1383155552793026560?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fMgku4"&gt;“Emerging applications of cryptography can play an important role in supporting our rights,” Snowden said &lt;a href="https://freedom.press/news/whistleblower-edward-snowden-charity-nft-auction/"&gt;in a statement from the Freedom of the Press Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. “This auction will drive the development of valuable and privacy-protecting uses of encryption, to safeguard press freedom and serve the public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9UklV2"&gt;Snowden, who currently lives in Moscow, copied top-secret information from the National Security Agency and gave it to Greenwald and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/17/6994115/laura-poitras-interview-encryption-snowden-citizenfour"&gt;documentary filmmaker Laura Poitras&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The articles based on Snowden’s information, published in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;won the Pulitzer Prize for Public Service. In 2020, seven years after Snowden passed his documents to Greenwald and Poitras, the &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-nsa-spying/u-s-court-mass-surveillance-program-exposed-by-snowden-was-illegal-idUSKBN25T3CK"&gt;US Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit ruled&lt;/a&gt; that the mass surveillance of Americans’ telephone records was illegal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388548/edward-snowden-nft-freedom-of-the-press-stay-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388548/edward-snowden-nft-freedom-of-the-press-stay-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T18:20:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T18:20:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Peak Design’s new magnet-powered phone case system delayed until August</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gWzo_cLVS7ceJ6Kgj014SpTMMeo=/0x92:2200x1559/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140354/20201018_Sean_Hollister_Verge_15.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eoaV6S"&gt;Peak Design has &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/peak-design/mobile-by-peak-design-phone-cases-mounts-chargers-magsafe/posts/3132766?ref=ksr_email_backer_project_update_registered_users"&gt;announced it is delaying shipment of products&lt;/a&gt; in its &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/peak-design/mobile-by-peak-design-phone-cases-mounts-chargers-magsafe/posts/3132766?ref=ksr_email_backer_project_update_registered_users"&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; for Mobile, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/19/21522620/peak-design-mobile-phone-case-bike-car-mount-tripod-hands-on-kickstarter"&gt;broad range of phone accessories&lt;/a&gt; designed to make it easy to mount your phone on everything from a motorcycle handlebar to a simple dock on your desk. It is meant to be compatible with iPhones and Samsung Galaxy phones. Originally targeted for May, the company now expects to be able to begin shipping in August, though some products will also come later. To make up for it, Peak is offering either full refunds for cancellations or discounts on other Peak Design products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6i4Cra"&gt;Peak Design has used Kickstarter to launch everything from camera-focused backpacks to tripods and its original product, an innovative camera mounting clip. But this new project is on a different scale of ambition: it’s multiple products designed to work together in an interlocking system of mounts, wireless chargers, mini tripods, wallets, and cases. Key to the entire system is a combination of magnets and physical locking mechanisms which can differ from product to product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8oP81W"&gt;The project apparently started about two years ago, which means that just before the company was running to launch in October of 2020 Apple announced the iPhone 12 — complete with the MagSafe system of cases, chargers, and wallets that connect with magnets. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Some prototypes in Peak Design’s mobile system" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wQq6znEkQQtz2ySBD1SF_SJs4vI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21971354/20201018_Sean_Hollister_Verge_27.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Some prototypes in Peak Design’s mobile system&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="jbatU0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1523637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wkoykp"&gt;Apple’s MagSafe system and Peak Design’s magnet system are different, but the company made the call to try to make its system interoperable in some ways with MagSafe. That has meant testing its products across all the different variables it could think of, mixing and matching Peak Design’s big portfolio of products with Apple’s new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfwHer"&gt;That complexity is one of the reasons for the delay, the first in Peak Design’s long history marketing products on Kickstarter. The second is the obvious one: delays introduced from COVID-19. The designers have been unable to travel to the factory to test their designs or go into their local workshop to suss out problems directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELmLDU"&gt;The company expects its first wave to include the most basic products in its lineup, cases and some “core mounts/accessories,” with a second wave coming “later.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8l4vYz"&gt;Peak Design will email Kickstarter backers discount codes for its products (20 percent off anything plus 50 percent off a future purchase in the Mobile product line). It also says people who wish to cancel their pledge can email info@peakdesign.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WbQ2UK"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9LvWedEvR98?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388468/peak-design-new-magnet-iphone-case-system-delayed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388468/peak-design-new-magnet-iphone-case-system-delayed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T18:14:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T18:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Robinhood can’t handle the Dogecoin rally</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v5auLwHRZvB2DZSfu9i8NbOhJqI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140309/acastro_210201_1777_robinhood_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LWI7tJ"&gt;Yesterday and today, the enthusiasm for joke cryptocurrency Dogecoin overwhelmed Robinhood, leading to “sporadic crypto order failures and delayed notifications for some customers,” &lt;a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/4/16/a-new-generation-of-investors-crypto-and-robinhood"&gt;Robinhood wrote in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yr2uD8"&gt;“These interruptions aren’t acceptable to us,” Robinhood wrote in its post. “We believe we’re the most intuitive crypto platform for Dogecoin traders and we’re proud to be a top choice for this community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3avk3"&gt;Robinhood has a history of exactly this kind of whoopsie. In March 2020, there were&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/9/21171584/robinhood-outage-week-us-stocks-third-market"&gt; three huge outages&lt;/a&gt; which Robinhood has said were due to “&lt;a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2020/3/3/an-update-from-robinhoods-founders"&gt;stress on our infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;.” And infamously, in January, Robinhood limited &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22254656/robinhood-gamestop-stonks-trade-freeze-class-action-lawsuits"&gt;trades on GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, pissing off the entire internet and getting itself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254584/gamestop-robinhood-short-reddit-wallstreetbets-aoc-ted-cruz"&gt;hauled in front of Congress&lt;/a&gt; in the process because it hadn’t planned for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;anything approaching the scale of Gamestonk.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1OWqan"&gt;Look, the app is very pretty and easy to use, but if it fails during the most &lt;em&gt;crucial&lt;/em&gt; buying and selling periods, are users going to stick with it? Whether you make money on your Dogecoin trade matters more than than how nice the app is. Besides,&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/platform/amp/2021/4/14/22383748/coinbase-nasdaq-ipo-direct-listing"&gt; there’s the now-public Coinbase platform&lt;/a&gt; to trade cryptocurrency on anyway — even if it &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/coinbase-dogecoin-listing-binance"&gt;doesn’t support Dogecoin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ehZ3N7"&gt;The Robinhood post, frustratingly, doesn’t go into the technical details that could have let users know how serious the failure was, or why it happened. When asked for comment, Robinhood declined to say anything on the record beyond the blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64RdPy"&gt;In conclusion, I must &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373990/robinhood-ipo-form-regulators-finance"&gt;once again beg for the Robinhood S-1&lt;/a&gt;, which I need in order to live. I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; know what the risk factors section looks like, and if these kinds of outages are significant enough to the company to be listed there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5e6Bz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 6:44PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Adds that Robinhood declined to comment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388447/robinhood-app-dogecoin-rally-failed-trades"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388447/robinhood-app-dogecoin-rally-failed-trades</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T17:53:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T17:53:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>You ever think about how Asus put out like 40 models of a laptop called the “Eee PC”</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="pile of netbooks" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MqkYvDCpI9jjjGTV_Mp-ThmXpes=/1x0:1020x679/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140173/pile_o_netbooks.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1JwOdb"&gt;There’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22385362/apple-event-ipad-airpods-pencil-tv-tags-rumors-spring-loaded"&gt;an Apple event next week&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s looking fairly likely that we’ll see updated models of the iPad Pro and perhaps the iPad Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OxpS38"&gt;Which is great, because it made me think about the Eee PC, which was either one of the greatest short-lived success stories in tech history or a collective delusion shared by a handful of late 2000s tech bloggers that never actually happened.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Eee PC 701SDX" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MUaxnz9OohZy_IiG9Ak_NDHPLw4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22449734/dims.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Eee PC 701SDX. It had an SD card slot, and an X.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jw4TJi"&gt;There were two products that arrived in 2007 that fundamentally changed computing: one, of course, was the iPhone. The second, obviously more important product was the $399 Eee PC 701. It originally ran a custom Linux operating system that reviewers loved (&lt;a href="https://www.laptopmag.com/reviews/laptops/asus-eee-pc-701"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laptop Mag&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Spoonauer said&lt;/a&gt; it was “ten times simpler to use than any Windows notebook”) and was generally heralded as a new kind of computer with tremendous mass appeal. Spoonauer: “Pound for pound, the best value-priced notebook on the planet.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4d79D"&gt;Again, this was a weirdo little two-pound plastic laptop that ran &lt;em&gt;a custom Linux distro&lt;/em&gt; that was basically a front for various websites. (We hadn’t invented the phrase “cloud services” yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFTh6T"&gt;Windows getting shown up by Linux was not allowed, so Microsoft did some Microsoft maneuvering, and by January 2008 the Eee PC was running Windows XP instead. It was also part of a larger category called “netbooks,” and we were all made to know what netbooks were.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A blue Eee PC" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GemsNYBRMI7fYi6EomiLxLYPBK0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22449759/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5ibG9nY2RuLmNvbS93d3cuZW5nYWRnZXQuY29tL21lZGlhLzIwMDkvMTIvYXN1c2VlZXBjMTAwNXBlMTYuanBn.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This Eee PC ran a “Pine Trail” processor so Joanna photographed it with pine branches. This was state-of-the-art tech blogging in 2009.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jzBH57"&gt;A little later, Microsoft created something called Windows 7 Starter, which was a hilarious cut-down version of Windows just for netbooks — you weren’t even &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2009/06/19/oems_cant_brand_windows_7_starter_desktop/"&gt;allowed to change the desktop background&lt;/a&gt;! — and the netbook explosion was unstoppable. My friend (and Verge co-founder) Joanna Stern built the early part of her career obsessively covering netbooks, first at &lt;em&gt;Laptop Mag&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;, and then with me at &lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yfABYp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Do you remember when the Nokia Booklet 3G was going to reinvent Nokia? You do not, because it didn’t.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vh59WB"&gt;And there was a lot to cover: at one point Joanna noted that Asus had put out &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2009-12-21-asus-eee-pc-1005pe-review.html"&gt;at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; 20 different models of Eee PC&lt;/a&gt; in 2008 &lt;em&gt;alone&lt;/em&gt;. And that was just Asus! Dell, HP, Lenovo and others all chased after the netbook idea furiously. Do you remember when the &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2009-12-04-nokia-booklet-3g-review.html"&gt;Nokia Booklet 3G&lt;/a&gt; was going to reinvent Nokia? You do not, because it didn’t. It was very pretty, though. I asked Joanna about this moment in time, and this is what she sent me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZyvYzp"&gt;“I was basically Bono in this ‘I Still Haven’t Found What I’m Looking For’ video. Eee PC after Eee PC. MSI Wind after MSI Wind. Toshiba whatever it was called after Toshiba whatever it was called. I was constantly looking for a netbook that had a keyboard that didn’t require doll hands, a trackpad that didn’t leave a blister on my thumb, a hard drive that didn’t take three days to open Microsoft Word. It was a constant search for the perfect blend of price, portability and power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uUCvfr"&gt;Joanna then demanded I embed the actual YouTube video of U2’s “I Still Haven’t Found What I’m Looking For,” which is exactly the sort of “wow that was really important once” energy this blog post needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ch8I0j"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e3-5YC_oHjE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9piM2e"&gt;The netbook explosion was all the more odd because every netbook had the same basic specs, as Microsoft charged more for a standard non-Starter Windows license if a computer had anything more than a 1.6GHz Intel Atom processor, 1GB of RAM, and a 160GB hard drive. So it was all colors and screen sizes, really. All to run a deeply-annoying version of Windows, on a computer that no one was even remotely claiming could replace a primary PC. By the end of it all, as the chips inevitably got more powerful, enough laptop vendors were telling Joanna that their new netbook-like computers &lt;em&gt;weren’t&lt;/em&gt; netbooks that she started calling them “&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2011-01-31-editorial-the-rise-of-the-notbook-the-fall-of-the-netbook.html"&gt;notbooks&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lyVB6o"&gt;And then the iPad came out in 2010, and netbooks were inexplicably such a part of the computing vocabulary that Steve Jobs introduced the iPad &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/0XJg74qnvxE?t=478"&gt;by explicitly saying that netbooks were bad&lt;/a&gt;. “The problem is netbooks aren’t better at anything,” is a real thing Steve Jobs said on stage, in order to clearly distinguish the then-new iPad from netbooks. It was important to him! &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Steve Jobs looking forlorn about netbooks in 2010" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M-du79JlI9Xr5P4fQ0kslY5cuJQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22449706/Screen_Shot_2021_04_16_at_4.20.19_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Steve Jobs looking forlorn about netbooks while announcing the iPad in 2010&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rzlsZt"&gt;Did any of this even &lt;em&gt;happen&lt;/em&gt;? Is this &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;? I remember it all, but I can’t tell if it meant anything, or if we all just believed Microsoft and Intel were so mysteriously powerful that we had to live in their product frameworks and 160GB of maximum hard drive space. Did anyone actually &lt;em&gt;buy&lt;/em&gt; a netbook? The only people I ever met who had netbooks were other tech writers; at one memorable trade show my colleague Adi Robertson showed up with &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; a gigantic gaming laptop &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a tiny netbook, two laptops both perfectly ill-suited for the tasks at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldTksI"&gt;I asked Joanna, who is now a senior personal technology columnist at the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, about all this, who replied: “Let’s be clear here. Apple’s coming event this week is actually about netbooks. The iPad Pro is an outgrowth of the netbook movement a decade ago.” Was she joking? I don’t know, and she wouldn’t tell me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GwflbH"&gt;Now, of course, there aren’t any netbooks, but everything is a netbook. The iPad is the iPad, with multiple models at various sizes and price points, and a furious ongoing debate about whether it can replace a laptop. (See? It’s a netbook.) Chromebooks exist, and both Apple and Microsoft worry about them in familiar ways. We are surrounded by appliance-like cheap computers that run goofy custom interfaces to cloud services on top of open-source operating systems — that’s an Echo Show, or a Google Chromecast, or even an Oculus Quest 2. Netbooks. Intel is badly in need of a reinvention and Windows itself is diminished; Microsoft would happily &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21071108/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-iot-windows-ios-android-future"&gt;call its operating system “Azure Edge”&lt;/a&gt; if anyone would go along for that kind of ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlM9rL"&gt;Did netbooks ever happen? Did netbooks... &lt;em&gt;win?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unK8sp"&gt;Eee, PC. Eee.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388238/asus-eee-pc-netbook-laptop-line-linux-ipad-pro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388238/asus-eee-pc-netbook-laptop-line-linux-ipad-pro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T17:48:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T17:48:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk says Starlink internet service should be ‘fully mobile’ by the end of this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A phone finding starlink satellites" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DSmPiM_POynWnu0eMaNj9nGrkVg=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69140148/1231999016.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo credit should read Costfoto/Barcroft Media via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bwy9dn"&gt;SpaceX’s new Starlink satellite internet service is in a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; limited beta testing period right now, but the company is already thinking ahead: as &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/08/spacex-wants-to-connect-starlink-satellite-internet-to-moving-vehicles.html"&gt;first noted by CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, SpaceX has filed an application with the FCC for Starlink components that would allow the service to work on moving vehicles. &lt;em&gt;Big&lt;/em&gt; moving vehicles, that is — Elon Musk tweeted that the existing Starlink terminals are too big for Tesla’s vehicles, and the idea is targeted at planes, RVs, trucks, and ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NuJXNj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Not connecting Tesla cars to Starlink, as our terminal is much too big. This is for aircraft, ships, large trucks &amp;amp; RVs.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1369051431903268865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nMSA0t"&gt;This would be a big change for Starlink, which right now does not even allow customers to move the existing hardware from address to address — if you can get in the beta, the signup forms are clear that the service is limited to the location you enter at checkout. That’s because the Starlink satellite constellation isn’t fully built out yet, so it’s not a permanent limitation, but it’s still a limitation today, and one that Elon once again clarified today in a tweet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dRpkhH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yeah, should be fully mobile later this year, so you can move it anywhere or use it on an RV or truck in motion. We need a few more satellite launches to achieve compete coverage &amp;amp; some key software upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1382842277719003136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DfGY4S"&gt;I actually have a Starlink system that I’ll be reviewing for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s upcoming Infrastructure Week — the promise of fast, reliable satellite internet that can compete with America’s various broadband monopolies is very enticing, but early testers have reported mixed results. (Which, again, Elon says will improve.) Let me know if you have questions in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388378/elon-musk-starlink-satellite-internet-service-moving-vehicles-trucks-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388378/elon-musk-starlink-satellite-internet-service-moving-vehicles-trucks-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T16:55:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T16:55:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>New York State just passed a law requiring ISPs to offer $15 broadband</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jd_UKPr_GKd-MFSnmCtM5IyalZo=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69139841/VRG_ILLO_4341_American_Ethernet.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Tr6Ana"&gt;Internet should become a lot more affordable in New York after Governor Andrew Cuomo &lt;a href="https://www.governor.ny.gov/news/governor-cuomo-signs-legislation-establishing-first-nation-program-provide-affordable-internet"&gt;signed a bill&lt;/a&gt; that requires all Internet Service Providers operating in New York state to offer a $15 a month broadband option for low-income consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4PlbUv"&gt;According to NY Assembly member Amy Paulin (&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-16/n-y-to-require-all-internet-providers-offer-low-cost-broadband?sref=P6Q0mxvj"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), the average price of broadband in New York is currently $50. This new bill caps the price at $15 for regular broadband and $20 for high-speed broadband, but only for those who qualify as low income. That’s still over 7 million people in 2.7 million households &lt;a href="https://www.governor.ny.gov/news/governor-cuomo-signs-legislation-establishing-first-nation-program-provide-affordable-internet"&gt;according to a press release from Cuomo’s office&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0RxNR"&gt;This is a remarkable move toward making broadband internet the affordable utility most people treat it as. Cuomo’s office told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that for $15 a month ISPs must provide the greater of two speeds: either 25 Mbps down, or the speed of the ISP’s existing low-income broadband service. The former is the same speed defined as broadband by the FCC, and it’s not considered especially speedy. The FCC’s 25 Mbps definition of broadband has remained in place since 2015 and has been criticized as outdated. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22312065/fcc-highspeed-broadband-service-ajit-pai-bennet-angus-king-rob-portman"&gt;Earlier in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, a bipartisan group of senators called on the FCC to redefine broadband as 100 Mbps down and 100 Mbps up, as that would better reflect how people actually use their internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Zlv4R"&gt;Still, paying $15 a month for 25 Mbps down is a heckuva lot better than paying $50 a month for those same speeds. Better yet, for those living in urban areas such as New York City, where the internet tends to be much faster, &lt;a href="https://www.nyassembly.gov/leg/?default_fld=&amp;amp;leg_video=&amp;amp;bn=A03006&amp;amp;term=&amp;amp;Summary=Y&amp;amp;Actions=Y&amp;amp;Memo=Y&amp;amp;Text=Y"&gt;the same bill&lt;/a&gt; caps the price of broadband up to 200 Mbps at just $20 a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuOkaU"&gt;In addition to capping the price on internet for low-income households, Cuomo also launched a new website, the &lt;a href="https://forward.ny.gov/find-affordable-internet-options-new-york-state"&gt;Affordable Broadband Portal&lt;/a&gt;, to help people find affordable internet in their area. He also announced a partnership with the Ford Foundation and Google founder Eric Schmidt’s Schmidt Futures to &lt;a href="https://www.governor.ny.gov/news/governor-cuomo-announces-launch-connected-ny-fund-provide-no-cost-internet-access-50000"&gt;create the ConnectEd NY fund&lt;/a&gt;. The goal of the fund is to provide free internet access to approximately 50,000 students in economically disadvantaged school districts. It’s expected to operate through June 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFb1f9"&gt;Cuomo has passed a number of popular pieces of legislation in the last month—including the legalization of recreational weed use. A cynical person might interpret this latest, and extremely good move, as &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/13/magazine/andrew-cuomo.html"&gt;another effort to distract from the growing number of scandals surround Cuomo&lt;/a&gt;. But a good thing is a good thing regardless of the motivation, and this appears to be a very good thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gcmtld"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388184/new-york-affordable-internet-cost-low-income-price-cap-bill"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388184/new-york-affordable-internet-cost-low-income-price-cap-bill</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
