<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-21T05:19:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-21T05:19:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T05:19:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dating apps are encouraging users to get vaccinated with the promise of more matches</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gjc2j2vemh8RAiyBQkBeOpFlzws=/61x0:4567x3004/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69321688/Tinder_COVIDStickers_Overview.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tinder’s profile vaccination badges.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Tinder&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="97pZSi"&gt;A group of the USA’s biggest dating apps are encouraging users to get vaccinated, just in case the health benefits weren’t reason enough. New features will range from badges for users to show their vaccination status, free premium features for vaccinated users, and links to vaccination resources like the &lt;a href="http://Vaccines.gov"&gt;Vaccines.gov&lt;/a&gt; website. The apps taking part in the scheme include Match Group’s Tinder, Hinge, Match, OKCupid, BLK, Chispa, and Plenty of Fish services, as well as Bumble and Badoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EY6DQP"&gt;The aim is to encourage users to get vaccinated, with the implied promise of more matches and hence more dates. The announcement cites research from OKCupid suggesting that people who either are, or plan to be, vaccinated get 14 percent more matches. Some apps will even let users filter matches by vaccination status. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UleogWTtgsd43eB_IpSu82CXLqs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22530213/Hinge_Covid_Vaccine_Badge_Horz.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hinge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A mockup of Hinge’s vaccination indicator.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="haYAo9"&gt;Specific features will vary by app. Tinder is giving out free premium features to vaccinated users, adding pro-vaccine profile stickers, and incorporating links to vaccination resources. Bumble and Badoo will offer similar vaccine profile badges, and complimentary premium credits to vaccinated users. Hinge is also giving out normally paid-for features, and is encouraging users to share their vaccination status on their profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ZKQFf"&gt;What’s unclear at the moment is how the apps plan to verify that users who claim to be vaccinated have actually received a jab. Many of the apps, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/23/21077423/tinder-photo-verification-blue-checkmark-safety-center-launch-noonlight"&gt;such as Tinder&lt;/a&gt;, already offer verification features, so theoretically they already have systems in place to verify similar information. We’ve reached out to the group for confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SEMgS3"&gt;At the time of writing, the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/world/covid-vaccinations-tracker.html"&gt;vaccine tracker&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reports that 48 percent of people in the US have received at least one dose of the vaccine, while 38 percent are fully vaccinated. President Biden has set a target of getting 70 percent of adults in the country their first shot by July 4th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447028/dating-apps-covid-19-vaccine-tinder-hinge-match-okcupid-blk-chispa-plenty-of-fish-bumble-badoo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447028/dating-apps-covid-19-vaccine-tinder-hinge-match-okcupid-blk-chispa-plenty-of-fish-bumble-badoo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-21T04:15:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T04:15:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon is shutting down Prime Now and folding two-hour deliveries into its main app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hYZC8YqdqX1ryEAHPmG01xizMl0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69321638/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iLZyeO"&gt;Amazon is shutting down its standalone Prime Now delivery app, with its speedy two-hour delivery options moving exclusively into the company’s main app and website, the &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/prime-now-finds-a-new-home-on-amazon"&gt;company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. Prime Now services have already moved into the main app in India, Japan, and Singapore, while in other countries Amazon is already directing Prime Now users into its main app and website via a pop-up, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/21/amazon-is-shutting-down-its-prime-now-fast-delivery-app.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;. The standalone Prime Now app and website will be retired by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vPfhrL"&gt;Originally launched in 2014, Prime Now was designed to offer deliveries of essential items within hours rather than days for Prime members. The service was initially available in just a small number of cities, but has since expanded to over 5,000 locations around the world, &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; notes. Writing in a blog post, Amazon’s vice president of grocery Stephenie Landry said shutting down the separate app will “make this experience even more seamless for customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qy4izV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon says it will be “even more seamless for customers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JzAStT"&gt;Two-hour delivery options from Amazon Fresh and Whole Foods have been available on the main Amazon site and app in the US since 2019, but the company says third-party partners and local stores around the world will be moved onto its main service by the end of the year. These include local stores like Bartell’s in Seattle, Morrisons in Leeds, or Monoprix in Paris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0qYApN"&gt;Today’s news follows Amazon’s announcement &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220331/amazon-pantry-discontinued-prime-grocery-delivery-services"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt; that it would be discontinuing its Amazon Pantry service and making those household goods and groceries available through the main Amazon website. It’s also been rebranding its Go Grocery brand as Amazon Fresh, &lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/amazon-rebrands-amazon-go-grocery-amazon-fresh-closes-seattle-area-store-near-microsoft-hq/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeekWire &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Between the moves, Amazon is consolidating and simplifying its sprawling array of grocery delivery services.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447020/amazon-shutting-down-prime-day-delivery-app-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447020/amazon-shutting-down-prime-day-delivery-app-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-21T04:08:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T04:08:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Smaller Pixel 6 leaks with flat screen and fewer cameras</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dWmKknsp9GG8QoIu3cza5DLzSH8=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69321632/PIXEL_6_5K3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jw8QBm"&gt;Yesterday &lt;em&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/em&gt; released CAD renders of what is supposedly Google’s next flagship phone, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen"&gt;the Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and now the noted leaker has followed up with details and images of the smaller model, &lt;a href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/google-pixel-6-renders-design-exclusive/"&gt;posted at &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The so-called Pixel 6 looks like it’ll adopt the same distinctive design as the Pro, with one colorway featuring orange and white sections broken up by a glossy black bar that houses the camera bump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27MzEy"&gt;You’ll find one fewer camera in that bump, according to the leak — it’s said to be a dual-camera setup, presumably a regular wide and an ultrawide. The 6 Pro, on the other hand, appears to include a periscope telephoto lens. Both phones are depicted with a single centrally aligned hole-punch selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wKCqlx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A 6.4-inch display without curved edges&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="On1SQc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt; says that the Pixel 6 has a 6.4-inch display with flat edges, unlike the curved 6.67-inch panel used in the 6 Pro. The 6 reportedly also has wireless charging, an in-display fingerprint sensor, and bottom-firing stereo speakers, with dimensions of 158.6mm x 74.8mm x 8.9mm. The &lt;em&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/em&gt; renders match up with designs shown off by &lt;em&gt;Front Page Tech&lt;/em&gt;’s Jon Prosser &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VzupAfbY8a4"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h2e31s"&gt;There’s no word on exactly when the Pixel 6 will launch, but Pixel phones do have a habit of leaking (or even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18663172/google-pixel-4-camera-sensor-design-official-photo"&gt;being announced by Google&lt;/a&gt;) well before their eventual release date, so we could well be waiting until fall. At this point, it’s almost a surprise that leakers managed to beat Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352032/google-pixel-5-4a-5g-price-release-date-specs"&gt;to the punch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWRPbb"&gt;Google has also said it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;planning to release a Pixel 5A phone&lt;/a&gt; later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-21T03:30:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T03:30:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Kensington’s $399 StudioDock won’t fit the new, slightly thicker 12.9-inch iPad Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L1t1l2OADILkzW4pksRMRx4_UTk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69321578/DSCF7579.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tmzK2w"&gt;Kensington’s StudioDock, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22333551/kensington-studiodock-review-ipad-desktop-dock-accessory"&gt;high-end $399.99 desktop hub for the iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; that was released earlier this year, isn’t compatible with the new 12.9-inch model hitting stores today. A representative for Kensington confirmed the news to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, saying it’s because the new iPad Pro is 0.5mm thicker than the 2018 and 2020 models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ezaBH"&gt;The StudioDock uses a rotatable magnetic mounting plate to secure the iPad when it’s plugged in over USB-C, expanding its connectivity with extra USB-A, ethernet, and HDMI ports. Although the only difference between the StudioDock versions for the 12.9-inch and 11-inch iPad Pro is the size of that mounting plate, Kensington says it won’t be user-replaceable. Instead, the company plans to release an entirely new SKU to fit the 2021 12.9-inch iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2AUaAU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Kensington StudioDock turns your iPad into a tiny iMac","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22333551/kensington-studiodock-review-ipad-desktop-dock-accessory"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NUKh4H"&gt;The new 11-inch iPad Pro should be unaffected, because its dimensions are the same as last year’s model. The 12.9-inch version, however, is slightly thicker because it uses a new, more advanced display with Mini LED technology. Apple itself has warned that its 2020 Magic Keyboard “may not precisely fit” the 2021 12.9-inch iPad Pro due to this difference in thickness, although we found it worked fine in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhUgUb"&gt;No such luck for the StudioDock — you’ll need to buy a whole new one if you want to upgrade your iPad. This wasn’t entirely unforeseeable, and I warned of the possibility when reviewing the StudioDock in March because new iPad Pro models did seem overdue. But the incompatibility is unfortunate for such an expensive product, especially since it was only just released.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22446998/kensington-studiodock-2021-ipad-pro-compatibility-new-version"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22446998/kensington-studiodock-2021-ipad-pro-compatibility-new-version</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T19:36:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T19:36:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart’s accessibility features try to make a hectic game easier to play  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YHjSwL-33uL562j70q_QLegSZ6w=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69320356/RACRA_Juggernaut_Legal_scaled.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iOIPLG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278233/ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-ps5-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; brings alternate realities to the beloved PlayStation franchise on June 11th, and along with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22431256/ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-ps5-interiew-tech-ray-tracing-ssd"&gt;leveraging the PlayStation 5’s SSD&lt;/a&gt;, Insomniac Games &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/insomniacgames/status/1395407201355845633?s=20"&gt;announced new accessibility features&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday that build on the studio’s recent work and address the limited options presented in the earlier PS4 &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xx1Nma"&gt;As an action platformer, &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank&lt;/em&gt; often requires multiple types of movement: You’ll shoot through waves of oncoming enemies while running around a level, and quickly shift to jumping across floating platforms, and using various gadgets to fly, swing, and now reality-warp through stages. &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; seems to keep those core mechanics but adds even more potentially sensory-overloading visuals, from cracks in reality to exploding fragments of buildings. All of which makes the new features Insomniac is adding all the more welcome. You can get a taste of what &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;actually plays like in the demo below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TXCUbi"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GffelVJeGws?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n1wnDd"&gt;That occasionally hectic gameplay of the earlier game can be fun, but without customization options for controls — as noted &lt;a href="https://dagersystem.com/disability-review-ratchet-and-clank/"&gt;in this accessibility review&lt;/a&gt; — it could also make the game hard to play for people with disabilities that impact fine motor skills. Along with full controller remapping, &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://support.insomniac.games/hc/en-us/articles/360061494611-What-Accessibility-options-does-Ratchet-Clank-Rift-Apart-feature-"&gt;addresses the issue in a few ways&lt;/a&gt;, like how you can repeatedly fire one of the game’s various weapons with a button press instead of squeezing a trigger. The game can also automatically switch between targets, and correct your aim, if for instance flying enemies give you trouble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2CIh2s"&gt;For movement, &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;includes features to make flying in the game easier to control, automatically leveling off your glider so you don’t nose dive, and an “Off-Screen Ledge Guard” which should save you from falling off ledges you can’t see if you’re distracted while smashing robots. There’s also an option to assign all of your movement controls to a single button so you don’t have to hit jump and swing on different parts of the controller.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YmeNBdmORva10uJTr-j5tyUPqoc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528495/RACRA_toggles.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Insomniac Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The various toggles in &lt;/em&gt;Rift Apart.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YGgCVd"&gt;Visually, &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;also allows you to tone down the game’s striking, but over-the-top visual effects. You can adjust all the obvious settings like contrast and field of view, but the game also smartly uses a visual shading system similar to what developer Naughty Dog used in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21274923/the-last-of-us-part-2-accessibility-features-naughty-dog-interview-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;to help make things legible. You can apply colored shaders to your character, any of the enemies in game, even interactable objects to make things easier to visually track and find. The game also offers a similar array of adjustments for changing the size of the in-game HUD and button prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_i0SiMNklVieAvPw5J_WCWua2KQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528607/RACRA_contrastmenu02.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Insomniac Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual shaders can help provide contrast, visibility, and make it easier to track things if you’re color blind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dD7rG6"&gt;As part of this new generation of consoles, Sony appears to be trying to be a bit more mindful of the various accessibility issues that can come up while playing. It’s been praised for offering software accessibility options &lt;a href="https://caniplaythat.com/2020/11/06/ps5-accessibility-review-can-i-play-that/"&gt;on the PS5 by default&lt;/a&gt;, like a built-in screen reader, but the real way you can see how things are changing is by looking at the developers Sony owns, works with, and publishes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1UseOX"&gt;Insomniac Games and Naughty Dog clearly seem focused on making their games more accessible. Insomniac’s been building up to this over time as well; the company took special care to add &lt;a href="https://support.insomniac.games/hc/en-us/articles/360052412831-What-Accessibility-options-does-Marvel-s-Spider-Man-Miles-Morales-feature-"&gt;a wide range of accessibility features&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549085/spider-man-miles-morales-review-ps5-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when that game launched with the PS5. The real trick with accessibility options, though, is standardizing them across the board, which seems like it might at least be starting to happen with these Sony exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iul33Q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;launches June 11th on PS5. You can see &lt;a href="https://support.insomniac.games/hc/en-us/articles/360061494611-What-Accessibility-options-does-Ratchet-Clank-Rift-Apart-feature-"&gt;an exhaustive list&lt;/a&gt; of the accessibility options Insomniac is building into the game by visiting its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62DxPJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445828/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-ps5-accessibility-toggles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445828/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-ps5-accessibility-toggles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T18:06:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T18:06:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>One of the US’s largest insurance companies reportedly paid $40 million to ransomware hackers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VVGlo5vtTy7Iri4My15JFspF-eA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319980/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Nmb6K"&gt;CNA Financial, one of the largest US insurance companies, paid $40 million to &lt;a href="https://threatpost.com/cna-hit-novel-ransomware/165044/"&gt;free itself from a ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt; that occurred in March, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-20/cna-financial-paid-40-million-in-ransom-after-march-cyberattack?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The hackers reportedly demanded $60 million when negotiations started about a week after some of CNA’s systems were encrypted, and the insurance company paid the lower sum a week later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9S8zmS"&gt;If the $40 million figure is accurate, CNA’s payout would rank as one of the highest ransomware payouts that we know about, though that’s not for lack of trying by hackers: both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396283/apple-schematics-leak-ransomware-quanta-supplier-leak"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22341642/acer-ransomware-microsoft-exchange-revil-security"&gt;Acer&lt;/a&gt; had data that was compromised in separate $50 million ransomware demands earlier this year. It also seems like the hackers are looking for bigger payouts: just this week we saw reports that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22443933/colonial-pipeline-ransom-4-million-hack-gas-shortage"&gt;Colonial Pipeline paid a $4.4 million ransom to hackers&lt;/a&gt;. While that number isn’t as staggering as the demands made to CNA, it’s still much higher than &lt;a href="https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/featured/average-ransomware-payouts-shoot-up/"&gt;the estimated average enterprise ransomware demand in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fbvm5p"&gt;Law enforcement agencies &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/colonial-pipeline-ransomware-payment/"&gt;recommend against paying ransoms&lt;/a&gt;, saying that payouts will encourage hackers to keep asking for higher and higher sums. For its part, CNA told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;that it wouldn’t comment on the ransom, but that it had “followed all laws, regulations, and published guidance, including OFAC’s 2020 ransomware guidance, in its handling of this matter.” In &lt;a href="https://www.cna.com/web/wcm/connect/96a7c7dd-96d1-41cc-8a0c-25604bfc2898/Security-Incident-Update-5-12-21.pdf?MOD=AJPERES"&gt;an update from May 12&lt;/a&gt;, CNA says that it believes its policyholders’ data were unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pPg36v"&gt;According to&lt;em&gt; Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, the ransomware that locked CNA’s systems was Phoenix Locker, a derivative of another piece of malware called Hades. Hades was allegedly created by a Russian group with the &lt;em&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/em&gt;-esque name Evil Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLBWWu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Bloomberg wrote that the ransomware used against CNA was a derivative of one created by Evil Corp; we initially suggested it was Evil Corp’s original ransomware instead. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pearXi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqyspG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446388/cna-insurance-ransomware-attack-40-million-dollar-ransom"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446388/cna-insurance-ransomware-attack-40-million-dollar-ransom</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T17:50:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T17:50:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Slack’s newest feature will help me remember to pause notifications before calls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nrhi205WN4uoQ9frnFmE2twly2U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319828/acastro_190412_1777_slack_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="G3NGDD"&gt;Slack has added a small but very welcome new feature: when you’re setting a status, you can check a box in that same menu to pause notifications for as long as that status is up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7eCgCQ"&gt;I discovered the checkbox on Thursday while preparing for an interview. When I do interviews or calls, I like to set a status to tell my colleagues what I’m up to and then turn off Slack notifications so I’m not distracted by pings or mentions. Previously, though, pausing notifications required clicking into a second menu — and I’d sometimes forget to turn them off. This new checkbox has the benefit of saving me a bit of time and helping me remember to pause notifications when I need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DTBaxH"&gt;Slack tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that this feature is rolling out now, so you might not have it just yet. If you want to see if you do, go to the “Set a status” menu, type something in the “What’s your status?” field, and then look under the “Clear after:” menu. You should see a checkbox titled “Pause notifications.” Check that, and when you save your status, you won’t get notifications while the status is live.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZpVbO_wENTOVbELEhq1lxeqiVks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22529269/Screen_Shot_2021_05_20_at_2.24.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slack’s new checkbox to pause notifications right from the status menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EuuRZV"&gt;There’s been a fair amount of Slack news within the last day or so. Earlier on Thursday, Slack had an outage &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446007/slack-down-outage-messages-trouble-loading"&gt;that lasted for more than an hour&lt;/a&gt;. And on Wednesday, Slack introduced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22444705/slack-pronouns-field-profiles"&gt;pronouns field for profiles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="utyaSb"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zXXQxi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446385/slack-pause-notifications-set-status-menu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446385/slack-pause-notifications-set-status-menu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T17:35:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T17:35:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Blizzard shows off Overwatch 2’s new 5 vs. 5 multiplayer and a trio of maps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p6Q7e5K25ar3SCOi1L770kS9hzw=/194x0:2234x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319717/Screen_Shot_2021_05_20_at_5.09.41_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uWg8lN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430644/blizzard-overwatch-2-livestream-twitch-youtube"&gt;Blizzard’s two-hour &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2 &lt;/em&gt;stream&lt;/a&gt; showed off the best look yet at the much-anticipated sequel to the competitive team shooter. And while there’s still no release date, the studio did show off plenty of new information about the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5jdU1"&gt;Chief among those is one of the biggest changes to &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; in the game’s history: the sequel will be shifting the default PvP multiplayer mode from six-on-six matches to five-on-five games. Within the current role queuing system, that translates to cutting out a tank character on each team, which will now consist of two support, two DPS, and just a single tank character. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IvLD9P"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Rock to that Rio rhythm in Overwatch 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Points of interest: &lt;br&gt;   Club Sinestesia&lt;br&gt;   Peacock Payload&lt;br&gt;   Oh! Lucio-Oh’s! &lt;a href="https://t.co/8gFxkyN2Ny"&gt;pic.twitter.com/8gFxkyN2Ny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1395471785492111367?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3isScZ"&gt;The explanation behind the changes is to both simplify and shake up &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;’s combat and meta, which tends to calcify toward tank-centric plays, specifically based on utilizing shielding mechanics from characters like Reinhardt or Orisa. In &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;, tank characters are getting some big buffs to make them more powerful (and to help compensate for the lack of a second tank). Reinhardt, for example, is getting a second Firestrike attack, while Winston’s Tesla coil cannon is getting a ranged alt-fire mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4qlnft"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Enjoy a New York slice between battles in Overwatch 2. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Points of interest: &lt;br&gt; ️ Grand Central Terminal&lt;br&gt;   Engine 11&lt;br&gt;  Jephs Corner Pizza &lt;a href="https://t.co/BqxpOvuaYj"&gt;pic.twitter.com/BqxpOvuaYj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1395457550846418947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tFwHf5"&gt;The goal is to help shift &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;’s combat away from hiding behind / healing tanks and to give the rest of the team more room to spread out, flank, and focus on objectives (instead of just trying to keep the tanks alive). One less tank also means that players have to be smarter about the maps, utilizing cover and creative flanking angles instead of just rolling down the main path in a shield fortress. It’s a big change to the game, one that exemplifies the approach that Blizzard is taking here in terms of trying to keep things fresh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AKpksl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Race toward the Monte Carlo finish line in Overwatch 2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Points of interest: &lt;br&gt; ️  Auto Pilot Cars&lt;br&gt;✨  Sparkles&lt;br&gt; ️  Flying Yachts &lt;a href="https://t.co/tlE6d8UJ8R"&gt;pic.twitter.com/tlE6d8UJ8R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1395484742842212353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xPYVBU"&gt;The stream also showed off other new aspects in the upcoming sequel, including a better look at the cleaner UI for &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; (which, among other changes, makes it easier for support characters to track teammates they’re healing), new character designs, and other tweaks that are planned for character abilities (like Mei, who won’t be able to fully freeze opponents anymore).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3IH4F"&gt;The development team also showcased several new maps. There was a better look at the upcoming Toronto map, which had been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20943766/blizzard-overwatch-2-sequel-announcement-blizzcon-2019"&gt;announced alongside &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2 &lt;/em&gt;back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but also a trio of new maps: New York, featuring a futuristic Grand Central station; Rio, which has a nightclub for the EDM hero Lúcio; and Monte Carlo, set on a winding racetrack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wjmf86"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Weather the Toronto winter in Overwatch 2&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Points of interest: &lt;br&gt;  Hotel Montebianco&lt;br&gt;☕ Tim Fordsons&lt;br&gt;  Maple Leaf Trees &lt;a href="https://t.co/FwJNo5y5j8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FwJNo5y5j8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1395464121701838849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vXlven"&gt;There’s still no firm release date for &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;, but Blizzard has already confirmed that it won’t be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267131/diablo-4-overwatch-2-release-date-2022-activision-blizzard-earnings"&gt;launching until at least 2022&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446374/overwatch-2-preview-five-player-multiplayer-new-maps-changes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446374/overwatch-2-preview-five-player-multiplayer-new-maps-changes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T17:28:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T17:28:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>US Treasury wants cryptocurrency transfers over $10,000 to be reported to the IRS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XOJVgfwTEbCuWmxMUhn3ty4E5WQ=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319668/acastro_170726_1777_0007_v3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z3blrE"&gt;The US Treasury Department said Thursday it will require any cryptocurrency transfer worth $10,000 or more to be reported to the IRS. “Cryptocurrency already poses a significant detection problem by facilitating illegal activity broadly including tax evasion,” the agency said in a new &lt;a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/The-American-Families-Plan-Tax-Compliance-Agenda.pdf"&gt;report on tax compliance proposals&lt;/a&gt;. “This is why the President’s proposal includes additional resources for the IRS to address the growth of cryptoassets.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RY52YU"&gt;The Treasury report said that even though cryptocurrency transactions are a small fraction of business transactions in the US, requiring large crypto transactions to be reported would help “to minimize the incentives and opportunity to shift income out of the new information reporting regime.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JRWI8T"&gt;The Treasury Department plan outlined several policies aimed at increasing tax enforcement, which, in addition to the new cryptocurrency proposal, includes new reporting requirements and a big increase for the IRS’s budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="egI3Lh"&gt;“At the crux of these proposals is a commitment to revitalizing tax enforcement,” according to the report. “Working to close the tax gap reflects a commitment to ending our two-tiered tax system, one where most American workers pay their full obligations, but high earners who accrue income from opaque sources often do not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o6mvbq"&gt;The Treasury Department’s Office of Tax Analysis estimated that the proposed updates would raise an additional $700 billion in tax revenue over the next 10 years and could bring in as much as $1.6 trillion in the following decade. Many of the changes the Biden administration proposes in the report would require Congressional approval, however. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4i8fP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s9d0ld"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446364/treasury-cryptocurrency-irs-fraud-tax-evasion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446364/treasury-cryptocurrency-irs-fraud-tax-evasion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T17:05:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T17:05:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple employees call for company to support Palestinians in internal letter </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ju6H8FQCl5fE3uiW5xOJRpENqGA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319478/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0yclD6"&gt;Apple employees are circulating an internal letter calling on Tim Cook to put out a statement supporting the Palestinian people. Nearly 1,000 workers have signed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="orkeeG"&gt;The writers, who are part of the Apple Muslim Association, specifically ask the company to recognize that “millions of Palestinian people currently suffer under an illegal occupation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mzm6X"&gt;The move comes on the heels of Israel’s deadly bombing campaign in Gaza, which has killed roughly 227 people, including at least 63 children. On Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-20/israel-unleashes-strikes-after-vowing-to-press-on-in-gaza?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_content=business&amp;amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;cmpid=socialflow-twitter-business&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;the Israeli government approved a unilateral cease fire&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VqD2tg"&gt;Members of the Apple Muslim Association — an official employee group — say they were inspired to write the note after the company failed to put out a statement condemning the violence toward Palestinians. “We are frustrated and disappointed because once more, many of those in positions of power and influence ... either choose to remain silent or release ineffectually neutral ‘both sides’ statements with regards to the Palestinian situation,’” they wrote. Historically, the company has not been quick to voice solidarity with Muslim employees or support Muslim causes, according to one current worker. (Tim Cook was, however, an outspoken critic of Donald Trump’s Muslim ban). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LkmQv0"&gt;The letter was sent Monday. Apple has not yet responded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wnm7IX"&gt;Discussions about the violence internally were dominated by pro-Zionist voices, sources said, with Muslim employees and allies trying unsuccessfully to turn the talks toward the plight of Palestinians and Muslim Apple workers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="walB4z"&gt;The news comes two days after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441236/jewish-google-employees-support-palestine-letter-anti-zionism-israel"&gt;a group of Jewish employees at Google&lt;/a&gt; put out a statement calling for the company to protect anti-Zionist speech. Google workers also asked that the company review its business contracts to ensure they do not enable Israeli violations of Palestinian rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2hkAq"&gt;On May 12th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432909/apple-petition-hiring-antonio-garcia-martinez-chaos-monkeys-facebook"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;published another internal letter&lt;/a&gt; from Apple employees, calling for an investigation into the hiring of Antonio García Martínez — author of the controversial book &lt;em&gt;Chaos Monkeys&lt;/em&gt;. Shortly after publication, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433437/apple-hire-antonio-garcia-martinez-out-petition-investigation"&gt;Martínez was fired&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vuu0ic"&gt;Here is the text of the full letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="uh6DGA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10510681"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oqiKra"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446059/apple-employees-palestinians-support-internal-letter-tim-cook"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446059/apple-employees-palestinians-support-internal-letter-tim-cook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
