<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google promises it won’t just keep tracking you after replacing cookies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ItGlXXNdecUVi8wqsYXkhkGi9Iw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68902665/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2Wf171"&gt;Google is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21064698/google-third-party-cookies-chrome-two-years-privacy-safari-firefox"&gt;slowly phasing out third-party tracking cookies&lt;/a&gt;, and today, it’s making it clear that it won’t just replace them with something equally invasive despite the impact the change will have on Google’s lucrative advertising business. In a blog post, Google explicitly states that it “will not build alternate identifiers to track individuals as they browse across the web” after the third-party cookies are gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PAO5jm"&gt;“Instead, our web products will be powered by privacy-preserving APIs which prevent individual tracking while still delivering results for advertisers and publishers,” writes Google. “Advances in aggregation, anonymization, on-device processing and other privacy-preserving technologies offer a clear path to replacing individual identifiers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iq6feQ"&gt;Third-party cookies have been blocked for a while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192830/apple-safari-intelligent-tracking-privacy-full-third-party-cookie-blocking"&gt;in Safari&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20848629/firefox-69-block-third-party-tracker-default-enhanced-tracking-protection-android-windows-mac-os"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; (though the browsers differed in how far they go), and Google plans on doing the same in Chrome. The cookies allow advertisers to track you as you move between different websites, which gives advertisers a better idea of what your interests are. These hyper-targeted ads are very valuable, resulting in the creation of an ad industry whereby individual user data is proliferated across “thousands of companies,” according to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DFPaQR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google says this practice has led to users not trusting the internet&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5s5Xl4"&gt;Google says this practice has led to users not trusting the internet or advertisers, which puts the future of the web at risk. For all of the privacy concerns, advertising is still the primary way many companies on the internet make their money (&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;and Google included). That’s why Google says it wants to move away from third-party cookies and toward “a more privacy-first web.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPG6sk"&gt;For all the talk of privacy, Google makes it clear it’s not trying to get rid of targeted advertising in general; it just wants to replace the more invasive methods of old with a new one of its own design, which it calls &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/2021-01-privacy-sandbox/"&gt;Privacy Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;. Part of Privacy Sandbox’s job is to hide the individual inside a large crowd of “cohorts” with similar interests it will then target ads toward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApoXD9"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/03/02/chrome-beta-89/"&gt;teardown of the Chrome 89 beta APK&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Android Police &lt;/em&gt;gives us a first look at Privacy Sandbox controls and the use of “Web Crowd” cohorts for more relevant advertising:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zRwvDcpHs7-p2raL6ki-iGHt9DI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341962/Screen_Shot_2021_03_03_at_10.18.50.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/03/02/chrome-beta-89/" target="_blank"&gt;Android Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrome 89 beta Privacy Sandbox controls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4IGQCK"&gt;Google’s embrace of a privacy-first web comes amid increasing regulatory pressure from across the globe. The company acknowledges that, while noting some of its competitors will still pursue solutions built around individual identities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1MBjs"&gt;“We realize this means other providers may offer a level of user identity for ad tracking across the web that we will not — like PII graphs based on people’s email addresses,” writes Google. “We don’t believe these solutions will meet rising consumer expectations for privacy, nor will they stand up to rapidly evolving regulatory restrictions, and therefore aren’t a sustainable long term investment.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310332/google-privacy-replacing-third-party-cookies-privacy-sandbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310332/google-privacy-replacing-third-party-cookies-privacy-sandbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Artificial intelligence research continues to grow as China overtakes US in AI journal citations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UAgztavodrYu6yfBfLw7TJuhAG8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68902671/acastro_180329_1777__brains_science_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Zx5xE"&gt;The artificial intelligence boom isn’t slowing yet, with new figures showing a 34.5 percent increase in the publication of AI research from 2019 to 2020. That’s a higher percentage growth than 2018 to 2019 when the volume of publications increased by 19.6 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zN2Qiv"&gt;China continues to be a growing force in AI R&amp;amp;D, overtaking the US for overall journal citations in artificial intelligence research last year. The country already publishes more AI papers than any other country, but the United States still has more cited papers at AI conferences — one indicator of the novelty and significance of the underlying research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LWh4X"&gt;These figures come from the fourth annual AI Index, a collection of statistics, benchmarks, and milestones meant to gauge global progress in artificial intelligence. The report is collated with the help of Stanford University, and you can read all 222 pages &lt;a href="https://hai.stanford.edu/research/ai-index-2021"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JilbIp"&gt;In many ways, the report confirms trends identified in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/12/18136929/artificial-intelligence-ai-index-report-2018-machine-learning-global-progress-research"&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/12/21010671/ai-index-report-2019-machine-learning-artificial-intelligence-data-progress"&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;: the sheer volume of AI research is growing across a number of metrics, China continues to be increasingly influential, and investors are pumping yet more money into AI firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZJaShm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More money is being invested in fewer AI companies&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lSvk51"&gt;However, details reveal subtleties about the AI scene. For example, while private investment in AI increased 9.3 percent in 2020 (a higher increase than 2018 to 2019 of 5.7 percent), the number of newly funded companies receiving funds decreased for the third year in a row. There are several ways to interpret this, but it suggests that investors expect that the winner-takes-all dynamic that has defined the tech industry — in which digital economies of scale tend to reward a few dominant players — will be replicated in the AI world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SJlt24"&gt;The report’s section on technical advances also confirms the major trends in AI capabilities, the biggest of which is the industrialization of computer vision. This field has seen incredible progress during the AI boom, with services like object and facial recognition now commonplace. Similarly, generative technologies, which can create video, images, and audio, continue to increase in quality and availability. As the report notes, this trend “promises to generate a tremendous range of downstream applications of AI for both socially useful and less useful purposes.” Useful applications include cheaper computer-generated media, while malicious outcomes include misinformation and AI revenge porn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bx0gWF"&gt;One area of AI research that seems like it’s just beginning to come into its own is biotech. The drug discovery and design sector received the most private investment of any sector in 2020 ($13.8 billion, 4.5 times more than in 2019), and experts canvassed for AI Index’s report cited &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754310/deepmind-alphafold-ai-protein-folding-casp-competition"&gt;DeepMind’s AlphaFold program&lt;/a&gt;, which uses machine learning to fold proteins, as one of the most significant breakthroughs in AI in 2020. (The other frequently cited breakthrough last year was OpenAI’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21346343/gpt-3-explainer-openai-examples-errors-agi-potential"&gt;text-generation program GPT-3&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gv8YfJ"&gt;One area where the Index AI report struggles to gauge progress, though, is in ethics. This is a wide-ranging area, spanning everything from the politics of facial recognition to algorithmic bias, and discussion of these topics is increasingly prominent. In 2020, stories like Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/23/google-timnit-gebru-ai-ethics/"&gt;firing of researcher Timnit Gebru&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/8/21284683/ibm-no-longer-general-purpose-facial-recognition-analysis-software#:~:text=IBM%20will%20no%20longer%20offer%20general%20purpose%20facial%20recognition%20or,addressed%20the%20letter%20to%20Sens."&gt;IBM’s exit from the facial recognition business&lt;/a&gt; drove discussions of how AI technology should be applied. But while companies are happy paying lip service to ethical principles, the report notes that most of these “commitments” are non-binding and lack institutional frameworks. As has been noted in the past: AI ethics for many companies is simply a way to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/3/18293410/ai-artificial-intelligence-ethics-boards-charters-problem-big-tech"&gt;slow roll criticism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310840/ai-research-global-growth-china-us-paper-citations-index-report-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310840/ai-research-global-growth-china-us-paper-citations-index-report-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lifx’s bacteria-killing smart bulb works, but here’s the small print</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/45MwfRJq7zpzf0bF1gXFwuLZX7A=/1x0:916x610/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68902440/lifx_clean_bottom_fixed_1600x1600.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LIFX Clean is a smart bulb that can kill bacteria.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: LIFX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;These things take time&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="47DTMF"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.lifx.com/products/lifx-clean-antibacterial-smart-light"&gt;Lifx Clean&lt;/a&gt; is a new smart lightbulb with an intriguing twist. Not only is it a fully functional color-changing lightbulb, the company also claims it is capable of disinfecting surfaces and the air around it. First announced last August, the $69.99 Lifx Clean is now shipping to preorder customers in the US, with wide availability planned this spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ib7TVn"&gt;Lifx has an array of scientific studies as well as its own lab tests to support its claim that the Clean is the “world’s first antibacterial, germicidal smart light.” But can the lightbulb work as well in the average home as it did in the lab?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="thxLCK"&gt;It’s no coincidence that Lifx announced the bulb in a year in which we all had to pay more attention than ever before to keeping ourselves and our homes clean. Lifx’s CEO David McLauchlan says the company started having early discussions about developing a product like the Lifx Clean last March, the same month COVID-19 was officially declared a pandemic by the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="HqFrrR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We saw the alcohol companies were making hand sanitizer and clothing companies were making facial masks”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UArAnY"&gt;“We saw the alcohol companies were making hand sanitizer and clothing companies were making facial masks, and I said to the team that we can’t go do these things, but we do make lights,” McLauchlan said in a call. “There’s this technology out there, why don’t we look into it and figure out if we can do this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtFDhL"&gt;The “technology” McLauchlan is referring to here is a very specific kind of blue light with a wavelength of around 405nm. This high-energy visible (HEV) light has been shown across a number of studies to “inactivate” (read: kill) a range of bacteria including &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3330698/"&gt;salmonella&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5068139/"&gt;E. coli&lt;/a&gt;, and methicillin-resistant &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2663198/#:~:text=Detailed%20investigation%20of%20the%20bactericidal,to%20a%209%2Dlog10"&gt;staphylococcus aureus&lt;/a&gt; (aka MRSA) in lab-based studies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iKljZD"&gt;Other experiments have used it in real-world situations like hospitals. &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0195670110003312"&gt;Across&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0305417911000908?via%3Dihub"&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1757177413483646"&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; conducted between 2010 and 2013, researchers found that the lights reduced the number of bacteria on frequently touched surfaces in a hospital’s burns unit. The reduction varied a lot — between 27 and 90 percent — even within these individual studies, depending on factors like how many days the light was used for, and how much activity there was in the room where it was used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FjGci9hffY52Z9tYwRVZW0Jnmlg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339362/Computer_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lifx&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;HEV lights’ lower energy means they’re safe for humans, but also that they take longer to kill bacteria.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5KiizC"&gt;The Lifx Clean incorporates this technology into a household lightbulb via an array of eight 405nm LED lights, which sit alongside the standard red, green, and blue diodes that you find in Lifx’s other bulbs. The array then has a typical diffuser placed over it, meaning that it looks almost identical to a standard Lifx bulb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xTxXs"&gt;It’s benign in appearance — vastly different from another light-cleaning tech that’s become popular during the pandemic era: UV light. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/20/21265221/nyc-mta-ultraviolet-light-uvc-coronavirus-disinfect-puro-pictures"&gt;Pilot programs have used UV light to clean subways, buses&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/jetblue-deploys-honeywells-ultraviolet-cleaning-system-for-aircraft-interiors-301101993.html"&gt;aircraft cabins&lt;/a&gt;, and Transport for London has rolled it out to &lt;a href="https://tfl.gov.uk/info-for/media/press-releases/2020/october/installation-of-uv-light-devices-on-tube-escalators-is-latest-step-in-tfl-s-extensive-anti-viral-cleaning-regime"&gt;disinfect escalator handrails&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozZXWl"&gt;UV is fast acting, but it’s also incredibly dangerous when used incorrectly. That’s according to Jim Malley, a professor of civil and environmental engineering at the University of New Hampshire who’s been studying the use of UV and other light as a disinfectant for over 30 years. It can cause erythema, the reddening of the skin that’s most commonly associated with sunburn, and repeated exposure has even been tied to skin cancer, he says. The light is particularly damaging to your eye’s cornea, and exposure to it can give you “the worst headache you’d ever imagined.” Although your cornea can generally recover from being exposed to UV, Malley tells me, repeated damage “does seem to tie to early blindness.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ypUzk4"&gt;In comparison, HEV light doesn’t have those same problems. “Blue light, 405 nm, doesn’t have that kind of energy,” Malley explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9gskb"&gt;HEV light comes with its own disadvantages. Most notably, the light’s effect on bacteria just hasn’t been studied as much as UV. Much of the research that has been done has focused primarily on its ability to kill bacteria, and there’s less evidence to suggest it’s effective against viruses. That’s a very important caveat since COVID-19 is caused by the coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 — a virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="POBcRY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I really want to be emphatic that we’re not trying to sell it as a ‘coronavirus killer’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2a3Dui"&gt;Lifx isn’t shy about pointing this out. In its announcement for the Lifx Clean last August, the company explicitly said that “no claim is currently being made that the product is effective in an antiviral capacity of any kind, including on SARS-CoV-2.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UMDQei"&gt;“I really want to be emphatic that we’re not trying to sell it as a ‘coronavirus killer,’” McLauchlan cautions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="305kP9"&gt;But Lifx still thinks that a disinfecting lightbulb, even if it’s antibacterial rather than antiviral, can help in an era of a global viral pandemic. Bacterial infections, after all, can create serious complications for anyone sick with a virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YS9eK6"&gt;HEV lights aren’t particularly fast when they’re being used to kill bacteria. &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2663198/#__p16:~:text=.%20For%20the%20Staphylococcus%2C%20Streptococcus%2C%20and,with%20an%20irradiance%20of%2010%20mW%2Fcm2."&gt;A study from 2009&lt;/a&gt; found that it took as much as 60 and 90 minutes for 405 nm light to inactivate almost all the bacteria on test, despite the fact that the light was positioned a grand total of 2cm away from it. Hospital studies have focussed on using the light &lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1757177413483646"&gt;continuously during daylight hours&lt;/a&gt; from anywhere between eight to 14 hours or more to achieve their desired bacteria reductions. In comparison, UV light can kill many bacteria and viruses in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YZGx2X"&gt;These drawbacks mean that HEV lights haven’t really caught on as a disinfection technology, despite the research backing it up, Malley tells me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="18Zt5U"&gt;“It’s not competitive, it’s not practical. You just can’t have hours and hours of contact time” Malley says. In a world where a UV light can sanitize a phone in 60 seconds, 405nm light “can’t compete.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yFkWc"&gt;Lifx provided &lt;a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0219/0638/files/QL20343-2A_An_Evaluation_of_the_Antimicrobial_Efficacy_of_HEV_Light_Report_FINAL.pdf?v=1614653165"&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;of its tests of the light against E. coli and MRSA, which showed how its light performed over periods ranging from two to 12 hours, at a variety of distances. While the Lifx Clean can kill over 80 percent of E. coli bacteria on a glass surface in two hours under the right conditions, you’d have to run Lifx’s Clean bulb for up to eight hours to achieve a similar kill rate for MRSA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="13JdKM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s not competitive, it’s not practical. You just can’t have hours and hours of contact time”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dkvTFv"&gt;The length of time involved in killing bacteria is a downside, but McLauchlan argues that the smart bulb’s scheduling features mean you can have it automatically come on when you’re not around. “You can literally have your lights come on at midnight when everyone’s in bed and stay on in the disinfectant mode till 6AM and provide a disinfectant effect in that room or that surface,” McLauchlan says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zsOkBw"&gt;The light’s efficacy also declines the farther away it is from a given surface. The results above were achieved by having the bulb just 40 cm away from the bacteria, which puts it at roughly desk lamp height. Move the bulb farther away, and it generally takes longer to kill the same amount of bacteria. Even after eight hours, Lifx’s tests show the bulb only killed around half the MRSA bacteria on a surface four feet away, or just over 65 percent of the E. coli. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3Zaz3"&gt;These results mean you’re unlikely to see much of an impact if you expect to use the Lifx Clean as an overhead light. Instead, the company sees people using the bulb in fixtures above desks and other surfaces. To its credit, Lifx is being upfront about these limitations, and these test results are &lt;a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0219/0638/files/QL20343-2A_An_Evaluation_of_the_Antimicrobial_Efficacy_of_HEV_Light_Report_FINAL.pdf?v=1614653165"&gt;available publicly on its website&lt;/a&gt; for everyone to view. If you’re planning on picking up one of the bulbs, it’s worth giving it a read to understand where, and for how long, you’ll need to leave the bulb running to get an effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hxQ5x0"&gt;But there are other drawbacks with using HEV light that no amount of smart scheduling or clever placement are likely to be able to overcome. Lifx, for example, &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/buddy/lifxclean"&gt;initially said&lt;/a&gt; the Lifx Clean would be able to disinfect the air surrounding the bulb. However, the slow disinfection time makes that a pretty difficult feat to pull off, Malley explains, because of how air particles tend to move around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3BXJx"&gt;“They’re not going to be able to keep blue light on that particle of air long enough” Malley says. If bacteria gets really close to the blue light then you could see a reduction, he speculates, “but in general, I don’t think it can compete because you just can’t keep the air near that kill zone long enough.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CJv-3ynIzkLgvBeQfIpKTmdk3Ao=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339370/ezgif.com_gif_maker.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lifx&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outwardly, the Lifx Clean looks like the company’s other smart bulbs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A4PFu7"&gt;There are all sorts of variations in people’s homes that could affect how reliably the bulb kills bacteria. Disinfecting light is, by its very nature, a line-of-sight technology, so any areas of shade won’t be disinfected, and any lampshade in the way will also curtail its effectiveness. One of the &lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1757177413483646"&gt;hospital studies from 2013&lt;/a&gt; found that the light killed an average of 15 percent less bacteria on the side of a room that was indirectly lit compared to the areas directly under the ceiling lights. It also can’t penetrate deep into porous surfaces, McLauchlan admits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ixgPkS"&gt;The amount of variation in the average home could mean the results Lifx quotes from its lab tests won’t exactly match the real world. For reference, all the test results quoted above had the bacteria sitting on a glass slide. That might work for nonporous surfaces like kitchen or bathroom countertops, but Malley cautions that trying to generalize too much from lab results like this to the average home could end up looking “pretty unrealistic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="U1tA9M"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I wouldn’t see [HEV light] as a substitute for cleaning, but as an adjunct”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="adnfrE"&gt;Variations like this between lab results and how people actually use products in the home are nothing new, says John Coia, a clinical microbiologist and professor of clinical microbiology at the University of Southern Denmark. Coia co-authored several of the real-world studies that found HEV light could reduce the amount of bacteria when used in hospital settings. He points out that even when it comes to traditional chemical disinfectant, many people might already not be using the correct concentrations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djJWFa"&gt;“You can make the argument about whether people are using the correct concentration [of HEV light], but do people use disinfectants at the right concentration? The answer is they probably don’t,” Coia says. “In many cases, they probably use concentrations which are actually sub-lethal.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JncSVX"&gt;Everyone we spoke to, as well as Lifx, agreed that the Lifx Clean isn’t going to replace any normal cleaning. But used correctly, it could be an extra tool in your cleaning arsenal. “I wouldn’t see [HEV light] as a substitute for cleaning, but as an adjunct,” Coia says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="g8ypqC"&gt;Multiple studies have shown that under the right circumstances, HEV lights like the Lifx Clean certainly can kill bacteria. But even Lifx’s own laboratory tests have shown the limitations of the technology. It needs enough time, it needs to be the right distance away, and it needs a direct line of sight to bacteria in order to kill it. Lifx’s “germicidal smart light” isn’t snake oil, but nor is it a silver bullet that’ll save you from your weekly cleaning chores.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22308944/lifx-clean-germacidal-smart-light-bulb-bacteria-killing-sanitation-high-energy-visible-405nm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22308944/lifx-clean-germacidal-smart-light-bulb-bacteria-killing-sanitation-high-energy-visible-405nm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T07:19:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T07:19:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Parler has dropped its hosting lawsuit against Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XGsuMmjaA5gee0j5kOLPPL1QKVI=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68902360/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4nzU4i"&gt;Parler has withdrawn its antitrust lawsuit against Amazon, ending its two-month effort to legally compel the company to reinstate its hosting account. Parler made the decision in &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341999/document_21_.pdf"&gt;a motion filed late Tuesday night&lt;/a&gt; in federal court for the Western District of Washington. The company gave no explanation for the move, but reserved the right to refile on similar grounds in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rFk2VS"&gt;Notably, the decision to withdraw came on the same day Parler was due to file an amended complaint in the case. Parler had failed to meet an earlier February 16 filing deadline and received a two-week extension from the court — but with the case withdrawn, that deadline is now moot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDGr86"&gt;Amazon first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223335/parler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol"&gt;suspended service to Parler on January 9th&lt;/a&gt;, in the wake of an unprecedented mob attack on the capitol building. Parler had sought to use antitrust law to force Amazon to restore service, but faced an uphill battle in court. In a response filing, Amazon revealed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech"&gt;more than 100 violent threats&lt;/a&gt; the company had flagged to Parler in the weeks leading up to its takedown, including one that told Jack Dorsey, “you will die a bloody death.” Parler had refused to moderate the content, citing its free speech policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iVqkx3"&gt;On January 21, the court &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22231457/parler-amazon-web-services-lawsuit-judge-preliminary-injunction-denied"&gt;rejected a preliminary motion&lt;/a&gt; ordering Amazon to reinstate Parler’s hosting account, calling the presented evidence “dwindlingly slight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PB521Z"&gt;With Parler &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/15/22284036/parler-social-network-relaunch-new-hosting"&gt;back online&lt;/a&gt;, many of the underlying issues in the case are less urgent. Parler restored web service on February 15th, using a range of smaller hosting and registrar services as an alternative to Amazon. Content posted before the ban was lost, however, and Parler’s app remains unavailable on the iOS or Google Play app stores. Parler cited the networks success in restoring service as a reason to extend the filing deadline, predicting that it would “have a material impact on how Parler pleads the amended complaint.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tjltk3"&gt;Parler did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310873/parler-amazon-aws-lawsuit-antitrust-hosting-free-speech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310873/parler-amazon-aws-lawsuit-antitrust-hosting-free-speech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T20:18:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T20:18:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can now beam Steam games from your PC to practically anyone, anywhere, for free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2yq2lriSzEDXoir6SRhXXJp4phg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68901071/acastro_180509_1777_steam_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9opB4c"&gt;Valve is significantly expanding your ability to share games at home and with your friends for free using Steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vrXcem"&gt;One change is the introduction of &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/353380/discussions/10/3106892760562833187/"&gt;a Linux version of its Steam Link app&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you stream games from a computer to a device with the Steam Link app installed on the same local network. This new Linux version means that you can now stream games from a computer to a Linux-based set top box hooked up to a TV, for example. The app is also available on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/steamlink/about/"&gt;Android, iOS, and Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDndl0"&gt;Valve has also rolled out a big update to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20924545/steam-remote-play-together-beta-valve-online-co-op-local-multiplayer"&gt;Remote Play Together feature&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you stream games on your computer over the internet so you can play them with friends. Just last week, Valve introduced a way to let you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300768/steam-remote-play-together-no-account-required-beta"&gt;play games with friends who don’t have a Steam account&lt;/a&gt;, but the feature only let you play with one friend without a Steam account at a time. Now, though, you can play with as many friends without Steam accounts as you want, depending on how many other players a game supports and your network’s bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LjOO2S"&gt;If you want to try the feature, which is in beta, &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/homestream/discussions/0/3111395750231979202/"&gt;follow the instructions here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22310321/valve-steam-linux-steam-link-remote-play-together-account"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22310321/valve-steam-linux-steam-link-remote-play-together-account</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T17:18:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T17:18:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Japanese billionaire is looking for eight people to join him for a Moon voyage on SpaceX rocket</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="SpaceX CEO Elon Musk Announces Details Of Commercial Space Program" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6obmQENUjQMA-tN-6kuQxWa2C4k=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68900268/1035243908.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yusaku Maezawa announcing his plan to fly on SpaceX’s Starship rocket in September 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qfqdy6"&gt;Japanese billionaire Yusaku Maezawa invited the public on Tuesday to apply for a spot on SpaceX’s Starship in his private mission around the Moon, reaching out to a “wider, more diverse audience” two years after announcing he’d only ride with a select group of artists. The trip is currently slated for 2023, but that date might not hold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JsalJ1"&gt;“I want people from all kinds of backgrounds to join,” Maezawa said in a video posted Tuesday afternoon, when the contest’s &lt;a href="https://dearmoon.earth/pre-reg.html"&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; went live. “It will be 10 to 12 people in all, but I will be inviting 8 people to come along on the ride.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XSyZ5b"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h_L3wLmrMuA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rvZIp7"&gt;Maezawa, the founder of Japan’s largest online fashion retailer, is worth about $2 billion. He &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/17/17869990/elon-musk-spacex-lunar-mission-ticket-moon-passenger-bfr-falcon-yusaku-maezawa"&gt;was revealed as Starship’s first signed passenger back in 2018&lt;/a&gt; during an event with CEO Elon Musk at SpaceX’s California headquarters. At the event, Maezawa, an avid art collector, announced his Dear Moon Project, which aimed to bring “six to eight artists from around the world” to join him in a roughly six-day lunar flyby mission sometime in 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfMIF4"&gt;“These artists will be asked to create something after they return to Earth, and these masterpieces will inspire the dreamer within all of us,” Maezawa said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TcfGgf"&gt;In a YouTube video posted on Tuesday, Maezawa said that plan “has since evolved,” adding that “maybe every single person is doing something creative could be called an artist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WrmBvr"&gt;Now, anyone who meets two criteria could get picked for the ride: those who “can push its envelope to help other people and greater society in some way” and are “willing to support other crew members who share similar aspirations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZVBNpS"&gt;Project updates have been scant over the past two years. In January 2020, Maezawa launched a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/12/21062584/spacex-yusaku-maezawa-japan-billionaire-starship-girlfriend-contest-moon"&gt;bizarre campaign&lt;/a&gt; to search for a “female partner” who would accompany him on his trip around the Moon. A website for the contest received 27,722 applications, and Japanese streaming service AbemaTV was set to document the mission in a reality TV show called &lt;em&gt;Full Moon Lovers&lt;/em&gt;. Weeks later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21114712/yusaku-maezawa-space-girlfriend-not-happening"&gt;the show was canceled&lt;/a&gt;, and Maezawa called off his search due to “personal reasons,” he &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yousuck2020/status/1222716360888729600?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, apologizing to the AbemaTV crew and all of the applicants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="muBLOP"&gt;Starship is SpaceX’s next-generation, fully reusable Mars rocket system designed to ferry humans and up to 100 tons of cargo on future missions into deep space. Only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262937/spacex-sn9-starship-test-flight-successful-explode-landing"&gt;early iterations&lt;/a&gt; of the rocket have flown so far, with one of two recent high-altitude tests flying as high as 7.8 miles over SpaceX’s Starship facilities in Boca Chica, Texas. Both of those tests ended in fiery explosions during their landing attempts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9wP94H"&gt;Maezawa’s announcement on Tuesday lacked any details on how the selected astronauts would train for the mission, but he made clear the undisclosed ticket price is on him: “I will pay for the entire journey. I have bought all the seats, so it will be a private ride.” He said it will take three days to get to the Moon, where Starship will loop behind it and begin its three-day journey back to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUUkjj"&gt;Under a rigorous and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22256657/spacex-launch-violation-explosive-starship-faa-investigation-elon-musk"&gt;sometimes bumpy&lt;/a&gt; development timeline, Musk and SpaceX president Gwynne Shotwell have said Starship’s first orbital flight could come at the end of 2021. Last year, Musk said Starship needs to “do hundreds of missions with satellites before we put people on board,” a feat that calls the 2023 moonshot date into question. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JzrR2E"&gt;SpaceX’s other crew vehicle, Crew Dragon, is already in its operational phase and is racking up future flights with private astronauts and tourists. The acorn-shaped capsule flew its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/15/21565237/spacex-crew-1-dragon-launch-success-falcon-9-nasa"&gt;first two crews of astronauts&lt;/a&gt; to the International Space Station last year under NASA’s Commercial Crew Program. The private astronaut missions lined up include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250327/space-tourists-axiom-private-crew-iss-price"&gt;a flight to the space station&lt;/a&gt; planned for early next year carrying real estate investors and philanthropists, and an “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22261038/spacex-announces-first-all-civilian-mission-to-space"&gt;all-civilian&lt;/a&gt;” charity-focused mission announced last month that’s slated for launch by year’s end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UpoTWz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309546/japanese-billionaire-maezawa-dear-moon-spacex"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309546/japanese-billionaire-maezawa-dear-moon-spacex</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T16:49:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T16:49:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>A jury says Intel owes $2.18 billion for infringing a zombie chip company’s patents</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7xYHUV3aRy8s0gwIhQt-_aoNbD8=/137x0:1063x617/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68900038/Eg7I_l_XYAY3OBJ.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9v4IFd"&gt;Intel may owe quite a bit of cash to a semiconductor company that hasn’t existed for 20 years. A Texas jury has asked Intel to pay $2.18 billion for infringing two patents owned by VLSI Technology, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-02/intel-told-to-pay-2-18-billion-after-losing-texas-patent-trial"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldtHov"&gt;VLSI seemingly rose from the dead in 2019 specifically to sue. The last time it was an independent company was in 1999, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1999/05/04/business/company-news-philips-in-1-billion-deal-for-vlsi-technology.html"&gt;when Philips purchased the semiconductor design firm for $1 billion&lt;/a&gt;. Its assets later traveled to Philips spinoff NXP (which you may know from its tap-to-pay NFC chips, among other things). NXP will reportedly get some of Intel’s money, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4pA2WX"&gt;One of VLSI’s claims to fame was being part of the original project with Apple and Acorn to produce the first ARM processors — &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1990-11-28-fi-4993-story.html"&gt;and the ARM company&lt;/a&gt; — responsible for the underpinnings of the chips that now appear in every smartphone, most tablets, and a growing number of laptops and servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mzxA3v"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;how it started:               how it’s going: &lt;a href="https://t.co/R5bPcH1aOQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/R5bPcH1aOQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ken Shirriff (@kenshirriff) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kenshirriff/status/1327021630636212224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uXFirB"&gt;Technically, the patents are newer than&lt;em&gt; all &lt;/em&gt;of that VLSI history. They were originally issued to Freescale Semiconductor, and Sigmatel in 2009, 2010, and 2012, respectively, and the earliest of them was filed in 2005. But &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports they were all assigned to the new VLSI in 2019, an LLC that’s attached to a Fortress Investment Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0rTuzH"&gt;Calling out VLSI as a zombie brand was part of Intel’s argument, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="9CIL9K"&gt;VLSI “took two patents off the shelf that hadn’t been used for 10 years and said, ‘We’d like $2 billion,”’ Lee told the jury. The “outrageous” demand by VLSI “would tax the true innovators.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="t0k4Si"&gt;But that didn’t keep jurors from awarding roughly a tenth of Intel’s yearly profits — $2.18 billion — for infringing two of the three patents. (They’re about “managing clockspeed in an electronic device,” a “minimum memory operating voltage technique,” and “voltage-based memory size scaling,” in case you’re curious.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3klKc"&gt;Intel tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that it’s not done fighting yet: “Intel strongly disagrees with today’s jury verdict. We intend to appeal and are confident that we will prevail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCI92S"&gt;Fortress and VLSI Technology have other lawsuits pending against Intel, too.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309864/intel-vlsi-lawsuit-awarded-2-billion-damages-patent-infringement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309864/intel-vlsi-lawsuit-awarded-2-billion-damages-patent-infringement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T15:52:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T15:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hulu reenables picture-in-picture mode for iOS 14</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uNtJSzqC9AgW8pyvNnmoR0Mb2Hw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68899685/acastro_200320_1777_huluStock_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xR9ZDv"&gt;Hulu has fully reenabled picture-in-picture support (PiP) on iOS, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/03/02/hulu-ios-14-picture-in-picture/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=webfeeds"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, which means half-watching network TV is once again possible for Hulu subscribers on iPhone and iPad devices. Hulu joins a collection of major streaming services that support the feature on iOS, leaving YouTube as the major exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ja70VW"&gt;PiP for iPhones was enabled for Hulu around iOS 14’s original release, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hulu_support/status/1364725362610045012?s=20"&gt;but it was later disabled&lt;/a&gt; to “work on a few updates to provide the best experience for our viewers,” Hulu said. Now that the feature is back, users can enable PiP mode by starting a show or movie and touching the PiP button to pop the video into a resizable, floating player.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TPLyeL_eZoStuGcFUipTJnmfLS8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22340593/B10DEEF4_5290_42FD_ACC5_EF5B41A0FC22_1_201_a.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hulu&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The picture-in-picture button inside Hulu’s app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tExGZC"&gt;Hulu joins services like Disney Plus, Apple TV Plus, Netflix, Amazon Prime, and HBO Max in supporting PiP. All of those services now either feature a dedicated PiP button like Hulu or default to picture-in-picture if you swipe to the home screen while a video is playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lYDk5g"&gt;YouTube remains the odd one out. Picture-in-picture is not allowed in Google’s official YouTube app for iOS. Paying for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/premium"&gt;YouTube Premium&lt;/a&gt; enables background play, but that only extends to audio on iOS. Google has also periodically &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21445912/youtube-videos-website-picture-in-picture-ios-14-google-apple-premium"&gt;disabled&lt;/a&gt; and reenabled PiP support for the web version of YouTube on iOS. As of October 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498327/youtube-picture-in-picture-web-safari-ios-14-chrome-background-playback"&gt;PiP was possible again&lt;/a&gt;, though it doesn’t appear to work as of today. Right now, only iPhones running the iOS 14.5 beta can do PiP on the web version of YouTube, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/02/10/youtube-site-picture-in-picture-ios-14-5-beta/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llzwKo"&gt;If you’re curious how to get PiP set up on your own device, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451195/apple-iphone-ipad-pip-picture-in-picture-how-to-use-youtube"&gt;check out &lt;em&gt;The Verge’s &lt;/em&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309754/hulu-picture-in-picture-mode-ios-14-returns"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309754/hulu-picture-in-picture-mode-ios-14-returns</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T14:57:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T14:57:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA’s latest Mars rover has the same processor as an iMac from 1998</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WdyzQxGIpNdTBf-vhuyJR0P52e0=/0x0:800x533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68899353/25_feb_peserverance4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9hdibO"&gt;NASA’s brand-new Perseverance rover is the most advanced machine that’s ever landed on Mars. But when it comes to rovers, “state of the art” is a subjective term. Perseverance is running on none other than a PowerPC 750, a single-core, 233MHz processor with just 6 million transistors that’s most famous for powering the original “Bondi blue” iMac from 1998. It’s the same type of processor that NASA already uses in its Curiosity rover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RDaHYt"&gt;That may seem like a waste to some. After all, even with the difficulty of buying computer parts these days, surely NASA&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;could have found the budget for something like Intel’s $500 &lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/processors/core/i9-processors/i9-10900k.html"&gt;Core i9-10900K&lt;/a&gt; CPU (with 10 cores and a max clock speed of 5.3GHz) somewhere in the $2.7 billion cost of Perseverance. But &lt;a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2269403-the-perseverance-rover-runs-on-processors-used-in-imacs-in-the-1990s/"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt; explains&lt;/a&gt;, such an advanced chip is actually a detriment to the unique operating conditions of Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xquwjpUh81lOY2W3EQ4rOpBiC3s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/7009607/angled_original_imac_large_2x.0.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bOIjEu"&gt;That’s largely because Mars’ atmosphere offers far less protection from harmful radiation and charged particles than Earth’s atmosphere. A bad burst of radiation can badly wreck the sensitive electronics of a modern processor — and the more complex the chip, the more can go wrong. Plus, at 138 million miles away, it’s not like NASA can just swap out the processor if things go sideways. Because of those conditions, Perseverance actually features two computing modules: one is a backup just in case something goes wrong. (A third copy of the module is also on board for image analysis.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8EBVbb"&gt;To make the system even more durable, the PowerPC 750 chip in Perseverance is a little different than the one in the old iMacs. It’s technically &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RAD750"&gt;a RAD750 chip&lt;/a&gt;, a special variant that’s hardened against radiation and costs upwards of $200,000. The chip is popular for spacecraft, too: in addition to Perseverance and Curiosity, it also powers the Fermi Space Telescope, the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/20/4752114/deep-impact-mission-ends-NASA"&gt;Deep Impact&lt;/a&gt; comet-hunting spacecraft, and the Kepler telescope, among others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gkHqH5"&gt;While the processor may be weak compared to a modern smartphone or gaming PC, &lt;a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/mars2020/spacecraft/rover/brains/"&gt;NASA’s spec sheet&lt;/a&gt; for Perseverance notes that it’s far more powerful than earlier rovers like Spirit or Opportunity: its 200MHz clock speed is 10 times faster than those older rovers, and with 2GB of flash memory, it offers eight times the storage. (Rounding things out, Perseverance also has 256MB of RAM in case you were looking to build your own rover.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4laQzH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Linux has made it to Mars","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291324/linux-perseverance-mars-curiosity-ingenuity"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="HSQ57a"&gt;But while the chip itself has been to Mars before, Perseverance features some new computer technology that’s debuting on the planet for the first time: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291324/linux-perseverance-mars-curiosity-ingenuity"&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, which powers the Ingenuity helicopter that will attempt to fly autonomously on Mars as part of Perseverance’s mission. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/2/22309412/nasa-perseverance-mars-rover-processor-cpu-imac-1998"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/2/22309412/nasa-perseverance-mars-rover-processor-cpu-imac-1998</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T14:31:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T14:31:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter users on Android can now join the platform’s Clubhouse-like Spaces</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-4nJ62ElLFYscatQzAsvGwX3tg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68899179/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8YR8uC"&gt;Twitter has opened its audio chat room, Spaces, to Android users, the company tweeted Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GETEtc"&gt;Twitter introduced a limited version of the Clubhouse competitor on iOS in January. While any users of Twitter’s iOS app can join and listen to Spaces, only a few can host them at the moment. Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1339639767089238019?s=20"&gt;said it was giving Spaces&lt;/a&gt; to “a very small feedback group” to start, with women and people from other marginalized groups given priority. Now, users of Twitter’s Android app can join and listen to Spaces as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LRcpHM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Android folks, our beta is growing! starting today you will be able to join and talk in any Space. SOON you’ll be able to create your own but we’re still working out some things. keep your    out for live Spaces above your home tl&lt;/p&gt;— Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1366767412117458946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z9Nmps"&gt;The announcement tweet doesn’t mention when Android users will be able to host Spaces; it looks like Android users can speak and listen to conversations in Spaces but not host their own chats just yet. A Twitter spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that both Android and iOS users will be able to start and listen to Spaces “soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Efns3O"&gt;Twitter has ramped up its forays into voice-based features over the past several months. In addition to launching Spaces in beta, it introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21294481/twitter-audio-tweets-now-available-iphone-ios"&gt;audio tweets last June on iOS&lt;/a&gt; for a limited number of people, allowing users to record and send audio messages up to 140 seconds long — a nod to the original tweet length of 140 characters. It also introduced support for voice-based direct messages &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287091/twitter-voice-dm-test-india-brazil-japan"&gt;in India last month&lt;/a&gt; for both iOS and Android apps.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cUin8N"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21296032/twitter-audio-tweets-accessibility-volunteers"&gt;Twitter faced some criticism&lt;/a&gt; for failing to include captions on its audio messages for its users who are deaf and hard of hearing, but it said it would be adding automated captions to audio and video in tweets sometime this year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309629/twitter-launches-spaces-android-ios-audio-clubhouse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309629/twitter-launches-spaces-android-ios-audio-clubhouse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
