<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-28T11:43:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T11:43:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:43:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to hide Google Meet in Gmail</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cw7_wEI5QXwOt5I86upZzZuJTqE=/26x0:1190x776/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644979/google_meet_poup.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fE7Io9"&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21240509/google-meet-video-conferencing-free-gmail"&gt;rolled out Google Meet&lt;/a&gt;, a revamped version of its video chatting program Hangouts Meet, in April 2020, and made the app available to anyone with a Google account. You can start or join a Meet videoconference &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246277/google-meet-gmail-zoom-hangouts"&gt;right from your Gmail inbox&lt;/a&gt;, using the buttons that Google has placed on the left-hand side of the page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e6p11d"&gt;But what if you don’t intend to use Meet, or even if you just don’t want it to be there all the time? No worries — you can hide the buttons. (Note: if you’re on a corporate Google Workspace account, you may not be able to change this, depending on your administrator’s settings.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dX319b"&gt;Here’s how to hide Google Meet in Gmail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LntVdi"&gt;Open Gmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3LtBHk"&gt;Click on the cog icon in the top-right corner and on “See all settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9hzZkB"&gt;Click on the “Chat and Meet” tab. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9ATF5z"&gt;Next to the “Meet:” label, select “Hide the Meet section in the main menu.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="edpU66"&gt;Click “Save changes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can hide the Meet buttons from your Gmail." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I9KE41u2s4w6WZEbut1QdH4Fxdo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22745689/Screen_Shot_2021_07_28_at_11.19.13_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can hide the Meet buttons from your Gmail.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tjfSxT"&gt;That’s it! And even if you hide the Meet shortcut in Gmail, you can always access Meet by going to &lt;a href="https://meet.google.com/"&gt;https://meet.google.com/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKkzCZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 28th, 2021, 11:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on June 4th, 2020;  there have been slight tweaks in the text, and one of the screenshots has been updated to reflect interface changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AEqFns"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22598038/how-to-google-meet-gmail-hide"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22598038/how-to-google-meet-gmail-hide</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aliya Chaudhry</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T11:02:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:02:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to schedule an email in Gmail</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JQMLdNDi1A_KbWaYr28CZex_3eY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644775/acastro_180424_1777_gmail_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y0Dr5D"&gt;Google announced that Gmail would natively support email scheduling in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/1/18290065/gmail-scheduling-email-smart-compose-improvements-announced"&gt;April 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and the feature became available in desktop and mobile about a month later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSQ1IX"&gt;Previously, you’d have to use a third-party add-on to do this sort of basic scheduling. Thankfully, Gmail’s feature is perfectly easy to use, and it has a range of applications for scheduling work and personal messages. Maybe you’re trying to talk to someone in a different time zone, nag someone about an event, or you just want to remind your future self about something. If so, schedule an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NsLwGC"&gt;To schedule a message via Gmail in a desktop web browser, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yoJaCx"&gt;Compose a new email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Vg9cOH"&gt;Click the triangle next to the blue “Send” button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6htd1B"&gt;Select one of the suggested times, or click “Pick date &amp;amp; time” to customize when exactly you want the message to go out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uWPybc"&gt;Click “Schedule send” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="oWw3JT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:6246071"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dfucdK"&gt;The process is exactly the same in Gmail’s mobile app. But instead of clicking part of the send button, when composing an email, you have to click the three dots in the top right-hand corner of the screen. That’ll bring up the option to schedule a time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3EgNaz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10673600"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hgEbEO"&gt;Finding scheduled emails and canceling them is also easy. There’s a new “Scheduled” folder in desktop and mobile. Simply click on a message in the folder and click “Cancel send” in the top right of the window to stop a message from being sent. It’ll go right back to your drafts folder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTEa0S"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 28th, 2021, 10:40AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on May 6th, 2019; there are a few minor tweaks in the introduction, and some of the screenshots have been replaced to reflect changes in Gmail’s interface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R8uj1f"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LoWHqy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22597939/gmail-schedule-email-how-to-desktop-mobile-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22597939/gmail-schedule-email-how-to-desktop-mobile-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google shows off Play Store’s upcoming data privacy section</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pqe3zVNeBdGprt5iHtRg0ne5lr8=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644728/Untitled__2_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The section gives a summary of data collected, and security practices.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yjhP1v"&gt;Google has revealed an in-progress design for the Play Store’s upcoming safety section, which will provide information about an app’s data collection, privacy, and security practices. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422894/google-play-app-privacy-info-apple-app-store-labels"&gt;Announced in May&lt;/a&gt;, developers will be able to start declaring their safety info in October until a deadline of April next year. The safety section is currently due to start appearing in app descriptions in the first quarter of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IeKSLI"&gt;Although Google says the design is subject to change, screenshots released today show the safety section sitting above a listing’s existing Ratings &amp;amp; reviews section. It offers a summary of an app’s data privacy features, including the types of data collected and whether data is encrypted. There’s also a “See details” option to get more specifics on what collected data is used for, and whether the collection is essential for using the app.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yD2xZoMs93pnuF_1K2vYbXyVxxo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22745164/Untitled__3_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tapping “See details” provides more info.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Pg4HSG"&gt;The section allows developers to “give a user deeper insight into their privacy and security practices, as well as explain the data the app may collect and why — all before a user installs the app,” Google says. If developers haven’t provided the information by the time the section starts appearing, a “No information available” message will appear in its place in the listing. Eventually, apps that don’t provide the information could see their updates blocked, Google has previously said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVrM5K"&gt;Google’s safety section — which will be required by all third-party and first-party Google apps — follows the introduction of very similar “privacy labels” to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;Apple’s App Store&lt;/a&gt; last year. Like Google’s section, Apple’s labels are designed to offer more transparency about user data collection, including whether it’s used to track users or is personally identifiable. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kTsll1Y2zfwiYjuC7dYznEpe6iw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22745165/Untitled.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An updated timeframe for the introduction of the feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NJ7FgO"&gt;Apple and Google’s initiatives have arrived as their respective &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407376/apple-european-union-antitrust-charges-app-store-music-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager"&gt;app&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567532/google-play-store-antitrust-lawsuit-state-ag-app-fees"&gt;stores&lt;/a&gt; are facing intense antitrust scrutiny over concerns they give the two companies too much control over their respective mobile ecosystems. A core part of Apple and Google’s arguments is that their stores help keep mobile users safe. New initiatives like privacy labels and safety sections seem like an attempt to bolster these arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3bKyGk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EtG2oS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597534/google-play-store-safety-section-privacy-info-app-store-privacy-nutrition-labels"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597534/google-play-store-safety-section-privacy-info-app-store-privacy-nutrition-labels</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter pilots a new shopping section for brands</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ve41m-H8BLDVQ3XDb5yADnH3rv4=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644730/Shop_Module_Hero_23July.001__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GameStop and Arden Cove are two of the brands piloting the feature.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3YKwAD"&gt;Twitter is piloting a new feature that allows businesses to add a shopping section to the top of their profiles, the company has announced. The Shop Module launches in the US today and offers a carousel of products for visitors to browse. Tapping a product will link to a listing with the option of making a purchase without ever leaving Twitter. The pilot is currently limited to iOS devices for people who use the service in English, Twitter says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bIhHzi"&gt;“People talk about products on Twitter everyday, so we’re excited about how this early exploration of the Shop Module can build a bridge between people talking about and discovering products on Twitter to actually purchasing them,” Twitter says. The pilot is only available with a small number of brands for now, including GameStop, Arden Cove, and around ten others. Twitter did not reveal a timeline for when it might expand to more brands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VmxUyhg6fHdAKn-pox2jwU-lyok=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22745182/Arden_Cove_GIF.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The module consists of a carousel with links to product listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G5Vf1j"&gt;Other social media platforms including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21399858/facebook-shop-app-update-sell-product-instagram"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326120/instagram-shopping-facebook-pay-shop-app"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163106/whatsapp-carts-feature-shopping-in-app-ecommerce"&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22594636/pinterest-idea-pins-tag-product-brand-shoppable"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; have also used new features to turn their services into shopping destinations, and even Twitter has previously experimented with embedding a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/8/6120079/twitter-commerce-buy-button"&gt;“Buy” button directly into tweets&lt;/a&gt; (it &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/1/18/14311230/twitter-buy-button-dead-killed-shuts-down"&gt;officially dropped the feature in 2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5vvut"&gt;The Shop Module pilot comes as Twitter is exploring ways of making money beyond showing ads. In this year alone, Twitter has announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22464291/twitter-blue-subscription-service-canada-australia-undo-reader-mode"&gt;paid subscription service&lt;/a&gt; with access to premium features, as well as plans to let users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545167/twitter-opens-super-follows-ticketed-spaces-new-feature-test-application-ios-android"&gt;charge for access to exclusive content&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;Tip Jar feature&lt;/a&gt; for one-off payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZ9b37"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1EIlvD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597576/twitter-shopping-module-pilot-gamestop-arden-cove-brands"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597576/twitter-shopping-module-pilot-gamestop-arden-cove-brands</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Great Ace Attorney Chronicles is the perfect vacation game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LxriWt719QPJlIewLjTgakjH7oo=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644724/TGAAC_Ryu_Herlock_01_bmp_jpgcopy.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NOsHWx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Ace Attorney Chronicles &lt;/em&gt;is the kind of engrossing murder mystery that’s perfect for a long vacation — it just happens to be a video game. As a prequel of sorts, &lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; takes place long before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/12/18306762/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trilogy-remastered-review-xbox-ps4-switch"&gt;the original &lt;em&gt;Ace Attorney&lt;/em&gt; trilogy&lt;/a&gt;, with new characters and a much more grounded tone, but with the same absorbing investigative gameplay and shock story twists that make it hard to put down. It’s the best of the franchise in one lengthy package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QINK1r"&gt;The game — which is actually a collection of two titles that previously launched in Japan — follows a budding defense attorney named Ryunosuke Naruhodo during the late 19th century in Japan. Things immediately get off to a rough start. In the first case, Naruhodo is forced to defend himself in court after being accused of murder. The second case features a shockingly unexpected death... which Naruhodo is also accused of committing. Things don’t slow down from there. The story jumps from Meiji-era Japan to Victorian London, with lots of delightful twists along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="yAw5eV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10673550"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pOVXzM"&gt;If you’ve never played an &lt;em&gt;Ace Attorney&lt;/em&gt; game, they play out a bit like a visual novel crossed with a detective game. Scenes generally revolve around either a court appearance or the investigation of a crime, so you’ll spend most of your time searching for clues, interrogating witnesses, and reading over lots and lots of dialogue. It works because of the incredible writing — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22594314/the-great-ace-attorney-nintendo-switch-translation-janet-hsu-interview"&gt;buoyed by a great localization&lt;/a&gt; — that seamlessly jumps from goofy to serious to heart-wrenching. Most importantly, there’s the incredible feeling that comes from finding the right piece of evidence or contradictory testimony that will blow a case wide open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pUOQ0F"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3f68MAdy-w?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tvOz3L"&gt;That was all true of past games, and &lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; improves the formula in a few ways. For starters, the cases feel more grounded in reality, with less bizarre coincidences that make it impossible to predict what’s really going on. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/10/12866404/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-spirit-of-justice-nintendo-3ds-review"&gt;Later entries in the series went a little extreme in this regard&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; reels things back without getting rid of the exaggerated characters and silly puns. Perhaps my favorite addition, though, is Herlock Sholmes, a detective who joins forces with Naruhodo. Like the real Sherlock, he’s gifted in the art of deduction, but he’s also a bit of a goof, constantly making mistakes that Naruhodo has to correct. Just like in court, it’s really satisfying finding the correct answers based on his flawed observations, particularly since he’s always so sure of himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yNFFIB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; also introduces a few other new features that make it a bit more accessible than past entries. For one, you can play the 10 cases in any order, as if you were picking episodes to play on Netflix. But there’s also a new “story” mode that essentially plays the game for you. It’ll run through dialogue automatically and even choose the right piece of evidence, without you having to touch a single button. Given how long &lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; is — it’ll probably take you at least 40 hours to play through the whole thing — I found it nice to just sit back and watch at times. It’s also handy for those moments when you’re not quite sure how to proceed, as getting stuck can really ruin the flow of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xIemK"&gt;As a largely standalone prequel, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557963/great-ace-attorney-chronicles-preview-hands-on-switch-ps4-steam"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; is a great starting point for new players&lt;/a&gt;, but it also might just be the best that &lt;em&gt;Ace Attorney&lt;/em&gt; has to offer. It has shocking twists, lovable characters, and the unmatched joy that comes from solving a complex crime. And with 10 meaty chapters to play through, it’ll keep you busy at least until the end of summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oL2t7y"&gt;&lt;small&gt;The Great Ace Attorney Chronicles &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is available now on the Nintendo Switch, PS4, and Steam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22597736/the-great-ace-attorney-chronicles-review-switch-ps4-steam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22597736/the-great-ace-attorney-chronicles-review-switch-ps4-steam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Extreme heat is on Democrats’ infrastructure agenda</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-WEATHER-HEAT" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WhK2iRKxY-bmlg7CSziryTsOMrc=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644542/1233735221.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;People wait to buy ice cream from a vender on the National Mall as the DC area experiences a heatwave on June 30, 2021, in Washington, DC. - Climate change is causing record-setting temperatures to become more frequent. Globally, the decade to 2019 was the hottest recorded, and the five hottest years have all occurred within the last five years. | Photo by BRENDAN SMIALOWSKI/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oq7WZQ"&gt;During a summer of deadly heatwaves, Democratic senators are pressing for a bigger federal response to the danger posed by extreme heat. Senators Ed Markey (D-MA), Alex Padilla (D-CA), and Cory Booker (D-NJ) reintroduced the Preventing Heat Illness and Deaths Act today. Representative Charlie Crist (D-FL) will introduce similar legislation in the US House of Representatives.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;They&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;are pushing for its measures to be included in either the bipartisan infrastructure or budget reconciliation package that Democrats are scrambling to advance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2sTAK"&gt;“We’ve heard that extreme heat is among the White House priorities in the climate space, and I am fighting to include provisions of my bill,” Markey said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="jA0MmS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’ve heard that extreme heat is among the White House priorities in the climate space.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JRvQfF"&gt;The bill would create the first federal financial assistance program to fund community-based projects that are specifically focused on extreme heat, according to Markey. It would also formalize and expand the National Integrated Heat Health Information System (NIHHIS) launched under President Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mv5uIy"&gt;“The rising health risks of extreme heat must be urgently addressed,” Markey told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Extreme heat is a complicated issue that will require a comprehensive response.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2uCQS6"&gt;Extreme heat has been the deadliest weather-related disaster in the US &lt;a href="https://www.weather.gov/hazstat/"&gt;over the past 30 years&lt;/a&gt;. It killed almost 200 people in the Pacific Northwest in June alone. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580120/emergency-department-visits-spiked-june-heat-wave-us-northwest"&gt;Thousands more went to emergency departments&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594471/heatwaves-prediction-more-study-climate-change"&gt;record-shattering temperatures&lt;/a&gt; also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22559961/heat-roads-washington-oregon-climate-infrastructure"&gt;buckled roads&lt;/a&gt; and melted power cables in a region that normally has relatively mild summers. On top of that, it’s been an explosive fire season for the Western US, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547454/2021-heat-wave-temperature-high-heat-dome"&gt;made worse by the soaring temperatures&lt;/a&gt;. The pain and damage wrought by this year’s heat were a “wakeup call,” Markey said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="i2wb6e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The pain and damage wrought by this year’s heat were a “wakeup call”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AqBqNt"&gt;Public health experts say heat-related deaths are largely preventable. Homes and buildings can be upgraded so that they stay cooler even when the mercury rises outside. And cities like New York have worked to provide residents with air conditioning or get them to cooling centers when temperatures are dangerously high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUF43h"&gt;The financial assistance program proposed by Markey, Padilla, and Booker would provide a total of $100 million to community projects over five years. That might include efforts to cool down neighborhoods by planting more trees in urban areas (which provide shade and remove heat from the air through evapotranspiration). The money could also go toward retrofitting homes and buildings, or painting rooftops and pavements lighter colors since dark surfaces trap heat. Other eligible projects include research on extreme heat, and raising public awareness of the risks and how to stay safe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CnI10H"&gt;At least 40 percent of the funds would be earmarked for projects in low-income communities and neighborhoods facing a higher risk of health problems connected to environmental issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sK1CYj"&gt;The second part of the bill bolsters the NIHHIS, run jointly by the CDC and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). While NIHHIS has researched and coordinated efforts between federal agencies to address extreme heat since 2015, it doesn’t get annual funding from Congress. If passed, the Preventing Heat Illness and Deaths Act would funnel $100 million to the NIHHIS over five years and create an interagency committee to guide its work. It would also commission a study on extreme heat in the US that would examine ways to make the US more resilient in the face of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NC4anD"&gt;The bill was first introduced last July, but proposed environmental policies have a better shot of moving forward under the Biden administration than they did last year under Donald Trump. Even so, Democrats are struggling to move ambitious climate agendas through a divided Congress in two tracks, with one bill passed across bipartisan support and another through the budget reconciliation process. Sen. Markey is pushing for the extreme heat measures to be included in either bill, although negotiations for the measures remain in flux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cjmcd7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why some city neighborhoods are hotter than others ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22575481/nyc-urban-heat-island-effect-thermal-camera-surface-temperature"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="XszuHX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hot summer days are even hotter for many Americans of color ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452777/hot-summer-weather-race-urban-heat-island-us-cities"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="s5e769"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Climate change responsible for about a third of heat deaths, study says ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461924/climate-change-heat-deaths-study"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597823/extreme-heat-democrat-infrastructure-budget-reconciliation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597823/extreme-heat-democrat-infrastructure-budget-reconciliation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Snapchat’s built-in map will start recommending places for you to visit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wdcr_NMOovSiuxYNPLs83D_WFeI=/0x11:1552x1046/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644268/Screen_Shot_2021_07_27_at_6.19.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Snap&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RnDEB8"&gt;More than 250 million people use Snapchat’s built-in map to see where their friends are in the world. The map interface was recently upgraded to a main tab inside the app, and today, Snap is adding a new feature that’ll surface popular places it thinks you may want to visit. Snap Map users will also start seeing lists of places, such as bars or restaurants, they’ve either tagged in past posts or favorited to check out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBIntn"&gt;The “Popular” tab at the bottom center of the Snap Map will show recommendations for places to go based on factors like your current location, friend activity on the map, and the kind of places you’ve saved as favorites. “This new algorithm in our Popular Tab sets Snap Map apart as a highly personalized discovery platform, and is a first-of-its-kind feature for Snapchat, overall,” a Snap spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C0BNtx"&gt;With these additions and other recent updates, such as integrations with the restaurant review website The Infatuation and Ticketmaster, Snapchat is turning its map into a unique way to discover the world around you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LCecZs"&gt;And while it’s not a meaningful driver of revenue for Snap yet, advertisers are able to target ads based on the locations of people who have opted into sharing that information — a potentially good way to encourage foot traffic to a local business. Seeing friends on a map alongside info about businesses is also a relatively unique feature that Facebook hasn’t managed to copy. Snap recently reported &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589236/snapchat-users-293-million-q2-2021"&gt;that is has 293 million daily users&lt;/a&gt;, making its user base about 42 percent larger than Twitter’s.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596908/snapchat-map-place-visit-popular-tab-bars-restaurants"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596908/snapchat-map-place-visit-popular-tab-bars-restaurants</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T09:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T09:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s back-to-school gift guide 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nI_9UcQrSU-sXPEHN0FMm9aKrhs=/143x0:1156x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644114/VRG_ILLO_4675_BTS_GG_2021_LEDE.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Great gifts for high schoolers and the college bound&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="iYqwJ1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School is back in session&lt;/strong&gt; — well, almost. After a turbulent year and a half, many high school and college campuses are looking to return to in-person classes in the fall as vaccination rates continue to climb and the US enters a new phase of the pandemic. Some students will continue to study remotely. Some will opt for a hybrid approach. But all will need supplies to carry out their coursework and make the most of their precious time off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3fR5Sp"&gt;If you’re not sure about what to get the student in your life, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;staff has corralled a list of items that are sure to please high school students, college kids, and post-grads alike. Some, like Logitech’s C920S webcam ($65) and the 2020 MacBook Air ($900), are practical favorites, while others, like &lt;em&gt;Salt Fat Acid Heat&lt;/em&gt; ($17), are meant to appease the student in all of us, whether you’re involved in academics or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V2BDkl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: If you’re looking for a wider selection of laptop picks, we also have guides to the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college"&gt;&lt;em&gt;best laptops for students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;&lt;em&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cHi8gf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10661581"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="efT22S"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22586264/back-to-school-gift-ideas-college-dorm-high-school-supplies-tech-gadgets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22586264/back-to-school-gift-ideas-college-dorm-high-school-supplies-tech-gadgets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T09:20:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T09:20:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony has sold 10 million PS5 consoles </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VmixewYt34O3mW85ggy7P36Ahhc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644060/vpavic_4278_20201030_0119.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i4m06q"&gt;Sony has now sold more than 10 million PS5 consoles. That’s up more than 2 million sales from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407195/sony-ps5-sales-numbers-q4-2020-earnings"&gt;7.8 million Sony previously revealed&lt;/a&gt; in April, and it means the PS5 continues to outpace sales of the PS4, making it the fastest-selling console in Sony’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rzttgu"&gt;The PS5 may be selling well, but supply is constrained and it’s still difficult to purchase a console right now thanks to a global chip shortage. “While PS5 has reached more households faster than any of our previous consoles, we still have a lot of work ahead of us as demand for PS5 continues to outstrip supply,” says Jim Ryan, president and CEO of Sony Interactive Entertainment. “I want gamers to know that while we continue to face unique challenges throughout the world that affect our industry and many others, improving inventory levels remains a top priority for SIE.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H2V4hi"&gt;Sony has also shared some milestones around PS5 launch titles today. &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales &lt;/em&gt;has sold more than 6.5 million copies since its launch in November, with &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; selling more than 1.1 million copies since its launch last month. &lt;em&gt;Returnal &lt;/em&gt;has also sold more than 560,000 copies since its April launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IxSXwo"&gt;While Sony continues to share console hardware figures, Microsoft stopped sharing Xbox sales numbers in the Xbox One era. “We’re all in on games,” said Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596578/microsoft-q4-2021-earnings-revenue-xbox-cloud-services-surface-gaming"&gt;during the company’s earnings call yesterday&lt;/a&gt;. “The Xbox Series S and X are our fastest selling consoles ever, with more consoles sold life-to-date than any previous generation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKB0e6"&gt;Daniel Ahmad, a senior analyst at Niko Partners, shared &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZhugeEX/status/1420141968546537472"&gt;estimates on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that the Xbox Series X / S “total sell in was 6.5m as of June 30, 2021.” That’s up from previous estimates of 5.7 million for Xbox One, and 5 million for Xbox 360 in the same timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ngXnJh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, July 28th 9:35AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with Xbox Series X / S sales estimates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597784/sony-ps5-playstation-5-sales"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597784/sony-ps5-playstation-5-sales</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-28T09:09:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T09:09:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Atmos-ready Sonos Arc sees a rare discount at Wellbots</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image of the front of the Sonos Arc soundbar with a TV in the background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r-NSo6TZiVETkANumXJ7o_adOW4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69644005/DSCF0849.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;In a rare move, Wellbots is offering the standout Sonos Arc for $50 off MSRP. | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0EgzLH"&gt;Sonos products are an easy sell, at least when the price is right. Like most products in the Sonos lineup, the Sonos Arc features a clean design and excellent sound quality, the latter of which is evident while listening to everything from Dolby Atmos movies to the lush sounds of The National’s most recent album, &lt;em&gt;I Am Easy to Find&lt;/em&gt;. What’s more, the all-in-one soundbar includes built-in support for Alexa and Google Assistant, as well as Apple’s AirPlay 2. Granted, you’ll need a recent TV that supports Atmos over HDMI ARC to truly unlock the Arc’s potential, but if you have one, it’s a great way to future-proof your home theater setup. Normally $800 and rarely discounted, the white iteration of the Sonos Arc is &lt;a href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1264455&amp;amp;u=1225169&amp;amp;m=83747&amp;amp;urllink=www%2Ewellbots%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fsonos%2Darc%2Dsoundbar&amp;amp;afftrack=VergeDailyDeal072821" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale at Wellbots for $50 off&lt;/a&gt; with promo code &lt;strong&gt;DADMUSIC&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21279703/sonos-arc-review-dolby-atmos-soundbar-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tjeBxF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10672350"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="iZjzDR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sonos CEO discusses the Arc and customer backlash over leaving old products behind","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/7/21249926/vergecast-podcast-interview-sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-s2-arc-atmo-soundbar"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="e6LtcW"&gt;As far as tablets go, Apple’s iPad lineup doesn’t really have much in the way of competition. Yes, there are competent Android tablets like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22150980/samsung-galaxy-tab-a7-tablet-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab A7&lt;/a&gt;, and Amazon makes the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22578620/amazon-fire-hd-10-plus-productivity-bundle-kids-pro-2021-tablet-review-which-to-buy"&gt;Fire HD 10&lt;/a&gt; and a wealth of other entry-level slates, but none of them feel particularly premium. Apple’s iPad Air does, however, and it’s not just because of the bevy of attractive colors. The fourth-gen model supports USB-C and the Apple Pencil 2. It also comes with a terrific 1080p display and a quick A14 Bionic processor, which should be more than enough power for most users. It’s not going to outperform, say, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;M1-equipped iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;, but it also doesn’t need to. Right now, the 64GB, 2020 iPad Air is available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J66ZMY7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746838897268969922#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $500, matching its all-time low. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="D5SsBB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JTNOUl"&gt;If you’re looking to stock up on a few items before the school year, eBay is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fe%2F_electronics%2Fcertified-refurbished-back-to-school&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F28%2F22596188%2Fsonos-arc-soundbar-2020-ipad-air-acer-27-inch-gaming-monitor-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently having a sale&lt;/a&gt; on all things refurbished. For a limited time, you can save on headphones, laptops, and a host of notable tech, including Acer’s impressive Nitro XV272U. The 27-inch, QHD gaming monitor — which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/16/22286158/acers-nitro-xv272u-gaming-monitor-g-sync-1440p-qhd-amazon-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;we’ve highlighted before&lt;/a&gt; — features an IPS display and 1440p resolution, along with a 144Hz refresh rate and AMD FreeSync support, a technology that steadies gameplay and helps prevent tearing. It also comes with a 1ms response time and a range of ports, including four USB Type-A 3.0 ports, two HDMI ports, and a DisplayPort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="raPpwy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 preview: a first look at Apple’s latest software","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ijoOYF"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F264454133603%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals072821%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F28%2F22596188%2Fsonos-arc-soundbar-2020-ipad-air-acer-27-inch-gaming-monitor-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nitro XV272U is currently available from Acer (via eBay) for $250&lt;/a&gt;, and, like every item featured in eBay’s ongoing sale, the monitor comes with a 30-day return policy and a two-year warranty, something you often don’t get with refurbished products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yEI4uA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10672478"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mA18gf"&gt;Other deals of note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="A0reFA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747488882315534238#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon’s second-gen Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; are $80 at Best Buy, the lowest price we’ve seen on the noise-canceling earbuds since Amazon Prime Day. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Mixamx"&gt;Roku’s Streambar is $100 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Roku-Streambar-Streaming-Premium-Released/dp/B08G8JH836/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1117087/2092?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Froku-streambar-hd-4k-hdr-streaming-media-player-38-premium-audio-all-in-one-and-voice-remote-with-tv-controls-2020%2F-%2FA-79829328" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, matching its best-ever price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CqVRF4"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747489000218086029#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2020 version of Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt; with a Core i5 processor, 8GB of RAM, and 128GB of storage is just $430 at Best Buy, $200 off its regular price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21355769/acer-chromebook-spin-713-review-best-chromebook-to-buy" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uj6IV1"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07N1WW638/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TP-Link’s RE220 Wi-Fi extender&lt;/a&gt; is $20 at Amazon, nearly matching its best price to date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VQsTYo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-13527013?sid=VergeDailyDeals072821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fapple-magsafe-charger-2" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s official MagSafe Charger&lt;/a&gt; is $30 at Woot, $10 off the normal retail price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v4oSx4"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747413801888654818#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s 55-inch QN90A Neo QLED&lt;/a&gt; is $300 off at Best Buy, bringing the price down to $1,500 for a limited time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EtPbOn"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Charger-Anker-Foldable-PowerPort-Included/dp/B08T67HDH1/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s PowerPort III charger&lt;/a&gt; is $13 at Amazon, the steepest discount we’ve seen on the popular fast charger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hot82d"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F334087468632%2F%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals072821%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F28%2F22596188%2Fsonos-arc-soundbar-2020-ipad-air-acer-27-inch-gaming-monitor-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-pack of Google Nest Mini&lt;/a&gt; is $64 at eBay via BuyDig’s digital storefront, one of the better bundles we’ve seen for those looking to outfit their home with Google's entry-level smart speaker. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="I1baCb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596188/sonos-arc-soundbar-2020-ipad-air-acer-27-inch-gaming-monitor-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596188/sonos-arc-soundbar-2020-ipad-air-acer-27-inch-gaming-monitor-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
