<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-09T14:38:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T14:38:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T14:38:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>NASA seeks to put first person of color on the Moon in Artemis mission</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YRn0roG1HDeVBsbiT3wyCswKK1g=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102884/GSFC_20171208_Archive_e001861_orig.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tweet-text"&gt;Acting NASA administrator Steve Jurczyk said Friday that under President Biden’s budget request, the agency’s Artemis mission has a new goal: in addition to landing the first woman on the Moon, it will also send the first person of color to the lunar surface. So far, the only Earthlings to touch the Moon’s surface have been white men. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RfgyZF"&gt;“The president’s discretionary request increases NASA’s ability to better understand Earth and further monitor and predict the impacts of climate change,” &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/acting-nasa-administrator-statement-on-agency-fy-2022-discretionary-request"&gt;Jurczyk said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “It also gives us the necessary resources to continue advancing America’s bipartisan Moon to Mars space exploration plan, including landing the first woman and first person of color on the Moon under the Artemis program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8nuxGH"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BC5khqpKovU?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RgXVWL"&gt;Biden’s 2022 budget request includes $24.7 billion for NASA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z51NCU"&gt;NASA previously announced that its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/13/18622415/nasa-moon-return-first-woman-astronaut-artemis-program"&gt;Artemis mission&lt;/a&gt;, named for the Greek Moon goddess and twin sister of the god Apollo, would put a woman on the Moon’s surface by 2024. Last November, the agency &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166077/nasa-artemis-astronauts-18-first-woman-moon-mike-pence-space-council"&gt;introduced the 18 astronauts&lt;/a&gt; who will staff the Artemis mission. The group includes several people of color and nine women. It’s not yet known who the first woman or person of color on the Moon will be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7T0Seg"&gt;The Space Launch System — the giant rocket the space agency plans to use to send people to the Moon — has its first uncrewed flight scheduled for later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AU7GUR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"All the news of NASA’s Artemis program, the agency’s attempt to returns humans to the Moon","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700565/nasa-artemis-moon-return-landing-trump-administration-jim-bridenstine"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375899/nasa-first-person-of-color-artemis-mission-moon-woman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375899/nasa-first-person-of-color-artemis-mission-moon-woman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T14:26:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T14:26:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>The White House wants to spend $100 million to monitor the air we breathe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="615463_ME-SMOKE-AIR-QUALITY-BRV_BRV" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bIUOWXagvLptksCz7pkTNgTZFfw=/48x0:3552x2336/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102763/1228565206.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smoke from Southern California wildfires blankets the LA Basin, obscuring downtown skyscrapers in a view from a closed Griffith Observatory.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Brian van der Brug / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bTNNe3"&gt;Today, the White House proposed spending $100 million on a new program aimed at tracking air quality in some of the most polluted communities in the US. It was a tiny piece of President Joe Biden’s initial $1.5 trillion federal budget request for 2022, but it is representative of the new administration’s&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;efforts to address legacies of environmental wreckage and injustice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNv8gV"&gt;The air quality program would be funded through the Environmental Protection Agency, whose budget Biden seeks to raise by more than 21 percent. There aren’t many details yet on what the program might look like. But on top of tracking air quality, it would be able to notify people with “real-time data” in places with some of the worst pollution in the nation. The program would “hold polluters accountable,” &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/FY2022-Discretionary-Request.pdf"&gt;according to the budget request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="HwNztp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The $100 million could go toward tackling some problematic gaps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xAI17E"&gt;The $100 million could go toward tackling some problematic gaps in how air quality is measured today. Those gaps can leave some communities, particularly &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4626327/"&gt;low-income&lt;/a&gt; neighborhoods and &lt;a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/116/13/6001?utm_campaign=Hot%20News&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=89531294&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9xNvMHn1bWk9yKfonfI3tKRFqpBykQxjDPLwQQ8jOWV6x-lOYIn8RzUEdKwvI0RkzvF9opoWwdz4RPe8VAmXGxrue0heNyHVsPkDmeLZHAAcWSn38&amp;amp;utm_content=89531294&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email"&gt;people of color&lt;/a&gt;, more vulnerable to pollution than others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QBFhBI"&gt;High-quality air quality monitors that researchers and regulators use have typically been too&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;expensive to deploy widely. Because they can be spread thin in some regions, they can miss differences in pollution levels from neighborhood to neighborhood. From one block to another, pollution can actually grow &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21303326/data-air-pollution-mapped-google-street-view-aclima"&gt;as much as eight times thicker&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y4iHYO"&gt;Even where there are government air quality monitors, communities have been let down. These devices have failed spectacularly in the past, an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21833693/air-quality-index-monitoring-epa-pollution-health-reuters"&gt;investigation by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; revealed last year. When a refinery exploded in Philadelphia in 2019, the federal air quality index reported clean air in the city that day even though 700,000 pounds of hazardous chemicals had been released. That’s because the closest official air monitor was programmed to take measurements just one out of every six days, and it happened to miss the event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gb6zrF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More affordable commercial air quality monitors have hit the market&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="74o9UZ"&gt;Luckily, more affordable commercial air quality monitors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21440343/air-quality-sensors-wildfire-smoke-pollution-climate-change"&gt;have hit the market&lt;/a&gt; lately. That’s allowed a growing network of everyday people to track air quality from their homes. While these devices are not quite as sensitive as official monitors, they’ve begun to fill in the gaps when it comes to mapping pollution in the air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FEsKdA"&gt;That’s come in particularly handy as more intense fire seasons have choked the air across much of the western US. For the first time last year, the EPA and US Forest Service included data from popular at-home air quality sensors in their &lt;a href="https://fire.airnow.gov/?lat=40.764548399999995&amp;amp;lng=-73.9227458&amp;amp;zoom=10"&gt;fire and smoke map&lt;/a&gt;. The description of Biden’s proposed initiative as a “community” air quality monitoring and notification system, suggests that it might add to those efforts to merge citizen science with government data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDN612"&gt;Today’s $1.5 trillion proposal from the White House includes funding requests for discretionary spending, which makes up about a third of the total federal budget. The Biden administration plans to announce a fuller budget proposal later this spring for the 2022 fiscal year that starts in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JV29vx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375827/white-house-biden-budget-request-100-million-air-quality-monitor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375827/white-house-biden-budget-request-100-million-air-quality-monitor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T14:12:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T14:12:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>OneWeb, SpaceX satellites dodged a potential collision in orbit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Fairy lights in the night sky" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h1z1cf5YTaS6mZ7CpV1qpfQ3mXI=/0x443:7118x5188/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102707/1210396023.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starlink satellites visible in the night sky in April 2020.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Patrick Pleul / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="k79daZ"&gt;Two satellites from the fast-growing constellations of OneWeb and SpaceX’s Starlink dodged a dangerously close approach with one another in orbit last weekend, representatives from the US Space Force and OneWeb said. It’s the first known collision avoidance event for the two rival companies as they race to expand their new broadband-beaming networks in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hSDCsS"&gt;On March 30th, five days after OneWeb launched its latest batch of 36 satellites from Russia, the company received several “red alerts” from the US Space Force’s 18th Space Control Squadron warning of a possible collision with a Starlink satellite. Because OneWeb’s constellation operates in higher orbits around Earth, the company’s satellites must pass through SpaceX’s mesh of Starlink satellites, which orbit at an altitude of roughly 550 km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2wJKCr"&gt;One Space Force alert indicated a collision probability of 1.3 percent, with the two satellites coming as close as 190 feet — a dangerously close proximity for satellites in orbit. If satellites collide in orbit, it could cause a cascading disaster that could generate hundreds of pieces of debris and send them on crash courses with other satellites nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lhejKL"&gt;Currently, there’s no national or global authority that would force satellite operators to take action on predicted collisions. Space Force’s urgent alerts sent OneWeb engineers scrambling to email SpaceX’s Starlink team to coordinate maneuvers that would put the two satellites at safer distances from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0bYq35"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Coordination is the issue. It is not sufficient to say ‘I’ve got an automated system.’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OdtND5"&gt;While coordinating with OneWeb, SpaceX disabled its automated AI-powered collision avoidance system and manually steered its Starlink satellite out of the way, according to OneWeb’s government affairs chief Chris McLaughlin. It was unclear why exactly SpaceX disabled the system. SpaceX, which rarely responds to reporters, did not return multiple requests for comment for this story, nor did David Goldman, the company’s director of satellite policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N4qv8y"&gt;SpaceX’s automated system for avoiding satellite collisions has sparked controversy, raising concerns from other satellite operators who say they have no way of knowing which way the system will move a Starlink satellite in the event of a close approach. “Coordination is the issue,” McLaughlin says. “It is not sufficient to say ‘I’ve got an automated system,’ because the other guy may not have, and won’t understand what yours is trying to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LSxBricZOFk2t78xAO0QYUgohik=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22432826/Satellites.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: OneWeb / SpaceX&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OneWeb satellites (left) launch in batches of 36. SpaceX’s Starlink satellites (right) launch in batches of 60.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UlziMS"&gt;SpaceX has roughly 1,370 Starlink satellites in orbit and is on track to launch thousands more, with ambitions to build a 12,000-satellite network of global broadband coverage. OneWeb has launched 146 satellites so far, of the roughly 650 it plans to send into orbit for a similar global network, operating in higher orbits around Earth. And Jeff Bezos’ Amazon has pledged to join the same race, planning to launch over 3,000 satellites in low-Earth orbit. All companies want to beam broadband internet into Earth’s most rural regions to meet increasing demand from consumers and governments alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XhpM8"&gt;“This event was a good example of how satellite operators can be responsible given the constraints of global best practices,” says Diana McKissock, the head of the Space Force 18th Space Control Squadron’s data sharing and spaceflight safety wing. “They shared their data with each other, they got in contact with each other, and I think in absence of any global regulation, that’s... the art of the possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="d2K8Ip"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“What is the point of having it if you have to turn it off when there’s going to be a potential collision?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pODbDc"&gt;Still, the sharp increase of satellites in orbit, mainly driven by SpaceX’s Starlink venture, has moved faster than any authority can regulate the industry for safety. McKissock says SpaceX has made efforts to increase its transparency in orbit; the company currently provides location data of its satellites to other operators. But its automated system for avoiding collisions is a closed book where openness and coordination are needed the most, analysts and operators say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjtb86"&gt;“What is the point of having it if you have to turn it off when there’s going to be a potential collision?” Victoria Samson of the Secure World Foundation says, adding that the void of any clear international framework for managing active objects in space makes it largely unclear who would be held responsible if a collision actually occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="51lVkr"&gt;Satellite maneuvers in space are common, but worry in the industry is mounting as OneWeb, SpaceX, Amazon, and other companies race to toss more satellites into space. And this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20847243/spacex-starlink-satellite-european-space-agency-aeolus-conjunction-space-debris"&gt;Starlink close call isn’t the first&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019, a European Space Agency satellite had to move out of the way of a Starlink satellite to avoid a potential collision. SpaceX didn’t move its satellite because of a computer bug that prevented proper communication with ESA, it said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zuhyrp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s just crossing your fingers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fQntcq"&gt;With more OneWeb satellite launches planned on a monthly basis, and with planned constellations from Amazon and Telesat in higher orbits than Starlink, the need to establish clear rules of the road in orbit is becoming more urgent than ever. SpaceX looms especially large, not just because of the size of its constellation but because of where it’s sending them. “OneWeb and others will have to transit through Starlink to reach their destinations, so SpaceX needs to ensure now that other satellite operators can do that safely,” says Caleb Henry, a satellite industry analyst at Quilty Analytics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WSBWQa"&gt;McKissock says the 18th Space Control Squadron is fully aware of the industry concerns with SpaceX’s autonomous avoidance approach. “So it’s been interesting,” she says. “But like I said, I’m glad they talked to each other. The scary situation is when one of the operators is not communicative, and then it’s just crossing your fingers.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374262/oneweb-spacex-satellites-dodged-potential-collision-orbit-space-force"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374262/oneweb-spacex-satellites-dodged-potential-collision-orbit-space-force</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:40:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:40:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Today I learned Disney is making a retractable lightsaber, and I need to see it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7TKQtz3Gh0zLK3m_JM3zuyB96_k=/146x0:1145x666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102431/StudyingSkywalkersEpIV_luke_obi_wan_lightsaber.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7Ldz72"&gt;To whom it may concern at The Walt Disney Company and / or Lucasfilm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KCZyph"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show me the damn lightsaber&lt;/em&gt;. I know you have a real one now. And it’s time to fess up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncBEnC"&gt;Let’s backtrack a bit. Yesterday, at a seemingly routine press event for the upcoming launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374457/avengers-campus-opening-disneyland-june-4th"&gt;Disneyland’s new Avengers Campus&lt;/a&gt; area on June 4th, Josh D’Amaro, the chairman of Disney parks, ended his presentation with a surprise reveal of a new lightsaber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="URqnFx"&gt;According to tweets from theme park reporter Carlye Wisel, who attended the press conference, the lightsaber was not the typical IRL lightsaber of “a giant light up stick attached to a neat-looking hilt.” In fact, it was the holy grail of replica sabers: one that can fully extend and retract its blade, just like the “real” lightsabers in the films. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="14KXv3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I just attended a virtual press conference and Josh D'Amaro had a lightsaber and it worked like a LIGHTSABER not a "im carrying around this long stick" lightsaber like a FUCKING LIGHTSABER LIGHTSABER&lt;/p&gt;— carlye wisel   hosts Very Amusing!  ✨  (@carlyewisel) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/carlyewisel/status/1380267046164783105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VU0NBC"&gt;There’s plenty of evidence that a better toy saber has been on Disney’s mind for a while. The company’s current crop of replica props and customized Galaxy’s Edge sabers are already hugely popular, to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XAFYT0"&gt;The company is clearly aware of the fact that the large plastic blades are a cumbersome annoyance — both Disney and plenty of third-party sellers &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.shopdisney.com/lightsaber-sheath-star-wars-galaxys-edge-400021042131.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offer carrying bags&lt;/a&gt;. And a truly retractable saber that lights up and looks good (and no, those lame plastic ones of stacked tubes don’t count) would be a huge upgrade for park fans and cosplayers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fQVxQu"&gt;More illuminating is a &lt;a href="https://wdwnt.com/2018/11/disney-files-patent-for-retractable-internally-illuminated-lightsaber/"&gt;patent that Disney filed in 2018&lt;/a&gt; for a “Sword Device with Retractable, Internally Illuminated Blade” — a lightsaber hilt with a motorized retractable blade that can extend out of the hilt, complete with lighting and sound effects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UV1B5f"&gt;To be clear, given that Disney’s new model almost certainly lacks the ability to coalesce a beam of pure energy that can slice through any object, it’s still not a real lightsaber. Plus, I’m not sure where Disney would be able to source kyber crystals. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xC6J4T_hUKg"&gt;Hacksmith Industries’ retractable 4,000-degree plasma blade&lt;/a&gt; is still the closest to achieving that, but that build required a massive power pack and is almost certainly not safe to sell as a children’s toy at a theme park. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ghym2a"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xC6J4T_hUKg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TyOhr1"&gt;But to return to my original point: after teasing this fantastic upgraded saber... &lt;em&gt;DISNEY DIDN’T RELEASE THE VIDEO. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YbAodk"&gt;There are probably a few reasons for this. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/carlyewisel/status/1380272525645553668"&gt;Wisel’s report notes&lt;/a&gt; that the new saber “*zhooped*” out of a “little box (like a hilt but much wider),” suggesting that the retractable saber is still in the design stage and that there’s probably some work that needs to be done before it’s ready for primetime. Disney may also be planning to save the new sabers for its upcoming immersive &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdisneyworld.disney.go.com%2Fdestinations%2Fstar-wars-galactic-starcruiser%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F4%2F9%2F22375720%2Fdisney-parks-lightsaber-retractable-blade-rumor-patent" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Star Wars: Galactic Starcruiser&lt;/a&gt; hotel, where the more realistic sabers would fit right in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HjAtDP"&gt;But I don’t really care about all those very logical business reasons. I just want to see the cool new lightsaber. Ball’s in your court, Disney. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/9/22375720/disney-parks-lightsaber-retractable-blade-rumor-patent"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/9/22375720/disney-parks-lightsaber-retractable-blade-rumor-patent</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:28:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:28:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Biden calls for new funding to fight semiconductor shortage in budget request</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-POLITICS-WEAPONS-BIDEN" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p45pFXEJ60wJNJOmbY-vhH9piUQ=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102380/1232182558.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Brendan Smialowski / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r85ZTR"&gt;In its first budget proposal to Congress on Friday, the White House called for new funding to fight the ongoing semiconductor shortage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BSZgtK"&gt;Among other measures, the White House’s budget request includes $150 million to fund two new manufacturing programs, including one targeting domestic semiconductor manufacturing. It’s the latest effort from the White House to address the ongoing semiconductor shortage, which has stalled supply for consumer items like the PlayStation 5 and &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/ford-semiconductor-gm-toyota-microprocessor-chip-shortage/"&gt;halted production at Ford assembly lines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WOmbGb"&gt;The “American Jobs Plan,” the sweeping &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22359496/biden-american-jobs-package-broadband-semiconductors-electric-vehicles"&gt;$2 trillion infrastructure package&lt;/a&gt; unveiled in March, also included new funding to build domestic chip manufacturing capacity, allocating over $50 billion for investment in the sector. In February, President Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298376/biden-sign-semiconductor-shortage-executive-order-apple-amd-playstation"&gt;signed an executive order&lt;/a&gt; calling for government reviews into the semiconductor supply chain. These reviews were set to end in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3SggiU"&gt;The global semiconductor shortage is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278431/biden-administration-global-semiconductor-chip-shortage-executive-order"&gt;the result of a number of factors&lt;/a&gt; spurred on by the coronavirus pandemic. As more Americans began to work and learn online, the demand for products like laptops and other consumer electronics rose dramatically. The production of chips also slowed down largely due to former President Trump’s trade war with China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EELZ2b"&gt;On Monday, White House and cabinet officials are set to host a virtual CEO summit on semiconductor supply chain resilience. The conversation will focus on Biden’s jobs plan and ways to strengthen the semiconductor supply chain. Companies like Alphabet, AT&amp;amp;T, Ford, General Motors, Intel, and Samsung are expected to be in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375814/biden-google-ceo-summit-budget-semiconductor-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375814/biden-google-ceo-summit-budget-semiconductor-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:24:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:24:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google announces Pixel 5A 5G by denying rumors it’s canceled</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JWXFGGjH4XNIMpW3v5TvkISQS1Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102351/akrales_201013_4137_0300.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zsVfLf"&gt;Google has officially announced a new Pixel phone, the Pixel 5A 5G. It’s done so in the same way it has announced a lot of recent Pixel phones: by reacting to a rumor. This time is a little less fun than usual, though, because the rumor in question is that the phone had been canceled entirely. In response, a Google spokesperson sent along the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ldx0Xl"&gt;Pixel 5a 5G is not cancelled. It will be available later this year in the U.S. and Japan and announced in line with when last year’s a-series phone was introduced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5R83xJ"&gt;Earlier today, &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-5a-reportedly-canceled"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;cited two independent sources claiming the Pixel 5A had been canceled, following a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jon_prosser/status/1380536151996559362"&gt;tweet from Jon Prosser&lt;/a&gt; claiming it was due to chip shortages. It does appear that the chip shortages are real, however, as Google is only planning to release the Pixel 5A 5G in the US and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyzxf6"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@onleaks/exclusive-first-look-at-the-google-pixel-5a-1614036211-183558310"&gt;rumors about the Pixel 5A 5G&lt;/a&gt; point to it being somewhat similar to the Pixel 4A 5G — another lower-end phone designed to broaden Google’s market reach by keeping the cost down. Code pointing to the existence of the Pixel 5A has &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/07/31/google-pixel-5a-makes-first-appearance-in-aosp-days-before-pixel-4a-launch/"&gt;been seen in the Android Open Source Project as early as July 2020&lt;/a&gt;. The Pixel 5A 5G is &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@onleaks/exclusive-first-look-at-the-google-pixel-5a-1614036211-183558310"&gt;expected to be similar&lt;/a&gt; (but not identical) in size to the Pixel 4A 5G, with a 6.2-inch FHD+ display, dual rear cameras, and a headphone jack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EKgOEo"&gt;Google’s statement says it will be announced “in line with when last year’s a-series phone was introduced,” which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352032/google-pixel-5-4a-5g-price-release-date-specs"&gt;in August 2020&lt;/a&gt;. However, &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/04/07/google-i-o-2021-has-been-announced-and-its-the-first-free-i-o-in-memory/"&gt;many have speculated&lt;/a&gt; that it would be announced at this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371782/google-io-2021-date-announcement-virtual-online-event-date-android"&gt;year’s online-only Google I/O developer conference&lt;/a&gt; alongside a lower-cost version of the Pixel Buds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iiz21T"&gt;Google is also rumored to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364543/google-pixel-6-custom-in-house-processor-gs101-whitechapel-arm-report"&gt;creating a higher-end flagship Pixel phone later this year&lt;/a&gt;. Assumed to be the Pixel 6, the big deal with that rumored phone is that it will begin to use more Google-designed chips, including the so-called “Whitechapel” system on a chip.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYQHR8"&gt;Google has a history of just admitting it has phones to announce in response to rumors. Back in 2019, it famously tweeted out an image of the Pixel 4 after it started to leak in earnest. It was an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662941/google-pixel-4-leak-editorial-premium-high-end-phone"&gt;innovative way to take control of the usual phone rumor hype cycle&lt;/a&gt; at the time. This time, Google’s response is a little less cheeky. Having to straight-up deny cancellation rumors feels a lot less like hype and a lot more like damage control. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:23:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:23:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Phoebe Waller-Bridge will co-star with Harrison Ford in Indiana Jones 5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="77th Annual Golden Globe Awards - Arrivals" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZfQvebwz2BKdqNzejH9KSI8j0yM=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102339/1197737728.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Steve Granitz/WireImage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wxYNUl"&gt;Phoebe Waller-Bridge is joining the as-yet-untitled fifth &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones &lt;/em&gt;film, co-starring as an as-yet-announced character opposite Harrison Ford (who’ll be returning as the titular adventurer, of course). Also set to return is John Williams, who has scored the previous four films and whose “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgncJgSbbck"&gt;Raiders March&lt;/a&gt;” theme is indelibly associated with the character. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pyIHHN"&gt;Disney hasn’t announced details on who Waller-Bridge (best known for her award-winning series &lt;em&gt;Fleabag&lt;/em&gt;, along with appearances in &lt;em&gt;Solo&lt;/em&gt; and the upcoming &lt;em&gt;No Time to Die&lt;/em&gt;) will be playing, although in a 2019 interview with &lt;em&gt;The Sun, &lt;/em&gt;franchise creator Steven Spielberg did acknowledge that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/5/17203922/steven-spielberg-indiana-jones-female-lady-heroine-woman"&gt;might be time for a female iteration of the character&lt;/a&gt;. Using the fifth film to pass the torch from the 78-year-old Ford to Waller-Bridge could be a good way to help rejuvenate the franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7sKe4l"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Indiana Joan Jones is the female lady heroine that women need","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/5/17203922/steven-spielberg-indiana-jones-female-lady-heroine-woman"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="qCnYA8"&gt;That said, the last time the &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; franchise tried to hand things off to a younger actor — Shia LaBeouf, who played Jones’ song in the widely panned &lt;em&gt;Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/em&gt; in 2008 — things didn’t quite pan out. (It’s no surprise that Ford, not LaBeouf, is heading the upcoming film.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jQ4WHo"&gt;Further complicating that theory is the fact that Lucasfilm president Kathleen Kennedy &lt;a href="https://www.slashfilm.com/indiana-jones-5-will-be-the-last-in-the-franchise/"&gt;previously confirmed&lt;/a&gt; at Disney’s investor event last December that the fifth &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; film would be the final movie in the series. But presumably, in today’s world of reboots, sequels, and Disney Plus spinoffs, there’s plenty of room for Disney to continue the franchise if it chooses to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XrG6tx"&gt;Unlike the first four films in the series, which were directed by Steven Spielberg, James Mangold will direct &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones 5&lt;/em&gt; (although Spielberg is still on board as an active producer of the film). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DRw4ty"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones 5&lt;/em&gt; is set to hit theaters on July 29th, 2022. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375779/phoebe-waller-bridge-indiana-jones-5-harrison-ford"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375779/phoebe-waller-bridge-indiana-jones-5-harrison-ford</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T13:10:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T13:10:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google updates YouTube ad targeting terms to remove hate speech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qB9Un6kPoAhiCH1f6exVnFZymcY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102249/acastro_180806_1777_youtube_cancel_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fipdk5"&gt;Google says it has blocked several terms associated with hate speech from being used as ad keywords on YouTube videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxd96b"&gt;The move follows a &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2021/04/09/google-blocks-advertisers-from-targeting-black-lives-matter-youtube-videos"&gt;report by &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which found that advertisers could search for terms like “white lives matter” and “white power” when deciding where to place ads on YouTube: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6y5Psj"&gt;Google offered advertisers hundreds of millions of choices for YouTube videos and channels related to White supremacist and other hate terms when we began our investigation, including “all lives matter”—a phrase frequently used as a dismissive rejoinder to Black Lives Matter—and “White lives matter”—which the Southern Poverty Law Center &lt;a href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/white-lives-matter"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; as both a neo-Nazi group and “a racist response to the civil rights movement Black Lives Matter.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Hl5ici"&gt;At the same time, &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; found, Google was blocking advertisers from using terms such as “Black Lives Matter” to find videos and channels to run ads against. After &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; reached out to YouTube parent company Google for comment, it says the company actually &lt;a href="https://github.com/the-markup/investigation-youtube-ad-placements"&gt;blocked more racial and social justice terms&lt;/a&gt;, including “Black excellence” and “civil rights.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6S0Nw0"&gt;“We take the issue of hate and harassment very seriously and condemn it in the strongest terms possible,” a Google spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Though no ads ever ran against this content on YouTube, because our multi-layered enforcement strategy worked during this investigation, we fully acknowledge that the terms identified are offensive and harmful and should not have been searchable. Our teams have addressed the issue and blocked terms that violate our enforcement policies. We will continue to be vigilant in this regard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HFEFOQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We fully acknowledge that the terms identified are offensive and harmful and should not have been searchable”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rNAm0T"&gt;YouTube says it has several layers of protection in place to prevent offensive or harmful ads from running on its platform, and that it regularly removes videos containing hate speech. Last year, the company says it blocked or removed more than 867 million ads for trying to evade its detection systems and more than 3 billion bad ads in total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p2Zp4h"&gt;Google says it does not publicly disclose how it develops its enforcement tools, so that so-called bad actors can’t circumvent its rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnONCO"&gt;YouTube has battled hate speech on its platform for several years, with mixed results. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/5/18652576/youtube-supremacist-content-ban-borderline-extremist-terms-of-service"&gt;2019, it banned white supremacist content&lt;/a&gt;, and the company said it would restrict channels from monetizing videos that “repeatedly brush up against our hate speech policies,” preventing them from running ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vwVWJ2"&gt;In a blog post last June, &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/inside-youtube/susan-wojcicki-my-mid-year-update-youtube-community"&gt;YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki said&lt;/a&gt; the company’s hate speech policy “specifically bans videos alleging that a group is superior based on qualities like race, gender, religion, or sexual orientation in order to justify discrimination, segregation or exclusion.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375702/google-updates-youtube-ad-targeting-hate-speech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375702/google-updates-youtube-ad-targeting-hate-speech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T12:39:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T12:39:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some Pixel 5 users can’t stream Netflix in HD because of a DRM issue</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Pixel 5 (top) and the Pixel 4A 5G (bottom)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8-yq88lH2Qwde1dLphBc_pGpceo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69102063/akrales_201012_4137_0010.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VAzoNH"&gt;Some Pixel 5 owners are &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GooglePixel/comments/ml5l9w/widevine_changed_to_l3_after_april_updatepixel_4a/"&gt;apparently experiencing a bug&lt;/a&gt; with Google’s Widevine DRM platform that’s causing their phones to only play back Netflix videos in standard definition, instead of the usual HD and HDR10 quality that they should be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99e0Q1"&gt;Google is aware of the issue and is working on a firmware fix, but it still has to test and verify it so it’s not clear when it will be released. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5if2hY"&gt;The issue, while not widespread, appears to be causing afflicted Pixel 5 devices to be downgraded to Widevine’s L3 status, instead of the usual Widevine L1 (which is what authenticates to allow for HD and HDR playback for Netflix, among other things). &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/06/pixel-widevine-l3/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; speculates&lt;/a&gt; that the issue appears to have been exacerbated by the recent April security update for the phone, although its not clear if the two are actually linked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZOdrlT"&gt;Widevine is Google’s DRM service, which is used by a variety of premium streaming companies, including Netflix, Amazon Prime, Disney Plus, and Google Play Movies. Content is secured using a three-level system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mstutl"&gt;L1 is the most secure and ensures that all content processing and cryptography is handled within a trusted execution environment on the device’s processor. L2 devices only execute cryptography operations within that secure environment, while L3 devices don’t do any content processing or cryptography operations in a secure area of the chipset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UZrn2O"&gt;Generally, in order to ensure that streamed content doesn’t get stolen, companies mandate that higher-quality HD, HDR, and 4K versions of movies and shows be limited to the more secure L1 devices. Google’s Pixel phones &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be L1-rated devices, but the aforementioned issue seems to be causing them to register as L3 hardware instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YFJUNl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375527/pixel-5-users-hd-netflix-drm-widevine-issue-firmware-fix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375527/pixel-5-users-hd-netflix-drm-widevine-issue-firmware-fix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T12:23:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T12:23:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hans Zimmer’s ringtone for the Oppo Find X3 Pro is fit for a Hollywood score</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/THmENA15zQgYr6Suy6yWuuqijtk=/0x0:1440x960/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69101935/Hans_Zimmer_2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Oppo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2JrrWE"&gt;Hans Zimmer, the legendary composer of &lt;em&gt;The Lion King&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Inception&lt;/em&gt;, and other iconic soundtracks, has brought his epic compositions to a new audio medium: phone sounds. Yes, Hans Zimmer created a ringtone and other phone sounds for Oppo’s newest flagship, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22324860/oppo-find-x3-pro-flagship-announced-10-bit-microlens-specs"&gt;the Find X3 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eGZoV7"&gt;The fact that Zimmer made these ringtones isn’t news. Oppo made a big deal about his involvement in March, posting a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LaQEEHooI64"&gt;video interview with him&lt;/a&gt; and an entire song &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CK2oi-JWoss"&gt;he composed just for Oppo&lt;/a&gt; (called “Colourful Future,” if you were wondering) on its YouTube channel. But these videos didn’t have what I wanted to hear: the actual Zimmer-composed sounds by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTXRKX"&gt;So I asked an Oppo PR rep if they could send the tones my way, and they did. Now, I can’t stop listening to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oaK2xZ"&gt;I’ve embedded them in this post so you can hear them, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NySR4b"&gt;Ringtone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VbvxaP"&gt;Here is the Zimmer-made ringtone — it’s beautiful. As my colleague Ian Carlos Campbell said, “Does he want me to cry every time the phone rings?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="x1gB2z"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="265" src="https://clyp.it/2lig5ktt/widget?token=1918ee862a722caa98ca9e1992058518" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EvAw0p"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QK5iYy"&gt;“I want the ringtone to open a door that says there is the possibility to feel something,” Zimmer said about the ringtone in Oppo’s video interview. It worked, Hans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4rOzB5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="W9WW9Q"&gt;Alarm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5mC3nL"&gt;Here’s the Zimmer-composed alarm tone. It sounds like waking up to a beach sunrise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uzb85b"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="265" src="https://clyp.it/4nsekecn/widget?token=c6dd755e66f4a5ba87ceec23f0a6eb46" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WqkLMo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="860BgG"&gt;Text tone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="khPUjq"&gt;Here’s the charming text tone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TEDSqK"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="265" src="https://clyp.it/cpabpgwb/widget?token=8ff9f9d6894606db344b26a33b53ac72" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OCC8Mf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JfOsLu"&gt;Notification sound&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="z1JG7s"&gt;And here’s a generic notification sound, which I’d like all of my apps to use from now on, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0KMtwh"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="265" src="https://clyp.it/21mar2a2/widget?token=c5f77c980e5ec3336b9e21e57abf1391" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HQ3LZw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bfe0Gb"&gt;These are so good that now I’m hoping Google or Apple will work with Zimmer to refresh their phone sounds next. (Just imagine Zimmer’s take on the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FTcXZqIZxbA"&gt;iPhone’s classic Marimba ringtone&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phTDXT"&gt;I also recommend you watch Zimmer’s full interview &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LaQEEHooI64"&gt;on Oppo’s YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;, where he describes how he hears colors. Honestly, I believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8L4zdS"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LaQEEHooI64?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TS0Kph"&gt;&amp;lt;iframe width=”100%” height=”265” src=”&lt;a href="https://clyp.it/4nsekecn/widget"&gt;https://clyp.it/4nsekecn/widget&lt;/a&gt;” frameborder=”0”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22373999/hans-zimmer-oppo-find-x3-pro-ringtone-sounds-alarm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22373999/hans-zimmer-oppo-find-x3-pro-ringtone-sounds-alarm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
