<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-09T16:58:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:58:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:58:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection remasters two classics for PS5 and PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/slhetAxk7Es6zc-bhYOt92dFO2g=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836750/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_1.41.24_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="enxYDX"&gt;At its PlayStation Showcase on Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IfrfJn_-24g"&gt;Sony announced &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a remaster of both &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: The Lost Legacy&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s coming to both PS5 and PC. The collection will be released in early 2022, Sony says, though the PS5 version will be released first while the PC version will arrive “shortly after,” &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/09/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-coming-to-ps5-and-pc/"&gt;according to a PlayStation Blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LLQx4h"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/10/11639246/uncharted-4-cinematic-game-review-ps4-playstation"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the fourth mainline game in the hit series starring Nathan Drake, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/17/16158114/uncharted-the-lost-legacy-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lost Legacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a side story starring Chloe Frazer and Nadine Ross. The arrival of &lt;em&gt;A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt; on PC isn’t a &lt;em&gt;complete&lt;/em&gt; surprise, as the PC release was mentioned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455810/sony-ps5-profitable-uncharted-4-pc-investor-presentation"&gt;in a May investor presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxJfNN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; creator Naughty Dog’s last big release was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21286964/the-last-of-us-part-2-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which was released in June 2020. The game got a patch in May that enables the game to run at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22443868/the-last-of-us-part-2-ps5-patch-update-60fps"&gt;a targeted 60fps on PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt;. Sony is also rumored to be working on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375262/sony-remake-the-last-of-us-ps5-studio-reorganization-report"&gt;a PS5 remake of the original &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22661816/sony-playstation-showcase-uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22661816/sony-playstation-showcase-uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:56:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:56:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>God of War: Ragnarok finally has a trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nkjYFeIFg5GJOQQhPSSEdJIRAKw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836724/E_3vU3YXMAEXoy2.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S4aDF1"&gt;We’ve finally got a first glimpse at the newest entry in the “Kratos tries to Dad” series and it looks pretty damn cool. &lt;em&gt;God of War: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;, first teased &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440393/sony-god-of-war-ragnarok-sequel-ps5-playstation-5-2021-teaser"&gt;almost exactly a year ago&lt;/a&gt; with naught more than a logo, finally has a trailer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQtQMi"&gt;The new trailer, showcased during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664376/playstation-ps5-games-showcase-how-to-watch-date-time"&gt;Sony’s PlayStation event&lt;/a&gt;, features Atreus bickering with his father about his destiny as the cataclysm of Ragnarok looms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5f2TC3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ty7WudwSKMA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CwOEGx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt; is the ninth entry in the series and sequel to 2018’s award-winning &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; took the marquee PlayStation franchise from ancient Greece to ancient Scandinavia, pitting Kratos against the gods and monsters of Norse mythology. Developed by Santa Monica Studios, &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; stars a not really kinder nor gentler Kratos as he struggles to be a father to his son Atreus. Together, Atreus and Kratos journey across a realm fighting monsters, vindictive gods, and having a neat lil’ chat with a kick ass, world-eating, giant snake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMUe7Z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; was a critical darling, earning numerous accolades including Game of the Year during 2018’s Game Awards. &lt;em&gt;God of War: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt; was slated for release in 2021 before the covid-19 pandemic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465232/god-of-war-ragnorok-ps5-ps4-delay-2022"&gt;delayed the game until 2022&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665085/sony-god-of-war-ragnarok-playstation-ps5-showcase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665085/sony-god-of-war-ragnarok-playstation-ps5-showcase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:53:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:53:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Gran Turismo 7 will release in March 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Gran Turismo 7" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XQr6vwnh5-0FZwvHD5MxH6TbzTQ=/203x0:2354x1434/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836699/gt7.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zM8A2b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo 7 &lt;/em&gt;resurfaced during Sony’s PlayStation Showcase 2021 with a new trailer. Sony’s head of PS Studios Hermen Hulst shared that it’s coming March 4th, 2022, and the trailer shows off more cars that you’ll likely never be able to afford — and lots of them. Inside of the cars, outside of them, and the gorgeous, presumably ray-traced vistas that you’ll be zipping around in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZK27qY"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21275346/gran-turismo-7-ps5-sony-playstation-5-polyphony-digital"&gt;first trailer&lt;/a&gt; that debuted in June 2020 showed us as much, but this new one shows, well, even more of that, plus a more in-depth glimpse of the deep customization that &lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo&lt;/em&gt; sims are known to offer. It also shows off some online gameplay as well as a look at the game’s deep photo mode. Hulst shared in a post-event chat that the game will take advantage of the DualSense’s rumble features and adaptive triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4fffb"&gt;Positioned next to the free-roaming action in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; on the Xbox Series X / S consoles and PC, &lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo 7&lt;/em&gt;’s driving should deliver a more subdued but nevertheless exciting gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LW4YzX"&gt;Sony says more info will be shared about the game in the coming weeks, and &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/09/gran-turismo-7-arrives-on-ps5-and-ps4-march-4/"&gt;it has details about its various modes and courses here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664477/gran-turismo-7-ps5-racing-march-2022-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664477/gran-turismo-7-ps5-racing-march-2022-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:52:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:52:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>The next Halo Infinite multiplayer preview will be available to everyone on September 24th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oIlRu7x66srb_sFTbO7gNbSGpa8=/166x0:1962x1197/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836688/halo_infinite_keyart_primary_horiz_9e788e276ba740e3af6451ef073fd3de.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FDSmd1"&gt;343 Industries is holding another &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer preview later this month, and this time, it will be open to everyone. The next &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer preview will kick off on Friday, September 24th, and all you need to do is &lt;a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/en-us/community/halo-insider"&gt;sign up to be a &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; Insider&lt;/a&gt; before September 14th to get access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ueIj81"&gt;This test will include access to the 4v4 multiplayer and Big Team Battle modes, alongside the regular Bot Arena and Academy Weapon Drills bot modes that were playable in the previous test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="C1fZzd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The next &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloInfinite?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HaloInfinite&lt;/a&gt; multiplayer preview is targeted to arrive on Sept. 24! All fully registered Halo Insider profiles as of Sept. 13 are eligible to participate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Don’t miss out! Head to &lt;a href="https://t.co/3a5Xr1hUIc"&gt;https://t.co/3a5Xr1hUIc&lt;/a&gt;, get your profile fully filled out, then prepare for takeoff. &lt;a href="https://t.co/9GgAQP4f6p"&gt;pic.twitter.com/9GgAQP4f6p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Halo (@Halo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Halo/status/1436057075466051584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LKZOkO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; is set to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22637945/halo-infinite-release-date-launch"&gt;release on December 8th&lt;/a&gt;, but at launch, you won’t be able to edit multiplayer levels in Forge mode or play the campaign mode cooperatively with friends. 343 Industries tested a variety of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; maps during the previous technical preview, so we’re expecting to see some new maps appear later this month that demonstrate the potential for the Big Team Battle mode.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665435/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview-september-24th"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665435/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview-september-24th</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:51:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:51:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Venom is coming in Spider-Man 2 for the PS5 in 2023</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FxxiZDARpprrew_G25Me2m9uUhA=/358x0:2050x1128/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836681/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_4.41.50_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mz11fw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/09/marvels-spider-man-2-and-marvels-wolverine-revealed/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt; is officially coming to the PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt; in 2023, bringing back both Peter Parker and Miles Morales from Insomniac Games’ previous PlayStation Spider-Man titles to face off against a new foe: Venom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZWWyKD"&gt;Unlike last year’s &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;, which was a cross-generational release on both PS4 and PS5, &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt; will be exclusive to the PS5. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GVde6czfsqA1XBGzILhVI78zUZs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22838175/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_4.49.21_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7jT1kR"&gt;There was no gameplay shown off in the brief teaser trailer, which showcased both Spider-Men teaming up together to take on a variety of goons while a mysterious man voices his desire for a true challenge, a gauntlet that gets taken up by iconic Spider-Man villain Venom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4I7kW7"&gt;It’s not clear whether Venom will be joining Peter and Miles as a playable hero in &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt; or if players will be fighting against the webbed villain in the upcoming sequel. With a release date set for sometime in 2023, though, there’s plenty of time for Insomniac to reveal more information in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwxUX1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665533/spider-man-2-insomniac-games-peter-parker-miles-morales-venom-ps5-2023"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665533/spider-man-2-insomniac-games-peter-parker-miles-morales-venom-ps5-2023</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:49:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:49:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Insomniac is making a Wolverine game for PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bglu1RpngzbpAJuU9H0dASNYC6c=/33x0:816x522/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836667/E_3uSOUWYAIJgi4.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MfDxIA"&gt;Insomniac had a huge hit on its hands when it ventured into the realm of superheroes with &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;. Now, the studio is jumping into another Marvel universe with a game simply titled &lt;em&gt;Wolverine&lt;/em&gt;. We don’t know much about it, other than Logan has &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; hairy knuckles and looks as angry as usual. But given the studio’s track record, you can likely expect some really solid action mixed with an MCU-style narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8TXlIa"&gt;Here’s what Insomniac has to say about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="lAy7lS"&gt;Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Wolverine&lt;/em&gt; is a standalone game being directed by Brian Horton (creative director) and Cameron Christian (game director), who recently led the creative efforts on Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;, a game we’re extremely proud of at Insomniac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SreemS"&gt;In the vein of our &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; games, our goal here is to not only respect the DNA of what makes the character so popular, but also look for opportunities to make it feel fresh and truly reflect the Insomniac spirit. Even though Marvel’s&lt;em&gt; Wolverine &lt;/em&gt;is very early in development, from what I’ve seen of its emotional narrative and cutting-edge gameplay (see what I did there?), the team is already creating something truly special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yDslwT"&gt;It was a big surprise, and it was followed by an even bigger one: the studio is also working on &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt;, which will feature Venom and is launching in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665529/insomniac-wolverine-ps5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665529/insomniac-wolverine-ps5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:42:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:42:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch the first trailer for the Alan Wake remaster</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IaHvZr7wno12U9N726saKI2ClRg=/85x0:1003x612/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836609/Alan_Wake_Remastered_Featured_im.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Remedy Entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wys0f0"&gt;Sony debuted &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mRVBZC-RJF0"&gt;the first trailer&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake Remastered &lt;/em&gt;at its PlayStation Showcase on Thursday. I’ve never played any of the games in the &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake&lt;/em&gt; series, but I was intrigued by the mysterious and spooky trailer shown during the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UOv190"&gt;If you’re not familiar with the plot of &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake&lt;/em&gt;, here’s the YouTube description for Thursday’s trailer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Y3joYi"&gt;Play as troubled author Alan Wake, who goes on a desparate search for his missing photographer wife, Alice. The sleepy Pacific Northwestern town of Bright Falls isn’t what it seems. A malevolent presence lurks in the dark, and a horror story Alan doesn’t remember writing is coming true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="xvys0A"&gt;Fortunately, you won’t have long to wait until you can play the game for yourself — &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake Remastered&lt;/em&gt; is coming to PlayStation 4 / 5, Xbox Series S / X, and the Epic Games Store on PC next month, on October 5th. The remastered version offers 4K visuals and packs in both story expansions, &lt;em&gt;The Signal&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Writer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uPI5wg"&gt;You can read more about the game in a &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/09/rewriting-history-alan-wake-remastered-brings-the-writers-story-to-ps4-and-ps5/"&gt;new PlayStation Blog post&lt;/a&gt; from Remedy Entertainment creative director Sam Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665443/sony-playstation-showcase-alan-wake-remastered-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665443/sony-playstation-showcase-alan-wake-remastered-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:15:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:15:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic is getting a remake for the PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nDtQWprp353bLSmJPxSpXior-Yk=/189x0:2238x1366/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836455/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_4.06.00_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kqGWUl"&gt;The legendary &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; roleplaying game &lt;em&gt;Knights of the Old Republic&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/09/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-is-the-legendary-tale-remade-on-playstation-5/"&gt;is getting a PS5 remake&lt;/a&gt;, Sony announced today at its 2021 fall showcase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FoKnz4"&gt;The remake is being developed by Aspyr, which had previously worked on the Mac, Android, and iOS ports of both the original &lt;em&gt;Knights of the Old Republic&lt;/em&gt; and its sequel, &lt;em&gt;Knights of the Old Republic II: The Sith Lords&lt;/em&gt;. Sony Interactive Entertainment and Lucasfilm Games will also be working on the remake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s2RuSy"&gt;Missing from the announcement is BioWare — which originally developed &lt;em&gt;Knights of the Old Republic&lt;/em&gt; in 2003 — but doesn’t seem to be involved in the new version, although Sony’s announcement post does note that Aspyr has recruited some of the original development team to work on the remake.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UgYJKBafS6V2xJNNlzMBAPGyO8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22837963/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_4.06.09_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iP8GVP"&gt;Set thousands of years before the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; films, &lt;em&gt;Knights of the Old Republic &lt;/em&gt;(or &lt;em&gt;KOTOR&lt;/em&gt;, as its known by fans) is considered one of the greatest &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; games ever made, pitting players against the villainous Darth Revan and his Sith Empire. The original game was followed by a sequel (developed by Obsidian Entertainment) and the long-running &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Old Republic&lt;/em&gt; MMO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y23OIE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic Remake&lt;/em&gt; will be a console exclusive for the PlayStation 5 when it launches, although there’s no details yet on a release window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyccgw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 9th, 4:25pm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added details on launch exclusivity. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665460/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-ps5-darth-revan"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665460/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-ps5-darth-revan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T16:07:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T16:07:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch exec takes over secretive car project</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/glD8qhJRzYoj4Ep5u5PO-wfaL5o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836415/acstro_190902_apple_event_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="svd8NW"&gt;Just two days after Ford &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22661291/apple-car-chief-ford-doug-field"&gt;hired away Doug Field, the head of Apple’s secretive car project&lt;/a&gt;, the tech giant has tapped Apple Watch exec and former Adobe CTO Kevin Lynch to take his place, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-09/apple-s-watch-software-chief-takes-over-self-driving-car-project?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g4s1eN"&gt;It’s the latest changing of the guard for the project, known as Project Titan, which has rotated leaders about as much as it has reportedly shifted focus. To wit, Korea’s &lt;em&gt;Maeil Economic Daily&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/09/apple-chose-to-develop-apple-car-alone/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; earlier Thursday that Apple may no longer be trying to work with other automakers to bring its autonomous electric car to life. Rather, the report states, Apple now plans to go it alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2tpGcU"&gt;Lynch started working on the project in July, when he was brought on to help develop the vehicle’s software. He joined Apple in 2013 from Adobe, where he was the company’s chief technology officer. While there, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4124972/adobe-cto-kevin-lynch-allegedly-leaving-to-join-apples-ranks"&gt;he somewhat famously wrote Adobe’s official response&lt;/a&gt; to Apple’s decision to keep Flash out of iOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="armIzd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Lynch wrote Adobe’s defense of putting Flash on ios, once upon a time&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bHNbMM"&gt;Curiously, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;writes that Lynch still reports to Apple’s chief operating officer Jeff Williams and not John Giannandrea, the company’s head of AI — who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163939/apple-self-driving-car-john-giannandrea-ai-siri"&gt;was tapped last year to oversee the car project&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gsfmvh"&gt;Field, meanwhile, ran Project Titan from 2018 up until this week when he was poached by Ford. Before that, he spent years at Tesla helping bring cars like the Model 3 to market. (Before that, he worked at... Apple.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aKqP82"&gt;Launched in 2014 as a reported effort to build an electric car, Apple eventually pivoted the project to focus on the self-driving technology stack. But recently, it seems to have pivoted back, striking up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261893/apple-electric-car-hyundai-ming-chi-kuo-rumor-report"&gt;conversations with major Asian automakers along the way&lt;/a&gt; (as well as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225026/apple-canoo-acquisition-investment-electric-car-goev"&gt;considering buying electric vehicle startup Canoo&lt;/a&gt;). At this point, though, it might as well exist in a quantum state to anyone not actually working on the project. Until it’s observed, the Apple Car is both everything and nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665353/apple-watch-kevin-lync-project-titan-electric-car"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665353/apple-watch-kevin-lync-project-titan-electric-car</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T15:45:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T15:45:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>This NVMe SD card is literally too hot to handle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jw1WRPp4ZX5j-o2UAgQkRe_i8pw=/0x5:1108x744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836337/anandtech_sd_express_card_too_hot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16938/silicon-motion-sm2708-sd-express-review-nvme-ssd-served-hot" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="34QXSL"&gt;When we say a gadget has “blazing-fast speeds,” we don’t mean it literally. But &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16938/silicon-motion-sm2708-sd-express-review-nvme-ssd-served-hot"&gt;when &lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt; benched&lt;/a&gt; one of the first NVMe-based SD card reference designs, it found the tiny plastic-covered rectangle hitting skin-searing temperatures of 96 degrees Celsius (roughly 205 degrees F). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sPVenU"&gt;Last year, we wrote how this next wave of SD cards — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/19/21264389/new-sd-express-card-specification-four-times-faster"&gt;SD Express&lt;/a&gt; — might quadruple their theoretical speed to nearly four gigabytes per second, by using the PCI-Express and NVMe interfaces more commonly found in the SSD in your computer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22608153/ps5-ssd-speed-test-storage-expansion-m2-playstation-5"&gt;or next-gen game console&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ICxskW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Theoretical speeds are theoretical, but this is still fast&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SRb149"&gt;We haven’t quite hit those speeds yet, anyhow: the specific card &lt;em&gt;AnandTech &lt;/em&gt;tested topped out at around 900MB/s writes and 400MB/s reads in raw sequential tests, and less in normal use. Besides, the Silicon Motion SM2708 controller is aimed at PCIe Gen 3x1 and PCIe Gen 3x2 for maximum speeds of around 985MB/s and 1,97MB/s, respectively, not the nearly 4GB/s speeds that a future controller might deliver with Gen 4x2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HJhIoe"&gt;That’s still faster than today’s SD cards, though, whose UHS-II variety tops out at around 300MB/s reads and very slightly slower writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4PoZaX"&gt;But those speeds may be beside the point if the card’s emitting tremendous amounts of heat inside your computer or camera. Hopefully that won’t be true of other cards (or other controllers, at least). For what it’s worth, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22545402/sony-alpha-1-a1-mirrorless-camera-review-specs-price-features-test"&gt;high-end cameras&lt;/a&gt; have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/14/21515666/nikon-z6-z7-ii-features-specs-price-4k-60fps"&gt;begun&lt;/a&gt; to standardize on the rival CFexpress format, which already claims gigabyte-plus reads and writes — though some users complain that &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=cfexpress+heat+site:www.dpreview.com&amp;amp;rlz=1C1GCEA_enUS968US968&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjl5u7R0fLyAhX-IzQIHVdvDhYQrQIoBHoECAcQBQ&amp;amp;biw=1024&amp;amp;bih=604"&gt;they get a little toasty&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cFji7"&gt;For now, you don’t have to worry about it: manufacturers are still working on their SD Express cards and readers. Last we checked, you can’t find them on shelves.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665216/sd-express-card-sm2708-nvme-heat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665216/sd-express-card-sm2708-nvme-heat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
