<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can still get free Stadia hardware when you buy Cyberpunk 2077</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/egGSH-qtyob_avyBRYXkMI8X6g4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68501523/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nKTJyf"&gt;It’s a different kind of Cyber week. Cyber Monday is in the past, but the anticipated &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; game has finally launched, and it’s almost &lt;em&gt;impossible &lt;/em&gt;to avoid seeing buzz about it online. One of this week’s best deals is aimed right at people who don’t have a console or a beastly gaming PC. The game is available on Google Stadia, and until supplies last, Google is offering a complimentary hardware bundle worth $100 to people who buy &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; on its cloud game streaming platform. Find details on this and a few more deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5WRnMf"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HfuM2f"&gt;Get Stadia hardware when you buy Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GOmCec"&gt;A few &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;writers found that playing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;actually a fantastic experience&lt;/a&gt; on Stadia, Google’s cloud gaming streaming service that doesn’t require an expensive console or PC — just a controller, a Gmail account, and a strong internet connection. While supplies last, people who buy the $59.99 game through Stadia will get a free Premiere Kit, containing a Stadia controller and a 4K HDR-ready Chromecast Ultra, which is all you need to play games from your TV. It’s a $100 value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VauDUc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9585191"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VJaIHn"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xfKlEt"&gt;Get six months of HBO Max for 20 percent off&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A promotional picture of Wonder Woman 1984" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ePKGrOkaB8tivzdSNnbsVOMze8g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19821876/wonder_woman.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Warner Bros.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="33tgfd"&gt;Warner Bros. recently announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;all of its 2021 films will be released on HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;, for 30 days, at the same time that they’re released in theaters. If that sounds appealing to you, there’s a deal happening that will let you save 20 percent when you prepay for six months of service. The $14.99 per month service would normally cost $90 after half a year, &lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;aff_sub=verge"&gt;but you can get it for $70&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hEG5M"&gt;Even if you’re in it for the movies alone, the price works out in your favor versus going to the theater. Though, note that this payment is nonrefundable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="NmMYaU"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zTiewp"&gt;Get a great VR headset for $100 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9VqI0M"&gt;Oculus has reduced the price of its Rift S tethered virtual reality headset by $100, making it $299. This is the biggest price cut yet and could be one of the last opportunities to pick it up since it’s technically discontinued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3attoz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221560"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="sXd4Ks"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="z52RXI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/12/22169431/cyberpunk-2077-google-stadia-deal-free-sale-hbo-max-oculus-rift-s-headset"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/12/22169431/cyberpunk-2077-google-stadia-deal-free-sale-hbo-max-oculus-rift-s-headset</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T23:52:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T23:52:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Get another glimpse inside the PlayStation 5 with iFixit’s new teardown</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The PS5’s pieces after being disassembled " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-mYu4OShJA-WX2f77wk14yuB-t8=/0x67:1600x1134/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500683/3MqFL2AQmEZugiii.huge.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eGwg8C"&gt;iFixit has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FTeardown%2FPlayStation%2B5%2BTeardown%2F138280%3Fvgo_ee%3D3bheJeT%252FPRsWKKl8dfWh0vlMy%252BOWWuyaZunZiCXh6gI%253D&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22170536%2Fifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;released its teardown of the PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt; and its DualSense controller — and it goes into even more detail than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505598/sony-ps5-playstation-5-tear-down-hardware"&gt;the one Sony did earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The gadget repair company discovered that the console has a ton of screws holding it together, and that there’s a weird catch to replacing the optical drive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An x-ray image of the Playstation 5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZbW9pl2FPKwHtX9Z_zSsS87cCEE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164030/mt1GGBDVuMOiI22J.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Creative Electron (via iFixit)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The company also released a always-fun X-ray of the PS5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="y91UFz"&gt;It turns out that the optical drive is software-locked to the motherboard. The physical swap is apparently a piece of cake, but any replacement you put in won’t read disks, so if your optical drive fails you’ll be sending it to Sony. It’s a bummer, especially for me: I’ve had terrible luck with PlayStation optical drives, and the only drive I haven’t had to replace is the one on my PS4 (which was only a few years old when I sold it). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYa5ZD"&gt;No sweat for the owners of the discless Digital edition, though — and as we’ve seen previously, adding an extra SSD is going to be easy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551165/sony-ps5-playstation-5-no-m2-ssd-expansion-launch"&gt;when the console finally supports it&lt;/a&gt;: it only involves unclipping a single side panel and taking out a screw.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The PS5’s power supply" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MhPu3s3lPkVqXaFDQr1PgePIbt8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164085/Qx2tDqSSJ6DC5inI.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O3Mg8c"&gt;The teardown also provides an inside look at the power supply (above), which Sony didn’t show us before. As someone who’s dabbled in PC gaming, it’s always shocking to me when I’m reminded of the PS5 only has a 350W power supply (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nRGNfqVvPtk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=287"&gt;and it uses as few as 200 of those watts&lt;/a&gt; under load!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A picture of the DualSense with the back taken off" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j35cEPc3CVTTPXvwxbrw6aq2T1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164070/eLQUaWaTxpN4JIWt.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To me, the inside of the controller looks nicer than Cyberpunk does on the console.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1DpKFs"&gt;Turning to the DualSense controller, iFixit found its battery is relatively easy to replace — which is good considering it still uses an internal Li-ion that’ll degrade over time. It’s also &lt;em&gt;massive &lt;/em&gt;at 5.7 watt-hours, compared to the 3.7Wh pack in the DualShock 4. Those adaptive triggers and haptic feedback motors must be thirsty. We also get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/3/21547303/sony-ps5-dualsense-adaptive-triggers-haptics-teardown-features"&gt;another look&lt;/a&gt; at the awesome screw drive that powers those adaptive triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZURv6J"&gt;What I don’t see is an easy way to unhook the LEDs that surround the DualSense’s touchpad. This may be a niche thing, but I absolutely hated the light on the DualShock 4, and while the new one isn’t as annoying, I still wish Sony would let you turn it off or let screwdriver-handy gamers unhook it without so much fuss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aR1e5T"&gt;You can head over &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FTeardown%2FPlayStation%2B5%2BTeardown%2F138280%3Fvgo_ee%3D3bheJeT%252FPRsWKKl8dfWh0vlMy%252BOWWuyaZunZiCXh6gI%253D&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22170536%2Fifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to iFixit’s teardown page to see far more photos&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want a feel for what taking apart the devices might be like (without risking what’s now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;effectively a $1,000 console&lt;/a&gt;), the company has provided videos of the teardowns that you can watch below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uxMQfB"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-rxy1rq2s8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="SH17fT"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/viqj_MWjb4I?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=2&amp;amp;start=2" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="WYRtsA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5: everything you need to know about Sony’s newest consoles","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21450334/playstation-5-ps5-sony-news-price-features-specs-hardware-games"},{"title":"Sony’s PS5 teardown video reveals removable sides, dust catchers, and storage expansion","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505598/sony-ps5-playstation-5-tear-down-hardware"},{"title":"Sony will optimize PS5 fan performance with software updates using individual game data","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/19/21522991/sony-ps5-fan-optimize-update-game-performance-data"},{"title":"The PS5’s new controller is amazing — here’s how it works","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/3/21547303/sony-ps5-dualsense-adaptive-triggers-haptics-teardown-features"},{"title":"Sony confirms the PS5 won’t support SSD storage expansion at launch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551165/sony-ps5-playstation-5-no-m2-ssd-expansion-launch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170536/ifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170536/ifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T21:28:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T21:28:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>FDA authorizes first COVID-19 vaccine in US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Coronavirus - Wed Dec 9, 2020" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xpQrz1zF16wvrwFHfnb9nqck9gc=/4x0:4492x2992/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500375/1230031767.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nurse in Belfast prepares a dose of the vaccine.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Liam McBurney / PA Images via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5A4HDt"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration has &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/144412/download"&gt;authorized &lt;/a&gt;the use of a COVID-19 vaccine developed by Pfizer and BioNTech, a landmark moment in the fight to suppress a virus that has killed nearly 300,000 people in the United States and sickened tens of millions around the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Zfj5m"&gt;“Today’s emergency use authorization of the Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 Vaccine holds the promise to alter the course of this pandemic in the United States,” Peter Marks, director of the FDA’s Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-takes-key-action-fight-against-covid-19-issuing-emergency-use-authorization-first-covid-19"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Z6n2O"&gt;The vaccine is authorized in the US for people over the age of 16. It was found to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573072/pfizer-vaccine-effective-authorization-fda-safe"&gt;95 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; at preventing symptomatic COVID-19 in clinical trials. “That is extraordinary,” Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nowthisnews/status/1333146966985908224"&gt;said in a press conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of November. It’s far better than experts had dared hope for. The FDA was prepared to authorize a vaccine as long as it was at least 50 percent effective. “We were shocked,” Pfizer’s chief executive officer, Albert Bourla, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/21/us/politics/coronavirus-vaccine.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We couldn’t believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEFgKD"&gt;The shot appears to protect people against the most severe forms of the disease. It is also highly effective in people over the age of 65, who are particularly vulnerable to COVID-19. Scientists will continue to monitor the vaccine after it’s deployed to see how well it works in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NquwhR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Scientists will continue to monitor the vaccine after it’s deployed&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cqNna2"&gt;The news of the clearance comes at the same time that the FDA has faced public pressure from the White House to authorize the vaccine. Chief of Staff Mark Meadows told Stephen Hahn, the commissioner of the FDA, to resign if the vaccine was not cleared by Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/12/11/trump-stephen-hahn-fda-covid-vaccine/"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The agency had originally planned to complete the authorization by Saturday. On Thursday, an independent committee said it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168565/covid-19-vaccine-independent-committee-recommends-authorization"&gt;recommended authorization&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kAeSxQ"&gt;The Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine has already been authorized by regulatory authorities in the United Kingdom, Canada, and Bahrain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YUchFa"&gt;The authorizations of this vaccine, which have come less than a year after development began, shatter the record for the fastest vaccine developed. The record was previously held by the mumps vaccine, which took four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ttI8Gt"&gt;Researchers were able to condense the normally years-long vaccine development process into months by, among other steps, shortening the time between clinical trial phases and scaling up manufacturing of potential candidates as trials were ongoing. Companies did not skip steps in the safety testing process, though. The FDA said that it needed to see &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/10/06/health/fda-covid-vaccine-safety-data-bn/index.html"&gt;two full months&lt;/a&gt; of safety data on any COVID-19 vaccine because that’s the window when most dangerous side effects could occur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2wJm2K"&gt;The vaccine will be made available under an Emergency Use Authorization, a designation that lets the FDA make products available during an emergency situation when there are no other options available. The process lets the agency sidestep some of the more lengthy regulatory steps it usually needs to formally approve or license a pharmaceutical. It typically takes the FDA a &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/2772943"&gt;full year&lt;/a&gt; to review vaccine data once it’s submitted by companies. For this emergency authorization, that was condensed to a few weeks; Pfizer and BioNTech submitted their data on November 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tsu4jG"&gt;The Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine is made from a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562309/pfizer-coronavirus-vaccine-gene-based"&gt;gene-based technology&lt;/a&gt; that’s never been used before in an authorized vaccine for people. It contains a tiny bit of the genetic material for the coronavirus spike protein, which the virus uses to enter cells. The body builds that spike protein from the genetic instructions and then generates defenses against it. The Moderna vaccine, which the FDA’s vaccine advisory committee will review on December 17th, also uses this technology. The platform is another reason why the vaccine was developed so quickly — once researchers have the genetic sequence of a virus, it’s relatively easy to design a gene-based vaccine to attack it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gsMPJY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Now starts an equally daunting task: distributing the vaccine and vaccinating people. &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yc9zGf"&gt;Now starts an equally daunting task: distributing the vaccine and vaccinating people. Pfizer’s vaccine has to stay at ultracold temperatures, which makes shipping it around the country and the world more challenging. Doses of the vaccine will also be limited through the start of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MKEwX3"&gt;Health care workers and residents in long-term care facilities will be the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21779433/covid-vaccine-priority-health-care-workers-long-term-care"&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; to receive the vaccine, and doses could be administered within days. Other high-risk groups, including older adults and people with underlying health conditions, will likely be next in line. On the most optimistic timeline, vaccinations for the general population could start in March or April, but hospitals say that some of those timelines &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/07/pledge-to-vaccinate-20-million-against-covid19-in-december-seems-unrealistic/"&gt;seem unrealistic&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flmYG0"&gt;The US has purchased 100 million doses of the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine, enough to vaccinate 50 million people. The Trump administration &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/feds-pfizer-vaccine-doses-covid-19-88fd7c59fd0af8669ed3cdafdf08881e"&gt;reportedly declined&lt;/a&gt; an offer to secure an additional 100 million doses this summer. Although the US can acquire up to 500 million more doses, the rejected offer means they may not be available until the summer. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T20:55:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T20:55:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s long-struggling developers will see their bonuses after all</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iqRGhnhlDruA7bdIQQXbCG_xF1E=/65x0:299x156/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500312/screen_image_mercenary_01_1x_20ad7dfe.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6J9IwN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, CD Projekt Red’s latest game,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;has been in development for nearly a decade. It was first announced &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2012/05/30/cd-projekt-red-announces-cyberpunk"&gt;in May 2012&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s had a rocky development cycle, with numerous delays and, in the final stretch of development, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494499/cyberpunk-2077-development-crunch-time-cd-projekt-red"&gt;a required six-day workweek&lt;/a&gt;. But despite the long development, the game didn’t review quite as well as CDPR wanted, meaning developers who had been toiling for years could have been on the brink of losing performance bonuses that were tied to review scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9JoqP"&gt;The studio’s developers won’t have to worry about review scores anymore, though: CDPR will now pay full performance bonuses regardless of the critical reception of the game, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-11/cd-projekt-changes-developer-bonus-structure-after-buggy-release"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8Ji7y4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We underestimated the lengths and complexity involved to make this a reality”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gql0RN"&gt;“We initially had a bonus system that was focused on the game’s ratings and the release date, but after consideration, we believe that measure is simply not fair under the circumstances,” Adam Badowski, studio head and creative director for &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, said in an email to staff obtained by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;. “We underestimated the lengths and complexity involved to make this a reality, and still you did everything you could to deliver an ambitious, special game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kU3wV5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; received favorable reviews this week — it currently has a &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pc/cyberpunk-2077"&gt;Metacritic score&lt;/a&gt; of 90 out of 100, which typically indicates that a game is very good. By contrast, some of the top games of this year &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game"&gt;edge it out&lt;/a&gt; with Metacritic scores in the low 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6PGsA9"&gt;But reviewers &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2020-12-11-cyberpunk-2077-launches-with-some-real-dystopia-in-tow-opinion"&gt;reportedly weren’t&lt;/a&gt; given review code for the console versions of the game, and there are now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;numerous reports&lt;/a&gt; of bugs and issues when playing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; on older consoles. Given the current problems players are now finding, &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077’s&lt;/em&gt; Metacritic score could easily fall below 90 as more publications post reviews. If it falls below that score, developers wouldn’t have received their bonuses under the previous system, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ODYEh4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEWS: CD Projekt executives took responsibility for Cyberpunk's buggy launch in an email to staff today, saying this year's performance bonuses will no longer be tied to review scores, given the circumstances. Before, the threshold was 90+ on Metacritic &lt;a href="https://t.co/poW86s3xaf"&gt;https://t.co/poW86s3xaf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jason Schreier (@jasonschreier) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1337555816417800194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tLSTEQ"&gt;CDPR leaders would hand out tokens every month to staffers who went above and beyond, and those tokens were supposed to be transferrable into bonuses if the game met “certain criteria, like critical acclaim and a timely release,” according to the report. Now, though, it sounds as if all staffers will get their performance bonuses no matter where the review score lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Hcc2y"&gt;CDPR didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IWpXRl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; has been a big retail success, despite the reviews and buggy release. It sold more than 8 million preorders, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED_IR/status/1336941257965375489"&gt;according to CDPR&lt;/a&gt;, completely making back its development and marketing budget on day one. It also broke Steam’s concurrent player record for a single-player PC game, with more than one million concurrent players &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteamDB/status/1336924375212318721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1336924375212318721%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2Fcyberpunk-2077-beats-steam-record-for-concurrent-players-121942545.html"&gt;on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rGOko4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077’s 1.04 patch makes changes to reduce epilepsy risk ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 is huge, ambitious, and safe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 shines on next-gen consoles and Stadia, but older hardware struggles","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WCRrOq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o1KPok"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y0HLFR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yu9zUX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5kC556"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170655/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-developers-staff-bonuses-review-score"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170655/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-developers-staff-bonuses-review-score</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T19:50:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T19:50:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s 1.04 patch makes changes to reduce epilepsy risk </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Keanu Reeves as Johnny Silverhand in Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sqwbO3hybpPsHl1RcUwLfqjDIrc=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500166/Cyberpunk2077_No_Future_RGB.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V5X0px"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; developer CD Projekt Red (CDPR) is rolling out an update to the game that could reduce the potential for some sequences to induce epileptic symptoms. The risks of seizure were brought to light by &lt;em&gt;Game Informer&lt;/em&gt; editor Liana Ruppert &lt;a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2020/12/07/cyberpunk-2077-epileptic-psa"&gt;earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;. The 1.04 hotfix is &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37043/hotfix-1-04"&gt;now live&lt;/a&gt; on PlayStation consoles and PC, and CDPR is working to have the update out “as soon as possible” on Xbox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5YixaT"&gt;CDPR says it has changed the way its “braindance” sequences look. During these sequences, a device is placed in front of your character’s eyes that flashes red and white lights. The effect is similar to what actual neurologists do to trigger seizures for diagnoses, according to Ruppert, who reported that she suffered an epileptic episode when she played the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qOBxGW"&gt;The flashing effect during braindances has been “smoothed out and the flashes reduced in frequency and magnitude,” according to CDPR’s patch notes. Ruppert said she worked with the studio this week to help test the fix. “I think this will help MANY epileptics and non-epileptics feel safer in #Cyberpunk2077,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DirtyEffinHippy/status/1337511117535518721"&gt;Ruppert said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oJIVLq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I've been staying off of socials today but I am so thrilled to see this change! I worked with CDPR earlier this week to test some braindance animations and I think this will help MANY epileptics and non-epileptics feel safer in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cyberpunk2077?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Cyberpunk2077&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@CDPROJEKTRED&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href="https://t.co/KUOVFJGFmA"&gt;https://t.co/KUOVFJGFmA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Liana Ruppert (@DirtyEffinHippy) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DirtyEffinHippy/status/1337511117535518721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PIzFwU"&gt;The update has many other fixes, including one for an issue where some copyrighted songs would play even when a player had toggled a setting to disable copyrighted music from playing. CDPR had warned streamers to turn off all music in the game &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168295/cyberpunk-2077-twitch-dmca-copyright-strike-music-turn-off-bug"&gt;on Thursday&lt;/a&gt; as a temporary workaround to avoid potentially triggering a DMCA strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6WedJ"&gt;Despite &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077’s&lt;/em&gt; many early issues, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;reports of poor performance on older consoles&lt;/a&gt;, the game has been a huge financial success so far. CDPR has already earned back the total costs of development and marketing purely through digital pre-orders, according to a document on CDPR’s investor site (&lt;a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2020/12/current-report-no-652020.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). The game had more than eight million preorders, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED_IR/status/1336941257965375489"&gt;CDPR announced on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HoRy1A"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; also smashed Steam’s concurrent player record for a single-player game, peaking at more than 1 million concurrent players on Thursday, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteamDB/status/1336924375212318721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1336924375212318721%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2Fcyberpunk-2077-beats-steam-record-for-concurrent-players-121942545.html"&gt;according to SteamDB&lt;/a&gt;. That figure more than doubled the previous record held by &lt;em&gt;Fallout 4&lt;/em&gt;, which had a peak of more than 470,000 concurrent players &lt;a href="https://steamdb.info/app/377160/graphs/"&gt;in 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7F0kM2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 is huge, ambitious, and safe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 shines on next-gen consoles and Stadia, but older hardware struggles","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T18:48:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T18:48:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Familiars.io is a simple, Pokémon-style multiplayer game that you can play right inside Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Screenshot from Familiars, a game by Nigel Nelson" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/USb9cCXVRpETBwkoG3fWi7KYpZQ=/0x35:1490x1028/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68499910/Screen_Shot_2020_12_11_at_6.31.26_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kdXO8M"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.familiars.io/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Familiars.io&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a minimalist monster-catching game that went online &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClayLoam/status/1170922830076100608"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, and right now, you can play it inside Twitter. As developer Nigel Nelson &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClayLoam/status/1337488664243277824"&gt;tweeted this afternoon&lt;/a&gt;, he ported (or in his words, “smuggled”) the entire game to an embedded Twitter card. That means that you can play it directly through Twitter’s web interface or mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6nOxW"&gt;The game is built around &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt;-style exploration and combat in a shared, lo-fi setting. You can wander around capturing enemies to expand your team of familiars, then use them to fight other players (or simply walk around saying “howdy,” if you prefer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LFO8JI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;just smuggled my ENTIRE GAME into this "video" embed tweet, enjoy &lt;a href="https://t.co/tYhXidt2Ur"&gt;https://t.co/tYhXidt2Ur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;—      ʟ5    (@ClayLoam) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClayLoam/status/1337488664243277824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SpGe0V"&gt;“Me and my brother used to do this thing where we would start new games on &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Red and Blue&lt;/em&gt;, progress through the game as fast as we could in a 3-hour period, and then fight each other with our pokémon teams,” Nelson says. “A year ago I was looking for a new project, and my brother suggested that a multiplayer &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt;-like PVP experience might be fun, and I thought it was a great idea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bWnxn3"&gt;The game’s Twitter version won’t necessarily be online for long. &lt;em&gt;Familiars.io &lt;/em&gt;is using the Player Cards that Twitter offers for linear media, and Twitter &lt;a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-for-websites/cards/overview/player-card"&gt;admonishes users&lt;/a&gt; to not “circumvent the intended use of the Card” with interactive experiences. In 2015, Twitter disabled &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/may/04/twitter-kills-ms-dos-games-embedded-in-tweets"&gt;embedding classic MS-DOS games&lt;/a&gt; in tweets. But the game has nonetheless taken off on the platform. Nelson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that he’s seen about 3,000 logins and 250 players online at a time, compared to a standard user base of one or two people. “I’ve had a few ideas for new fun things to add, but I think I might need to take a step back to figure out how to make my servers accommodate the increased player base,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nv3PRD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Familiars.io&lt;/em&gt; is a hobby and a work in progress; some users have tweeted reports of bugs, particularly on Firefox. But I’ve enjoyed the illicit thrill of Twitter gaming on desktop Chrome and Android’s Twitter app just fine — and &lt;em&gt;Familiars.io&lt;/em&gt; itself isn’t going anywhere. If the game gets taken off Twitter, its virtual world is still &lt;a href="https://www.familiars.io/"&gt;available on the web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170499/familiars-io-monster-catching-pokemon-style-multiplayer-game-play-inside-twitter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170499/familiars-io-monster-catching-pokemon-style-multiplayer-game-play-inside-twitter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T18:03:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T18:03:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Norman Abramson, a father of modern wireless networks, dies at 88</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1t09fEf5VzKp5XP8qiYl5GSPEGk=/52x0:624x381/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68499737/manoa_engineering_in_memorial_norm_abramson.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: University of Hawaii at Manoa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qrn2iH"&gt;Norman Abramson, one of the pioneers behind wireless networks, has died at 88, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/11/technology/norman-abramson-dead.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Abramson and the team of graduate students and faculty he led were responsible for creating ALOHAnet, an early wireless network whose innovative techniques are still being used today in modern satellite, phone, and computer networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vQhZTz"&gt;Abramson died of skin cancer that had metastasized in his lungs, according to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UHANGi"&gt;An engineer and student of communications theory — a discipline at the intersection of mathematics, information theory, and semiotics — Abramson studied at Harvard, and he received a master’s at UCLA and a PhD from Stanford. He was drawn to Hawaii partly because of his love of surfing, and in 1966, took a faculty position at the University of Hawai’i (UH) Mānoa’s College of Engineering. He rose to become chair of the school’s information and computer sciences department before retiring after three decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rgPbWx"&gt;Hawaii helped give Abramson’s seminal project its name: ALOHAnet was created by Abramson and his collaborator Franklin Kuo, while teaching at UH. Like the wired ARPAnet, which served as the basis for the internet, ALOHAnet was designed as a system to connect UH to other colleges and universities to share research. It delivered packets of data over radio channels more efficiently by not needing to schedule a transmission. If a data packet wasn’t received, it would be sent again. Some of the ideas that originated in the ALOHAnet project would go on to be used in the development of Wi-Fi and Ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5lW7aH"&gt;“There are very few people who had as significant an impact as Norm on the way the entire planet communicates and shares information today,” University of Hawai’i president David Lassner said in &lt;a href="https://www.hawaii.edu/news/2020/12/04/in-memoriam-norman-abramson/"&gt;a memorial posted on the college’s blog&lt;/a&gt;. “Norm linked the islands of Hawaiʻi to each other and to the world, leaving a legacy at UH and beyond through his ideas and his students.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hRZiZx"&gt;Abramson is survived by his wife, son, and three grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vtNDI1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170330/norman-abramson-alohanet-wirless-network-dies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170330/norman-abramson-alohanet-wirless-network-dies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T17:38:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T17:38:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft really recorded a Christmas carol with the words ‘Bingle Bells’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m6CDqmsLk5ql2XGMBSTZC_YIJ98=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68499567/Screen_Shot_2020_12_11_at_1.50.51_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yI5ypq"&gt;Microsoft tweeted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/microsoft/status/1337509023277584385?s=21"&gt;a fake commercial&lt;/a&gt; for a pretend holiday album called &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Holiday Hits&lt;/em&gt;, a not-real, four-CD album that claims it features “60 festive favorites.” I want to reiterate that &lt;em&gt;this is not a real album&lt;/em&gt; — but the company actually went to the effort to record tidbits of Microsoft-themed versions of classic Christmas carols anyway for the lols. I dearly love puns, dad humor, and terrible jokes, but even I groaned at some of what Microsoft did here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3P8F99"&gt;Here are the lyrics to one eye-rolling carol:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="IKFET7"&gt;Joy to the Word / spellcheck is done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ujc8Tk"&gt;It fixed all of my stuff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="2bMcDA"&gt;Or how about this classic? I look forward to hearing your collective sighs of despair over the Internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="TLVI9g"&gt;Please Mute Ye Merry Gentlemen / You’re talking far too loud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujyMZ3"&gt;We’re trying to have a meeting / You’re yelling in a crowd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="A893xg"&gt;But by far the worst offender is “Bingle Bells,” which is somehow actually stuck in my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8ltUaK"&gt;Bingle Bells, Bingle Bells / Bing goes all the way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zctmb9"&gt;Oh what fun it is to surf the World Wide Web today, hey &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0PkwA8"&gt;I have to give Microsoft some credit for some of the fictional song titles, though. “Deck the halls with ‘90s Clip Art” sounds like a great theme for a holiday party. “Windows Wonderland” is actually pretty clever. “Let it Segoe! Let it Segoe! Let it Segoe!” made me do that thing where you breathe quickly through your nose when you read something funny online. And the whole video is presented in the style of an old Christmas-themed infomercial, which is charming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxD3yZ"&gt;You should just watch Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/microsoft/status/1337509023277584385?s=21"&gt;one minute and fifteen second ad&lt;/a&gt; for this fake album for yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rxl6tR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Reply All Records presents: Microsoft Holiday Hits. The great selection of holiday songs EVER assembled.    &lt;a href="https://t.co/Ml0lIqGeEt"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Ml0lIqGeEt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Microsoft (@Microsoft) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Microsoft/status/1337509023277584385?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b1DFJu"&gt;Microsoft has been on something of a holiday advertising blitz this year. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21779499/microsoft-windows-ugly-sweater-paint-xp-95-girls-who-code"&gt;The company sold&lt;/a&gt; MS Paint and Windows-themed ugly sweaters online, but as of this writing, &lt;a href="https://gear.xbox.com/pages/windows?ocid=Evergreen_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_buy_HolidaySweater"&gt;they’re sold out&lt;/a&gt;. An Xbox ad from earlier this week, which I should note was a short film made by &lt;em&gt;Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt; director Taika Waititi, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/7/22158941/xbox-series-x-s-ad-master-chief-dj-cat-taika-waititi-short-film"&gt;featured Master Chief as a DJ cat&lt;/a&gt;. Another holiday ad featured dogs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150065/microsoft-holiday-2020-commercial-dogs-halo-minecraft-flight-simulator"&gt;frolicking in &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qymx0u"&gt;You can certainly say Microsoft’s ads have been memorable, which I guess is the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gJJECd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft is selling ugly Windows sweaters, and part of the proceeds benefit Girls Who Code","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21779499/microsoft-windows-ugly-sweater-paint-xp-95-girls-who-code"},{"title":"Master Chief is a DJ cat in Taika Waititi’s Xbox short film","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/7/22158941/xbox-series-x-s-ad-master-chief-dj-cat-taika-waititi-short-film"},{"title":"Microsoft’s best commercial features dogs frolicking in Halo, Minecraft, and Flight Simulator","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150065/microsoft-holiday-2020-commercial-dogs-halo-minecraft-flight-simulator"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22170391/microsoft-christmas-holiday-carol-album-bingle-bells-ad"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22170391/microsoft-christmas-holiday-carol-album-bingle-bells-ad</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T17:31:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T17:31:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can now use Google Assistant features with more wired headphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="google assistant on the pixel" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/stHO3fXNJcad8unmvobdbP0pUog=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68499543/google-pixel-phone-8793.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Google Assistant on a Google Pixel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8xJqdb"&gt;While many new wireless headphones and earbuds are already equipped with support for virtual assistants, Google has extended that convenience to more users of wired headphones. As &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/12/04/google-assistant-headphones-wired/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out, it’s now possible to quickly access Google Assistant features on an Android phone using 3.5mm and USB-C headphones that were previously unsupported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X79eg1"&gt;Until now, Google Assistant integration was limited to wireless or wired options “optimized for Google Assistant support.” The company’s USB-C Pixel Buds were one of a few wired headphones to offer rich, hands-free integration with Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CprijK"&gt;That’s no longer the case: plugging in a set of “non-optimized” wired headphones will now trigger a notification indicating that you can summon Google Assistant by pressing the action button on your headphones. You’ll be able to set timers, create calendar appointments, and hear notifications without having to tap on your phone screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YXZKhL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Set timers, create calendar appointments, and hear notifications without tapping your phone screen&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ThaTpR"&gt;I got it working with a pair of 3.5mm Apple EarPods (a relic!) and a Pixel 4A running Android 11 with the November security update. Sure enough, Google Assistant can be summoned with a long press of the in-line action button, allowing me to set and cancel timers and create and cancel calendar appointments, all without touching the phone screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KnbfFt"&gt;Naturally, this is an update that will apply to a dwindling number of wired headphone users (solidarity, y’all), but it’s a nice one if you happen to fall into that group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m2pd6Y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170015/google-assistant-android-wired-headphones-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170015/google-assistant-android-wired-headphones-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T16:31:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T16:31:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this story about schools buying FBI-grade phone-hacking tech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4pK877oJfryJ4B8LCGF-bsEGOlM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68499216/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FDxYpO"&gt;If you were worried about sending your kids back to school after the pandemic ends (or if you are a kid worrying about going back to school), I’m afraid &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/u-s-schools-are-buying-phone-hacking-tech-that-the-fbi-1845862393"&gt;this &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; article&lt;/a&gt; is not going to help. Tom McKay and Dhruv Mehrotra have done a fantastic job reporting about how some US school districts are buying tools designed to break into phones to download texts and photos… even ones that have been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="U7Vg38"&gt;While companies like Cellebrite have partnered with federal and local police for years, that the controversial equipment is also available for school district employees to search students’ personal devices has gone relatively unnoticed—and serves as a frightening reminder of how technology originally developed for use by the military or intelligence services, ranging from blast-armored trucks designed for &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-san-diego-military-vehicle-20140918-story.html"&gt;use in war zones&lt;/a&gt; to invasive surveillance tools, keeps trickling down to domestic police and even the institutions where our kids go to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="aNFVba"&gt;The devices are also expensive. The &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; reporters found some school districts that had spent up to $12,000 on the tech, which was designed for use in war zones and police investigations. Commenting on the devices, Cooper Quintin of the Electronic Frontier Foundation says that they “started out in the provenance of the U.S. military or federal law enforcement, and then made their way into state and local law enforcement, and also eventually make their way into the hands of criminals or petty tyrants like school administrators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSKYqr"&gt;Unlike in law enforcement, though, school districts don’t have to get a warrant to use the devices on students’ phones. The Supreme Court ruled that school officials only need to reasonably believe that a student is guilty of something and that searching the phone will probably obtain evidence of it. &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/u-s-schools-are-buying-phone-hacking-tech-that-the-fbi-1845862393"&gt;The article goes into detail&lt;/a&gt; about the many legal issues involved and how students don’t necessarily have the right to say no, so you should definitely take some time to dig into it. Just have something nearby that you can use to help lower your blood pressure when you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170292/gizmodo-schools-fbi-grade-phone-hacking-surveillance-tech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170292/gizmodo-schools-fbi-grade-phone-hacking-surveillance-tech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
