<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-19T12:40:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T12:40:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:40:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Pixel 6 and 6 Pro launch event live blog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro lineup" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3YgsF1z4R1qUrFipuIgnquXaxGU=/448x0:7198x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70016057/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The biggest Pixel in years — literally&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="8lbYBY"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors"&gt;leaks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;pre-annoucements&lt;/a&gt;, ads and yet &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu"&gt;more leaks&lt;/a&gt;, the time has come for Google to officially launch the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro. We already know many details: the custom &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Tensor processor&lt;/a&gt; that powers it, the colors and many of the specs, and even some of the software features have all been officially announced. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/9/22718007/google-pixel-6-leak-teases-magic-eraser-camera-five-years-android-security-updates"&gt;rumors have filled in more details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7Wplu"&gt;But there will be more to hear from Google. This is easily the most important Pixel the company has launched in years, it’s a launch where the company says it is taking on flagships from Apple and Samsung at the high end. Google hasn’t really talked big game about its phones before, so even if we’ve seen a lot of rumors, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; Google goes about making this launch happen will be interesting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rKj7Ak"&gt;We’ll likely get a deeper dive into the specs on these phones, including whether the new camera system really is good enough to justify the massive camera ledge on the backs of these phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RdCxGr"&gt;We’ll be live blogging the event alongside our other extensive coverage of the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro, so watch along as we watch Google finally try to step up to the big leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F8gUx1"&gt;Google Pixel 6 live blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="BDLczB"&gt;&lt;div class="live-center-embed" data-src="https://livecenter.norkon.net/frame/voxmedia/17674/vox"&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;(function(n){function c(t,i){n[e](h,function(n){var r,u;if(n&amp;&amp;(r=n[n.message?"message":"data"]+"",r&amp;&amp;r.substr&amp;&amp;r.substr(0,3)==="nc:")&amp;&amp;(u=r.split(":"),u[1]===i))switch(u[2]){case"h":t.style.height=u[3]+"px";return;case"scrolltotop":t.scrollIntoView();return}},!1)}for(var t,u,f,i,s,e=n.addEventListener?"addEventListener":"attachEvent",h=e==="attachEvent"?"onmessage":"message",o=n.document.querySelectorAll(".live-center-embed"),r=0;r&lt;o.length;r++)(t=o[r],t.getAttribute("data-rendered"))||(u=t.getAttribute("data-src"),u&amp;&amp;(t.setAttribute("data-rendered","true"),f=n.ncVizCounter||1e3,n.ncVizCounter=f+1,i=f+"",s="nc-frame-c-"+i,t.innerHTML='&lt;div style="position: relative; height: 300px; border: none;" id="'+s+'"&gt;&lt;iframe src="'+u+"?"+i+'" style="position: absolute; left: 0; top: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; fullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;',c(t.firstChild,i)))})(window);&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="emq4hZ"&gt;Watch the Google Pixel 6 launch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="az887K"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WNarpiGz3Kk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733532/google-pixel-6-pro-event-live-blog"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733532/google-pixel-6-pro-event-live-blog</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Wyze’s new Video Doorbell Pro costs $65 and promises six months of battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YvEcmvSCQo3EtucvoqgBZfJsovI=/0x0:3954x2636/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015985/04.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wyze’s Video Doorbell Pro promises up to 6 months of battery life&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Wyze&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AtUhsg"&gt;Smart home company Wyze has revealed its latest category-breaking device, and this time, it’s going straight for Ring’s lunch with an impressive-sounding video doorbell that checks pretty much all the right boxes. Except maybe the “cool style and nice design” one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2SKTF"&gt;Available for preorders on October 19th and shipping in December, the &lt;a href="https://wyze.com/wyze-video-doorbell-pro.html"&gt;Wyze Video Doorbell Pro costs $65&lt;/a&gt; (plus shipping), can be installed fully wired or wire-free, has up to six months of battery life, and a 1:1 aspect ratio that can take in your entire front porch. It records and streams video in 1440 x 1440 HD and offers 12-second clip playback for motion and sound events for free. The recordings are stored in Wyze’s cloud; there is no local storage option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0JHPoA"&gt;The doorbell comes with a Wyze wireless Chime, which offers 20 different ringtones. In addition, the Doorbell Pro will work on 2.4GHz and 5GHz Wi-Fi. If you want smart notifications — like person, animal, or package detection — you will need to sign up for Wyze’s Cam Plus service (which starts from $1.49 a month). This also adds unlimited video length recording and takes away the 5-minute cool-down period (during which time the camera won’t record after it finished the last recording).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ilYS_fWLeYEBpV-CjG_Ocm7VA8g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938885/01.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Wyze&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wyze’s new doorbell comes with a wireless plug-in chime so you can hear your doorbell ring inside your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="K5KwtA"&gt;The downside here is that because the battery is built in, you will have to take it down to charge it (via a USB cable). But if you are able to hard-wire it, with 16- to 24-volt wiring, the doorbell will work off wired power, rather than just trickle-charging from the battery. This adds the ability to capture an extra 3-6 seconds of pre-roll video before an event, meaning you’re less likely to miss a visitor who buzzes and runs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bfJteL"&gt;Also, Wyze told me that the doorbell won’t work with existing electronic doorbell chimes; you have to use the included wireless one. And the company says certifications for Alexa and Google Assistant compatibility are under development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qb20Bz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://wyze.com/wyze-doorbell.html"&gt;Wyze’s current video doorbell &lt;/a&gt;costs $50 (plus shipping) and offers 1080p HD video with a 3:4 aspect ratio. It is hard-wired only and doesn’t support 5GHz Wi-Fi. The closest Ring comparison is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252181/ring-video-doorbell-new-wired-size-features-price"&gt;Ring Video Doorbell Wired&lt;/a&gt;, which costs $79.99 with a wireless Chime included but doesn’t have the option of battery power. For a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21249028/ring-video-doorbell-specs-price-date"&gt;battery-powered Ring&lt;/a&gt;, the next option is $100 without the Chime — but Ring’s doorbells will work with an existing mechanical chime. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jHrJvk"&gt;However, Wyze hasn’t managed to be the cheapest in the market this time. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698612/amazon-blink-video-doorbell-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-panel"&gt;Blink announced a $50 wired and battery-powered doorbell&lt;/a&gt; last month that can run for up to two years on two AA lithium batteries. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734238/wyze-video-doorbell-pro-price-specs-shipping"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734238/wyze-video-doorbell-pro-price-specs-shipping</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T12:22:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:22:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>The new MacBook Pros have one big question mark: battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gqh_ToGRXYPcvFG0NBU8EADjT9o=/240x0:2640x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015925/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_8.43.20_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JmfhOe"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;new MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;are here&lt;/a&gt;, and they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"&gt;may actually live up to the “Pro” moniker&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s one big question that comes with the new sizes and processors: how’s the battery life? To hear Apple tell it, it’s going to be great — the company even &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/exM1uajp--A?t=2638"&gt;said onstage&lt;/a&gt; that the 16-inch had the best battery life ever, besting last year’s M1 Macs (which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558095/apple-silicon-m1-chip-arm-macs-soc-charge-power-efficiency-mobile-processor"&gt;also boasted would have the longest-lived batteries&lt;/a&gt;). But the metric Apple used to back up that claim is a bit suspect, and its other numbers tell a very different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEPp25"&gt;In its keynote and &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-unveils-game-changing-macbook-pro/"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, Apple says the 14-inch MacBook Pro will provide 17 hours of video playback and estimates that the 16-inch model can last for an unprecedented-for-Macs 21 hours. But using video playback as a measure of battery life is really only useful if you’re trying to sell a particular narrative — not if you just want to let people know how long their laptops will actually last. For one, Apple says these figures are derived from watching a movie using the Apple TV app. That’s not generally what people use their laptops for unless they’re marathoning the &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; extended cuts. Plus, modern CPUs have so much silicon dedicated to video playback that it’s almost become effortless for them. It’s a battery flex, not a battery test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V4vz8j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In a more realistic test, the 14-inch MacBook Pro doesn’t beat the Air — those numbers didn’t make it onstage&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zvAbe0"&gt;That point is backed up by the fact that Apple’s more realistic wireless web test tells a very different story. Apple says the test involves browsing 25 popular websites using Wi-Fi, with screen brightness set to “8 clicks from bottom.” Under these conditions, the 16-inch MacBook Pro fails to beat even the M1 MacBook Air — it only gets 14 hours of life compared to the Air’s 15 hours. Apple’s estimate for the new 14-inch is 11 hours, the same as the 2020 &lt;em&gt;Intel&lt;/em&gt; MacBook Air. Even this unflattering test (for the new MacBooks, not the old ones) has limitations: last we heard, Apple runs it using its own Safari browser instead of the more popular (and, according to macOS’s Activity Monitor, more energy-hungry) Chrome. Plus, some websites will drain your battery much faster than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKkaaD"&gt;In terms of hard numbers, the 14-inch MacBook Pro has a 70 watt-hour battery, and the 16-inch takes it all the way up to &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/hazmat/packsafe/more_info/?hazmat=7"&gt;the FAA limit&lt;/a&gt; of 100Wh (the 13-inch M1 MacBook Pro has a 58.2 Wh battery, for comparison). Again, though, these metrics only tell us so much. The 16-inch Intel-based MacBook also had a 100Wh battery, and it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features"&gt;only provided around eight hours of usage&lt;/a&gt;, despite Apple’s quoted 11-hour battery life. Plus, Apple is quoting three hours &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; battery life for the 14-inch than the 13-inch, despite the new laptop having a bigger battery. Yes, that number’s not based on a great metric, but that’s also not necessarily a good sign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M0fVMvkIsOc2hZlL52jl2DPTszI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937340/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_4.33.22_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple quotes less runtime for the 14-inch MBP than the 13-inch one, despite the roughly 20 percent bigger battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NXKL80"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558095/apple-silicon-m1-chip-arm-macs-soc-charge-power-efficiency-mobile-processor"&gt;pulled this same trick last year&lt;/a&gt;, but it almost didn’t matter — the ARM processors lasted so much longer than Intel’s that we were willing to let it slide that the MacBook Air probably wouldn’t actually reach Apple’s estimated 18 hours of battery life. This year, Apple is setting even higher expectations for battery life, even though the new laptops are supposed to be significantly more powerful. It just seems unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bZJKwE"&gt;The MacBook Pro 14- and 16-inch have to feed more power-hungry (in relative terms, at least) performance cores, and they have fewer efficient cores to make use of when you’re doing light work like checking email or browsing a website or two. The standard M1 has four performance and four efficiency cores, where the M1 Pro and Max only have two efficiency cores, having traded in the rest for more performance ones: the cut-down eight-core M1 Pro that comes with the base 14-inch laptop has six performance cores, while the 10-core full M1 Pro and M1 Max have eight performance cores. They also have more powerful GPUs — the old M1 has 7 or 8 GPU cores; the new versions are rocking 14 to 32. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sZcZYF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Different numbers of CPU and GPU cores could also affect battery life&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hoc6ao"&gt;On top of that, the 14- and 16-inch laptops have what Apple calls an “advanced thermal architecture,” which includes an extra fan. Will that make a big impact? Will Apple be able to beat the original M1’s extra efficiency cores using sheer battery size? We simply won’t know until we can test these laptops in the real world — stay tuned for that in our upcoming reviews. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbmERv"&gt;Great battery life has been the biggest story of Apple’s M1 laptops up until this point, with many people describing the Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro’s battery life as “all day.” It’s understandable why Apple would want to keep riding that goodwill and say that it’s done that again — and while it may have, the company hasn’t proven it yet, not with what it’s presented. So, if you want to be sure you’re getting the MacBook with the best battery life, you may want to hold off for a bit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724608/apple-m1-pro-m1-max-macbook-pro-how-to-buy-price-availability-release-date"&gt;on pre-ordering the new ones&lt;/a&gt; — at least for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22733390/macbook-pro-14-16-inch-battery-life-question-usage-processors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22733390/macbook-pro-14-16-inch-battery-life-question-usage-processors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T12:15:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:15:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>When WhatsApp went down, Brazilian workers’ jobs went with it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p0U18BV7v52gTeRslv49aqZzzBA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015891/acastro_210119_1777_whatsapp_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The Facebook outage shut down an entire economy of informal work&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="f3Qm7F"&gt;The day before a job, Luiza Ferreira always messages her client on WhatsApp to confirm they need her services. Ferreira is a cleaner in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, and she cleans different households every day. If the job is confirmed, she knows she won’t be wasting money on her commute and guarantees income for that day. If the job is not confirmed, she tries to fit another client in her schedule so she doesn’t lose money for the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0zth4"&gt;But on October 4th, that system fell apart. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709806/facebook-says-the-six-hour-outage"&gt;A configuration change in Facebook’s internal network&lt;/a&gt; wiped the company’s services off the internet for six hours — including WhatsApp. Cut off from Brazil’s primary mode of communication, Ferreira’s business ground to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZscmXP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“That’s income I can’t really get back”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aEe5ZL"&gt;“By the time I started using SMS instead of WhatsApp, it was too late and I couldn’t book another client for the next day instead,” Ferreira told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an interview through WhatsApp audio notes. “My client didn’t see the text message I sent her. When WhatsApp was down, it really disrupted my life.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cj9rk3"&gt;The outage lasted for six hours, but it cost Ferriera two whole days’ worth of earnings, since she also couldn’t schedule work for the following day. “That’s income I can’t really get back,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdL2hh"&gt;Facebook and WhatsApp are &lt;a href="https://mediarxiv.org/k2hjv/"&gt;the most popular online platforms&lt;/a&gt; in Brazil, spanning regional and social divides. Fifty-nine percent of the population has a Facebook account and 66 percent use WhatsApp, turning the services into a kind of essential infrastructure for the country. Professor Rafael Grohmann, coordinator of the DigiLabour Research Lab and a collaborator of the project Fairwork at University of Oxford, attributes Brazilians’ use of WhatsApp instead of text messaging or email to several factors. Brazil lacks telecom infrastructure and competitive market share that makes communications service affordable, and the free app allows Brazilian users to bypass expensive messaging services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="au4egv"&gt;&lt;q&gt; “Loads of clients were calling a single phone number”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oU6BRJ"&gt;“During the pandemic, [WhatsApp] became the place where everything is done,” Grohmann says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zNatze"&gt;The app has become particularly vital for informal workers, who depend on the free service to manage their work schedules, charge clients, and sell products. So when both platforms went down, the livelihoods of Ferreira and millions of other informal workers went down with them. According to the Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics, &lt;a href="https://agenciabrasil.ebc.com.br/economia/noticia/2021-07/taxa-de-informalidade-no-mercado-de-trabalho-sobe-para-40-diz-ibge"&gt;34.7 million people in Brazil work in the informal economy of the country&lt;/a&gt;, without the safety net of formal employment and benefits. During the pandemic, the number of informal workers has grown by 40 percent due to the &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/brazils-economic-crisis-prolonged-by-covid-19-poses-an-enormous-challenge-to-the-amazon-157556"&gt;worsening economic crisis&lt;/a&gt; in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvDVrS"&gt;There are competing services for arranging informal work — most notably Uber and Rappi — but they all charge a percentage of the workers’ pay. As a result, workers often actively move their clients onto WhatsApp to avoid losing a cut of their earnings. “It’s common for cleaners to tell their clients, this platform gets 15 to 20 percent of my pay, I’ll give you a cheaper price if you schedule through WhatsApp and pay me through bank transfer,” Grohmann said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPmu50"&gt;During the outage, Bruno Torres, an online salesman for children’s clothes, estimated he lost around R$3,000 (US$500). “We needed to post our new merchandise and speak to our clients who were asking if we had any new clothes,” Torres said. “Loads of clients were calling a single phone number.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="KCWmAd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We really depend on this service to be able to work in our day to day life”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zaZzfk"&gt;For Torres, WhatsApp is a free tool of communication that allows him to speak to several clients at the same time, thus maximizing his profit. “Without WhatsApp, there would be a decline in my sales,” Torres said. “And it would also impact my psychological wellbeing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d3HGty"&gt;WhatsApp commerce also extends to one-off sales of homemade goods and a wide range of less easily classifiable work. In &lt;a href="https://cetic.br/media/docs/publicacoes/2/20201104182616/painel_tic_covid19_3edicao_livro%20eletr%C3%B4nico.pdf"&gt;a research paper about the effects of the pandemic on work&lt;/a&gt;, the Information and Communication Nucleus of the Brazilian Internet Steering Committee (NIC) found that 30 percent of internet users who worked during the pandemic sold products or services over messaging apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mu1qH3"&gt;“People find ways to sell their wares, in Brazil we call this &lt;em&gt;viração&lt;/em&gt;, when you manage to survive by selling things, be that cakes or clothes, whatever,” Grohmann explained. “This is a way for the working class to survive and they start to depend more and more on WhatsApp for that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jod4lQ"&gt;Grohmann says even securely employed workers use the app to communicate during the workday, and that the audio feature is particularly helpful for informal workers who cannot read or write well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XVdIHT"&gt;“Brazil has a very high illiteracy rate, so audio notes are very useful,” Grohmann explained. “We also have a very oral culture. So the use of audio notes for Brazilians is really important and it intersects with the culture of informal work and who does that work. I know people who send me voice notes saying ‘OK’ rather than writing it down.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="19Ub4f"&gt;Grohmann says that WhatsApp has also &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2020/7/1/brazil-deliverymen-for-uber-other-apps-protest-amid-pandemic"&gt;allowed workers to organize against precarity&lt;/a&gt;, showing how the use of privatized modes of communications can be negotiated and used to the advantage of the workers. “Delivery app workers in Brazil started organizing through WhatsApp, in group chats [designed for organizing strikes],” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H59vri"&gt;Once the disruption to WhatsApp was repaired, workers who had their livelihood disrupted rushed to make up for lost time and money. There’s no guarantee there won’t be another outage, but most informal workers depend on the free, dynamic service to make a living. “We really depend on this service to be able to work in our day to day life,” Torres said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tHzypx"&gt;Leaving the platform for another isn’t really an option. The usage of WhatsApp in Brazil is practically an inescapable fact of daily life. Grohmann explains that workers wouldn’t move to other comms services because most Brazilians use WhatsApp. “A few people created accounts on Telegram when WhatsApp was down, but very few people in Brazil use other communication platforms other than WhatsApp,” he said. “Changing platforms wouldn’t mean better communication with clients.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22734705/facebook-whatsapp-outage-brazil-informal-workers-economy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22734705/facebook-whatsapp-outage-brazil-informal-workers-economy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Froio</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:57:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:57:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple botched the MacBook Pro notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x9TlV48LFAI48qHXlzAIzozo3O0=/25x0:1936x1274/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015766/Apple_MacBook_Pro_16_inch_Final_Cut_Pro_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xxYGjp"&gt;The day that many have been dreading has finally arrived. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732912/apple-macbook-pro-notch-display"&gt;Apple has added a notch to its new MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;. And somehow, Apple — notch pros at this point — managed to utterly botch the notch. Because the new MacBook Pros completely missed out on the most important part of the notch: &lt;em&gt;adding Face ID&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePfAmo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"&gt;I’ve been on the record&lt;/a&gt; of being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/11/6/18057258/macbook-air-update-face-id-notch-bezel-security"&gt;extremely pro-MacBook notch&lt;/a&gt;: back in 2018, I argued that Apple &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do exactly what it’s done here: add a notch to its MacBook laptops, taking up the exact width of the persistent menu bar that already permanently lives on the top of its macOS software (barring the occasional dip into a full-screen app). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VsI5JT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The MacBook Air needs Face ID and a delightful notch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/11/6/18057258/macbook-air-update-face-id-notch-bezel-security"},{"title":"The iPhone’s notch: should it stay or should it go?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tQHLHR"&gt;And to be fair, Apple has actualized most of the benefits of a notch: smaller bezels, particularly at the top of the display, allowing for Apple to at least play in the same ballpark (if still not quite on the same level) as the ultra-thin bezels that have become the norm on premium Windows laptops from companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yZ10E"&gt;Which is why the lack of Face ID here is such a glaring miss. As a means of visual identity across its product lineup, the notch is practically synonymous with Face ID on Apple’s devices. Seeing one here (and then not offering the tech) is incongruous right off the bat. It starts things off on the wrong foot; sure, most people don’t &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the idea of a notch, but usually, there’s the acceptance that you’re getting the addition of Face ID. Here the cost of the notch returns far fewer rewards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9Xq8j"&gt;It’s possible that there are still technical issues here: maybe the Face ID module is just too big to fit into a laptop display, although Apple managed to fit it into both its iPhone and iPad hardware just fine. The existence of any number of IR-powered Windows Hello facial unlock systems would also indicate that the challenges (if they even exist) can be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a68sYc"&gt; Plus, look at the thickness of Apple’s new MacBook Pro lid:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h6ouCH7C7m5U_ybPSfd_JQVpctE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938870/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MBoLCy"&gt;You’re telling me that can’t fit a Face ID module? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phou79"&gt;The hardware is all there: the M1 Pro and M1 Max share the same architecture as the A-series chips that Apple has offered for years, and Apple already offers Face ID on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;its M1-powered iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. And Apple’s notch already conceals a few extra components: as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pogue/status/1450489697382408192"&gt;David Pogue notes on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the cutout also hides Apple’s TrueTone sensor, light sensor, and an LED status light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8Quzzv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As you evaluate your opinion on the MacBook Pro’s notch, keep in mind that it houses more than just a 1080p camera. It also houses the TrueTone sensor (colors consistent in all lighting conditions), light sensor (adjusts brightness/keyboard illumination), and “camera on” LED. &lt;a href="https://t.co/XpKvhvtEWn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XpKvhvtEWn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— David Pogue (@Pogue) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pogue/status/1450489697382408192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KhtKML"&gt;It’s easy to imagine Apple integrating a lot of the useful things that Face ID does on its phones directly into its laptops. The highly marketed ability to instantly boot the new MacBook Pros with the ultra-fast M1 Pro and M1 Max chips could go even faster by unlocking your computer before you’ve even touched the keyboard. Face ID’s password unlocks would be incredibly convenient on websites since you’re already staring at your computer the whole time. And Apple would get to play up its Animoji and Memoji avatars with the sorts of wacky demos the company thinks are hilarious at its events. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VQbge7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple even says that Face ID is more secure&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YwhXQZ"&gt;The lack of Face ID means that Apple is &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; playing catch up to Windows. The past few years have seen Windows Hello facial recognition unlocking become more and more of a standard feature across laptops. Apple, meanwhile, despite arguably doing the most to popularize facial recognition unlocking (and Face ID) for personal tech, is still weirdly sitting on the sideline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="La6en2"&gt;Plus, there’s the security aspect. Apple &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; to brag about how secure its computers are. And yet, the company insists on locking down its computers exclusively with Touch ID — security tech that is, by Apple’s own estimations, orders of magnitudes less secure. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204587"&gt;According to Apple’s documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the odds of guessing a four-digit passcode are 1 in 10,000. The odds of someone else having a matching fingerprint to unlock Touch ID on your computer are 1 in 50,000. But Apple &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208108"&gt;also says&lt;/a&gt; that the probability of a random person managing to unlock your device using Face ID is a whooping 1 in 1,000,000. Apple has better biometric security available that it could put on its laptops; it’s just choosing not to, year after year and redesign after redesign. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PjFa_Ynp8kmOnhpfBkcU_mo9AdU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938880/Untitled.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The notch has arrived, whether you like it or not&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iD84Cf"&gt;Apple — and customers — do both still like Touch ID, at least conceptually. The argument for fingerprint-based biometrics has become a stronger one when wearing a mask for health purposes defeats a lot of the convenience of Face ID. And there have been rumors for years that Apple has been planning to bring back Touch ID to its iPhones in the form of an in-display sensor. But if Apple really is worried about losing some of the convenience of Touch ID, it could simply offer both security options, taking the bold step of actually letting its customers decide which biometric method they’d like to use. Or Apple could really take a stance on security and let users use &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; Touch ID and Face ID for even more secure biometric authentication, giving the company more security stats to tout and customers an extra layer of security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUZrdV"&gt;A notch for Face ID would have been acceptable — even great. Or maybe Apple really, truly believed that Touch ID was the right solution for its computers and that all the new MacBook Pros needed was a higher resolution webcam and smaller bezels. But in that case, Apple could have tried to engineer a hole-punch camera, like those found on virtually every major Android flagship, for a more seamless look and feel that would still allow it to cut down the bezels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hbb7vL"&gt;But instead, the new MacBook Pros are stuck in a terrible no man’s land: all the size of a notch, without any of the utility. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734676/apple-macbook-pro-notch-botch-face-id-missing-feature-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734676/apple-macbook-pro-notch-botch-face-id-missing-feature-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:50:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:50:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>The MLB may launch streaming service for local games — no cable TV required</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration a Major League Baseball (MLB)..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QHc7fNjyFZaQfB_tdfSCR6crjB8=/45x0:3764x2479/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015718/1234971615.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IGTruc"&gt;You may soon be able to watch your local teams’ home games without cable TV, as the MLB is considering launching a web-based streaming service that will do exactly that (via &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/10/17/mlb-in-talks-to-launch-nationwide-streaming-service-for-home-games/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Shrinking viewership rates may be the main factor behind the potential streaming service. As the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; points out, the MLB viewership has dropped 12 percent this year in comparison to 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sFHPAf"&gt;The MLB already offers MLB.TV, a streaming service for out-for-market games. Unlike MLB.TV, the planned streaming service will only focus on local games that you can currently only view via regional cable. MLB.TV would still be available if and when the new streaming service launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UZ5mcS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A subscription could cost anywhere from $10 to $20 per month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uovjtD"&gt;Having both MLB.TV and the new service would, in theory, let you view both local and out-of-market games without paying for regular cable, preventing you from having to deal with broadcast blackouts. This still isn’t the perfect solution — ideally, there would be one streaming service that lets you watch any game you want. That probably won’t happen anytime soon, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XRmdUl"&gt;The new streaming service would give the MLB the chance to win back cable-cutting fans, airing the same games that you’d normally see on cable TV but without the added costs of cable. The &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; reveals that subscriptions for the service would vary based on location and could range anywhere from $10 to $20 / month. The MLB has experimented with having &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/9/17100294/facebook-exclusively-streaming-25-mlb-games-2018"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18524132/youtube-mlb-baseball-games-exclusive-streaming-13-deal-sports"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; stream games in the past, but having a dedicated service for home games will make them more convenient to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rtMzZ8"&gt;And as an added bonus, the MLB might not be the only sports league streaming on the service either — the National Basketball Association and National Hockey League may partner with the MLB on the platform, which could launch as early as 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734293/mlb-streaming-service-local-games-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734293/mlb-streaming-service-local-games-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:29:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:29:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Get 10 percent off a PC you can build yourself at NZXT</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aAsUZCX3XDSgh_es0_ubGd_Zr-I=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015591/NZXT_BLDKit_RGB_Banner_1920x1080_Blog_header_EN_JPG_2021.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="O8f2dO"&gt;For the next 48 hours, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fcollection%2Fgg-sale&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NZXT is giving 10 percent off all of its pre-built BLD systems&lt;/a&gt;. This includes its pre-fab configurations, as well as any custom-tailored builds. With PC parts at something of a premium right now, a sale like this is fantastic for anyone that’s been biding their time on investing in a new PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K06gA1"&gt;Pre-builts are the easiest way to currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632047/nvidia-gpu-supply-rtx-30-series-constraints-2022"&gt;get your hands on a new GPU&lt;/a&gt; without having to spend &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22345891/nvidia-amd-rtx-gpus-price-scalpers-ebay-graphics-cards"&gt;an absolute mint&lt;/a&gt;, and with NZXT’s BLD service, you also get the added benefit of a two-year warranty on parts and labor, as well as guaranteed performance right out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQIvpN"&gt;While NZXT has been in the pre-built PC game for a while now, a new service it’s offering is the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fcollection%2Fbld-kit&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NZXT BLD kit&lt;/a&gt;. This is the first time a major PC manufacturer has offered a service like this and sounds perfect for anyone that's wanted to build their own PC but has found the prospect too intimidating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ISCIWB"&gt;The BLD kit comes with an illustrated guide, and videos to lead you through each step of the process. Each part comes labeled, and the kit even comes with all the tools you need to put everything together. NZXT is also extending its 2-year warranty to these DIY kits and even has tons of resources for troubleshooting if you ever need help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0MFOEq"&gt;The kit currently comes in two flavors, the Starter Pro and the Streaming Plus, the specs for each kit are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lbI5St"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fproduct%2Fbld-kit-starter-pro-pc&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starter Pro: $1399&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ww3Kq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case&lt;/strong&gt;: H510 Compact Mid Tower White/Black Chassis with 2x 120mm Aer F Case Fans&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt;: Intel Core i5-11400F&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU&lt;/strong&gt;: Gigabyte RTX 3060 TI Gaming OC LHR&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOBO&lt;/strong&gt;: AsRock B560 Pro4&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt;: Team T-Force Vulcan Z 16GB (2 x 8GB)&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSU&lt;/strong&gt;: Seasonic 550W Bronze&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STORAGE&lt;/strong&gt;: Western Digital WD Blue SN550 NVMe M.2 1TB&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COOLER&lt;/strong&gt;: Deepcool Gammaxx GTE V2&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WIFI&lt;/strong&gt;: MSI MS-B905C WIFI Dual Band Wireless PCI-E Adapter Card&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WINDOWS&lt;/strong&gt;: Microsoft Windows 10 Home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJvZq6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fproduct%2Fbld-kit-streaming-plus-pc&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming Plus: $1599&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sw0Gxr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case&lt;/strong&gt;: H510 Compact Mid Tower White/Black Chassis with 2x 120mm Aer F Case Fans&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU:&lt;/strong&gt; AMD Ryzen 5 5600X&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU&lt;/strong&gt;: Gigabyte RTX 3060 TI Gaming OC LHR&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOBO&lt;/strong&gt;: MSI B550-A Pro&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt;: Team T-Force Vulcan Z 16GB (2 x 8GB)&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSU&lt;/strong&gt;: Seasonic 650W 80+ Bronze&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STORAGE&lt;/strong&gt;: Western Digital WD Blue SN550 NVMe M.2 1TB&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COOLER&lt;/strong&gt;: NZXT Kraken M22 120MM Liquid Cooler&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WIFI&lt;/strong&gt;: MSI MS-B905C WIFI Dual Band Wireless PCI-E Adapter Card&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WINDOWS&lt;/strong&gt;: Microsoft Windows 10 Home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cTKLLM"&gt;While the BLD kit is currently only available to people in the US, NZXT also has several pre-fab systems available at different price points. available to anyone that wants to cash in on this deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqkg9g"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fcollection%2Fstarter-series&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Starter Series&lt;/a&gt;: $1,100 to $1,400&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="w3oSwJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815623"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7LqGGY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fcollection%2Fstreaming&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Streaming Series&lt;/a&gt;: Starting at $1,700 to $2,900&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0KZa8R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815626"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Lqyk8E"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnzxt.com%2Fproduct%2Fcreator-pc&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F10%2F19%2F22732659%2Fget-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Creator PC&lt;/a&gt;: $4,000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JQauZH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815632"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="STCnoh"&gt;This tier only has a single configuration but pulls out all the stops in terms of performance. This absolute beast of a machine might be considered by some to be overkill, but is just what you’ll need if you need to edit photos or videos or play games at their highest settings. This desktop comes equipped with an RTX 3090 GPU, 64 GB of RAM, and an unlocked Intel i9-11900K CPU. This model even includes primary and secondary storage with a 4TB hard drive and a 1TB SSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D0grw3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/19/22732659/get-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/19/22732659/get-10-percent-off-a-pc-you-can-build-yourself-at-nzxt-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:12:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>What is the new Apple Music Voice plan, and who is it for? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oPgqtP1eofYR_1L0cCWkwBn9-1o=/0x87:1306x958/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015526/Apple_HomePod_mini_Apple_Music_Voice_AirPods_3rd_gen_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Music Voice relies entirely on your dulcet tones to play music from any Siri-enabled device&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BKzS5L"&gt;The new Apple Music Voice plan that Apple announced at its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724306/apple-macbook-pro-event-biggest-announcements-airpods-m1-pro-max"&gt;“Unleashed” event&lt;/a&gt; on Monday is causing some confusion. I’m here to help you understand this new, cheaper option, which capitalizes on the power of Apple’s smart voice assistant, Siri (don’t laugh).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dfonFq"&gt;Put simply, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733053/apple-music-voice-plan-playlists-price-siri"&gt;Apple Music Voice plan&lt;/a&gt; is a voice control-only access to the service’s catalog of 90 million songs. It arrives later this year, and with it, you can play everything — full albums, individual songs, Apple’s playlists; it’s all-you-can-eat Apple Music. The caveat is you have to use your voice to control it, and you have to play it through a Siri-enabled device, such as a HomePod Mini (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"&gt;now in some spiffy new colors&lt;/a&gt;), AirPods, or an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtGi64"&gt;What it is not is a fee to use Siri to play your own music. If you have tracks purchased through or stored on iTunes, you can still play those with the Apple Music app and control them with voice, as before. What paying for this service does is add access to the company’s streaming catalog for a lower price than its Individual or Family plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="anApKx"&gt;Apple Music Voice seems best suited to casual listeners who don’t spend hours carefully curating playlists and just want to listen to some music on the fly. While you can request specific songs and albums, you can also just say, “Hey, Siri plays some ’90s Britpop” or “Hey Siri, play something chill.” There’s also access to Apple Radio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i3X4-3Zt9-7jRKtrziV3ZJqGzuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938603/Apple_HomePod_mini_hero_5up_10182021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HomePod Mini is a Siri-enabled smart speaker you can use to play songs on the Apple Music Voice plan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CNpJMp"&gt;The most significant difference between the two plans — beyond price: one is $4.99, and one is $9.99 — is access to the Apple Music app. With the Voice plan, you can’t open the Apple Music app, search for an artist or song, and select a track. Instead, you have to ask Siri to play the song you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lboR5"&gt;You can use the Apple Music app to see a queue of recently played music and suggestions for using Siri to control your music. There are also “suggestions based on the listener’s music preferences” that include limited content available for playback through the app, &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-introduces-the-apple-music-voice-plan/"&gt;according to Apple&lt;/a&gt;. Apple hasn’t shared how exactly this will look or work yet, so we’ll have to wait for the service to roll out to test it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IFaIVk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The cheaper plan doesn’t let you create playlists&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l42mQc"&gt;The cheaper plan also doesn’t let you create your own playlists, manage your playback queue, download songs to your library, scroll the lyrics on your iPhone or iPad, or stream from any third-party speakers (such as Google Nest Hub, which does support the full Apple Music plan). It also won’t play some of the higher-quality audio formats available in Apple Music, such as lossless and spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wT27Qb"&gt;You can use Apple AirPlay to play music through any and all AirPlay 2-enabled speakers you might have — which makes this plan a notch better than Amazon’s similar voice-only music streaming service. That plan — the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GKLDPRYNF2VUAKMM"&gt;Amazon Music Unlimited Single Device Plan&lt;/a&gt; — costs $3.99 to access Amazon Music’s catalog, but you can only play it on one Echo or Fire TV device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJCX2r"&gt;What’s unique about both these voice streaming plans is that you can just buy a smart speaker — an Amazon Echo or a HomePod Mini — plug it in, and ask it to play music. (You can literally say, “Hey Siri, start my Apple Music Voice trial” and be up and running.) This takes away a lot of friction from getting going with streaming music, providing an easy set-up for someone who’s not very techie. It will probably make a great gift for your parents this Christmas if you’re tired of listening to The Eagles on their FM radio every time you visit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFg4eY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram will let users co-author posts and share likes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BG8S0n0OHYXez8Bi4C9GvtuoXk0=/0x1:1581x1055/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70015436/Collab_Post_Accept_or_Decline_Flow.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Users will have to accept an invite to be co-author of a post.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HKMpaI"&gt;Instagram is kicking off a week of product reveals with the announcement of “Collabs,” a new feature that lets two users jointly share ownership of a single feed post or Reel. Tomorrow, it’s following this up by testing a new way to add a nonprofit fundraiser to a post, and finally on Thursday it’s rolling out the ability to create photo and video posts on desktop, as well as launching new music-focused effects for Reels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLIFRT"&gt;The new Collabs feature effectively allows two accounts to co-author a post or Reel. The post or Reel will appear jointly to each user’s followers and will share the same comment thread, as well as view and like counts. Collabs are enabled from the tagging screen, after which the second account will have to accept the invite.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yyh-hdEDxNXdrfzjxL00OMKUBUs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938184/Reels_3D_Lyrics.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Instagram&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of the new 3D Lyrics effect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rnE5YF"&gt;The service is also rolling out the ability for users to post photos and videos from desktop browsers on Thursday, following a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550010/instagram-post-from-desktop-web-browser-testing"&gt;limited test earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. This might sound like a very basic feature to only now be coming to desktop, but Instagram’s desktop functionality has historically lagged well behind what’s possible on its apps. It only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21215449/instagram-dm-web-browser-update-direct-message"&gt;added DMs to the browser last year&lt;/a&gt;, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dwY2Gq"&gt;Finally, there are a couple of minor features also coming this week. Tomorrow, Instagram will start testing a new way to create fundraisers in posts, which will be accessible after tapping the “+” button on the top right of its interface. There are also a pair of new music-focused features coming to Reels on Thursday. Superbeat adds effects to a video to the beat of a song, while Dynamic and 3D lyrics offer a more interesting way to display song lyrics during a video. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734118/instagram-collabs-desktop-posts-superbeat-dynamic-3d-lyrics-product-week"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734118/instagram-collabs-desktop-posts-superbeat-dynamic-3d-lyrics-product-week</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T10:58:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T10:58:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Casio G-Shock GSW-H1000 review: bad timing</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A shock to the ecosystem&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="NoJZpA"&gt;Although the Wear OS watch market has been dominated by the likes of Fossil for many years now, Casio has quietly carved out a niche for itself as a purveyor of more rugged devices. The Japanese company first released its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/29/11525360/casio-smart-outdoor-watch-fs10-android-wear-review"&gt;Smart Outdoor Watch&lt;/a&gt; all the way back in 2016 and has continued to iterate on the idea with Pro Trek-branded models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4ZCAE"&gt;All this time, though, there was one obvious question. Why hasn’t Casio made a G-Shock smartwatch?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJUN5u"&gt;G-Shock is one of the most iconic watch brands in the world and has long had a strong association with streetwear culture. Unlike, say, Tag Heuer, whose Swiss luxury always seemed like an odd fit for smartwatches, many G-Shock models are both status symbols and relatively accessible digital pieces at the same time. It doesn’t make much sense for most people to spend thousands of dollars on a smartwatch that will likely be obsolete in a few years, but there are lots of G-Shocks that cost under $100. Surely this is the perfect brand for smartwatches?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UtCwoi"&gt;Well, here’s the G-Squad Pro GSW-H1000. It’s Casio’s first truly smart G-Shock watch — unless you count some earlier models with limited Bluetooth functionality — and it’s available now for $699. That’s a high price for any smartwatch, and this one struggles to justify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t4fhRr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10813305"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Nf0lLW"&gt;G-Shocks come in several shapes and sizes, and the GSW-H1000 is definitely toward the bulkier, more rugged end of the lineup. It feels extremely well made, has 20-bar water resistance, and is absolutely huge. It’s not really the sort of watch I would normally wear, but I do quite like the way it looks. Then again, my wife immediately laughed at it and said, “You would need to be far more into streetwear than you actually are in order to pull that off.” Which, ouch. But maybe that means Casio has pulled off the G-Shock look?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ni56nC"&gt;Style is, of course, subjective, and I think this watch achieves what it was going for. But if you’re into the subtler, more slimline G-Shocks like the &lt;a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-casio-g-shock-value-prop"&gt;recently popular GA-2100&lt;/a&gt;, just know that this very much isn’t that. While it was comfortable enough on my wrist, I’m not sure I could recommend it to people with smaller frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB0Xw5"&gt;In truth, the GSW-H1000 isn’t all that different to Casio’s prior &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/4/17/17247436/casio-pro-trek-smartwatch-wear-os-cheaper-version"&gt;Pro Trek Wear OS watches&lt;/a&gt;. The focus is more on fitness than hiking this time around, but the physical proportions are similar and you still get the compass, altitude sensor, barometer, and GPS connectivity. (One major omission is any form of NFC, so there’s no mobile payments support.) The proprietary barrel charger is as awkward as ever, and Casio is also still making use of a dual-layer LCD that can extend battery life up to a month in its basic monochrome timekeeping mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvkD3b"&gt;Underneath that monochrome display is a fully circular 1.2-inch 360 x 360 LCD screen. It feels quite small relative to the rest of the watch, but it isn’t difficult to use, and I like that it doesn’t dominate the watch’s design. The bigger problem is that it just doesn’t look great compared to the OLED panels used in most smartwatches — it’s quite low in contrast and isn’t easily visible in bright sunlight. The monochrome layer, however, can be left on all the time and is much more glanceable if you don’t need to use it for anything complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VKaUU9TzpqKDPGCvsHPxUImXrv0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22935253/IMG_0233.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ppkkpn"&gt;One slight oddity with the GSH-H1000 is that Casio included very few watchfaces. You only get an information-dense digital face, a basic analog option, and one that matches the layout of the monochrome LCD. That latter setting was my favorite because it felt less jarring shifting between always-on and active display modes. Obviously, you can download whatever watchface you like from the Play Store, but it’s clear that Casio designed this watch around the dual-layer mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NbRatj"&gt;The sense that this is more of a curated Wear OS product extends to the software, which is built around a dedicated Casio app that you activate with the bottom-right button on the watch. This handles features like the barometer and altimeter, as well as letting you access G-Shock Move, a fitness-focused app that you have to install on your phone alongside the base Wear OS app, which is a slightly awkward process. Once set up, though, G-Shock Move can be linked to Google Fit and supports a ton of activities — from paddleboarding to fishing — and I found it worked well for tracking my bike runs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tN3kv1"&gt;The unfortunate thing about this watch’s software is that Casio announced it right before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22629459/galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-bixby-google-wearos"&gt;Google and Samsung came out with the Galaxy Watch 4 and Wear OS 3&lt;/a&gt;, which is the biggest refresh Google’s smartwatch platform has received in several years. From Casio’s point of view, it might not be a necessary upgrade. So much of your interaction with this watch is through Casio’s own custom software, and if that’s what you’re buying it for, the underlying OS isn’t quite as important as it might be with a Wear OS Michael Kors. Even battery life concerns are mitigated somewhat because of the dual-layer screen — I got a couple of days’ use out of this watch easily in dual-layer mode.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X1032QZaBQC1WRv31WELwpeW3fg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22935254/IMG_0230.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3E5qkC"&gt;Personally, though, I would like my smartwatch to be functional as a smartwatch, especially if I’m dropping $699 on it. I’m not about to dual-wield this thing with an Apple Watch, after all. And Wear OS 2 is really just not fit for purpose at this point. That’s why Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617462/galaxy-watch-4-classic-samsung-apple-watch-google-ecosystem"&gt;essentially abandoned it with Wear OS 3&lt;/a&gt;, which lifts features from Samsung’s much better Tizen-based watches. Casio’s customizations work well enough by themselves, but I know what I’d rather have running behind the scenes. There’s no word from Casio on whether this watch will get an update, and I wouldn’t bank on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x1IMXZ"&gt;The GSH-H1000 arguably has more going for it than any other Wear OS 2 watch ever made. The build quality is great, it has genuine brand cachet, and Casio has done a lot of work to improve the software and performance. If you’re a G-Shock fan who’s been waiting for a smartwatch and you love this particular design, then hey, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KbA0Fq"&gt;But it’s expensive, the styling is divisive, and it’s come at a really bad time considering the launch of Wear OS 3. Considering all of that, it’s hard to imagine this being the right watch for many people. I do think Casio is onto something here and I’ve mostly enjoyed wearing the GSH-H1000, but I have to think there’s going to be a more broadly appealing G-Shock smartwatch somewhere down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22732325/casio-g-shock-gsw-h1000-g-squad-pro-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22732325/casio-g-shock-gsw-h1000-g-squad-pro-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
