<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-22T13:04:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T13:04:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T13:04:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Malaysian news site fined $124,000 for five reader comments</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MALAYSIA-MEDIA-COURT" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C_MtHIrbKpQ7wmmvqMyuP8tRgRQ=/4x0:4596x3061/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68856120/1231247672.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by MOHD RASFAN/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WSaXE6"&gt;A Malaysian news site was fined the equivalent of nearly $124,000 for five comments below an article. News outlet &lt;em&gt;Malaysiakini&lt;/em&gt; has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/malaysiakini/status/1362681271470551045"&gt;raised money&lt;/a&gt; to cover the fee of 500,000 ringgit, but human rights advocates say it was targeted for its reporting on government corruption, and they worry that the case could chill political speech online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hPpD5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/19/world/asia/malaysia-press-freedom-guilty.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; the verdict on Friday, when a panel of judges found &lt;em&gt;Malaysiakini&lt;/em&gt; guilty of contempt of court. &lt;a href="https://www.malaysiakini.com/news/532693"&gt;The outlet argued&lt;/a&gt; that it wasn’t responsible for reader comments, and it removed them after police warned that the comments illegally insulted Malaysia’s judiciary. But the court said it should have preemptively moderated the comments and never allowed them online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="knFm1b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malaysiakini&lt;/em&gt; is a prominent independent outlet, and it’s earned international accolades for its reporting over the past two decades. It’s faced &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-54277437"&gt;periodic legal harassment&lt;/a&gt; within the country, though, culminating in the contempt of court charges that were filed last year. Co-founder Steven Gan also faced charges and a possible prison sentence. Gan’s situation was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/12/business/media/freedom-digital-news-sites-autocrats.html"&gt;compared to that&lt;/a&gt; of Filipino journalist Maria Ressa, whom authorities accused of “cyber libel” after her site &lt;em&gt;Rappler&lt;/em&gt; published critical reporting. But unlike Ressa, who was &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/06/15/876943655/philippine-journalist-maria-ressa-found-guilty-of-violating-cyberlibel-law"&gt;convicted last year&lt;/a&gt;, Gan was acquitted of personal charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oAPEC6"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reports that this case was the first of its type brought against a news outlet in Malaysia, and Amnesty International Malaysia called it “a grave setback for freedom of expression in the country.” But Malaysia’s internet crackdown echoes an international push to make sites legally responsible for what users post — including in the United States, where lawmakers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268421/cda-section-230-25th-anniversary-reform-stakes-big-tech-internet"&gt;have taken aim&lt;/a&gt; at a rule offering blanket protection against liability.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295496/malaysiakini-guilty-contempt-of-court-fine-reader-comments-judiciary"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295496/malaysiakini-guilty-contempt-of-court-fine-reader-comments-judiciary</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T12:50:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T12:50:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon rainforest fires got even worse last year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BRAZIL-ENVIRONMENT-FIRE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XYLmVJ6bQU_dSUIBJXJrXcX8G4k=/0x92:4494x3088/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855922/1228063125.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smoke rises from an illegally lit fire in a section of Amazon rainforest, south of Novo Progresso in Pará state, Brazil, on August 15th, 2020.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Carl de Souza / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Q65FYa"&gt;Fires in the Amazon reached devastating new levels in 2020, new NASA satellite imagery shows. The space agency developed a &lt;a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/147075/a-new-tool-for-tracking-amazon-fires"&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; to track fires from space after Brazil’s Amazon suffered a record-breaking year of fires in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELU7zn"&gt;Specialized sensors on satellites collect visible and infrared imagery, which NASA uses to detect thermal anomalies — basically hotspots caused by fire. Its satellites found 1.4 million of those anomalies in the Southern Amazon last year, compared to 1.1 million in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xEyaq0"&gt;“Fire activity was up significantly in 2020,” Douglas Morton, chief of the Biospheric Sciences Laboratory at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center, said in the &lt;a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/147946/fires-raged-in-the-amazon-again-in-2020"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; today. “All types of fires contributed to the increase, including deforestation fires and understory fires, the most environmentally destructive types.” The effects of these kinds of fires can last for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QWe3R_naXe3El1DwG64x0JGWYF0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320513/amazonburnedwide_vir_2020_lrg.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;NASA grouped fires into four different types marked on this map: fires caused by deforestation to make way for industry (red), uncontrolled fires that burn the understory of the forest (green), fires burning in savanna-grasslands (blue), and small fires set by subsistence farmers to clear land (purple). NASA looks at the duration, intensity, and movement of fire “hotspots” to identify what kind of fire is burning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZG6JT8"&gt;Fires caused by deforestation were up 23 percent in 2020 compared to the year before. These blazes are started intentionally to clear parts of the rainforest to make room for cattle ranching and farming. This was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/28/20836891/amazon-fires-brazil-bolsonaro-rainforest-deforestation-analysis-effects"&gt;the main culprit behind catastrophic fires in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, when deforestation in the country hit an &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-brazil-deforestation/brazil-amazon-rainforest-deforestation-hits-11-year-high-in-2019-government-data-idUSKBN1XS1PK"&gt;11-year high&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m1HOck"&gt;There was a steep 60 percent rise in the most destructive kind of fire: uncontrolled understory fires that spread from a blaze that might have been intentionally set. Large fires aren’t natural in the Amazon’s wet terrain. In a typical year, fires are primarily the result of people setting chopped-down, dried-out trees aflame. But this year, drier conditions in the southeastern Amazon made it easier for human-made blazes to escape into parts of the rainforest that hadn’t been cleared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rdnkI1"&gt;“As a result, the scale of the fires in this area was extraordinary and devastating,” Morton said. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Clearing the rainforest to make way for ranches and agriculture is a process that can take several years of logging and burning." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QypQYW_POMGOj5IGXpkD3geKSdg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320532/deforestationtimeseries_2013_2018.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clearing the rainforest to make way for ranches and agriculture is a process that can take several years of logging and burning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Yw3A8f"&gt;The numbers are even more alarming considering how bad 2019 already was. That year, Brazil suffered a more than &lt;a href="http://queimadas.dgi.inpe.br/queimadas/portal-static/situacao-atual/"&gt;80 percent jump&lt;/a&gt; in the number of fires compared to 2018, according to the country’s National Institute for Space Research (INPE). Since entering office in 2019, Brazil’s right-wing President Jair Bolsonaro has worked to &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/americas/20210123-brazil-indigenous-leaders-sue-bolsonaro-for-killings-and-ecological-destruction"&gt;open up the Amazon to more development and set aside less land for Indigenous tribes&lt;/a&gt; and conservation efforts. NASA found that &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/amazon-deforestation-falls-where-land-is-under-indigenous-control/"&gt;Indigenous territories saw fewer fires&lt;/a&gt; compared to other lands without protections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfpSOO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="elRI7X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295437/amazon-rainforest-fires-worse-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295437/amazon-rainforest-fires-worse-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T12:45:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T12:45:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX’s Crew Dragon performing ‘beautifully’ on ISS as NASA eyes a backup ride</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dXqrkXmF6TRzYBtEoUh8JZZ6zDY=/0x0:5568x3712/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855875/50953553088_6da480ba2a_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Russia’s Progress 77 cargo resupply ship is seen approaching the International Space Station through the window of SpaceX’s Crew Dragon spacecraft. | NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kmtr2l"&gt;SpaceX’s Crew Dragon astronaut taxi is doing “beautifully” so far in its first operational, long-duration stay on the International Space Station, NASA’s human spaceflight chief Kathy Lueders told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;The capsule, named Resilience, sent three NASA astronauts and a Japanese astronaut to the station last November, and a trivial housekeeping task is the only unexpected hiccup faced by the crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BG68Yx"&gt;“We’ve been very, very happy with how things are going,” Lueders said in an interview. “The only minor thing we had was we’re getting some little bits of lint on the seal” where Crew Dragon connects to the ISS, she added. Astronauts have been floating in and out of the spacecraft for months, leaving behind a buildup of lint and dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KN73np"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I can handle having housekeeping issues”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dGEtvw"&gt;SpaceX &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/15/21565237/spacex-crew-1-dragon-launch-success-falcon-9-nasa"&gt;launched the Crew-1 mission&lt;/a&gt; on November 15th carrying Commander Mike Hopkins, pilot Victor Glover, and mission specialists Shannon Walker and Soichi Noguchi, a Japanese astronaut. The mission marked SpaceX’s first fully operational mission under its NASA contract after nailing its final test milestone last summer with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/30/21269703/spacex-launch-crew-dragon-nasa-orbit-successful"&gt;launch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/2/21350663/nasa-spacex-crew-dragon-astronauts-bob-behnken-doug-hurley-splash-down"&gt;return&lt;/a&gt; of two US astronauts, Bob Behnken and Doug Hurley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oOnig4"&gt;Some extra dust is definitely not the worst problem NASA and SpaceX could face on a $100 billion orbital laboratory that has housed astronauts in low Earth orbit for over 20 years. “I can handle having housekeeping issues,” Lueders said. Astronauts have been using a vacuum to suck out all the lint, but for a longer-term fix to the pileup, a tiny cover was trucked to the station on the NS15 cargo resupply mission, launched Saturday by Northrop Grumman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V2uWXR"&gt;NASA and SpaceX have been closely monitoring Crew Dragon’s health in space as it tallies 98 days docked to the ISS — the longest duration for a human-rated US spacecraft. Perhaps most intimately familiar with the capsule is Hopkins, who’s been using Crew Dragon as his bunking quarters while others sleep elsewhere on the station. (Lueders made clear that Hopkins wasn’t solely to blame for all the dust — “don’t make me get in trouble with Mike Hopkins, Joey!”)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uCFWc33GxPo7FEAmHiLj3E61dMY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320567/50902727167_f0845a77a0_k.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA / Johnson Space Center&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SpaceX’s Crew Dragon “Resilience” spacecraft is seen docked to the International Space Station’s Harmony module.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6MpT8X"&gt;SpaceX’s next mission, Crew-2, is slated for April 20th, reusing the capsule that flew Behnken and Hurley for the DM-2 mission. NASA decided to allow SpaceX to reuse its capsules for astronaut flights last year, setting the stage for a rigorous refurbishment and certification process for SpaceX. It’s similar to what the agency will go through with Boeing’s Starliner, Crew Dragon’s rival capsule that’s still in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FXZhRy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;refurbishing astronaut capsules in “dragonland”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3KJsqn"&gt;That refurb process will take place in Florida, where the company used to refurbish its old Cargo Dragon vehicles. Lueders said SpaceX engineers call their Kennedy Space Center refurbishment facilities “Dragonland.” SpaceX has already added infrastructure for Crew Dragon refurbishment. One crew capsule already went through the pipeline: in January, SpaceX re-flew the Crew Dragon it launched in 2019 (without any astronauts) as a cargo ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1ynJLC"&gt;NASA still needs a backup seat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="lmC4dj"&gt;Even though Crew Dragon Resilience is doing well on the ISS, and the upcoming Crew-2 launch is on schedule for April, NASA still wants to have a backup plan. The station’s other three crew members are two Russian cosmonauts and NASA astronaut Kate Rubins, who are due to return to Earth in April on the same Soyuz capsule they rode in on last year. If the Crew-2 spacecraft runs into problems before its April flight, NASA will need another option to get an astronaut to the ISS. Otherwise, they risk leaving the station with no NASA crew members for the first time since the station was first occupied in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xIlfIT"&gt;The agency announced earlier this month that it’s seeking another seat on Russia’s Soyuz spacecraft as a safety net. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reported that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278958/nasa-axiom-soyuz-russian-commercial-crew-spacex"&gt;NASA was in talks with space infrastructure startup Axiom Space&lt;/a&gt; to book that Soyuz seat, instead of buying directly from the Russians — only the second time in the decades-long NASA-Russia relationship to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KaoAm9"&gt;Lueders said the US company (without specifically naming Axiom, because the talks were ongoing) reached out to NASA with its own proposal and offered the backup solution. So, as a legal formality, NASA issued a notice saying it’s looking to buy a Soyuz seat because — as Lueders put it — “one of our commercial providers out there said ‘Hey, there’s a commercial opportunity for me here,’ so they gave us an unsolicited proposal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mEJ5LY"&gt;Axiom’s chief executive, Michael Suffredini, co-founded the Houston-based company in 2016 after spending 10 years as NASA’s ISS program manager. It’s unclear whether Axiom had already owned the Soyuz seat it’s selling to NASA or whether the Houston-based company is currently going through the process with Roscosmos to buy it. Roscosmos (Russia’s space agency) and Axiom both declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LHhzjO"&gt;No matter the arrangement, the dealmaking and seat swapping is poised to give NASA the assurance it needs to keep a US astronaut on the ISS. NASA and the State Department are “in the final stages” of coming up with an agreement with Roscosmos to fly Russian cosmonauts on future flights of SpaceX’s or Boeing’s capsules in exchange for flying more US astronauts on Soyuz spacecraft, Lueders said. Nailing that agreement has been a yearslong process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qckd5"&gt;“We were hoping it would happen a little bit sooner, and so unfortunately it wasn’t happening in time for the April Soyuz seat,” Lueders said. That delay gave Axiom a chance to make a deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uNaHHI"&gt;“If you said, ‘Kathy, what’s your logistics dream?’ I would say every vehicle going up to the ISS needs to have a US crew member on it, and we believe every US vehicle going up to have a Russian crew member on it,” Lueders said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295119/spacex-crew-dragon-iss-nasa-eyes-backup-soyuz-ride"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295119/spacex-crew-dragon-iss-nasa-eyes-backup-soyuz-ride</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T12:30:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T12:30:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Barack Obama and Bruce Springsteen are now co-hosts of a Spotify-exclusive podcast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qU4_UVGSegGnc_KbiaqewgGLVJk=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855787/_SNY2355.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZxhDp8"&gt;Barack Obama is getting into the podcast game. Today, Spotify announced that the former president and rockstar Bruce Springsteen — yes, you read that right — will host a show called &lt;em&gt;Renegades: Born in the USA&lt;/em&gt; exclusively for the audio platform. They’ll discuss “race, fatherhood, marriage, and the state of America,” per a press release, and the first two episodes premiere today for both free and premium Spotify users. The first season will contain eight episodes total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49JvfQ"&gt;Higher Ground, the production company owned by Michelle and Barack Obama, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/6/18655475/spotify-signs-podcast-deal-with-the-obamas-production-company"&gt;signed a deal&lt;/a&gt; with Spotify in 2019, committing themselves to creating exclusive podcasts for the platform. &lt;em&gt;Renegades&lt;/em&gt; is the second of those shows. &lt;em&gt;The Michelle Obama Podcast&lt;/em&gt; debuted this past summer on Spotify and was later made available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494284/spotify-michelle-obama-podcast-release-exclusive"&gt;across platforms&lt;/a&gt;, including Apple Podcasts. Spotify has said the show was the biggest Spotify Original show “in history,” but it hasn’t shared specific numbers. Presumably, this show will be just as big, if not bigger, giving Spotify even more of a chance to bring people over to its platform for podcasts. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22291508/barack-obama-bruce-springsteen-spotify-podcast-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22291508/barack-obama-bruce-springsteen-spotify-podcast-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T12:18:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T12:18:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile just brought back a true unlimited data plan with 5G and no throttling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lDgbCAqNAIeyRHBvOHBQ-5Kz3W4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855699/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SDBh15"&gt;T-Mobile has just announced a new monthly phone plan called Magenta Max that the company says is designed for the era of 5G. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fstories%2Fmagenta-max&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F22%2F22295466%2Ft-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to this press release&lt;/a&gt;, T-Mobile claims Magenta Max is “the first and only 5G consumer smartphone plan that can’t slow you down based on how much data you use.” That makes it sound like the carrier is doing away with what’s known as deprioritization, where your speeds are subject to slowdown after you exceed a certain amount of data in a billing cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kuw1DY"&gt;“T-Mobile has lit up the highest-capacity 5G network available — a network so powerful it can start unleashing the power of 5G to deliver unlimited premium data,” the company said.  Magenta Max promises “unlimited 4K UHD” video streaming compared to the DVD-quality (or 1080p at best) limit that comes with many unlimited plans. T-Mobile is also extending the company’s “Netflix on Us” promotion to single-line customers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R0-wI8Q_HvbP_ntwWv_Xf5KfwWw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320564/max.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="95rEr5"&gt;Magenta Max takes the place of the previous Magenta Plus plan and will be available starting on February 24th. It includes 40GB of high-speed tethering data, plus the usual T-Mobile perks like free in-flight Wi-Fi from Gogo, extensive international coverage, and Scam Shield protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VA4WAj"&gt;T-Mobile says pricing is “$57 per line per month for three lines with autopay and monthly taxes and fees included.” For a limited time, that’s dropped to $47 per line per month for three lines. Single-line customers will have to pay more at $85 per month with autopay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWVMpe"&gt;A lot of this has a “too good to be true” sound to it, so I’m also on the lookout for any asterisks or limits that T-Mobile isn’t talking about on the surface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fInXA9"&gt;Alongside Magenta Max, T-Mobile is also making changes to the core Magenta plan. It’s bumping up the monthly deprioritization ceiling to 100GB from the 50GB it’s at currently. Customers will also get more high-speed tethering data: it’s now 5GB compared to 3GB before.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:46:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:46:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Avengers: Endgame directors’ production company signs overall deal with Spotify </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dOcN_Amil1APhrcja3SBd4YU48g=/151x0:1747x1064/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855433/Screen_Shot_2021_02_22_at_9.00.24_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4vH7qy"&gt;Anthony and Joe Russo’s AGBO production company is entering the audio space in a new multiyear deal with Spotify, following its massive success with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21526664/netflix-movies-billion-dollar-box-office-blockbuster-ted-sarandos-earnings"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extraction &lt;/em&gt;on Netflix&lt;/a&gt; and the upcoming Tom Holland-led feature &lt;a href="https://tv.apple.com/us/movie/cherry/umc.cmc.40gvwq6hnbilmnxuutvmejx4r?ctx_brand=tvs.sbd.4000&amp;amp;itscg=MC_20000&amp;amp;itsct=atvp_brand_omd&amp;amp;mttn3pid=a_google_adwords&amp;amp;mttnagencyid=1625&amp;amp;mttncc=US&amp;amp;mttnsiteid=143238&amp;amp;mttnsubad=OUS2019895_1-491374017553-c&amp;amp;mttnsubkw=120033862727_kwd-330092397590_CJq46RN4_&amp;amp;mttnsubplmnt="&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cherry &lt;/em&gt;on Apple TV Plus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ejR8Kn"&gt;The directors, best known for their work on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18513309/avengers-endgame-spoiler-free-review-marvel-cinematic-universe-iron-man-thor-captain-america-phase-4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avengers: Infinity War &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as well as sitcoms like &lt;em&gt;Arrested Development&lt;/em&gt;, will produce several series for Spotify. The move comes at a time when Spotify is trying to assert itself as the dominant podcast platform. With the Russo brothers, known for their specific type of blockbuster storytelling, the company is looking “to tell more stories that have the power to span generations and territories.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="liM9CW"&gt;Spotify has signed other deals with storytellers and celebrities in recent months. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21453026/spotify-chernin-entertainment-partnership-first-look-podcast-ip"&gt;Chernin Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-01-21/spotify-and-ava-duvernays-array-partner-to-produce-scripted-and-unscripted-podcasts/"&gt;Ava DuVernay&lt;/a&gt;, and, most notably, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/19/21263927/joe-rogan-spotify-experience-exclusive-content-episodes-youtube"&gt;Joe Rogan&lt;/a&gt; have all signed deals with Spotify to produce exclusive content for the platform. While many people may still use Spotify as a music-only platform, the company hasn’t hidden its ambitious podcasting goals, where executives are hoping to boost subscriber numbers and advertising revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UWB8KG"&gt;Spotify hasn’t announced if the Russo brothers are already working on their first series for Spotify or if everything is still in early stages of development at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295081/russo-brothers-spotify-deal-agbo-avengers-deal-podcasts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295081/russo-brothers-spotify-deal-agbo-avengers-deal-podcasts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:45:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:45:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>DC Comics is launching a podcast universe on Spotify </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q6EQPKEJ5AiwmoCoPhucDFWd0BM=/0x0:1220x813/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855429/dc_spotify.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qdIQYp"&gt;DC is launching another universe to tell its superhero stories — but this time, it’s not on HBO Max or Cartoon Network: it’s on Spotify. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eei277"&gt;The publisher is working on nine shows for Spotify, including shows about Catwoman, Wonder Woman, the Riddler, Batgirl, Superman and Lois Lane, and more — although DC creative director Jim Lee didn’t give too much more information about what those shows entail right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cqAYHQ"&gt;Spotify and DC Comics signed a podcasting deal last June. The multiseries, multiyear deal was part of a bigger partnership between &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21294489/spotify-dc-comics-podcast-exclusive-deal"&gt;Spotify and DC Comics’ parent company&lt;/a&gt;, WarnerMedia. The first project out of the partnership is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493298/spotify-dc-comics-batman-podcast-bruce-wayne-premiere"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Batman Unburied&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which will explore the “darker aspects of Bruce Wayne’s psychology.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGflmD"&gt;Competition within the podcasting space has heated up over the last few years. DC Comics’ biggest competitor, Marvel, &lt;a href="https://www.marvel.com/articles/podcasts/marvel-entertainment-and-siriusxm-enter-a-major-multi-year-deal-to-create-original-podcasts-for-siriusxm-and-pandora"&gt;has its own podcasting deal&lt;/a&gt; with Pandora. The company also has a deal with podcasting platform Stitcher for several series. Both Pandora and Stitcher are owned by SiriusXM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uECgKl"&gt;It’s a good time for all three companies, as there’s more superhero content than ever before and interest from millions of people to find and devour new content. With &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22202992/dc-films-multiverse-batman-wonder-woman-aquaman-hbo-max-dceu-marvel-disney-plus"&gt;shows like &lt;em&gt;GCPD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Pacemaker &lt;/em&gt;coming to HBO Max (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/22/21377631/the-batman-teaser-trailer-robert-pattinson-matt-reeves-dc-fandome"&gt;spinoffs of &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and James Gunn’s &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt;), it’s a perfect opportunity to have content, well, everywhere. (Not to mention &lt;em&gt;Zack Snyder’s Justice League &lt;/em&gt;is just around the corner.) For example, Jeffrey Wright will take on a role in a DC Comics &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/jeffrey-wright-starring-in-batman-podcast-from-hbo-max-exclusive"&gt;podcast show for Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, but he’s also Detective Jim Gordon in &lt;em&gt;The Batman.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jy7XVH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295156/dc-comics-spotify-universe-podcast-superhero"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295156/dc-comics-spotify-universe-podcast-superhero</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:35:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:35:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify HiFi is a lossless streaming tier coming later this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dRpWCiVtheHUbyN9uvHc4w3pjOU=/158x0:1835x1118/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855332/Screen_Shot_2021_02_22_at_11.29.46_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p1sCH4"&gt;Spotify is going hi-fi. Well, “HiFi.” It’s taken longer than competitors like Tidal and Amazon Music, but today, the leading subscription music service announced a new lossless streaming tier that will allow listeners to get the most from their digital music library. The news came at the company’s Spotify “Stream On” virtual event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GCiu0i"&gt;Spotify HiFi will be available later this year and “will deliver music in CD-quality, lossless audio format to your device and Spotify Connect-enabled speakers, which means fans will be able to experience more depth and clarity while enjoying their favorite tracks.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9Ubjjf"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W07MvWbuWkI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zvJorF"&gt;Spotify has done small tests of higher-quality streaming in the past, but now it’s going to launch the feature more widely — with the caveat that it’ll be available only “in select markets.” Pricing is yet to be announced. Higher-quality streaming has apparently been among the top requests from its customers; as it stands today, Spotify tops out at 320kbps audio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHW4MD"&gt;Amazon rolled out Amazon Music HD &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/17/20869526/amazon-music-hd-lossless-flac-tier-spotify-apple"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. The lossless plan costs $14.99 per month (or $12.99 for Prime customers), a premium over the standard Amazon Music Unlimited service. Tidal, which has supported high-resolution audio since its very beginning, is priced slightly higher at $19.99 monthly for the “Hi-Fi” plan. Tidal offers what it calls “&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftidal.com%2Fmasters&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F22%2F22295273%2Fspotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tidal Masters&lt;/a&gt;” that can even exceed high-resolution 96 kHz / 24 bit audio. Smaller services like Qobuz have also sought to appeal to audiophiles with lossless streaming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pheala"&gt;Apple Music, on the other hand, still lacks any kind of lossless streaming tier, despite Apple selling the very high-end AirPods Max headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:33:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:33:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ACCGYzU2wR3-6BaupyrR4XrSoRA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68855298/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;In the US, 5G remains a work in progress, despite carriers waving “5G Mission Accomplished” banners for years | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The fourth industrial revolution will not be televised&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="2rF2Fy"&gt;After an introduction from Consumer Technology Association president Gary Shapiro, Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg takes the stage. He wears a simple black T-shirt with an unmistakable red check and begins delivering his keynote speech. The topic at hand is 5G, something Vestberg speaks about enthusiastically. The keynote covers the eight “currencies” of 5G, features a professional athlete, and highlights how 5G will transform the drone industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPtmvC"&gt;That was CES 2019. It was also CES 2021. Verizon hasn’t been alone in fueling the 5G hype machine; AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile have been talking up their 5G networks for years. Now, it’s showtime. With major flagship phones and a lot more budget devices supporting it, this is the year when a critical mass of phone buyers will finally see for themselves what all this talk is about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QaXFel"&gt;Here’s the bad news: if they’ve been listening to the hype, they’re going to be disappointed. We’ve been promised a fourth industrial revolution with fantastical things like remote surgery and driverless cars. Instead, what we have now is widespread 5G that’s more or less the same speed as (or even slower than) 4G and super-fast mmWave 5G in &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; parts of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; major cities with highly limited range. So where is this 5G future we’ve been promised? The truth is that it’s coming along, but it will materialize more slowly and in less obvious ways than what we’ve been led to believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uEFYKL"&gt;Spectrum wars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="dzciVm"&gt;To understand the complicated 5G situation in the US right now, you first need to know that there are low-, mid-, and high-band frequencies that carriers can use. Low-band is slower but offers widespread coverage. High-band, often called mmWave, is very fast but extremely limited in range. Mid-band sits in a sweet spot between the two, with good range and better-than-LTE speeds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXZ3ph"&gt;If you were building a 5G network from scratch, you’d probably want a bunch of mid-band spectrum, right? The trouble is, spectrum is a limited resource. &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/authors/sascha-segan"&gt;Sascha Segan&lt;/a&gt;, lead mobile analyst at &lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt; and a wealth of 5G knowledge, sums up part of the spectrum problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjjNjv"&gt;“Our government did not make the right channels available to the carriers,” he says. “Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T have basically just been using leftover odds and ends of their 4G spectrum... putting the 5G encoding on these leftover bits and bobs so they can pop a 5G icon on the screen. And the performance is meaningless.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="hRkK5K"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s kind of like having that super fast sports car and you’re stuck on the Santa Monica freeway.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xixtRf"&gt;The technology Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T are using to get nationwide 5G coverage is called Dynamic Spectrum Sharing (DSS), which allows 4G and 5G to coexist on the same spectrum. That helps carriers make the transition from one technology to the other, but it comes at a cost. Michael Thelander, president and founder of wireless industry research firm &lt;a href="https://signalsresearch.com/"&gt;Signals Research Group&lt;/a&gt;, sums it up this way: “It’s kind of like having that super fast sports car and you’re stuck on the Santa Monica freeway. You can’t experience the full capabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Sv52l"&gt;T-Mobile, on the other hand, doesn’t need to rely on spectrum sharing as much as the other two, thanks to its acquisition of Sprint and its mid-band spectrum. That has given it an edge in its 5G offerings thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WD5bmM"&gt;By early 2022, though, we will likely see Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T catching up. A swath of mid-band spectrum known as C-band went up for auction in late 2020. And while we don’t know which companies won which blocks of spectrum, we know those two carriers, in particular, spent big; bidding &lt;a href="https://auctiondata.fcc.gov/public/projects/auction107"&gt;topped out at over $80 billion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uw17dY"&gt;What happens next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="VsP8hz"&gt;The networks might not be firing on all cylinders yet, but more and more mobile devices are ready for them. In fact, by the end of the year, it may be harder to find a non-5G phone than one that supports the technology. Not only do Apple and Samsung’s flagship phones support 5G across their lineups, but it’s also making its way into more midrange and budget devices, thanks to new 5G-ready low-end processors like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22204586/qualcomm-snapdragon-480-5g-android-smartphone-price"&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 480&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiBmo5"&gt;More people than ever will buy a 5G phone this year — likely not because they really wanted 5G, but because the phone they were going to get anyway supports it. The good news is that there really isn’t a downside to buying a 5G phone now if it’s time to upgrade. The “5G tax” that put a higher price tag on 5G phones over the past couple of years seems to be disappearing, and we haven’t noticed any other drawbacks like excessive battery drain in our testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuP5JW4ilTFsD1GqJPcjnL_wagE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21973509/vpavic_4243_20201017_0144.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 series includes 5G connectivity across the lineup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sPWa6a"&gt;So what’s the reaction like so far from, say, someone who bought an iPhone 12 — not for 5G, but because it’s the new iPhone? “They’re frustrated and angry,” says Segan. “With both Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T, because of what I’ll call technical difficulties, their nationwide 5G is often slower than their 4G. So people are getting these iPhones and they’re finding that frequently they have worse performance than they had before 5G.” The “technical difficulties” he refers to include DSS in Verizon’s case and the limitations of the narrow 5MHz band that AT&amp;amp;T often uses for its 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p5fWGR"&gt;That’s not great. But a couple of factors will make a difference over the next year. First, that C-band spectrum will start coming online around the end of the year. If you’re one of the frustrated owners of an iPhone 12 or Galaxy S21, there’s good news: your phone is already approved to use C-band, so if you’re on Verizon or AT&amp;amp;T, you should see speed improvements when that happens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="u7PitC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They’re finding that frequently they have worse performance than they had before 5G”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MvPKH7"&gt;Not all 5G phones support C-band, though. Those that don’t will need a software update to use it, and there’s no guarantee that your phone’s manufacturer will offer one. Inexpensive 5G models, in particular, may not see a C-band update, even if they have the hardware to support it. Phone makers need to apply for Federal Communications Commission approval to enable it and may be less likely to bother with the cost of this step for phones with a shorter lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFIJxS"&gt;The other factor is something that will likely happen sooner than C-band becoming available: large gatherings. That’s when Segan thinks Verizon’s Ultra Wideband could really shine. “When we’re all vaccinated, I think people are going to be desperate... for all of these dense, crowded, communal experiences that we will have been missing for a year and a half. And so Verizon should be working on applications and experiences right now like the thing they did at the Super Bowl, or what they’ve talked about doing at Disney World, that you can only do on Ultra Wideband.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4L8b2T"&gt;Again, that will depend on your 5G phone supporting the right &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; of 5G — not every 5G phone supports mmWave. The aforementioned iPhone and Samsung flagships do, and other Verizon models that support are denoted as “UW.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oDOGa4"&gt;Where are our jetpacks?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ftsEj7"&gt;And what about the stuff of CES keynotes like remote surgery and self-driving cars? That’s on the way, too, but it’ll take longer. Thelander explains: “The first focus of 5G was really a feature called ‘enhanced mobile broadband’ and that’s just getting fast data speeds to the consumer on their smartphone. Things like factory automation and the functionality behind that, that was really developed afterwards, so it lags, from a standardization perspective.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="TCL 10 5G UW" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-45gdo6AJkDTvjeyQhEZkf3YK80=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21990050/cfaulkner_201023_4258_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first focus of 5G has been to boost mobile data speeds for consumers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uvow5O"&gt;Getting the technology piece sorted out is only half of the equation. “Once you’ve got a certain feature or functionality defined in a standard, now a vendor has to go out and build that functionality, then you have to test it, and then you have to have the industry adopt it,” Thelander says. “The technology may be there, the standard may be there, it may work fine, but it has to be implemented and rolled out. And you have to have the business case for it. How do you make money off of it? All those types of things… it just takes time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="SQZrz1"&gt;Despite networks constantly waving their “&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/mission-accomplished"&gt;5G Mission Accomplished&lt;/a&gt;” banners in TV commercials over the past year, 5G is very much still a work in progress. It’s going to get better, but how soon that happens for you depends on a lot of factors: which phone you have and what bands it supports, which network you’re on, where you are, and what you’re doing. It seems clear now that there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/23/18637213/5g-race-us-leadership-china-fcc-lte"&gt;never really was a “Race to 5G”&lt;/a&gt; — just technological progress as usual, which is often slow, confusing, and uneven. That’s a little bit harder to sell in a keynote or a commercial.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-22T11:14:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T11:14:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u2r1v0qpkmDCofvfzLEcU6WDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809161/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DzZXIa"&gt;One of the most frustrating tasks for many of us these days is finding how and where to get an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. It can be a real exercise in exasperation: the websites are often difficult to navigate and prone to frequent crashes; in addition, after finding an open appointment slot and filling out multiple pages of questions, you are often told that the opening has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Vp4Bt"&gt;In view of all this, we’ve tried to gather as much helpful information as we can about ways to research and snag vaccination appointments for yourself and others. We’ll update this as more information presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JYv8ZW"&gt;Research the vaccination qualifications in your state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jJJ2mU"&gt;To begin with, it’s a good idea to try to pin down if you or the person you are assisting is currently qualified for the COVID-19 vaccine. Find the vaccine information site (or sites) that is being run by your state and / or city. This will also help you figure out when you might be qualified if you aren’t already. If you can’t find it via a quick search, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/plan-your-vaccine/"&gt;NBC News has created a simple website&lt;/a&gt; that lets you find out what the current situation is in your specific state. &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/covid-19/where-to-get-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;Prescription company GoodRx&lt;/a&gt; offers similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N5dWHX"&gt;Find all the places that might offer appointments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XK1Cc0"&gt;There are, fortunately or unfortunately, many different sites where you can go to find out if you can get an appointment to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvDmn"&gt;For example, here in New York City, we’ve had to navigate separate sites run by the city and the state. Various hospital systems also have their own sites, as do pharmacies such as Walgreens and CVS, which have recently begun offering appointments for vaccinations. It’s a lot to check — and it can be enormously confusing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usTdFX"&gt;As a result, your first step is probably to check your state’s government health website (searching your state name and “COVID vaccine” will probably do it). If you’re an urban dweller, check for your city’s information site as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8ot2F"&gt;While most personal physicians do not have access to vaccines, your doctor may be able to tell you some of the places to check. Other resources include your local hospital system, your union (especially if your employment qualifies you for a vaccination), and, of course, friends and colleagues, many of whom have probably been doing their own searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZ6Bfn"&gt;As you find resources and sites, make sure to bookmark them. I keep a folder on my bookmarks bar called “COVID” — you may want to name yours something more cheerful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8lP4_R3np2CX9crqTcg9Mq6I2Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13963741/IMG_1653.1419968302.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6uguNM"&gt;Have all your information ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dt0LZ"&gt;Many of us who have tried to register for vaccination appointments have gone through the experience of filling out several screens of information only to find that, by the time we got to the end, the appointment was gone. So it’s a good idea to have all your data — such as your name, age, address, insurance info, and the registration ID / password for the site — immediately at hand. The faster you can go through the registration process, the more likely you are to actually get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRD8jU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague Cory Zapatka says that he highly recommends using a password manager if you have one. He created accounts with all the vaccination sites in his area, even if they didn’t have appointments available at the time, so that if / when the time came, he could just auto-fill and get in right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9bBlc"&gt;And if you do get an appointment, make sure you have the appropriate paperwork already handy — especially since available appointments can be last minute. Necessary paperwork could include proof of employment, proof of age, or proof of a qualifying condition. Since the last one may require a doctor’s note or other record, it’s a good idea to call your doctor now — or if you’ve got access to a doctor’s or hospital website, that may offer you access to the proof you need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dqUcf"&gt;One more thing: check to see if you’ve gotten all the email that has been sent to you by your vaccine supplier. At least one staff member of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; found a necessary consent form hiding in her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCK4vB"&gt;Watch for news of upcoming vaccination sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bDlWg4"&gt;Keep an eye on the news. More and more sites and hubs are being added as the US gears up for a stronger push. If you see a news item saying that a hub is about to open, find the site for the hub and keep checking — once it does open, the available slots will probably go quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz172X"&gt;One thing that sometimes helps is to look for patterns in the appearance of new appointments. For example, when I heard that the pharmacy chain Walgreens was going to begin giving out vaccines in my area, I spent a couple of days going onto the site, and suddenly realized that there was a pattern: the company was only scheduling appointments two to four days in advance and was adding new appointments each day just after midnight. Once I understood the pattern, I was able to get appointments for a couple of friends, and let others know about it as well. (Note: since vaccine supplies and scheduling methods can change on a dime, this particular strategy may no longer work by the time you read this.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsRia6ki1VqiuNodQvjKHdK9-ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299690/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_8.47.56_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gz26d4"&gt;Look for help online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PgrwN8"&gt;There are a number of online resources popping up headed by developers and other technology-savvy folks who have taken the time and effort to try to make sense of this confusion. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/10/covid-vaccine-appointment-websites/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/09/nyregion/vaccine-website-appointment-nyc.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some of these listings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vhk2GI"&gt;An NYC site called &lt;a href="https://www.turbovax.info/"&gt;TurboVax&lt;/a&gt; pulls “the latest appointments from 43 city and state-run vaccine sites in the NYC area” and puts them on Twitter. Followers who set their Twitter notifications for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/turbovax"&gt;@turbovax&lt;/a&gt; can quickly find out about newly opened appointment slots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c0AX5B"&gt;Another called &lt;a href="https://nycvaccinelist.com/"&gt;NYC Vaccine List&lt;/a&gt; uses a combination of scripts and checks by volunteers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;scour various sites for openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="111Dwk"&gt;In California, &lt;a href="https://www.vaccinateca.com/"&gt;VaccinateCA&lt;/a&gt; checks pharmacies and hospitals for information about open appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZYJAS8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatenj.com/"&gt;Vaccinate NJ&lt;/a&gt; also uses volunteers to try to help state residents find vaccine opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZJic26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.covid19vaccinetx.com/"&gt;Covid 19 Vaccine TX&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced resource for registering with local counties and finding locations where vaccines may be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WLYqtL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.macovidvaccines.com/"&gt;MA Covid Vaccine Appointments site&lt;/a&gt; offers lists of and links to sites with available appointments. A volunteer-run Massachusetts site, &lt;a href="https://vaccinatema.com/"&gt;Vaccinate MA&lt;/a&gt;, tries to improve on the state website with a map-based design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yR8waA"&gt;A volunteer group in the state of Washington has launched the &lt;a href="https://www.covidwa.com/"&gt;WA COVID Vaccine Finder&lt;/a&gt; as an aggregation resource for vaccination appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C1YLfR"&gt;There are several sites that aggregate the aggregators: &lt;a href="https://wherecanigetavaccine.com/"&gt;Where Can I Get A Vaccine?&lt;/a&gt; offers a list of sites available for various US states. &lt;a href="https://covidshotfinder.com/"&gt;COVIDShotFinder&lt;/a&gt; lets you select a state or county and look for the various vaccine resources available. &lt;a href="https://www.findashot.org/"&gt;Find A Shot&lt;/a&gt; also shows you possible openings depending on your state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jdCWU8"&gt;One possible strategy is to use page-change-monitoring tools such as &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/blog/how-to-be-alerted-of-covid-19-vaccine-availability-in-your-local-pharmacy/"&gt;Visualping&lt;/a&gt; to generate alerts for when new appointments become available. These apps watch websites for you and send alerts to your email, text, or even Slack account when new information appears. They can be very useful (and allow you to take time for, say, lunch). But since these are, for the most part, business apps, you may need to pay for the privilege. For example, while &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/pricing"&gt;Visualping does have a free service&lt;/a&gt;, it is limited to pinging you once an hour up to 65 times a month, which may not be often enough if you’re trying to score an appointment.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="nhHjOx"&gt;By the way, if you’re a developer and / or coder who wants to help, check out &lt;a href="https://www.usdigitalresponse.org/"&gt;US Digital Response&lt;/a&gt;, an independent organization which, according to its website, “connects experienced, pro-bono technologists with local government and non-profit organizations responding to crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reservation Of The Anticovid Vaccine For Over Eighty In Apulian Pharmacies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4leCSmB_jTd6jhw7V_SvQQsfQ8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299704/1231117569.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Davide Pischettola / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are able, it’s a good idea to reach out and help those who may not be able to get appointments on their own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8mSy40"&gt;If you can, help others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Kz9AlN"&gt;One of the worst things about the distribution of the COVID-19 vaccines is that those who need it the most are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;often the least likely to be able to navigate the technology required to get an appointment&lt;/a&gt;: older people, differently abled people, or those who don’t have or can’t afford computers and / or internet connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2VOR9"&gt;If you have the time and talent, reach out to anyone you know who may not be able to get an appointment on their own. This could be as simple as finding phone numbers they can call to try to schedule an appointment, going online and getting an appointment for them, or helping them get to and from the vaccination site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evm4o5"&gt;You could also see if there are any groups that are organizing help. &lt;a href="https://www.westsiderag.com/2021/01/19/need-help-signing-up-for-a-vaccine-a-young-tech-savvy-person-can-help-you"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The West Side Rag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, reports that a group of New Yorkers created the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScO11RAr7tqHU6LJp_ZNMl5mRbxdg-zc1lO1SuVHBBDLTyJrg/closedform"&gt;Vaccine Appointment Assistance Team (VAAT)&lt;/a&gt; to help their non-technically-savvy neighbors navigate the process. (At the time this was written, because of low supplies of vaccine, VAAT had temporarily suspended their services.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rm5plO"&gt;Look for leftover vaccine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M5v0nn"&gt;While the vaccines can last for six months while they’re kept frozen, once thawed and refrigerated, the Pfizer vaccine will last five days while the Moderna vaccine will last for 30 days. As a result, when people don’t show up for their appointments, some centers will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229169/leftover-vaccines-random-people-grocery-stores-pharmacies"&gt;offer vaccinations to those who may not immediately qualify&lt;/a&gt; rather than waste vaccines that would otherwise be rendered unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI3933"&gt;However, running to a nearby pharmacy or vaccine hub in the hit-and-miss hopes that there will be some shots waiting at the end of the day isn’t the most effective way to be vaccinated. (Besides, getting hypothermia while waiting in the cold isn’t going to help.) At least one group is trying to ameliorate the situation: a pilot project called &lt;a href="https://vaxstandby.com/"&gt;Vaccination Standby&lt;/a&gt; says that it will monitor providers around the US for word of extra doses and text notifications to those whose zip codes are near the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAc3tM"&gt;There are also local organizations that are offering standby lists. For example, Buncombe County in North Carolina has a &lt;a href="https://www.buncombecounty.org/countycenter/news-detail.aspx?id=19137"&gt;vaccination waitlist and standby list&lt;/a&gt;, as does the &lt;a href="https://www.co.monroe.in.us/egov/documents/1611179705_09719.pdf"&gt;Monroe County Health Department&lt;/a&gt; in Indiana. Check your local government site to see if there’s one in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fg3eNk"&gt;Be persistent!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JTTPvK"&gt;Yes, it’s frustrating as hell, but keep at it. If a website crashes, try again. If you’re dropped from a phone call, call again (and have a game, video, or book ready to keep yourself occupied while you’re on hold). If you can’t find anything during working hours, try late at night or very early in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBXxUO"&gt;Persistence may be one of the most important aspects of getting an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. You may be tempted to give up, especially after hitting the “no appointments available” wall time and time again. But until vaccine production is ramped up enough to cover more of our population, and until distribution becomes more organized and easier to manage, simple stubbornness may be your best tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwiVs8"&gt;And hopefully this article, and all the advice it contains, will soon be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QdqaC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 11:10AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include the WA Covid Vaccine Finder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rW1K6i"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 16th, 10:10AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include a mention of webpage change monitoring tools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Jkqbm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 19th, 11AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include another Massachusetts site and two general vaccination finding sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSy6ej"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 22nd, 10:40AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add the Find A Shot site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwQk0g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0F1RM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
