<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-21T16:04:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T16:04:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T16:04:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch is finally making some friends in the music industry</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SVqXVu1F7pFy_rz2cHhAYXHCsck=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890137/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bTdSQo"&gt;Twitch is attempting to mend fences with a big pillar of the music industry by announcing an agreement to “work together” with the National Music Publishers’ Association (NMPA). Details are vague right now, but the agreement says they plan to “build productive partnerships between the service and music publishers” after a year of conflict over music rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXHKXS"&gt;Twitch has long had a contentious relationship with the music industry, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534983/riaa-copyright-twitch-streamers-licensing-letter"&gt;has accused the company&lt;/a&gt; of allowing streamers to play copyrighted music without the appropriate licenses. Streamers have come under the eye of music publishers as well, with some being subject to waves of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562372/twitch-soundtrack-riaa-music-youtube"&gt;Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) takedown notices&lt;/a&gt; that resulted in Twitch deleting content from their channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EKp9nF"&gt;The Amazon-owned streaming service is now attempting to appease both groups, with the agreement suggesting there could be new business opportunities for publishers down the road and fewer takedown notices for streamers. Neither is guaranteed, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HoNNNc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s a new reporting process rights holders can opt in to&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vCU2nK"&gt;The one tangible announcement here is a new — and potentially more forgiving — reporting process that music publishers can use to flag songs being used without a license in someone’s stream. The idea of this, in part, is to “address when creators inadvertently or incidentally use music in their streams,” according to a press release. This process starts with a warning instead of immediate penalties, according to Twitch, which could address critiques from streamers who had their content deleted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8BuhzG"&gt;That said, this new process is &lt;em&gt;separate&lt;/em&gt; from the one in place for the DMCA, and it does not change Twitch’s rules about how music can be used on the platform. And &lt;a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/business/9633425/twitch-nmpa-music-publishers-agreement"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Twitch isn’t paying for additional music licenses as part of the deal, so it’s unclear exactly how much will change as a result of this new partnership. If publishers opt in to the new process, it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; resolve DMCA issues. But since that requires the rights holders to opt in and use it instead of the traditional takedown notice, we just don’t know yet if that will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ptWik"&gt;The rest of the deal promises some grand partnerships — “from virtual shows to studio sessions, the partnerships stemming from this agreement will connect the Twitch community in many ways to the music they enjoy” — but we don’t have a great idea of what it all amounts to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9y4Cs"&gt;The agreement indicates Twitch is at least attempting to resolve some of the issues with licensed music on the platform — and, ideally, ease some of the burden from streamers who get punished for playing music on their channel. But right now, we just don’t know how much of an impact the deal will have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="MRkLHE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The music industry has taken another step toward a legal fight with Twitch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534983/riaa-copyright-twitch-streamers-licensing-letter"},{"title":"Bait and Twitch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562372/twitch-soundtrack-riaa-music-youtube"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686404/twitch-national-music-publishers-association-nmpa-agreement-music"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686404/twitch-national-music-publishers-association-nmpa-agreement-music</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T16:01:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T16:01:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix is reportedly closing in on its biggest acquisition ever — the Roald Dahl catalog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q0Q6WAWoZOdi0eRhr1bmOt0bZ1Q=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890125/RD_NETFLIX_LH_V009__0_00_07_21_20181127_5885_fizs41.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0888VS"&gt;Nearly three years after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18114572/netflix-animated-adaptations-willy-wonka-matilda-bfg-roald-dahl-books"&gt;Netflix signed a deal with The Roald Dahl Story Company&lt;/a&gt; to create a universe of animated features based on the author’s books,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-21/netflix-is-said-to-be-nearing-deal-to-buy-roald-dahl-catalog"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports the streamer is in talks to buy the works outright. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ElJ737"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Reed Hastings and the Giant Acquisition&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w8zHLF"&gt;There’s no word on exactly how much it costs to own Willy Wonka, the BFG, Matilda, and all the rest, but in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/netflixs-roald-dahl-deal-could-create-tv-universe-1164419/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter &lt;/em&gt;cited&lt;/a&gt; sources claiming that simply licensing 16 titles from the catalog cost Netflix more than $100 million. A deal for this catalog would likely rank as Netflix’s largest, and if it’s close enough that an announcement is possible within “days,” as the report suggests, we could hear more during Netflix’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641142/netflix-tudum-fan-trailers-interviews-announcements-date-movies-shows"&gt;Tudum fan event this weekend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OB1nK0"&gt;Under the current deal, Taika Waititi is &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/taika-waititi-netflix-charlie-and-the-chocolate-factory-animated-series-willy-wonka-oompa-loompa-1203524577/"&gt;working on Roald Dahl animated series projects for Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, covering &lt;em&gt;Charlie and the Chocolate Factory &lt;/em&gt;and its sequel, &lt;em&gt;Charlie and the Great Glass Elevator&lt;/em&gt;. That’s in addition to two different versions of Matilda, including a film version of &lt;em&gt;Matilda the Musical&lt;/em&gt; and an animated series, plus plans to make a&lt;em&gt; The BFG&lt;/em&gt; cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m9mWcX"&gt;At those costs, it’s clear why Netflix might be ready to pay whatever it costs to secure rights to those properties long-term. If the deal is closed, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;notes it will happen despite the shadow cast by Dahl’s history of antisemitic statements and sometimes &lt;a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/politics/2018/11/i-d-still-read-roald-dahl-s-books-my-children-we-can-t-forget-he-was-anti-semite"&gt;misogynistic storytelling&lt;/a&gt;. The Dahl Family and the Roald Dahl Story Company &lt;a href="https://www.roalddahl.com/global/rdsc-and-family-notice"&gt;released an apology&lt;/a&gt; for the remarks in 2020, saying, “We hope that, just as he did at his best, at his absolute worst, Roald Dahl can help remind us of the lasting impact of words.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686472/netflix-rumor-roald-dahl-willy-wonka-bfg-matilda"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686472/netflix-rumor-roald-dahl-willy-wonka-bfg-matilda</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T15:34:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T15:34:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11 won’t stop older PCs, but it might make you sign this waiver</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fJrKyASnXL6ZlXdEAyK6l9bFvQQ=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889997/Screen_Shot_2021_06_24_at_9.54.09_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DLpxf2"&gt;Today, Microsoft officially reinstated its PC Health Check app for anyone to download, letting you easily see whether your computer is ready for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557060/microsoft-windows-11-hands-on-preview"&gt;Windows 11&lt;/a&gt; ahead of its October 5th debut. (The company had previously removed the app because it was somewhat misleading, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22644194/microsoft-windows-11-minimum-system-requirements-processors-changes"&gt;when a more robust version returned in late August&lt;/a&gt;, it was only available to Windows Insiders.) You can find the app at the very bottom &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fwindows%2Fwindows-11" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;of this page&lt;/a&gt; if you scroll down, or &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; if you don’t mind direct downloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9Vzdk"&gt;But in some ways, the new PC Health Check app is &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; misleading because it suggests my perfectly good 7th-gen Core i7 desktop gaming PC isn’t ready for Windows 11, despite the fact that I’ve already installed Windows 11 and am running it with no major issues. In fact, I took this screenshot of my system that “doesn’t currently meet Windows 11 system requirements” &lt;em&gt;from inside Windows 11 — &lt;/em&gt;a beta version that’s just a stone’s throw away from final. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p5uh9SRZohO5jKenDWvIQUXhJCc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867880/health_check_sean.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;My 7th-gen i7 might be more capable than a supported 8th-gen i3, but no official support for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ur4lQT"&gt;This is a long-winded way of saying what Microsoft revealed to us in August: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22644194/microsoft-windows-11-minimum-system-requirements-processors-changes"&gt;Windows 11 will not block PCs with older CPUs from installing Windows 11&lt;/a&gt; just because those CPUs aren’t on its whitelist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AqT1SZ"&gt;Instead, Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/28/22646035/microsoft-windows-11-iso-workaround-no-update-guarantee"&gt;reserving the right to deny you Windows Updates&lt;/a&gt;, up to and including security updates, if those CPUs become a problem down the line. That brings me to the waiver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q2sxBV"&gt;When I recently tried to upgrade my system to the Windows 11 beta, the installer popped up an unusual message: a press-button-to-accept acknowledgment that my PC would “no longer be supported” and that I might even be voiding my PC’s warranty if I were to continue. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ItjuyT2m5N2LVVyxDHQSzA3X0yk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867844/waiver_windows_11.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Windows 11 upgrade waiver I spotted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OafLZ8"&gt;I’ve asked Microsoft for more information on the waiver but haven’t heard back yet. I’ll let you know what we hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tb9MUa"&gt;The PC Health Check app &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;handy if you aren’t sure about some of the other Windows 11 requirements, particularly ones that might make you dig into your BIOS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security"&gt;to turn on your TPM 2.0 module or Secure Boot&lt;/a&gt; — things that your system might totally already have and are fairly easy to switch on but are often turned off by default. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="u6MQBI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Windows 11 upgrade situation just got less and more confusing","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22643275/windows-11-upgrade-system-requirements-pc-health-check"},{"title":"Microsoft is threatening to withhold Windows 11 updates if your CPU is old","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/28/22646035/microsoft-windows-11-iso-workaround-no-update-guarantee"},{"title":"Why Windows 11 is forcing everyone to use TPM chips","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OcIARz"&gt;Microsoft will hold a Surface event tomorrow, September 22nd. We’ll be live, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"&gt;here’s what to expect&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686457/windows-11-health-check-compatible-supported-cpu-old-pc-waiver"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686457/windows-11-health-check-compatible-supported-cpu-old-pc-waiver</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T14:51:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T14:51:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple updates macOS Safari with a new look, but you can turn off the big changes  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ClwxmS1tx6h35I4zaLj-NSLsmnU=/72x0:3033x1974/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889701/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_10.13.17_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f7yYKY"&gt;Apple has released a redesigned version of Safari for macOS Big Sur and Catalina. The update, announced as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;the upcoming macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt;, was released the same day as iOS and iPadOS 15, bringing the web browser’s new look and features across Apple’s platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhGyTy"&gt;To update to the new Safari 15, you can go to System Preferences &amp;gt; Software Update, where it should automatically refresh and show up. Unlike updates to macOS, you shouldn’t have to reboot your computer after updating Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ifbP7h"&gt;The development behind this version of Safari has been interesting. The full OS update that it was originally a part of, which also brings features like Universal Control and Quick Notes, isn’t here yet, but Apple decided to ship the new Safari anyway. For those who have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;upgraded to iOS 15&lt;/a&gt;, that’s a good thing — it means that you can immediately use tab groups across all your devices. The update &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmacos%2Fmonterey-preview%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F21%2F22686070%2Fapple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;also includes features&lt;/a&gt; like better tracking protection and automatic switching to HTTPS for sites that support it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K1ya7BytHYBoR43IHnYVerGzVSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867613/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.13.23_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s original vision for Safari 15, which has been toned down slightly over the beta period.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pPxAad"&gt;While the Safari update brings new features, it also brings a new design. Apple’s made several changes to it since it was announced (though not as many as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629183/ios-15-beta-safar-address-bar-fix-options-accessible-controls"&gt;it’s made to Safari for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;), tweaking it to be less starkly minimal. Looks-wise, it’s still a major change from Safari 14, but there are preferences that you can tweak to walk back some of the more distracting changes. If you don’t want websites to be able to change the color of your tab bar, you can go to Safari’s preferences &amp;gt; Tabs, and uncheck “Show color in tab bar.” If you want your tabs to be on their own row, you can switch from Compact mode to Separate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7gw4O1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10765531"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5BhnTyGRWTeUiCyHZHXIlGTEjqs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867568/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.50.16_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “I prefer the old Safari” config.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CBUpAT"&gt;Unchecking “Automatically collapse tab titles into icons” turns the tab bar into a sort of carousel when you have too many of them. I certainly don’t prefer it, but it’s an option if that’s your sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qhpaRgyCNx2coIns0bGV37hs-JM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867576/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.52.35_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unchecking the “automatically collapse tab titles” box hides the true chaos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ux5zvl"&gt;While Safari 15 takes a bit to get used to (I'm still getting over the learning curve myself), Tab Groups is a great feature to share between my iPhone and computer. Safari 15 also comes with the &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212816"&gt;usual host of security updates&lt;/a&gt;, though none seem too severe. After you update, be sure to let us know what you think of the new design — is it a breath of fresh air or just another refresh that you’ll grudgingly get used to?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T14:09:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T14:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos just fixed the main drawback of its excellent Roam portable speaker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Np87jLGt21bxcuhrd-2RAbTvtT0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889511/RoamSidetable.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7aDukN"&gt;I’m generally a big fan of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368487/sonos-roam-bluetooth-speaker-review-features"&gt;Sonos Roam&lt;/a&gt;, but in the months since the portable speaker was released, I’ve definitely come across one downside: subpar power management. When the device is sitting around idle, its battery drains much faster than I’d like — and more rapidly than most Bluetooth speakers. Sometimes that means a dead Roam at the very moment you want to use it most. This has led me to completely power off the speaker when it’s not being used, which is less than ideal for something that’s meant to slot into a multi-room sound system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aa8NZQ"&gt;Thankfully, today, Sonos has made some improvements to address battery drain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wPXwm3"&gt;After installing the latest software update (with the Sonos app on Android or iOS), the Roam should last longer on a charge when it’s not doing anything. “We’ve improved Roam’s power management to help extend Roam’s battery life when it’s not actively being used,” Sonos said in its update notes for the Sonos S2 13.3 update. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ORZBUs5UAHQfPO5KtvUNUWlvfqY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22422266/RoamFrame.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roam’s playback buttons can now wake it from sleep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P7dKpd"&gt;The update also makes it possible to wake the Roam from sleep by pressing any of the buttons on top; before, this could only be done with the power button around back. And the Sonos app will now notify you if the Roam is connected to a charger that isn’t providing enough juice to actually charge the battery. Last, Sonos says two Roams that had been stereo paired will now automatically relink if one of them briefly loses connection to the network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bj12a"&gt;To install the update, make sure you’ve got the latest version of the Sonos app installed on Android, iOS, PC, or Mac. On mobile, you should automatically be prompted to update your devices when you open the app. If not, you can still manually check for the update by tapping on the gear tab, choosing system, and then system updates.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686311/sonos-roam-battery-drain-fix-update-idle-inactive"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686311/sonos-roam-battery-drain-fix-update-idle-inactive</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:42:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:42:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mercedes-Benz EQS will cost over $100,000 but is still cheaper than an S-Class</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zcZA04A3DITm0pULs3vB9tAqiDY=/428x0:5045x3078/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889348/The_All_New_EQS.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZsDOKu"&gt;Mercedes-Benz just announced the pricing of its all-electric luxury sedan, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375877/mercedes-benz-eqs-ev-s-class-specs-hands-on"&gt;the EQS&lt;/a&gt;, and not surprisingly, it starts north of $100,000. What is surprising, though, is that the starting price is cheaper than a gas-powered S-Class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hRvyJ2"&gt;When it arrives at dealerships this fall, the EQS will start at $102,310. By comparison, the 2022 Mercedes-Benz S-Class starts at $111,350. This is a rare case of an electric vehicle selling cheaper than its gas equivalent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DyAoO2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is a rare case of an electric vehicle selling cheaper than its gas equivalent. &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MsnTct"&gt;Mercedes is offering three trim levels: Premium, Exclusive, and Pinnacle. Each trim comes in two versions, depending on the size of the infotainment screen: the 450+ sedan with a 12.8-inch portrait touchscreen; or the 580 4MATIC (yes, I know, these brand names are inscrutable) with the 56-inch Hyperscreen. Both versions of each trim come with Mercedes’ MBUX voice-activated assistant as standard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8YB3k2"&gt;Here is a glance at the features that come with each trim level:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7-7rhxLY6sVwJ2RrEet-nmu5D4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867622/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_1.14.47_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2smZFH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588587/mercedes-benz-electric-ev-2030-caveat"&gt;As we’ve noted previously&lt;/a&gt;, Mercedes is interested in testing out whether customers are willing to pay more for added features, even after buying the vehicle. The company is offering various add-ons, like an increased steering angle for the rear wheels, which customers can pay to unlock and then receive as an over-the-air software update. It’s easy to see how the initial cost can rise steadily as owners decide they want more unique features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9utUbt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 2022 Mercedes-Benz EQS is a declaration of maximum electric luxury","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375877/mercedes-benz-eqs-ev-s-class-specs-hands-on"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="8ZnPwu"&gt;Still, it’s clear that Mercedes is trying to make a statement by pricing the EQS cheaper than the S-Class. The company has said it wants to shift to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588587/mercedes-benz-electric-ev-2030-caveat"&gt;EV-only sales by 2030&lt;/a&gt;. To get there, it will need to price its vehicles in a way that will make its wealthy customers think twice about replacing their old S-Class with just another gas-powered vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686248/mercedes-benz-eqs-electric-vehicle-price-cheaper-s-class"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686248/mercedes-benz-eqs-electric-vehicle-price-cheaper-s-class</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:13:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:13:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>As lawsuits pile up, Activision Blizzard loses its chief legal officer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0N8rJkkZxxdBBH8DnnI0YfR3lpQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889215/acastro_210729_1777_blizzard_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uo75mT"&gt;Another high-level Activision Blizzard employee has left the company. Claire Hart, Blizzard’s chief legal officer, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/claireelisehart_after-more-than-three-years-at-blizzard-entertainment-activity-6845779647314169856-Nnrf/?src=aff-lilpar&amp;amp;veh=aff_src.aff-lilpar_c.partners_pkw.10078_plc.Skimbit%20Ltd._pcrid.449670_learning&amp;amp;trk=aff_src.aff-lilpar_c.partners_pkw.10078_plc.Skimbit%20Ltd._pcrid.449670_learning&amp;amp;clickid=waH1njULNxyORZnwUx0Mo38VUkBQ6MyXVRgd2Q0&amp;amp;irgwc=1"&gt;announced in a LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt; that her last day was Friday, September 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YFm0Tt"&gt;“The past three years have been full of unexpected twists and turns, but I feel honored to have worked with and met so many great people at Blizzard and across the Activision Blizzard businesses,” Hunt said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UDzQpG"&gt;Those “unexpected twists and turns” might be an allusion to the series of legal troubles Activision Blizzard faces due to allegations of harassment, abuse, and discrimination. To date, Activision Blizzard is facing suits from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Nx3jXE"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;California Department of Fair Employment and Housing&lt;/a&gt; for enabling a “culture of harassment.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xS5Ran"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ecf.cacd.uscourts.gov/doc1/031136037480"&gt;Its own investors&lt;/a&gt; for essentially failing to accurately disclose knowledge of these harassment and discrimination problems to investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xA5s6g"&gt;The CODE-CWA for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674269/activision-blizzard-sued-nlrb-labor-violations"&gt;unfair labor practices&lt;/a&gt; involving intimidating employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="hQE8OV"&gt;And Activision Blizzard is under investigation by the EEOC and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684779/activision-blizzard-investigation-sec-activision-bobby-kotick"&gt;SEC&lt;/a&gt; — all within the last four months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="toj0zE"&gt;Hunt’s departure is the latest in a string of high-profile employees leaving amidst the company’s ever-growing legal issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9HLKOU"&gt;Blizzard president &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt; and head of global human resources &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608320/blizard-jesse-meschuk-leave-company-hr-svp"&gt;Jesse Meschuk&lt;/a&gt; left in early August. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;Three top game designers&lt;/a&gt; who worked on such titles as &lt;em&gt;Diablo 4&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; also left Blizzard in August. (Blizzard did not confirm if they were fired or left voluntarily.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkAMSB"&gt;Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick said &lt;a href="https://investor.activision.com/news-releases/news-release-details/activision-blizzard-provides-update-workplace-initiatives"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt; that the company is cooperating with all these investigations and that “there is absolutely no place anywhere in our company for discrimination, harassment, or unequal treatment of any kind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LO7gF4"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1bkEp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOMHUD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686183/activision-blizzard-chief-legal-officer-leaves"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686183/activision-blizzard-chief-legal-officer-leaves</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook put a battery in its new Portal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1_ZeTc0jT0_ZVZvVZc3VHXPacvI=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889145/Portal_Go_Portal__Family_Call.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook’s Portal Go and Portal Plus&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8epFkM"&gt;Facebook on Tuesday announced two new Portal video calling devices, the first major refresh of the hardware lineup since 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNzLfm"&gt;The new devices, the Portal Go and updated Portal Plus, retail for $199 and $349, respectively. The 10-inch Portal Go is an all-new, portable form factor wrapped in fabric with a standalone battery, while the latest Portal Plus introduces a sleeker design of the most expensive, 14-inch Portal that first debuted three years ago. Both devices are available now for preorder and start shipping on October 19th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sH7bsy"&gt;Like the rest of the lineup, the Portal Go features a wide-angle camera that automatically follows whoever is in focus, zooming and panning as they move in and out of the center of the frame. It’s the first Portal that doesn’t require a constant power connection, and Facebook is also billing it as a portable Bluetooth speaker with support for Spotify and Pandora. The new Portal Plus functions similarly to its predecessor, but Facebook got rid of the swivel display that could rotate from portrait to landscape view. Both Portals have a physical shutter to cover the camera like past versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="f5E5WM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re really looking ahead to the future of hybrid work.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9b9Aff"&gt;Unlike Amazon’s Echo lineup of smart home devices, Facebook’s Portal is almost entirely intended for video calling. The latest software updates to Portal’s Android-based interface put even more of an emphasis on video calls in a remote work setting. A new calendar app syncs with Outlook or Google to show upcoming meetings and let you quickly jump into calls from Portal’s home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j74RTQ"&gt;Aside from Facebook-owned Messenger and WhatsApp, all Portal devices now support Zoom, Cisco’s Webex, BlueJeans, and GoToMeeting. And in December, Portal will add support for Microsoft Teams, potentially opening it up for use by a wider swath of mid to large-size companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1d74BZ"&gt;The integration with Teams is an example of how Facebook thinks Portal will increasingly be used as a standalone video conferencing device for remote workers. Next year, the company will launch a program to let businesses bulk order and manage Portals that can, for the first time, be used without a Facebook account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AqmGfy"&gt;“We’re really looking ahead to the future of hybrid work,” Micah Collins, Facebook’s director of product management for Portal, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;during a virtual briefing last week. He said that Portal is primarily used between families but that the company saw a noticeable uptick in usage for work meetings since pandemic shutdowns began last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wjquyaTwY28AsZZdc-O70jSMcjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865278/Microsoft_Teams_GroupCall_Portal_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TtmmsIWpbkxzKY4E3qpIanU4nbA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865610/Portal_Go_Video_Call_Kitchen.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VzGpx-gtynMHsgJVKUyIccxhNaI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865613/Portal__Kitchen_Home_Screen.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Portal Plus (top left and above) and the portal Portal Go (top right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fKvMDB"&gt;Facebook hasn’t disclosed Portal sales, but according to the research firm IDC, it shipped more than 600,000 Portals last year, an increase of over 28% from 2019. And it shipped close to 400,000 units in the first half of this year — a signal that sales will grow year-over-year again. Those numbers pale in comparison to the success of Amazon’s Echo lineup, though Amazon hasn’t disclosed sales for its most direct Portal competitor, the video calling-equipped Echo Show. (Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379470/apple-tv-homepod-speaker-camera-video-call-soundbar-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;also rumored&lt;/a&gt; to be working on a dedicated video calling device.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1JBMRX"&gt;While Facebook is showing steady growth with Portal sales, its “growth is dampened by negative brand perceptions,” Adam Wright, IDC’s senior analyst for smart home devices, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;Even still, he noted that “some aggressive marketing during the early stages of the Covid-19 pandemic” helped boost sales by positioning Portal “as a good way to minimize the impacts of lockdowns and social distancing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBalgk"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20913653/facebook-portal-10-inch-2019-review-price-specs-features-whatsapp-video-calling"&gt;our 2019 review of the Portal lineup&lt;/a&gt;, we gave the devices poor marks for the lack of streaming services and apps, poor sound quality for playing music, and the requirement of needing a Facebook account. While the app integrations have certainly improved, Portal still doesn’t support most of the major video streaming services. And a Facebook account is still needed unless the Portal is purchased through the new business program.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684447/facebook-releases-portal-go-plus-video-calling-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684447/facebook-releases-portal-go-plus-video-calling-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roblox will start verifying the age of teenage players</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NI6NMNtfcvBuM8dmxl3puNiN1X0=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889125/Roblox_Age_Verification.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Roblox’s age verification process involves scanning government-issued ID. | Image: Roblox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A1clox"&gt;Roblox is rolling out an age verification feature that will allow players to confirm their age and gain access to features reserved for older players. Age verification will be optional, and Roblox tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it will “not retain any data” from the verification process, which requires showing a form of ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgXArS"&gt;For now, only one feature requires age verification: Roblox’s new voice chat feature, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654884/roblox-voice-chat-spatial-moderation-discord"&gt;Spacial Voice&lt;/a&gt;. During its initial beta test, it will only be available to players who verify they are at least 13 years old. (Roblox didn’t say whether it would later be available to users regardless of verification status.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rPcvpp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Roblox, explained: Everything you wanted to know about one of the biggest apps on the planet","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22457264/roblox-explainer-game-app-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KFdBlu"&gt;But the implication seems to be that other features — perhaps specific Roblox games or community tools — could be age-gated as the company works to protect its relatively young user base. More than half of Roblox’s users are still under 13 (Roblox says “nearly 50 percent” were over 13 as of the second quarter of the year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JHjxd"&gt;Verification will require uploading an “ID card, driver’s license, or passport” as well as a selfie taken “on the spot” to help confirm that the ID was really uploaded by the person to whom it belongs. Roblox only accepts government-issued IDs, which could pose a problem — younger players are less likely to have formal IDs than older players, and that’s likely even less common in certain regions where an ID is harder to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wsyhqq"&gt;The feature starts rolling out today and will be available globally to users who are at least 13 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0MGG0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction September 21st, 4:05PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Nearly” half of Roblox’s users are now over 13; this story initially said more than half were over 13.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684672/roblox-age-verification-optional"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684672/roblox-age-verification-optional</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:55:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:55:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 worked fine with the slowest compatible SSD we could find</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YwHqYsnb0TPi6LXwXx2bvXuK8o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69676444/vpavic_4278_20201030_0206.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eGpAhB"&gt;If your PS5 is already running out of speedy solid state storage, there’s a fix. Sony’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22664808/ps5-playstation-5-update-m2-ssd-sony-software"&gt;new update for the PS5&lt;/a&gt;, released in full on September 14th, allows you to expand your paltry 667GB of usable space by popping in the same sort of M.2 SSD stick you might slip into your laptop or desktop PC. My colleague Mitchell has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22366087"&gt;a PS5 SSD buying guide right here&lt;/a&gt; that meets all of Sony’s recommendations, such as speeds of at least 5,500MB/s. That might leave you wondering, though: what about slower SSDs? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AJUnow"&gt;That’s why we tracked down an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/XPG-S50-Lite-Internal-AGAMMIXS50L-1T-C/dp/B08HVZWGPP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ADATA XPG Gammix S50 Lite&lt;/a&gt;, one of the slowest compatible PCIe Gen4 drives we could find at 3,900MB/s reads and 3,200MB/s writes, and stuck it into a PS5 in August. And this week, &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry &lt;/em&gt;corroborated our findings with an even slower SSD with 3,200MB/s writes. The short version: today’s games don’t need all the speed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The PS5 reads 3898.001 megabytes per second in its speed test" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4_5tGJnWAryRays4zRc7ziYw5go=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759876/IMG_1307.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Yep, that’s a 3900MB/s drive all right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="v7uWpg"&gt;We compared the S50 Lite against both the PS5’s internal SSD and a 5,000MB/s Sabrent Rocket 500GB in a battery of tests, including load times for games like early PS5 showcases &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales.&lt;/em&gt; We also measured how long it takes to back up games to each kind of drive, throwing in a Seagate external HDD for comparison, since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381494/sony-ps5-april-update-games-external-usb-storage-social-features"&gt;Sony now allows you to archive PS5 games and play PS4 games&lt;/a&gt; from an traditional hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dE5QEx"&gt;The verdict? Surprisingly, even the slowest compatible SSD we could find had near-identical load times to the one Sony includes in the box. Sometimes it’s a second slower, sometimes a second or two faster, but basically it’s a total wash. Hopping through dimensions in &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;, I saw no appreciable difference with the slowest SSD in gameplay, either. Stepping through pocket dimensions was instantaneous, and when there was a slight pause during a boss fight, I saw the same pause on the internal SSD as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qHZe23"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10684101"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zea66Q"&gt;I also didn’t necessarily see a huge difference between the drives when it comes to transferring games back and forth, but there was one big surprise: at least in this beta, it appears that Sony may be throttling the write speed of the PS5’s own internal drive. It took only 2:26 to send &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22274549/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-ps5-update-graphics-expansion"&gt;both PS5 and PS4 copies&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; to the Sabrent SSD, for instance, but 12:47 to go back to the PS5 — over five times longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="59Q8qI"&gt;On average, I saw write speeds of around 1,100MB/s transferring my five test games to either of my add-in M.2 drives, but just around 220MB/s sending those same games back to the PS5. Both of those are far better than the 141MB/s average transfer speeds I saw sending games to the Seagate HDD and the 97MB/s I saw beaming them back — it took over half an hour (31:24) to transfer the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games’ 176.5GB back to the internal SSD. But the slower internal SSD write speeds are weird, and Sony didn’t have a comment when I asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QT365P"&gt;In late September, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-the-worst-and-best-nvme-ssds-tested-on-playstation-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry &lt;/em&gt;tested an even slower drive&lt;/a&gt;: the 256GB version of Western Digital’s SN750 SE, which is capable of just 3,200MB/sec reads. And yet, the results were the same. Even with a drive that only offers 58 percent of the speeds Sony asks for, there was effectively no difference in today’s games — and Sony appears to be artificially limiting transfers back to the internal drive for some undisclosed reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSk2nn"&gt;So the big question is this: if not today, will game developers fully optimize tomorrow’s games for the incredible speeds a top-tier SSD can afford? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D718aM"&gt;For instance, take a look at our load times for &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; in our original chart above. Regardless of drive, the PS4 version takes over four times longer to load! It’s the difference between waiting through a loading screen filled with gameplay tips to keep you occupied, and — at 10 seconds flat from the time you leave the PS5’s home screen to the time you can move Cloud Strife in your save game — barely seeing a loading screen at all. The latter is incredible to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YlIBe4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4WZ3pTe61O4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kOH5dC"&gt;Also, see our &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Miles Morales &lt;/em&gt;numbers? The game doesn’t &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; load as quickly as it could. Sometimes, you’ll boot up the game to see Marvel, Insomniac, and PlayStation Studios intros that eat up a whole 26 seconds, making the game take more like 43 seconds to load in total. But other times, it’ll mysteriously bypass those, loading in more like 17 seconds, and I couldn’t figure out why. I’d love to have a toggle to turn off those intros, and here’s hoping more PS5 games skip them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4F4sa4"&gt;Would I run out and buy the slowest PCIe Gen4 SSD I can buy for my PS5? I’m not so sure, because Sony picked its recommended SSD spec for a reason — even if today’s games and today’s PS5 aren’t taking full advantage, developers may need that additional headroom in the future. They’ve been promised 5,500MB/s to deliver instant game worlds, and I’d hate to find out I bought the wrong drive years down the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5sHxD"&gt;Plus, there might already be some moments in &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;where you’ll notice a difference, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fitzymj/status/1420825603784122371"&gt;says Insomniac technical director Mike Fitzgerald&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lXpgVe"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We tried some below-spec Gen4 M.2 drives as well and saw up to 15% slower loading in the most SSD-stressing areas of the game. Not too shabby, but keep a close eye on technical specs if you’re making an SSD purchase, as our game does rely on high-quality storage.  &lt;/p&gt;— Mike Fitzgerald (@fitzymj) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fitzymj/status/1420825603784122371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jj3Wyt"&gt;Then again, Microsoft also uses an SSD in its Xbox Series X, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21185141/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-comparison-specs-features-release-date"&gt;but one with sustained raw performance at 2.4GB/s&lt;/a&gt;, compared to the PS5’s listed 5.5GB/s read speeds. So even if developers do take advantage, it’s possible many next-gen games never see the full benefit if they’re targeting both Xbox and PlayStation instead of PS5 specifically. You’ll likely see the most benefit from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432601/sony-playstation-studios-ps5-games-25-new-ip-interview"&gt;Sony’s exclusive PlayStation Studios titles,&lt;/a&gt; though Square Enix’s speedy &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade&lt;/em&gt; load times gives me hope for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pm1LS1"&gt;Either way, for a list of SSDs that actually meet Sony’s requirements and recommendations, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-m2-ssd-options-buying-guide-which-drives-compatible-playstation-5"&gt;here’s our buying guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UmGd7q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 2:08PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Clarified that we tested Ratchet and Clank gameplay, not just load times, and that the Xbox Series X’s 2.4GB/s is a sustained performance metric.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="paMKk4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, September 21st at 12:55PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added Digital Foundry’s tests with an even slower 3,200MB/sec drive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iu_-r-2u58AoJ6EYQq4n1dD3Go8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22748660/ps5ssd1_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22608153/ps5-ssd-speed-test-storage-expansion-m2-playstation-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22608153/ps5-ssd-speed-test-storage-expansion-m2-playstation-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
