<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-23T13:05:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T13:05:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T13:05:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new partnership aims to improve haptic feedback on Android devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Qualcomm Lofelt" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NDLypBfVTwnmXPYkTS4tEVU9_s0=/69x0:807x492/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862616/0_66eU5_KB84vIXV7A.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Qualcomm&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LLRmGy"&gt;Haptic feedback on Android phones running the Snapdragon 888 chipset might get noticeably better starting in the second half of 2021. Qualcomm recently announced (via &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/23/qualcomm-and-lofelt-join-forces-with-aim-to-improve-android-haptics/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) that it’s working independently with a company called Lofelt to enhance haptics through &lt;em&gt;software&lt;/em&gt;, not hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uI46SY"&gt;That initially read as a puzzling decision, since hardware — not software — seems to play the bigger role in the quality of the vibration. But this actually sounds very clever, definitely more clever than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/6/21/11993380/put-some-bass-on-your-wrist-basslet"&gt;Lofelt’s Basslet vibrating wearable&lt;/a&gt; that it launched on Kickstarter in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxTUdl"&gt;Outside of some high-end LG phones, most Android phones deliver muddy or rattling vibrations that don’t feel that great. Even the best ones can’t compete with Apple’s Taptic Engine it builds in-house and builds into iPhones and Apple Watch wearables. Tactile, punchy vibration probably isn’t high up on the list of many people in terms of must-have features, but it can go a surprisingly long way in making you feel like you’re using a quality product.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Qualcomm Lofelt" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wSZE_SMmiA5rHq5F1ZHtuU9fWe0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323210/0_66eU5_KB84vIXV7A.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Qualcomm&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RvbHly"&gt;Lofelt has developed a framework and an open API for phone manufacturers (as well as in game controllers “and beyond” &lt;a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/qku6b8nf1d79/6lLhSn0gs9DIb54g7HmQrV/40df630d856a049a228fcd8680a7eaab/Lofelt_Qualcomm_Partnership.pdf"&gt;says the press release&lt;/a&gt;) that can convert universal haptic data into signals that are finely tuned and improved for that device’s specific hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEIpXh"&gt;So, instead of incorporating a standard haptic actuator on the chipset that companies are required to adopt, it developed a more scalable software solution that can work on any phone running the required Snapdragon hardware. Manufacturers can keep making phones the way they want, and Lofelt’s API can help to create a more uniform haptic experience across the vast Android ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fdfbot"&gt;Lofelt CEO and co-founder Daniel Büttner spoke at length on &lt;em&gt;Medium &lt;/em&gt;in a post called &lt;a href="https://medium.com/lofelt/the-keys-to-delivering-better-haptics-on-android-f502403c22e7"&gt;“The Keys to Delivering Better Haptics on Android,”&lt;/a&gt; and it covers everything you’d want to know about why the gap between haptics on Android and Apple devices has been so wide in the past few years. It comes down to fragmentation, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhVxx9"&gt;Apple could set a standard for haptics on both a hardware and software level by which its small batch of phones abide. Android, on the other hand, is the Wild West in terms of haptics, as it is in most other areas. The post illustrates that pretty much the only way forward to improve haptics in Android is through software. Hey, if you can’t reverse fragmentation at this point, you might as well lean into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8tB2z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297285/qualcomm-lofelt-haptics-vibration-snapdragon-888-api-software"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297285/qualcomm-lofelt-haptics-vibration-snapdragon-888-api-software</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T13:02:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T13:02:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Frogger is coming to the Peacock streaming service as a game show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HZDVBm6_6apLZXNZlV4WlTVGb2Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862596/acastro_200714_1777_peacock_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cg0mJ1"&gt;Konami’s &lt;em&gt;Frogger &lt;/em&gt;game series is apparently &lt;a href="https://frogger.castingcrane.com/age-gate"&gt;getting turned into a game show&lt;/a&gt;, set to be streamed on NBC’s Peacock. The show’s contestants will apparently have to go through “physically demanding” obstacle courses and will be asked to “dodge treacherous traffic, leap over snapping gators and hop over hungry hippos to conquer the course.” One would hope those are simulated using foam and rubber. Otherwise, there could be some liability issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x6CNEw"&gt;The show promises longer episodes than normally expected from a game show: according to a promotional email, they’ll be an hour long (currently, 13 have been ordered). To be fair, I’ve definitely played over an hour of &lt;em&gt;Frogger&lt;/em&gt; before without even thinking about it, and as fun as the game is, it’ll probably be even more fun to watch humans try (and more importantly, fail) to overcome some of the same challenges gamers have had to over the years. Bonus points if they have to actually dress up as frogs, but perhaps that would make it &lt;em&gt;too &lt;/em&gt;challenging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hsr69"&gt;While the show will feature American contestants, it’s being filmed in Australia, according to &lt;a href="https://frogger.castingcrane.com"&gt;the sign-up form&lt;/a&gt;. The show also promises to pay the winner (who may be dubbed the Frogger?) a “huge cash prize,” but it doesn't specify how much that’ll actually be. Hopefully enough to afford a lakefront lilypad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tcOHZ"&gt;Streaming seems like the perfect medium for a physical challenge-based game show like this, especially if it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21324215/peacock-nbc-universal-comcast-app-how-to-watch-download-price-subscription-stream-shows"&gt;available on the free tier&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s hard to imagine many people carving out a time slot in their schedules to watch it like they’d have to with traditional television, it’s the type of thing people might look at on a weekend and say, “Oh, yeah, I’d love to watch some people fall on their faces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GZeOnJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297371/frogger-game-show-nbc-peacock-konami"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297371/frogger-game-show-nbc-peacock-konami</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:45:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:45:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lenovo’s refreshed ThinkPads feature Ryzen 5000 mobile chips and 16:10 displays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Lenovo ThinkPad T14s Gen 2 open, angled to the right. The screen displays a looking-up shot of skyscrapers. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pSgxK9JE9b4qLmJt8TVukpQhElw=/0x334:2000x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862530/05_Thinkpad_T14s_Gen_2_Hero_Front_Facing_Right.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Here’s the ThinkPad T14s Gen 2. | Lenovo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1z1AlI"&gt;Lenovo has announced a number of updates to its ThinkPad line. We’re getting upgrades to the lightweight ThinkPad X13 and convertible X13 Yoga, as well as the high-end T-Series, the budget-oriented L-Series, and the P-Series of mobile workstations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aD4w7D"&gt;The biggest news is that all of these models have gotten spec bumps. Each series includes models with AMD’s Ryzen 5000 mobile processors as well as Intel’s 11th Gen vPro chips. They’re also getting connectivity upgrades, including some options for Wi-Fi 6E on the Intel systems and Wi-Fi 6 for the AMD ones. Some models support 5G as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cDu2r"&gt;The news I’m personally most excited about is that the X13 i (Intel), X13 (AMD), and X13 Yoga (Intel) are getting 16:10 displays. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238671/16-9-aspect-ratio-hp-elite-folio-dell-latitude-lenovo-thinkbook-plus-legion-7"&gt;Manufacturers across the board&lt;/a&gt; have been switching to taller screens for business and productivity notebooks. They give you more room for multitasking and less of a need for scrolling and zooming out. There’s also a new Dolby Audio speaker system with user-facing speakers on the X13 — they were bottom-firing on previous models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDzPVg"&gt;The updated T-Series (including the T14s i, T14 i, and T15 with Intel and the T14s and T14 with AMD), L-Series (including the L14 and L15 with AMD and the L14 i and L15 i with Intel), and the P-Series (including the P14s, P14s i, and P15s) all include the new chips as well. The models also have new security options including Match-on-Chip fingerprint readers; some Intel systems including the T14s i and X13 i have human presence-detection sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo ThinkPad L15 Gen 2 open, angled to the left. The screen displays a PowerPoint presentation." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QZ_HC5eGrM7aBGWCt0wTtcm28hQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323082/04_Thinpad_L15_Gen_2_15inch_Hero_Front_Facing_Left_INTEL.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lenovo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s the ThinkPad L15, Gen 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5EH7tJ"&gt;Pricing and availability are a bit confusing, so bear with me. It looks like most of the Intel models are coming in March, while the AMD models are coming in May. The X13 Yoga is the exception — it’s coming in April. The T-Series starts at $1,159 (for the T14), the L-Series starts at $689 (for both models), and the P-Series starts at $1,3169 (for the P14s). The X13 starts at $1,139 (for the AMD model) and the X13 Yoga starts at $1,379. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UoxfdJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sT4vEb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cf2J60"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwlmX5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297126/lenovo-thinkpad-x13-yoga-laptops-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297126/lenovo-thinkpad-x13-yoga-laptops-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:38:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:38:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Are The Office and Friends bets paying off for Peacock and HBO Max?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/np3l1X4zX4j5SkvEJ2QXQfCeO0g=/0x5:1071x719/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862490/the_office.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: NBC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PtPrZL"&gt;In mid-2020, &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/23/21035338/friends-netflix-leaving-january-2020-hbo-max-may-streaming-seinfeld-the-office"&gt;moved to HBO Max exclusively&lt;/a&gt;. On January 1st, 2021, &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;made a similar move, leaving Netflix to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174856/the-office-netflix-peacock-streaming"&gt;stream solely on Peacock&lt;/a&gt;. The shows, whose moves cost a combined $1 billion roughly, were designed as anchors for the new streaming platforms: they would bring subscribers in and keep them subscribed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xyAzMX"&gt;Neither WarnerMedia nor NBCUniversal has given hard insights into how much &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;have driven subscriptions or retention, but new data from research firm Antenna provides some interesting context about the latter show. Here are the basics: &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;arriving on Peacock drove more signups than the nationwide launch, including a notable uptick in people signing up for the $10-a-month premium plan that allows them full ad-free access to all nine seasons. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLCgpm"&gt;While sales of &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;on iTunes also saw an increase, Antenna’s team noticed a much bigger addition to Peacock subscribers than overall digital purchases. Peacock has grown &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22253988/peacock-nbcuniversal-comcast-streaming-broadband"&gt;to 33 million users&lt;/a&gt;. That’s 7 million more than the 26 million figure NBCUniversal CEO Jeff Shell &lt;a href="https://www.cordcuttersnews.com/peacock-reaches-26-million-subscribers/"&gt;reported on December 8th, 2020&lt;/a&gt;. (It’s unclear how many of those users are paying the $10 ad-free premium plan or are streaming for free.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vrx2jH"&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast, which owns NBCUniversal, is also an investor in Vox Media, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NzsMJv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;seemingly&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;performing well for Peacock, a relatively new streaming platform compared to Netflix or Hulu, isn’t surprising. It remained the most watched show on Netflix for several years before leaving. Shell told analysts on a Comcast earnings call at the end of January that viewership of &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;on Peacock was far outpacing viewership on Netflix. (Although he didn’t provide any data to back that up.) A streaming service can’t rely on just one show, though, and Shell said it’s the supplementary effect of &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;landing on Peacock that makes them feel confident in the streaming bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LlY3U"&gt;“We’re seeing people who are watching &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt; on Peacock are watching lots of our other comedies,” Shell told analysts. “It’s really driving &lt;em&gt;Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/em&gt; and really driving &lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Nine-Nine&lt;/em&gt;, amongst others. It’s kind of an ecosystem.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e7vT0P"&gt;In the United States, audience demand and interest in &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;increased once it left Netflix. Demand for the show was 39 percent higher within the first three days that it was on Peacock compared to the last day it was on Netflix, according to Parrot Analytics. Over the first 20 days the show was on Peacock, it maintained an increased demand. This indicated that “the rediscovery of this show by new audiences could be driving a longer term resurgence,” according to Wade Payson-Denney, an insight analyst at Parrot Analytics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VP09jo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s really driving &lt;em&gt;Parks &amp;amp; Recreation&lt;/em&gt; and really driving &lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Nine-Nine&lt;/em&gt;, amongst others. It’s kind of an ecosystem”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K4pA8k"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;is a little less clear. WarnerMedia announced back in July 2020 that &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;was the most watched show on HBO Max, with &lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant &lt;/em&gt;coming in&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;second and &lt;em&gt;The Big Bang Theory &lt;/em&gt;in third, but it didn’t provide any data, making those statements effectively moot. Still, HBO Max has also seen subscriber growth, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252069/hbo-max-subscribers-wonder-woman-1984-att-earnings"&gt;17.2 million activations by January 2021&lt;/a&gt;, nearly doubling figures announced in October 2020. While most of that growth is likely more &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21504152/wonder-woman-1984-release-delay-new-date-warner-bros-disney-black-widow-dune-tenet"&gt;attributable to &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984’&lt;/em&gt;s premiere&lt;/a&gt;, subscribers may stick around for &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;and other library programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OrSB2m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;are perfect examples of “snackable TV.” They’re comfort programs that people return to time and time again. In 2019, Nielsen found that 72 percent of time spent watching Netflix was devoted to library programming, with &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;topping the list. Even if &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;aren’t always primary drivers, they may do their job of keeping people who sign up to watch &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984 &lt;/em&gt;or Premier League games. If &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;keep people from canceling, they’ll have done their jobs. This is a similar philosophy behind Disney’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22291848/disney-plus-star-launch-europe-canada-international-streaming-hulu-breakdown"&gt;decision to add Star&lt;/a&gt; (bringing shows like &lt;em&gt;How I Met Your Mother &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;24&lt;/em&gt;) to its Disney Plus service in certain international markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEwQEd"&gt;What’s perhaps most interesting is that having &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Friends &lt;/em&gt;leave Netflix has had little impact on Netflix’s business, according to Antenna. While some Netflix subscribers who signed up for Peacock in January 2021 canceled Netflix to switch over to Peacock, the number was so low that it had little impact on Netflix’s business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V6C4sH"&gt;Turns out, people are more than willing to supplement their Netflix subscriptions with one or two others. That’s good news for quite a few companies. The remaining question is how many people keep their Peacock and HBO Max subscriptions all year-round. The streaming wars are not-so-secretly the “churn wars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E2ZmeN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LdFzk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0G3dLg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MR2xsg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EWGOXa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mqOrQw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvRga0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94wlM6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AVdspy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22297077/the-office-friends-peacock-hbo-max-streaming-wars-disney-plus-star"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22297077/the-office-friends-peacock-hbo-max-streaming-wars-disney-plus-star</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:10:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:10:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Join us for a live event about tech regulation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I6EFIwV1dIh0qOzt8gk8lw9-HgI=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68832158/VRG_VergreLive_Event.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dkv72I"&gt;The most powerful companies on the internet have never been less popular in Washington, and industry-wide regulation has never seemed to close. So on March 1st at 2PM ET. The Verge is hosting a event about regulating the internet — from antitrust to privacy to the many proposals for changing Section 230. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pf7LEw"&gt;Like a lot of things in 2021, we’ll be holding this event remotely, meeting over video and taking live audience questions online. It’s free, and &lt;a href="https://voxmediaevents.com/thevergelive/thevergearticle"&gt;you can register online right now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2jq4o"&gt;The event will kick off with a keynote from Senator Amy Klobuchar, one of the sponsors of the SAFE TECH Act, discussing how she’s approaching tech regulation across a variety of issues, as well as her agenda for the next congressional term. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c692S4"&gt;After that, we’ll have a panel focusing specifically on Section 230 reform, featuring the following panelists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="bLWbSO"&gt;Michael Cheah, General Counsel at Vimeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lyp6ab"&gt;Sydette Harry, Researcher, Writer, and Strategist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="21zO9B"&gt;Amanda Keton, General Counsel at the Wikimedia Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="c4D6rc"&gt;Congress has introduced several proposals to overhaul Section 230, most recently the SAFE TECH Act, a sweeping rollback of the law’s protections. These proposals would affect the entire internet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268421/cda-section-230-25th-anniversary-reform-stakes-big-tech-internet"&gt;raising huge questions&lt;/a&gt; about the future of online communication. Yet public debate has focused on just a few companies: Facebook, Twitter, and Google, tagged collectively as “Big Tech.” And they’re just part of a much larger debate over how to regulate the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3DnkPx"&gt;Both sessions will be followed by brief Q&amp;amp;A sessions, and registrants will be able to pass along questions through our built-in chat system. We won’t be posting the full video publicly, so the only way to see it will be to &lt;a href="https://voxmediaevents.com/thevergelive/thevergearticle"&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; and watch along with everyone else. We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22287443/section-230-amy-klobuchar-internet-regulation-panel-event-sign-up"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22287443/section-230-amy-klobuchar-internet-regulation-panel-event-sign-up</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:06:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:06:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>There’s a hidden message in the parachute of NASA’s Mars rover</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ikx05RBAATpYLYu7XYKYy_66pPc=/0x86:1280x939/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862307/Mars_Perseverance_EAF_0002_0667110418_573ECV_N0010052EDLC00002_0010LUJ01.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view of NASA’s Perseverance rover looking up at its parachute, which reads “Dare Mighty Things” in a hidden code, while zooming through the Martian atmosphere before landing.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pgyniY"&gt;The parachute that helped NASA’s Perseverance rover &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289668/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-success"&gt;land&lt;/a&gt; on Mars last week unfurled to reveal a seemingly random pattern of colors in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295739/nasa-perseverance-rover-landing-mars-video-footage"&gt;video clips&lt;/a&gt; of the rover’s landing. But there was more to the story: NASA officials later said it contained a hidden message written in binary computer code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k9Il5q"&gt;Internet sleuths cracked the message within hours. The red and white pattern spelled out “Dare Mighty Things” in concentric rings. The saying is the Perseverance team’s motto, and it is also emblazoned on the walls of Mission Control at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), the mission team’s Southern California headquarters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ymt46U"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"dare mighty things" ! Well done! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NASA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASAPersevere?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NASAPersevere&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Di1hkFQApd"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Di1hkFQApd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Abela_Paf (@FrenchTech_paf) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FrenchTech_paf/status/1363965938421411841?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 22, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Bd7zsO"&gt;The parachute’s outer ring appears to translate to coordinates for JPL: 34°11’58” N 118°10’31” W. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9ZRA2"&gt;Allen Chen, the entry, descent, and landing lead for Perseverance, dared the public to figure the message out during a press conference on Monday. “In addition to enabling incredible science, we hope our efforts in our engineering can inspire others,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ieg0tJ"&gt;“Sometimes we leave messages in our work for others to find for that purpose, so we invite you all to give it shot and show your work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3yzYh"&gt;Adam Steltzner, Perseverance’s chief engineer, confirmed the message late Monday night on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dRDIWd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It looks like the internet has cracked the code in something like 6 hours!  Oh internet is there anything you can’t do?  For those who just want to know:  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mars2020?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Mars2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CountdownToMars?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CountdownToMars&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/yTJCEnbuLY"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yTJCEnbuLY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Steltzner (@steltzner) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/steltzner/status/1364076615932645379?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NuNs3f"&gt;The “Dare Mighty Things” message wasn’t the only quirk Perseverance brought to Mars. Zooming in on one of the &lt;a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/mars2020/multimedia/raw-images/"&gt;several thousand images&lt;/a&gt; NASA released from the rover this week shows a tiny family portrait of past Mars rovers, Perseverance, and the Ingenuity helicopter, which accompanied Perseverance to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mYCh2fk7MXOJ6NQM99o6rs5fXmo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323013/Untitled_6_00001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: NASA / JPL | Edit by Joey Roulette / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A family portrait is seen on Perseverance in this photo taken by the rover’s onboard Left Navigation Camera (Navcam).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="As4eay"&gt;NASA has included hidden messages on its rovers in the past. The Curiosity rover, which landed on the Red Planet in 2012, had tiny holes dotted in its hollow aluminum wheels to allow Mars pebbles caught inside to escape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0VOejR"&gt;Those holes read “JPL” in Morse code. So when Curiosity roved the surface, “JPL” was stamped in Morse code on the Martian soil (though it was erased shortly after by the Martian wind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MmAyEq"&gt;Chen told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Perseverance engineers might have put more hidden messages on the rover beyond the “Dare Mighty Things” code in its parachute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UZv4bQ"&gt;“People can’t resist putting a little personal touch in their work,” Chen said. “But the vast majority of these will never be known — even by me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OpTLRM"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="What is Perseverance doing on Mars exactly?|100862" data-volume-uuid="bbc900ba2" data-volume-id="100862" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-763" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297094/hidden-message-parachute-nasa-mars-perseverance-rover"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297094/hidden-message-parachute-nasa-mars-perseverance-rover</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:02:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:02:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater remaster coming to PS5, Xbox Series X, and Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yt57ibRzHT-wA7a7gyij2UQo5sw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862293/THPS_NextGen_004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk in &lt;/em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2. | Image: Activision&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YqIlwn"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21419054/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-review-xbox-pc-ps4"&gt;very good remaster&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2&lt;/em&gt; is hitting next-gen consoles and the Nintendo Switch &lt;a href="https://blog.activision.com/tony-hawk/2021-02/Tony-Hawks-Pro-Skater-1-2-Platforms-Announcement"&gt;this year&lt;/a&gt;. The game will launch on the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S on March 26th, but there’s no specific release date for the Switch release beyond “2021.” The game was first released last year for PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TwbcaL"&gt;On next-gen consoles, you’ll be able to play the game at 120fps at a 1080p resolution or at 60fps in 4K, &lt;a href="https://blog.activision.com/tony-hawk/2021-02/Tony-Hawks-Pro-Skater-1-2-Platforms-Announcement"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. (The PS5 and Xbox Series X can run at a native 4K, while the Xbox Series S version can run at 1440p and upscale to 4K.) The next-gen version will also offer spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TLRreY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Get ready to drop in and take &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/THPS?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#THPS&lt;/a&gt; 1+2 to the next level on New Platforms     Coming to PS5™, Xbox Series X|S - March 26 and on Nintendo Switch™ - Coming 2021. AVAILABLE NOW on PS4™, Xbox One, and PC. &lt;a href="https://t.co/NUVbECnx1e"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NUVbECnx1e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 1 and 2 (@TonyHawkTheGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TonyHawkTheGame/status/1364243630358220800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VnlNdm"&gt;If you already own &lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2&lt;/em&gt; on PS4 or Xbox One, you won’t necessarily be entitled to a free upgrade to the next-gen version, however. Activision spelled out the different upgrade scenarios &lt;a href="https://support.activision.com/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2-upgrade-and-purchase-faq"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt;, but here’s the gist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="P2xJi0"&gt;If you own the Digital Deluxe versions of the older-gen games, you can download the next-gen upgrade for free. (Though if you live in Japan, the PS4 to PS5 upgrade will cost 100 yen, according to Activision.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iHlZnk"&gt;If you originally bought the game digitally but &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; have the Digital Deluxe version, you can pay $10 to upgrade to the “Cross-Gen Deluxe Bundle,” which includes content from the Digital Deluxe version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eL0QB2"&gt;If you have the physical PS4 version of the game, you will be able to upgrade to the PS5 version, but you’ll need to you have your disc in your console to play the next-gen version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JxUv8q"&gt;If you have the physical Xbox One version, you’re out of luck — there’s no upgrade offer for the Xbox Series X / S version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="Y1Ol8Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2 is the perfect remaster","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21419054/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-review-xbox-pc-ps4"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297221/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297221/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:01:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:01:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Maps finally rolls out dark mode on Android </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mAlw93bRBMcAbNv0XF9rdoO5Ims=/50x0:952x601/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862287/GoogleMaps_NightMode.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EQl6LS"&gt;The Google Maps app is getting a true dark mode, at least on Android. The company announced today that it is finally widely releasing the dark theme option that it’s been testing in the app &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/09/29/google-maps-dark-theme/"&gt;since September 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYchlH"&gt;The dark mode, which takes things much further than the previously available night mode color option, will be accessible in the app’s settings menu, under “theme.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMyW0c"&gt;Google announced the dark mode rollout as part of a &lt;a href="https://t.co/RkceFy7Rrs"&gt;batch of new features&lt;/a&gt; coming to Android, including some updates to Android Auto. In addition to custom wallpapers, Android Auto is now going to feature games as well. &lt;em&gt;Trivia Crack&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Song Quiz&lt;/em&gt;, and Google’s own Are You Feeling Lucky? will be available. The games can be accessed through the assistant by saying “Hey Google, play a game.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y1eYlrlMA_omPxiqIvjRmbQhw4E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323100/Android_Auto_Play_A_Game.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ugQdxz"&gt;Android Auto is also getting a split-screen feature that will put Maps side by side with media controls, much like what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/24/18693555/apple-ios-13-carplay-interface-update-hands-on-test-review"&gt;Apple started doing in CarPlay in iOS 13 in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. (Though this feature will only be available in cars with wider displays.) Google is adding shortcuts to the Android Auto launch screen, too, which will allow for quick access to weather or setting your home thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bmStHZ"&gt;The Android Auto features will be available “in the coming days” on phones running Android 6.0 and above in compatible cars. Google Maps dark mode will roll out “soon.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAlvZq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297204/google-maps-dark-mode-android-auto-split-screen-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297204/google-maps-dark-mode-android-auto-split-screen-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:01:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:01:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>The US offshore wind boom will depend on these ships</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ozn7qfx_6osRuaX7E33vkT8EfRo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862285/acastro_210216_4409_windTurbine_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge | Images: Dominion Energy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The race is on to build them &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="rOlD48"&gt;New offshore wind developments are poised to help the US usher in a new era in energy — but first, they need ships. More specifically, they need massive specialized vessels capable of erecting a skyscraper-sized turbine in the open ocean. Perhaps unsurprisingly, these are hard to come by. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Adana"&gt;Wind turbine installation vessels are already in short supply globally. And in the US, policies aimed at protecting domestic shipbuilding make it even harder for wind farm developers to get their hands on those vessels. Unless the US figures out how to bridge that gap, it could be choppy waters ahead for the country’s offshore wind dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTkolA"&gt;In the US, President Joe Biden has set a goal of “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/"&gt;doubling&lt;/a&gt;” offshore wind this decade, part of a broader effort to power the country’s electricity sector with purely clean energy by 2035. In order to meet those goals, the US will need to build up a lot more aquatic infrastructure off its shores. There are already plans for at least 16 wind projects off the East Coast of the US — they’re just awaiting permits — and they’ll need the services of these very specialized ships.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="F1zt3T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s pretty insane. It’s a pretty limited market.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GnvhGI"&gt;“It’s pretty insane. It’s a pretty limited market,” says Claire Richer, director of federal affairs at American Clean Power Association (ACP), a group that represents the renewable energy industry in the US. If all of a sudden, all of the prospective US wind farm projects began construction at the same time, “then we have a problem,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpPpnF"&gt;All of the offshore wind projects being developed around the world are vying for time with these vessels at a rate of up to $180,000 a day. The industry is still pretty nascent, providing  just &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/offshore-wind-outlook-2019"&gt;0.3 percent of power generation globally&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s expected to change because the potential is enormous. Offshore wind could one day generate 18 times the global electricity demand of today, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/offshore-wind-outlook-2019"&gt;International Energy Agency&lt;/a&gt;. It forecasts that offshore wind will be a trillion-dollar industry by 2040, growing by 13 percent each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KC5TAz"&gt;The industry is already advancing at breakneck speeds; massive new turbines can harness more power than ever before. Take General Electric’s Haliade X, which became commercially available in 2020. At 853 feet tall, it dwarfs previous generations of turbines. Imagine the Statue of Liberty stacked on top of the Washington Monument, and you’ve got a sense of its size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="GE’s Haliade X prototype" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jp5qu707pQxXhLf6Y3CqCOYX1ZY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322774/wind_offshore_haliade_x_prototype_aerial_3000px.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: GE&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GE’s Haliade X prototype dwarfs older turbines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PNlclh"&gt;To put that monstrosity together at sea, you need a special kind of boat called a wind turbine installation vessel. These ships need to be big and strong enough to carry the turbine pieces from port to installation site. Once they’re on location, these giants have legs that can reach down to the seafloor. That steadies the vessel and lifts it up out of the water so it can act as a stable platform. On top of that platform is a crane powerful enough to lift turbine components and install them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1VjYxa"&gt;There were only 32 of these wind turbine installation vessels in the world in 2020, according to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.rystadenergy.com/newsevents/news/press-releases/the-world-may-not-have-enough-heavy-lift-vessels-to-service-the-offshore-wind-industry-post-2025/"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Norwegian firm Rystad Energy. Even though more are being built, the global fleet won’t be enough to meet offshore demand beyond 2025, according to Rystad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkiYzD"&gt;Building new vessels capable of constructing massive wind turbines can take several years. And despite the growing need, shipbuilders and offshore wind developers have been hesitant in the past to invest in new ships until upcoming projects have acquired the permits they need to begin construction — which slows things down even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oriiuU"&gt;“It’s been this kind of a chicken and egg situation in the vessel market,” says Alexander Fløtre, a product manager for Rystad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="p72wLk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Vessels in the existing fleet are becoming obsolete&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eVggJe"&gt;What’s more, some of the vessels in the existing fleet are becoming obsolete because turbines are growing increasingly gigantic. At 351 feet long, a single turbine blade for the Haliade X is already longer than the tower height of one of GE’s older turbines. Longer blades can generate more power, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21293456/ge-200-meter-onshore-taller-wind-turbines-3d-printing"&gt;taller turbines&lt;/a&gt; can reach stronger winds at higher altitudes. So companies are competing with each other by building bigger turbines. “You see this race,” Fløtre says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyLd0N"&gt;That makes the shortage of ships a bigger problem. So far, there are only 12 vessels in the world capable of installing next-generation wind turbines like the Haliade X, according to ACP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxeZex"&gt;There’s yet another challenge that’s specific to the US: none of the existing global fleet complies with &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/27/16373484/jones-act-puerto-rico"&gt;America’s Jones Act&lt;/a&gt;. The 1920 act requires vessels moving between two points in the US to be built, owned, crewed, and registered in the US. That also applies to a vessel transporting turbine parts from a US port to a project site that’s within federal waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dominion Energy hired the Luxembourg-flagged vessel Vole Au Vent to construct a pilot project off the shores of Virginia." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u8rvn3dc7MTuTlobcnuPrFuCat0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322863/CVOW_Turbine_2_Install_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dominion Energy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dominion Energy hired the Luxembourg-flagged vessel Vole Au Vent to construct a pilot project off the shores of Virginia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OqR3v9"&gt;The first Jones Act-compliant wind turbine installation vessel is currently being built by Virginia-based utility Dominion Energy, but it won’t be ready until 2023, and it comes at an enormous cost of $500 million. That’s even more than what companies have bid to lease federal waters for offshore wind development, according to ACP’s Richer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cY8nG9"&gt;“Dominion’s installation vessel is going to have to be constantly working in order to recoup the cost of construction,” says Patrick Finn, a maritime tech analyst for the consultancy Thetius. Jones Act restrictions make shipbuilding significantly more expensive in the US, Finn says. A similar vessel built in South Korea might cost about half of what Dominion is paying, according to Finn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4DCoFq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are only 12 vessels in the world capable of installing next-generation wind turbines&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="udJi4L"&gt;For Dominion, the steep cost may still be worth it. “There was a big need there that we saw in the US,” says Mark Mitchell, senior vice president for project construction at Dominion. “It’s an important step to support the industry coming to the US and it certainly provides an important option to install even our own project.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvcmd1"&gt;Dominion will need the vessel to build its planned 2,640 MW wind farm off the coast of Virginia. After that, the vessel will eventually be hired out for other companies’ projects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="voBPYf"&gt;There are ways to work around Jones Act requirements. Smaller “feeder” vessels that are already Jones Act-compliant can bring equipment and turbine components to foreign installation vessels stationed out at sea. Some companies are &lt;a href="https://www.windpowerengineering.com/abs-to-class-first-jones-act-compliant-offshore-wind-service-operation-vessel/"&gt;already designing&lt;/a&gt; new &lt;a href="https://splash247.com/wartsila-unveils-jones-act-hybrid-sov/"&gt;Jones Act-compliant vessels&lt;/a&gt; to service the construction or operation of new wind farms. If the foreign vessels aren’t transporting goods, then they won’t be in violation of the act. That’s how the US’s &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/future-energy-is-blowing-in-wind/"&gt;first offshore wind farm at Block Island&lt;/a&gt; was built. A second small wind farm, a 12 MW demonstration project Dominion built off the coast of Virginia, was just completed last year.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rr4naTSM5gdgxjL2qRVfCvuEUOA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322736/2020_11_02_GustoMSC_NG_16000X_SJ_Dominion_Energy_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dominion Energy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A rendering of the first Jones Act-compliant wind turbine installation vessel being built by Dominion Energy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jaCJFN"&gt;In the future, turbines could even be &lt;a href="https://crew.udel.edu/industrializing-offshore-wind-power-generation/"&gt;assembled almost entirely at port&lt;/a&gt; and brought out to sea pretty much intact. Doing so could eliminate the need for a specialized wind turbine installation vessel. The US could use much cheaper vessels to transport the completed turbine and even repurpose Jones Act-compliant vessels used in the oil and gas industry. “It allows us to do it for less cost and faster,” says Willett Kempton, a professor at the University of Delaware who is leading research into this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XrIiZw"&gt;Whatever route offshore wind developers choose, all of these options have the potential to spur a boom in US boatbuilding. “That’ll be a boost for the Gulf Coast economy, my hometown,” says Joseph Orgeron, co-founder of the company 2nd Wind Marine. “There will be quite a number of purpose-built ships that will have to be built in the US, just to take care of US offshore wind development over the next 20 years,” Orgeron says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="coqcIB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A boom in US boatbuilding&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FPWi6A"&gt;Orgeron’s company provided the feeder vessels for the construction of the Block Island wind farm in 2016. Before that, his family’s business supplied vessels for oil and gas development in the Gulf of Mexico. That boom started declining in the 1980s, and their vessels were used more and more to take old oil and gas structures out of the Gulf. Now, the future of Orgeron’s business is in offshore wind.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tvdINc"&gt;“That [industry], basically that could be fired back up,” Orgeron says. Only this time, they won’t be building new oil rigs or tearing down their hulking remains. Instead, they’ll build new giants for a new age of more sustainable energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVDC4o"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFMBQR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22296979/us-offshore-ships-wind-boom-installation-vessels"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22296979/us-offshore-ships-wind-boom-installation-vessels</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Stadia’s next exclusive is PixelJunk Raiders, releasing March 1st</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r8-ADL656mEd0AeQYNnVRyWl44A=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862244/PJR_keyart.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Q Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xdsP4L"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; is the next exclusive coming to Google’s Stadia cloud gaming service. The title, a third-person rougelite that sees you battle through procedurally generated alien environments, will release on the Stadia platform on March 1st. It’ll sell for $19.99 (€19.99), and it will be included free with a Stadia Pro subscription. An &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UJGyLNxTBQg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;announcement trailer&lt;/a&gt; bills &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; as “Only on Stadia,” suggesting this isn’t a timed exclusive &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UJGyLNxTBQg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;Crayta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ol4QT"&gt;The announcement notes that &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; supports Stadia’s State Share feature, which has previously been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233066/stadia-state-share-hitman-3-world-of-assassination"&gt;used with the &lt;em&gt;Hitman&lt;/em&gt; games&lt;/a&gt; to let players to share specific parts of missions with one another. In &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt;, the feature allows your “placed turrets, traps and gadgets to impact other players’ worlds.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ieJinB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With support for Stadia’s State Share&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qCBeO7"&gt;The release of &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; comes exactly a month after Google announced its decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260803/google-stadia-game-development-studio-shut-down-jade-raymond"&gt;shutter its in-house game development studios&lt;/a&gt;, a division of multiple teams tasked with building original games for Stadia. Despite their closure, it seems Google still plans to bring exclusive titles to Stadia from third-party studios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="22pPiy"&gt;Other previously announced exclusives for the service include games from &lt;em&gt;Rock Band&lt;/em&gt; developer Harmonix and &lt;em&gt;Until Dawn&lt;/em&gt; studio Supermassive Games, in a deal that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21323326/google-stadia-exclusive-game-deals-harmonix-rock-band-supermassive-until-dawn"&gt;announced last year&lt;/a&gt;. Uppercut Games was also announced as developing an exclusive title for Stadia. It’s unclear if these deals have been affected by Google’s recent studio closures.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296898/google-stadia-pixeljunk-raiders-exclusive-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296898/google-stadia-pixeljunk-raiders-exclusive-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
