<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-25T05:36:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T05:36:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T05:36:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Gabe Newell has big plans for brain-computer interfaces in gaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c5czHhFCPb4Svk9-fxY5bPoIvQM=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68715814/msedge_vJOA5MrBw6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newell during a recent interview with 1 News.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.tvnz.co.nz/one-news/new-zealand/gabe-newell-says-brain-computer-interface-tech-allow-video-games-far-beyond-human-meat-peripherals-can-comprehend" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;1 News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vft5gy"&gt;Valve co-founder and president Gabe Newell talks about Valve’s exploration of brain-computer interfaces (BCIs) for gaming and beyond, in an interview with &lt;a href="https://www.tvnz.co.nz/one-news/new-zealand/gabe-newell-says-brain-computer-interface-tech-allow-video-games-far-beyond-human-meat-peripherals-can-comprehend"&gt;New Zealand’s &lt;em&gt;1 News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although Newell admits that the idea of having your brain interface directly with a computer sounds “indistinguishable from science fiction,” he says developers would be making a “silly mistake” if they ignore the area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d96UwI"&gt;Newell says that Valve is currently working with OpenBCI headsets to develop open-source software with the aim of making it easier for developers to understand the signals coming from people’s brains. At its most basic, this could allow software to understand whether a player is enjoying a game, and adjust the experience accordingly. For example, games could turn up the difficulty if they sense a player is getting bored. But Newell’s more ambitious ideas involve actually writing signals to people’s brains, rather than just reading them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="uD39Ut"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Oh, remember Bob? Remember when Bob got hacked by the Russian malware? That sucked”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ypHH49"&gt;Newell suggests our ability to experience existing games is limited by our physical body — or “meat peripherals” as he puts it. But interfacing directly with a player’s brain could open up a lot more possibilities. “The real world will seem flat, colorless, blurry compared to the experiences you’ll be able to create in people’s brains,” Newell says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0sN6qI"&gt;Valve has spoken publicly about its work on brain-computer interfaces before. Back at 2019’s Game Developers Conference, Valve’s principal experimental psychologist, Mike Ambinder gave a talk on the company’s work in the area, &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2019/03/24/valve-psychologist-explores-controlling-games-directly-with-your-brain/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;VentureBeat&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; at the time, covering many of the same possibilities and use cases that Newell outlines in his recent interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WsElhQ"&gt;Beyond their use in gaming, Newell says that BCIs could help with other areas of human life like sleep. “One of the early applications I expect we’ll see is improved sleep — sleep will become an app that you run where you say, ‘Oh, I need this much sleep, I need this much REM,’” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Xv8Bf"&gt;Despite the possibilities, Newell admits that brain-computer interfaces carry their risks. He says that the idea of a BCI making someone feel pain is a “complicated topic,” and adds that the interfaces will be susceptible to viruses like other technologies, suggesting that they’ll need similar safeguards in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AbYmGP"&gt;“Nobody wants to say, ‘Oh, remember Bob? Remember when Bob got hacked by the Russian malware? That sucked — is he still running naked through the forests?’” Newell quips. “People are going to have to have a lot of confidence that these are secure systems that don’t have long-term health risks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWY79C"&gt;Regardless, it sounds like Valve doesn’t have any plans to commercialize its research just yet. Newell says that they’re making such rapid progress that any device risks being outdated once it’s gone through the slow process commercialization. “The rate at which we’re learning stuff is so fast,” Newell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErOTSy"&gt;Other high-profile companies currently exploring brain-computer interfaces include Facebook, which is working on a way to allow users to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/30/20747483/facebook-ucsf-brain-computer-interface-typing-speech-recognition-experiment"&gt;type with their brains&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/28/21406143/elon-musk-neuralink-ai-pigs-demo-brain-computer-interface"&gt;Elon Musk’s Neuralink&lt;/a&gt;, which is attempting to develop a less-invasive way of connecting a computer to the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TNj4z"&gt;You can check out more of Newell’s thoughts on the potential for brain-computer interfaces in the full write up from &lt;a href="https://www.tvnz.co.nz/one-news/new-zealand/gabe-newell-says-brain-computer-interface-tech-allow-video-games-far-beyond-human-meat-peripherals-can-comprehend"&gt;&lt;em&gt;1 News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who he also recently spoke with about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/22/22244057/valve-gabe-newell-half-life-new-zealand-game-development"&gt;Valve’s future game development plans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248202/gabe-newell-valve-brain-computer-interface-bci-meat-peripherals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248202/gabe-newell-valve-brain-computer-interface-bci-meat-peripherals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T03:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T03:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google plans vaccination clinics at some of its sites</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k2w-755rGM-xtZdlSWkuJjNLJVE=/60x0:1541x987/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68715716/vaccinationsite.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="D0a4j1"&gt;Google is launching an initiative to provide more than $150 million to promote education and equitable distribution of coronavirus vaccines, the &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/health/vaccines-how-were-helping"&gt;company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. It’s going to make some Google facilities — buildings, parking lots, and open spaces — available as vaccination clinics, with plans to open sites in Los Angeles, San Francisco, Kirkland, Washington, and New York City first, and expand nationally as vaccines become more widely available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OSWuhB"&gt;Google and Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai says in a blog post that the company would give $100 million in ad grants to the CDC Foundation, the World Health Organization, and other nonprofits. It also plans to invest $50 million in partnerships with public health agencies to help get information about vaccines to underserved communities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GncDn8"&gt;“Our efforts will focus heavily on equitable access to vaccines,” Pichai writes in the post. “Early data in the U.S. shows that disproportionately affected populations, especially people of color and those in rural communities, aren’t getting access to the vaccine at the same rates as other groups.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="58rrBk"&gt;Google had already committed $5 million in grants to organizations like the Morehouse School of Medicine’s Satcher Health Leadership Institute, which is focused on addressing racial and geographic disparities in vaccine access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lifxrI"&gt;Google will also expand the vaccine information panels in its search results, and will start showing state and regional distribution information in search so people can check when they’re eligible to receive a vaccine. Google launched the vaccine information panels in search &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167185/google-vaccine-information-search-results-youtube-information-panels"&gt;last month in the UK&lt;/a&gt;, listing information on each individual vaccine. They’re similar to the info panels it used to share facts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/21/21189051/google-coronavirus-website-launches-covid19-trump-enhanced-search-results"&gt;about COVID-19&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/17/21225828/google-showing-covid-19-testing-centers-search-results"&gt;locations of testing centers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOM9GG"&gt;The company says searches for “vaccines near me” have increased fivefold since the beginning of the year. In the coming weeks, COVID-19 vaccination locations will be available in search and Maps for Arizona, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas, and more states and countries will be added soon. The search results will include details about whether appointments or referrals from a doctor are required, whether there’s a drive-thru option or if access is limited to specific people. Google says it’s working with &lt;a href="http://VaccineFinder.org"&gt;VaccineFinder.org&lt;/a&gt;, government agencies, retail pharmacies, and other authoritative sources to gather the data on vaccination sites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTVswh"&gt;The initial rollout of coronavirus vaccines in the US has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;slow and messy&lt;/a&gt;, as states have tried coordinate plans for appointments with little federal guidance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1iJAwm"&gt;“Getting vaccines to billions of people won’t be easy, but it’s one of the most important problems we’ll solve in our lifetimes,” Pichai writes in the post. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22247533/google-plans-vaccination-clinics-search-location-pandemic-coronavirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22247533/google-plans-vaccination-clinics-search-location-pandemic-coronavirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T15:30:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T15:30:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>ESPN Plus apologizes for “technical issue” during UFC pay-per-view event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="UFC 257: Poirier v McGregor" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hkSVnczizkXjpq46fmNoc3KN4zQ=/0x31:4031x2718/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68714105/1230757574.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jeff Bottari/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WiXwsL"&gt;ESPN Plus says it will issue partial refunds to customers who paid for a UFC pay-per-view event Saturday only to run into technical problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2k7qOn"&gt;Conor McGregor vs Dustin Poirier was the headline match of the &lt;a href="https://mmajunkie.usatoday.com/events/ufc-257"&gt;UFC 257 main card&lt;/a&gt;, which was set to get underway at about 10PM ET Saturday. To watch, ESPN Plus subscribers, who pay $59.99 per year for the streaming service, also paid $69.99 for Saturday’s event. But users in the US &lt;a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/ufc-257-pay-per-view-045617758.html"&gt;began reporting a blackout&lt;/a&gt; on the ESPN Plus app Saturday evening that lasted through some of the earlier fights on the main card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGX9RY"&gt;A spokesperson for Disney, which owns ESPN, said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday that the company was “aware that a technical issue prevented a portion of users from accessing the early part of the ESPN+ pay-per-view event, and we apologize for that experience. We worked as quickly as possible to identify and resolve the issue.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0aL4iK"&gt;The spokesperson didn’t say what the specific issue was, but it affected some users in the western US and was resolved by 11PM ET, according to the company, in time to see the signature fights. Users were affected between a few minutes to more than an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jW0Aca"&gt;The company says it will provide partial refunds to users affected by the outage. Customers who paid for the fight through a third-party platform like Apple, Roku, Google, or Amazon, will need to seek refunds from the platform, but Disney/ESPN says it will work with those companies on the refund process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZi32R"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247257/espn-plus-technical-issue-ufc-pay-per-view-mcgregor-poirier"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247257/espn-plus-technical-issue-ufc-pay-per-view-mcgregor-poirier</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T13:22:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T13:22:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>New trailers: Godzilla vs. Kong, The World to Come, Son of the South and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W62kYel6R61X_nd204Edo9Z4_ZI=/362x0:1496x756/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68713716/godzilla_vs_kong.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Godzilla vs. Kong | Warner Bros.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZArnBR"&gt;I finally finished &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; last night and I get why everyone loved it so much. I was totally prepared to not like the earnest, goofy Ted but Jason Sudeikis won me over. I won’t spoil in case you haven’t seen it, but &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;has plenty of plot developments you expect will turn out a certain way —because we’ve been conditioned to have plots drawn out as long as possible and with as much unnecessary drama as possible— but then the characters behave like actual people! They’re smart and funny and nuanced and I can’t wait to see them again in Season 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sBuqKw"&gt;But look what just dropped this morning: The &lt;em&gt;Godzilla vs. Kong&lt;/em&gt; trailer! Let’s gooooo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5hT3Vx"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/odM92ap8_c0?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="XooTBu"&gt;Godzilla vs. Kong &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3ld3U3"&gt;The trailer for the long-awaited flick about the showdown between Kong and Godzilla— whose release was pushed back a year due to the coronavirus pandemic— is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; here and it looks very awesome, with lots of roaring, punching, and stuff exploding. What more could we ask for? Alexander Skarsgard, Millie Bobby Brown, Rebecca Hall, and Brian Tyree Henry star in &lt;em&gt;Godzilla vs. Kong&lt;/em&gt;, which hits theaters and HBO Max on March 26th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="owqnIs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XdBp0KktXpk?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5qt3QJ"&gt;Dear Comrades!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="sEVuGx"&gt;Sorry if I gave you whiplash switching genres here! This movie tells the story of the 1962 Novocherkaask massacre, where Soviet troops fired on a crowd of unarmed protesters striking over working conditions and food prices (the incident was referenced in Solzhenitsyn’s &lt;em&gt;The Gulag Archipelago) Dear Comrades! &lt;/em&gt;is told through the eyes of Lyuda (played by Julia Vysotskaya), a former Communist party stalwart whose daughter goes missing after the attack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="L3xU3a"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xEpSdb_f1pE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6dGD7a"&gt;Boogie &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="j488zd"&gt;This film tells the story of a Chinese-American basketball player with aspirations of playing in the NBA, whose parents want him to follow the more traditional path to college. Written and directed by Eddie Huang, &lt;em&gt;Boogie&lt;/em&gt; stars Taylor Takahashi, Taylour Paige, Pamelyn Chee, Mike Moh, Jorge Lendeborg Jr., Alexa Mareka, Perry Yung, and Pop Smoke. It hits theaters March 5th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="swBQbX"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x0IjvDWw0i4?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qX5Ux9"&gt;Son of the South &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HK3lzt"&gt;Based on Bob Zellner‘s autobiography &lt;em&gt;The Wrong Side of Murder Creek, &lt;/em&gt;this Spike Lee-produced movie tells the story of the son and grandson of Ku Klux Klan members who joins the civil rights movement during the 1960s. Lucas Till, Lucy Hale, Julia Ormond, and Cedric the Entertainer star in &lt;em&gt;Son of the South, &lt;/em&gt;which hits theaters in February. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kY54OZ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RhQu4tcHLeU?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="innAsn"&gt;The World to Come&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="mjx0v0"&gt;I thought I recognized Vanessa Kirby (Princess Margaret in seasons 1 and 2 of &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;) in this trailer (I did!). It’s a romance between two women set in the US in the 1800s. Kirby plays new neighbor Tallie, who connects with farmer’s wife Abigail (Katherine Waterston) as the pair battle loneliness and isolation (and awful husbands). Casey Affleck and Christopher Abbott also star in &lt;em&gt;The World to Come&lt;/em&gt;, which is due in theaters February 12th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O77qfD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22246258/new-trailers-godzilla-kong-comrades-son-south-hbo-max-theaters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22246258/new-trailers-godzilla-kong-comrades-son-south-hbo-max-theaters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T11:41:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T11:41:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla sues former employee for allegedly stealing software</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yZIf8QzcGleUN7B49rtr83yLgJY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68713397/acastro_180430_1777_tesla_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="D3aRB4"&gt;Tesla is suing a former employee for allegedly stealing company information, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/22/tesla-sues-former-employee-for-allegedly-stealing-software-code.html"&gt;CNBC reported&lt;/a&gt;. The company says software engineer Alex Khatilov stole files from Tesla’s internal network related to its Warp Drive software, used to automated many of the company’s business processes. Tesla alleges in the lawsuit that Khatilov moved files to his personal Dropbox account, and that he was one of only a few Tesla employees who had access to the files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QsGtDZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22256438/491775490_Tesla_Inc_v_Alex_Khalitov_Case_4_21_cv_00528_YGR.pdf"&gt;According to the lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, Khatilov told Tesla investigators he “forgot” about moving the files to his personal Dropbox when they confronted him. He &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/01/22/ex-staffer-being-sued-by-tesla-denies-he-stole-massive-cache-of-code/"&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in an interview that he had unintentionally moved the files to Dropbox, and, had been unaware that Tesla had filed a lawsuit against him until the newspaper contacted him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zhYddn"&gt;Tesla has not hesitated to sue in order to protect its proprietary data in the past; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755428/tesla-martin-tripp-settlement-whistleblower-hacing-amount"&gt;in December the company settled&lt;/a&gt; with former process technician Martin Tripp, who admitted to leaking confidential information to a reporter. In 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18275617/tesla-former-employee-lawsuit-trade-secret-theft-zoox-xpeng-feature"&gt;Tesla sued self-driving startup Zoox&lt;/a&gt; accusing four Zoox employees —who had previously worked at Tesla— of taking confidential documents. That case was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21222763/tesla-zoox-startup-lawsuit-settlement-autonomous-driving"&gt;settled last April, with Zoox admitting&lt;/a&gt; that “certain of its new hires from Tesla” were in possession of Tesla documents. And its case against &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/10/20689468/tesla-autopilot-trade-secret-theft-guangzhi-cao-xpeng-xiaopeng-motors-lawsuit-filing"&gt;Guangzhi Cao, who Tesla accuses&lt;/a&gt; of stealing files related to Tesla’s Autopilot system, is still ongoing. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247095/tesla-sues-former-employee-software-dropbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247095/tesla-sues-former-employee-software-dropbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T10:08:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T10:08:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber reportedly lays off 185 former Postmates workers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Uber logo against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zeK4IMndXXzD1gtLrouwEbHw12Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68713107/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TaCAPP"&gt;Uber has laid off about 185 Postmates workers, and plans to further integrate Postmates’ infrastructure within its Uber Eats segment, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/23/technology/uber-postmates-layoffs.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. Uber acquired &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/6/21312447/uber-postmates-acquisition-announced-food-delivery"&gt;Postmates in July for $2.65 billion&lt;/a&gt;, following a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/10/21287128/grubhub-just-eat-takeaway-merger-uber-deal-antitrust"&gt;failed attempt&lt;/a&gt; to buy rival food delivery service Grubhub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HS0bly"&gt;Meal delivery has been one bright spot for Uber amid the pandemic, as bookings in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551683/uber-q3-2020-earnings-revenue-loss-delivery"&gt;Uber Eats division rose 135 percent&lt;/a&gt; year-over-year in the third quarter while its ride-hailing segment dropped 50 percent over the same time period. It’s consolidated other parts of the company in a bid to become profitable by the end of 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;selling its autonomous vehicles segment to Aurora Innovation&lt;/a&gt; in December, the same month it &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/08/air-taxi-start-up-joby-acquires-uber-elevate-.html"&gt;sold its Uber Elevate flying taxi division&lt;/a&gt; to Joby Aviation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dqFAJV"&gt;The latest cuts will see Postmates founder and CEO Bastian Lehmann depart the company, along with most of its executive team, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CspnEV"&gt;Uber Eats continues to trail competing food delivery service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21563716/doordash-ipo-profit-pandemic-food-delivery-drones"&gt;DoorDash, which went public in December&lt;/a&gt;, and showed a brief period of profitability over the summer. According to market research firm Edison Trends, in the fourth quarter &lt;a href="https://trends.edison.tech/research/food-delivery-and-rideshare-report-oct-2020.html"&gt;DoorDash had 48 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the market share for food delivery services, with the combined Uber Eats/Postmates at 35 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZRei4"&gt;Uber did not immediately reply to a request for comment on Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aeLRNc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VrHc41"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247045/uber-eats-postmates-layoffs-food-delivery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22247045/uber-eats-postmates-layoffs-food-delivery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T10:02:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T10:02:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX launches record batch of satellites in first in-house rideshare mission</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l7IebwA4RO1P-55e5zp8XqI_r-o=/0x0:2048x1365/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68713095/EsbDiSFXcAASE03.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;143 spacecraft inside Falcon 9’s payload fairing  | SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V0duL6"&gt;SpaceX launched a batch of 143 spacecraft to space from Florida on Sunday morning under the company’s new cost-cutting SmallSat Rideshare Program, breaking the record for the most satellites lofted into space on a single launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KqtJ2H"&gt;The Transporter-1 mission kicks off a potentially lucrative business line for SpaceX, which unveiled in 2019 its SmallSat Rideshare Program, essentially a carpool for dozens of satellites of different shapes and sizes. The program offers relatively cheap access to space for small satellite companies starting at $1 million for the first 485 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CCyEuj"&gt;Much like a rideshare Uber, a company’s small satellite can hitch a ride to space with other spacecraft instead of buying an entire rocket at a much higher price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FG6kOV"&gt;After scrubbing an initial launch attempt on Saturday due to bad weather, SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket lifted off 24 hours later from its Cape Canaveral Space Force Station launch pad at 10AM ET, sending a mix of shoebox-sized CubeSats and much heavier microsatellites to a 326-mile-high polar orbit — an unusual trajectory for a Florida launch site. SpaceX launched its first polar mission from Florida in August last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rQqevn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Liftoff! &lt;a href="https://t.co/js3zVM77rH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/js3zVM77rH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— SpaceX (@SpaceX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1353357167617732608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UWz9k8"&gt;The launch, SpaceX’s third so far this year, marks the most satellites carried to space on a single rocket, a record previously held by an Indian satellite launch in 2017 carrying 104 satellites. The 143 spacecraft aboard SpaceX’s Falcon 9 include 48 Earth imaging satellites dubbed SuperDoves from Planet, 17 tiny communications satellites for Toronto-based Kepler, and 30 small satellites for the US and Europe packaged by Berlin, Germany-based Exolaunch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5fexve"&gt;Also aboard the flight are small capsules of human ashes arranged by Celestis, a spaceflight memorial company. Ten Starlink satellites are also hitching a ride, inching SpaceX toward the 1,000 mark for the number of active satellites in space supporting its broadband internet constellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4M8qzm"&gt;DARPA, the Pentagon’s R&amp;amp;D agency, pulled out from the rideshare mission earlier this month after its two 187-pound satellites were damaged during launch processing in Cape Canaveral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wRthmo"&gt;The Transporter-1 mission, coming just four days after SpaceX launched 60 of its Starlink satellites to space, keeps pace with what’s set to be a remarkably eventful year in orbit as SpaceX, OneWeb and other companies race to build vast constellations of internet-beaming satellites. In the past 16 days, SpaceX has launched more satellites to space than what the entire world launched in any year before 2013, according to data compiled by Jonathan McDowell, a Harvard astronomer and expert satellite tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ao9SnT"&gt;Rideshare missions on larger rockets appeal to a growing demand for affordable launch services from small satellite companies, ramping up competition with companies like Rocket Lab and Virgin Orbit with smaller rockets tailored for dedicated small satellite launches.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22245907/spacex-launches-record-batch-of-satellites-in-first-in-house-rideshare-mission"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22245907/spacex-launches-record-batch-of-satellites-in-first-in-house-rideshare-mission</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-24T08:26:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T08:26:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Xbox Series X is available at Target</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AhND8i5Iuht7KMnA-JRXnCoS400=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68712841/vpavic_201103_4275_0196.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="orqH4y"&gt;Microsoft’s flagship Xbox Series X is one of the most powerful gaming consoles available right now. If you are having difficulty finding it, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-x-console%2F-%2FA-80790841&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target has restocked the Xbox Series X today&lt;/a&gt;, so you may want to check it out while supplies last. Given the challenge it has been to secure a unit, inventory will likely not last long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IC20Te"&gt;Although no walk-in purchases are available, you will have the option to either have it shipped to your home or request an in-store pickup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jxvtrb"&gt;Like every major hardware launch, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;demand for the Xbox Series X and its competitor, the PlayStation 5, is through the roof&lt;/a&gt;, and the usual problems of supply and demand are exacerbated by the fact that both next-gen consoles launched during a pandemic. Many retailers have sold the console exclusively online. The biggest struggle has been trying to guess when and where the next PS5 or Xbox Series X / S restock will happen, and there is no clear indication of when they will resume in-store walk-in purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kKY5pt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10297750"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22244594/xbox-series-x-console-restock-target"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/24/22244594/xbox-series-x-console-restock-target</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-23T14:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-23T14:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Italian watchdog tells TikTok to block users whose ages can’t be verified</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lf99npg-mxd36DIPy6oOElswR5Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68710990/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bSdSWn"&gt;Italy’s data privacy authority has ordered video sharing app TikTok to temporarily block the accounts of any users whose ages can’t be confirmed, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-italy-tiktok-idUSKBN29R2H6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. The order comes after the death of a 10-year-old girl in Palermo, whose parents told authorities their daughter was participating in a “blackout challenge” she saw on the app. The child died of asphyxiation, and authorities are investigating whether anyone invited her to try the challenge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjtZ79"&gt;The Italian Data Protection Authority &lt;a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9524224"&gt;ordered TikTok &lt;/a&gt;to block unverified users in Italy until at least February 15th. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/23/italy-blocks-tiktok-for-certain-users-after-death-of-girl-allegedly-playing-choking-game"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it had not found content on its platform which would have encouraged the child to participate in the challenge, but said it was cooperating with the investigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYNacv"&gt;“Privacy and safety are top priorities for TikTok and we are constantly strengthening our policies, processes, and technologies to protect all users, and our younger users in particular,”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a TikTok spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nQo8wi"&gt;Under its terms of service, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/strengthening-privacy-and-safety-for-youth"&gt;users must be at least 13&lt;/a&gt; years old to sign up for an account on TikTok, but Italian authorities said it’s easy to get around that rule.  TikTok has a version of its app in the US for children under 13— &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/tiktok-for-younger-users"&gt;TikTok for Younger Users&lt;/a&gt;— which is meant to limit the content and interaction available to those users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BY5XgM"&gt;As it skyrocketed in popularity, TikTok spent much of the past year adding more privacy controls for younger users’ accounts. It introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/16/21222817/tiktok-family-pairing-linked-accounts"&gt;remote parental controls&lt;/a&gt; and allowed parents to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570244/tiktok-parental-controls-family-pairing-private-accounts-search-limits"&gt;change kids’ privacy settings&lt;/a&gt; on the app. Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227871/tiktok-young-teen-privacy-restrictions-default"&gt;TikTok updated the default privacy settings&lt;/a&gt; for users between 13 and 15 years old, putting limits on who can see and comment on their videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="otAY1q"&gt;But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/14/21258502/tiktok-complaint-child-privacy-ftc"&gt;children’s privacy advocates have argued that TikTok &lt;/a&gt;does not do enough to protect children on its platform. Its Beijing-based parent company ByteDance &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/27/18243312/tiktok-ftc-fine-musically-children-coppa-age-gate"&gt;paid a $5.7 million fine&lt;/a&gt; to the US Federal Trade Commission in 2019 for an earlier version of TikTok called Musical.ly, over allegations it violated the Children’s Online Privacy Act (COPPA) in allowing users under 13 to sign up for the app without their parents’ consent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xp2nUB"&gt;The temporary suspension of unverified accounts in Italy bans TikTok from “further processing user data for which there is no absolute certainty of age and, consequently, of compliance with the provisions related to the age requirement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Km0Uyf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 23rd 5:55PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added statement from TikTok spokesperson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/23/22246088/italy-tiktok-block-users-teenagers-verified-children"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/23/22246088/italy-tiktok-block-users-teenagers-verified-children</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-23T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-23T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tiger and the need to complicate the world we grew up in</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M3BNQi5xJ4j36GIRyB2-zefDDqc=/27x54:1227x854/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68710305/Screen_Shot_2021_01_22_at_4.53.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: HBO&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7hF16i"&gt;The year is kicking off with what’s becoming a loose tradition: a documentary about a renowned ‘90s athlete that aims to shade in a more complete picture. This time around, it’s &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt;, a two-part HBO Sports documentary about golf superstar Tiger Woods. Like &lt;em&gt;The Last Dance&lt;/em&gt;, which chronicled Michael Jordan’s final season with the Chicago Bulls while reflecting on his entire career, &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; attempts to complicate the prevailing narrative of a legend defined by his meteoric rise and equally steep fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U6rE16"&gt;Even if you didn’t know golf, you probably knew about Tiger Woods. If you came of age in the ‘90s or early aughts, it was impossible to not know about the man who brought raucous, Michael Jordan-levels of celebrity to golf — a sport so traditionally restrained that Adam Sandler was able to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y1emDAYCfVQ"&gt;make a hit comedy&lt;/a&gt; where the only real joke was “what if a golfer got real pissed off all the time?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RYU2ca"&gt;Tiger Woods was a phenomenon. He had the sort of generational talent that becomes synonymous with a sport while simultaneously redefining what’s possible — despite (or because of) the fact he was so different from what came before. It also might be why Tiger Woods’ fame as a golfer was equally matched by his notoriety as gossip fodder, as his addictions and indiscretions piled up for a fall as ravenously chronicled as his rise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yw9rQu"&gt;Throughout most of its roughly three-hour runtime, &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; feels like a &lt;em&gt;Behind the Music&lt;/em&gt; special narrowly focused on Tiger’s life: directors Matthew Heineman and Matthew Hamachek are very interested in Woods’ early years as a child prodigy and the complicated relationship the golfer had with his controlling father. It’s against this backdrop that &lt;em&gt;Tiger &lt;/em&gt;holds the golfer’s entire career and public life up for scrutiny: it portrays his unprecedented successes as owed in part to the arguably abusive upbringing his father gave him and his descent into painkiller addiction and infidelity as the response of a man who was lost after his father died. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P8vswi"&gt;For the most part, &lt;em&gt;Tiger &lt;/em&gt;is successful at humanizing the person behind the headlines, even if it works at a remove. Woods himself mostly appears in archival footage, with the exception of a brief surprise appearance at the end of the film. His story is mostly told by the people who were around him at the heights of his renown: friends, rivals, journalists, and lovers form a motley crew of people caught up in the hurricane of his fame. It’s a good exploration of the casual dehumanization that’s part and parcel of modern celebrity, but at the same time, the film is so limited in scope that it can’t quite escape the lurid fascination it’s ostensibly critiquing. This is especially true in its second part, which veers into sensationalism by treating Woods’ sex scandal — the second widest-known thing about him — as a suspense narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fLci0t"&gt;Much like &lt;em&gt;The Last Dance&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; hits the mark. But the production is hindered by its subject’s involvement. Woods didn’t let anyone get too close to home, which means &lt;em&gt;Tiger &lt;/em&gt;is missing the insight you can get with a strong critical lens. Both compensate for this by focusing on the phenomenon of fame over the men themselves. These are stories less about people and more about culture in a way that’s wholly unique to professional sports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tqA9nI"&gt;Athletes make for a good measuring stick of our cultural biases because their existence tends to raise certain possibly uncomfortable questions: how much agency do we afford them? How much do we fixate on their perceived moral failings? How much pushback do we give when they don’t stick to sports? Race is an inextricable part of these stories, too. Black athletes make millions for executives and entertain fans — which leads both groups to a strange feeling of ownership over them. It manifests as a benevolent frenzy when they are performing, and it can be terrifyingly hostile when they are not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kAQ5YI"&gt;For Woods, that sense of public ownership manifested itself in the continual headlines in the early 2000s about his bad behavior. He wasn’t punished by the public just because of a salacious tabloid culture; he was punished because people felt like he tarnished the lily-white image of professional golf. He stepped out of line. It’s not hard to make the leap to other unfairly maligned athletes: Colin Kaepernick overstepped when he protested police brutality; Serena Williams has been raked over the coals for not being “sportsmanlike enough,” which is code for, ironically, what happens when &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/9/10/17837598/serena-williams-us-open-umpire-carlos-ramos"&gt;a woman behaves like one of her male colleagues&lt;/a&gt;. Some people who like the Lakers hate that LeBron James is vocal about current events. These biases aren’t new, and they’re not going anywhere. They’re a part of how we tell our pop culture stories, bad-faith arguments that often dictate how these stories are framed in our memory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cv59EP"&gt;Yet the first draft of a celebrity narrative is rarely an accurate one. It’s a managed story, carefully orchestrated by publicists and corporate interests. Star power means money, and money must be protected — yet celebrity also dictates that famous people appear relatable, that the wider public be privy to some aspects of their personal lives. And thus, infamy is sticky. If you’re Tiger Woods, the headlines can be hard to shake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aD6Dgp"&gt;It’s also rare that pop culture affords the notorious a careful reappraisal. Lately, the stars of ‘90s gossip headlines are getting a better rap than most, sitting at the confluence of an industry in dire need of content and an audience voracious for new stories about the heroes they grew up with. Though it’s imperfect, &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; can serve as a reminder that the easy stories aren’t necessarily the ones we should be telling. In truth, we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; meet our heroes — and think about who the villains really are, too.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/23/22245068/tiger-woods-tiger-documentary-review-hbo-sports-comeback"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/23/22245068/tiger-woods-tiger-documentary-review-hbo-sports-comeback</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Rivera</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
