<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-17T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon shareholders are calling for independent audit of how the company treats workers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dcy0kPRHTQrBx04wku0idvCYiYU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285873/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Amazon investors want an audit of the company’s workplace safety  | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Gzrjrm"&gt;Citing the recent scrutiny on its employees’ working conditions, a group of Amazon shareholders has filed a resolution asking the board of directors to commission an independent audit on workplace health and safety at the company. The resolution calls for the audit to be conducted with input from Amazon employees and experts in workplace safety and surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wzRTkk"&gt;“As Amazon strives to be ‘the Earth’s Safest Place to Work,’ a review is needed of the practices that have made the company a leader in workplace injuries and a target for criticism and regulation,” the shareholders’ resolution reads. “With surveillance and productivity quotas linked to high injury rates, we urge Amazon to commission an independent audit of these practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AoxBwO"&gt;If Amazon doesn’t challenge the resolution, shareholders will vote on it at the company’s annual shareholder meeting in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Wcn8p"&gt;Mary Beth Gallagher is director of engagement at Domini Impact Investments, which filed the resolution. She said Amazon needs to evaluate its business model, as well as its high turnover and injury rates. Gallagher pointed to the numerous safety &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810754/amazon-new-york-ag-reinstate-fired-worker-health-safety-covid"&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783988/amazon-ordered-pay-500000-hiding-covid-case-numbers-california-workers"&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21216172/amazon-coronavirus-protests-response-safety-jfk8-fired-covid-19"&gt;raised&lt;/a&gt; about Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/20/21188292/amazon-workers-coronavirus-essential-service-risk"&gt;workplaces&lt;/a&gt; during the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/4/1/21201162/amazon-delivery-delays-coronavirus-worker-strikes"&gt;pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, and the deaths of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22836393/amazon-warehouse-tornado-collapse-illinois-disaster"&gt;six people at an Amazon warehouse&lt;/a&gt; in Illinois that was struck by a tornado on December 10th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EWhSun"&gt;All the incidents “have raised serious questions and drawn scrutiny from legislators, regulators, and the public,” Gallagher said in a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. She said Domini wants the audit to examine “the way in which employee productivity metrics and surveillance contribute to a less safe and stable work environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3m9mrJ"&gt;Courtenay Brown, a worker at an Amazon Fresh warehouse in New Jersey and leader of workers’ group United for Respect, testified before Congress on December 7th about work conditions at her facility. She said she sorts up to 50,000 groceries for delivery daily, stepping in and out of temperatures as low as minus-10 degrees Fahrenheit. Since the warehouse is understaffed, there are few opportunities for breaks. And, she said, workers are monitored from the moment they pull into the parking lot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GKFvNR"&gt;“If we fall behind in any way during our 11 hour shift, we risk being disciplined,” Brown said before the Senate Finance Subcommittee on Fiscal Responsibility and Economic Growth. “We are pushed to our limit to the point where we can’t even take regular bathroom breaks. Often we have to run to and from the bathroom in under two minutes so we don’t get in trouble.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAJ01B"&gt;The shareholders want the audit to evaluate the company’s productivity quotas, surveillance practices, and the effects of these practices on injury rates and turnover. Amazon did not reply to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; about the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x779SH"&gt;Gallagher says her company’s hope is that a thorough evaluation “will produce corporate policy changes that make workplaces safer for associates and cement Amazon as the industry leader in health and safety it states it wants to be.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aoqTQy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="behdFk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22832447/amazon-shareholders-independent-audit-company-worker-treatment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22832447/amazon-shareholders-independent-audit-company-worker-treatment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>FedEx receives its first electric delivery vans from GM’s BrightDrop</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6peY-grffxSPDGCSthqewv6pNz0=/0x157:8509x5830/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285627/BrightDrop_EV600_with_FedEx_Express_Branding.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yMlHaq"&gt;FedEx is the first customer to receive electric delivery vans from General Motors’ new EV-focused company BrightDrop. The logistics giant says it will integrate the EVs into its fleet starting in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ckuDR6"&gt;BrightDrop, which is GM’s new dedicated electric delivery van spinoff, said it delivered five of its larger-sized EV600 delivery vans to FedEx, the first in a planned 500-vehicle order. The EV600, which went into production last fall, has 600 cubic feet of cargo space, can travel up to 250 miles on a full battery, and has a gross vehicle weight of less than 10,000 pounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9k04xJ"&gt;The vans were delivered to FedEx’s facility in Inglewood, California, where they will be housed and maintained. FedEx plans to begin deploying BrightDrop’s vehicles on the roads making deliveries in Los Angeles starting in the first half of 2022 and will add more vehicles as BrightDrop makes them available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="71hYh8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;FedEx has more than 200,000 motorized vehicles in its fleet&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S6c2zX"&gt;FedEx has more than 200,000 motorized vehicles in its fleet. As of 2019, the company had 2,944 electric vehicles in service, which included electric and hybrid delivery trucks, forklifts, and airport ground service equipment. The company has committed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311210/fedex-carbon-neutral-2040-2-billion-electric-vehicles-planes"&gt;spending $2 billion to become carbon neutral&lt;/a&gt; by 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pdJlv6"&gt;When GM first announced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225394/gm-brightdrop-electric-delivery-ep1-ev600-ces-2021"&gt;creation of BrightDrop&lt;/a&gt;, it brought up FedEx’s interest in buying electric vans from the company as a point of validation. What it didn’t mention was that FedEx has been on the hunt for a reliable EV supplier for a long time. The company had a deal with erstwhile EV startup Chanje to buy 1,000 electric delivery vans but was left in the lurch when Chanje failed to make good on its promise. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22822775/chanje-fdg-electric-delivery-vans-investigation-amazon"&gt;FedEx is now suing Chanje&lt;/a&gt;, which officially shut down earlier this year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArV6ih"&gt;GM also partnered with FedEx Express on a pilot last year to test out the EP1, an electric pallet that can be used to transport packages from a delivery vehicle to a customer’s front door. Using the electric pallet allowed FedEx workers to handle 25 percent more packages a day, GM said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VW5cDq"&gt;Meanwhile, GM decided to spin off a new EV-focused logistics business as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536601/gm-ev-investment-increase-amount-electric-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;a massive, $35 billion pivot to electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt;. GM has been nipping at the heels of Tesla and other EV makers as it attempts to &lt;a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/the-death-of-the-ev-1-118595941/"&gt;rewrite its history&lt;/a&gt; and lead the charge into an all-electric future. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22839470/fedex-gm-brightdrop-electric-delivery-van-ev600"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22839470/fedex-gm-brightdrop-electric-delivery-van-ev600</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Could a Witcher-style multiverse really exist? We asked a physicist  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wnbGbnC-buBXg5hZJWaLkSfXFlA=/0x0:3936x2624/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285584/W_207_Unit_01998_RT.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Toss a coin to the physicist who agreed to this interview&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="LJQakt"&gt;Those who plan on watching the second season of Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;The Witcher &lt;/em&gt;can look forward to plenty of epic monster battles, character development, and Henry Cavill staring broodingly into the middle distance. But season 2 also reveals a lot about the broader world that &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; takes place in — or more accurately, the many worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ierZlS"&gt;Specifically, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22826460/witcher-season-2-review-netflix"&gt;this darker and more serious&lt;/a&gt; chapter in the epic fantasy saga zooms in on a seminal event in the &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt; lore known as the &lt;a href="https://witcher.fandom.com/wiki/Conjunction_of_the_Spheres"&gt;conjunction of the spheres&lt;/a&gt;. During the conjunction, which took place approximately 1,500 years before the events of the show, a bunch of different spheres of reality collided with one another, causing elves, dwarves, humans, and monsters to all get mixed up together on the same continent, much to their mutual discontent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMkcqt"&gt;While this cosmic collision is pure fantasy, there is a potentially scientific idea at its core: some physicists have proposed that our universe may really be just one in a much grander multiverse of realities. If that’s true, it may even be possible for different universes to interact to some extent. These ideas are wildly controversial, with one camp of physicists arguing that the multiverse is more a matter of philosophy or religion than a fruitful terrain for scientific inquiry. Others say that since we can’t rule out the existence of a multiverse, there’s no harm in speculating about its nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9lKOY"&gt;With season 2 of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; dropping on Netflix today, it felt like an apt time for some rampant speculation. To keep things as scientifically grounded as possible, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;chatted with University of California, San Diego&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;cosmologist &lt;a href="https://briankeating.com/"&gt;Brian Keating&lt;/a&gt; about some of the most mind-bending multiverse ideas physicists have proposed, where pop culture stretches these ideas beyond recognition, and the cosmic horizons we may never see past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVXrJq"&gt;This conversation has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1kELg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; is not alone in popularizing the idea of the multiverse. It’s a big theme in the Marvel cinematic universe now, it’s in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. Some physicists would say the multiverse is nothing &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; science fiction. But could you tell us a bit about why others think it might really exist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HTd53q"&gt;Yeah. So the multiverse is kind of a natural extrapolation of what we call the Copernican principle, which is that where we are and who we are and what we are shouldn’t be significant or aberrant. It should be kind of representative of the properties throughout all of reality. And just as there’s many planets, there are many stars, there are many galaxies, and there are many clusters of galaxies, so, too, the logic would have one believe there is no reason to suspect that there should be only one universe. In fact, one of the foremost proponents of the multiverse paradigm, &lt;a href="https://sitp.stanford.edu/events/andrei-linde-universe-or-multiverse"&gt;Andrei Linde&lt;/a&gt;, who’s a professor at Stanford, claims that we shouldn’t be biased in favor of a universe. That we should, in fact, start from this [idea] that there probably is a multiverse. And the notion has been extended by other people to really encompass all the different types of possibilities for the existence of more than one universe: A universe that is characterized by laws of physics, constants of nature, intelligent or conscious beings, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oi16Tk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s no doubt in any physicists’ minds that there are regions of our universe which are unobservable to us.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R7E52d"&gt;The multiverse comes as directly as a consequence of two very different branches of physics. One is cosmology, in particular what’s called inflation, the theory of the ultra-high energy origin of the expansion of space and time that would later become our observable universe. And also from string theory, which predicts sort of a landscape of possible values for different fundamental constants and forces. So these two different fields, which aren’t really associated with one another, both imply that there is the possibility for a multiverse. And as yet, there is a vast disagreement as to whether or not the multiverse actually is part of physics, or if it’s pure philosophy. And if it’s part of physics, how could one go about testing it or even falsifying its existence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ObRPK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So to be clear, we have no direct evidence for the existence of a multiverse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0l8URu"&gt;So the question is whether or not it’s even in principle &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; to provide evidence that supports a multiverse. And if such evidence can’t be found, is it possible to rule out the existence of the multiverse? Because you might be living in a multiverse, but then you might not be able to detect that you’re living in a multiverse the same way that bacteria in a petri dish can’t detect that they live inside of a laboratory inside of a building inside of a planet. It’s too remote from the sphere of reality that they have access to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZA0wmC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s like eating cosmic Wonder Bread.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vD9iIz"&gt;Now, there are people who propose there are ways to measure the possibility that we are in a multiverse. The one particular signature would be looking for an impact, or a collision with another universe, that would produce an observational pattern in the oldest light in the universe called the cosmic microwave background radiation, which is what I study. And that theory, or conjecture, is pretty wildly contested. It’s not at all clear if you could categorically detect and therefore motivate the existence of the multiverse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hRfJ9W"&gt;But there’s no doubt in any physicists’ minds that there are regions of our universe which are unobservable to us. And in that sense, you know, we already believe in a sort of multiverse. But then, extending and adding new features onto that multiverse, from inflation or from string theory, that’s where things get very controversial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TC6jvU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As I said a moment ago, we’ve seen a lot of depictions of the idea of the multiverse in pop culture. I think what makes &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stand out a little bit is it’s not just positing there are all these different universes out there in their own separate bubbles, but that universes have collided with each other. There’s a historical, cataclysmic collision that sort of sets the stage for the events of the series. In the context of a multiverse, do physicists have any ideas as to whether, or how, different universes might interact?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIVspt"&gt;First of all, physicists aren’t in agreement that the multiverse is a serious scientific paradigm worthy of discussion. A lot of people believe it’s not. On the other hand, if you do take it seriously, then you can ask questions about it. But then it’s not clear whether or not there’s any evidence, or set of evidence, that could prove it wrong. Because you could say, well, we thought this was evidence for the multiverse. But actually, in the multiverse, since anything is possible to happen, you can get any range of predictions that you want. And so it’s kind of unsatisfying. It’s like eating cosmic Wonder Bread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="giG1h4"&gt;In the context where these universes collide, it could be just as light travels at a finite speed, the Sun could disappear right now, and we wouldn’t see it for eight minutes. So it’s not possible to say something is ruled out just by not seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q4s8oN"&gt;So there could be a multiverse. It could be one light-year away from us, in a certain sense, in which case next year we’ll see it. It could be 10^50 light-years away from us, in which case we’ll never see it. So it could turn out, yes, tomorrow we impact a universe that’s one light-year away from us. But the thing I would gently push back on is that the notion of a collision nucleating some vast explosion is not at all clear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2AnPLv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Just because something is mathematically possible doesn’t mean it has any physical relevance.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MuNoHR"&gt;For example, we know for sure we will eventually collide with the Andromeda galaxy, which is our nearest neighbor galaxy. It’s almost like a twin sister of ours, and it has almost the same number of stars, hundreds of billions of stars. It’s even more massive than ours, and it’s one of the few galaxies we’re moving towards rather than expanding away from, according to Hubble. That galaxy will someday crash into our galaxy, but it’s not like every single point will collide and each star will hit another star. In fact, they’ll mostly pass right through each other. So if a galaxy, which is billions of times more dense than the universe on average, can pass right through another galaxy, all the more so a universe could pass through another universe in a certain sense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TympVk"&gt;So I think it’s artistic license to suggest that that could nucleate some fireworks. But I admit it’s pretty cute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ElySmS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could there be any sorts of interactions between different universes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtdCiu"&gt;Yeah, in fact, one of the ways you might see the impact of a universe adjacent to ours is that it might have a gravitational force that deflects the light traveling in our universe. But all of this would be taking place at the boundary of what we can see just today. In other words, it wouldn’t be happening to us. It would be happening 45 billion light-years away from us and we would just be seeing it now [&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: 45 billion light years is the approximate radius of the observable universe&lt;/em&gt;]. Unless you’re talking about some interdimensional wormhole between different universes, and that’s incredibly speculative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9S0fnQ"&gt;And some of the problems with these physical phenomena when applied to science fiction, like wormholes and other things, is that they’re barely at the level of speculation. They’re completely removed from testability in laboratory settings. They’re mathematical possibilities. But as I always say, mathematics allows the possibility for infinity. You know, just divide one by zero. But there is nothing that we know about in the universe that’s infinite. Nothing that has infinite temperature, density, pressure, energy, etc. So just because something is mathematically possible doesn’t mean it has any physical relevance. So I don’t want to be a downer. But the reality is, yes, it is possible to witness the effects of another universe interacting with ours. But it would be occurring not here, but a very, very distant there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbQJu8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So it sounds like a physically plausible story about the multiverse would not have a lot of cool stuff to look at. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErRgiq"&gt;Well, yeah, it’s like saying, you know, a black hole or a wormhole as is possible. Of course, we measure black holes, but we don’t measure any near us, right? There’s not one that we can kind of play with and jump into and then pop out, you know, in the Andromeda galaxy, even, let alone in another universe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iGR8ME"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s no reason to be chauvinistic, to think it would be like our universe.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HsLeWG"&gt;And by the way, if the laws of physics change from universe to universe, it’s not at all clear that the laws of mathematics, or the laws of logic, would be forbidden from changing. In other words, you get into a wormhole in our universe. You pop out in another universe. Well, the laws of wormholes are based on the laws of black holes, which are the consequence of general relativity, which is a consequence of partial differential equations, which is a consequence of calculus, which is a consequence of real numbers. And who knows if there’s such a thing as real numbers in another universe? Just as the old joke goes, an old fish swims by two young fish and says to them, “How’s the water?” And they say, “What’s water?” They have no concept of it. It’s so alien to their existence that they can’t even contemplate it. And there’s no reason to be chauvinistic, to think it would be like our universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abgE0F"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like we see that idea represented at least a little bit allegorically in science fiction — and this true in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; as well — in how when beings move from universe to universe, they often can’t survive in the other universe for an extended period of time because it’s fundamentally so different.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A8vJQa"&gt;In my first book &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Losing-Nobel-Prize-Cosmology-Ambition/dp/1324000910?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Losing the Nobel Prize&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I made this kind of analogy which I called the petriverse. So imagine there’s some bacterium and it’s in a petri dish and it starts making a colony. That bacterium, if it was very smart, could realize that there’s a possibility for another colony really far away from it to exist because it has the agar gel and it has gravity and sunlight and whatever. It could deduce that there is a possibility for another universe in the petriverse, and actually some of these other colonies when they do form, even though they are only a couple of centimeters away, they produce toxins that prevent other bacteria from invading their space. So it’s like, a barrier that makes it inhospitable and hostile to the existence of hopping between universes, just like what you described. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9auN2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sorts of advances in physics could we make in the coming decades that might shed light on this question of whether the multiverse is real? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNBLLN"&gt;I think the field that I’m studying, which is the cosmic microwave background, the key observable, and what we’re trying to discover, is unequivocal evidence that inflation took place. And if inflation took place, that would come concomitantly with the multiverse in most physicists’ anticipation. They go as a direct consequence. If you discover these waves of gravity embedded in the cosmic microwave background, then you would get a very strong piece of evidence that would seem to mandate the multiverse exists. [&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: Keating later clarified that this would be ‘perhaps the strongest circumstantial evidence possible’ for a multiverse.&lt;/em&gt;] On the other hand, it may be that inflation took place, but it’s too weak to produce observable gravitational waves, in which case you might need to wait till a future version of the &lt;a href="https://www.ligo.caltech.edu/"&gt;LIGO&lt;/a&gt; [the Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory] experiment in space called &lt;a href="https://lisa.nasa.gov/"&gt;LISA&lt;/a&gt;. And that could potentially take us back and show us evidence of the fundamental origination from, perhaps, the surrounding multiverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OENgck"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The multiverse ensures full employment for cosmologists for years to come.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AlbpWs"&gt;And I should point out there’s other ways that multiverses [could exist]. There’s a quantum mechanical version of the multiverse called the “many worlds interpretation.” And that’s that at every possible moment of time, every possible choice, every possible observable, is instantiated. But we only observe one particular outcome for each observation because we’re sort of coherently oscillating with those quantum mechanical wave functions, and therefore we can observe them. Those are kind of parallel universes going on right now. So if I turn my head to the right or the left, there’s a whole universe where Brian turned his head to the left. So that’s a version of the multiverse. There’s also a version of the multiverse where the universe is cyclical in a certain sense; it’s coming into existence, it’s coming out of existence in a collapse. It’s reemerging, and it’s kind of growing, and then that universe collapses. So that’s kind of a temporal multiverse. And those kinds of models have been around since antiquity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DwFLPA"&gt;I would say, it’s hard to find a model of cosmology that doesn’t have some version of a multiverse in it, whether that’s temporal or spatial, or spatial and temporal, or quantum mechanical. So there are hopes that one could get some confidence from measuring aspects of quantum mechanics. And then there’s the cosmic and gravitational wave experiments that I do. And then, perhaps if string theory were to make much more concrete predictions. So I think there’s a lot more theoretical advances that need to be made, a lot more experimental [advances]. But fundamentally, we may never be able to prove it wrong. In other words, you ruled out 10^499 different universes but you didn’t rule out this one. And these observations therefore become what’s called unfalsifiable. In which case you can’t prove that inflation’s wrong, but you also can’t prove that the alternatives are right. And in that case, all hope would be lost. You can’t prove it using an experiment or evidence, you can only prove it on Twitter or something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WTteDx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sounds like the multiverse is going to continue to fuel physics beef for many years to come. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAMqKc"&gt;Yes. I always say, inflation for economists means one thing. But for us, the multiverse ensures full employment for cosmologists for years to come. And for science fiction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4T149q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pJ4Tko"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taUbu3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZcvUK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wT2vtr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iVg2bK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50G7Gn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ayEPk1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qg9tsT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Jfk2b"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPEhlh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AHb7Av"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ru68b8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bY7DTW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hh3SuA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1gZHdF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cLmuSr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22839928/witcher-multiverse-physicist-explains"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22839928/witcher-multiverse-physicist-explains</id>
    <author>
      <name>Maddie Stone</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T06:42:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T06:42:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo adds five new Sega Genesis games to its Switch Online Expansion Pack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jWlXKsiovMm0jlv6OvFtu7hoJ48=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285129/NintendoSwitchOLEDmodel_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ly0vPj"&gt;Nintendo has expanded its Expansion Pack for the Switch, adding five new Sega Genesis titles to the most expensive tier of its online subscription service. Those titles are &lt;em&gt;Altered Beast&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; ToeJam &amp;amp; Earl&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Dynamite Headdy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sword of Vermilion&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;em&gt; Thunder Force II. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRl2sP"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing"&gt;Expansion Pack subscription tier&lt;/a&gt; costs $49.99 annually for an individual subscription or $79.99 for a family membership (compared to $19.99 / $34.99 for a regular Switch Online subscription). For the extra cash, subscribers get access to larger back catalog of games. Both tiers include classic NES and Super NES titles like the	&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Super Mario World &lt;/em&gt;while the Expansion Pack adds games from the Nintendo 64 (like &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;) and the Sega Genesis (known as the Sega Mega Drive outside of North America). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gFc09j"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;5 additional &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SEGAGenesis?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SEGAGenesis&lt;/a&gt; games are now available for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitchOnline?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NintendoSwitchOnline&lt;/a&gt; + Expansion Pack members! Which will you play first?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Altered Beast&lt;br&gt;- ToeJam &amp;amp; Earl&lt;br&gt;- Dynamite Headdy&lt;br&gt;- Sword of Vermilion&lt;br&gt;- Thunder Force II &lt;a href="https://t.co/MhtISzBN0M"&gt;pic.twitter.com/MhtISzBN0M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1471646839225077761?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aCZAek"&gt;Other Sega Genesis titles available in the Expansion Pack include &lt;em&gt;Golden Axe, Streets of Rage 2, Shinobi III: Return of the Ninja Master, Sonic The Hedgehog 2, Ecco The Dolphin, Phantasy Star IV, &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Castlevania Bloodline&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841042/nintendo-switch-online-expansion-pack-sega-geneis-games-new-titles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841042/nintendo-switch-online-expansion-pack-sega-geneis-games-new-titles</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T06:16:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T06:16:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton scrubs viral ads starring Chris Noth after the Mr. Big actor is accused of sexual assault</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Celebrity Sightings In New York - November 07, 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YtB9C7RuG2w-jAwBD8bTFVAOm_A=/0x130:3100x2197/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285105/1236439110.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Chris Noth played Mr. Big in Sex and the City and its sequel series And Just Like That. | Photo by Jason Howard/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PWyeRt"&gt;Peloton has removed a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/13/22831861/peloton-and-just-like-that-big-commercial-response"&gt;viral ad starring Chris Noth&lt;/a&gt;, the actor who plays Mr. Big in HBO Max’s &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City &lt;/em&gt;and its sequel series &lt;em&gt;And Just Like That, &lt;/em&gt;after Noth was accused of sexual assault. Peloton says it’s stopped promoting the videos until it “learns more” about the accusations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJ9Xia"&gt;In a story &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/chris-noth-accused-of-sexual-assault-1235063596/"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, two women alleged that Noth assaulted them in 2004 and 2015 respectively. One of the women said that “seeing that [Noth] was reprising his role in Sex and the City set off something in me.” She added: “For so many years, I buried it,” but decided it was time “to try to go public with who he is.” Noth has denied the allegations against him and claims the sexual encounters were consensual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0a6YW0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Every single sexual assault accusation must be taken seriously”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KR6FHx"&gt;A spokesperson for Peloton &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/peloton-chris-noth-sexual-assault-allegations-1235063871/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it was unaware of the allegations when it made the commercial. “Every single sexual assault accusation must be taken seriously,” said a spokesperson for the company. “We were unaware of these allegations when we featured Chris Noth in our response to HBO’s reboot. As we seek to learn more, we have stopped promoting this video and archived related social posts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GovZT5"&gt;The ad essentially resurrected Noth’s character after he was killed off in an episode of &lt;em&gt;And Just Like That &lt;/em&gt;after a 45-minute Peloton workout. It was made in collaboration with actor Ryan Reynolds and his marketing company, Maximum Effort. Reynolds supplied a voiceover for the commercial, which extolled the benefits of Peloton’s exercise bikes for healthy living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49l2v8"&gt;The ad has now been deleted from social media accounts belonging to Peloton, Maximum Effort, and Reynolds.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841034/peloton-viral-ads-sex-and-the-city-mr-big-chris-noth-sexual-assault"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841034/peloton-viral-ads-sex-and-the-city-mr-big-chris-noth-sexual-assault</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T05:59:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T05:59:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is pushing the Control Panel aside in its latest Windows 11 updates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GI30Ri1yNaQaK7xV6ralEgXqji4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285033/VRG_ILLO_4030_Windows_10_Guide_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GBNwvU"&gt;Microsoft is finally signaling the end of the legacy Control Panel in Windows 11. The software giant introduced a number of changes in its Settings section of Windows 11 earlier this year, and this month the company has started testing even more ways to replace Control Panel functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMuqVw"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/12/01/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22509/"&gt;new test versions of Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft has moved the advanced network settings into a new page in the Settings app, which includes sharing options for folders, printers, and network discovery options. Some entry points to the network and device settings in Windows 11 also now redirect to the Settings app, instead of forcing you into the Control Panel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LFmI0iml9ltrPFSGi2dpnw_nvA4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103467/D51G3TZ.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Control Panel in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JHDrgN"&gt;Elsewhere, links to the section of the Control Panel used to uninstall apps now redirect to the Settings app. Even the section for uninstalling Windows Updates &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/12/15/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22523/"&gt;is now part of the Settings app&lt;/a&gt;, instead of being housed in the Control Panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VExSC5"&gt;These latest changes are welcome, and come after attempts to move away from the Control Panel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/28/9045331/microsoft-windows-10-review"&gt;in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft originally introduced a separate Settings app in Windows 8, as a way to overhaul its traditional Control Panel. The two have existed alongside each other for legacy support reasons, just like how Microsoft had two browsers (Internet Explorer and Microsoft Edge) inside Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26SuKw"&gt;The Settings app was designed to be a new broom that sweeps clean, but there are still plenty of settings that require you to head into the Control Panel. Windows 10 improved things, and Windows 11 offers an even more modern take on how users control their PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rf2hO7"&gt;Microsoft describes these latest changes as an “ongoing effort to bring over settings from Control Panel into the Settings app.” So it’s clear Microsoft is committed to cleaning this area of Windows up, and eventually making the Control Panel redundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XA9A6G"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"&gt;Windows 11 has largely been an attempt to modernize&lt;/a&gt; and simplify a Windows operating system that has been used the same way for decades. Microsoft didn’t quite go far enough with the Control Panel for the initial release of Windows 11, but in other areas like the taskbar it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812258/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-clock-multiple-monitors-start-menu-updates"&gt;simplified things far too much&lt;/a&gt;. These monthly changes pave the way for Microsoft to finalize what has felt like an unfinished version of Windows so far.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841028/microsoft-windows-11-control-panel-changes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841028/microsoft-windows-11-control-panel-changes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T23:01:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T23:01:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG refreshes its pricey Pro OLED monitors for 2022 and adds a 27-inch option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QF2xc275699hRBPk-N_mCUhw09E=/0x0:1796x1197/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284663/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_00_1200.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="paZXTd"&gt;In 2021 LG &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224922/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-4k-monitor-ces-2021"&gt;added an OLED-based monitor for pros to its lineup&lt;/a&gt;, and now the company has revealed the follow-up UltraFine OLED Pro monitors it’s planned for 2022. While its first effort was only available as a $3,999 31.5-inch 4K monitor, next year’s version will include a 27-inch variant. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/akWb2Np5u72wRkGLxhKQseQH6UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103191/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_01_1800.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpLtHz"&gt;Naturally, the 32BP95E and 27BP95E still feature the precise lighting control you’d expect from an OLED panel; however, these screens aren’t meant for gaming or even TV and movie watching. The promise LG’s DisplayHDR 400 True Black technology ensures that if you’re editing photos or video, everything looks the way it truly should. They’ll also ship with detachable self-calibration sensors and monitor hoods and use the LG Calibration Studio software to adjust their settings for the environment. Other hardware specs like their port selections appear to be similar to the 2021 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hTt0eMZdKSmg48vKIZ5R3kobt1g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103210/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_02_800.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mcXD6w"&gt;The monitors can accurately display colors covering 99 percent of the DCI-P3 and AdobeRGB color gamut plus a 1,000,000:1 contrast ratio, so it will be difficult to find as accurate reproduction on any consumer display. LG didn’t note a refresh rate in its press materials, so we’d expect it’s still set at 60Hz. You could buy an expensive screen like this and use it for gaming, but it’s not really intended for use in daytime lit environments or fast-moving action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Tveky"&gt;It also won’t hit the peak brightness of LCD monitors like LG’s own UltraFine displays, or the $4,999 (plus $999 optional stand) Apple Pro Display XDR &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"&gt;we reviewed in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, but even with local dimming, those simply can’t display absolute black like an OLED panel can. As Nilay Patel said about Apple’s monitor, “while it can run with the very best full-array local dimming LCDs I’ve ever seen, it’s still a local dimming LCD: sometimes it blooms, and sometimes all of the dimming zones are lit up, and blacks look gray across the whole screen.” We would expect that things will be different with these screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eAPVGF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"LG UltraFine 4K Display (2019) review: bigger isn’t better ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/2/20678597/lg-ultrafine-4k-2019-mac-monitor-review-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Apple Pro Display XDR review: category of one  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VHdkX4"&gt;There’s no word on pricing but these monitors should start shipping next month in “key markets.” Still, hopefully, the smaller model will be a bit cheaper than last year’s, which finally started shipping in the US in September — if you can’t wait for the updated versions, that one’s currently available from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-32EP950-B-Ultrafine-Display-DCI-P3/dp/B097NYL7XS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-32ep950-b-oled-monitor&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840813%2Flg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1621997-REG%2Flg_32ep950_b_32_oled_uhd_dci_p3.html%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840813%2Flg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ZwpXG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840813/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840813/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T21:30:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T21:30:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Holmes trial is about money  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Theranos Founder Elizabeth Holmes Attends Criminal Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/czzIlkNNUQtftxTFVPvO1CscoQM=/1x0:4000x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284417/1237270984.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;It was never about the people&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="7rhnf1"&gt;Prosecutor Jeffrey Schenk opened his closing arguments in the case against Elizabeth Holmes by talking about a banker. Holmes knew Theranos, the company she founded, was running out of money, and she was on the phone asking her banker to clear a check early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CINZPi"&gt;“Holmes had a choice to make,” Schenk said. She could figure out a way to raise funds to keep the company moving, or risk seeing it wither away. And her choice, he said, was to raise the funds through fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QH4GQ7"&gt;The prosecution’s closing statement on Thursday was a reminder of what this trial is really about: money, and mostly rich people’s money. Those rich people, who gave their money to Theranos after Holmes pitched them on the promise of the company, are who the prosecutor referred to as ‘victims.’ Their money is what, according to the legal system, was manipulated during the years Theranos was the hottest startup in Silicon Valley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WV0NBG"&gt;That focus is because Holmes is on trial for fraud. That’s what she could get in trouble for in the aftermath of Theranos’ collapse — misrepresenting what the company could do in order to get money out of (mostly) investors (but technically also) patients and doctors. Holmes isn’t on trial because the tests her company made were bad. She’s not in trouble because her company gave people incorrect information about potentially devastating health issues. She couldn’t go to jail for overseeing workplace former employees described as &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Business/theranos-employees-describe-culture-secrecy-elizabeth-holmes-startup/story?id=60544673"&gt;secretive&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/theranos-employees-claim-toxic-work-culture-part-61720603"&gt;unhealthy&lt;/a&gt;, and where the chief scientist &lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/elizabeth-holmes-trial-dredges-up-toxic-memories-for-theranos-workers"&gt;died by suicide&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="5J6M2y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She’s not in trouble because her company gave people incorrect information about potentially devastating health issues&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3zR4Kt"&gt;Theoretically, she could have continued to oversee a company doing all of those things, and not be facing 20 years in prison. The reason she’s staring down incarceration isn’t for making bad tests — it’s for lying about those tests in order to fundraise. “An honest pitch filled with honest representations to her investors and to patients would not have resulted in any revenue,” Schenk said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhhZd0"&gt;She didn’t make an honest pitch, Schenk argued. And that’s why, he told the jury, she should be found guilty of fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSavQ0"&gt;Before diving into the specific ways Holmes wasn’t honest, Schenk broke down exactly what the government had to prove in order to show that she met the technical, legal requirements for fraud. Holmes is on trial for two things: conspiracy to commit fraud, and fraud. She allegedly &lt;em&gt;conspired&lt;/em&gt; to commit fraud against investors and patients, and allegedly &lt;em&gt;committed&lt;/em&gt; fraud against investors and patients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LwUQi6"&gt;To meet the bar for a conspiracy, Holmes had to have been part of an agreement to make false statements for the purpose of getting money that would keep Theranos alive. In order to have committed fraud, she had to have known and participated in a plan to get money by making misleading statements, and those statements had to be things that could reasonably trigger someone to spend money. And — in a key element — she had to have acted with the &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; to defraud someone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ziYiJX"&gt;Schenk spent around three hours pacing in front of the jury and walking them through all the ways Holmes made misleading statements to investors. He talked about the pharmaceutical company logos &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799756/elizabeth-holmes-pfizer-logo-confession"&gt;she admitted to adding&lt;/a&gt; on to Theranos-conducted lab reports, which investors said gave the impression those companies had prepared the reports themselves. He emphasized that she’d given investors misleading information about what types of tests could be run on the Theranos machines, and gave the impression that the machines were accurate even though they weren’t. He pointed to media interviews where she’d given the same types of answers, and said that Holmes then turned around and sent articles based on those interviews to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKakDL"&gt;Then, Schenk showed the jury evidence that he argued means Holmes gave that misleading information intentionally — like text messages about Theranos’ money issues, and emails about problems with demonstrations of the Theranos devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KLImjP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Schenk showed the jury evidence that he argued means Holmes gave that misleading information intentionally&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cmBEds"&gt;(Defense attorney Kevin Downey focused his closing statements on the idea that Holmes didn’t actually have intent. He started in on that argument on Thursday, and will continue it Friday morning). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8B5sWY"&gt;Schenk pointed out that patients saw the misleading statements given in media interviews, as well, which is one way they were allegedly defrauded. Patients also got bad information about the accuracy of the Theranos tests in advertisements and on the company website, even though Holmes new that there were problems with certain tests — like the hCG test, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22687026/theranos-patient-bad-test-miscarriage-pregnancy"&gt;told patient Brittany Gould that she might be having a miscarriage. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igEek9"&gt;Holmes intentionally directed misleading statements to patients for the same reason she did investors, Schenk said: to raise money. But, as he noted multiple times, individual tests raised less money than investors. He spent less time focusing on the patients and their experience than he did on the investors. Unlike the investors, he didn’t refer to the patients who were given bad medical test results as victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tj0dFG"&gt;Closing arguments from the prosecution told a story about a company that was running out of money, and a CEO who lied to people in order to get them to give them more money. That’s illegal. And that’s what the legal system is equipped to get people in trouble for. Schenk summed that up quite well towards the end of his closing arguments: “This case is about real people, who lost real money.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1eFDF8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QpA89P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840697/holmes-trial-theranos-closing-arguments"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840697/holmes-trial-theranos-closing-arguments</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T21:19:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T21:19:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Schools across US cancel classes over unconfirmed TikTok threats</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_gqIcUhNUSnHkWe-_-7-ilOOm0o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284380/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Unconfirmed threats on TikTok led some schools to cancel classes | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WUW6gk"&gt;School districts across the United States are cancelling classes on Friday, December 17th due to reports of threats that are supposedly being made on TikTok. Districts in &lt;a href="http://nixle.us/alert/9144787/"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.wfaa.com/article/news/education/threats-against-kaufman-high-school-prompts-school-closure-friday-texas/287-6c32c971-27d0-4df6-a7e9-5a26fe9fedea"&gt;Texas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.lfalls.k12.mn.us/2021/12/december-17-threat/"&gt;Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://abc17news.com/news/education/2021/12/16/gasconade-county-school-district-to-close-friday-after-tiktok-threat-challenge/"&gt;Missouri&lt;/a&gt; have said they plan to close down Friday in response, according to the districts and local media reports. Elsewhere, districts have said they plan to have heightened police presence or have emailed parents to say they’ve been investigating the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M6kFt4"&gt;But so far, there’s little evidence that the threats are credible — or even exist. The districts and local police departments largely say they’ve heard about a trend referencing the possibility of shootings or bombings on December 17th, but it’s not clear how many have seen a specific threat or a threat against their schools in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDn440"&gt;A number of districts and law enforcement divisions say they’ve looked into it and don’t view the threats as credible or even real. “Law enforcement agencies have investigated this threat and determined that it originated in Arizona and is not credible,” Baltimore County Public Schools &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BaltCoPS/status/1471498518003027979?s=20"&gt;wrote on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “Currently, there have been no threats to any of the schools in Mexico, [Missouri],” wrote a &lt;a href="https://abc17news.com/news/education/2021/12/16/gasconade-county-school-district-to-close-friday-after-tiktok-threat-challenge/"&gt;Missouri school district&lt;/a&gt;. “There have been no local, credible threats,” Ohio’s Milford Exempted Village School District &lt;a href="https://www.milfordschools.org/news-feed/entry/safety-update%3A-tiktok-challenge-dec-17-723/"&gt;wrote to parents&lt;/a&gt;. In New Jersey, Governor Phil Murphy &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/status/1471613653749313547?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “there are no known specific threats against New Jersey schools.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dQVUxZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;While there are no known specific threats against New Jersey schools, the safety of our children is our highest priority and we will work closely with law enforcement to monitor the situation and remain prepared.&lt;/p&gt;— Governor Phil Murphy (@GovMurphy) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/status/1471613654953046028?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cPgrKK"&gt;The reports of threats on TikTok may be self-perpetuating. Videos being posted to TikTok warn others that they should skip school on December 17th due to supposed threats of shootings or bombings, which seem to have prompted others to create similar videos. And now that schools are canceling classes in response to those supposed threats, a new wave of videos have popped up with additional warnings based on both the supposed claims and  the actual, factual cancellations of some school classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8iyAls"&gt;TikTok says it has not identified any videos making specific threats. “We have not found evidence of such threats originating or spreading via TikTok,” the company wrote in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1471572096111239175?s=20"&gt;a tweet&lt;/a&gt; Thursday afternoon. TikTok said it is working with law enforcement to look into the warnings with “utmost seriousness,” nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sJCYJW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We handle even rumored threats with utmost seriousness, which is why we're working with law enforcement to look into warnings about potential violence at schools even though we have not found evidence of such threats originating or spreading via TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;— TikTokComms (@TikTokComms) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1471572096111239175?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="seT3YQ"&gt;One school district in Little Falls, Minnesota, opted to cancel classes on Friday after being notified by the state’s Department of Public Safety about “a TikTok trend that emerged targeting Friday, December 17, as a day of threats of shootings and bombings in schools.”  &lt;a href="https://www.lfalls.k12.mn.us/2021/12/december-17-threat/"&gt;According to a post&lt;/a&gt; on the Little Falls Community Schools website, law enforcement determined via interviews that Little Falls was “specifically identified in a TikTok post related to this threat,” unlike other schools and school district that believe they haven’t specifically been named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qsFBpB"&gt;But the district didn’t say that they had actually viewed the threat themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wal8Gu"&gt;Superintendent Stephen Jones said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the Little Falls district made the decision to cancel after consulting with law enforcement. “What I can tell you is that the threat was communicated to schools through students reportedly viewing it on TikTok,” Jones said, adding that police were following through with an investigation. “The fact that the origin of the threat has not been determined has led us to be proactive in our desire to be cautious to keep our kids and families safe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sr9qfh"&gt;At least one police department says it viewed a message threatening a school on Friday: Police in Gilroy, California &lt;a href="http://nixle.us/alert/9144787/"&gt;describe a threatening post&lt;/a&gt; that included initials matching a local high school, and school was canceled as a result. But police say they later determined the post was actually about a different high school in Los Angeles. The Los Angeles School Police Department identified who posted it, they said, and determined he was not a “credible threat.” Gilroy police didn’t say whether the post was made on TikTok. The Los Angeles School Police Department and the Gilroy Police Department did not immediately respond to requests for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHDWI3"&gt;School districts have dealt with dangerous rumors going viral on TikTok before. This year, there was concern about a “slap a teacher” challenge, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3aq3e5/slap-a-teacher-tiktok-challenge-hoax"&gt;which turned out to be fake&lt;/a&gt;. Another supposed challenge dared kids to steal items from their school; in that case, some students actually followed through — though others, it turned out, were just &lt;a href="https://www.curbed.com/2021/09/the-grown-up-hysteria-around-tiktoks-devious-licks-trend.html"&gt;pretended to take things&lt;/a&gt; to get in on the trend.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840621/tiktok-december-17-school-threats-district-cancellations-alleged-shootings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840621/tiktok-december-17-school-threats-district-cancellations-alleged-shootings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T20:46:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T20:46:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>FTC opens antitrust probe into Meta’s purchase of VR fitness app Supernatural</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KF6XqMiPf_vdDmE4BU3x9oDyrsE=/0x4:2160x1444/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284319/Supernatural_VR.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EnIbqZ"&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission has opened an in-depth antitrust probe of Meta’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753403/supernatural-within-studio-facebook-meta-oculus-vr-fitness-experiences-metaverse"&gt;plan to buy the popular VR fitness app Supernatural&lt;/a&gt;, according &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/ftc-slows-meta-platforms-metaverse-strategy-by-extending-antitrust-probe-of-vr-deal?utm_source=ti_app&amp;amp;rc=k5vrz1"&gt;to a new report by &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AUXFEt"&gt;The probe means that antitrust regulators are starting to scrutinize the-company-formally-known-as-Facebook’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22537795/is-facebook-cornering-the-vr-market"&gt;interest in scooping up VR startups&lt;/a&gt;, not just its traditional social media acquisitions. According to &lt;em&gt;The Information’s &lt;/em&gt;Josh Sisco, Meta’s previous five virtual reality acquisitions, including its deal for the studio behind hit game &lt;em&gt;Beat Saber&lt;/em&gt;, weren't probed by the government because the purchase prices were too small. “But those regulators are slowing down the $400 million-plus Supernatural deal, according to two people with knowledge of the situation,” the report notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBYLQq"&gt;It’s unclear what criteria the FTC, which is simultaneously suing Meta in a bid to unwind the acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp, is using to evaluate the VR deal. VR is a nascent but fast-growing industry that third-party estimates say Meta has a majority market share of, thanks mostly to the early success of its Quest 2 headset. While the FTC might eventually approve the Supernatural deal, its decision to investigate signals that Meta’s playbook of quickly buying the hottest VR startups on its platform may already be coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840635/ftc-opens-antitrust-probe-meta-deal-vr-fitness-app-supernatural"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840635/ftc-opens-antitrust-probe-meta-deal-vr-fitness-app-supernatural</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
