<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-21T10:59:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:59:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:59:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft removes Xbox Live Gold requirement for free-to-play games today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bzkeT_8-ID-yXliU6NwdPwhqwTI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69163080/acastro_180604_1777_xbox_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qgVYZV"&gt;Microsoft is removing its requirement for an Xbox Live Gold subscription to play free-to-play multiplayer games today. The software maker has been testing this removal over the past few weeks, and now every Xbox One and Xbox Series S / X owner will be able to play free multiplayer games without Xbox Live Gold. Microsoft is also unlocking Xbox party chat and the Looking For Groups (LFG) feature as part of this rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gFhCw3"&gt;The Xbox Live Gold changes mean popular games like &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and many others will no longer require a subscription. More than 50 games will now be free-to-play. The changes certainly make the $299 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"&gt;Xbox Series S console&lt;/a&gt; a lot more appealing as a device for free-to-play multiplayer games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O96hlE"&gt;Microsoft’s removal of the Xbox Live Gold requirement came after the company was forced to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/23/22245630/microsoft-xbox-live-gold-price-increase-reversed-f2p"&gt;reverse a price hike&lt;/a&gt; to its Xbox Live Gold subscriptions earlier this year. Microsoft had attempted to double the cost of a yearly Xbox Live Gold subscription, a move that didn’t go down well with Xbox fans. Microsoft quickly backtracked and offered to remove the paywall for free-to-play multiplayer games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K7zn1u"&gt;Now that Microsoft has also made Xbox party chat and LFG free to use, it leaves Xbox Live Gold in a weird spot. Xbox Live Gold also provides monthly free games to subscribers and discounts for the Microsoft Store, but most of its core features are now free to all modern Xbox owners. You’ll still need an Xbox Live Gold subscription for an Xbox 360, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T54uLj"&gt;Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22345276/microsoft-xbox-live-network-rebrand-name-change"&gt;dropping Xbox Live branding&lt;/a&gt;, referring to the set of software and services as simply the Xbox network now. The company has also been convincing its loyal base of Xbox Live Gold subscribers to migrate over to Xbox Game Pass, a subscription service with more than 100 games that is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/24/21336892/microsoft-xbox-series-x-game-pass-event-showcase-future"&gt;Microsoft’s main focus for its plans for gaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395433/microsoft-xbox-live-gold-free-multiplayer-games-party-chat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395433/microsoft-xbox-live-gold-free-multiplayer-games-party-chat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:41:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:41:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku’s Quibi content has a new, original name</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FXGT8N-WyjnPO3I9tiPQIajMNo0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162965/akrales_190422_3301_0198.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1MzNnM"&gt;Roku is officially getting into original content. The set-top box maker announced Roku Originals, a new brand, in a &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210421005270/en/Roku-Unveils-%E2%80%9CRoku-Originals%E2%80%9D-Brand-Bringing-Bold-Fresh-Entertainment-to-The-Roku-Channel/?feedref=JjAwJuNHiystnCoBq_hl-Q-tiwWZwkcswR1UZtV7eGe24xL9TZOyQUMS3J72mJlQ7fxFuNFTHSunhvli30RlBNXya2izy9YOgHlBiZQk2LOzmn6JePCpHPCiYGaEx4DL1Rq8pNwkf3AarimpDzQGuQ=="&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; today. Roku says it will debut over 75 original series and films this year on its free, ad-supported network, The Roku Channel. Quite a few of these original new shows will come from the Quibi library of content &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220426/quibi-roku-channel-acquisition-content"&gt;Roku got in a fire sale in January 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vOqzS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285819/roku-original-content-job-listing-plan-original-shows-movies"&gt;Earlier this year, &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; spied a job listing that suggested Roku would be investing in original content beyond the Quibi stuff it now owns. Free, ad-supported content is still a relatively new but growing area in streaming. Peacock, Paramount Plus, and even Plex have all had some success wooing viewers with totally free stuff they can watch on their set-top boxes and smart TVs. It makes sense that Roku, a company that makes the bulk of its money from ads already, would follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="purple text saying Roku Originals" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_--x06s1KCnsxXE8UmBwWIJh_10=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459357/Roku_Originals_Logo.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Roku&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The very original new brand for original content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g0WvOV"&gt;There’s no word on which content will be released first or when it will even begin airing, but it's likely you’ll see the old Quibi content before any of Roku’s other original programming. That content is full of big names like Anna Kendrick, Idris Elba, and Liam Hemsworth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJXPyt"&gt;What will be interesting is how the Quibi content airs. Quibi’s gimmick (which was absolutely bizarre but also totally ahead of its time) was that content would change depending on how you held your phone, with separate and sometimes totally different streams provided for portrait and landscape mode. For example, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/quibi-is-either-a-clever-gimmick-or-the-future-of-enter-1840876439"&gt;in the short film &lt;em&gt;Nest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, holding the phone in landscape mode shows you the point of view of the main character, while holding it in portrait mode shows you the point of view of the Nest security cameras in the home the character is in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKtm3b"&gt;Presumably, Roku will just be providing one stream: the landscape one. In some cases, that might actually affect how the story is presented or could even remove crucial context from a scene meant to be viewed in portrait mode on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Rc0Ws"&gt;All of the new Roku Originals will air on The Roku Channel, alongside old episodes of &lt;em&gt;This Old House&lt;/em&gt; and over 40,000 free movies and TV shows Roku has paid to license. Besides being playable on Roku devices, you’ll be able to tune into via your browser, iOS, Android, Amazon Fire TV, and some Samsung smart TVs.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395533/roku-originals-quibi-content-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395533/roku-originals-quibi-content-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:39:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:39:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Trans streamers are creating the visibility Twitch won’t give them</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6R_HBgKjuQ8FMqXlDW0Q6uo9zKg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162947/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DKRJ7O"&gt;“Identity shapes what we want to share and what we want to broadcast, [so] it is part of our content,” says Yana Calou, PR director of Trans Lifeline. The nonprofit operates a peer support and crisis hotline and offers microgrants to trans and nonbinary recipients. More recently, it launched &lt;a href="https://peer2peer.live/"&gt;a streaming discovery tool called Peer2Peer&lt;/a&gt; that functions as a searchable directory. Broadcasters can tag themselves in categories like “trans,” “Black,” or “lesbian,” and viewers can search for the tags they want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y1NSCJ"&gt;With Twitch reluctant to allow identity-based tagging, marginalized viewers’ ability to find streamers and associated communities of people like them has been limited. But when a group of streamers approached Trans Lifeline about hosting the website they had created to facilitate these connections, Calou says they thought it was “a wonderful idea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y620uw"&gt;“Having [an identity-based] tagging system that users consent to provides both streamers and viewers with the ability to have an experience that brings them comfort and connection and joy,” says Calou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxNePE"&gt;Project lead and creative director Steph Loehr saw the demand for this kind of service across years of Twitch streaming herself. “Identity-based tagging is invaluable,” she says. “Streamers of vulnerable minority communities are doing literal lifesaving work on Twitch every day by providing safe communities for others like them.” Front-end developer Lucia Everblack has similar experience. “It really is life changing and potentially even life saving because we’re giving people a direct route to talk to those people who might be able to share a point of view with them,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="A8CkAE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s a failure of content moderation.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PLCBwn"&gt;Peer2Peer targets gaps in Twitch’s own tagging system. The streaming company removed the ability to create custom communities, which included identity-based tags, in 2018, and streamers, including Loehr, have continually asked for them to be reinstated, particularly &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/8/25/21176485/twitch-trans-streamers-discoverability-tags"&gt;the ability to self-identify as trans&lt;/a&gt;. Though streamers can tag themselves broadly as LGBTQIA+, trans streamers found that this left them with reduced visibility overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dY5zis"&gt;Harassment for marginalized groups has long been an issue on Twitch, but it’s a problem that can be mitigated in part through visibility and community. “What we had been hearing from Twitch is that they removed the trans tag and other tags because of harassment, but what we actually know as experts in peer support is that when you have the ability to find and connect with community, you actually have much more resilience and support in dealing with harassment,” says Calou. “Trans streamers are saying ‘we’re getting harassed anyway’… It’s a failure of content moderation and the ability to enforce their anti-harassment policies on their part.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TlO0tc"&gt;Peer2Peer helps to provide that community in several ways. Firstly, it’s worldwide, where Trans Lifeline’s hotline is located in the US and Canada. It doesn’t require picking up the phone, which may be uncomfortable for some. And of course, it’s all virtual in a time of a pandemic. “You can’t go to a gay bar or a queer bar right now, right?” points out Everblack. “Streaming has become this really important space where people could connect…and I think as we’ve launched Peer2Peer we’ve really seen this huge increase in people being able to find one another.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w21m5M"&gt;“For us on the hotline so many of our callers report that this is the first time that they’ve ever spoken to another trans person,” says Calou. “And so I think…as a viewer being able to find other trans people on Twitch to be able to watch and connect with as you’re questioning or coming out, having those kinds of contact can mean that that’s maybe the first time that people are really interacting with another trans person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fLVGs7"&gt;However, Peer2Peer isn’t only for trans users. It also has tags relating to racial identity, disability, religion, and so on. Advisory board member Irene Nieves has been central in keeping the site as inclusive as possible. “A large issue that a lot of people have, especially as people of color or as Black people on Twitch, is that it’s near impossible to find other people unless you already have a pre-existing community,” she says. “So a large part of the work that I do is specifically centered around making sure that we have as many voices being amplified as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="k5hmxv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s near impossible to find other people unless you already have a pre-existing community.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W94yyh"&gt;“With Twitch specifically, one of the issues that I personally have and that we’re trying to divest away from with P2P is only highlighting people during events. [For example], only uplifting Black voices during Black History Month,” Nieves adds. “So when we do our outreach specifically at P2P we’re just trying to organically as possible make sure as many people are being seen and represented as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYoZyz"&gt;Everblack has also been focused on keeping the site accessible. “I’ll use a screenreader to read the content out and make sure that it makes sense and that there isn’t information that someone using a screen reader can’t reach,” she says as an example. Calou also emphasizes the consent that’s baked into the platform. Streamers can opt in and out of tags at will and unlist themselves entirely if they choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Chi1Bb"&gt;So far, the platform has spread almost entirely through word of mouth to almost 1,500 streamers. “I’m gonna cry,” Nieves laughs when I ask her about the reception. “We spent a year on this project…and the response has been mindblowing. So many amazing people saying ‘I feel seen, I feel heard.’” Everblack was surprised to see so many people tweeting out screenshots of their profiles. “[Streamers get] a thrill out of seeing their name and their channel and the tags that they assigned. It’s really rewarding to see that,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mQLtsA"&gt;“There hasn’t been any negative feedback,” adds Nieves. “There’s always a concern that there’s going to be discriminatory hate or there’s going to be people who don’t necessarily see the value… but it’s just been amazing.” Calou says that it’s gotten some Trans Lifeline employees into watching Twitch who hadn’t known much about streaming before. “People were really surprised and felt like this is this incredible place to discover and find interesting people who share lived experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EyQqND"&gt;As the site keeps growing, it’s also becoming more robust. Everblack says that since the team uses the site themselves, they’ve got “a bunch of ideas for new features.” Users have also been suggesting updates, including new tags, via its feedback system. “It’s so cool because it’s ever evolving,” says Nieves. “It’s this rolling stone where it started from a great place because [we wanted] to have all of the tags be as inclusive as possible and as far reaching as possible, but it’s only getting better because people are able to contribute to those tags themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9QBCY"&gt;She gives examples such as the “aromantic” tag, which now has a couple dozen streamers listed underneath it. “When we added it, people went on social media and said ‘I feel seen. I told [P2P] that I wanted to have it represented and… I go back and it got accepted and I can use that.’ What’s so cool is that no tag doesn’t fulfill a purpose. They’re there so that people can feel represented in their identity,” Nieves says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="037OcY"&gt;All of the team members I spoke to also mentioned that, as Peer2Peer grows, they hope it might have a wider influence, including on Twitch itself. “We’re hoping that Twitch can use our website as a reference for doing better themselves, and owning up to their moral responsibility to empower, protect, and foster marginalized streamers on their platform,” says Loehr. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5kFNVO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Hopefully it can be an example to the company”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uohn6D"&gt;Nieves says she hopes the industry will see why the service Peer2Peer provides is important and act accordingly. “We want Twitch to see this and be like ‘we should be doing this. Look how many people are getting involved,’” she says. Everblack, meanwhile, notes that she would be happy for the site to continue as is, but if Twitch &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; take notice, it could go one of two ways. “Maybe they hire us... and we build this out on their site for them, or at least act as consultants for that. Or Twitch just steals the idea and one day we wake up and everything we did and all of our hard work is nullified by Twitch doing it. I’m fine either way really.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="54dmws"&gt;“Hopefully it can be an example to the company that this is actually working well for people,” adds Calou. “That this is what we want, and [that they could be] listening to communities about what they want instead of saying what’s ‘actually’ best for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xErYe6"&gt;“In the meantime, it feels really wonderful to be able to build something like this,” they say. “I think particularly what this points to is that if Twitch isn’t going to do this then trans people are figuring out other ways and coming together. If we’re not going to have a seat at the table we’re just going to build our own table.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22392534/peer-2-peer-twitch-streaming-tool-trans-streamers-lgbtq"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22392534/peer-2-peer-twitch-streaming-tool-trans-streamers-lgbtq</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Castello</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:07:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:07:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro are available refurbished for 45 percent off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xq1PmTsFLqaQPVE1ypbttjwo35w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162616/bfarsace_210114_4372_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OpjJdW"&gt;At Best Buy, you can get a refurbished set of the Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro truly wireless earbuds &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738397414024596357#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $110 today in the silver colorway&lt;/a&gt;. This model released just a few months ago alongside the Samsung Galaxy S21, and at most retailers they still sell for their original $200 price. The lowest price we’ve seen recently for a new set is $165, and that’s bound to happen again at some point. But if you’re all about saving money, this refurbished deal can’t be beat. The Galaxy Buds Pro provide the “best sound quality yet for Samsung earbuds,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to audio expert and &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;reviewer Chris Welch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBLnKJ"&gt;These come with a charging case, a USB cable, and three pairs of ear tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jFuQO6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="QnXS2i"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_FJFnm9PCfY?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Zrbuj"&gt;Oculus is set to announce some VR games later today, April 21st, and we expect it to share more on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22386496/resident-evil-4-vr-remake-oculus-quest-2-announced" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that exciting VR port of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. To celebrate the big day, Oculus is reducing the cost of several hit games for Quest headsets. In the mix are some solid games that I can personally recommend, like &lt;em&gt;In Death: Unchained&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;I Expect You To Die&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Room VR: A Dark Matter&lt;/em&gt;. Check out the sale here. If you’re new to VR and don’t mind throwing down $100 for a mix of some classic experiences bundled together, I’ll provide that link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="whFwtj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10457990"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="M9Uei6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="CQEGom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/21/22395450/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-earbuds-refurbished-vr-game-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/21/22395450/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-earbuds-refurbished-vr-game-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Inside the glass fibers connecting our wireless world</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GgBgBWKLbyVdgbxP8ahQaIQJTfY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162418/adiaconis_untitled_20210419_0197_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TSzjiy"&gt;All modern means of communication rely on glass, from the Gorilla Glass on our phones to the infotainment screens in our cars. Most of the time, the glass is right in front of us, but when it comes to the internet — whether it’s 5G, Starlink satellites, or Wi-Fi — it’s easy to miss the 750,000 miles of fiber optic cables currently running under our oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJzJpZ"&gt;These tiny strands of glass carry our photos, emails, and video chats from our phones to data centers to friends and family all across the world. It’s through these hair-thin strands of fiber that we are able to instantly communicate to almost anyone, anywhere, and it all relies on a 5,000-year-old technology: glass.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cwmHS6Zy5oFKfFikMOTfBb1iQ6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459251/adiaconis_untitled_20210419_0197_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alix Diaconis / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A telecommunications-grade strand of single-core, optical fiber.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MlYr8T"&gt;Very little has changed in the way we use glass throughout its long history. It has always been a transparent and durable material through which light passes. And since light can travel quickly and at high frequencies while carrying loads of encoded information, a cable made of near-perfect glass is a secure medium to send all of our communications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDegkJ"&gt;When I began researching materials that were shaping our future, Gorilla Glass was the obvious choice. But my path quickly turned to fiber and the urgent need to not only improve data transmission speeds but also provide all of humanity with internet access. Tune into our video to learn more about how these tiny strands of glass create the backbone for present and future of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22393952/glass-fiber-internet-cable-wifi-speed-5g-explainer-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22393952/glass-fiber-internet-cable-wifi-speed-5g-explainer-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Becca Farsace</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s AirTags don’t have a built-in keychain loop, and we have some thoughts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fsh9JcBTVaabDsfJuV2nAvrMoWk=/77x0:904x551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162411/airtagaccessories.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CwaDy4"&gt;Apple’s new AirTag trackers are finally here after years of rumors. The $29 trackers work with Apple’s Find My network, utilizing both Bluetooth and UWB technology to help owners track anything from their keys to their bags. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzvFVZ"&gt;But the design of the new trackers is somewhat controversial: unlike most Bluetooth trackers, Apple’s iteration doesn’t include a built-in key ring loop. The subsequent debate has shattered the tranquility of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s newsroom over whether Apple’s somewhat Spartan design is brilliant or bogus. Well, at least between two of the most genteel &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers, Jon Porter and Chaim Gartenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/492kammhY61DFUGcSC-yVmeGOFs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458151/keychain.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist’s rendering of an AirTag design featuring a keychain hole punch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qh75iy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Porter, reporter&lt;/strong&gt;: Debate me, coward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KMiTJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim Gartenberg, news editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Gladly! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvGf9T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Let’s start with a point that we’ll definitely both agree on: it’s a relief to see the AirTags’ battery is user-replaceable. It sounds like such a basic point, but considering Apple’s track record with its AirPods, Magic Mouse, iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, MacBook line, Magic Keyboard — wait does anything else Apple makes have replaceable batteries? — it wasn’t a guarantee. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20901686/tile-tracker-mate-pro-slim-sticker-release-date-news-features"&gt;Tile’s keychain-focused Mate and Pro trackers&lt;/a&gt; have removable batteries, but its Sticker (which has a very similar form factor to the AirTag) doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HWw9NV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Brilliant or bogus?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DOebJ1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I will grant you that easily accessible, user-replaceable batteries are always a good thing. And on a whole, the overall aesthetics of the AirTags are nice, with a two-tone shiny white plastic / chrome back that’s vaguely reminiscent of the old iPods to me. But the overly sleek Apple design highlights the biggest issue I have here: there’s no built-in loop or hole to attach a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P8Ur5Y"&gt;The AirTag is a product that’s designed to track your keys, and yet it offers no way to actually attach itself to those keys out of the box, something that’s practically table stakes from Tile, Chipolo, and virtually every other Bluetooth tracker from the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TKNaTC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: I hear you, but I think Apple’s approach is better. It means it can sell just one version of the AirTag to track whatever item you want, rather than selling different devices whether you want to track your keys, or your bike, or your jacket. Just buy an AirTag and buy whatever accessory you need to attach it. And for what it’s worth, I really like the design of the little holder accessory they’re selling to attach the AirTag to a set of keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xhwlMC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: That little &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMHJ23ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-leather-key-ring%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;keychain accessory costs $35&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;em&gt;more than an entire AirTag&lt;/em&gt;. Even Apple’s cheapest AirTag case, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMK0W3ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-loop%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the $30 plastic loop&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t look like it’ll even be useful for attaching to keys. This is just Apple’s typical accessory tax, forced onto customers because of an intentional choice of aesthetic form over useful function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNKKxo"&gt;And don’t get me started on the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMX862AM%2FA%2Fairtag-herm%25C3%25A8s-bag-charm%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hermès accessories&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VOt7rznNzumaSTrrkX8AFrjBc6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458169/Screen_Shot_2021_04_20_at_5.57.30_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nmRXJl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Okay fine, I’m not going to argue that the $349 Hermès key ring isn’t incredibly stupid, and it would be nice if the leather key ring actually included an AirTag at that price. The setup is too expensive, period, and hopefully third-party accessory manufacturers will step in to fill the demand for cheap keychain holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="girWDS"&gt;But more importantly, I think separating the tech bit from the holder bit makes sense for an accessory that’s going to have to withstand so much abuse on a daily basis. Keys can be sharp, and they beat up anything that shares a pocket with them, so I’d prefer it if that thing that gets beaten up is a holder rather than the core piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t773Ho"&gt;Look at a Tile key fob tracker that’s been used for a couple of years, and it looks grimy as hell. I wouldn’t be surprised if some people end up replacing the whole device when the battery runs out, just so they can get a shiny new tracker. But when your AirTag keychain inevitably starts looking worse for wear, you just replace the holder rather than the tracker itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Co3luD8e5pkvGFCzcC1RfxhbWE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22457308/yJBAy1w.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hywvlC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: These are all valid points, but you’re ignoring the fact that &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Faccessories%2Fall%2Fairtag&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;these accessories and protective cases&lt;/a&gt; could all exist in &lt;em&gt;addition&lt;/em&gt; to including a cutout to directly attach a key ring. There’s already a similar cottage industry of accessories for Tile’s trackers for those who want them, and with the marketing power of Apple behind it, there’s no reason to think that AirTags wouldn’t have eclipsed that level of interest from accessory makers, even if it did have a cutout for a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NM8Yi5"&gt;It’s not that cases are bad — Apple’s leather option does look great and is almost definitely a more robust option than my hypothetical cutout. But it’d be nice to give customers the choice, instead of just forcing them into an option that requires spending more money right from the start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D24Qfh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are all the AirTag accessories we know about ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394331/apple-airtag-release-launch-accessory-roundup-nomad-belkin"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PwfbZF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: At a certain point, though, you’re running up against physical limitations, and Apple has to pick its battles. I’m already seeing some of our esteemed colleagues in Slack complaining about how thick these trackers are, which I’d wager is because Apple prioritized building in a removable battery. Adding a loop with enough space for a key chain to go through adds yet more bulk. You have to draw the line somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lSBjAD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: Fair enough. So, Jon, are you buying an AirTag tracker? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naEYZZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Honestly, I’m going to wait to see how the third-party accessories work out. If I can get a half-decent leather keychain holder for the equivalent of $20 or so, then I think it makes a lot of sense spending $50 all-in with the tracker itself. Yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pfzgre"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I might buy one to stick in my luggage at some point, but I generally don’t lose my keys enough to need to invest in a tracker for them (famous last words, potentially). Especially not at the $65 price tag that Apple is asking for a full key ring setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYatkG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LMETVs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:57:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:57:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>EU outlines wide-ranging AI regulation, but leaves the door open for police surveillance</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8d6PbeA0DAaP0h_LXbRsK4PHHMY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162373/acastro_181017_1777_brain_ai_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i5YqCS"&gt;The European Union has &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/proposal-regulation-european-approach-artificial-intelligence"&gt;published a new framework&lt;/a&gt; to regulate the use of artificial intelligence across the bloc’s 27 member states. The proposal, which will take years to implement into law and will be subject to many tweaks and amendments during this time, nevertheless constitutes the most ambitious AI regulations seen globally to date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VyCCa1"&gt;The regulations cover a wide range of applications, from software in self-driving cars to algorithms used to vet job candidates, and arrive at a time when countries around the world are struggling with the ethical ramifications of artificial intelligence. Similar to the EU’s data privacy law, GDPR, the regulation gives the bloc the ability to fine companies that infringe its rules up to 6 percent of their global revenues, though such punishments are extremely rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FKmwgt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s our first ever legal framework on artificial intelligence.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4TqWkn"&gt;“It is a landmark proposal of this Commission. It’s our first ever legal framework on artificial intelligence,” said European Commissioner Margrethe Vestager during a press conference. “Today we aim to make Europe world-class in the development of secure, trustworthy, and human-centered artificial intelligence. And, of course, the use of it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i481DH"&gt;Civil rights groups are wary about some aspects of the proposal. One of the most important components is a ban on four specific AI use cases throughout the EU. These bans are intended to protect citizens from applications that infringe on their rights, but critics say some prohibitions are too vaguely worded to actually stop harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SA1Pka"&gt;One such prohibition is a ban on the use of real-time “remote biometric identification systems in publicly accessible spaces for the purpose of law enforcement,” which would include facial recognition. The regulation adds, though, that there are numerous exceptions to this prohibition, including letting police use such systems to find the “perpetrator or suspect” of any criminal act that carries a minimum three-year sentence. Using technology like facial recognition in these cases would need to be approved by judiciaries or similar bodies, but this would still give law enforcement an extremely broad scope to deploy AI surveillance as and when they want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Video surveillance of a premises" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2gUSVGrwLT3kxTqKE07XMys9A3g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459274/1232158944.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Alexandra Schuler / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The proposal leaves significant room for law enforcement use of facial recognition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JJsUwx"&gt;“There are just too many exceptions and they are quite arbitrary,” Alexandra Geese, a German Green MEP, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;regarding the regulation. “I don’t see the point of saying ‘we don’t want biometric recognition’ and then granting continuous exceptions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXeuRg"&gt;Sarah Chander, a senior policy advisor for digital rights group EDRi, agreed and said the proposal only offered “a veneer of fundamental rights protection.” Chander told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that banning mass biometric surveillance outright was “the only way to safeguard democracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="dFOkXg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There are just too many exceptions and they are quite arbitrary.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LOEtb1"&gt;An earlier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383301/eu-ai-regulation-draft-leak-surveillance-social-credit"&gt;leaked version of the proposal&lt;/a&gt; did feature a much stricter ban on AI for mass surveillance, but this was evidently watered down. As Geese told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;: “It looks like the Commission said, ‘Look we want to ban this thing,’ and then the safety authorities of the member states, the ministers of the interior, stepped in and said ‘No way.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AS2X2A"&gt;The fact that the ban mentions only “real-time” biometric identification also constitutes a substantial loophole. It seems to suggest that using facial recognition software after any target images have been captured is allowed. That would clear the way for European police to use services like the controversial Clearview AI, which has seen &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/clearview-ai-fbi-ice-global-law-enforcement"&gt;rapid uptake in the US&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UId00z"&gt;Other prohibited applications of AI include the use of the technology to create social credit scores, to cause physical or physiological harm to people, and to manipulate people’s behavior using subliminal cues. “We prohibit them altogether because we simply consider them to be unacceptable,” said Vestager of these use cases during the press conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pRlXXc"&gt;All other AI applications are sorted into three groups of stratified risk. The bottom category includes common, low-risk applications like spam filters, for which regulation will likely not change at all. Above those are “limited-risk” uses cases like chatbot used to buy tickets or find out information, which will require a little more oversight. And above those are high-risk uses of AI, which are “the main focus of the framework,” as Vestager said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pyeoV2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;AI systems like chatbots would be required to identify themselves to users&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B5cxsY"&gt;The high-risk applications are those which affect material aspects of people’s lives, like algorithms used to assess someone’s credit score or whether they can get a loan, as well as AI tools that control critical machinery like autonomous vehicles and medical devices. Their deployment and development will be overseen by various regulatory mechanisms — in some cases, based on existing national regulators like those devoted to digital privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="deYAdd"&gt;“Those AI systems will be subject to a set of five strict obligations because they will potentially have a huge impact on our lives,” said Vestager at the conference. These requirements include the mandatory use of “high-quality” training data to avoid bias, the implementation of “human oversight” into each system, and the creation of detailed documentation that explains how the software works to both regulators and users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74PLsx"&gt;Another notable aspect is compulsory transparency obligations for AI systems that interact with humans, like chatbots, and for AI-generated content, like deepfakes. “The aim is to make it crystal clear that as users we are interacting with a machine,” said Vestager.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Robot helps with control - “Please wear a mask”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2glOF9e6VvIcBIv5Y1EM5epTCdg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459269/1229663756.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Marcel Kusch / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI systems would have to identify themselves as such to users. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="anzuYu"&gt;In addition to these new regulations, all AI systems classified as high-risk will also have to be indexed in a new EU-wide database. Daniel Leufer, a Europe policy analyst at Access Now, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that this was an unexpected and welcome addition to the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXZ2aQ"&gt;“It’s a really good measure, because one of the issues we have is just not knowing when a system is in use,” said Leufer. “For example, with ClearView AI we rely on investigative journalism and leaks to find out if anyone’s using it.” A database would provide “basic transparency about what systems are in use... enabling us to do our job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZF1th"&gt;Digital rights groups said there were additional problems beyond the loopholes involving biometric identification. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22381370/automatic-gender-recognition-sexual-orientation-facial-ai-analysis-ban-campaign"&gt;hoped-for ban&lt;/a&gt; on the use of AI to automatically identify gender and sexual orientation was absent, for example, while algorithms used for predictive policing, which are frequently found to be affected by &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/07/17/1005396/predictive-policing-algorithms-racist-dismantled-machine-learning-bias-criminal-justice"&gt;racial bias&lt;/a&gt;, will not have strong oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2n5AF"&gt;“These are supposedly high risk [AI applications], but in terms of enforcement are self-assessment,” says Chander. “This allows companies who profit from the development of these systems to decide whether or not they conform with the law. It’s astounding.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lpQPSu"&gt;Despite such objections, many will see the EU as following through on a promise to create a “third way” between the US and China on AI policy. As Vestager noted at the press conference, the bloc wishes to distinguish itself with fair and ethical applications of AI, and this proposal is still the biggest step toward regulation in line with those values. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wAjDy"&gt;“I’m a little bit suspicious,” Geese said, “but I’m very happy that the EU is trying to be a global standard setter.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393785/eu-ai-regulation-proposal-social-credit-ban-biometric-surveillance-exceptions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393785/eu-ai-regulation-proposal-social-credit-ban-biometric-surveillance-exceptions</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:17:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:17:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the M1-powered iPad Pro compares to other iPad models</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kk2fuz1qoN65Gtr9IWma5nu9h8U=/3x0:977x649/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162095/ipad_pro_2021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPad Pro 2021&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oYWndI"&gt;Apple has announced the next generation of its iPad Pro line. But most of the biggest changes for Apple’s flagship tablet are largely on the inside. The latest iPad Pros feature a new eight-core M1 processor; the same chip featured in the most recent model refreshes for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;newly announced iMac&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rIw2yY"&gt;Like last year, the iPad Pro comes in two sizes: 11 inches and 12.9 inches. The 12.9-inch model this year also includes a new Mini-LED screen, which Apple is branding as a “Liquid Retina XDR” display. The iPad Pro 2021 refreshes also include support for Thunderbolt 3 and USB 4, in addition to 5G connectivity. Both iPad Pros also feature a new 12-megapixel ultrawide camera that can automatically track you during video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7V3r5T"&gt;Of course, specs don’t always tell how much has changed between model refreshes. And it can be easy to presume, at first glance, that not much has changed — especially if you own a 2020 iPad Pro. If you want to see how both iPad Pro models with the M1 chip compare to the other three iPads Apple currently sells, along with the 2020 Pro models, take a look at the chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xwiUSk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10457124"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="NDuhGp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder the new iPad Pro with the M1 processor","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22394384/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-comparison"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22394384/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-comparison</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cadillac’s Lyriq EV will start at $59,990</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E98bZgyRJK8qXhwvbOyZ6uzy4ZQ=/0x148:1780x1335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161957/MY23LYRIQ_HERO_FRONT_3_4_BLACK_ROOF_FINAL.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Cadillac&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LgBpMP"&gt;Cadillac has announced that its first electric car, the Lyriq, will start at $59,990 before tax, license, and dealer fees. The luxury brand of General Motors also said the electric SUV will be available for reservations starting in September ahead of the start of production in the first quarter of 2022. The Lyriq SUV will officially go on sale shortly after that in the first half of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PaeoGK"&gt;The Lyriq got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357717/cadillac-lyriq-gm-ev-suv-touchscreen-size-specs-release-date"&gt;a proper debut last August&lt;/a&gt;, but that was technically still just a show car. The photos Cadillac showed off Wednesday as it announced pricing are of the final production version. You’d be forgiven if you didn’t notice the difference; even Cadillac says that there have only been minor changes since then, like the addition of an extra seat and cupholder, smaller wheels, and a slight difference in the door design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BP3MXi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Only small changes from the version that debuted last year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j6a4nC"&gt;Cadillac also released a more complete spec sheet, though there aren’t any big changes here either. The Lyriq is slated to get “more than” 300 miles of range out of a 12-module, 100kWh version of GM’s new flexible Ultium EV battery pack. The SUV will be powered, for now at least, by just one electric motor capable of generating 255kW of power (around 340 horsepower). And owners will be able to charge it quickly when they drain the pack. The Lyriq can charge at up to 190kW at public fast charging stations or up to 19.2kW at home (with the right equipment), which adds around 52 miles of range per hour. Oh, and the Lyriq weighs an astonishing 5,610 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nSygls"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10457025"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qA7qQa"&gt;The Lyriq is not only Cadillac’s first EV, but it’s going to be a showcase for a lot of the automaker’s other leading technologies. It will, of course, have Super Cruise, which is the hands-free driver assistance system that started at Cadillac but is now spreading to other GM vehicles. The Lyriq also features a massive 33-inch display that stretches from the left of the driver all the way to the middle of the dashboard. There’s an active noise cancellation system to dampen road noise, LED headlamps, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2D77a"&gt;The $59,990 starting price isn’t cheap, but Cadillac is clearly trying to make the Lyriq as enticing to EV-wary buyers as possible. The real question will be how quickly that price tag escalates start picking trim levels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxPh5N"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394483/cadillac-lyriq-electric-suv-price-specs-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394483/cadillac-lyriq-electric-suv-price-specs-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T08:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T08:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Tamagotchi Pix has a built-in camera for taking pictures with your pet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p1rouh0FKIFPB_WhL1S6AqeKPq0=/59x0:1942x1255/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161878/Tamagotchi_Pix.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;image: Bandai&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PPmRF3"&gt;Today, Bandai is announcing the Tamagotchi Pix: a combination of its classic Tamagotchi pet-rearing toy line with a new built-in camera for taking pictures with your digital pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AR12k8"&gt;The Pix is shaped like a hatching egg, with the top part of the “broken shell” working as a shutter button. Using the camera, you can insert yourself (and friends) into photos with your Tamagotchi, with appropriately cute photo frames. We’ve reached out to Bandai for more information about the camera quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ppWDt"&gt;Photos taken with the Pix are stored locally, and any photos you take will appear in a feed that documents your time with your pet. Bandai frames this as a sort of on-device social media, but because the Pix can’t connect to Wi-Fi and sharing photos is limited, it’s not actually social. Presale for the Tamagotchi Pix starts today for $59.99.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-2h6kqUEZQu9px6dEWAEhWPMEk8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22454749/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_9.36.03_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bandai&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix’s top shell works as a shutter button when you’re taking photos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g2u8i5"&gt;Past Tamagotchi, like &lt;a href="https://tamagotchi.fandom.com/wiki/Tamagotchi_On"&gt;the Tamagotchi On&lt;/a&gt;, have used Bluetooth to connect to other devices, but the Pix is taking a less high-tech approach. If you want to share images with other Pix-carrying friends, they can take a picture of a “Tama Code.” Bandai says these codes contain the entirety of what you are sharing, so you can basically exchange pictures via QR codes. Bandai also plans to award Tama Codes for in-game items if you play games on tamagotchi.com starting in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUGOGq"&gt;Besides the camera features, Tamagotchi Pix also has new touch-based buttons in place of the usual physical ones, and several new gameplay mechanics. Have you ever wanted to influence your Tamagotchi’s future employment status off-world? Apparently, how you raise your Tamagotchi and decorate its room will now affect its future profession and what other eggs you can raise after your first Tamagotchi grows up. Tamagotchi can also engage in new activities like painting, cooking, and ordering food for delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6VRTE"&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix captures a little bit of the feeling of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;’s augmented reality camera. It’s not as robust — you’re just pasting your pet on a photo rather than finding them moving out in the world — but some of that AR magic is there. Obsessively documenting your pet’s life in photos might re-create some of that parent-child bond, but I think what’s more powerful is the basic feeling the Pix’s little AR photos could conjure: that you exist in the same space as your Tamagotchi and that, in some way, it’s real — even if it’s confined to a plastic egg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8I9Kb"&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix comes in four different colored “shells”: “floral” (pink), “sky” (purple), “ocean” (blue), and “nature” (green). Pink and purple are available for presale today, and blue and green are “coming soon,” according to Bandai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePTQXh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29nSSN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22386339/tamagotchi-pix-pet-egg-camera-toy-ar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22386339/tamagotchi-pix-pet-egg-camera-toy-ar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
