<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-29T18:03:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T18:03:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T18:03:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok settles lawsuit with actress over its original text-to-speech voice</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mgFXXRKe3Q3Dt39FOJEFJUgXnVo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69928467/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AfRJ4J"&gt;TikTok has agreed to settle a lawsuit with Bev Standing, the voice actress who said she was behind the app’s original text-to-speech voice. Standing sued TikTok in May, saying that the app was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22435058/tiktok-voice-sues-unauthorized-usage-text-to-speech"&gt;using her voice without permission&lt;/a&gt;. A robotic version of what sounded like Standing’s voice had been in the app for months, speaking over what felt like every other video at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hEZPai"&gt;Details of the settlement were not disclosed. TikTok and a lawyer for Standing were not immediately available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0nGsCZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Standing said her voice was meant to be used for Chinese translations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="05ik8b"&gt;It sounds as though some strange mixup led to Standing’s voice being used by TikTok. Standing said that she made recordings for a text-to-speech feature “several years ago” but that they were meant to be used for translations of Chinese texts. No one else was supposed to use them. But somehow, her voice seems to have made its way to TikTok, where it became a near-ubiquitous presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOIZSU"&gt;“No matter what I do, I believe this is going to affect my business,” Standing &lt;a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/2021/05/09/voice-tiktok-sues-company-emotional-distress/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H2Dl1x"&gt;TikTok never confirmed that it used Standing’s voice, but the feature sure sounded like her. About two weeks after the lawsuit was filed, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452815/tiktok-voice-change-text-to-speech-lawsuit"&gt;TikTok’s text-to-speech voice changed&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of Standing’s odd monotone recording, it changed to a voice that’s relentlessly upbeat. One assumes TikTok checked the copyright on it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701167/bev-standing-tiktok-lawsuit-settles-text-to-speech-voice"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701167/bev-standing-tiktok-lawsuit-settles-text-to-speech-voice</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T17:39:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T17:39:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cadillac axes Escalade’s hands-free driving feature due to chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MIsXUGo-B97pTWLVIzVqO1DLbIw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69928293/cadillac_2021_escalade_0433.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XrhZig"&gt;The 2022 Escalade is heading into production, but it’ll be missing a key feature when the first customers pick up their new ride: the hands-free driving mode known as Super Cruise. It’s the latest feature to get the axe as a result of the global semiconductor shortage, which has been an especially big drain on the auto industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ImJ4Yc"&gt;The shortage is also forcing Cadillac to hold off on adding Super Cruise to the CT4 and CT5 sedans, &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/2022-cadillac-escalade-super-cruise-hands-free-chip-shortage/?UniqueID=A3F2E32E-2148-11EC-8A3C-BD1F16F31EAE&amp;amp;PostType=link&amp;amp;TheTime=2021-09-29T17%3A14%3A01&amp;amp;ServiceType=twitter&amp;amp;ftag=COS-05-10aaa0b"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Roadshow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; With the Bolt currently not on sale due to the massive battery recall, that means parent company General Motors’ most advanced technological feature is currently not available on any new car. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwZRzI"&gt;“[W]e’re confident in our team’s ability to find creative solutions to mitigate the supply chain situation and resume offering the feature for our customers as soon as possible,” Cadillac told &lt;em&gt;Roadshow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSLwZN"&gt;Super Cruise debuted on the CT6 (which has since been discontinued). It uses a variety of sensors, software, and eye-tracking to allow drivers to take their hands off the wheel on pre-mapped roads — as long as they keep watching where the vehicle is going. Cadillac &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/6/17433810/cadillac-super-cruise-expands-2020-gm"&gt;announced in 2018&lt;/a&gt; that it would expand the feature to all cars and SUVs in its lineup and that Super Cruise would come to other GM models as well. Other automakers are working on similar features, like Ford, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383460/ford-bluecruise-hands-free-adas-f150-mustang-mache"&gt;calls its own system BlueCruise&lt;/a&gt;. (GM is currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/24/22591805/gm-cruise-lawsuit-trademark-infringement-hands-free-driving-autonomous"&gt;suing Ford over the name&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8T3D38"&gt;Automakers have had to make a number of hard choices because of the chip shortage. In some cases, they can’t get the ones they need, and in others, they have to prioritize where to use the chips they &lt;em&gt;can &lt;/em&gt;get. GM has so far focused more on cutting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575836/gm-wireless-charging-cadillac-chevy-tahoe-chip-shortage"&gt;specific features from certain models&lt;/a&gt; where possible, like wireless charging, HD radio, auto stop-start, and, in some trucks, a fuel economy module. But it’s also had to briefly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654357/gm-factory-shutdown-chip-shortage-truck-suv"&gt;stop production at various plants altogether&lt;/a&gt;, like pretty much all of its peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFsuJg"&gt;Losing Super Cruise on the Escalade is particularly notable, though, because GM has spent the last few years positioning Cadillac as the brand that’s most representative of the automaker’s future. Cadillac is where GM first started rolling out Super Cruise and is also going to sell one of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357717/cadillac-lyriq-gm-ev-suv-touchscreen-size-specs-release-date"&gt;the first electric vehicles built on the parent company’s new electric vehicle platform&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hG512g"&gt;The 2022 Escalade was supposed to be a flagship in this push. GM and Cadillac adorned it with a massive touchscreen and fitted it with Super Cruise. Now, though, that feature is in limbo for the luxury SUV, and with no end to the chip shortage in sight, it could be a while before buyers get the option back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701086/cadillac-super-cruise-2022-escalade-semiconductor-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701086/cadillac-super-cruise-2022-escalade-semiconductor-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T17:09:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T17:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ring’s security drone could be flying in your home soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DpiMO_sOqal1SlPAyd7QIDd4h2c=/0x0:6075x4050/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69920820/49339_12021hesby_09e_lifestyle_product_hovering_0308_R3_RGB_16x9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring’s Always Home Cam security drone is ready for takeoff.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Ring&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ngbeZJ"&gt;First announced at last year’s Amazon hardware event, the Ring Always Home Cam is now ready for take-off. Starting today, September 28th, you can request an invitation to be a crash-test dummy for Ring’s newest innovation. The Always Home Cam is a Ring camera attached to a drone that can fly predetermined paths in your home when triggered via a Ring Alarm sensor or from the Ring app. The camera costs $249.99; if you live in the US, you can apply for &lt;a href="https://ring.com/always-home-cam-flying-camera"&gt;an invitation to buy it&lt;/a&gt; today, and the devices will ship later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6BjxoL"&gt;Designed to solve the problem of wanting to be able to see inside your home when you’re not there but not wanting to have dozens of cameras watching you when you are, the Always Home Cam only records when it’s in flight. When not in use, it sits in its charging dock that blocks its lens. It can fly to specific viewpoints on demand — such as the front door or kitchen stove — and can also tie into a Ring Alarm home security system and buzz over to any action — such as a door or window opening when the alarm is armed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8DUhntZ9ECJy92_tNzCv_df2QjA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882429/49339_11802hesby_01a_lifestyle_product_livingroom_table_0194_R4_RGB_1x1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Always Home Cam sits in a charging base when not in use, where its camera is disabled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1h5aS"&gt;In the year since it announced the product, Ring has been working on refining the ambitious device and essentially making sure it won’t go on a rampage through your home. “It’s not an overstatement to say we’ve made a thousand refinements to it,” Ring founder Jamie Siminoff said in an interview ahead of the announcement. “We learned how to fly.” While they had working prototypes when they announced in 2020, it’s only now ready for regular people’s homes, says Siminoff. But not everyone’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KErIoP"&gt;Ring is rolling out the invite-only program as a sort of post-beta test flight. “I have it in my home, and it does work,” said Siminoff. “But today’s homes are so unique, so we really need to get it into more customers’ homes to make sure everything we are doing is right.” After all, it is an autonomous flying machine in your home. “With any other product, we would have probably just been shipping. With this one, we are going to take our time, make sure it’s right before we go to full, general availability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="QAScwx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 15 is meant to hang on your wall","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Ring video doorbells are finally getting package alerts","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22691923/ring-video-doorbell-package-alerts-amazon-event"},{"title":"Blink’s first doorbell is finally released, four years later","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698612/amazon-blink-video-doorbell-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-panel"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="y3g3I5"&gt;The invite-only program, which is a recent trend with Amazon products, is a way to attract the right type of customer to the product at this stage, says Siminoff. “It’s a customer that’s willing to and wants to work with us,” he said. “They understand what they’re getting into. We use this as a tool to deliver the best products to customers and be transparent with them.” So, does this means if it crashes into your big screen TV, you’re just plumb out of luck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IcaIgImKI5JHNXo3rmIT0EqVE-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882432/20210922_lifestyle_ots_backyard_fcc_rgb.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The home security drone can be controlled through the Ring app, or respond autonomously to events in your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YNtWSn"&gt;In terms of day-to-day use and features, much of what was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21453709/ring-always-home-cam-indoor-drone-security-camera-price-specs-features-amazon"&gt;announced last year&lt;/a&gt; is the same. The Always Home Cam is an indoor-only camera attached to a drone with enclosed propellers. It streams and records to the Ring app, is fully autonomous and can be commanded to fly on-demand to pre-set locations through the app or programmed to take off when Ring Alarm detects a disturbance. Ring says the resolution of the camera has increased to 1400 x 1400 HD, which is a bump up from the 1080p resolution it was when it was first announced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOo7Ui"&gt;The camera only records in-flight, and the drone makes an audible noise, so it’s clear when footage is recording. It has obstacle avoidance technology, but its shrouded propellors should prevent any serious damage if there is a collision (“But you should keep it away from your Van Gogh,” joked Siminoff). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lm9eQL"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Ring Always Home Cam demo video|104113" data-volume-uuid="d5072579f" data-volume-id="104113" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-120" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="chorus"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s9QA7G"&gt;The Always Home Cam is designed for use on a single floor, as it can’t navigate stairs. But Siminoff says multi-floor support is something the company is exploring. It should also only fly when there is no one home. While the drone has been tested with ceiling and tabletop fans, Siminoff said it might have difficulties if a fan is blowing full speed. “But if it feels like it’s not doing the right thing, it’ll just land in a safe area and sit there,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="pw3mpa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It only records in-flight, and the drone makes an audible noise, so it’s clear when footage is recording&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Eez7QZ"&gt;The battery life is short, with flight time limited to around five minutes. “The idea is it’s very like tactical; you don’t need to go see that a door’s ajar for two hours,” said Siminoff. “It’s meant to go out for a few minutes, see what you need to see, and then fly back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ReOboC"&gt;A flying camera in your home does feel like a sci-fi fantasy / horror story come true. But from a practical and privacy standpoint, the concept is a solid one. You only need one camera to see an entire floor of your home, and there’s no danger of it accidentally recording without you knowing about it. Also, it’s way cool. “There’s something about watching this fly through your house on your phone; it feels like something out of Hollywood, but it’s your house,” said Siminoff. “For me, it really was a jaw-dropping experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oHwD4K"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, 5:09PM ET, September 29th 2021: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The resolution of the Always Home Cam is 1400x1400 HD, not 1080p as an earlier version of this article stated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xshEcw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="LlQn8M"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T16:27:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T16:27:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google says a new wired Nest doorbell is coming next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R4fse5Jr1MzFTx9g6Khw_iGlauM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927824/fion_180428_2519_8644.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new version of the excellent Nest Hello video doorbell (pictured) will arrive in 2022.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Florence Ion for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gLODRV"&gt;Google is working on a successor to the excellent Nest Hello doorbell, which it recently rebranded the Nest Doorbell (wired). The new Nest Doorbell will support 24/7 recording, will work with the Google Home app (not the Nest app), and should launch in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DwOVcb"&gt;Rishi Chandra, GM of Google Nest, shared the news in a &lt;a href="https://www.googlenestcommunity.com/t5/Blog/Message-from-our-GM-Updates-for-our-Nest-customers/ba-p/17122"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the Google Nest Community forum today. “We commit to being more transparent with you on where we are taking the camera portfolio,” writes Chandra. “We know that those with wired doorbell connections prefer to have a doorbell that can also support 24/7 continuous video history (via the Nest Aware subscription). We are excited to share that we will be launching a 2nd generation of Nest Doorbell (wired) in 2022.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RRieQe"&gt;There were no further details shared on the new doorbell camera, so we don’t know if it will be smaller than the new, very large Nest Doorbell (battery). Although it’s likely it will be as it won’t have to pack in a hulking great battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PnMk52"&gt;We also don’t know if it will have offline storage and battery backup in case of power outage, a feature on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22609444/google-nest-cam-indoor-floodlight-doorbell-price-specs-news"&gt;Google’s newest battery-powered Nest cameras and doorbells&lt;/a&gt;. The current Nest Doorbell (wired) also has a few features the Nest Doorbell (battery) doesn’t, including Alexa and SmartThings integration, a wider field of view, a bigger zoom, and a 2K color sensor. Plus, you get alerts for sounds (people talking, dog barking) with a subscription to Nest Aware. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CHPKkV4xZQG57Ee5tuluPgOK98M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22886006/dseifert_4748_nest_doorbell_cam_battery_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Doorbell (battery) has lower quality video specs than the current Nest Doorbell (wired).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gak7OE"&gt;While Google has already said sound alerts should be coming to its new cameras, my guess is that some of these higher-end hardware specs won’t make it to the second generation Nest Doorbell (wired). To date, Google’s own version of original Nest products tend to take out the bits that made them the best in class in pursuit of a lower price point. Case in point, the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21725036/google-nest-thermostat-2020-review"&gt;Nest Thermostat&lt;/a&gt; ditches the lovely tactile dial of the original version, for almost half the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="j5nNyl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new Nest Doorbell will support 24/7 recording&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rJVHne"&gt;Chandra also shared details on the merging of the Nest app with the Google Home app. The whole post was essentially an apology to users for having to use the Google Home app to manage the new cameras, when they were used to the seamless experience of the excellent Nest app with their older Nest devices. “We are committed to bringing the experiences and Nest devices you have come to love in the Nest app into the Home app,” he writes. “This will take time to get right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8W4BbO"&gt;He did share that the ability to flip between events quickly and easily in the Google Home app will be coming soon. Currently, you have to scroll through hours of nothingness if your events are far apart. There will also be the option of just playing a glimpse of the events versus playing them back fully. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kCsrJs"&gt;He also confirmed that a desktop option for the Google Home app is coming in 2022, where users can view and control their new Nest cameras and doorbell feeds — but notably he didn’t mention the old ones, which include the first-generation Nest Cams and Nest Cam IQs. With the demise of the Nest Hello (sorry, Nest Doorbell (wired) first gen) the only legacy product that works exclusively in the Nest app is the Nest Protect Smoke alarm. Once that one moves over, it’s probably closing time for the Nest app. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700859/google-nest-doorbell-wired-2nd-gen-launching-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700859/google-nest-doorbell-wired-2nd-gen-launching-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T16:15:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T16:15:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch announces new safety tools in the fight against hate raids</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x4sOJSzqSN9HxK_S1d2b5tIR2Xo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927741/acastro_190812_1777_twitch_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LDeupH"&gt;Twitch is adding new tools in the fight against harassment on the platform. Twitch announced it will be adding phone verification chat controls that will allow streamers to require a viewer to have a verified phone number in order to chat. Additionally, Twitch is tweaking the existing email verification settings to give creators greater control over who gets to chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ekA9Lv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today we're putting more power in the hands of the community, by enabling phone verified chat! Now creators and mods can require viewers to verify their account via phone number (or email) before they can chat. For more information review the blog: &lt;a href="https://t.co/TlqCS4OzQC"&gt;https://t.co/TlqCS4OzQC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitch (@Twitch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1443276027686383622?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xr21U3"&gt;With these new tools, creators can set email or phone verification requirements for accounts that fall under certain age limits or following lengths. For example, a streamer can make it such that accounts less than a week old or that have only been following for less than a few minutes must have a verified phone number in order to chat. Streamers can also add exemptions to certain kinds of viewers like VIPs, subscribers, or mods. By limiting who can chat based on having a verified phone number, Twitch aims to cut down on hate raid incidents as it’s unlikely bots have phone numbers tied to their accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iljtBf"&gt;Twitch also built ban evasion protections into the verification tools. Users are able to tie up to five accounts to a single phone number. If one account associated with a phone number is suspended, all other accounts associated with that same number are also suspended both site and channel-wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kqzsZc"&gt;These tools and updates arrive as creators struggle to keep themselves safe in the face of an explosion in abuse on the platform. Since August, marginalized streamers have been the target of harassment brigades known as “hate raids” in which a streamer’s chat is suddenly flooded with racist, transphobic, and otherwise hateful messages generated by hundreds of bot accounts at a time. To combat this, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22633874/how-to-stop-a-hate-raid-twitch-safety-tools"&gt;streamers increasingly relied on community developed tools&lt;/a&gt; and resources like panic button programs and mass bot-banning tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCV6jQ"&gt;Creators also took to social media to call out Twitch for what they perceived as the platform’s slow or inadequate response to hate raids. Coordinated under the #twitchdobetter and #adayofftwitch hashtags, streamers organized a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650578/twitch-streamers-walkout-protest-hate-raids"&gt;Twitch walkout&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654534/streamers-twitch-walkout-viewership-drop"&gt;draw attention to the problem&lt;/a&gt;. Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620874/twitch-implements-improved-chat-filters"&gt;did acknowledge the sudden spike in hate raids&lt;/a&gt;, promising more tools were forthcoming to help creators protect themselves. Now those tools are here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0nmLN7"&gt;Phone verification is the result of months of work according to Angela Hession, vice president of Twitch trust and safety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ru8YLb"&gt;“This tool was inspired based on community feedback many months ago,” Hession tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Hession understands the deployment of these new tools looks reactive but that their development takes time because Twitch has to account for all its users in different regions across many different kinds of devices. Hession also recognizes the frustration streamers have toward the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VV2B41"&gt;“We need to do better at articulating our safety priorities and our progress so the community knows what we’re working on and why,” Hession says. There are, however, reasons why Twitch can seem so tight-lipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ueTcXs"&gt;“I think where we struggle was [striking] this fine balance because a lot of our safety work actually is behind the scenes because we don’t want bad actors to know the technology that we’re working on,” Hession says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="u0PWxg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We need to do better at articulating our safety priorities and our progress”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wNtyjj"&gt;Hession says these tools are only part of a multi-pronged approach to fight harassment on the platform. Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666953/twitch-sues-alleged-hate-raiders-harassment-streamers"&gt;Twitch filed a complaint in US federal court&lt;/a&gt; against two alleged hate raiders. The suit is meant to hopefully identify the two users known only by their handles, CruzzControl and CreatineOverdose, while acting as a deterrent for other would-be malicious actors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4gRWyP"&gt;“Taking legal actions will hopefully stop the bad actors from doing it anywhere else on the internet,” Hession says. “We are just constantly working on proactive detection filters, we also have banned thousands of bots as we’ve improved our proactive detection filters, and we will constantly be changing and tweaking as we see these bad actors are highly motivated and innovative in trying to get around our filters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nyqSqp"&gt;Phone verification is available today and streamers can follow instructions &lt;a href="https://blog.twitch.tv/en/2021/09/29/securing-your-chat-with-phone-and-email-verification/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if they want to enable it for their channel. Hession wants users to know safety is Twitch’s number one priority and that it’s a journey rather than an end state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EIZWwP"&gt;“Anyone experiencing any harassment or hate on our services is one too many. And we need to do a better job at communicating that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qe0hhl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="85MPCM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700937/twitch-safety-tools-verification-phone-hate-raids"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700937/twitch-safety-tools-verification-phone-hate-raids</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T15:54:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T15:54:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos says Google is blocking it from offering more than one voice assistant at once</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TUJjkFRfz7dqZkBfq6uKXjZ4N3k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927520/cwelch_171017_2068_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HKpy5o"&gt;Sonos developed a system called “Concurrency” that could make multiple voice assistants interoperable on its smart speakers but had to put its plans on hold because of Google, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/29/smart-home-monopoly/"&gt;a new &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; explains. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62CEZo"&gt;Concurrency does more or less what its name suggests by allowing Google Assistant and Amazon’s Alexa to be used side by side. “Sonos today sells speakers that let you choose between Alexa and Google, but only one can operate at a time — you have to disable one before you can use the other. In the Concurrency demo, talking to both of them required nothing more than saying their names,” &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; shares about Sonos’ demo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5HsCok"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sonos wants voice assistants to work together&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ug6dWt"&gt;The basic idea behind relying on multiple assistants is that each is more capable of doing different tasks, offers different integrations with smart home devices, and features different approaches to privacy and security. For example, “maybe you don’t want a company collecting so much data about your smart home. While Alexa keeps a log of what happens in your house until you go in and delete it, Google doesn’t store a history of how you use third-party devices,” &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; writes. Sonos has been working on some version of the idea &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/14/14596904/sonos-ceo-alexa-smart-home-outdoor-speakers-patrick-spence-interview"&gt;since at least 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELB8NM"&gt;While Amazon appears to be on board with Concurrency — “We subscribe to the thought that voice assistants should be interoperable,” Amazon’s David Limp told &lt;em&gt;The Post&lt;/em&gt; — Sonos says Google is standing in the way. Specifically, “Google’s distribution agreement says its assistant must operate as the only general-purpose AI,” according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjKgIR"&gt;Google spokesperson José Castañeda offered the following statement in response to Sonos’ claims. It doesn’t deny the company’s policy around Google Assistant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ElZohJ"&gt;Competition in the nascent smart home market is thriving, and there are a number of efforts underway to develop common standards between companies. Google is committed to making the smart home ecosystem more interoperable and open. To do this, we drove the creation of an industry working group alongside &lt;a href="https://zigbeealliance.org/members/"&gt;other tech companies&lt;/a&gt; to address interoperability and develop &lt;a href="https://buildwithmatter.com/"&gt;common standards&lt;/a&gt; that will give consumers more choice, protect their privacy and create easy-to-use experiences. We are one of the most active members of this group. Interoperability will continue to be a priority for us, but we also want to ensure users have a positive experience using our products and that we protect their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="6MkQT7"&gt;Sonos is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055048/sonos-google-lawsuit-sues-speakers-assistant-amazon"&gt;already fighting with Google&lt;/a&gt; over claims that the company cloned its multiroom speaker tech, which Google denies “vigorously”. Sonos also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623470/sonos-survey-voice-assistant-google-fight"&gt;appears to be working on its own voice assistant&lt;/a&gt;, entirely separate from its implementation of Google Assistant and Alexa. Concurrency could be a major win for anyone struggling to bridge between multiple smart home devices and make Sonos products that much more useful to customers. The question is whether the company’s partners will ever let it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1AZDb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 29th, 4:26PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from Google.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f0PHpp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PdBp3V"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700724/sonos-smart-speakers-concurrency-google"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700724/sonos-smart-speakers-concurrency-google</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T15:52:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T15:52:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon sent us a 13-page PDF to prove Elon Musk is as litigious as Jeff Bezos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin New Shepard Space Vehicle Flies The Billionaire And Other Passengers To Space" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dgOqlzvg4ehtgg4yFuGhLagThl4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927511/1329728877.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QlIRA3"&gt;On Tuesday, Elon Musk accused &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22699254/musk-bezos-spacex-blue-origin-code-confernce-2021"&gt;Jeff Bezos and his companies&lt;/a&gt; of using the legal system to slow SpaceX’s progress during a talk at the 2021 Code Conference. Just a few hours later, Amazon — which is working on a competing satellite-based internet project — sent &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; an unsolicited 13-page list of lawsuits, government petitions, and other legal actions that SpaceX has taken over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cpt0vA"&gt;“Attached is a list of some of the times SpaceX has sued the U.S. government on procurement matters and protested various governmental decisions,” a spokesperson for Amazon’s satellite division, Project Kuiper, wrote in the email. “It is difficult to reconcile their own historical record with their recent position on others filing similar actions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZHvP1x"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It is difficult to reconcile their own historical record with their recent position”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i4ALjt"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F528420595%2FSpaceX-Litigation-Protests&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F29%2F22700600%2Famazon-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-spacex-lawsuits" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; — published below, as Amazon insisted it was provided on the record — indeed contains a number of lawsuits filed by SpaceX, including some dating as far back as 2004, when Musk was still literally trying to get the startup off the ground. But it also includes more procedural actions, like times when SpaceX has filed opinions on how the government should allocate certain bands of spectrum for satellite communications — advocacy that has increased as SpaceX began building its Starlink satellite network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="0VOd8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Elon Musk to Jeff Bezos: ‘you cannot sue your way to the Moon’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22699254/musk-bezos-spacex-blue-origin-code-confernce-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="8VyILh"&gt;All told, there are 39 actions documented in the list, split into three categories: litigation, protests with the Government Accountability Office, and oppositions filed with the FCC. Amazon made notes on each action, which stretch the table to be 13 pages long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b5gF6G"&gt;Moments after this story was published, Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1443302848096178178"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; in response to Amazon’s statement that “SpaceX has sued to be *allowed* to compete, BO [Bezos’ space company, Blue Origin] is suing to stop competition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TNSSYH"&gt;The list provides a window into just how closely Bezos’ company is tracking and scrutinizing SpaceX’s actions as it tries to compete in the nascent satellite internet market. It’s not the only list Amazon has compiled, either. Earlier this month, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664342/amazon-spacex-starlink-fight-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-fcc"&gt;a filing with the FCC&lt;/a&gt;, the company laid out a number of occasions where it believes Musk and SpaceX have bent or broken government rules: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="TgMpff"&gt;“Try to hold a Musk-led company to flight rules? You’re ‘fundamentally broken,’” Amazon wrote in its filing, referring to the time Musk complained that the Federal Aviation Administration’s regulatory structure slowed down SpaceX’s operations. “Try to hold a Musk-led company to health and safety rules? You’re ‘unelected &amp;amp; ignorant,’” it added, referring to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1259159878427267072?s=20"&gt;Musk’s beef with officials&lt;/a&gt; who sought to keep factories closed to curb the spread of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="lpdgDU"&gt;What’s somewhat surprising is that Amazon offered this unsolicited response, since Musk’s comments at Tuesday’s Code Conference event were specifically in reference to Bezos’ space company, Blue Origin, suing to stop NASA from awarding a lunar lander contract to SpaceX. “You cannot sue your way to the Moon, no matter how good your lawyers are,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrRZhJ"&gt;Of course, Musk also recently criticized Amazon for taking legal action in the satellite internet space. In August, Musk &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/27/22644158/elon-musk-jeff-bezos-spacex-blue-origin-lawsuits-complaints-starlink-tweet"&gt;maligned Bezos for stepping down from his CEO role at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; “in order to pursue a full-time job filing lawsuits against SpaceX” after Amazon protested an expansion of Starlink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1GQim3"&gt;SpaceX and Blue Origin did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2JpoR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting from Joey Roulette.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyKOJO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 29th, 4:13PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added tweet from Musk responding to Amazon’s statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IB6QrV"&gt;
&lt;iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="SpaceX Litigation &amp;amp; Protests" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/528420595/content?start_page=1&amp;amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;amp;access_key=key-bksOsSriLQzuJRqNfazJ" tabindex="0" data-auto-height="true" data-aspect-ratio="1.2941176470588236" scrolling="no" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p style="   margin: 12px auto 6px auto;   font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif;   font-style: normal;   font-variant: normal;   font-weight: normal;   font-size: 14px;   line-height: normal;   font-size-adjust: none;   font-stretch: normal;   -x-system-font: none;   display: block;"&gt;&lt;a title="View SpaceX Litigation &amp;amp; Protests on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F528420595%2FSpaceX-Litigation-Protests%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F29%2F22700600%2Famazon-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-spacex-lawsuits" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpaceX Litigation &amp;amp; Pro...&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title="View seanokane's profile on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fuser%2F273808991%2Fseanokane%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F29%2F22700600%2Famazon-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-spacex-lawsuits" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;seanokane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700600/amazon-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-spacex-lawsuits"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700600/amazon-elon-musk-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-spacex-lawsuits</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T15:43:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T15:43:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to find your lost iPhone — even if it’s off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A purple iPhone 12" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xxmdXDJ2xj6wpidTTrR5CzNWgyg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69925408/vpavic_4547_20210421_0021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fJ0xk1"&gt;Apple’s Find My app has been a very useful (and reassuring) feature, allowing you to locate a misplaced (or stolen) phone so that you can retrieve it (or contact the authorities, if that’s safer). With the expansion of Find My to a variety of other objects, especially via &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;Apple’s AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, it’s become even more useful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TMV5J8"&gt;And now that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;iOS 15&lt;/a&gt; brings with it the capability to locate your phone even if the battery has run out or it’s been turned off — if you’ve got the right phone — the utility of Find My has become even greater. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECF20O"&gt;You will be able to locate a shut-off phone if you have the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hdzDEF"&gt;iPhone 11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="83xhGf"&gt;iPhone 11 Pro / iPhone 11 Pro Max&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oFLhI1"&gt;iPhone 12 / iPhone 12 Mini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XJvpcX"&gt;iPhone 12 Pro / iPhone 12 Pro Max&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EgrF78"&gt;iPhone 13 / iPhone 13 Mini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BlZysq"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro / iPhone 13 Pro Max&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="0gkbP2"&gt;You’ll know that this feature is active if, when you shut your phone down, you see the phrase “iPhone Findable After Power Off” under the power-down toggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hv0yZ6"&gt;Activate the Find My app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="czJIfR"&gt;If you’re new to the iPhone or have never set up the Find My app yet, here’s how you start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="zIfTal"&gt;Go to your settings, tap on your name, and then on “Find My.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LuzA3e"&gt;Tap on “Find My iPhone.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mIyfi6"&gt;Toggle “Find My iPhone” on. If you have upgraded to iOS 15, you can also activate “Find My network,” which will let you find your phone even if it’s offline. “Send Last Location” will send the location of your iPhone to your Apple account when the battery is about to die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Turn on the Find My feature in your settings." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hEyLTj__UBAbTD4HpxYhdYbZFn0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884575/IMG_49615EE7ED8B_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turn on the Find My feature in your settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Turn on “Find My network” to find your phone when it’s off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RNDYVuILGJl6ncQVRmWvCChpZxc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884577/IMG_E77E43DD93EA_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turn on “Find My network” to find your phone when it’s off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IAs1td"&gt;And that’s it! After that, if you can’t find your iPhone, then you can track it either by using the Find My app on a Mac (or another iPhone, if you have one) or on any browser by going to &lt;a href="http://iCloud.com/find"&gt;iCloud.com/find&lt;/a&gt; and signing in using your Apple ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0WCkuy"&gt;If you’re using the web version, then you’ll see a green dot that locates your iPhone. Select the dot and then the circled “i” (for information), and you’ll be given the choice of having your phone play a sound, erasing it, or putting it on “Lost Mode.” In “Lost Mode,” you can enter a phone number where you can be reached and a message (“Please return this phone asap!”). After that, the phone will be locked until you reenter its passcode.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Find My app lets you locate your phone, send a notification, or erase it. (Note: the map has been blurred for privacy reasons.)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DtyCr1Ryk_qdHRUm_kBoMOlC5oE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884619/Screen_Shot_2021_09_28_at_10.10.46_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Find My app lets you locate your phone, send a notification, or erase it. (Note: the map has been blurred for privacy reasons.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XMD6QL"&gt;If you’re using the Find My app, you’ll get basically the same features (except in a more aesthetically pleasing form), along with map directions on how to get to your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTXF7S"&gt;And yes — if you’re using iOS 15 on your iPhone, you will be able to locate it even if it’s run out of battery power or has been shut off. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Find My can locate a phone even if it’s off — as long as it has iOS 15 installed." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2Gh52_nYw0SlvCzEQB_hNMpsde4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884670/Screen_Shot_2021_09_27_at_4.50.43_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find My can locate a phone even if it’s off — as long as it has iOS 15 installed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SZblTv"&gt;(Note: you can also use the Find My app to help with your own security — to share your location with individuals and send recurring notifications of when you leave and arrive. You can find directions for setting that up in our article “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676312/ios-iphone-apple-location-tracking-turn-off-on"&gt;How to use iPhone’s location tracking&lt;/a&gt;.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPzGxS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 29th, 2021, 3:30PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add information on which iPhones can be found after power off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8QN2OV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIsHvH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2R8t8E"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22697218/iphone-apple-ios-15-find-my-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22697218/iphone-apple-ios-15-find-my-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T15:19:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T15:19:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Surface Pro 7 vs. Pro 8: what’s the difference?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Surface Pro 8" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tqEb0014hwtFyZeJ51E7dAXMXLM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927362/bfarsace_210921_4770_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pro 8 offers Thunderbolt 4 support, a 120Hz display, a better camera, more storage, and more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aRBaAl"&gt;During its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684950/microsoft-surface-event-biggest-announcements-pro-8-duo-studio-laptop"&gt;recent Surface event&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft launched the largest upgrade of its flagship Intel-powered Surface Pro lineup in years: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685923/microsoft-surface-pro-8-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt;. The new 2-in-1 machine boasts a 120Hz display, Thunderbolt 4 support, and new processors, but all of those improvements come at a cost — literally. Whereas the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeMicrosoftSurfaceReview&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Pro-7%2F8n17j0m5zzqs%3Fcrosssellid%3D%26selectedColor%3D86888a" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro 7 starts at $549.99&lt;/a&gt;, the Surface Pro 8 starts at $1,099.99, meaning it’s nearly double the price. And that’s also before you factor in the cost of Microsoft’s new stylus and detachable keyboard, two add-ons that are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688403/surface-pro-8-duo-studio-x-go-true-price-keyboard-pen-stylus-bundle"&gt;more like necessities&lt;/a&gt; if you intend to use the 2-in-1 as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3RXHP"&gt;With all that said, is it worth upgrading or picking up the Pro 8 over the last-gen model when it launches on October 5th? To help make your decision a little easier, we’ve put together the comparison below based on specs and our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686705/microsoft-surface-pro-8-keyboard-screen-photos-video-hands-on"&gt;initial impressions of the Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bRdkia"&gt;What’s improved on the Surface Pro 8?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="PZOp5K"&gt;Two Thunderbolt 4 USB-C ports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C8O1SQ"&gt;You can double the refresh rate from 60Hz to 120Hz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cIGutN"&gt;11th-gen Intel quad-core Core CPUs, starting with i5 instead of i3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dNd01o"&gt;10MP rear-facing camera, with 1080p and 4K video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fHHsMg"&gt;Larger, 13-inch display with higher 2880 x 1920 resolution (up from 12.3-inch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EQHexv"&gt;Double the RAM on the base model (8GB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pLeX2a"&gt;Microsoft says the battery should last up to 16 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B1X1vQ"&gt;New sensor that adjusts the display temperature based on ambient lighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3URsFf"&gt;LTE support for enterprise users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="26BwNl"&gt;Preloaded with Windows 11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="DHULZd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771697"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UtWO1X"&gt;The Surface Pro 8 is more than just an incremental update. Microsoft’s newest slate features a modernized look with slimmer bezels, making it the Surface Pro’s largest visual redesign in years. Like the Surface Pro X, the Surface Pro 8 features a 13-inch display as opposed to the 12.3-inch found on the Pro 7. In his recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686705/microsoft-surface-pro-8-keyboard-screen-photos-video-hands-on"&gt;hands-on take&lt;/a&gt;, my colleague Dieter Bohn also remarked that the Pro 8 feels slightly nicer to hold, given the corners are softer. And if color matters to you, the touchscreen machine is also now available in graphite instead of black, which is a colorway still available for the Pro 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4asgn"&gt;Spec-wise, the display on the Pro 8 is significantly better compared to its predecessor, given there’s now an option to ramp up the refresh rate from 60Hz to 120Hz, which could improve scrolling and make using the stylus easier. Gaming could certainly be more enjoyable on the Pro 8, too, especially given the device comes preloaded with the Xbox app and a one-month trial of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate. In addition, the latest Pro supports Dolby Vision and is the first Surface device to come with an ambient color sensor, which automatically adjusts the display’s color temperature and brightness based on the surrounding lighting conditions. The new Pro 8 also boasts a 3:2 display and 2880 x 1920 pixels as opposed to 2736 x 1824, although, technically, both share the same 267 pixels per inch. Regardless, the expanded size still offers you a little more space for, say, multitasking. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V3hC5yr_1Au32B8HK7Bk42n5aGA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869371/Surface_Pro_8_with_Type_Cover_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 8 is equipped with a larger, 13-inch touchscreen and narrower bezels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="a0yIxA"&gt;The Pro 8 also appears to be superior to the Pro 7 when it comes to performance and battery life. The new 2-in-1 is available with either a quad-core, 11th-gen Intel Core i5 or Core i7 processor, and with up to 32GB of RAM. The Pro 8 also comes with a removable SSD in one of four configurations: 128GB, 256GB, 512GB, or 1TB, something you could previously only find on the Pro 7 Plus. It’s important to note, however, that Microsoft says the SSD should be repaired or replaced by a trained Microsoft-authorized technician — they’re “not user removable.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="36q2k0"&gt;The Pro 7, meanwhile, comes with a dual-core, 10th-gen Intel Core i3 or a quad-core, 10th-gen Intel Core i5 or Core i7, and with up to 16GB of RAM. It’s available in 128GB, 256GB, 512GB, and 1TB capacities. Overall, Microsoft says the Surface Pro 8 shows a 40 percent improvement over the Pro 7 when it comes to sustained CPU performance; it’s also 74 percent faster on the graphics side, according to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9jruzF"&gt;Battery life on the Pro 8 is, at least on paper, greater as well, with Microsoft claiming it can last up to 16 hours on a single charge. The tech giant also says it can charge from 0 to 80 percent in a little over an hour. The Pro 7 was supposed to last up to 10.5 hours on a charge in comparison, though, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923662/microsoft-surface-pro-7-review-tablet-specs-features-price-usb-c-windows-10"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we noted it lasted 7-8 hours or less when working with graphically intensive apps and pages. We don’t expect Microsoft’s battery claims regarding the Pro 8 to hold up in real-world usage, though, especially with a 120Hz display.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-qvCkiEhAqkEFB0QGCvdKoMsfCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19249911/akrales_190930_3688_0218.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last-gen Surface Pro 7 features older, 10th-gen Intel processors and lacks Thunderbolt ports.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0JQbpg"&gt;The Pro 8 additionally stands out in some ways when it comes to connectivity, depending on your needs. Instead of a USB-A port and the integrated microSD card slot featured on the Pro 7, Microsoft went with two Thunderbolt 4 ports, allowing the tablet to support either two 4K displays with a 60Hz refresh rate or a single 8K monitor at 30Hz. The Core i3 and Core i7 models can also be configured with LTE, though the feature is only available to enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sMaPit"&gt;The Pro also boasts better cameras than its successor. The new model’s rear camera is a 10MP shooter as opposed to an 8MP, and the rear camera on the Pro 8 can also capture 4K video. The Pro 8’s new face-tracking tech could also improve video calls by keeping you in focus while you walk around and talk. Microsoft says the Windows Hello camera has been upgraded, too, and it pairs with Microsoft Studio mics for audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Surface Slim Pen 2 with haptic feedback." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/se8t99tuv1LBp3-Wy3WLuwzrBdg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22868461/bfarsace_210921_4770_0013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Surface Slim Pen 2 comes with haptic engines for a smoother inking experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zlOAjT"&gt;Unsurprisingly, Microsoft also improved the Pro 8’s optional accessories. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;new Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt; ($129.99) features a sharper tip that allows for better precision and a built-in haptic motor, which helps the stylus better emulate the feeling of writing on paper and makes for a smoother inking experience. You can also charge the pen inductively when you’re not using it via the built-in slot on the detachable Surface Pro Signature Keyboard ($179). The new keyboard is also stiffer thanks to a carbon-fiber core, but not heavier or thicker, which gives it less bounce when typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sELKqo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How the Microsoft Surface Pro 8 stacks up to the Surface Laptop Studio, Go 3, and more","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688116/surface-pro-8-go-3-laptop-studio-4-spec-gpu-power-features"},{"title":"How to preorder all of the new Surface hardware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683783/microsoft-surface-pro-x-8-3-go-laptop-studio-preorder-price-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="S2BoiQ"&gt;What’s the same on both models?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0nX5Qm"&gt;Both share a similar, flat-edged appearance &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0bJFBR"&gt;Each has a 5MP front-facing camera for Windows Hello facial recognition that can capture video in up to 1080p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="34qz5R"&gt;Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth support &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wdze6B"&gt;Each is compatible with both generations of the Surface Slim Pen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7uCRf2"&gt;Each features a built-in kickstand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SLhpzM"&gt;Both are compatible with an optional keyboard and stylus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tfMKvh"&gt;Both have a 3.5mm headphone jack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="jQMX75"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9644155"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N7KXsN"&gt;Besides a larger display and the new Thunderbolt 4 ports, the Surface Pro 8 is otherwise very similar physically to its predecessor. It has a rounded, flat-edged appearance, with a built-in kickstand on the back and physical buttons for volume and power. You can also use both generations of the Surface Slim Pen with either model, but note you won’t be able to enjoy the new haptic functionality afforded by the Surface Slim Pen 2 on the Pro 7. Although slightly heavier at 1.96 pounds, the Pro 8 is still light and measures less than half an inch thick, much like the Pro 7. Both also come in the platinum (read: silver) and a darker colorway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Ak1WB"&gt;The front-facing camera and various wireless connectivity are also similar across devices, in addition to select ports. While the Pro 8 has a better rear camera, the 5MP front-facing camera is just like the Pro 7’s and can capture video in up to 1080p. Both models also offer dual far-field studio mics, Wi-Fi 6, and Bluetooth support, and each comes equipped with a 3.5mm headphone jack in addition to the usual Surface Connect port. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQBb4G"&gt;Finally, both offer support for Windows 11. While the latest model ships with Windows 11, Pro 7 users will be able to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22690092/how-to-upgrade-windows-11-free-early-final-version"&gt;download the latest OS update for free&lt;/a&gt; when it releases on October 5th. This means both devices will be able to take advantage of features like the new Start menu, widgets, and the operating system’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548738/microsoft-teams-windows-11-integration-announcement-features"&gt;deeper integration with Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt;. A new OS update will also bring Android apps to Windows 11 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650000/microsoft-windows-11-android-apps-support"&gt;next year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GA6WI_hV-WzwgxNrz8x6G1ghUsA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869374/Surface_Pro_8___Modes_under_embargo_until_September_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pro 8 is compatible with a detachable keyboard and stylus, both sold separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;aside id="HswiAH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft Surface Pro 7 review: I wish this looked like a Surface Pro X","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923662/microsoft-surface-pro-7-review-tablet-specs-features-price-usb-c-windows-10"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="sJqFpQ"&gt;Why you might want to buy the Pro 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gDx2yy"&gt;With a larger display, improved performance, potentially more battery life, and higher-res cameras, Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 8 looks to be a notable step up from the Surface 7 in several key ways. The Pro 8’s support for Thunderbolt also means you can connect the device to multiple monitors, enjoy faster transfer speeds, and, theoretically, use the device with an external GPU. That, along with the display’s 120Hz refresh rate, is helpful if you intend to use the tablet primarily for gaming or as a creative tool. And while the starting price is higher, you’re getting double the RAM and an i5 CPU to start, instead of an i3. If you want closer-to-comparable specs in the older Pro 7, you’re starting at $799.99 instead of $549.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8kEkJ"&gt;If you’re an enterprise customer, the Pro 8 may also be worth considering, as you’ll be able to benefit from LTE support alongside the other aforementioned perks. The LTE model isn’t available yet, however, and Microsoft says it won’t arrive until next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9c4tf"&gt;Keep in mind that this is all based on Microsoft’s provided hardware specs and our early hands-on impressions with the Pro 8. We won’t know for certain how Microsoft’s latest 2-in-1 performs until we can spend some additional time with it, so if you’re considering the Pro 8, we suggest waiting for our full review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pw2K5Y"&gt;Why you may want to stick with the Pro 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="X2UUuN"&gt;If you’re on a tight budget and need a Windows tablet for casual use or everyday tasks, it may be better to stick with the Surface Pro 7. The 2-in-1 also comes with a built-in microSD card slot for transferring data and a USB-A port — a nice perk if you continue to work with older peripherals. The Pro 8 doesn’t have either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ViVc6I"&gt;Given the significant improvements in its internals and display, the Pro 8 is naturally more expensive and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-8%2F8qwcrtq8v8xg%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starts at $1,099&lt;/a&gt; (without accessories). Again, you’ll also have to pay an extra $179 for the Surface Pro Signature Keyboard and $129 for the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-slim-pen-2%2F8tb9xw8rwc14%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt;, though, if you want both accessories, they’re available as a &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-signature-keyboard-with-slim-pen-2%2F8vdb5vrkc5tq%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;package deal for $280&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mL1zpM"&gt;In contrast, the Pro 7 is &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Pro-7%2F8n17j0m5zzqs%3FselectedColor%3D86888a%26ranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale&lt;/a&gt; starting at $549.99, while the Pro 7’s detachable &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-type-cover%2F91v4vtmhxwpm%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro Type Cover keyboard&lt;/a&gt; — something the Pro 8 no longer offers, by the way — and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pen%2F92fp8q09qhxc%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pen&lt;/a&gt; start at $129.99 and $67.99, respectively. Note, as well, that keyboard covers compatible with Surface Pro 7 don’t work with the Pro 8, so you can’t buy yourself a cheaper Pro 7 one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4yYlem"&gt;When you do the math, there’s still a difference of about $600 between the two, assuming you’re buying the base model of each with its accompanying keyboard and stylus. The added expense is substantial, especially if you don’t care for Thunderbolt 4, a 120Hz display, and the other, more premium features that define the Pro 8.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22688324/microsoft-surface-pro-7-vs-8-spec-comparison-upgrade-worthwhile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22688324/microsoft-surface-pro-7-vs-8-spec-comparison-upgrade-worthwhile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-29T15:15:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-29T15:15:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can finally rate Apple’s apps on the App Store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ucAA2Huwjoixhj4Wik797kZ8HK0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69927350/acastro_210831_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mzwh7q"&gt;For years, Apple has let you redownload many built-in apps from the App Store that you may have deleted, but store listings for those apps had a distinct difference from others: there was no way to leave a rating or review. That appears to have changed recently, though, as you can now review Apple’s apps in the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S8Q3gr"&gt;In a cursory, unscientific scan of some of Apple’s apps, many of them don’t have overwhelmingly positive scores. Files, Apple Maps, and Home all had ratings between three and three-and-a-half stars. Apple News is currently sitting at 2.3 stars. &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/rate-and-review-apple-iphone-built-in-apps/"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; observed&lt;/a&gt;, Podcasts has a whopping two-star rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fnx7HA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There aren’t a lot of ratings yet&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qWZKo6"&gt;That said, most of Apple’s apps just don’t have many ratings — many don’t break triple digits — meaning the current reviews represent an infinitesimally small sample of the huge number of iOS users who are out there. (To give you a sense of just how large the iOS ecosystem is, Apple said in January that there were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253162/iphone-users-total-number-billion-apple-tim-cook-q1-2021"&gt;more than a billion iPhones in active use&lt;/a&gt;.) It also means that Apple’s apps have far fewer ratings than well-known apps like Gmail (347K), Facebook (1.1 million), and TikTok (10 million).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="luPjyO"&gt;But even if there are only a few ratings right now, I still think the change is a good one, and I’m curious to see how ratings shake out for Apple’s apps over time. Now, if you’ll excuse me, I’m going to start drafting my review of Apple Mail where I publicly beg for a built-in snooze function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5WYtdd"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700805/apple-app-store-built-in-ratings-reviews-stars"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700805/apple-app-store-built-in-ratings-reviews-stars</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
