<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-18T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA is set for its most daring attempt to land on Mars in a search for ancient life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dHmeI_59U9lyL60dONEW6CUG3IU=/460x0:5523x3375/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836252/05_GuidedEntry_10k.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An illustration showing NASA’s Perseverance rover making its way toward the Martian surface.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g9ex47"&gt;On February 18th, NASA will make a daring attempt to land a car-sized rover on Mars in its most complex mission yet to hunt for ancient extraterrestrial life. If it survives the plunge through the Red Planet’s atmosphere, the Perseverance rover will kick off the first leg of a grand relay race to capture humanity’s first cache of pristine Martian soil samples, among many other scientific objectives it hopes to score along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ghJ60n"&gt;What time will NASA’s Perseverance rover land on Mars?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BHILAe"&gt;Having traveled 293 million miles since its launch in July last year, the rover is now gearing up to execute the Solar System’s most grueling parking job ever. At around 3:48PM ET, Perseverance will begin its wicked seven-minute descent toward the Martian surface, hitting the planet’s atmosphere at speeds of roughly 12,100 miles per hour before being calmly deposited in a messy jungle of cliffs, massive boulders, and dangerously sandy pits at Mars’ Jezero Crater.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EWTu9Pk0PWDD4oZj1qfkdOu9hqw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310629/09_Touchdown_10k.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This illustration shows NASA’s Perseverance rover and its descent stage executing a “skycrane” maneuver for a safe touchdown at Mars’ Jezero Crater.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yL2U7H"&gt;In that fully autonomous landing sequence, the spacecraft carrying Perseverance will endure blazing heat, ditch its protective shell, and deploy a set of parachutes. As it approaches the surface, the spacecraft’s descent stage will fire onboard thrusters to slow itself down to a sedate 2 mph and hover some 66 feet above the surface. Then comes the “skycrane” technique: the descent stage, still firing its six mini rocket thrusters, will gently lower Perseverance on cables the rest of the way to the surface. Once the rover touches down, it’ll snip its cables, prompting the descent stage to take off, eventually landing far away from Perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tMJC2D"&gt;How to watch Perseverance’s ‘seven minutes of terror’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="UPgGzT"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/21X5lGlDOfg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LgU7Qd"&gt;To virtually join engineers at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory as they track Perseverance’s plunge into Mars, the agency will have &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasalive"&gt;live streams&lt;/a&gt; of NASA coverage and video and audio of mission control beginning at 2:15PM ET. Actual footage of the spacecraft’s landing will take about a week to beam back to Earth, but it’ll be worth the wait. Perseverance has 19 on-board cameras, and its landing gear has four, promising views of parachute deployment and other steps of its rapid descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrGtQK"&gt;If the landing choreography goes as planned, NASA would become the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266752/uae-china-nasa-mars-missions"&gt;third spacefaring power&lt;/a&gt; this month to reach Mars after the United Arab Emirates and China. NASA has said some of the rover’s onboard instruments, like a tool that will try to convert Martian carbon dioxide to oxygen, are being tested to inform future astronaut missions to Mars under the agency’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700565/nasa-artemis-moon-return-landing-trump-administration-jim-bridenstine"&gt;Artemis program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pKEeFD"&gt;A high-stakes landing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8LdeS5"&gt;Dozens of mission engineers at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in California have spent years planning, troubleshooting, mapping, and stressing over the seven-minute landing sequence. “Everything’s come down to that,” Al Chen, NASA’s entry, descent, and landing lead, said in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. He calls his team of about 30 engineers working this week “glorified delivery guys.” But with a $2.7 billion rover, the stakes are much higher than your average drone-delivered Amazon package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T52RZr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We have this big 200-foot cliff wall going right through the middle”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="71UwTg"&gt;“We know that the rest of the mission, the surface mission and everything that comes afterward and the rest of the campaign, is depending on us. So we wanna make sure we don’t let anybody down,” Chen said. Making it even more nerve-wracking, an 11-minute communications delay between Mars and Earth means Perseverance will have to carry out its descent and landing all by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t1iSFO"&gt;Comparatively, NASA’s past Mars rovers had it easy. They also had to endure the infamous “seven minutes of terror,” but they got easier landing zones. NASA’s Opportunity rover was greeted by a flat, wide-open desert of the Martian Eagle Crater when it touched down in 2004. The Spirit rover’s Gusev Crater landing site and Curiosity’s site at the Gale Crater were similarly flat, dotted only with small rocks. A wholly different extraterrestrial landscape awaits Perseverance at the Jezero Crater, the site of an ancient river delta believed to bear traces of past life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lxWXLv"&gt;“We have this big 200-foot cliff wall going right through the middle” of the crater, Chen said. “There are a bunch of craters around the site that are full of sand, that even if we landed there it wouldn’t be safe to drive out of. And there are rocks in a lot of different places that we definitely don’t want to come down on.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nPZ9sL"&gt;What will Perseverance do on Mars?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BBHGKP"&gt;Why would NASA pick such a difficult region to land in? It’s “because the geology on Jezero crater is so exceptionally well-preserved,” said Briony Horgan, a scientist at Purdue University working on Mars Perseverance. Jezero’s 28-mile-wide diameter could be a goldmine for fossilized microorganisms, and its mix of different rock formations offers researchers a smorgasbord of potential samples. What’s more, scientists believe Jezero hosted a river delta about 3.5 billion years ago, preserving organic matter in muds long after it dried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FAKPJO"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tomorrow I arrive at Jezero Crater, a dry lakebed on Mars. I’ll chart a path along its ancient shoreline, to see if it’s like similar places on Earth. I’m looking for rocks that tell a story of past microbial life. &lt;a href="https://t.co/5RCEWdNc9b"&gt;https://t.co/5RCEWdNc9b&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CountdownToMars?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CountdownToMars&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/NsNJjXHPbu"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NsNJjXHPbu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— NASA's Perseverance Mars Rover (@NASAPersevere) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASAPersevere/status/1362137708294934529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wr6gnz"&gt;“We think, based on looking at orbital data of the delta, that those muds that could contain signs of organic materials and life are actually preserved at the base of the delta at the cliffs,” Horgan said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M25bER"&gt;This is key for Perseverance’s primary mission: packing about 43 soil samples in cigar-sized tubes and depositing them across 5–10 different sites at Jezero. Those tubes will sit on the surface for years until a future “fetch” mission planned jointly by NASA and the European Space Agency arrives for pickup. That mission’s turn in the relay race will come in the late 2020s, when a fleet of four spacecraft and robots will work in concert to land on Mars, gather the sample tubes, and shoot a soccer ball-sized sample canister back into space for a journey home to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iow54L"&gt;&lt;q&gt;All that wild science and engineering hinges on a successful landing on Thursday&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dzV4kU"&gt;Perseverance’s secondary objectives include a mini-helicopter named &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21339544/nasa-mars-helicopter-ingenuity-perseverance-rover-flight-date"&gt;Ingenuity&lt;/a&gt;. Detaching from the rover’s belly, the $85 million craft will attempt to fly in Mars’ ultrathin atmosphere up to five times during a month-long window that will begin a month or two after Perseverance lands. Using helicopter blades to traverse a planet with a much thinner atmosphere than Earth’s requires extra power and speed for the craft’s four-foot-wide propellers. If the flight demo succeeds as engineers hope, it would mark the first demonstration of vertical rotorcraft on another world and could unlock access to more volatile extraterrestrial regions that are too rough or slippery for more traditional grounded rovers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hHYWJsVuFPjLPrzF_KUN22_6gkY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22312172/Helicopter_landing_composite.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An illustration showing NASA’s little Ingenuity helicopter carrying out its flight demonstration above the surface of Mars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="t314Xk"&gt;Ingenuity, while weighing about as much as a half-gallon of milk, will have solar panels for power, its own communications hardware, and two cameras (one to record Martian landscapes during flight and another to help with navigation). Perseverance is also decked out with 19 cameras plus a few microphones that promise high-def audio of Martian wind. For engineers, the audio-visuals provide a means to monitor the rover’s instruments and make sure everything looks and sounds normal. A so-called SuperCam sticking out of the top of the rover — basically looking like Perseverance’s robot head — will fixate on Martian rocks, zap them with a laser beam, and analyze the cloud of vapor produced as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oq48s7"&gt;Locating ‘tiny parking lots’ on Mars &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FUtKCV"&gt;All that wild science and engineering hinges on a successful landing on Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tc5mVj"&gt;Perseverance has 4.8 miles of cushion for its landing zone. For a mission millions of miles away to Mars, 4.8 miles is a tiny bull’s-eye, one that’s 10 times smaller than the flat surface the Curiosity rover landed on in 2012, and 300 times smaller than that of NASA’s first Mars rover, Sojourner, in 1997. Such tactical precision is made possible by two pieces of tech the other rovers didn’t have: a “Range Trigger” that will accurately shoot out Perseverance’s parachutes when it decelerates to 940mph during its descent, and an enhanced navigation system that links up with a Mars orbiter to calculate exactly where in Jezero the rover will land. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BvsQow"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We just need tiny little parking lots that are interspersed that we can reach”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HY1efC"&gt;“It’s kinda like what people used to use in the car, looking out the car window and seeing what you see and then trying to figure out where you are by looking at your map,” Chen said. “We no longer need the entire [landing zone] to be a flat and boring parking lot of a runway, we just need tiny little parking lots that are interspersed that we can reach.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qx3YIk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWlowr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJe252"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3OEZGp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Oj3O3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="feyIIw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ElFHKG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P2mchg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VyLIp9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287160/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-landing-watch-live-stream-start-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287160/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-landing-watch-live-stream-start-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:52:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:52:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boost your Nintendo Switch’s storage with this $70 512GB microSD card</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FVht1m0p1c6smlbgPIcBJmdGVVQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836173/akrales_171025_2091_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jX35Yz"&gt;It’s a good thing that Nintendo’s Switch supports microSD because prices for the expandable storage format just keep getting better. Today, for instance, you can buy PNY’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KD4XJLX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB microSD card at Amazon for just $70&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a Deal of the Day, so this price will expire later tonight. Previously, it was rare to find this amount of storage for less than $100, and with each Switch game being between 5-15GB in size, this will serve you a long time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yQcIQx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10349001"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1F2Y7F"&gt;Also at Amazon, you’ll find the lowest price yet offered on Apple’s most recent Mac mini with the M1 processor. It’s the base model with 256GB of storage, which is admittedly not much, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;but you’ll pay $600&lt;/a&gt; at checkout instead of $670. This price drop beats all other retailers, but the catch is that Amazon says people who buy one right now at this price won’t get one until late March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mFkRkP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="orDn7a"&gt;I mentioned recently that Google’s Nest Audio smart speaker is $20 off its usual $100 price. If you’re in the market for two of them, you can save a little more than that per speaker ($25 off) &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/996990/1036?subId1=VergeNintendoSwitchStorage021821&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fga01420us2.html"&gt;at Adorama&lt;/a&gt;. Add this two-pack of speakers to your cart, then insert the coupon code &lt;strong&gt;50OFF199 &lt;/strong&gt;to get both for $150 altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="euoXO5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503894"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZtYv9r"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/18/22289131/microsd-card-pny-nintendo-switch-mac-mini-m1-google-nest-deal-sale-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/18/22289131/microsd-card-pny-nintendo-switch-mac-mini-m1-google-nest-deal-sale-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:40:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:40:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Scientists try to fix flat maps with new double-sided projections</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zFncByLgV0o8ppaew0Cg3-DyIr4=/0x0:960x640/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836121/equidistant_azimuthal_projection.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A double-sided projection to show off our 3D planet in 2D.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Gott, Goldberg, Vanderbei&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="D23gK2"&gt;A trio of scientists have devised a new way to try to represent our spherical planet as a flat picture with a new class of projection that involves printing the map as a double-sided circle, &lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2021-02-astrophysicists-re-imagine-world-distorted-radically.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phys.org &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. The Double-Sided Gott projections involve splitting a globe in two and printing the separate hemispheres on separate sides. The &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/2102/2102.08176.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; is the work of J. Richard Gott, Robert Vanderbei, and David Goldberg from Princeton and Drexel universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZVqiy"&gt;While 3D globes are the most accurate way of representing the layout of the Earth’s surface, it’s much more convenient to refer to a 2D representation. There are a variety of ways of converting this 3D shape into 2D, which are referred to as map projections, but none of them are perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xAelb3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We believe it is the most accurate flat map of Earth yet”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K9Jd28"&gt;The most famous projection is probably the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercator_projection"&gt;Mercator projection&lt;/a&gt; (which is used by Google Maps for local area maps), but it gets really distorted near the North and South poles. The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winkel_tripel_projection"&gt;Winkel Tripel&lt;/a&gt; is another option, and it’s the one used by National Geographic for its world maps, but it still splits the Pacific Ocean in two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sNjszX"&gt;In 2007, Goldberg and Gott devised a system for scoring the accuracy of flat maps, where the closer a score is to zero, the more accurate it is. A globe, for instance, would get a perfect zero. By their calculations, the Mercator projection scores 8.296 and Winkel Tripel does better at 4.563. Their own azimuthal equidistant double-sided projection, meanwhile, scores 0.881. “We believe it is the most accurate flat map of Earth yet,” the trio write. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGwncZ"&gt;It might technically be flat, but having a map printed on two sides of a piece of paper introduces obvious limitations. The scientists admit that “our double-sided flat map is actually more like the globe of the Earth than the other flat maps” because you can’t see both sides at once. Instead, they see it as the kind of map that might be included as an extra sheet in a magazine, or printed on cardboard or plastic and stored in boxes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WFZc20"&gt;For more about the problems with 2D projections, check out this video from &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jJKQ0n"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Why all maps are wrong|24429" data-volume-uuid="d4c74decc" data-volume-id="24429" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-960" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289120/globe-2d-map-double-sided-gott-equidistant-azimuthal-projection"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289120/globe-2d-map-double-sided-gott-equidistant-azimuthal-projection</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:38:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:38:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia is nerfing its new RTX 3060 for Ethereum cryptocurrency mining</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x-vnDtIQMeS5VG-PPAgIbQasXFE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836115/acastro_180529_1777_nvidia_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qxWy0N"&gt;Nvidia is purposefully making its new RTX 3060 graphics cards less efficient to mine Ethereum cryptocurrency. New drivers that will accompany the release of the GPUs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22280277/nvidia-rtx-3060-graphics-card-release-date-time"&gt;later this month&lt;/a&gt; will reduce the hash rate of Ethereum mining by around 50 percent, using software detection for cryptocurrency mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s9P609"&gt;“We designed GeForce GPUs for gamers, and gamers are clamoring for more,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/02/18/geforce-cmp/"&gt;says Matt Wuebbling&lt;/a&gt;, head of global GeForce marketing at Nvidia. “Yet NVIDIA GPUs are programmable. And users are constantly discovering new applications for them, from weather simulation and gene sequencing to deep learning and robotics. Mining cryptocurrency is one of them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m9Iq6f"&gt;It’s clear Nvidia is making the changes to try to help with the availability of its GeForce products. Nvidia is offering a new &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fcmp%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F18%2F22289154%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cryptocurrency Mining Processor&lt;/a&gt; (CMP) for Ethereum miners instead. These will include the best performance for mining and efficiency, but they won’t handle graphics at all. Nvidia says these CMP products, crucially, “don’t impact the availability of GeForce GPUs to gamers.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AbZfwBYTG6BGCgUQDVO5SM_MAqI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22312133/xV6u2t6.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nvidia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia’s new Cryptocurrency Mining Processor (CMP).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OXm3Se"&gt;The CMP products won’t have display inputs so they can be more densely packed into systems designed for mining. Nvidia is also ensuring CMPs have lower peak core voltage and frequency to improve the big power requirements associated with Ethereum mining. “With CMP, we can help miners build the most efficient data centers while preserving GeForce RTX GPUs for gamers,” says Wuebbling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wqCIMl"&gt;While the introduction of a dedicated option for miners is welcomed, Nvidia’s move to specifically nerf mining performance on the RTX 3060 is likely to receive some criticism. It’s an artificial limit imposed with software restrictions that’s been put in place because Nvidia is struggling to make enough GPUs to satisfy demand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JwDhMQ"&gt;The entire industry, from gaming to car manufacturing, is affected by chip shortages right now. Nvidia clearly feels now is the right time to respond to GPU demand by ensuring what’s likely to be its most popular new GPU is focused purely on gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289154/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289154/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:38:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:38:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Why Google caved to Australia, and Facebook didn’t</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DpIDxNA6jLp_VoShAVoipVZ6nbM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836113/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GyJ9sS"&gt;On February 16th, I wrote that &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/australias-bad-bargain-with-platforms"&gt;Australia’s News Media Bargaining Code threatened to splinter the internet&lt;/a&gt;. On February 17th, the splintering arrived: Google cut a deal with News Corp. that will ensure its services continue to be provided in Australia, and Facebook walked away from the bargaining table and began preventing people from sharing news links from Australian publishers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCTNGG"&gt;I think Facebook basically did the right thing, and Google basically did the wrong thing, even though Google had a much tougher call to make. Today, let’s talk about why the tech giants made the decisions that they did, why Australia’s shakedown is rotten, and what’s likely to happen next. (If you didn’t &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/australias-bad-bargain-with-platforms"&gt;read my piece on the subject&lt;/a&gt;, it offers a lot of useful context for what follows.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JasDhI"&gt;In development for three years, the bargaining code is intended to give Australia’s heavily concentrated media industry more leverage as publishers seek direct payment from Google and Facebook for the right to display links to their work. It does this by forcing the platforms into binding arbitration with publishers who bring cases, and puts the decision for how much the platform has to pay the publishers into the hands of the arbiter. Each side throws out a number, and the arbiter picks the one they think is most fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UySyPw"&gt;By design, the arbitration process favors the publisher. Also by design, it encourages platforms to avoid the process altogether by signing one-off deals with individual publishers in hopes that they can get better terms that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DPVkce"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Google&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M9w69j"&gt;Over the past few days, Google has been signing deals with the biggest publishers in Australia for exactly this reason. &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/google-australia-news-technology-seven-west-media-2021-2#:~:text=Google%20signed%20up%20a%20major,force%20payments%20to%20media%20outlets."&gt;Seven West Media got a deal&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/feb/17/nine-agrees-to-join-google-news-showcase-in-australia-for-reported-30m-a-year#:~:text=Australia's%20biggest%20locally%2Downed%20media,laws%20being%20debated%20in%20parliament."&gt; Nine Entertainment got a deal&lt;/a&gt;, and on Wednesday, one of the country’s biggest conglomerates — Rupert Murdoch’s News Corp. — got its deal. In exchange for an undisclosed sum, Google will feature News Corp. articles in its News Showcase product in Australia and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1mqiXD"&gt;“Among the News Corp publications joining Google News Showcase will be the&lt;em&gt; Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Barron’s&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;MarketWatch&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt;; in the UK: the&lt;em&gt; Times&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Sunday Times&lt;/em&gt;; and the &lt;em&gt;Sun&lt;/em&gt;; and in Australia a range of news platforms, including the &lt;em&gt;Australian&lt;/em&gt;, news.com.au, Sky News, and multiple metropolitan and local titles,” the company told me in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mu6fGa"&gt;As announced, the deals pertain to &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/google-news-showcase/"&gt;Google News Showcase&lt;/a&gt;, a tab within Google News that contains licensed content from official partners. But the people I’ve spoken with are operating under the assumption that if there’s a deal between Google and a big publisher in Australia, that publisher either can’t or won’t be dragged to arbitration for showing links and snippets of text in search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dC7snt"&gt;Search, of course, is what Google cares about the most, which explains why the company caved. Removing links to news stories from Google would break the search engine in Australia, &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2021/02/11/endorsement-australias-proposal-technology-news/"&gt;opening it up to rivals&lt;/a&gt;. And so the company signed a bunch of deals under duress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Skmycc"&gt;(It’s worth mentioning that any Australian publisher aggrieved by an unfair exchange of value with Google here could opt out of search results at any time by adding one line of HTML to their website. But almost none of them do because traffic from Google drives significant advertising and subscription revenue to them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oyGQD5"&gt;With its moves today, Google has now invited every other country to pursue a similar protection racket. Parliament members in Canada and the European Union have already endorsed measures similar to Australia’s. And a basic tenet of the open web — that hyperlinks can be freely displayed on any website — just took a body blow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uJdReU"&gt;I’d feel better about this if publishers said a single word about how much of their new Google revenue they planned to spend on journalists’ salaries or news gathering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8fbNK8"&gt;They didn’t, though, and why would they? Australia’s bargaining code doesn’t say one word about requiring that any of this money be spent on journalism, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Xu35mr"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;II.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eVSx0f"&gt;Unlike Google, Facebook’s core service doesn’t rely heavily on news articles. The company estimates that only about 4 percent of posts on the network are works of journalism. It is not all that hard to imagine opening up Facebook and scrolling for a few minutes, never to see a link to a news article at all — and in fact, millions of people do this every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nwoyNR"&gt;And so it is perhaps less surprising that when Google blinked at Australia’s demand, Facebook walked away. Here’s William Easton, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/02/changes-to-sharing-and-viewing-news-on-facebook-in-australia/"&gt;Facebook’s managing director for Australia and New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KcMUZK"&gt;While the government has made some changes, the proposed law fundamentally &lt;a href="https://australia.fb.com/post/our-response-to-australias-proposed-news-media-laws/"&gt;fails to understand&lt;/a&gt; how our services work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XK3rse"&gt;Unfortunately, this means people and news organisations in Australia are now restricted from posting news links and sharing or viewing Australian and international news content on Facebook. Globally, posting and sharing news links from Australian publishers is also restricted. To do this, we are using a combination of technologies to restrict news content and we will have processes to review any content that was inadvertently removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="U1HpAx"&gt;And just like that, news articles originating in Australia disappeared from Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="22Nont"&gt;Easton says that in the past year, Facebook sent more than 5 billion clicks to Australian publishers, whose value he estimated at AU$407 million. If the current situation holds, Facebook will send those same publishers zero clicks — a move that, I imagine, may force publishers to recalibrate in their minds the relative value that Facebook and publishers provide one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myruWq"&gt;Of course, many critics were apoplectic that Facebook had taken this move, calling it &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/matthewstoller/status/1362135211606220800?s=20"&gt;a vile act of censorship&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JuddLegum/status/1362172282102304769"&gt; unchecked greed&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evelyndouek/status/1362171044136710144"&gt;destruction of the public sphere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tLnF6S"&gt;Certainly the execution of the ban left something to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vFB6Bb"&gt;Rather than building a blacklist of news sites to restrict, Facebook tried using its machine learning systems to identify news publishers, and the systems went &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-02-18/bom-health-authorities-betoota-caught-in-facebook-news-ban/13166394?section=technology"&gt;predictably haywire&lt;/a&gt;. There were reports that government and emergency pages, nonprofit groups, and the Bureau of Meteorology &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maxchalm/status/1362160410984476672?s=21"&gt;could no longer share&lt;/a&gt;. Given how long the possibility of restricting links has loomed, you’d think Facebook would have better prepared for it to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhWEoi"&gt;And while I don’t want to make light of these mistakes, to the extent that they teach Facebook’s user base to seek their news elsewhere, they can serve a noble purpose. I don’t know a single journalist who feels comfortable with social networks being anyone’s primary source of news, particularly after years of daily reporting on the misinformation and conspiracy theories that so often thrive on them. And so it is more than a little strange to see so many people insisting that Facebook is obligated to share publishers’ content, on whatever terms those publishers set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yS1m62"&gt;Some, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WillOremus/status/1362132040544628736?s=20"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt;’s Will Oremus&lt;/a&gt;, have noted that removing high-quality news sources from Facebook will likely mean a boost for lower-quality blog posts, memes, and other junk. That seems fair, and I do think it bears watching. But what if, in the meantime, Australians simply… visit websites? Subscribe to newsletters? Read… books? I realize I sound hopelessly naive here. But if this is the beginning of more people coming to understand the value in visiting trusted news sources directly, I think we’d all be better off. Publishers included!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kwdgQ"&gt;In reality, though, I suspect the great Australian news outage of 2021 will be short-lived. Australia’s treasurer, a leading figure in the negotiations, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joshfrydenberg/status/1362144150712315905?s=21"&gt;said he spoke with Mark Zuckerberg today&lt;/a&gt; and that negotiations continue. (&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/17/business/media/australia-google-pay-for-news.html"&gt;Fun fact from &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Australia’s treasurer was also “&lt;a href="https://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/ryan-stokes-society-wedding-a-sizzler-20161202-gt30re.html"&gt;the best man at the wedding of Ryan Stokes&lt;/a&gt;, who is a son of Kerry Stokes, the billionaire owner of Seven West Media, one of the companies that have reached a deal with Google.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bb1vLs"&gt;“We will continue to engage with the government on amendments to the law, with the aim of achieving a stable, fair path for both Facebook and publishers,” Facebook told me today when I asked for an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dclaz9"&gt;In the meantime, though, I’m glad Facebook called publishers’ bluffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pqfBIw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III. What’s next&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dCFcyG"&gt;I wish Australia would take Facebook’s rejection as a sign it should rethink its approach to media regulation entirely. It could just tax companies based on their revenues, for example. It could earmark those revenues to support journalism — nonprofit public media, even, &lt;a href="http://www.orangemedianetwork.com/blog/screengaze/the-importance-of-public-broadcasting/article_dda75496-e27e-11e6-a558-2f6b46140340.html"&gt;which has consistently been shown to have powerful civic benefits&lt;/a&gt;. Or it could pursue a bargaining code that requires big media conglomerates to create and support &lt;em&gt;jobs&lt;/em&gt; in journalism, rather than simply accept tens of millions of dollars and spend them however they like — or just return it to shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s3U0e7"&gt;In reality, though, none of that seems likely to happen. Google’s capitulation means that Australian crony capitalism is now likely to be exported worldwide. Legacy media outlets will become richer — and also more dependent on the tech giants that they excoriate daily for having too much power over them. All the while, the media industry will continue to consolidate, and it will be harder to get or keep a job in journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YNvIof"&gt;A bargaining code that truly sought to level the playing field between the platforms and the public would take these realities into account. There is still time to amend it before Parliament takes a vote, and here’s hoping that lawmakers do — both in Australia and beyond it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="AE46su"&gt;
&lt;p id="QZMQt8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288510/google-facebook-australia-news-media-bargaining-code"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288510/google-facebook-australia-news-media-bargaining-code</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:29:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:29:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout is coming to Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="fall guys" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pDHogLEpHtKgkHlFZv-12f92osY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836072/ss_b2b6b170330b8af1f50d0e90efad984adafeb281.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uDooaf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout&lt;/em&gt;, Mediatonic’s charming platformer battle royale title, is coming to Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One this summer, Microsoft announced in &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/02/18/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-this-summer/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; today. The news comes just one day after Mediatonic announced that the game was going to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288187/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-nintendo-switch-mediatonic"&gt;ported to the Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt; sometime this summer as well. While no firm release date has been announced, both ports will likely launch within the same time frame. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcfjtX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; originally released in 2020 on PC via Steam and PS4, where it was a free title for users with an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402473/fall-guys-sony-ps-plus-most-downloaded-game-all-time"&gt;active PlayStation Plus subscription&lt;/a&gt;. The game mixes battle royale with the platformer genre, where players compete in elimination-type challenges. The title draws inspiration from competitive game shows like &lt;em&gt;Wipeout&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I57O8m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout&lt;/em&gt; is currently available on PC and PS4 and is backward compatible on PS5. &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; also received a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/22/21397170/fall-guys-mobile-china-game-developer"&gt;mobile version&lt;/a&gt;, but it is only available in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="G6aHDE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fall Guys is coming to Nintendo Switch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288187/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-nintendo-switch-mediatonic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289166/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-series-x-s-one-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289166/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-series-x-s-one-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:16:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:16:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Halo Bolt portable car jump-starter is more than a battery saver</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c0EAdcMS0KLjJnMLUAPKId88jk4=/0x1:2040x1361/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836020/khatton_210216_4411_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fRNeGs"&gt;Getting my license at age 16 was a breath of fresh air. It was me, my used 2007 Mazda6, and the open road. As anyone who knew me at the time will say, though, I was a misfortune magnet as a teenager and this extended to my car. There was even a running joke among my peers that I was on a first-name basis with the local tow truck drivers because &lt;a href="https://ohio.aaa.com/membership.html"&gt;AAA&lt;/a&gt; had to dispatch them on a regular basis — a dead battery being one of the more common mishaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zIYf4c"&gt;Whether the battery died so often because I left a light on, the weather was frighteningly cold, or I waited too long to replace the battery, doesn’t really matter. However, my mom eventually saw fit to save me both time and money by gifting me the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Halo-Portable-Laptop-Charger-Starter/dp/B079FSPRXM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Halo Bolt Portable Car Jump Starter&lt;/a&gt; so I would always have a way to give my little car a boost when I needed it most. Neither of us knew how often I would actually use it. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cDxG7dlPVPbGrxfPN31e3d_n0po=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310675/khatton_210216_4411_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Halo Bolt can be attached to the battery using the short jumper cables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LnfbJ9"&gt;As my car aged and I put thousands of miles on it driving across Ohio and back to attend college, it needed more and more attention. On average, I would use my Halo Bolt charger at least once every few months, and it always worked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwYc4M"&gt;The device comes with its own set of short jumper cables which store easily in its carrier bag. The Bolt’s manufacturer says it can jump-start a standard car’s battery up to 217 times. (Luckily, I didn’t have to test it quite that often.) Additionally, the company claims that one of these chargers can jump a car, boat, lawn mower, or motorcycle. In between uses, simply plug it into a wall socket for a few hours before returning the charger to the car. It fits snugly under my driver’s seat and retains its charge for long periods of time without needing to be topped up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D0wRZB"&gt;The real value for me, however, comes from the ability to plug other electronic devices into it through its two 2.4A USB ports and three-prong AC outlet. Of my Mazda’s two power sockets, only one worked, and more often than not, I found myself in need of multiple outlets. Using the Halo Bolt’s two USB ports, I could quickly and easily charge my phone, my iPod Touch, and even the occasional laptop. When not actively jumping a car, it can charge multiple devices at once. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I0TV5fruixOqehBqmy1QOMt9cu0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310680/khatton_210216_4411_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bolt includes two USB ports and an AC outlet for portable charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wOdj0G"&gt;Coincidentally, when I said goodbye to my first car, I seemed to have shed the bad luck that haunted me. I have yet to use my Halo Bolt to jump-start my newest vehicle, but I still find uses for the portable charger. It comes in handy when a storm has knocked out my apartment’s power supply. I’ve been able to keep my phone charged, which gives me peace of mind knowing I can contact loved ones or ask for help in case of an emergency. The product listing claims the Halo Bolt offers enough charge to allow for dozens of hours of talk time, depending on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSaNNZ"&gt;Finally, the Bolt has an LED floodlight, which I’ve used in tandem with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01GCT9VIO?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;manual flashlight&lt;/a&gt; to see my way around my apartment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4e9EeY"&gt;The Halo Bolt weighs less than three pounds and comes in a variety of colors and patterns, including paisley, floral, graphite, chevron, camouflage, and more. The Halo Bolt 58830 model runs about $80, which is well worth the peace of mind that comes with having a power source to jump my car’s battery or to see me through a power outage.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9nwdf6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348983"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iG5zAm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XJ7eqd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SZ5hqX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22288004/halo-bolt-car-battery-jump-start-charger-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22288004/halo-bolt-car-battery-jump-start-charger-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kaitlin Hatton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The team behind indie adventure Minit returns with a side-scrolling racing game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x5xwkSzY9y1sCUXOIud6vVx3QrY=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835872/minit_funracer_x4_7.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Devolver Digital&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qj2xHF"&gt;The indie gem &lt;em&gt;Minit&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17207310/minit-indie-game-review-die-every-60-seconds-love-letter-classic-gaming"&gt;released back in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, felt like a breath of fresh air. The monochromatic adventure game took a seemingly absurd time constraint — killing the player every 60 seconds — and turned it into both a passionate love letter to top-down classics like &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda &lt;/em&gt;and an ingenious and clever quest that threw constant surprises at the player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xteSAm"&gt;Now, the core team behind &lt;em&gt;Minit — Nuclear Throne &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Disc Room &lt;/em&gt;developer Jan Willem Nijman, designer Kitty Calis, composer Jukio Kallio, and artist Dominik Johann&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;are back with a new spinoff title, &lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer. &lt;/em&gt;The game takes the same core idea and applies it to a side-scrolling biking game reminiscent of arcade titles of decades past. All proceeds of the game, which is being published for free by indie label Devolver Digital, go to charity, including Doctors Without Borders and Special Effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="631uEG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;releases today for $2.99 on both Steam and itch.io, with the latter store having a pay-what-you-want option for those who’d like to give more. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pnOMa1wQKt9duVxTPS5oVSAbJsM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310133/minit_funracer_x4_4.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Devolver Digital&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ro6mr5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;has less of a narrative than the game it’s based on and an even tighter time constraint of less than 10 seconds to begin with. You’re simply plopped down onto a highway full of obstacles and challenged to find your way to the end before the timer runs out and you start over from the beginning. But &lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;lives up to the original by hiding scores of secrets to find through experimentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LFkz3i"&gt;The main engine of progress in the game is earning coins and using the currency to unlock new upgrades, which, in turn, help you progress further along the route. But there are Easter eggs and fun little side quest-style unlockables — like an air horn for waking up the sleeping cats by the side of the road or an impromptu helicopter chase if you bump two cop cars — that make the game worth exploring in full. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Nwtxi8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Our philosophy has always been if you have fun making something it really shines through in the final product.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qx6v5a"&gt;“We wanted to make a full game, not just something you would buy just for charity,” says Calis. “The bigger it gets, the more we can help, and in the end we want people to have a good time and to do good, too.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A1hFmt"&gt;In my first few play sessions last week with a preview build of the game, I died — a lot, as is expected. But after my first few upgrades, I felt like I was making steady progress and really enjoying the fast-paced, trial-and-error design. And the new music from Kallio, a longtime collaborator of Nijman’s who also co-wrote the catchy &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys &lt;/em&gt;soundtrack&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;is a fantastic addition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vL6pOo"&gt;“Our philosophy has always been if you have fun making something it really shines through in the final product,” Nijman says. Asked about other &lt;em&gt;Minit &lt;/em&gt;spinoffs or sequels in the future, Nijman and Calis say they aren’t yet ruling out future works — or as Nijman called it, a “Minit cinematic universe” — using the game’s pixel art style or its core time constraint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VROxgK"&gt;“Never say never,” Calis says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXVBVH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287453/minit-fun-racer-charity-game-release-date-announce"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287453/minit-fun-racer-charity-game-release-date-announce</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bravely Default is a classic RPG series designed for lapsed fans</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cwamv0YKNVNUA4_XsdTe2rLv-Yk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835901/Switch_BRAVELYDEFAULTII_screen_01.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IgAb6j"&gt;When Masashi Takahashi, a producer at Square Enix, started working on &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;, he had a very specific audience in mind. Takahashi had grown up playing classic turn-based roleplaying games — he distinctly remembers watching his older brother play &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy III&lt;/em&gt; while he was still in kindergarten — and felt that many modern RPGs had become too complex, leaving older players behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4c6QHl"&gt;“They seem kind of impenetrable,” he says of modern games. “I thought if I could make a game that was able to make [older players] recall things they liked about games when they were younger, and create a game for that type of audience, that was one thing that spurred me forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMP1Gh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/6/5383040/bravely-default-nintendo-3ds-review"&gt;The first &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; launched on the Nintendo 3DS in 2014, and it was an experience clearly inspired by earlier &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games, starring a ragtag group of heroes traveling through a fantasy world powered by four magic crystals. Its defining feature was also the reason it had such a strange name: in battle, players could choose to be “brave” or “default,” in order to go all-in on an attack or stack chances for a more opportune time. It was followed by &lt;em&gt;Bravely Second: End Layer&lt;/em&gt; in 2016, also on the 3DS, and next week the series makes its debut on the Nintendo Switch with &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Zv4yrB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They seem kind of impenetrable.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xRV7Zn"&gt;The sequel takes place in a new fantasy realm and stars a new cast of heroes, but the formula is largely the same. The strange naming convention, Takahashi says, is inspired by other iconic Japanese RPG series. When a new, numbered &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; comes out, fans know it will be a brand-new adventure. Takahashi wanted the same kind of clean slate for the next &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikKw07"&gt;One difference eagle-eyed fans might notice, however, is that while the first two games in the franchise were developed by Square Enix and a partner studio called Silicon Studio, &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt; is being helmed by a relatively new company called Clay Tech Works. However, there isn’t much disconnect between the games, as Clay Tech was founded by some of the key staff from Silicon. “Although the public may be hearing of Clay Tech Works for the first time with this game, they are people we’ve worked with for a long time,” says Takahashi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Uqjzo8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mlpR7bXopF0?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QsyBPq"&gt;Coincidentally, Shota Fukebaru, director at Clay Tech, &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; got his start in RPGs with &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy III&lt;/em&gt; at a young age. And both Fukebaru and Takahashi say that &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy V&lt;/em&gt; and its job system — which gave players the ability to customize their fighters by assigning specific roles, and became a key feature in the &lt;em&gt;Bravely&lt;/em&gt; series — were extremely influential on their careers. “I remember playing that game and thinking, ‘Wow, this is something I want to do someday,’” Fukebaru says. “That’s where that dream originated for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="KQyQFP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1255519"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OX8D5s"&gt;Development on the sequel faced some challenges. Like most studios around the world, the team of around 50 at Clay Tech had to adapt to working from home, finding ways to effectively communicate with each other over Zoom meetings. There was also the process of taking a series originally designed for a dual-screened device and adapting the interface to work on the Switch’s single display. Naturally, though, the change in hardware was mostly beneficial; Takahashi says the team was able to make more detailed characters and a soundtrack that wasn’t limited by the 3DS’s tiny speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eXBN5"&gt;Takahashi also says that the team has been able to learn key lessons from each release and apply that to subsequent titles. The original &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt; was criticized for having poorly defined characters, for instance, something the developers tried to remedy in the first sequel. And when &lt;em&gt;Bravely Second&lt;/em&gt; players complained that the story was a little too YA, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/12/17561880/octopath-traveler-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;a follow-up called &lt;em&gt;Octopath Traveler&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; focused exclusively on adult characters and themes. Finally, while &lt;em&gt;Octopath&lt;/em&gt; had an ambitious story featuring eight different characters — hence the strange title — this meant that there wasn’t a clearly defined protagonist, something the team is aiming to fix in &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bn0Bk3"&gt;The new game is also launching at a time when classic JRPGs are experiencing something of a renaissance. Outside of the &lt;em&gt;Bravely&lt;/em&gt; series, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16951126/square-enix-tokyo-rpg-factory-lost-sphear-switch-ps4-pc"&gt;Square Enix studio Tokyo RPG Factory has been steadfastly focused on the genre&lt;/a&gt;, while indie creators have explored new ideas through games like &lt;em&gt;Undertale&lt;/em&gt;. When the creators of the classic series &lt;em&gt;Suikoden&lt;/em&gt; crowdfunded a spiritual successor last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21340344/eiyuden-chronicle-suikoden-spiritual-successor-kickstarter-funded"&gt;it was a resounding success&lt;/a&gt;. For Takahashi, who has been thinking about the genre since he was a five-year-old, it’s been rewarding to see so much renewed appetite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iChz7H"&gt;“This is something I’m really happy about,” he says. “Of course I really enjoy making these games — but I enjoy playing them as well.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287791/bravely-default-2-nintendo-switch-interview-square-enix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287791/bravely-default-2-nintendo-switch-interview-square-enix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tracking down mystery boats on the high seas  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tracking down mystery boats on the high seas  " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/23Aewejvca1Uyln0lC_aP0k96_s=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835882/Thumb_Textless.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Alex Parkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M5SEST"&gt;Out on the high seas, more than 200 miles from shore, seafood companies can operate with almost no oversight. These are ungoverned, international waters where it’s easier for companies to get away with overfishing and abuses like modern-day slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcP1vY"&gt;Scientists using new hacks for old technology are slowly changing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYjADs"&gt;Two decades ago, large vessels began carrying a little box that connects to what’s called the maritime Automatic Identification System (AIS). It sends out a radio signal with information about the ship, like an identifying number, and its size, course, and speed. That’s supposed to help ships avoid running into each other. It also helps authorities see where vessels are when they’re close to shore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5C4di"&gt;After the 9/11 attacks, AIS started getting more attention from the US government. It saw the tech as a way to keep an eye on potential threats to national security at sea. The US Coast Guard contracted the telecommunications company &lt;a href="https://www.orbcomm.com/PDF/datasheet/Satellite-AIS-Surveillance-Security.pdf"&gt;Orbcomm&lt;/a&gt; to launch satellites that could pick up on AIS signals from space. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="http://www.esa.int/Enabling_Support/Space_Engineering_Technology/i_Atlantis_i_leaves_Columbus_with_a_radio_eye_on_Earth_s_sea_traffic"&gt;Norwegian government&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://artes.esa.int/sat-ais/overview"&gt;European Space Agency&lt;/a&gt; were developing similar technology. When the first AIS-enabled satellites were launched in 2008, that was a game-changer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDMsUv"&gt;Now, satellites can pick up on a vessel’s AIS signals no matter where the ship is sailing. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/11/14/7219261/global-fishing-watch-map-tracks-illegal-fishing-across-the-globe"&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;, environmental groups and Google partnered up to create a near real-time &lt;a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/map/?locale=en"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; that traces the movement of about 60,000 commercial fishing boats with AIS. The effort is called Global Fishing Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="So8gB0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with Jennifer Jacquet and Gabrielle Carmine, two scientists on a mission to find out who’s doing what out on the open ocean. Check out the video above to see how they used AIS and some old-school sleuthing to spot corporate actors on the high seas. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22289075/high-seas-overfishing-exploitation-tracking-ais-tech-scientists"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22289075/high-seas-overfishing-exploitation-tracking-ais-tech-scientists</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
