<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-17T05:59:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-17T05:59:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-17T05:59:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is pushing the Control Panel aside in its latest Windows 11 updates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GI30Ri1yNaQaK7xV6ralEgXqji4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70285033/VRG_ILLO_4030_Windows_10_Guide_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GBNwvU"&gt;Microsoft is finally signaling the end of the legacy Control Panel in Windows 11. The software giant introduced a number of changes in its Settings section of Windows 11 earlier this year, and this month the company has started testing even more ways to replace Control Panel functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMuqVw"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/12/01/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22509/"&gt;new test versions of Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft has moved the advanced network settings into a new page in the Settings app, which includes sharing options for folders, printers, and network discovery options. Some entry points to the network and device settings in Windows 11 also now redirect to the Settings app, instead of forcing you into the Control Panel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LFmI0iml9ltrPFSGi2dpnw_nvA4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103467/D51G3TZ.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Control Panel in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JHDrgN"&gt;Elsewhere, links to the section of the Control Panel used to uninstall apps now redirect to the Settings app. Even the section for uninstalling Windows Updates &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/12/15/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22523/"&gt;is now part of the Settings app&lt;/a&gt;, instead of being housed in the Control Panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VExSC5"&gt;These latest changes are welcome, and come after attempts to move away from the Control Panel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/28/9045331/microsoft-windows-10-review"&gt;in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft originally introduced a separate Settings app in Windows 8, as a way to overhaul its traditional Control Panel. The two have existed alongside each other for legacy support reasons, just like how Microsoft had two browsers (Internet Explorer and Microsoft Edge) inside Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26SuKw"&gt;The Settings app was designed to be a new broom that sweeps clean, but there are still plenty of settings that require you to head into the Control Panel. Windows 10 improved things, and Windows 11 offers an even more modern take on how users control their PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rf2hO7"&gt;Microsoft describes these latest changes as an “ongoing effort to bring over settings from Control Panel into the Settings app.” So it’s clear Microsoft is committed to cleaning this area of Windows up, and eventually making the Control Panel redundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XA9A6G"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"&gt;Windows 11 has largely been an attempt to modernize&lt;/a&gt; and simplify a Windows operating system that has been used the same way for decades. Microsoft didn’t quite go far enough with the Control Panel for the initial release of Windows 11, but in other areas like the taskbar it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812258/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-clock-multiple-monitors-start-menu-updates"&gt;simplified things far too much&lt;/a&gt;. These monthly changes pave the way for Microsoft to finalize what has felt like an unfinished version of Windows so far.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841028/microsoft-windows-11-control-panel-changes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22841028/microsoft-windows-11-control-panel-changes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T23:01:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T23:01:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG refreshes its pricey Pro OLED monitors for 2022 and adds a 27-inch option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QF2xc275699hRBPk-N_mCUhw09E=/0x0:1796x1197/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284663/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_00_1200.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="paZXTd"&gt;In 2021 LG &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224922/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-4k-monitor-ces-2021"&gt;added an OLED-based monitor for pros to its lineup&lt;/a&gt;, and now the company has revealed the follow-up UltraFine OLED Pro monitors it’s planned for 2022. While its first effort was only available as a $3,999 31.5-inch 4K monitor, next year’s version will include a 27-inch variant. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/akWb2Np5u72wRkGLxhKQseQH6UQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103191/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_01_1800.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpLtHz"&gt;Naturally, the 32BP95E and 27BP95E still feature the precise lighting control you’d expect from an OLED panel; however, these screens aren’t meant for gaming or even TV and movie watching. The promise LG’s DisplayHDR 400 True Black technology ensures that if you’re editing photos or video, everything looks the way it truly should. They’ll also ship with detachable self-calibration sensors and monitor hoods and use the LG Calibration Studio software to adjust their settings for the environment. Other hardware specs like their port selections appear to be similar to the 2021 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hTt0eMZdKSmg48vKIZ5R3kobt1g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23103210/LG_OLED_Pro_Monitor_02_800.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mcXD6w"&gt;The monitors can accurately display colors covering 99 percent of the DCI-P3 and AdobeRGB color gamut plus a 1,000,000:1 contrast ratio, so it will be difficult to find as accurate reproduction on any consumer display. LG didn’t note a refresh rate in its press materials, so we’d expect it’s still set at 60Hz. You could buy an expensive screen like this and use it for gaming, but it’s not really intended for use in daytime lit environments or fast-moving action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Tveky"&gt;It also won’t hit the peak brightness of LCD monitors like LG’s own UltraFine displays, or the $4,999 (plus $999 optional stand) Apple Pro Display XDR &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"&gt;we reviewed in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, but even with local dimming, those simply can’t display absolute black like an OLED panel can. As Nilay Patel said about Apple’s monitor, “while it can run with the very best full-array local dimming LCDs I’ve ever seen, it’s still a local dimming LCD: sometimes it blooms, and sometimes all of the dimming zones are lit up, and blacks look gray across the whole screen.” We would expect that things will be different with these screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eAPVGF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"LG UltraFine 4K Display (2019) review: bigger isn’t better ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/2/20678597/lg-ultrafine-4k-2019-mac-monitor-review-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Apple Pro Display XDR review: category of one  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VHdkX4"&gt;There’s no word on pricing but these monitors should start shipping next month in “key markets.” Still, hopefully, the smaller model will be a bit cheaper than last year’s, which finally started shipping in the US in September — if you can’t wait for the updated versions, that one’s currently available from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-32EP950-B-Ultrafine-Display-DCI-P3/dp/B097NYL7XS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-32ep950-b-oled-monitor&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840813%2Flg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1621997-REG%2Flg_32ep950_b_32_oled_uhd_dci_p3.html%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840813%2Flg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ZwpXG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840813/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840813/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-monitor-2022-ces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T21:30:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T21:30:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Holmes trial is about money  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Theranos Founder Elizabeth Holmes Attends Criminal Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/czzIlkNNUQtftxTFVPvO1CscoQM=/1x0:4000x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284417/1237270984.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;It was never about the people&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="7rhnf1"&gt;Prosecutor Jeffrey Schenk opened his closing arguments in the case against Elizabeth Holmes by talking about a banker. Holmes knew Theranos, the company she founded, was running out of money, and she was on the phone asking her banker to clear a check early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CINZPi"&gt;“Holmes had a choice to make,” Schenk said. She could figure out a way to raise funds to keep the company moving, or risk seeing it wither away. And her choice, he said, was to raise the funds through fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QH4GQ7"&gt;The prosecution’s closing statement on Thursday was a reminder of what this trial is really about: money, and mostly rich people’s money. Those rich people, who gave their money to Theranos after Holmes pitched them on the promise of the company, are who the prosecutor referred to as ‘victims.’ Their money is what, according to the legal system, was manipulated during the years Theranos was the hottest startup in Silicon Valley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WV0NBG"&gt;That focus is because Holmes is on trial for fraud. That’s what she could get in trouble for in the aftermath of Theranos’ collapse — misrepresenting what the company could do in order to get money out of (mostly) investors (but technically also) patients and doctors. Holmes isn’t on trial because the tests her company made were bad. She’s not in trouble because her company gave people incorrect information about potentially devastating health issues. She couldn’t go to jail for overseeing workplace former employees described as &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Business/theranos-employees-describe-culture-secrecy-elizabeth-holmes-startup/story?id=60544673"&gt;secretive&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/theranos-employees-claim-toxic-work-culture-part-61720603"&gt;unhealthy&lt;/a&gt;, and where the chief scientist &lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/elizabeth-holmes-trial-dredges-up-toxic-memories-for-theranos-workers"&gt;died by suicide&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="5J6M2y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She’s not in trouble because her company gave people incorrect information about potentially devastating health issues&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3zR4Kt"&gt;Theoretically, she could have continued to oversee a company doing all of those things, and not be facing 20 years in prison. The reason she’s staring down incarceration isn’t for making bad tests — it’s for lying about those tests in order to fundraise. “An honest pitch filled with honest representations to her investors and to patients would not have resulted in any revenue,” Schenk said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhhZd0"&gt;She didn’t make an honest pitch, Schenk argued. And that’s why, he told the jury, she should be found guilty of fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSavQ0"&gt;Before diving into the specific ways Holmes wasn’t honest, Schenk broke down exactly what the government had to prove in order to show that she met the technical, legal requirements for fraud. Holmes is on trial for two things: conspiracy to commit fraud, and fraud. She allegedly &lt;em&gt;conspired&lt;/em&gt; to commit fraud against investors and patients, and allegedly &lt;em&gt;committed&lt;/em&gt; fraud against investors and patients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LwUQi6"&gt;To meet the bar for a conspiracy, Holmes had to have been part of an agreement to make false statements for the purpose of getting money that would keep Theranos alive. In order to have committed fraud, she had to have known and participated in a plan to get money by making misleading statements, and those statements had to be things that could reasonably trigger someone to spend money. And — in a key element — she had to have acted with the &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; to defraud someone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ziYiJX"&gt;Schenk spent around three hours pacing in front of the jury and walking them through all the ways Holmes made misleading statements to investors. He talked about the pharmaceutical company logos &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799756/elizabeth-holmes-pfizer-logo-confession"&gt;she admitted to adding&lt;/a&gt; on to Theranos-conducted lab reports, which investors said gave the impression those companies had prepared the reports themselves. He emphasized that she’d given investors misleading information about what types of tests could be run on the Theranos machines, and gave the impression that the machines were accurate even though they weren’t. He pointed to media interviews where she’d given the same types of answers, and said that Holmes then turned around and sent articles based on those interviews to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKakDL"&gt;Then, Schenk showed the jury evidence that he argued means Holmes gave that misleading information intentionally — like text messages about Theranos’ money issues, and emails about problems with demonstrations of the Theranos devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KLImjP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Schenk showed the jury evidence that he argued means Holmes gave that misleading information intentionally&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cmBEds"&gt;(Defense attorney Kevin Downey focused his closing statements on the idea that Holmes didn’t actually have intent. He started in on that argument on Thursday, and will continue it Friday morning). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8B5sWY"&gt;Schenk pointed out that patients saw the misleading statements given in media interviews, as well, which is one way they were allegedly defrauded. Patients also got bad information about the accuracy of the Theranos tests in advertisements and on the company website, even though Holmes new that there were problems with certain tests — like the hCG test, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22687026/theranos-patient-bad-test-miscarriage-pregnancy"&gt;told patient Brittany Gould that she might be having a miscarriage. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igEek9"&gt;Holmes intentionally directed misleading statements to patients for the same reason she did investors, Schenk said: to raise money. But, as he noted multiple times, individual tests raised less money than investors. He spent less time focusing on the patients and their experience than he did on the investors. Unlike the investors, he didn’t refer to the patients who were given bad medical test results as victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tj0dFG"&gt;Closing arguments from the prosecution told a story about a company that was running out of money, and a CEO who lied to people in order to get them to give them more money. That’s illegal. And that’s what the legal system is equipped to get people in trouble for. Schenk summed that up quite well towards the end of his closing arguments: “This case is about real people, who lost real money.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1eFDF8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QpA89P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840697/holmes-trial-theranos-closing-arguments"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840697/holmes-trial-theranos-closing-arguments</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T21:19:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T21:19:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Schools across US cancel classes over unconfirmed TikTok threats</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_gqIcUhNUSnHkWe-_-7-ilOOm0o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284380/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Unconfirmed threats on TikTok led some schools to cancel classes | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WUW6gk"&gt;School districts across the United States are cancelling classes on Friday, December 17th due to reports of threats that are supposedly being made on TikTok. Districts in &lt;a href="http://nixle.us/alert/9144787/"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.wfaa.com/article/news/education/threats-against-kaufman-high-school-prompts-school-closure-friday-texas/287-6c32c971-27d0-4df6-a7e9-5a26fe9fedea"&gt;Texas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.lfalls.k12.mn.us/2021/12/december-17-threat/"&gt;Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://abc17news.com/news/education/2021/12/16/gasconade-county-school-district-to-close-friday-after-tiktok-threat-challenge/"&gt;Missouri&lt;/a&gt; have said they plan to close down Friday in response, according to the districts and local media reports. Elsewhere, districts have said they plan to have heightened police presence or have emailed parents to say they’ve been investigating the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M6kFt4"&gt;But so far, there’s little evidence that the threats are credible — or even exist. The districts and local police departments largely say they’ve heard about a trend referencing the possibility of shootings or bombings on December 17th, but it’s not clear how many have seen a specific threat or a threat against their schools in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDn440"&gt;A number of districts and law enforcement divisions say they’ve looked into it and don’t view the threats as credible or even real. “Law enforcement agencies have investigated this threat and determined that it originated in Arizona and is not credible,” Baltimore County Public Schools &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BaltCoPS/status/1471498518003027979?s=20"&gt;wrote on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “Currently, there have been no threats to any of the schools in Mexico, [Missouri],” wrote a &lt;a href="https://abc17news.com/news/education/2021/12/16/gasconade-county-school-district-to-close-friday-after-tiktok-threat-challenge/"&gt;Missouri school district&lt;/a&gt;. “There have been no local, credible threats,” Ohio’s Milford Exempted Village School District &lt;a href="https://www.milfordschools.org/news-feed/entry/safety-update%3A-tiktok-challenge-dec-17-723/"&gt;wrote to parents&lt;/a&gt;. In New Jersey, Governor Phil Murphy &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/status/1471613653749313547?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “there are no known specific threats against New Jersey schools.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dQVUxZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;While there are no known specific threats against New Jersey schools, the safety of our children is our highest priority and we will work closely with law enforcement to monitor the situation and remain prepared.&lt;/p&gt;— Governor Phil Murphy (@GovMurphy) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/status/1471613654953046028?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cPgrKK"&gt;The reports of threats on TikTok may be self-perpetuating. Videos being posted to TikTok warn others that they should skip school on December 17th due to supposed threats of shootings or bombings, which seem to have prompted others to create similar videos. And now that schools are canceling classes in response to those supposed threats, a new wave of videos have popped up with additional warnings based on both the supposed claims and  the actual, factual cancellations of some school classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8iyAls"&gt;TikTok says it has not identified any videos making specific threats. “We have not found evidence of such threats originating or spreading via TikTok,” the company wrote in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1471572096111239175?s=20"&gt;a tweet&lt;/a&gt; Thursday afternoon. TikTok said it is working with law enforcement to look into the warnings with “utmost seriousness,” nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sJCYJW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We handle even rumored threats with utmost seriousness, which is why we're working with law enforcement to look into warnings about potential violence at schools even though we have not found evidence of such threats originating or spreading via TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;— TikTokComms (@TikTokComms) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TikTokComms/status/1471572096111239175?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="seT3YQ"&gt;One school district in Little Falls, Minnesota, opted to cancel classes on Friday after being notified by the state’s Department of Public Safety about “a TikTok trend that emerged targeting Friday, December 17, as a day of threats of shootings and bombings in schools.”  &lt;a href="https://www.lfalls.k12.mn.us/2021/12/december-17-threat/"&gt;According to a post&lt;/a&gt; on the Little Falls Community Schools website, law enforcement determined via interviews that Little Falls was “specifically identified in a TikTok post related to this threat,” unlike other schools and school district that believe they haven’t specifically been named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qsFBpB"&gt;But the district didn’t say that they had actually viewed the threat themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wal8Gu"&gt;Superintendent Stephen Jones said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the Little Falls district made the decision to cancel after consulting with law enforcement. “What I can tell you is that the threat was communicated to schools through students reportedly viewing it on TikTok,” Jones said, adding that police were following through with an investigation. “The fact that the origin of the threat has not been determined has led us to be proactive in our desire to be cautious to keep our kids and families safe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sr9qfh"&gt;At least one police department says it viewed a message threatening a school on Friday: Police in Gilroy, California &lt;a href="http://nixle.us/alert/9144787/"&gt;describe a threatening post&lt;/a&gt; that included initials matching a local high school, and school was canceled as a result. But police say they later determined the post was actually about a different high school in Los Angeles. The Los Angeles School Police Department identified who posted it, they said, and determined he was not a “credible threat.” Gilroy police didn’t say whether the post was made on TikTok. The Los Angeles School Police Department and the Gilroy Police Department did not immediately respond to requests for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHDWI3"&gt;School districts have dealt with dangerous rumors going viral on TikTok before. This year, there was concern about a “slap a teacher” challenge, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3aq3e5/slap-a-teacher-tiktok-challenge-hoax"&gt;which turned out to be fake&lt;/a&gt;. Another supposed challenge dared kids to steal items from their school; in that case, some students actually followed through — though others, it turned out, were just &lt;a href="https://www.curbed.com/2021/09/the-grown-up-hysteria-around-tiktoks-devious-licks-trend.html"&gt;pretended to take things&lt;/a&gt; to get in on the trend.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840621/tiktok-december-17-school-threats-district-cancellations-alleged-shootings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840621/tiktok-december-17-school-threats-district-cancellations-alleged-shootings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T20:46:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T20:46:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>FTC opens antitrust probe into Meta’s purchase of VR fitness app Supernatural</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KF6XqMiPf_vdDmE4BU3x9oDyrsE=/0x4:2160x1444/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70284319/Supernatural_VR.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EnIbqZ"&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission has opened an in-depth antitrust probe of Meta’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753403/supernatural-within-studio-facebook-meta-oculus-vr-fitness-experiences-metaverse"&gt;plan to buy the popular VR fitness app Supernatural&lt;/a&gt;, according &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/ftc-slows-meta-platforms-metaverse-strategy-by-extending-antitrust-probe-of-vr-deal?utm_source=ti_app&amp;amp;rc=k5vrz1"&gt;to a new report by &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AUXFEt"&gt;The probe means that antitrust regulators are starting to scrutinize the-company-formally-known-as-Facebook’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22537795/is-facebook-cornering-the-vr-market"&gt;interest in scooping up VR startups&lt;/a&gt;, not just its traditional social media acquisitions. According to &lt;em&gt;The Information’s &lt;/em&gt;Josh Sisco, Meta’s previous five virtual reality acquisitions, including its deal for the studio behind hit game &lt;em&gt;Beat Saber&lt;/em&gt;, weren't probed by the government because the purchase prices were too small. “But those regulators are slowing down the $400 million-plus Supernatural deal, according to two people with knowledge of the situation,” the report notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBYLQq"&gt;It’s unclear what criteria the FTC, which is simultaneously suing Meta in a bid to unwind the acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp, is using to evaluate the VR deal. VR is a nascent but fast-growing industry that third-party estimates say Meta has a majority market share of, thanks mostly to the early success of its Quest 2 headset. While the FTC might eventually approve the Supernatural deal, its decision to investigate signals that Meta’s playbook of quickly buying the hottest VR startups on its platform may already be coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840635/ftc-opens-antitrust-probe-meta-deal-vr-fitness-app-supernatural"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840635/ftc-opens-antitrust-probe-meta-deal-vr-fitness-app-supernatural</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T18:33:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T18:33:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 will no longer have NFTs after fan outcry</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FbPxxc45qbR4Q667wib3mLae1Xk=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70283878/ss_3b56a4aea69f1d49d4871eeb1913f460f067a138.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GSC Game World has scrapped its plans for NFTs in &lt;/em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: GSC Game World&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dgKLMj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chernobyl&lt;/em&gt; will no longer include NFTs, developer GSC Game World &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stalker_thegame/status/1471620399997886472"&gt;announced Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. The news arrives after a heavily criticized announcement Wednesday and after the studio posted and then deleted an explanation on Thursday that initially tried to explain it would, in fact, still have NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5eQnq5"&gt;“Based on the feedback we received, we’ve made a decision to cancel anything NFT-related in &lt;em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2&lt;/em&gt;,” the new statement says. “The interests of our fans and players are the top priority for the team. We’re making this game for you to enjoy — whatever the cost is. If you care, we care too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OcGmlC"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/mffnmpiQiw"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mffnmpiQiw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— S.T.A.L.K.E.R. OFFICIAL (@stalker_thegame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stalker_thegame/status/1471620399997886472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qPGkOp"&gt;GSC Game World had announced Wednesday that it would be partnering with NFT platform DMarket on digital items for the game. One of the NFTs it had planned to offer would have allowed the owner &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22834567/stalker-2-nfts-metahuman-dmarket"&gt;to become a “metahuman,”&lt;/a&gt; which actually meant they’d be turned into an NPC in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lLxJ6"&gt;Now, those plans are scrapped. I guess this explains why the studio deleted its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840383/stalker-2-developer-explain-nfts-gsc-game-world-deleted-tweet"&gt;earlier tweet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MWuh0O"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840488/stalker-2-nft-metahuman-gsc-web3-canceled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840488/stalker-2-nft-metahuman-gsc-web3-canceled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T18:05:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T18:05:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Read the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 developer’s deleted explanation for why you’re getting NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q2fqs1yOiltD5WxR3elJR9hAjLM=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70283780/ss_6a0d30d5fad86c12df46e59042efb55c9a4a3b53.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GSC Game World deleted a tweet elaborating why it plans to offer NFTs.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: GSC Game World&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0SYqpL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 16th, 6:44PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; 11 minutes after we posted this story, GSC Game World announced it was canceling &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840488/stalker-2-nft-metahuman-gsc-web3-canceled"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“anything NFT-related in &lt;/em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; Guess that explains why the earlier explanation was deleted. Our original story follows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="e2Iruk"&gt;
&lt;p id="QsA7uB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chernobyl&lt;/em&gt; developer GSC Game World posted a now-deleted statement on Twitter elaborating on its widely criticized &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22834567/stalker-2-nfts-metahuman-dmarket"&gt;plans to add NFTs to the game&lt;/a&gt;. In short, the company said it will be using funds earned from the NFTs to help with development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tU5Rsk"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chernobyl&lt;/em&gt; is truly the biggest and the most complex game we have ever created,” GSC Game World said. “All the funds that we earn during the development process (including the potential income from NFT) will be spent on improving the long-awaited game to make it even better.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fXmleqcEh9gVI-BE2T-RBfPtBN0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23102587/slack_imgs.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: GSC Game World&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GSC Game World’s now deleted statement addressing its plans to add NFTs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gbYE23"&gt;On Wednesday, the developer revealed it would be partnering with NFT platform DMarket on the virtual items. As part of its NFT plans, GSC Game World said it would be offering NFTs that allowed the owners to become a “metahuman,” or an NPC added to the game in their likeness. In its Thursday update, GSC Game World downplayed the role of those NPCs, saying they “aren’t even involved in the story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3HonLN"&gt;The company had previously been vague about its other planned NFTs, but GSC Game World shared more information in the deleted statement about what’s to come, acknowledging that after the metahuman, “some of you thought we would go a bit too far from here.” Here’s what’s apparently coming down the pike: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6Za2pb"&gt;We are going to implement (nick)names of the owners on some in-game desks / walls / etc. (please remember it’s a large open world we’re talking about), gloves / tattoos, skins / badges for the multiplayer mode (releasing as a free update after the story campaign) and collectible cards (DMarket platform only, no integration in &lt;em&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4MvrzB"&gt;The studio ended its Thursday statement by saying, “Please accept our apologies for yesterday’s miscommunication and all the feelings it caused. We know that you wish only the best for our game, and we appreciate it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kD5dDI"&gt;GSC Game World didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment about the deleted statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vqh4zw"&gt;This month, there has been a wave of video game NFT announcements. Ubisoft launched its own heavily criticized &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822410/ubisoft-nfts-quartz-digits-ghost-recon-breakpoint"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Recon: Breakpoint&lt;/em&gt; NFTs&lt;/a&gt;, some of which require &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stephentotilo/status/1469051945490993162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1470107122239262724%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es2_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fkotaku.com%2Fembed%2Finset%2Fiframe%3Fid%3Dtwitter-1470107122239262724autosize%3D1"&gt;hundreds of hours of gameplay&lt;/a&gt; be claimed. Peter Molyneux also revealed details about a business simulator where people can buy an NFT &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22832188/peter-molyneux-22cans-gala-nft-blockchain-business-simulator-game-interview"&gt;actually called “Land.”&lt;/a&gt; The virtual plots have already pulled in more than $54 million in total, &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/peter-molyneux-nft-game-sells-plot-for-900k"&gt;according to &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/12/peter-molyneux-raises-54m-on-promise-of-play-to-earn-nft-game-legacy/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840383/stalker-2-developer-explain-nfts-gsc-game-world-deleted-tweet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840383/stalker-2-developer-explain-nfts-gsc-game-world-deleted-tweet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T18:03:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T18:03:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are a go-to pick that’s often on sale&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HYaZ7v"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday may have come and gone, but there are still some great discounts available on Apple’s AirPods. In fact, we’ve actually been seeing some deals that are even better than they were during the recent shopping holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SziSp1"&gt;Since Apple launched the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third-gen AirPods&lt;/a&gt; in October and unveiled its new AirPods lineup, we’ve seen the starting price of the second-gen, entry-level model drop from $159 to $129. Even better, we’ve seen many retailers starting to heavily discount the second-gen AirPods as well as the more expensive AirPods Pro and Max, which offer noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard model. We’ve even recently seen some significant discounts on the third-gen AirPods, despite how recently they launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the best deals available on each model, including the entry-level AirPods, the AirPods Pro, the third-gen AirPods, and the AirPods Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UJyTOI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on MacBooks right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"},{"title":"Which AirPods should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="VFDHZw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10742787"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ej2msf"&gt;The best entry-level &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt; (second-gen) deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eg29V6"&gt;Once $159, Apple recently lowered the list price of the second-gen AirPods — now the entry-level model — to $129. It only sells the model with a wired charging case, however, which charges via a standard Lightning cable. Despite their age, we found these easy-to-use earbuds offer great wireless performance and reliable battery life, making them a great pick if you can live without a wireless charging case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtXs0h"&gt;Right now, Apple’s most affordable pair of AirPods are selling for their lowest price to date. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has discounted the earbuds to $89.99 (with delayed shipping), which is less than what we saw them go for on Black Friday and Cyber Monday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;AirPods (third-gen)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="d2yjBK"&gt;The newest pair of wireless earbuds support Apple’s MagSafe technology. The short stems yield a more subtle design, while improved sound and features like sweat and water resistance, support for spatial audio with dynamic head tracking, and improved battery life render them a nice improvement over the last-gen model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QiPrKN"&gt;Deals were once hard to come by on the third-gen model, but we finally started seeing some significant deals starting around Black Friday and Cyber Monday. In fact, like the second-gen AirPods, they’re currently selling for less than they were last month. At the moment, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is selling the $179 earbuds for $139.99, yet, just like their predecessor, with delayed shipping. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FAirPods-3rd-generation%2F510546422&amp;amp;sharedid=VergeBestAirPodsdeals1222021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; is also discounting the third-gen model, but only by $10 or so. You will, however, be able to get the earbuds in time for the holidays, if you intend to use them as a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q2OXRZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10744075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Iewbkw"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="S8o5q4"&gt;We think Apple’s premium true wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, are the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; an iPhone owner can buy, regardless of the price. They have better sound quality than the models above, offer active noise cancellation, and come with a wireless charging case. The earbuds also support Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; feature, which adds an immersive surround sound effect to select content, and come with swappable silicone tips. In addition, they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713126/airpods-pro-conversation-boost-firmware-update"&gt;recently received a firmware&lt;/a&gt; update that added Conversation Boost, an accessibility feature for those who are hard of hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bM8uVd"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"&gt;recently launched a new version&lt;/a&gt; of the AirPods Pro with a wireless charging case that supports Apple’s MagSafe technology, just like the third-gen AirPods. These start at $249, but you can buy them right now for $169 in-store at Staples until December 18th. If you miss out on that deal, they’re also going for $179 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQMJHXY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and $179.99 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-pro-with-magsafe%2F-%2FA-77603773&amp;amp;subid1=Verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. That’s not quite as low as the $159 price we saw this model drop to during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, but it’s still roughly a $70 discount off the cost you’d pay through Apple directly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="THtgJp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x5NHYH"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ESUeUd"&gt;The AirPods Max aren’t the iconic in-ear style that has become synonymous with the AirPods name. They’re large and luxurious, comprised of aluminum, steel, and mesh fabric that remains comfortable during extended listening sessions. They also sport excellent noise cancellation, Apple’s spatial audio feature, and a wide, balanced sound, even if they lag behind some of their peers when it comes to bass response. They’re not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;best noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for most people — blame the $550 sticker price — but it’s hard to find a pair of Bluetooth headphones that sound better and feature more intuitive controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBAAwB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="irGZgJ"&gt;Although the AirPods Max were discounted to $429 at Amazon during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, prices have since increased. Still, the Max are currently selling for around $479 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-AirPods-Max-Space/dp/B08PZHYWJS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfThsYtSLBr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1610235-REG%2Fapple_mgyn3am_a_airpods_max_green.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, saving you $70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Mpx47T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T17:42:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T17:42:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton rival Echelon’s new connected bike is fit for the club</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Echelon’s EX-8S against a dark background and blue LED flywheels" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-YuPO_T-aOJ3qgY7DMKW5UwYR4s=/0x197:3676x2648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70283671/Echelon_ex_8s_product_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behold, the EX-8S&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Echelon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oWVBtB"&gt;While Peloton is the most familiar name in connected fitness, Echelon’s bikes are probably the ones you’ve seen before without noticing. Echelon’s bikes are among the first that pop up when you google “cheaper Peloton alternative,” and it’s also the company behind Walmart’s $497 connected bike. (You might also remember them from last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452145/amazon-prime-bike-500-disavow-echelon-fitness-peleton-competitor"&gt;Amazon Prime Bike debacle&lt;/a&gt;.) Well, now one of Peloton’s biggest rivals is back with a new premium bike — the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fechelonfit.com%2Fpages%2Fechelon-ex-8s&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840197%2Fechelon-ex-8s-bike-peloton-curved-touchscreen-led" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;EX-8S&lt;/a&gt;, and it is extremely extra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5G2UBL"&gt;For starters, the bike sports a 24-inch 1080p curved touchscreen. Echelon says that’s to create a more immersive experience and that the screen itself also flips open 180-degrees for off-bike workouts. It’s also got not one but two light-up flywheels that can be customized by color and lighting pattern thanks to 15 LED lights — just in case you want to recreate that whole “I’m biking in a club” feeling from SoulCycle and other boutique cycling studios. During a briefing, an Echelon spokesperson confirmed you can see the lighting while you’re on the bike itself and that it’s also possible to sync them to your workout metrics. The company also claims that the two-flywheel design gives the bike better stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1p9VLW"&gt;If it looks like a light-up Peloton, that’s not a coincidence. Echelon says the bike was designed by Eric Villency, who designed the original Peloton bike and the SoulCycle bike. The bike also features 32 levels of motorized magnetic resistance. While most bikes rely on a resistance knob to tweak difficulty levels, the EX-8S also has a patent-pending digital resistance controller built into the handlebar. According to Echelon, this is so riders can easily adjust resistance while in third position (pedaling while standing). The bike itself weighs 125lbs and can support riders up to 300lbs. As for connectivity, the EX-8S also supports Wi-Fi and Bluetooth. It’s also compatible with SPD pedals. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P_xymY9ndJMnMsFg13ztqLtws9M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23102366/Echelon_ex_8s_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Echelon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like Peloton’s Bike Plus, the EX-8S’s screen rotates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CpKtHY"&gt;That said, connected fitness also heavily leans on its content, and Echelon’s content library hasn’t always been as polished as its competitors. On that front, Echelon says it’s adding new fitness programs and challenges in 2022, along with “more immersive multimedia experiences” like music videos, performances, and artist spotlights. That apparently includes former NFL athletes joining rides, spotlights from artists like Lady Gaga and Norah Jones, as well as Broadway shows like &lt;em&gt;Phantom of the Opera &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Dear Evan Hansen&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DXhiG2"&gt;Is the bike itself a tad ridiculous? Yes. It’s unclear who exactly sits in the Venn diagram of LED bike lovers and &lt;em&gt;Dear Evan Hansen&lt;/em&gt;. However, Peloton’s had a rocky quarter, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22778851/peloton-growing-pains-connected-fitness-tonal-hydrow-mirror"&gt;competition in connected fitness is amping up&lt;/a&gt;. Echelon releasing a premium bike just ahead of CES 2022 also hints the company might be hoping to make a big splash at the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xo1Psa"&gt;The EX-8S isn’t &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fechelonfit.com%2Fpages%2Fechelon-ex-8s&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22840197%2Fechelon-ex-8s-bike-peloton-curved-touchscreen-led" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available just yet&lt;/a&gt; but will retail at $2,399 along with a $34.99 monthly subscription to Echelon’s digital content. That’s a good deal more expensive than Echelon’s other bikes, especially its $497 &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FEchelon-Connect-Sport-Indoor-Cycling-Exercise-Bike-with-90-Day-Free-Premier-Membership-105-Value%2F533034706&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart-exclusive bike&lt;/a&gt; — though that only has a tablet holder. Echelon’s other connected bikes cost between $899.99 and $1,599.99. The company says pre-sales through January 15 will get a discounted price of $1,999.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840197/echelon-ex-8s-bike-peloton-curved-touchscreen-led"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840197/echelon-ex-8s-bike-peloton-curved-touchscreen-led</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T17:10:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T17:10:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Babble Royale turns Scrabble into Fortnite</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pNShDZuvD9HZTSphyRXwIwZ5ILI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70283572/ss_dfbfbf247467f68361989aa1eaeb1944e4d31a78.1920x1080.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JxQ5az"&gt;There used to be a joke that every game was turning into a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;-style battle royale, and here to make that bit a reality is &lt;em&gt;Babble Royale,&lt;/em&gt; a new Scrabble-style competitive online multiplayer game from designer Frank Lantz’s Everybody House Games (best known for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2017/10/11/16457742/ai-paperclips-thought-experiment-game-frank-lantz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Universal Paperclips&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21203463/hey-robot-smart-speaker-alexa-siri-google-assistant-web-free-quarantine"&gt;Hey Robot&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YtZHVU"&gt;Despite the fact that it feels like a joke meant to clown on Fortnite, PUGB, and other last-person-standing games in the genre, &lt;em&gt;Babble Royale &lt;/em&gt;is very much a real game, currently available on Steam in early access for both PC and Mac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1dJpyJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Babble Royale is now live in early access! I think it's the funnest game I've ever worked on. Come see for yourself.&lt;a href="https://t.co/5vxJDAlYXD"&gt;https://t.co/5vxJDAlYXD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/N6WGBpB8AM"&gt;pic.twitter.com/N6WGBpB8AM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Frank Lantz (@flantz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/flantz/status/1471192145453215745?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="emrTSK"&gt;Players parachute their beginning tile down into a grid (yes, actually), claiming a spot for themselves to start building words (as you would in Scrabble or Bananagrams) to expand outwards and eliminate other players. As you explore the map, you can spell your way onto tiles to pick up powerups or purchase additional upgrades using money gained by spelling bigger words. As time goes on, a “hot zone” will slowly creep in from the corner of the map, damaging or eliminating players from contention until only one speller reigns supreme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PdHXa0"&gt;And of course, there are optional cosmetics available to purchase to customize your character (i.e., the letter you parachute in with) with different patterns or hats. Yes, seriously. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/54GFvBDRrn4AtjvPwExAJlBGRww=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23102448/ss_79f91b9d34922f7511aa1c7c0987ab9d1014a003.1920x1080.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the world we live in now.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sHO4nX"&gt;I tried playing a few rounds of &lt;em&gt;Babble Royale&lt;/em&gt;, but while the concept is fun as a high-brow joke on the genre, I bounced off pretty hard on the actual gameplay. You can only play new letters off the last word that you spelled, which means that longtime Scrabble players will have to seriously think about how they play. There were also times where I just was plain stuck, walled in by existing words but unable to play any real ones of my own, leaving me to sit around until the game cleared out some of the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lYqH54"&gt;But for those who like competitive word games and don’t mind taking the time to adjust to &lt;em&gt;Babble Royale’s&lt;/em&gt; new strategies and idiosyncrasies, the new title is certainly one of the cleverest spins on the concept so far. The initial launch of &lt;em&gt;Babble Royale&lt;/em&gt; is also still in “Season Zero” as an early access launch, with more features and content planned for the future, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cln7VP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1759440/Babble_Royale/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Babble Royale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is available to download for free now on Steam. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839745/babble-royale-scrabble-fortnite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839745/babble-royale-scrabble-fortnite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
