<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-10T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Check, Please is the feel-good queer hockey / baking comic you didn’t know you needed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8nF4nb69qccm7c1LsXZn3b0cTak=/0x5:1300x872/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106059/CheckPlease_Banner_1300x875_b13a84c2_318e_4200_b50a_eb042de304ed_1300x.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Ngozi Ukazu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f6wu9V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comics have never been bigger: with Marvel TV shows, DC movies, and indie adaptations growing by the day, comic books have never been more prominent in pop culture. This biweekly Verge column recommends comic series new and old, whether you’re a longtime fan or a newcomer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r2KOhu"&gt;Comics can be pretty depressing these days. Existential drama, dark storylines, and epic battles for the fate of the galaxy are all regular occurrences. But on the other side of the spectrum is &lt;em&gt;Check, Please&lt;/em&gt;, a heartwarming hockey comic that’s the feel-good equivalent of a slice of warm apple pie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tWTpnz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is it? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check, Please&lt;/em&gt; is a webcomic / graphic novel by Ngozi Ukazu. It’s set across the four years of college for Eric “Bitty” Bittle, a gay NCAA hockey player at the fictional Samwell University. He is &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a baking vlogger who loves to make pies and basically anything else. The comic’s name is a pun — “check,” like the hockey move that Bittle is terrified of as a former figure skater and “check, please” like what a customer might say at a diner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIbApm"&gt;The comic spans Bittle’s time on the Samwell Men’s Hockey team, and it has something for everyone. Sports action? Check. An honest and cute queer romance? Check. Drama? Check. Baked goods? Double check. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L0sJ5RrpUk7Ra6hBesWB3gZDR0U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22433325/CheckPlease_2.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ngozi Ukazu&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yxBDLd"&gt;Rounding out the cast is Jack, the captain of the team and son of a former NHL legend with his own struggles, along with the rest of the team: a group of the nicest, most diverse, fun-loving college bros that you’ll wish you could have partied with in real life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JGONmh"&gt;The comic bounces from lighthearted to serious from chapter to chapter. One might deal with Bittle coming out to friends or family, another a triumphant hockey game, and a third with the team just hanging out at a diner. Ukazu gives everything its fair attention. A raucous party is treated as important as a visit from Bittle’s parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LIlo5W"&gt;Adding to everything is the incredible artwork: Ukazu’s art is perfect for the tone, with friendly characters and warm colors that help further build out the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="asI1Oq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who’s it by? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check, Please&lt;/em&gt; is written and illustrated by Ngozi Ukazu. Ukazu also ran an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/omgcheckplease?lang=en"&gt;in-universe Twitter account for Bittle&lt;/a&gt; during the run of the comic for an added dimension to the story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vayofh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can I read it? &lt;/strong&gt;You can read &lt;em&gt;Check, Please&lt;/em&gt; for free in its webcomic form through &lt;a href="https://www.checkpleasecomic.com/comic/01-01-01"&gt;Ukazu’s website&lt;/a&gt; or pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Check-Please-Hockey-Ngozi-Ukazu/dp/1250177960?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two-volume&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Check-Please-Book-Sticks-Scones/dp/1250179505?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;graphic novel&lt;/a&gt; (which features updated art and some additional content) if you prefer your comics in print. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22375972/check-please-queer-hockey-baking-comic-recommendation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22375972/check-please-queer-hockey-baking-comic-recommendation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T09:59:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T09:59:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic antitrust case versus Apple in Australia gets three-month stay </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CGTM665yR__G3wga7bj27k3Pf-Y=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106057/apple_fortnite_1984_parody.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image by Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qF227E"&gt;An Australian judge has ruled that Epic’s lawsuit against Apple in Australia will be temporarily suspended as the two sides prepare for a trial in the US, &lt;a href="https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2021/04/epic-vs-apple-australia-court-case-temporarily-suspended/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gizmodo Australia&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. Apple had &lt;a href="https://www.kotaku.com.au/2021/03/apple-tried-to-kill-epics-australian-fortnite-lawsuit-this-week/"&gt;asked for a permanent stay&lt;/a&gt; of the case in Australia, arguing that the US and Australia cases were very similar, and that the matter should be settled in the original jurisdiction of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="umZUrn"&gt;The two companies are fighting over Epic’s battle royale game &lt;em&gt;Fortnite, &lt;/em&gt;and the fees Apple charges&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; In August, Epic set up its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366259/epic-fortnite-vbucks-mega-drop-discount-iphone-android"&gt;own in-game payments system,&lt;/a&gt; effectively circumventing Apple’s App Store payments and avoiding the 30 percent surcharge Apple collects on App Store purchases. Apple then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments"&gt;removed &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; from its iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt; for violating its rules. Epic fired back with an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367963/epic-fortnite-legal-complaint-apple-ios-app-store-removal-injunctive-relief"&gt;antitrust lawsuit seeking to establish Apple’s App Store as a monopoly&lt;/a&gt; and tried to rally &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; fans with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367924/watch-epic-nineteen-eighty-fortnite-short-apple-app-store-ban"&gt;protest video&lt;/a&gt; mocking Apple’s iconic “1984” ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k6PyAm"&gt;In November, Epic filed a &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/epic-games-files-legal-proceedings-against-google-in-australia"&gt;similar legal claim&lt;/a&gt; against Apple in Australia, saying the iPhone maker’s conduct was “unconscionable, and breaches the Australian Consumer Law as well as various sections of the Competition and Consumer Act [of] 2010.” Epic has also filed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323100/epic-google-australia-legal-claim-fortnite-play-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;similar claims against Google&lt;/a&gt; and its mobile app store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cLQHTl"&gt;Australian Judge Nye Perram ordered Friday that the case in that country be temporarily stayed for three months. He also said the proceedings will continue to be suspended in Australia if Epic continues to pursue its case in the US, but could bring the case back to Australian courts depending on the outcome in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="clF5lN"&gt;On Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;Apple and Epic filed proposed findings of fact documents&lt;/a&gt; for the US court case, which is set to open in California on May 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dvDPV4"&gt;Neither Epic nor Apple immediately replied to requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Saturday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2Pnu3O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fortnite vs. Apple and Google: everything you need to know about Epic’s mobile app stores fight","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377047/epic-case-apple-australia-temporary-stay-fortnite-app-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377047/epic-case-apple-australia-temporary-stay-fortnite-app-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T09:13:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T09:13:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Logitech officially discontinues its Harmony remotes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UoBIA92PUa0RZmK-mZtE6SpbSZE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69105937/jbareham_160729_1150_0031.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SAW6qz"&gt;Logitech said Friday it is discontinuing its line of Harmony universal remotes, ending years of speculation that the devices were on their way out. Models that are currently in stock at retailers will be available while supplies last, and the company says it will continue to provide support and service for the Harmony remote “as long as customers are using it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAfPQZ"&gt;“While Harmony remotes are and continue to be available through various retailers, moving forward Logitech will no longer manufacture Harmony remotes,” according to a&lt;a href="https://support.logi.com/hc/en-us/community/posts/1500000658341"&gt; blog post on Logitech’s support page&lt;/a&gt;. “We expect no impact to our customers by this announcement. We plan to support our Harmony community and new Harmony customers, which includes access to our software and apps to set up and manage your remotes. We also plan to continue to update the platform and add devices to our Harmony database. Customer and warranty support will continue to be offered.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2rmnj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ir.logitech.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2004/Logitech-Acquires-Intrigue-Technologies-Maker-of-Acclaimed-Harmony-Remote-Controls/default.aspx"&gt;Logitech acquired Intrigue Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, the original maker of the Harmony remote, back in 2004. Harmony universal remotes were popular among consumers seeking one remote to rule them all— cable box, gaming console, and streaming devices. Some newer models were even able to be used with smart home devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QgEOKl"&gt;Logitech’s business has boomed during the coronavirus pandemic as people worked and schooled at home; in January, &lt;a href="https://s1.q4cdn.com/104539020/files/doc_financials/2021/q3/Logitech-F3Q21-Prepared-Remarks.pdf"&gt;the company reported its third-quarter sales&lt;/a&gt; were up 85 percent year over year to $1.67 billion, enough that it could splurge on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22260033/logitech-pandemic-super-bowl-ad"&gt;its first-ever Super Bowl commercial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aUE2hb"&gt;But with the rise of streaming services over the past few years, universal remotes are no longer as crucial as they once were. Logitech CEO &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20905042/logitech-ceo-harmony-universal-remote-streaming-smart-tv-voice-assistant-bracken-darrell"&gt;Bracken Darrell told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 that Harmony was a small business for the company; he said the remote business was only about 6 percent of the size of Logitech’s massive keyboard business, for instance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxLzNr"&gt;“I think over time, you’ll have fewer and fewer people who feel like they really need that universal remote,” Darrell said at the time. He added that the company appreciated hardcore Harmony users who love the device: “it’s so rare to have users that love something as much as a lot of our Harmony users do. We’ll always take care of them because we really believe that that’s part of the responsibility of the brand,” Darrell told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “So we do love Harmony for that reason. How long it will be out there, I don’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h3KbA6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bx-group-1122947-nbXkQWD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0fFfz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NOBcxt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377015/logitech-discontinues-harmony-universal-remotes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377015/logitech-discontinues-harmony-universal-remotes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Celebrate your COVID vaccination with these off-the-wall tchotchkes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PDLi-SCVT3eZAVKsbcIzBaoKu_0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69105874/acastro_200428_1777_coronavirus_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7hHDhe"&gt;Photographs of people getting triumphantly vaccinated against COVID-19 are all over social networks, as are announcements of upcoming appointments, first and second injections, and how well (or badly) they reacted to the vaccine. Like births, weddings, and graduations, the act of getting your Pfizer, Moderna, or Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson injection has become a cause for public celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74NCUs"&gt;So don’t you want something to mark the occasion? A souvenir of the first indication that you can begin to think seriously about hugging your relatives, entering a store without tension, and even &amp;lt;gasp!&amp;gt; eating comfortably in a restaurant?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9bkd1"&gt;Sites such as Etsy, Zazzle, and Redbubble are overflowing with T-shirts, hats, and buttons proclaiming “Fully Vaccinated,” “Hug me, I’m vaccinated,” “Vaccines cause adults,” and “Vaccinated AF.” (I just report these; I don’t write them.) There are necklaces, hats, toys, keychains, and cardholders. Okay, it’s a little weird, but still... So if you want to mark your future reentry into society with something to wear, hold, or just laugh at, here are a few samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ZGDFvE"&gt;
&lt;div id="c24OGR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437743" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="tOHOie"&gt;
&lt;div id="G2dhkL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437769"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Rg9Fha"&gt;
&lt;div id="Np86Dq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437821"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pwKrFa"&gt;
&lt;div id="QvNFUd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437995"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="S7X2C4"&gt;
&lt;div id="K3ueJ3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10438015"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="R9hDXA"&gt;
&lt;div id="ia4BS6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10438041"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8CdLpx"&gt;
&lt;div id="sRU8QV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10438056"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="QbcJYZ"&gt;
&lt;div id="jBzAsQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10438075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3Og5vL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22375608/covid-vaccination-pandemic-etsy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22375608/covid-vaccination-pandemic-etsy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T20:36:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T20:36:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Q Link Wireless made private customer information accessible with just a phone number</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aJb9u-kfluFGrk5cnoj9cYzkYHc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69104765/acastro_190228_1777_vpn_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5GNoTZ"&gt;A mobile carrier allowed anyone with one of its customers phone numbers to access their personal information, including name, address, phone number, and text and call history, according to &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/04/no-password-required-mobile-carrier-exposes-data-for-millions-of-accounts/?comments=1"&gt;a report by &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The carrier, Q Link Wireless, &lt;a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/south-florida-based-hello-mobile-beats-nationwide-prepaid-prices-1028340029"&gt;claimed to have over two million customers&lt;/a&gt; in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ETd9uD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoContract/comments/mkolj5/critical_security_issue_with_hellomobile_account/"&gt;noted a Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; saying that the app used by the carrier and its subsidiary Hello Mobile never asked for a password or any identifying information when the user was logging on with a phone number. Looking &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/my-mobile-account/id1408895511"&gt;through the reviews&lt;/a&gt;, there are references to the poor security practices (to put it mildly) going back to December of 2020. While it’s unclear when the credential-less login system appeared, there is an update note from two years ago that mentions an “updated login process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="apWHAE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A ton of information was available in the app, which didn’t ask for a password&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UKaEKS"&gt;The carrier has reportedly fixed the issue — though &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoContract/comments/mkolj5/critical_security_issue_with_hellomobile_account/gty65gj?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;it seems it may have done so&lt;/a&gt; by just turning off logins to the app altogether. Before the change, &lt;em&gt;Ars&lt;/em&gt; was able to see, but not change, a bevy of information from a Hello Mobile customer who volunteered their phone number, including their name, address, account number, email address, and which numbers they’d contacted or been contacted by. The last one is probably the most sensitive — while the contents of texts or phone calls weren’t shown, there’s still a lot of information that can be gleaned from knowing who you talked to and when you talked to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6J98r4"&gt;The app’s description mentions that it allows users to add more minutes or data to their plans, but it’s unclear if that required extra authentication. Regardless, there’s still a ton of information that was available to anyone able to get the phone number of one of Q Link Wireless’ customers. Reportedly, Q Link Wireless hasn’t notified its customers that their information had been accessible — which seems to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374464/linkedin-data-leak-500-million-accounts-scraped-microsoft"&gt;a worrying trend&lt;/a&gt; among companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372707/facebook-responds-533-million-data-leak-notify-users"&gt;that leak user data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmEFee"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars&lt;/em&gt; found no evidence that the security vulnerability was widely exploited, but having to worry about others having access to a ton of their sensitive data isn’t something that anyone needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ET8OCR"&gt;Q Link Wireless didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376452/q-link-wireless-hello-mobile-customer-data-unlocked-no-password-phone-number"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376452/q-link-wireless-hello-mobile-customer-data-unlocked-no-password-phone-number</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T20:23:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T20:23:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Firefox will no longer support Amazon’s Fire TV or Echo Show devices on April 30th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uI4m1Zg2ilRzrQCjM1nRH9TK_v8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69104734/dseifert_210219_4433_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H9L8qV"&gt;Firefox will no longer support Amazon Fire TV or Echo Show devices starting April 30th, Mozilla announced on Friday (&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/04/09/firefox-is-ending-support-for-amazon-fire-tv-and-echo-show-devices/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4n3pmQ"&gt;“You will no longer be able to install [Firefox] on FireTV, receive security updates, or be able to reinstall the app if you uninstall it starting on April 30, 2021,” &lt;a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/end-support-firefox-amazon-devices"&gt;Mozilla said in a support document&lt;/a&gt;. “If you have Firefox set as your default browser on Echo Show, you will be redirected to Amazon Silk for web browsing starting April 30, 2021.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cdc5Lz"&gt;Mozilla first brought Firefox to Fire TV devices in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/20/16801908/mozilla-firefox-amazon-fire-tv-app-google-youtube-feud"&gt;December 2017&lt;/a&gt;, giving Fire TV owners a way to watch YouTube in the midst of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/5/16738748/google-amazon-feud-youtube-pulled-off-fire-tv-echo-show-nest-devices"&gt;a bitter feud between Google and Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. In July 2019, however, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/9/20686773/youtube-fire-tv-prime-video-chromecast-amazon-google-launch-today-available"&gt;Google brought the YouTube app back to the Fire TV&lt;/a&gt;, giving users one less reason to use Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7TPq1"&gt;The Mozilla-made browser first came to Echo Show devices alongside Amazon’s Silk browser with the introduction &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/20/17883456/amazon-new-echo-show-2018-screen-features-price-fabric"&gt;Echo Show 10 in September 2018&lt;/a&gt;. There’s still no YouTube app for Echo Show, so the two browsers have offered a way to watch YouTube on the Amazon-made smart displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvfWdV"&gt;Mozilla now suggests using Silk to browse the web on Fire TV and Echo show devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mIMF9C"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"YouTube is back on the Fire TV, and Prime Video launches on Chromecast starting today","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/9/20686773/youtube-fire-tv-prime-video-chromecast-amazon-google-launch-today-available"},{"title":"Amazon introduces a redesigned Echo Show with a larger 10-inch display","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/20/17883456/amazon-new-echo-show-2018-screen-features-price-fabric"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376522/firefox-mozilla-ending-support-amazon-fire-tv-echo-show-google-youtube"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376522/firefox-mozilla-ending-support-amazon-fire-tv-echo-show-google-youtube</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T18:13:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T18:13:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lil Nas X released a Montero lo-fi remix to help you study for your Demonology test </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_RRssDjlhrMOz7tV4lIEf54TFTc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69104169/Screen_Shot_2021_04_09_at_2.31.17_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Lil Nas X&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mqeGBQ"&gt;In the latest virtuoso move to promote his hit song “Montero (Call Me By Your Name),” Lil Nas X posted &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dgh-zQJICbU"&gt;a lo-fi remix of the track to YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; Friday evening. According to his Twitter, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LilNasX/status/1380526435782127620"&gt;it’s his birthday&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems he has given us all this gift in celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MPO9Al"&gt;The video, which has the full title “Lil Nas X - MONTERO (Call Me By Your Name) but it’s lofi and something you can study to lol,” is honestly perfect. It sounds &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like something you’d hear on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSJ4gkVC6NrvII8umztf0Ow"&gt;Lofi Girl’s channel&lt;/a&gt;; if it ever gets slipped into the rotation on the channel’s iconic “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5qap5aO4i9A"&gt;lofi hip hop radio - beats to relax/study to&lt;/a&gt;” video, I wouldn’t bat an eye (ear?). Lil Nas X’s video even has five anime drawings of iconic looks from the rapper, clearly taking inspiration from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/11/22325348/youtooz-lofi-chill-anime-beats-chilled-cow-figurine"&gt;famous anime girl&lt;/a&gt; that is the face of the Lofi Girl channel.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uWEbHs"&gt;This genius lo-fi remix idea isn’t Lil Nas X’s first clever adaptation of the song that he’s posted to YouTube. At the end of March, he shared “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/54KlB1Fp9Ww"&gt;MONTERO but ur in the bathroom of hell while lil nas is giving satan a lap dance in the other room&lt;/a&gt;,” which is just as excellent as the lo-fi remix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WVnhfC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/54KlB1Fp9Ww?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5Q08e9"&gt;There’s also “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dPp1HUKNXio"&gt;Lil Nas X - MONTERO (Call Me By Your Name) [But Lil Nas X Is Silent The Entire Time]&lt;/a&gt;,” if you’re looking for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rUVkpC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPp1HUKNXio?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GntfI5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BSkRRT"&gt;Lil Nas X also released a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372657/lil-nas-x-twerk-hero-montero-call-me-by-your-name-browser-free-game"&gt;browser-based twerking game&lt;/a&gt; and partnered with MSCHF to release Satan Shoes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357225/nike-sues-lil-nas-x-unauthorized-satan-shoes-mschf"&gt;that Nike sued over&lt;/a&gt;. (Nike and MSCHF announced on Thursday that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374480/nike-mschf-lil-nas-x-unauthorized-satan-shoes-lawsuit-settled"&gt;they had settled&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FPbN3P"&gt;Just give this man all the Grammys already, we don’t even need to host the awards next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uoMoRc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Lil Nas X’s ‘Twerk Hero’ is a real game where you shake a virtual butt to Montero","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372657/lil-nas-x-twerk-hero-montero-call-me-by-your-name-browser-free-game"},{"title":"Nike and MSCHF settle Satan Shoe lawsuit, say any ‘confused’ buyers can get a refund","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374480/nike-mschf-lil-nas-x-unauthorized-satan-shoes-lawsuit-settled"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/9/22376309/lil-nas-x-montero-call-me-by-your-name-lo-fi-remix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/9/22376309/lil-nas-x-montero-call-me-by-your-name-lo-fi-remix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T17:25:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T17:25:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hasbro’s new $700 Optimus Prime toy can finally transform all on its own</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1WGZ9cBRCQEZ2-62CNRS3PaS5Jc=/64x0:577x342/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69103928/Apr_09_2021_17_13_10.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hgSpxM"&gt;Transformers are some of the most iconic toys around — an action figure &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a car! All in one! A true bargain! But as modern &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt; toys have gotten more complex, they have also become an &lt;a href="https://www.syfy.com/syfywire/think-transformers-toys-have-become-too-complicated-blame-michael-bay"&gt;absolutely huge pain&lt;/a&gt; to actually transform from car to robot and back again, often requiring multiple shame-filled trips back to the trashcan where you threw it in a fit of hubris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jeiqbQ"&gt;Hasbro is finally fixing that problem. Not by making the toys simpler, but by making them a lot more complicated &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; expensive in the form of its &lt;a href="https://hasbropulse.com/products/transformers-optimus-prime-auto-converting-programmable-advanced-robot-collectors-edition"&gt;new $700 Optimus Prime Auto-Converting Programmable Advanced Robot&lt;/a&gt;, which thanks to the power of real robotics technology (in the form of 27 servo motors and a mobile app) can actually transform all by itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kMJDnP"&gt;The new Transformer is almost breathtaking in its complexity: Hasbro says that the 19-inch figure features roughly 5,000 components, 27 patented servo motors, and 60 connected microchips in order to pull off the automated transforming feature. In addition to a mobile app, the new Optimus Prime toy also features voice commands that allow owners to control the transforming action or drive around the vehicle form by shouting things like “roll out” or “convert.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/06Fjsls8EqMOXsKArRIFeM1nrQs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22433527/Screen_Shot_2021_04_09_at_5.15.34_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hasbro&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Imaa6N"&gt;The downside of owning the first Transformer that can actually, y’know, transform on its own is the eye-watering price — for $700, the new Optimus Prime toy had better be able to fight off actual Decepticons to save the Earth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkloSO"&gt;The new model is being built in partnership with Robosen Robotics, which, &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22361383/optimus-prime-robot-toy-transformers-hasbro-robosen-robotics"&gt;as noted by &lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has been making suspiciously &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g5sPgeEEXRs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformer&lt;/em&gt;-looking motorized robots&lt;/a&gt; for years. The  new collaboration with Hasbro, though, gives Robosen the chance to bring its skills to an official Transformer product instead of a look-alike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDqw7h"&gt;The Optimus Prime Auto-Converting Programmable Advanced Robot is available to preorder now from the Hasbro Pulse website for $699.99. Orders are expected to ship on August 2nd. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376256/hasbro-700-optimus-prime-toy-transform-motor-automatic-voice-command"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376256/hasbro-700-optimus-prime-toy-transform-motor-automatic-voice-command</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T16:13:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T16:13:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>DuckDuckGo promises to block Google’s latest ad-tracking tech — if Google allows it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L_2IT52stOdEcY77jm6-7hNTtu0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69103512/acastro_200218_3900_StoryStream_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4vZW73"&gt;Google is &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/google-testing-its-controversial-new-ad-targeting-tech-millions-browsers-heres"&gt;just starting to test&lt;/a&gt; its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21064698/google-third-party-cookies-chrome-two-years-privacy-safari-firefox"&gt;replacement for third-party cookies&lt;/a&gt;, but DuckDuckGo is &lt;a href="https://spreadprivacy.com/block-floc-with-duckduckgo/"&gt;already announcing that it wants to block that tech&lt;/a&gt; with its Chrome extension. Google’s FLoC, or Federated Learning of Cohorts, technology is designed to be a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310332/google-privacy-replacing-third-party-cookies-privacy-sandbox"&gt;more privacy-centered way&lt;/a&gt; to track users and serve ads to them, but some privacy advocates, like the Electronic Frontier Foundation, have &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/googles-floc-terrible-idea"&gt;claimed that it could be harmful to consumers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0CJvSo"&gt;We have a great explainer on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358287/privacy-ads-google-chrome-floc-cookies-cookiepocalypse-finger-printing"&gt;what FLoC is&lt;/a&gt; for those who want to go in-depth, but the overview is that the tech works to sort users into groups based on their behavior. Advertisers can then target those groups instead of individual people. Privacy advocates argue that, while it’s better than the third-party cookie situation, FLoC IDs could still be bad for consumers, containing potentially sensitive information as well as providing another data point that lets advertisers individually identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BgN3rz"&gt;DuckDuckGo says that it agrees with those concerns &lt;a href="https://spreadprivacy.com/block-floc-with-duckduckgo/"&gt;in its blog post&lt;/a&gt; where it also announced that the latest version of its Chrome extension would prevent websites from tracking users via their FLoC identification. Of course, the company notes that the extension update will have to be approved by Google before it becomes available to its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qk7RS9"&gt;In addition to the extension update, DuckDuckGo says its search engine will opt out of collecting FLoC IDs and using them to identify or advertise to users, regardless of whether you’re using its Chrome extension. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irGph8"&gt;The stance isn’t surprising for a Google competitor, especially one that uses privacy as one of its main selling points. However, it does speak to the idea that FLoC will not be universally accepted — like with third-party tracking cookies before it, FLoC may be destined to become part of an arms race between advertisers and users who don’t want to be tracked. The technology isn’t even out of the testing phase yet, and other companies are already looking to block it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376110/duckduckgo-privacy-floc-block-chrome-extension-advertising-tech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376110/duckduckgo-privacy-floc-block-chrome-extension-advertising-tech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T16:00:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T16:00:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple refuses request to testify for Senate app store hearing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i4ilqchlztE6YxiGVW2_jo2uWy8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69103463/acastro_190322_1777_apple_streaming_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="78tDaB"&gt;Senate Judiciary Committee leaders are demanding that Apple provide a witness for an upcoming hearing on app stores and digital competition after the iPhone manufacturer has refused to participate, according to a new letter to the company released Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imbRdT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.klobuchar.senate.gov/public/_cache/files/6/e/6e3e8f7c-adf3-4f0a-ae4d-429ebdee5e7b/EBBA9ECB053293C7011FBA308652C607.2021.04.09-ltr-to-tcook-apple.pdf"&gt;In the letter addressed&lt;/a&gt; to Apple CEO Tim Cook, Sens. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) and Mike Lee (R-UT) say the company “abruptly” decided not to provide a witness for an April hearing on digital markets focused on Apple’s App Store and the Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RT3z2o"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple abruptly declared that it would not provide any witness”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8h7rdt"&gt;“Apple has been aware for weeks that the Subcommittee was planning a hearing on this topic and was engaged in discussions with our staff regarding who would testify on Apple’s behalf,” the senators wrote to Apple Friday. “Yet a little more than two weeks [16 days] before the planned hearing, Apple abruptly declared that it would not provide any witness to testify at a hearing in April.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhNpZ6"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZSug3"&gt;Apple’s App Store practices have been under intense scrutiny by lawmakers over the last year. In 2019, the House Judiciary Committee launched an investigation into competition in the tech industry, including Apple’s App Store. Throughout the probe, lawmakers homed in on the 30 percent fees Apple charges app developers. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21295778/apple-app-store-hey-email-fees-policies-antitrust-wwdc-2020"&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;interview last June&lt;/a&gt;, Chairman David Cicilline (D-RI) called the practice “highway robbery.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mvbzcQ"&gt;The criticism extends to the app developers themselves. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;publisher Epic Games sued Apple last year, accusing the company of violating US antitrust laws after it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;removed the popular battle royale&lt;/a&gt; game from the App Store. The trial is set to begin on May 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n3jmNZ"&gt;“Apple’s sudden change in course to refuse to provide a witness to testify before the Subcommittee on app store competition issues in April, when the company is clearly willing to discuss them in other public forums, is unacceptable,” the senators wrote. “We strongly urge Apple to reconsider its position and to provide a witness to testify before the Subcommittee in a timely manner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Elx5N3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376127/apple-senate-judiciary-hearing-klobuchar-app-store-google-play-antitrust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22376127/apple-senate-judiciary-hearing-klobuchar-app-store-google-play-antitrust</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
