<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-25T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple AirPods (third-gen) review: new design, same appeal</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The new regular AirPods get a lot right even before the gimmicky spatial audio part&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mYTlYX"&gt;For the first time since their introduction in 2016, Apple’s AirPods have a completely new design. The third-generation AirPods, priced at $179, bear a much closer resemblance to the AirPods Pro than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/20/14016568/apple-airpods-wireless-earpods-earbuds-review"&gt;long-stemmed original&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;second-gen pairs&lt;/a&gt;. Apple has upgraded their sound, added new features like spatial audio head tracking, made them more durable with IPX4 water resistance, and lengthened their battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFDLaT"&gt;What remains unchanged about the AirPods is their ease of use and deep integration with Apple’s ecosystem of devices including the iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple TV, and Apple Watch. If you’re living in Apple’s world, you still get exclusive features like the intuitive, just-hold-them-near-your-iPhone setup, audio sharing, automatic device switching, and other software tricks that have helped the AirPods stay atop the true wireless earbuds market by a wide margin. The third-generation AirPods also gain more extensive Find My support to help you locate them if they go missing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iup0oN"&gt;The AirPods Pro and AirPods Max didn’t even exist the last time Apple refreshed its standard AirPods. So the third-gen earbuds also establish more feature parity across the entire lineup. There are definitely still reasons to pick those products instead — active noise cancellation, namely — but anyone who’s ready to upgrade their original AirPods will find a lot to like with the new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LWOCkg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10826364"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="444ptP"&gt;These AirPods basically look like the AirPods Pro with their ear tips chopped off. They share similar contours, especially now that Apple has shortened the stems by 33 percent. There are also grilled black speakers, mics, and vents around each earbud. These hardware elements have become so prominent that I’m surprised Apple isn’t offering the new AirPods in black to help camouflage them. But nope: they still only come in white. Since their design is now so similar, Apple carried over the “force sensor” controls from the AirPods Pro, with an indent on each stem that designates where to press. The tap gestures from the old AirPods are gone. Apple’s non-remappable controls handle media playback, and you can summon Siri with a long press. But you’ve also got hands-free “Hey Siri” voice commands at your disposal for adjusting volume or changing up the playlist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfbDUX"&gt;Unlike the Pros, there are no silicone ear tips for a customizable fit: as with its previous standard AirPods, Apple sticks with a one-size-fits-most hard plastic design. They’re open-style earbuds that rest in your ears instead of extending deep into the ear canal. A lot of people love the barely there comfort of the AirPods. The main side effect of their open design is that they let in a ton of outside noise. For me, that’s always been a significant turnoff. But again, others value having the added awareness — be it for personal safety reasons or otherwise — and view this as an upside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GOF4UNksPfsgjJRt-H2qZmI9HNc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953794/IMG_0048_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The third-gen AirPods (below) are clearly cut from the same cloth as the AirPods Pro (above).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="die3Jr"&gt;Unfortunately, fit is where the old AirPods have always let me down. They just weren’t a good match for my large-ish ears and would come loose and fall out way too easily. All ears are different, and I know a ton of people who had no such issues. But I was expecting another round of disappointment when I put the third-gen AirPods into my ears for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nBcM1"&gt;Fortunately, the new shape fits my ears much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFVPQU"&gt;Apple says it conducted a ton of user research when designing the third-generation AirPods, involving thousands of ear scans, heat maps, and so on. And at least in my case, something about the new shape definitely works better. They’re staying put so well that I no longer feel the same anxiety about them tumbling onto the ground and down a sewer grate. That worry was always present with the older AirPods. The healthy dose of ambient sound remains, and I’m just someone who prefers earbuds that offer some quiet from the outside world. But I can finally say that Apple’s regular AirPods fit me, and that was never true previously. If you had issues with the original design, it’s worth giving these a try.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/woYRg7Y4GOzAoeIkIMHF92IN-90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953799/IMG_0047.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new AirPods have much shorter stems than before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YBojuP"&gt;The charging case now opens in landscape — just like the case for the AirPods Pro — but it’s noticeably smaller than that one. It’s closer in overall size to the original AirPods case, though a smidge thicker. The case still has a Lightning port for wired charging, and it also supports Qi-compatible wireless chargers. Apple says the new AirPods case is designed to work with the company’s MagSafe chargers. And sure enough, it grabs onto the circular MagSafe charging pad with the same perfect alignment as an iPhone 12 or 13. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nISprs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If the old AirPods never fit your ears, these might do the trick&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8V0LTd"&gt;But don’t expect to charge your earbuds by placing them on the back of Apple’s MagSafe-ready iPhones: there’s no reverse wireless charging. And to drive that point home, Apple told me it intentionally designed the AirPods case so that it doesn’t magnetically latch onto the back of those phones. You’ll feel some pull when sliding the case around the back of the phone, but it’s nowhere near enough force to keep the two attached. As for the actual battery life, Apple says the third-gen AirPods can hit six hours of continuous playback and a total of 30 hours counting case recharges. That’s a modest improvement over the five hours and “over 24 hours” estimates from the previous model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wiGbOD"&gt;Both the AirPods and their case are now rated IPX4 for water and sweat resistance. Plenty of people used the older generations for workouts, but the official certification gives added peace of mind if you’ll frequently be using these AirPods as a gym companion. There’s also a new “skin detection sensor” on each earbud that replaces the old IR sensor. It still tells the AirPods to pause when removed from your ears (or resume when placed back in), but Apple says this sensor can tell the difference between your ears or tight spaces like a pants pocket that might’ve fooled the previous AirPods into resuming playback if you put them in there without the case. It’s not difficult to envision future evolutions of this sensor tying into Apple’s health and fitness efforts. But for now it’s just there to make auto-pause more reliable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GFY7Ex"&gt;Apple has completely redesigned the acoustic driver and amplifier in the third-gen AirPods. The company told me it aimed to give them a sound profile similar to the AirPods Pro. There’s only so much you can do with open-style earbuds to improve bass performance; these will never pack the same low-end punch as many upscale in-ear buds. But the new AirPods do sound noticeably fuller and more dynamic than their predecessors — and yes, very similar to the Pros. In the right ways, they still sound like AirPods, and they’re tuned to work equally well for music, watching videos, podcasts, games, and so on. But Apple says music is still far and away the leading thing people use their AirPods for, so it’s trying to deliver the best audio quality possible in this form factor. I’ve found that the open design often leads to a more spacious soundstage. The AirPods are still handily outperformed by top-tier earbuds like Sony’s WF-1000XM4 or the Bose QuietComfort Earbuds, but among other buds with an open design, they’re up there with the best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WK-mSuFuVOg5iUNkHQdRI1SwPYA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953803/IMG_0044.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The third-gen AirPods have redesigned drivers and support spatial audio with head tracking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lfClhR"&gt;To further enhance their sound, the new AirPods use the same adaptive EQ feature as the Pros and Max. There’s an inward-facing mic on each earbud that analyzes what you’re hearing and, so Apple claims, adjusts the output in real time to what’s best for your unique ear shape. But the thing about adaptive EQ is that it’s impossible to ever really know when it’s doing something — or what that something is. It’s invisible to the listener at all times, so there’s not much to say about it. There’s no telling whether the improved sound is due to the redesigned drivers, the inclusion of adaptive EQ, or a combination of both. The third-gen AirPods do a better job of steering audio into your ears, which also helps achieve that full-bodied sound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPpQJ6"&gt;But that brings us to the big trick Apple is advertising with the new AirPods: spatial audio with head tracking. Like the AirPods Pro and Max, the third-gen pair can dynamically adjust the sound in each earbud as you turn your head from side to side, keeping the sound source anchored to the iPhone, iPad, Mac, or Apple TV you’re watching. When you’re watching movies in Netflix, HBO Max, Disney Plus, Amazon Prime Video, or other popular apps, this head tracking can be an immersive, fun experience and mimics surround sound better than a regular stereo mix would. It really does add to the satisfaction of watching movies on my iPad Pro. And for those times when someone’s asleep at home and you can’t take advantage of your soundbar or surround system on the Apple TV, you can listen in private with AirPods and spatial audio head tracking. Apple has also thought of other use cases: on group FaceTime calls, spatial audio creates a sound field that places the voices where they’re positioned on your device’s screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="HUXc0F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We’re still in the early days of spatial audio — and you can tell&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="683JZk"&gt;But when it comes to music, it all feels far more gimmicky. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;I’ve written about Apple Music’s Dolby Atmos-powered spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; before, and everything there applies here. The feature works with all headphones, but only the third-gen AirPods, Pros, and Max add head tracking to the equation. That doesn’t really change where I stand on it. Spatial audio mixes can often sound objectively worse than their stereo counterparts. It takes a lot of work from engineers and producers to get the most from Atmos, and it remains obvious that a lot of albums available in spatial audio on Apple Music haven’t gotten that level of attention. Instruments and effects can sound out of place, vocals can get drowned out in the mix, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x1oiF2"&gt;The situation is improving as newer records are mixed for Atmos from the get-go. (And Atmos mixes do generally sound a lot better on actual Atmos home theater systems.) The recent Giles Martin remix of &lt;em&gt;Let It Be&lt;/em&gt; by The Beatles takes advantage of spatial audio well without trying to do too much. It has that feeling of being in the room with the band. But other examples, like Kacey Musgraves’ &lt;em&gt;Star-Crossed&lt;/em&gt;, don’t do anything for me that I don’t already get from the stereo version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BrGfV"&gt;In short, spatial audio can wow when it comes to video, but we’re still in the very early stages of the music side — and it’s not a reason to buy these earbuds yet. Apple makes it easy to switch back and forth between spatial audio and regular sound in Control Center. And iOS 15 actually lets you “spatialize” sound from apps like Spotify that don’t otherwise offer the feature. I guess that’s nice to have if you really find yourself loving this new way of listening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W73EEHXIiB114uTu-QbiD6XBZUY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953861/IMG_0049_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like all AirPods before them, the third-gen earbuds are positioned as the perfect iPhone accessory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ajGJmS"&gt;The AirPods have long been the champion of voice calls, and with the third-gen set, Apple is trying to improve the fidelity of FaceTime calls by using a new AAC-ELD codec for clearer voice reproduction. There’s also acoustic mesh on the outward-facing side of each AirPod that’s meant to reduce wind noise. Despite the shorter stems, overall microphone performance remains excellent and the new AirPods remain easy to recommend if you want earbuds that guarantee you’ll come through clearly on calls. Stay tuned for our video review for the full mic test — with Becca, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="1Vctld"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10826383"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W1Oafy"&gt;Apple has also given the new AirPods a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22711557/apple-lost-airpods-pro-max-find-my-network-now-available"&gt;deeper level of integration with its Find My app&lt;/a&gt;. You could always play a sound to find a missing (nearby) earbud or see the location where they were last connected to your phone. But now the third-gen AirPods get the same “find nearby” feature as the AirPods Pro and Max. This is an AirTags-like interface for pinpointing where the AirPods are if you’re in close proximity to them. It’s not as accurate as an AirTag, but the UI will tell you when the AirPods are “nearby” and then show “here” when you’re right near them. If they’re really nowhere to be found, you can also now enable lost mode and be alerted if your missing AirPods come within range of millions of other iOS devices. My favorite of the new Find My features are the separation alerts that automatically pop up if you leave your AirPods behind somewhere. That alone should prevent a lot of heartbreak and lost earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4aimgs"&gt;The new AirPods are the first big redesign of Apple’s massively popular true wireless earbuds. From a fit and comfort standpoint, I think Apple succeeded: these are still wonderfully lightweight earbuds, and they actually stay in my ears now. The sound quality has seen some refinement, and the third-gen AirPods are a better gym buddy than their predecessors. Plus you’ve got longer battery life and nice-to-have features like spatial audio head tracking — even if Apple is overselling it a bit. I’ll personally be sticking with the AirPods Pro and other earbuds that offer noise cancellation or at least some isolation. But if you prefer the open-style AirPods and have an older pair that can’t hold a charge anymore, these are a worthwhile upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Y3dZlM"&gt;But before you go getting locked deeper into Apple’s ecosystem, it’s worth exploring your options. The game has changed a lot since the second-gen AirPods were released, and it’s possible to find better sound quality among competitors like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637548/oneplus-buds-pro-review-specs-price-features"&gt;OnePlus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22323748/anker-liberty-air-2-pro-review-wireless-headphone-price"&gt;Anker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and others. If you can do without the frills, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;spend much less and still be happy&lt;/a&gt;. Still, if you’ve got an iPhone, none of those can deliver the same seamless experience as the AirPods. They’re still designed to perfectly complement Apple’s smartphone, and in that regard they don’t disappoint. Perhaps more than any other Apple product today, AirPods still just work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VQxXLI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T11:40:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T11:40:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Eight things we learned from the Facebook Papers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XHo33xg_dwJugv7qha5Ofl2OST0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70042241/acastro_211024_4822_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A massive new document release shows chaos and confusion inside the world’s most powerful social network&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="BwFlxl"&gt;For months, Facebook has been shaken by a steady leak of documents from whistleblower Frances Haugen, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;beginning in &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but spreading to government officials and nearly any outlet with an interest in the company. Now, those documents are going much more public, giving us the most sweeping look at the operations of Facebook anyone not directly involved with the company has ever had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jlTwmg"&gt;The documents stem from disclosures made to the SEC and provided to Congress by Haugen in redacted form. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and a consortium of other news organizations have obtained redacted versions of the documents, which we’re calling The Facebook Papers. In order to receive the documents, we agreed to begin publishing our reporting on them this week, but we are not beholden to report on them in a certain way or coordinate what we cover with other outlets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XrgxMl"&gt;We’ve already done &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22743753/facebook-tier-list-countries-leaked-documents-content-moderation"&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks"&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; on the files, and we’ll keep reporting on them over the coming weeks. (There are a lot of pages.) This isn’t a comprehensive list of everything in the documents, and you should fully expect more to come out. Instead, think of it as a summary of the files that, so far, have stood out to us the most. Hopefully, it will help you make sense of the sheer volume of Facebook news coming out this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="95KZrK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook was caught off guard by vaccine misinformation in comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uXrltV"&gt;Facebook has taken a lot of criticism for its handling of COVID misinformation — including from President Biden, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580620/biden-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-platforms"&gt;accused the platform of “killing people”&lt;/a&gt; by letting anti-vaxx sentiment run amok — but the leaks show just how chaotic the effort was inside the company. One document dated March 2021 shows an employee raising the alarm about how unprepared the platform was. “Vaccine hesitancy in comments is rampant,” the memo reads. “Our ability to detect vaccine-hesitant comments is bad in English, and basically non-existent elsewhere. We need Policy guidelines specifically aimed at vaccine hesitancy in comments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pCJ6fW"&gt;(Editor’s note: We are not publishing the document itself since it contains the full name of a Facebook employee.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nIRvUo"&gt;“Comments are a significant portion of misinfo on FB,” says another employee in an internal comment, “and are almost a complete blind spot for us in terms of enforcement and transparency right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="nNomp2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“For English posts on Vaccines, vaccine hesitancy prevalence among comments is 50 percent.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K3ak7N"&gt;The document makes clear that Facebook already had a “COVID-19 lockdown defense” project dedicated to the platform dynamics created by the pandemic, including a workstream dedicated entirely to vaccine hesitancy. That team had also created significant automated flagging systems for misinformation — but according to the files, those simply weren’t being used to downrank anti-vaccine comments. As of the March memo, there were no plans to develop moderation infrastructure like labeling, guidelines, and classifier systems to identify anti-vaccine statements in comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vRUps8"&gt;The failure to meaningfully moderate comments was noticed outside the company. &lt;a href="https://firstdraftnews.org/articles/vaccine-misinformation-in-facebook-comment-sections-a-case-study/"&gt;A First Draft News study in May&lt;/a&gt; looked at the comments for a handful of major news outlets with more than a million followers and found one in five comments on vaccine-related stories contained some kind of anti-vaccine misinformation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwI6AD"&gt;The documents show Facebook was aware of the problem, and First Draft may have even underestimated the issue. One comment on the post reads, “for English posts on Vaccines, vaccine hesitancy prevalence among comments is 50 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pvzslW"&gt;Other aspects of the issue remained completely unstudied since the company had yet to dig in on the comment problem. “We currently don’t understand whether Group comments are a serious problem,” the post argues. “It’s clear to us that the ‘good post, bad comment’ problem is a big deal, but it’s not necessarily as clear that [vaccine hesitant] comments on [vaccine hesitant] posts are additive to the harm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cC6Red"&gt;Another document published &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21081616-copy-of-copy-of-covid-workstream-1-week-update_sanitized"&gt;shortly after April 2021&lt;/a&gt; shows the company still coming to terms with vaccine misinformation. The good news was that there was no evidence of a foreign influence campaign driving anti-vaxx sentiment, as had stung the company in 2016. But the vast majority of content was being sent by a relatively small portion of accounts, suggesting that Facebook had not yet taken the easiest measures to address the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7cl0Tf"&gt;Facebook has taken some steps recently to address misinformation in comments — including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736301/facebook-demote-groups-content-policy-violations-update"&gt;new downranking rules from just last week&lt;/a&gt;. But these documents show those changes came more than six months after the alarm had been raised internally and after Facebook had publicly expressed anxiety about the impending leak. Given the huge surge of COVID deaths among vaccine-skeptical populations over the past three months, it’s easy to see the recent changes as too little, too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="65ZogJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple threatened to ban Facebook over online “slave markets”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9sAQx3"&gt;Facebook scrambled to address human trafficking content after Apple threatened to kick its apps off the iOS App Store, a leaked SEV (or Site Event) report shows. &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21091528-apple-escalation-how-we-made-it-through-this-sev_sanitized_opt"&gt;The report&lt;/a&gt;, referenced briefly by &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-drug-cartels-human-traffickers-response-is-weak-documents-11631812953"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal’s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Facebook Files reporting, indicates that Apple threatened to pull Facebook and Instagram from iOS on October 23rd of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="38ESNh"&gt;Apple had been tipped off by &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-50228549"&gt;a BBC News Arabic report&lt;/a&gt; that found domestic workers being sold via Instagram and other apps, where sellers encouraged buyers to mistreat the workers by doing things such as confiscating their passports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="O29NG7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the policy was “highly likely leading to exploitation of domestic servants”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Ee0Ma"&gt;Facebook had been aware of the problem but hadn’t understood the scope of it, apparently because very little content (less than 2 percent of the material it found) had been reported by users. “Removing our applications from Apple platforms would have had potentially severe consequences to the business,” the Facebook report notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AUfoiq"&gt;After Apple escalated the issue, Facebook moderators swept the platforms for keywords and hashtags mentioned in the BBC reporting, ultimately disabling 1,021 accounts and removing 129,121 pieces of content. Facebook also removed a policy exception letting established brick and mortar businesses like recruitment agencies post ads about domestic workers. Facebook determined that even if the businesses were legal, the policy was “highly likely leading to exploitation of domestic servants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lBXrmh"&gt;Apple was apparently satisfied with the mitigation measures, and the incident was closed within a week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Lea8mb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Civic Integrity team was often directly blocked by Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3TQpnb"&gt;One of the most alarming incidents uncovered by the papers was that Mark Zuckerberg personally intervened to ensure Facebook would comply with a repressive law instituted in Vietnam, agreeing to moderate more aggressively against “anti-state” content on the platform. The anecdote leads &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/25/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-whistleblower/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;’s report&lt;/a&gt; on the papers and plays into a much more troubling dynamic described by Haugen before Congress. Facebook’s Integrity team had lots of ideas for how to make Facebook less harmful, but they were usually overruled, sometimes by Zuckerberg himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iSLPUM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-25/facebook-whistle-blower-files-reveal-internal-struggle-profit-vs-public-safety?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt; explores the issue in more detail&lt;/a&gt;, showing how the company often found its own efforts to downrank harmful content overwhelmed by the content’s inherent virality. As one employee put it, “I worry that Feed is becoming an arms race.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xcNybN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/10/25/facebook-employees-message-anguish-517012"&gt;highlights another employee quote&lt;/a&gt; showing just how demoralized the team had become. “If we really want to change the state of our information ecosystem, we need a revolution, not an evolution of our systems,” an employee wrote in October 2019. “If you don’t have enough good content to boost, it doesn’t matter how much you downrank the bad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YftFai"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook used a German anti-vaccine movement as a test case for more aggressive moderation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jmnXdq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21091529-querdunken-experiment_sanitized"&gt;Another document&lt;/a&gt; details Facebook’s so-called “Querdenken experiment,” in which the company’s moderators tested out a more aggressive moderation approach on a German conspiracy movement. Facebook’s Dangerous Content team was already developing a new classification — a “harmful topic community” — and the growing Querdenken was chosen as an experiment on how the classification would work in practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9UfIPl"&gt;As a Facebook employee writes in the document, “this could be a good case study to inform how we tackle these problems in the future”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qjPIYc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“this could be a good case study to inform how we tackle these problems in the future”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EN0Mjr"&gt;Querdenken has become one of the leading anti-lockdown and anti-vaccination groups in Germany, with &lt;a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/covid19/2021/09/29/querdenken-the-german-anti-lockdown-movement-that-thrives-on-public-distrust/"&gt;similarities to more extreme groups like QAnon&lt;/a&gt;. As the Facebook proposal framed it, the Querdenken movement had potential for violence but wasn’t yet linked to extreme enough activity that would justify banning followers from the platform entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdmviS"&gt;The documents give few details about how the experiment proceeded, although clearly, some version of the Querdenken plan was implemented. (A later report says “results from some initial samples look promising.”) And judging by the company’s public statements, it did result in a meaningful change to moderation policy: in September, Facebook &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/removing-new-types-of-harmful-networks/"&gt;announced a new policy on “coordinated social harm,&lt;/a&gt;” specifically citing Querdenken as an example of the new approach in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9yoom"&gt;Unlike many of the other documents, the Querdenken experiment shows Facebook’s moderation system as relatively effective. The company identified the group before it caused significant harm, took action with an eye towards long-term consequences and was transparent about the policy shift after it took place. But the incident shows how complex the interplay of policy and enforcement can be, with broader policies often rewritten with an eye towards specific groups. And for supporters of Querdenken, it may be alarming to learn that the rules of the world’s largest social platform were rewritten specifically to keep their movement from gaining public support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="g2e5A7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook’s January 6th response was shaped by glitches and delays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Fa9cla"&gt;Facebook discussed developing extreme “break-glass measures” to limit misinformation, calls to violence, and other material that could disrupt the 2020 presidential election. But when former President Donald Trump and his supporters tried to stop successor Joe Biden from being declared president on January 6th, 2021, Facebook employees complained these measures were implemented too late or stymied by technical and bureaucratic hangups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kudeCD"&gt;Reports &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/10/25/facebook-jan-6-election-claims-516997"&gt;at &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/22/technology/facebook-election-misinformation.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; outline&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s struggle to handle users delegitimizing the elections. Internally, critics said Facebook didn’t have a sufficient game plan for “harmful non-violating narratives” that toed the line between misinformation and content Facebook wants to preserve as free speech. And some plans, like a change that would have prevented Groups from changing their names to terms like “Stop the Steal,” apparently got held up by technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pGgwFx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook was trying to rebalance its News Feed for “civic health”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dOxXmo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-algorithm-change-zuckerberg-11631654215?mod=hp_lead_pos7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; first revealed&lt;/a&gt; that news outlets and political parties had complained about users favoring negative and hyperbolic content. Facebook was considering ways to fix the problem, and one method involved re-weighting the News Feed to optimize for “civic health” instead of primarily focusing on meaningful social interactions or session time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="joe2X7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21091530-ranking-for-civic-health_sanitized"&gt;In a product briefing called “Ranking For Civic Health,”&lt;/a&gt; Facebook acknowledged that “people think that political content on Facebook is low quality, untrustworthy, and divisive,” and the current ranking system was “not creating a wholly valuable civic experience for users.” (Based on document comment dates, the document was produced around January and February of 2020.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wLT5B7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“people think that political content on Facebook is low quality, untrustworthy, and divisive”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ih0o6u"&gt;The document says Facebook’s ranking algorithm recommended civic content that users themselves didn’t report finding valuable — something earlier leaks have indicated was a problem with meaningful social interactions (MSI) and other engagement-based metrics.  “Our current ranking objectives do not optimize for integrity outcomes, which can have dangerous consequences,” it says — for instance, MSI optimization was “contributing hugely to Civic misinfo,” and Facebook estimated that removing it from Civic posts would decrease it by 30 to 50 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IcPvpx"&gt;Facebook tried to improve civic health by asking users explicitly what they thought constituted good civic content. This sometimes revealed even bigger problems — since Facebook apparently found that 20 to 30 percent of respondents “may say that known Civic hate is ‘good for the community’” in surveys. Facebook settled on a strategy to “prioritize the reduction of policy-violating content — such as Civic Hate or Civic Misinfo — even if the individual user finds it valuable” and aimed to reduce the prevalence of civic hate speech, misinformation, and inflammatory content by at least 10 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0PSEr"&gt;The company ran rebalancing experiments in February 2020 by slightly increasing the amount of “civic” News Feed content that a random set of users saw, then optimizing that content through different metrics (including MSI and whether people thought content was “worth your time”). It also ran a survey to collect how users felt about civic News Feed content. The company aimed to have a new optimization system chosen by March of 2020 — although it’s not clear how the coronavirus pandemic may have changed those plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QeoSTY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why likes were never hidden on Facebook and Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s8u9SY"&gt;A highly publicized plan from early last year to hide like counts on Instagram never happened because testing the change hurt ad revenue and led to people using the app less. A quiet test of the experience on the Facebook app was also killed after leadership told Zuckerberg that it wasn’t a “top barrier to sharing nor a top concern for people.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZyeIJ"&gt;A lengthy internal presentation to Zuckerberg about the plan, dubbed Project Daisy, shows that there were concerns among leadership about how the Facebook app would have been perceived if Instagram hid like counts and Facebook did not, which is something employees who were involved in the project have told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Employees working on Instagram wanted to bill it as a way to depressurize the app for young people, but the team working on the Facebook app wasn’t into the idea. If Instagram went through with hiding likes, the presentation details how leadership at Facebook wanted to “minimize blowback to the Facebook app” for not hiding them and still “ensure credit ladders up to the Facebook company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zAk94x"&gt;Instead of hiding likes for all users by default as was originally planned, Instagram earlier adopted a half measure by letting people opt into hiding their likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Xj934V"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook’s “civic groups” policy stumbled over a simple design flaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TsjsfE"&gt;In October 2020, Facebook announced that it would stop recommending civic and political groups to users in the US as part of a broader effort to avoid the mistakes of the 2016 election. (The policy was made permanent shortly after the January 6th riot.) But actually keeping those groups out of Facebook recommendation feeds has been a huge challenge for the company — and &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21091531-sev-civic-non-recommendable-groups_sanitized"&gt;an internal document&lt;/a&gt; gives us new insight into why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lT8Fey"&gt;The document shows Facebook employees grappling with a public article, flagged by the PR team, which found 30 separate groups still appearing in recommendation feeds in apparent violation of the policy. Escalated on January 19th, the document says many of the groups named in the report had been labeled as civic groups at one point — but were somehow still being recommended as part of facebook’s Groups You Should Join feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="29K2qF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Reducing churn could have solved almost all of the problems&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IzVNdd"&gt;“Leakage has been there since Nov 2020 at the least,” the Facebook document reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llez64"&gt;It’s not clear which article the document is referring to, but there were a number of reports spotting enforcement failures at the time. The Markup found a bunch of groups slipping through &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/citizen-browser/2021/06/24/after-repeatedly-promising-not-to-facebook-keeps-recommending-political-groups-to-its-users"&gt;that January&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/citizen-browser/2021/06/24/after-repeatedly-promising-not-to-facebook-keeps-recommending-political-groups-to-its-users"&gt;again in June&lt;/a&gt;. Even now, it’s not clear the civic groups policy is being enforced as intended. At the time, most observers focused on the conceptual difficulty: it’s a hard philosophical problem to draw a clear line between which groups count as “civic” and even harder to scale it across a platform of Facebook’s size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NDxCI6"&gt;But the internal report shows the real problem was much simpler. Facebook’s monitoring system (referred to in the report as “Laser”) had been trained to only look at the past seven days of content when determining whether a page fell into the “civic groups” category, which meant pages were constantly filtering in and out as the period viewed by the algorithm changed. In practice, that meant a pro-Trump or pro-Biden group could easily dodge the label by posting a few days worth of less obviously political content.  The report estimates that a full 12 percent of labeled groups would churn out of the category from day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ob7CVb"&gt;According to the report, 90 percent of the groups highlighted by the article had been caught by Facebook’s existing “civic groups” classifier — but they’d filtered out as part of the churn. So reducing churn &lt;em&gt;alone&lt;/em&gt; could have solved almost all of the problems spotted by the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WjLH2B"&gt;There have been lots of stories like this over the past five years: Facebook sets a policy that seems measured and responsible, but a cursory test (usually from a journalist) shows banned content is still easily slipping through. From the outside, it’s often unclear how much of the problem is incompetence at Facebook and how much is just the inherent difficulty of managing a platform of that size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="08qHZ8"&gt;But in this case, the documents put the blame squarely on Facebook as a company. This was a high-profile policy with huge stakes for the country at large, with obvious delicacy in how it was implemented. A churn rate that high made it inevitable that targeted groups would slip through the cracks, and the company simply didn’t notice until reporters called them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Mqex8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LTmiAh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22740969/facebook-files-papers-frances-haugen-whistleblower-civic-integrity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22740969/facebook-files-papers-frances-haugen-whistleblower-civic-integrity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T11:14:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T11:14:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite’s infamous Craig gets a glow-up in latest campaign trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a-Gc_AcOBc4XSB3KhL0O2OCr_dY=/139x0:1125x657/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70042122/craig.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vSnDrE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744558/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-preview-trailer-master-chief-xbox-series-x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s new campaign trailer&lt;/a&gt; showcased all the Banished-beating activities the Master Chief will get up to while exploring the mysterious Zeta Halo ring. Hidden among the updates is a neat little callback to the game’s first infamous trailer, featuring a new face on an old friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0RsdxR"&gt;Craig The Brute is back and he’s had some work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J2DF7O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10826282"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E2CiLz"&gt;Craig became the &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/craig-from-halo-infinite-is-the-new-xbox-mascot-jokes-xbox-chief"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; meme&lt;/a&gt; back when Microsoft debuted an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21335520/halo-infinite-gameplay-xbox-series-x-trailer-demo"&gt;eight-minute demo&lt;/a&gt; highlighting &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign and gameplay. Fans picked the demo apart, lambasting it for its seemingly poor-quality graphics that Craig — the name given to the brute enemy looking extremely nonplussed that the Master Chief is trying to bash his face in — came to represent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2CIXUU"&gt;In the new trailer, that’s not the Craig but it is a brute enemy. Since all brutes mostly look the same, it’s safe to say Craig and all his brothers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"&gt;took some time off&lt;/a&gt; to work on themselves, practice a little self-care, and grow a pandemic beard. However, not everyone used their time wisely as Nu!Craig still doesn’t seemed bothered by the Master Chief’s right hook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jr6naS"&gt;The reaction to the new trailer has been positive and fans have noticed the graphical improvements. However, not everything shown off represents what we’ll see at launch. When a fan noticed the update to the Escharum enemy at the end of the trailer, a 343 Industries employee was quick to point out that wasn’t an in-engine render.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="n66XgL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hey Rhys - just to clear up confusion and set expectations, the Escharum on the left is not in-engine. Keep your eyes peeled for more on both  &lt;/p&gt;— John Junyszek (@Unyshek) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Unyshek/status/1452625175371915292?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1TjaAk"&gt;We’ll see more of Craig’s luscious new beard when &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; launches December 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zeWExk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744656/microsoft-halo-infinite-craig-brute-improved-graphics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744656/microsoft-halo-infinite-craig-brute-improved-graphics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T11:00:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T11:00:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zoom now has auto-generated captions available for free accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Q-1bU4_U-vnlm8x-FjsCpe-90A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70042053/acastro_200331_1777_zoom_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FQ3nNy"&gt;Zoom is following through on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300740/zoom-live-transcription-closed-captions-accessibility-free-accounts"&gt;its promise to add&lt;/a&gt; auto-generated closed captions to all free Zoom meetings accounts to make its service more accessible, the company &lt;a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-auto-generated-captions/"&gt;announced Monday&lt;/a&gt;. The captions are only available in English, but the company says it plans to expand to other languages in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4d6wJ"&gt;“It’s important to us that everyone can successfully connect, communicate, and participate using Zoom,” said Theresa Larkin, the company’s product marketing manager of meetings &amp;amp; chat. “Without the proper accessibility tools, people with disabilities face tremendous barriers when using video communication solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cj_RYP9Iybw8wQVvx1HWT_v5wYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953822/auto_captions.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Zoom&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Zoom has added captions for free accounts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="x8liC9"&gt;Zoom had previously offered AI-powered live transcription only for its paid accounts, which drew &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/12/17/zoom-captions-hearing-loss-free/"&gt;criticism from accessibility advocates&lt;/a&gt; who noted the ubiquity of Zoom calls during the pandemic left deaf users with limited options. Without the auto-captions, Zoom meeting hosts had to either use a third-party captioning service or manually add their own captions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pOOjCh"&gt;The company has added more accessibility options over the past year, including support for screen readers and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452400/zoom-accessibility-features-pin-spotlight-multiple-videos-during-call"&gt;allowing multiple videos to be visible&lt;/a&gt; at the same time, allowing a sign language interpreter to be visible at all times, even when another user on the call is speaking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZGdxk"&gt;To &lt;a href="https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/4409683389709"&gt;enable captions in Zoom meetings&lt;/a&gt;, an account owner or a user with admin privileges can sign into the Zoom web portal, then find “account management” in the navigation menu. Choose “account settings,” then click the “meeting” tab. Under “in meeting (advanced),” toggle the closed captioning option to enable it. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744704/zoom-auto-generated-captions-available-free-accounts-accessibility"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744704/zoom-auto-generated-captions-available-free-accounts-accessibility</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Best Buy stores will soon offer Samsung foldable repairs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A Best Buy store." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lg-MmU4YHeLxf9SRRQjTk6g-iIA=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041988/1336158138.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Scott Olson/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WbALcP"&gt;Samsung foldable owners will soon have more options for repairing their devices, with over 100 Best Buy stores gearing up to offer repairs in “early November,” &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/support/bestbuy/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The retailer is also officially offering repairs of Galaxy S and Galaxy Note devices as of today. Although some Best Buy stores offered similar repairs of these devices in the past, Samsung says this was previously a pilot program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpw77M"&gt;Expanding its repair options to foldables is important given the ongoing concerns people have about durability, especially when it comes to their internal folding displays. And when it comes to foldables, you’ll almost certainly want to turn to a professional for service. The devices are filled with stuff like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619139/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-flip-screen-durability-waterproof-aluminum"&gt;tape, glue, and goo&lt;/a&gt;, which make successful home repairs very difficult to pull off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4pXevt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Foldables are hard to repair yourself&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1qXDZ6"&gt;As well as offering repairs on Samsung devices, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18691649/best-buy-apple-iphone-mac-ipad-repairs-all-stores"&gt;as of early 2019&lt;/a&gt; Best Buy also offers authorized repairs on Apple devices across its stores in the US. Easy access to replacement screens and batteries are important for prolonging the life span of devices, saving customers money, and decreasing the amount of electronic waste that ends up in landfills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJ5EKu"&gt;Samsung says it has a network of over 550 Authorized Care locations across the US, and that it also has over 600 independent service providers. The company also offers a doorstep repair service called “&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/support/service/we-come-to-you/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;We Come to You&lt;/a&gt;,” as well as a mail-in service. For a full list of Samsung devices that can be repaired at Best Buy, check out &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/http://www.samsung.com/us/support/bestbuy" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9a1ibi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 25th, 11:28AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to clarify that Best Buy’s previous Samsung repair options were offered as part of a pilot program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744407/best-buy-authorized-samsung-foldable-repairs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744407/best-buy-authorized-samsung-foldable-repairs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T10:40:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T10:40:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is working on blockchain-linked Collectibles tab</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cDlztAUMH4XUKy_BonNSL_DRmto=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041900/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yDxkcA"&gt;Twitter is working on a tab that shows off a user’s NFT collection, and it’s beginning to look a lot more complete. The platform first began working on the feature in September — a tweet from Mada Aflak, a software engineer for Twitter, first showed off the early stages of its experiment in late September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Z2Vjoe"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As promised, here is the first experiment. Feedbacks and ideas are welcome :) &lt;a href="https://t.co/TDyhibCXfG"&gt;https://t.co/TDyhibCXfG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2ifru9T2Pa"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2ifru9T2Pa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mada Aflak (@af_mada) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/af_mada/status/1443243702156206089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OFXwpl"&gt;The tweet’s video demonstrates how you can connect your crypto wallet from popular providers like Coinbase, Metamask, and Crypto.com and then choose one of your NFTs to use as your profile picture. Your full collection of NFTs will be stored in a tab on your profile, labeled Collectibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4UGCX1"&gt;Once selected, your profile picture will have a small badge that verifies that it’s a real NFT. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689806/twitter-bitcoin-lightning-tipping-nft-authentication"&gt;Twitter hinted at letting users verify the NFTs they tweet&lt;/a&gt; back in September, so that detail doesn’t come as much of a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYMZQ7"&gt;These were the earlier stages of the feature, and reverse engineer Jane Manchun Wong just showed off how it has changed since then. She sent out a tweet showing a slightly more detailed version than the glimpse we got originally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="23HcHs"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Twitter is working on Collectibles profile tab, NFT view and NFT details view &lt;a href="https://t.co/BrqPyvaLOp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/BrqPyvaLOp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1452373149689909248?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S3GPqq"&gt;In addition to the Collectibles tab, Wong revealed that Twitter is working on a view that lets you get a close-up look at an NFT. You’ll also be able to tap through to a page that shows detailed information about the NFT, including a description, its creator, any properties, as well as some information about the collection. One change to note about the Collectibles tab is that it looks like it’ll take the place of the Likes tab on your profile — Wong notes that you’ll have to scroll horizontally to reach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FvdxWn"&gt;A feature dedicated to NFTs is definitely nice to have, but it also shows Twitter’s disregard for more pressing issues on the platform. As developer Nathan Lawrence points out, Twitter could be using its resources to add better features dedicated to fighting misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bP6Atk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We spent years begging Twitter for features to combat disinformation. We finally got Birdwatch, which is better than I expected, but so hidden that I suspect most people don’t know it exists.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This elevates NFTs to a UI level that _fact checking_ never got.&lt;/p&gt;— Nathan Lawrence   (@NathanBLawrence) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NathanBLawrence/status/1452386576311353344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dKlRVI"&gt;Lawrence also noted something even more concerning: Twitter appears to have integrated NFTs into its interface, while misinformation prevention tool Birdwatch remains hidden on a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/i/birdwatch"&gt;dedicated portion of the site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248903/twitter-birdwatch-fact-checking-misinformation"&gt;Twitter launched Birdwatch&lt;/a&gt;, a crowdsourced misinformation tool that empowers the community to identify and flag questionable content, in January. Since its launch, we really haven’t heard much about it besides the fact that &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/twitter-starts-rolling-out-birdwatch-fact-checks-inside-tweets/"&gt;Birdwatch notes now appear in tweets&lt;/a&gt;. Overall, it’s not a great look for Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744540/twitter-blockchain-linked-collectibles-tab"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744540/twitter-blockchain-linked-collectibles-tab</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:56:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:56:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla doesn’t want anyone to see its response to the Autopilot investigation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fV8JZVTlTo61gsFXU41Ubv57BCc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041660/tesla.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nwNP3e"&gt;Tesla wants to keep secret its response to the federal investigation into its Autopilot driver assist system. &lt;a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/inv/2021/INME-PE21020-1022.pdf"&gt;In a memo submitted to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) last week&lt;/a&gt;, regulators noted that Tesla has requested “confidential business information (CBI) treatment for the entirety of the information request submission.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JKtelU"&gt;If Tesla’s request is granted, it would effectively bar the public from seeing the company’s response to a host of information that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;NHTSA has requested&lt;/a&gt; regarding its probe into Autopilot and possible defects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="igFIFK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If Tesla’s request is granted, it would effectively bar the public from seeing the company’s response&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="atwqHR"&gt;The agency wants to know why Tesla didn’t issue a recall for Autopilot after it became obvious the driver assistance system had a problem “seeing” parked emergency vehicles. NHTSA is also asking Tesla for more information about the growing public beta test of its incomplete Full Self-Driving software, the recently launched “Safety Score” evaluation process for entering the program, and the nondisclosure agreements Tesla was making participants sign up until this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KLdocv"&gt;The request for confidentiality was made amid a period of intense scrutiny into Tesla and its willingness to rollout unfinished software updates to its customers. There have been at least a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;dozen incidents&lt;/a&gt; in which Teslas with Autopilot activated have crashed into parked emergency vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7anhPu"&gt;Tesla shipped a software update to its &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/534868/tesla-autopilot-update-emergency-vehicles/"&gt;cars meant to fix the issue&lt;/a&gt; with its driver assistance system in September. But NHTSA wants to know why Tesla didn’t go through the formal recall process with this update, potentially setting up a protracted fight over whether over-the-air updates that can materially change how cars operate should be subjected to the government’s stringent automotive safety rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OipKtf"&gt;Tesla started rolling out a new software update over the weekend, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/24/22743628/elon-musk-tesla-fsd-beta-10-3-rollback-issues-phantom-fcw"&gt;but reversed it on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; after the company’s CEO Elon Musk tweeted that they were “seeing some issues” with it. Some Tesla owners reported problems such as phantom forward collision warnings, disappearing Autosteer option, traffic-aware cruise control problems, and occasional AutoPilot panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7vAND"&gt;The news of Tesla’s request for confidentiality also comes as scores of the company’s fans have posted disparaging comments about a new hire at NHTSA, robotics expert Missy Cummings, whom they view as being hostile to the company. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/the-station-zoox-seattle-tesla-fans-attack/"&gt;Cummings reportedly received death threats&lt;/a&gt; from some Tesla fans, causing her to delete her Twitter account. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744629/tesla-autopilot-secret-response-nhtsa-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744629/tesla-autopilot-secret-response-nhtsa-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:36:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:36:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The new 14-inch MacBook Pro is already $50 off at Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_t67oBMGzCttlcZxrxqOUZi88mA=/14x0:2026x1341/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041585/akrales_211020_4803_0018.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vW3PZL"&gt;Last week, Apple introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"&gt;its new generation of MacBook Pro laptops&lt;/a&gt;, featuring a new design (complete with a notched screen) and faster M1 chips. If you had your eye on the 14-inch model instead of the 16-inch MacBook Pro, you can save just a little bit of cash on it when you preorder at Amazon. The configuration that has the M1 Pro chip (eight-core CPU, 14-core GPU), 16GB of RAM, and a 512GB SSD &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQSLL92?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;is $1,949.99 instead of $2,000&lt;/a&gt;. A $50 discount isn’t a whole lot, but it’s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="alRiTh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editor-in-chief Nilay Patel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22508064"&gt;just posted first impressions&lt;/a&gt; of his time with the latest MacBook Pro. It’s not a review (stay tuned for that), but check it out if you want to see some fresh images, along with takeaways from real-world usage of the M1 Pro and M1 Max chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="imDSyF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="akS6ee"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"&gt;Another product that Apple recently debuted&lt;/a&gt; is discounted at Amazon. The new AirPods Pro &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQMJHXY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that ship with a MagSafe charging case are $220&lt;/a&gt; instead of Apple’s $249 price. In terms of features and specs, these are the same wireless earbuds that first shipped in 2019 — you can &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;find those now for $197&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just the case that’s new here, and while we haven’t tested them yet (and thus, don’t know if the case has improved charging speeds or if it’s just magnetized), this is a decent deal I’d recommend for first-time AirPods Pro buyers who want everything they own to have MagSafe compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5oew0P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10826178"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="FQhU0P"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on: big screens, big ambitions, small price|104420" data-volume-uuid="0fd6d24c0" data-volume-id="104420" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-973" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zBspGJ"&gt;If you’re interested in preordering a Google Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"&gt;Best Buy still has stock of the phones&lt;/a&gt; and is including a free set of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465651/google-pixel-buds-a-series-earbuds-review-features-price"&gt;Pixel Buds A-series&lt;/a&gt; wireless earbuds at checkout through Wednesday, October 27th. Those normally cost $100, so this is a solid incentive. Google unveiled the Pixel 6 phones last week, and the highlight was on the promising, new Google Tensor chip inside of both of them. Check out the video above for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TAeZAvwbNBRS5kycCzSpvekXfHU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22012245/vpavic_201103_4275_0240.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uBaC7B"&gt;While this isn’t technically a deal, it’s worth sharing that Microsoft’s Xbox Series S console is currently available at Best Buy &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfRvlrDzyZc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for its normal $300 price&lt;/a&gt;. It was tough to find for several months following its debut in late 2020, and you may want to pick one up now if you planned to give it as a gift during the holidays. Supply of the console may dwindle as we get closer to Black Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NMpxId"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="NabZZD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/25/22744535/apple-macbook-pro-amazon-airpods-magsafe-google-pixel-6-buds-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/25/22744535/apple-macbook-pro-amazon-airpods-magsafe-google-pixel-6-buds-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:16:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:16:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite’s new campaign trailer has Master Chief chasing Cortana</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EQap1us9Ev4iBwCRc8yQIl1wXrA=/185x0:2243x1372/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041529/Screen_Shot_2021_10_25_at_9.04.27_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rGzWVh"&gt;Microsoft has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XCbMVbeKlCg"&gt;finally revealed&lt;/a&gt; a new look at &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign mode, marking the first time that developer 343 Industries has shown the campaign since its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21335520/halo-infinite-gameplay-xbox-series-x-trailer-demo"&gt;initial gameplay reveal in July 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XvJb6h"&gt;The new six-minute trailer shows off a lot of Infinite’s new gameplay and systems in a short amount of time, including new weapons, new enemies, menacing bosses, and a new AI companion character that will be accompanying players called “The Weapon.” The overview also shows off some of Infinite’s new open world gameplay and RPG style gameplay additions, which include optional bases and objectives for players to pursue and selectable upgrades for equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VIy3Fsmq0QubSBbZK4Tb-Ps0DL4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953711/Screen_Shot_2021_10_25_at_9.06.41_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Rh0sIB"&gt;Set after 2015’s &lt;em&gt;Halo 5: Guardians&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt; is the first mainline Halo game in over five years and will look to pick up the story of the artificial intelligence revolution led by Master Chief’s former ally Cortana that served as &lt;em&gt;Halo 5&lt;/em&gt;’s cliffhanger. &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt; will also pick up story threads from 2017’s real-time strategy spinoff &lt;em&gt;Halo Wars 2&lt;/em&gt;, which introduced the latest strain of Halo’s classic Covenant antagonists, the Brute-led “Banished.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OxVBlK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZtc5-syeAk"&gt;initial gameplay reveal&lt;/a&gt; was viewed by many as underwhelming, spawning disappointment in the purportedly next-gen visuals and the infamous “Craig” meme that dunked on a close-up shot of a particularly poorly rendered Brute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OEqyxM"&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;set to launch in just a few weeks on December 8th, the new campaign overview isn’t just a chance for 343 Industries to give players a better idea of what to expect from the game when it arrives, but also a chance for redemption and to better sell fans on &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s potential after its lackluster first impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5j3pyw"&gt;While 343 Industries has largely been keeping &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign under wraps (until today’s reveal, at least), the studio has been letting players try out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531861/halo-infinite-e3-2021-trailer-demo-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s free-to-play multiplayer mode&lt;/a&gt; in a series of preview weekends. These weekends have had a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22725770/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview"&gt;far more positive reception&lt;/a&gt; as an exciting evolution (and in many ways, a return to form) for the franchise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YqeUuB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Halo Infinite multiplayer feels like an exciting return to form","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22725770/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OVLTHm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;was originally intended to launch alongside the Xbox Series X and Series S last fall, but the game was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"&gt;delayed to 2021&lt;/a&gt; due to a variety of development challenges, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. It’s now set to arrive on PC, Xbox Series X / S, and Xbox One platforms on December 8th, although the game will ship &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634448/halo-infinite-co-op-campaign-forge-delay-launch"&gt;without a few key features&lt;/a&gt;, including the campaign’s co-op mode and the popular Forge multiplayer map editor, both of which are slated for a 2022 release in a future update. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744558/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-preview-trailer-master-chief-xbox-series-x"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744558/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-preview-trailer-master-chief-xbox-series-x</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon announces Alexa program for hospitals and senior care</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4qVseXkyIDAlBt8LnZjgE5LP9FY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041474/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PGi8NN"&gt;Amazon has two new programs that integrate Alexa into hospitals and senior living communities, the company announced today. They’re run through Alexa Smart Properties, which allows organizations to control a centralized Alexa system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmQyj6"&gt;“Early on in the pandemic, hospitals and senior living communities reached out to us and asked us to help them set up Alexa and voice in their communities,” Liron Torres, global leader for Alexa Smart Properties, said in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Hospitals wanted ways to interact with patients without using protective equipment, and senior living communities wanted to connect residents with family members and staff, she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWuNyJ"&gt;The program lets senior living facilities use Amazon Echo devices to send announcements or other messages to residents’ rooms. During the COVID-19 pandemic, many facilities relied on printed out sheets of paper slipped under resident doors to communicate changes in protocols, like around meals or quarantines. The Alexa program lets them send messages instantly into patient rooms. “Staff can be more available for other tasks,” Torres says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xzKRkb"&gt;Residents can also place calls through Alexa to family members or friends without having to rely on a staff member. Approved contacts would also be able to call in through Alexa. The facility could enable calling for a set of contacts approved by the resident and family members when they arrive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pa2Fdp"&gt;Two networks of senior living communities, Atria (which is nationwide) and Eskaton (based in California), are adding Alexa to some facilities, Amazon said. Amazon declined to say how much the program costs those facilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rxXiSj"&gt;In hospitals, the Alexa Smart Properties program lets nurses communicate with patients through the calling and intercom-esque drop-in features without having to enter patient rooms. Patients could ask questions, or nurses could check on how someone is feeling through the feature. “This enables hospitals to increase productivity and be able to save on medical supplies,” Torres says. Hospitals can also send information and announcements to patients through Alexa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taihVt"&gt;Patients can toggle on “do not disturb” to prevent drop-ins, Torres says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LsQU6C"&gt;Cedars-Sinai Medical Center in Los Angeles, BayCare Health System in Florida, and Houston Methodist are adding Alexa to their facilities, Amazon said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2oQvW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22740181/amazon-alexa-hospitals-senior-living"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22740181/amazon-alexa-hospitals-senior-living</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
