<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-21T13:42:48-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:42:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:42:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mercedes-Benz EQS will cost over $100,000 but is still cheaper than an S-Class</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zcZA04A3DITm0pULs3vB9tAqiDY=/428x0:5045x3078/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889348/The_All_New_EQS.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZsDOKu"&gt;Mercedes-Benz just announced the pricing of its all-electric luxury sedan, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375877/mercedes-benz-eqs-ev-s-class-specs-hands-on"&gt;the EQS&lt;/a&gt;, and not surprisingly, it starts north of $100,000. What is surprising, though, is that the starting price is cheaper than a gas-powered S-Class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hRvyJ2"&gt;When it arrives at dealerships this fall, the EQS will start at $102,310. By comparison, the 2022 Mercedes-Benz S-Class starts at $111,350. This is a rare case of an electric vehicle selling cheaper than its gas equivalent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DyAoO2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is a rare case of an electric vehicle selling cheaper than its gas equivalent. &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MsnTct"&gt;Mercedes is offering three trim levels: Premium, Exclusive, and Pinnacle. Each trim comes in two versions, depending on the size of the infotainment screen: the 450+ sedan with a 12.8-inch portrait touchscreen; or the 580 4MATIC (yes, I know, these brand names are inscrutable) with the 56-inch Hyperscreen. Both versions of each trim come with Mercedes’ MBUX voice-activated assistant as standard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8YB3k2"&gt;Here is a glance at the features that come with each trim level:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7-7rhxLY6sVwJ2RrEet-nmu5D4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867622/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_1.14.47_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2smZFH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588587/mercedes-benz-electric-ev-2030-caveat"&gt;As we’ve noted previously&lt;/a&gt;, Mercedes is interested in testing out whether customers are willing to pay more for added features, even after buying the vehicle. The company is offering various add-ons, like an increased steering angle for the rear wheels, which customers can pay to unlock and then receive as an over-the-air software update. It’s easy to see how the initial cost can rise steadily as owners decide they want more unique features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9utUbt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 2022 Mercedes-Benz EQS is a declaration of maximum electric luxury","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375877/mercedes-benz-eqs-ev-s-class-specs-hands-on"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="8ZnPwu"&gt;Still, it’s clear that Mercedes is trying to make a statement by pricing the EQS cheaper than the S-Class. The company has said it wants to shift to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588587/mercedes-benz-electric-ev-2030-caveat"&gt;EV-only sales by 2030&lt;/a&gt;. To get there, it will need to price its vehicles in a way that will make its wealthy customers think twice about replacing their old S-Class with just another gas-powered vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686248/mercedes-benz-eqs-electric-vehicle-price-cheaper-s-class"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686248/mercedes-benz-eqs-electric-vehicle-price-cheaper-s-class</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:13:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:13:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>As lawsuits pile up, Activision Blizzard loses its chief legal officer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0N8rJkkZxxdBBH8DnnI0YfR3lpQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889215/acastro_210729_1777_blizzard_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uo75mT"&gt;Another high-level Activision Blizzard employee has left the company. Claire Hart, Blizzard’s chief legal officer, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/claireelisehart_after-more-than-three-years-at-blizzard-entertainment-activity-6845779647314169856-Nnrf/?src=aff-lilpar&amp;amp;veh=aff_src.aff-lilpar_c.partners_pkw.10078_plc.Skimbit%20Ltd._pcrid.449670_learning&amp;amp;trk=aff_src.aff-lilpar_c.partners_pkw.10078_plc.Skimbit%20Ltd._pcrid.449670_learning&amp;amp;clickid=waH1njULNxyORZnwUx0Mo38VUkBQ6MyXVRgd2Q0&amp;amp;irgwc=1"&gt;announced in a LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt; that her last day was Friday, September 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YFm0Tt"&gt;“The past three years have been full of unexpected twists and turns, but I feel honored to have worked with and met so many great people at Blizzard and across the Activision Blizzard businesses,” Hunt said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UDzQpG"&gt;Those “unexpected twists and turns” might be an allusion to the series of legal troubles Activision Blizzard faces due to allegations of harassment, abuse, and discrimination. To date, Activision Blizzard is facing suits from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Nx3jXE"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;California Department of Fair Employment and Housing&lt;/a&gt; for enabling a “culture of harassment.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xS5Ran"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ecf.cacd.uscourts.gov/doc1/031136037480"&gt;Its own investors&lt;/a&gt; for essentially failing to accurately disclose knowledge of these harassment and discrimination problems to investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xA5s6g"&gt;The CODE-CWA for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674269/activision-blizzard-sued-nlrb-labor-violations"&gt;unfair labor practices&lt;/a&gt; involving intimidating employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="hQE8OV"&gt;And Activision Blizzard is under investigation by the EEOC and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684779/activision-blizzard-investigation-sec-activision-bobby-kotick"&gt;SEC&lt;/a&gt; — all within the last four months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="toj0zE"&gt;Hunt’s departure is the latest in a string of high-profile employees leaving amidst the company’s ever-growing legal issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9HLKOU"&gt;Blizzard president &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt; and head of global human resources &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608320/blizard-jesse-meschuk-leave-company-hr-svp"&gt;Jesse Meschuk&lt;/a&gt; left in early August. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;Three top game designers&lt;/a&gt; who worked on such titles as &lt;em&gt;Diablo 4&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; also left Blizzard in August. (Blizzard did not confirm if they were fired or left voluntarily.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkAMSB"&gt;Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick said &lt;a href="https://investor.activision.com/news-releases/news-release-details/activision-blizzard-provides-update-workplace-initiatives"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt; that the company is cooperating with all these investigations and that “there is absolutely no place anywhere in our company for discrimination, harassment, or unequal treatment of any kind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LO7gF4"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1bkEp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOMHUD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686183/activision-blizzard-chief-legal-officer-leaves"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686183/activision-blizzard-chief-legal-officer-leaves</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook put a battery in its new Portal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1_ZeTc0jT0_ZVZvVZc3VHXPacvI=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889145/Portal_Go_Portal__Family_Call.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook’s Portal Go and Portal Plus&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8epFkM"&gt;Facebook on Tuesday announced two new Portal video calling devices, the first major refresh of the hardware lineup since 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNzLfm"&gt;The new devices, the Portal Go and updated Portal Plus, retail for $199 and $349, respectively. The 10-inch Portal Go is an all-new, portable form factor wrapped in fabric with a standalone battery, while the latest Portal Plus introduces a sleeker design of the most expensive, 14-inch Portal that first debuted three years ago. Both devices are available now for preorder and start shipping on October 19th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sH7bsy"&gt;Like the rest of the lineup, the Portal Go features a wide-angle camera that automatically follows whoever is in focus, zooming and panning as they move in and out of the center of the frame. It’s the first Portal that doesn’t require a constant power connection, and Facebook is also billing it as a portable Bluetooth speaker with support for Spotify and Pandora. The new Portal Plus functions similarly to its predecessor, but Facebook got rid of the swivel display that could rotate from portrait to landscape view. Both Portals have a physical shutter to cover the camera like past versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="f5E5WM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re really looking ahead to the future of hybrid work.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9b9Aff"&gt;Unlike Amazon’s Echo lineup of smart home devices, Facebook’s Portal is almost entirely intended for video calling. The latest software updates to Portal’s Android-based interface put even more of an emphasis on video calls in a remote work setting. A new calendar app syncs with Outlook or Google to show upcoming meetings and let you quickly jump into calls from Portal’s home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j74RTQ"&gt;Aside from Facebook-owned Messenger and WhatsApp, all Portal devices now support Zoom, Cisco’s Webex, BlueJeans, and GoToMeeting. And in December, Portal will add support for Microsoft Teams, potentially opening it up for use by a wider swath of mid to large-size companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1d74BZ"&gt;The integration with Teams is an example of how Facebook thinks Portal will increasingly be used as a standalone video conferencing device for remote workers. Next year, the company will launch a program to let businesses bulk order and manage Portals that can, for the first time, be used without a Facebook account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AqmGfy"&gt;“We’re really looking ahead to the future of hybrid work,” Micah Collins, Facebook’s director of product management for Portal, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;during a virtual briefing last week. He said that Portal is primarily used between families but that the company saw a noticeable uptick in usage for work meetings since pandemic shutdowns began last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wjquyaTwY28AsZZdc-O70jSMcjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865278/Microsoft_Teams_GroupCall_Portal_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TtmmsIWpbkxzKY4E3qpIanU4nbA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865610/Portal_Go_Video_Call_Kitchen.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VzGpx-gtynMHsgJVKUyIccxhNaI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865613/Portal__Kitchen_Home_Screen.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Portal Plus (top left and above) and the portal Portal Go (top right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fKvMDB"&gt;Facebook hasn’t disclosed Portal sales, but according to the research firm IDC, it shipped more than 600,000 Portals last year, an increase of over 28% from 2019. And it shipped close to 400,000 units in the first half of this year — a signal that sales will grow year-over-year again. Those numbers pale in comparison to the success of Amazon’s Echo lineup, though Amazon hasn’t disclosed sales for its most direct Portal competitor, the video calling-equipped Echo Show. (Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379470/apple-tv-homepod-speaker-camera-video-call-soundbar-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;also rumored&lt;/a&gt; to be working on a dedicated video calling device.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1JBMRX"&gt;While Facebook is showing steady growth with Portal sales, its “growth is dampened by negative brand perceptions,” Adam Wright, IDC’s senior analyst for smart home devices, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;Even still, he noted that “some aggressive marketing during the early stages of the Covid-19 pandemic” helped boost sales by positioning Portal “as a good way to minimize the impacts of lockdowns and social distancing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBalgk"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20913653/facebook-portal-10-inch-2019-review-price-specs-features-whatsapp-video-calling"&gt;our 2019 review of the Portal lineup&lt;/a&gt;, we gave the devices poor marks for the lack of streaming services and apps, poor sound quality for playing music, and the requirement of needing a Facebook account. While the app integrations have certainly improved, Portal still doesn’t support most of the major video streaming services. And a Facebook account is still needed unless the Portal is purchased through the new business program.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684447/facebook-releases-portal-go-plus-video-calling-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684447/facebook-releases-portal-go-plus-video-calling-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roblox will start verifying the age of teenage players</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NI6NMNtfcvBuM8dmxl3puNiN1X0=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889125/Roblox_Age_Verification.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Roblox’s age verification process involves scanning government-issued ID. | Image: Roblox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A1clox"&gt;Roblox is rolling out an age verification feature that will allow players to confirm their age and gain access to features reserved for older players. Age verification will be optional, and Roblox tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it will “not retain any data” from the verification process, which requires showing a form of ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgXArS"&gt;For now, only one feature requires age verification: Roblox’s new voice chat feature, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654884/roblox-voice-chat-spatial-moderation-discord"&gt;Spacial Voice&lt;/a&gt;. During its initial beta test, it will only be available to players who verify they are at least 13 years old. (Roblox didn’t say whether it would later be available to users regardless of verification status.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rPcvpp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Roblox, explained: Everything you wanted to know about one of the biggest apps on the planet","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22457264/roblox-explainer-game-app-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KFdBlu"&gt;But the implication seems to be that other features — perhaps specific Roblox games or community tools — could be age-gated as the company works to protect its relatively young user base. Roblox says more than half of its users are now over 13, but that also implies that &lt;em&gt;nearly &lt;/em&gt;half of its users are still under the age of 13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JHjxd"&gt;Verification will require uploading an “ID card, driver’s license, or passport” as well as a selfie taken “on the spot” to help confirm that the ID was really uploaded by the person to whom it belongs. Roblox only accepts government-issued IDs, which could pose a problem — younger players are less likely to have formal IDs than older players, and that’s likely even less common in certain regions where an ID is harder to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wsyhqq"&gt;The feature starts rolling out today and will be available globally to users who are at least 13 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684672/roblox-age-verification-optional"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684672/roblox-age-verification-optional</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:55:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:55:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 worked fine with the slowest compatible SSD we could find</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YwHqYsnb0TPi6LXwXx2bvXuK8o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69676444/vpavic_4278_20201030_0206.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eGpAhB"&gt;If your PS5 is already running out of speedy solid state storage, there’s a fix. Sony’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22664808/ps5-playstation-5-update-m2-ssd-sony-software"&gt;new update for the PS5&lt;/a&gt;, released in full on September 14th, allows you to expand your paltry 667GB of usable space by popping in the same sort of M.2 SSD stick you might slip into your laptop or desktop PC. My colleague Mitchell has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22366087"&gt;a PS5 SSD buying guide right here&lt;/a&gt; that meets all of Sony’s recommendations, such as speeds of at least 5,500MB/s. That might leave you wondering, though: what about slower SSDs? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AJUnow"&gt;That’s why we tracked down an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/XPG-S50-Lite-Internal-AGAMMIXS50L-1T-C/dp/B08HVZWGPP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ADATA XPG Gammix S50 Lite&lt;/a&gt;, one of the slowest compatible PCIe Gen4 drives we could find at 3,900MB/s reads and 3,200MB/s writes, and stuck it into a PS5 in August. And this week, &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry &lt;/em&gt;corroborated our findings with an even slower SSD with 3,200MB/s writes. The short version: today’s games don’t need all the speed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The PS5 reads 3898.001 megabytes per second in its speed test" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4_5tGJnWAryRays4zRc7ziYw5go=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22759876/IMG_1307.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Yep, that’s a 3900MB/s drive all right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="v7uWpg"&gt;We compared the S50 Lite against both the PS5’s internal SSD and a 5,000MB/s Sabrent Rocket 500GB in a battery of tests, including load times for games like early PS5 showcases &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales.&lt;/em&gt; We also measured how long it takes to back up games to each kind of drive, throwing in a Seagate external HDD for comparison, since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381494/sony-ps5-april-update-games-external-usb-storage-social-features"&gt;Sony now allows you to archive PS5 games and play PS4 games&lt;/a&gt; from an traditional hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dE5QEx"&gt;The verdict? Surprisingly, even the slowest compatible SSD we could find had near-identical load times to the one Sony includes in the box. Sometimes it’s a second slower, sometimes a second or two faster, but basically it’s a total wash. Hopping through dimensions in &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;, I saw no appreciable difference with the slowest SSD in gameplay, either. Stepping through pocket dimensions was instantaneous, and when there was a slight pause during a boss fight, I saw the same pause on the internal SSD as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qHZe23"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10684101"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zea66Q"&gt;I also didn’t necessarily see a huge difference between the drives when it comes to transferring games back and forth, but there was one big surprise: at least in this beta, it appears that Sony may be throttling the write speed of the PS5’s own internal drive. It took only 2:26 to send &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22274549/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-ps5-update-graphics-expansion"&gt;both PS5 and PS4 copies&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; to the Sabrent SSD, for instance, but 12:47 to go back to the PS5 — over five times longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="59Q8qI"&gt;On average, I saw write speeds of around 1,100MB/s transferring my five test games to either of my add-in M.2 drives, but just around 220MB/s sending those same games back to the PS5. Both of those are far better than the 141MB/s average transfer speeds I saw sending games to the Seagate HDD and the 97MB/s I saw beaming them back — it took over half an hour (31:24) to transfer the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games’ 176.5GB back to the internal SSD. But the slower internal SSD write speeds are weird, and Sony didn’t have a comment when I asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QT365P"&gt;In late September, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2021-the-worst-and-best-nvme-ssds-tested-on-playstation-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry &lt;/em&gt;tested an even slower drive&lt;/a&gt;: the 256GB version of Western Digital’s SN750 SE, which is capable of just 3,200MB/sec reads. And yet, the results were the same. Even with a drive that only offers 58 percent of the speeds Sony asks for, there was effectively no difference in today’s games — and Sony appears to be artificially limiting transfers back to the internal drive for some undisclosed reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSk2nn"&gt;So the big question is this: if not today, will game developers fully optimize tomorrow’s games for the incredible speeds a top-tier SSD can afford? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D718aM"&gt;For instance, take a look at our load times for &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; in our original chart above. Regardless of drive, the PS4 version takes over four times longer to load! It’s the difference between waiting through a loading screen filled with gameplay tips to keep you occupied, and — at 10 seconds flat from the time you leave the PS5’s home screen to the time you can move Cloud Strife in your save game — barely seeing a loading screen at all. The latter is incredible to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YlIBe4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4WZ3pTe61O4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kOH5dC"&gt;Also, see our &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Miles Morales &lt;/em&gt;numbers? The game doesn’t &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; load as quickly as it could. Sometimes, you’ll boot up the game to see Marvel, Insomniac, and PlayStation Studios intros that eat up a whole 26 seconds, making the game take more like 43 seconds to load in total. But other times, it’ll mysteriously bypass those, loading in more like 17 seconds, and I couldn’t figure out why. I’d love to have a toggle to turn off those intros, and here’s hoping more PS5 games skip them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4F4sa4"&gt;Would I run out and buy the slowest PCIe Gen4 SSD I can buy for my PS5? I’m not so sure, because Sony picked its recommended SSD spec for a reason — even if today’s games and today’s PS5 aren’t taking full advantage, developers may need that additional headroom in the future. They’ve been promised 5,500MB/s to deliver instant game worlds, and I’d hate to find out I bought the wrong drive years down the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5sHxD"&gt;Plus, there might already be some moments in &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;where you’ll notice a difference, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fitzymj/status/1420825603784122371"&gt;says Insomniac technical director Mike Fitzgerald&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lXpgVe"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We tried some below-spec Gen4 M.2 drives as well and saw up to 15% slower loading in the most SSD-stressing areas of the game. Not too shabby, but keep a close eye on technical specs if you’re making an SSD purchase, as our game does rely on high-quality storage.  &lt;/p&gt;— Mike Fitzgerald (@fitzymj) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fitzymj/status/1420825603784122371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jj3Wyt"&gt;Then again, Microsoft also uses an SSD in its Xbox Series X, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21185141/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-comparison-specs-features-release-date"&gt;but one with sustained raw performance at 2.4GB/s&lt;/a&gt;, compared to the PS5’s listed 5.5GB/s read speeds. So even if developers do take advantage, it’s possible many next-gen games never see the full benefit if they’re targeting both Xbox and PlayStation instead of PS5 specifically. You’ll likely see the most benefit from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432601/sony-playstation-studios-ps5-games-25-new-ip-interview"&gt;Sony’s exclusive PlayStation Studios titles,&lt;/a&gt; though Square Enix’s speedy &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade&lt;/em&gt; load times gives me hope for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pm1LS1"&gt;Either way, for a list of SSDs that actually meet Sony’s requirements and recommendations, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-m2-ssd-options-buying-guide-which-drives-compatible-playstation-5"&gt;here’s our buying guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UmGd7q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 2:08PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Clarified that we tested Ratchet and Clank gameplay, not just load times, and that the Xbox Series X’s 2.4GB/s is a sustained performance metric.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="paMKk4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, September 21st at 12:55PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added Digital Foundry’s tests with an even slower 3,200MB/sec drive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iu_-r-2u58AoJ6EYQq4n1dD3Go8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22748660/ps5ssd1_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22608153/ps5-ssd-speed-test-storage-expansion-m2-playstation-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22608153/ps5-ssd-speed-test-storage-expansion-m2-playstation-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:53:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:53:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to put the Windows 11 Start menu back where it belongs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ClCbBuO0Gjyguk3pBcR7RYmAtQE=/8x0:2552x1696/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889116/twarren__windows11main_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T5Thwy"&gt;When you upgrade from Windows 10 to Windows 11, one of the first things you may do is wonder: where the heck is my Start menu? Traditionally, the Windows Start menu has been in the lower left corner of the screen, but when your new version of Windows appears, you’ll find the Start icon among a group of icons in the center of your taskbar at the bottom of the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Windows 11 Start menu is now a small icon in the center of the taskbar." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UV3BYnWrdkbDe3--xDj1Rmf7YtU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867032/Screenshot__7_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Windows 11 Start menu is now a small icon in the center of the taskbar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SDCe0H"&gt;Click on the Start menu icon, and things will look very different as well. Instead of the large square Live Tiles that used to pop up, you have a much more modest set of app icons, mostly showing Microsoft-related apps, pinned to the main page. Click on “All apps” on the top right corner (just below the search field) and you get the familiar A-to-Z listing of apps. But no tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OVPJLr"&gt;Look below the app icons, and you’ll find a “Recommended” section, which offers apps that Microsoft thinks you should try (such as Teams), and if you click on the “More” button, some of the files or apps you may have used recently.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Clicking on the search field offers immediate access to several popular apps." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ReSjcCcMS3g2GEWZxHLRLcTpZqI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867098/Screenshot__12_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clicking on the search field offers immediate access to several popular apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SJ9dGZ"&gt;By the way, that search field? Click in that, and the Start menu will open up, giving you immediate access to File Explorer, settings, and other apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="20teRv"&gt;While some may appreciate this more puritanical version to the Start menu, others who have gotten used to the more configurable version in Windows 10 may want to know how they can go back to the more familiar, and more personal, version.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can move the Start icon to the left using the Taskbar alignment option in your setup menu." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ARWcH79s26rDxObk_7UdhDSCXWY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867042/Screenshot__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can move the Start icon to the left using the taskbar alignment option in your setup menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P3ceG8"&gt;You can get some of the way there by moving the centered apps to the left of the taskbar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kSbuWv"&gt;Right-click on the taskbar and click on “Taskbar settings”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NEijmh"&gt;Select “Taskbar behaviors”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gsR825"&gt;Look for “Taskbar alignment” and click on the button on the right where it says “Center.” Select “Left” instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1yMLuh"&gt;Close the settings window, and you’ll see that the app icons in the taskbar have moved to the left, with the Start menu icon in the corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Now the Start menu icon is in the left corner, but the menu itself is unchanged." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ehJQnjDhrKnHt7zz_r7OnlJO3BU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867047/Screenshot__22_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now the Start menu icon is in the left corner, but the menu itself is unchanged.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OFlR5U"&gt;While this will place the Start menu back where you expected it, it will not restore the one you were used to. To get that back, you’re going to have to go to a third-party app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dqasxh"&gt;As this was being written, there was already at least one available. Stardock, a company whose Start10 app allows Windows 10 users to keep their beloved Windows 7 menu UI, has already made available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22619930/stardock-start11-windows-11-start-menu-beta"&gt;a beta of its Start11 app&lt;/a&gt;, which it says will bring back the classic Windows 10 Start menu. The apps costs $5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qXYrPB"&gt;So far, Start11 is the only app we’ve found that purports to restore the Windows 10 menu system. It is sure not to be the last, though — there were several apps out there that catered to Windows 7 fans when Windows 10 came out, and you can bet that there will soon be other alternatives for the Windows 10 “look” as well. (There are some regedit hacks floating around out there, but most are either very elaborate or &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/windows-11-classic-start-hack-gone"&gt;were made useless somewhere along Microsoft’s beta cycle&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zlu3QV"&gt;If a better solution presents itself, we’ll be sure to let you know.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22684671/windows-11-microsoft-start-menu-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22684671/windows-11-microsoft-start-menu-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:43:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:43:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now preorder the new Kindle Paperwhite</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kZNu61OmL4t3bHBvN6t8mqtMkH8=/168x0:1752x1056/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69889078/MGFhY2EzMDIt._CB641020890_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new e-reader is still waterproof and adds new features for an increased price.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JcOVZW"&gt;Amazon has officially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684801/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-features-price-release-date"&gt;taken the wraps off&lt;/a&gt; of the 11th-gen Kindle Paperwhite ahead of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684357/amazon-fall-event-devices-services-features-september-28th-echo-alexa"&gt;fall event on September 28th&lt;/a&gt;, and preorders are now open directly from the retail giant. The new Kindle comes in three flavors: a standard model (with or without ads), a Signature Edition, and one designed for kids. All versions of the 2021 Kindle Paperwhite will launch on October 27th. Preorders are only open at Amazon as of right now, but we’ll update this post with more retailers as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FNpl7P"&gt;The new baseline Kindle Paperwhite is the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08KTZ8249?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11th-gen ad-supported model, which starts at $140&lt;/a&gt;. The price represents a $10 increase over its predecessor, though, the last-gen model has seen some larger discounts in recent months. We will see if the higher price is justified once we do our full review, but improvements like a bigger screen, USB-C charging, longer battery life, adjustable color temperature, and a speedier processor sound appealing on paper. Ditching the lock screen ads will cost you an additional $20, bringing the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N38WQSH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ad-free Paperwhite to $160&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="waVKQq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Kindle deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="BE4ZvB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10765216"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sO5I6W"&gt;The pricier, step-up tier comes in the form of the new Kindle Paperwhite Signature Edition. This model offers Qi wireless charging, a massive (for e-books, mind you) 32GB of storage, and a light sensor that automatically adjusts the display illumination in response to ambient lighting conditions, a feature once reserved for the Kindle Oasis. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08B495319?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ad-free Signature Edition will run you $190&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3HRBkW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10765329"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qDwMtX"&gt;Lastly, Amazon is offering a new Kindle Paperwhite geared toward children. The apt-titled Kindle Paperwhite Kids is the same as the base model but comes with a one-year subscription to Amazon Kids Plus, giving your child access to a trove of kid-friendly books and audiobooks. The Kids model also comes with a two-year warranty and a kid-friendly cover, which is available in three different designs. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WPB8PW9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Paperwhite Kids costs $160&lt;/a&gt;, the same as a standard Paperwhite model without ads, and it is also not ad-supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mySaO2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10765369"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22685873/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-preorder-buy-how-to-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22685873/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-preorder-buy-how-to-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:29:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:29:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Demi Adejuyigbe reminds us that, once again, it’s September 21st </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T-ckEXjcjxGV5E2WYUlT4LPsPGk=/287x0:2594x1538/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69888999/Screen_Shot_2021_09_21_at_9.28.18_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Demi Adejuyigbe/YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WhAGjL"&gt;The 21st of September? Buddy, that’s today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8dNXMu"&gt;Lest you forget, comedian Demi Adejuyigbe has returned to memorialize Earth, Wind &amp;amp; Fire Day — more specifically September 21st, subject of the band’s evocative summer anthem “September.” For years, Adejuyigbe has jumped on the opportunity to mark the occasion with elaborate, often outrageous videos that have included everything from aerial banners to a mariachi band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nauq0I"&gt;The videos have become such a reliable marker of the end of summer that Adejuyigbe was able to hit a goal of $50,000 for charity &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21449277/september-21st-date-demi-adejuyigbe-earth-wind-fire"&gt;in just three hours&lt;/a&gt; last year, with the campaign ultimately generating more than $330,000 over the period of several days (more than $50,000 per charity listed). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sBlv5V"&gt;Adejuyigbe’s video for 2021 hit the interwebs not too long after 9:21AM PT. This year, he’s raising money for Imagine Water Works, a disaster relief organization helping with Hurricane Ida relief; the West Fund, a nonprofit for abortion access in Texas; as well as climate advocacy organization the Sunrise Movement. Adejuyigbe is raffling off a painting — September 21st-themed, as expected — that he promises to hand-deliver to the winner, regardless of where they live. Donations of $10 count toward a single raffle ticket. For each $100,000 reached, Adejuyigbe will also raffle off a September 21st jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nteekw"&gt;Adejuyigbe said this year’s video will be his last, but added that he hopes “we can use this last video to do some good.” Raffle tickets can be purchased &lt;a href="https://actionnetwork.org/fundraising/september-21stthats-today-by-demi-adejuyigbe"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;. As of 9:45AM PT, the fundraiser had already generated more than $50,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPsfv8"&gt;More of Adejuyigbe’s September 21st videos can be found below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zcZ8Xd"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_zzEDrYTkkg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="0WaRCy"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hpU6UEq8hA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="J2WRqp"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CG7YHFT4hjw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="odJHSV"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fPpUYXZb2AA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="c2faHY"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kPwG6L73-VU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686047/demi-adejuyigbe-september-21st-earth-wind-fire"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686047/demi-adejuyigbe-september-21st-earth-wind-fire</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:23:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:23:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>A new cybersecurity center wants to protect medical devices against hacks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Close-up of insulin pump with tubing being charged on desktop." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PuPxM2T1hUw_5uuE7IciT1sckAI=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69888965/1235021804.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Matt Harbicht / Getty Images for Tandem Diabetes Care&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KxAomE"&gt;It’s been around 10 years since security researcher Jay Radcliffe got up onstage at a conference and demonstrated that he was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/medtronic-security/medtronic-insulin-pumps-vulnerable-to-hackers-idUSN1E77O1VJ20110826"&gt;able to hack&lt;/a&gt; into his own insulin pump. If he’d wanted, he could have used the pump to deliver a lethal dose of the drug into his system. Instead, he demanded that medical companies take the security threat seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFtjwb"&gt;That presentation and &lt;a href="https://medcitynews.com/2012/03/hacker-shows-off-vulnerabilities-of-wireless-insulin-pumps/"&gt;others like it&lt;/a&gt; were wake-up calls about the potential danger of connecting vulnerable medical devices to the internet, says Mike Johnson, a securities technologies expert at the University of Minnesota’s Technological Leadership Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QqFHkt"&gt;In the decade since, there’s been an explosion in the number of connected medical devices — drug infusion pumps, pacemakers, monitors — that makes the issue even more pressing. There is an average of 10 to 15 internet-connected devices on each hospital bed, security researchers &lt;a href="https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/tech/82-healthcare-organizations-have-experienced-iot-focused-cyber-attack-survey-finds"&gt;estimate&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s just a matter of time,” Johnson says. “There are more devices and more exposure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EslhLs"&gt;That exposure is one reason the University of Minnesota set up a new Center for Medical Device Cybersecurity, which launched at the beginning of September in partnership with medical device companies like Medtronic (which made Radcliffe’s pump) and Boston Scientific. The center will function as a hub to help groups that touch medical devices at every stage in their lifecycle, from their development to their use at a patient’s bedside, understand and manage the cybersecurity risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cdn1Uj"&gt;“We want to bring all of these participants into the process and hopefully give them tools,” says Johnson, who’s involved with the center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2a27zy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; talked with Johnson about the center’s goals and the cybersecurity risks around medical devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zTHutk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWwQO1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it important to focus on the security of medical devices?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QyT1tk"&gt;Medical device security has been on the radar of security risk managers for a decade or more. Suddenly, there’s been an explosion in the healthcare arena around connected devices. The numbers today are 10 to 15 devices connected per hospital bed, and that’s a combination of bedside devices and potentially wearable or implanted devices as well. The more things we add to a network, the more chances it can be impacted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QkA8yY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There hasn’t been a really high-profile case of a patient being killed or seriously harmed, but it’s just a matter of time.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6NbIyk"&gt;There hasn’t been a really high-profile case of a patient being killed or seriously harmed, but it’s just a matter of time. We know the criminal element changes. They’re mostly driven by money, but there are other people driven by making a splash, like a terrorist group wanting to kill someone over the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fWAdc9"&gt;As the risk increases, security professionals and device manufacturers and others are saying, “Well, we really need to stay ahead of this.” Healthcare is not waiting for the massive accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYdYPt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18293817/cybersecurity-hospitals-health-care-scan-simulation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ransomware attacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on hospitals have been a significant and escalating issue for healthcare in the United States. Does that impact medical devices as well? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dinQ9R"&gt;The most imminent threat is probably from ransomware. We’ve seen it over and over, and we see it potentially impact &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;patient safety&lt;/a&gt;. So you might think, “What does a medical device have to do with ransomware?” But it’s part of the overall ecosystem. An attacker may not take over a device, but if the device is reliant on a single point of connectivity, and ransomware takes over the command server for the devices, all the devices could stop working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdtzNO"&gt;We want to understand the device’s security itself, but we also want to understand where the device sits in the ecosystem — what factors are important for it to function? What could happen to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GdGcaI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical device companies make the products that can get hacked, but doctors and hospitals use them — and those groups often don’t have the same cybersecurity resources or expertise. How are they involved in these conversations? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUZFAq"&gt;Providers are exposed to a lot of risks, and medical devices are just one of them. A medical device is connected to the network, and so are heating, ventilation and air conditioning. They both have equally important risk issues that need to be addressed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZIRFjS"&gt;When I visualize the spectrum, if you have a device manufacturer on the left, they’re about the nuts and bolts of this piece of equipment. On the right, you have a system like a hospital that has a cybersecurity risk and has something to protect. In the lifecycle of a device, it starts with the manufacturer, and if they do a good job, that’s great — but when they send it out, the security could be reduced because of how it’s deployed at a hospital or health center. That increases the risk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZjnQNf"&gt;They’re an important part of the system and hopefully a part of the center. There’s a very large health system in Minnesota that we’ve been talking to as we work to expand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGaOd0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hospitals aren’t the only places with internet-connected medical devices — pacemakers are implanted in people’s bodies, smartwatches can diagnose &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/12/17850660/apple-watch-series-4-ekg-electrocardiogram-health-2018"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;heart problems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, and people take their blood pressure through app-connected cuffs at home. Can we protect those, too? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eg4zbe"&gt;The home network can be a scary place for anything important. There aren’t the same resources, and there are all kinds of things that can go wrong. But you have to look at everything in terms of risk and impact. If, say, a blood pressure monitor gets hacked, the results could be manipulated. Still, patients with high blood pressure go to the doctor regularly enough, so they’d be able to double-check those numbers — and maybe it wouldn’t be too dangerous. On the other hand, something like a pacemaker is physically inside the patient. Messing with that would be a different story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jdsVHa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The home network can be a scary place for anything important.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JD8mO7"&gt;If manufacturers know this is going to end up inside someone or in someone’s home, they’d do a risk and threat assessment to understand what could happen and how big a deal it would be. Then, they’d design the security controls with that in mind. We would hope that a manufacturer would design it so even in a poorly secured network, you could have a secure connection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k3HwSE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the first step for the center in helping to improve this ecosystem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v0jWKe"&gt;We’re really focusing at the beginning here on generating interest, bringing people into the consortium, and providing training opportunities. We have a hackathon coming up that the center is involved in, and we’re starting on our inaugural introductory training course in device cybersecurity. We’re targeting everyone from big players like [medical device company] Abbott to smaller groups. Medical device cybersecurity is pretty specialized. So this is designed for an engineer, or somebody else in the product development cycle, who wants to understand why security is important and how to improve it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhzRL0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s been around a decade since this emerged as a major issue. How far is there left to go to ensure the whole ecosystem around medical devices is protected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1L5YP"&gt;Security isn’t a fixed end state. There’s not going to be an end state. It’s always a process to improve where improvement is needed and protect things that are most critical to protect. We want to prioritize the changes that can make the most difference and raise the bar over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iTcd6P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DB9Me8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686000/medical-device-cybersecurity-hack-minnesota"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686000/medical-device-cybersecurity-hack-minnesota</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T12:02:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T12:02:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook says it’s spent $13 billion on ‘safety and security’ since 2016</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m192L2nh5OhDyRz5e632-RZf6ZY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69888811/vpavic_160712_1138_0048.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jMEL6o"&gt;Facebook says it’s spent over $13 billion on “safety and security” since 2016 and has 40,000 people dedicated to the area, offering a glimpse at its operations after a week of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039?mod=bigtop-breadcrumb"&gt;leaks published by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The company used the numbers as an example of how it’s addressed problems on Facebook and Instagram, saying the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s stories lacked “important context” about complex issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tpq9U9"&gt;“In the past, we didn’t address safety and security challenges early enough in the product development process,” Facebook &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/our-progress-addressing-challenges-and-innovating-responsibly/"&gt;said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; today. “But we have fundamentally changed that approach. Today, we embed teams focusing specifically on safety and security issues directly into product development teams, allowing us to address these issues during our product development process, not after it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6m7uZX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In the past, we didn’t address safety and security challenges early enough”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K7d1nW"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Journal &lt;/em&gt;alleged that Facebook knew of serious problems like &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-vaccinated-11631880296?mod=article_inline"&gt;false COVID-19 information&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675130/facebook-instagram-teens-mental-health-damage-internal-research"&gt;negative emotional effects&lt;/a&gt; on users but delayed fixing them in fear of weakening engagement with its platforms. Facebook executive Nick Clegg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/18/22681056/facebook-vp-disputes-report-wall-street-journal-instagram-teens-clegg"&gt;issued a rebuttal&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend, accusing the paper of “deliberate mischaracterizations of what we are trying to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QfzR1z"&gt;Much of Facebook’s new response recasts allegations from the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; in a more positive light — focusing not on whether it acted too late, but on the ways it ultimately responded, like removing 20 million pieces of false COVID-19 and vaccination content and blocking 3 billion fake accounts in the first half of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fEAbfE"&gt;If accurate, the new safety and security figures do offer an update on some earlier Facebook numbers. The company has apparently quadrupled its staff in that area since 2017, when it employed 10,000 people and promised to double the number within a year. (The figure includes outside contractors.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aB7OJQ"&gt;Meanwhile, the $13 billion number &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-just-learned-the-true-cost-of-fixing-its-problems/"&gt;backs up a 2018 statement&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook would devote “billions of dollars per year” to safety and security, working out to an average of more than $2 billion annually. We don’t know how that money was distributed between 2016 and 2021, but Facebook made high-profile promises about ramping up investment during 2017 and 2018, which saw scrutiny over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/31/16587342/facebook-senate-hearing-russia-google-twitter"&gt;Facebook’s role in election propaganda campaigns&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/10/17165130/facebook-cambridge-analytica-scandal"&gt;Cambridge Analytica privacy controversy&lt;/a&gt; — so it’s likely a lot of the spending came from recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22685863/facebook-safety-security-staff-spending-misinformation-abuse-wall-street-journal-reports"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22685863/facebook-safety-security-staff-spending-misinformation-abuse-wall-street-journal-reports</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
