<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-12T13:44:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T13:44:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T13:44:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11 is getting updated snipping tool, calculator, and mail apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-lvTFfq19Hj2oW48baKxKEoRk5s=/126x0:1154x685/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69716589/mail_dark_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The updated Mail app for Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FGpvzu"&gt;Microsoft is improving some of the built-in apps available in Windows 11. Windows Insiders in the Dev Channel can now test new updates to the Snipping Tool, Calculator, Mail, and Calendar apps. Some of the updates are minor, but all are designed to match the new visual style in Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fdnFG8"&gt;Microsoft is replacing the classic Snipping Tool and Snip &amp;amp; Sketch apps in Windows 11 with a new Snipping Tool app that combines the best features of both apps. The Win + Shift + S keyboard shortcut will be the main way to take a screenshot in Windows 11, and it will activate the snipping menu with various options for selecting what content to screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xIRzk8vguuJGQD2mSOm8VAs0rd8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778653/SnippingDark.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The updated Snipping Tool now has a dark mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eD0eOM"&gt;Once a screenshot has been taken, the Snipping Tool includes edit options for cropping, annotations, and more. Microsoft is even finally adding a dark mode to the Snipping Tool, so it’ll match your Windows 11 theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nmldUA"&gt;Microsoft is also updating its Mail and Calendar apps in Windows 11 to match the operating system’s new visual style. “We have added rounded corners and other adjustments to make them look and feel part of Windows 11,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/08/12/first-set-of-windows-app-updates-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders-for-windows-11/"&gt;says Dave Grochocki&lt;/a&gt;, a senior program manager lead for Windows inbox apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/03YRSO1Lm-_VsbqzMI9rbhczTrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778655/mail_dark_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The updated Mail app for Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/otZrZD-U0rP6wcQ9TI8g7OqrqYQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778657/calendar_light_crop.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The updated Calendar app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pYR42R"&gt;The calculator app in Windows 11 is also getting some minor improvements that will let you set a separate theme to the one you’re using in the rest of Windows. Microsoft has also rewritten the calculator in C#, allowing developers to contribute to its improvements &lt;a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/calculator"&gt;over on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GIrCih"&gt;Finally, Windows 11 testers can now try out one-to-one and group audio or video calling in Microsoft Teams. You can also share your screen, just as you would in the regular Microsoft Teams app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="42oH2P"&gt;These aren’t the only apps that will be updated for Windows 11. Grochocki’s blog post teases more to come as Microsoft looks to finalize Windows 11 in time for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22553666/microsoft-windows-11-october-20th-release-date-hint-rumor"&gt;(likely) October release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22622012/microsoft-windows-11-snipping-tool-mail-calculator-calendar-app-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22622012/microsoft-windows-11-snipping-tool-mail-calculator-calendar-app-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T13:11:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T13:11:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Watch 4 calculates body fat from the wrist </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yo5IKfdL11wzdk-ageD72mDI2vQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69716397/BFARSACE_210810_4707_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lnKqTX"&gt;Samsung’s new Galaxy Watch 4 has a feature that can calculate body fat percentage and muscle mass, the company announced yesterday. It’s the latest tech company to offer a body composition feature, joining Amazon, which has a body fat percentage feature in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538610/amazon-halo-body-fat-percentage-accurate-study"&gt;Halo Band&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mAR60v"&gt;Body fat is generally a better way to assess health than weight, but it’s often calculated using a metric called the body mass index (BMI), which is crude and inaccurate. If wearables prove accurate, they could give people a better resource to monitor their health, Diana Thomas, a mathematician who studies body weight regulation at West Point, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538610/amazon-halo-body-fat-percentage-accurate-study"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in June&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLcz0s"&gt;The Galaxy measures body composition using a technique called bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA), which sends a weak electric current through the body. It’s calculating the amount of water in the body — the signal moves more quickly through tissue that has higher percentages of water. Since fat has a higher water content than muscle, the technique can estimate how much fat is present in a person’s body. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xwkick"&gt;&lt;q&gt;BIA can give an estimate of body fat, but it has limitations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HTImjw"&gt;BIA can give an estimate of body fat, but it has limitations, said Thomas in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. There isn’t a perfect one-to-one ratio between the amount of water in the body and body fat, and the amount of water in the body changes over time, she said. It can go up and down with exercise, for example, or if someone is drinking a lot of water. &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19932820.2020.1741904"&gt;One study&lt;/a&gt; found that BIA overestimated body fat if the measurement was taken right after someone drank around two cups of water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMbnXX"&gt;Most available devices that use BIA to track body composition send the current through the soles of the feet (like a smart scale) or through the palms. Samsung shrunk the sensors down to fit on the back of the watch. The company’s Healthcare Sensor Lab &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-79667-3#Abs1"&gt;published a study&lt;/a&gt; in January 2021 describing the technology. In the study, 203 people had their body composition analyzed by the watch, two other BIA devices, and a device that uses dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) — an X-ray technique that shows fat distribution through the body, which is considered the gold standard for body composition measurement. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-qqlshsvZGNzQta0IieOAjT7UH4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778694/Screen_Shot_2021_08_12_at_1.36.43_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung shrunk down the sensors used for bioelectrical impedance analysis and added them to the watch.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SGvqtJ"&gt;The smartwatch was accurate compared with the DXA measurement, the analysis found. Its calculations were also slightly closer to the DXA measurement than one of the two other BIA devices. Overall, the watch appears to work as well as a smart scale based on this study, Thomas said. She still wouldn’t use it in research studies based on the information available so far — the potential error rate as calculated in the study is too large for that. “For a personal touch point, it may be okay,” she said in the email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2qmPYfIZ9znnxaeTwL7nqKSuIH0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778738/Screen_Shot_2021_08_12_at_1.50.21_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Other BIA devices, like smart scales, use larger electrodes. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pekLos"&gt;Samsung’s approach is different from the body composition analysis feature in Amazon’s Halo. First, the Halo only calculates body fat — not muscle. Its app directs users to take photos of their body, which it combines into a 3D image used to calculate body fat percentage. The system also gets an accurate measure of body fat compared with the DXA, according to an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538610/amazon-halo-body-fat-percentage-accurate-study"&gt;Amazon-funded study&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vkXN3W"&gt;At the very least, both apps appear to work better than BMI at calculating body fat percentage. BMI is frequently used to guide medical decision-making, even though it’s &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/wellness/healthy-bmi-obesity-race-/2021/05/04/655390f0-ad0d-11eb-acd3-24b44a57093a_story.html"&gt;often misleading&lt;/a&gt; — which can skew the diagnosis of some conditions and perpetuate weight-based stigma in healthcare. It’s used, though, because it’s cheap and easy. Most people don’t have access to the more accurate, expensive machines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O84LjU"&gt;It’ll take more research to figure out how reliable the wearables can be in a real-world setting. But they’re easy to use and relatively cheap. If they work well enough to flag trends in people’s body composition that could affect their health, they could make these health metrics more accessible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PRnYcY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621600/samsung-galaxy-watch-body-fat-composition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621600/samsung-galaxy-watch-body-fat-composition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T12:53:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T12:53:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Audi’s new autonomous concept car is also sort of a Transformer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JORLXKIsQY-4fii-iE85y5EXVhs=/357x0:2124x1178/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69716258/A215696_large__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Aqtrs1"&gt;Audi released details of a new concept car this week called the Skysphere, a self-driving roadster that can change shape at the touch of a button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJV99u"&gt;The sleek, villainous-looking convertible pairs an electric powertrain with luxury amenities for a result that even Batman would find a bit over the top. Notably, the vehicle features an adaptable wheelbase that can change size based on the driving mode, as well as a digital cockpit with a retractable steering wheel and pedals that stow away when the car drives itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gW6d30"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a more fantastical outlook on the future than some of the German automaker’s other recent concepts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7qOxsW"&gt;It’s a more fantastical outlook on the future than some of the German automaker’s other &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391245/audi-a6-e-tron-concept-porsche-auto-shanghai-2021"&gt;recent concepts&lt;/a&gt;. But that doesn’t mean it’s any less achievable; at the unveiling event, Audi officials said the Skysphere represents what the company believes it can achieve, likely in the second half of this decade, as it pivots to electric and autonomous vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hs2nGa4R8hJGYwYw9FE_K15FxoE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778501/Aug_12_2021_12_25_56.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4s0UkE"&gt;The Skysphere is expected to have a range of 500km (310 miles), can accelerate 0 to 60mph in under four seconds, and offers about 553 pound-feet of torque. That all sounds fairly normal for a concept car with a hood that splits into two panels and opens like an elevator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T18nbh"&gt;Certainly the most jaw-dropping feature is the expandable wheelbase, in which the vehicle extends an extra 10 millimeters when switching between Sports mode (4.94 meters long) and Grand Touring mode (5.19 meters). That may not seem like a lot, but it’s enough to justify Audi’s claims that you are essentially getting two vehicles in one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30SNGO"&gt;The retractable steering wheel and pedals are a popular feature in concept cars that are meant to highlight the bridge between human and automated driving. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/27/14743922/peugeot-instinct-concept-car-mwc"&gt;Peugeot&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/2/13122632/volkswagens-electric-car-id-paris-diesel-emissions"&gt;Volkswagen&lt;/a&gt; both released concept cars with similar stowaway controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0Izx0g"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10698437"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yFHrX8"&gt;It’s not clear whether regulations will allow for the sale of a car with a retractable steering wheel — though policymakers are diligently at work on refining the rules of the road to better accommodate self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LiLaJQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621735/audi-skysphere-concept-car-autonomous-electric-transformer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621735/audi-skysphere-concept-car-autonomous-electric-transformer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T12:45:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T12:45:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Free Guy guy gets paid Fortnite skin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H4_aI0MO1ea0KLyeTT-IPGBxEPQ=/157x0:1936x1186/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69716217/Screen_Shot_2021_08_12_at_12.09.59_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zjWHw8"&gt;It’s another day ending in -y so &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is having a new crossover event. Today, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players can complete quests in order to earn &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/free-guy-quests-in-fortnite"&gt;a new &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; skin and emote&lt;/a&gt;. It was inevitable that &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; would get a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; crossover in some way. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is slowly gobbling up every &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608624/fortnite-street-fighter-guile-cammy-are-coming-to-fortnite"&gt;video game&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22553914/fortnite-crew-loki-release-date"&gt;pop culture&lt;/a&gt; IP known to man, so it’s only natural that the video game movie would get a piece of that action, too. After all, &lt;em&gt;Free Guy &lt;/em&gt;is the closest we’ve ever gotten to an actual &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;movie — for now. (Which is exactly the threat it sounds like.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qDJOMn"&gt;The “Dude” skin is a super beef-ified version of Ryan Reynolds’ character Guy and looks like the kind of person who routinely sets off the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=lunk+alarm&amp;amp;oq=lunk+alarm&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j0i512j0i131i433i512j0i512l4j69i60.1496j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8"&gt;lunk alarm&lt;/a&gt; at Planet Fitness. Dude curiously has a blue button up shirt tattooed on one of his pectorals which, I’m told by &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; reporter Chaim Gartenberg (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22611123/free-guy-review-ryan-reynolds-jodie-comer-video-game-movie"&gt;who reviewed Free Guy&lt;/a&gt;), has an actual Serious Lore explanation. Players can also earn the Good Guy emote, which features Ryan Reynolds’ voice saying, “Don’t have a good day, have a great day,” while the character does a little twirl that would make New Edition proud. Since the emote is voiced, developer Epic says that voice lines will be fully localized in game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIYyQc"&gt;Starting today and lasting until September 6th, finding special ATMs scattered around the world will give quests for players to complete. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players can complete quests in order to earn &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/free-guy-quests-in-fortnite"&gt;a new &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; emote&lt;/a&gt;, while a skin goes on sale at 8PM ET tonight. Soon you too can look like the most generic dudebro ever to grace &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; since... &lt;a href="https://fortnite.fandom.com/wiki/Jonesy"&gt;Jonesy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SatuHI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUKuCT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621903/free-guy-fortnite-skin-ryan-reynolds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621903/free-guy-fortnite-skin-ryan-reynolds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T12:31:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T12:31:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon vows to protect Tracfone’s low-income users in new merger promise </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QZGmqIeg1HoJ4jOg442u2zdC-P4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69716127/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aafQny"&gt;On Thursday, Verizon announced a range of new public commitments to protect low-income consumers in connection with its proposed acquisition of Tracfone. The commitments are part of a deal with public-interest groups and communications workers unions, who have agreed to support the acquisition on the basis of today’s announcement.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EpSM5T"&gt;For its part of the deal, Verizon pledges to continue to provide Tracfone’s Lifeline subsidy programs for at least three years after the merger closes. Verizon is also promising to offer a subsidized 5G program for low-income Tracfone users. According to the Communication Workers of America (CWA), over 1.7 million Tracfone customers depend on the Lifeline program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1HD7hL"&gt;The CWA, Public Knowledge, and the Benton Institute for Broadband and Society had initially criticized Verizon’s proposed purchase of Tracfone, suggesting that the deal could harm Tracfone’s low-income customer base. But the groups announced Thursday that they would be withdrawing their opposition in response to the new concessions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oYHWTd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These commitments ensure TracFone customers will continue to have access to Lifeline”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZU9RBa"&gt;“These commitments ensure TracFone customers will continue to have access to Lifeline, an essential program for millions of families,” senior CWA researcher Brian Thorn said in a statement Thursday. “Today’s success would not have been possible without the support of our allies and an FCC interested in protecting the interests of customers over corporations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3NmZ4e"&gt;Last September, Verizon announced its plan to purchase Tracfone in a deal valued at more than $6 million. The acquisition would give Verizon over 20 million new subscribers and a tighter grasp on the low-income wireless and value phone market. Verizon plans to close the deal before the end of the year, although the current status of the Federal Communications Commission’s review of the merger is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uVSn87"&gt;Earlier this year, several Senate Democrats called on the FCC to add similar conditions to Verizon’s proposed merger to protect low-income subscribers. On Thursday, Sens. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT), Ron Wyden (D-OR), and Ed Markey (D-MA), among others, applauded the new conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dBZs6N"&gt;“These commitments should now be a floor and a starting place for the FCC’s review of the acquisition and negotiations with Verizon,” the senators wrote. “As important as the terms of these commitments are, the conditions must be made legally binding, vigilantly monitored, and vigorously enforced to ensure the company makes good on these promises.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlmipB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTQf5I"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621905/verizon-tracfone-merger-lifeline-fcc-public-interest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621905/verizon-tracfone-merger-lifeline-fcc-public-interest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The lightest folding electric bike is a costly rideable that almost does it all</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Hummingbird’s second-generation electric bike gets a lot right&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="6kdB23"&gt;“The world’s lightest folding electric bike” is a claim that ostensibly ticks all the boxes for a rideable. A foldable design that makes it easy to store and carry on public transport? Check. An electric motor to take the effort out of hills? Check. A light 22.7-pound (10.3kg) construction that makes it easier to carry in and out of train stations and into your walk-up apartment? Check. The Hummingbird Folding Electric Bike Gen 2.0 has a lot going for it on paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FrcCp4"&gt;It’s an enviable spec list for anyone who, hypothetically, may have recently moved to a building on top of a hill, 20 minutes away from their nearest station. But they’re also specs that anyone looking for a folding bike to help with a public transit-based commute could benefit from. On a crowded train commute, no one wants to be lugging around any more weight than absolutely necessary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHyaSB"&gt;Hummingbird is one of three major producers of folding electric bikes based in the UK alongside Brompton and Gocycle. At £4,495 (around $6,224.50 / €5,303.36), its new e-bike is expensive, even by the standards of these high-spec folding electric bikes (Gocycle’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357905/gocycle-g4-g4i-g4i-plus-prices-folding-e-bikes-specs"&gt;recently announced range of G4 bikes&lt;/a&gt; starts at $3,999, for example, while &lt;a href="https://us.brompton.com/bikes/brompton-electric"&gt;Brompton’s starts at $3,550&lt;/a&gt;). But it’s a bike that comes so close to having it all that, for the right person, this could easily be a price worth paying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8hTRkb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10697893"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZDWCIV"&gt;The Hummingbird Folding Electric Bike Gen 2.0 (which for the sake of brevity I’ll be referring to as the Hummingbird Electric 2.0) has a similar profile to Brompton’s classic folding bikes. Yes, its frame is significantly thicker, but the combination of small, 16-inch wheels with an elongated seat post and handlebar stem means that its profile feels instantly familiar. But Hummingbird has done a better job to minimize and hide as many cables as possible. The bike’s rear motor is entirely self-contained, meaning it also houses the battery and sensors, with no need for additional cables. As such there are just two brake cables running down from the handlebars, one of which is routed internally through the frame to reach the back wheel. There’s no ugly battery pack hanging off the handlebars either. It’s a slick design, all in all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7EVEfQ"&gt;So too are there similarities with Brompton’s folding mechanism here. Opening one latch is enough to let the bike’s back wheel swing and fold up underneath the bike’s frame, and a second folds down the handlebars. A small plastic ridge on the end of the handlebar locks under the rear wheel mechanism to hold it in place. The seat post’s standard height adjust latch can then be used to hide its length within the frame, and the pedals are also removable if you need the extra space (I never did). Folding the bike is a painless process that you can do in under a minute with a little practice, although I found it a little more fiddly to unfold it because of how tightly the handlebars lock onto the rear wheel’s folding mechanism. Hummingbird tells me this is a problem specific to my demo bike, and that it should be less tight on production models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xjCK3v_8FnqB7QEhUxi64rDa6S0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761811/jporter_210803_4693_005.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bike’s folding process is relatively simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pbsiuF"&gt;It’s an easy process, but Hummingbird’s bike doesn’t fold nearly as compactly as a Brompton. While folded, the Hummingbird Electric 2.0 measures 46 x 23 x 8 inches (117 x 60 x 20cm), compared to 23 x 22.2 x 10.6 inches (58.5 x 56.5 x 27cm) for a Brompton or 34.6 x 24.2 x 14.6 inches (83 x 61.5 x 37cm) for Gocycle’s G4. It’s small enough to fit on a moderately crowded train, but you’ll have an easier time if you stow it in an area designed for luggage. At least you don’t have to put up with the restrictions or costs associated with trying to take a full-size bike on the train — in London, for example, there are significant restrictions placed on when you can take non-folding bikes on trains and the Underground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VtHSTf"&gt;What Hummingbird’s electric bike lacks in space efficiency it arguably more than makes up for in portability. Its 22.7 pounds (10.3kg) is lighter than my personal (admittedly budget) full-size aluminum road bike, which is neither electric nor folding. For comparison, Gocycle’s G4 weighs 36.6lbs (16.6kg) and Brompton’s electric bike weighs upward of 36.5Ibs (16.6kg) including its battery. I had little trouble carrying Hummingbird’s bike around the London Underground on an evening when I was too inebriated to ride it home. My only complaint is that I wish it had an option to be wheeled around while folded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q0P5AS"&gt;Given the focus on weight, the e-bike is pretty bare-bones as standard. There are no built-in lights, fenders, kickstand (though you can half-fold the bike to make it freestanding), bell, or a rear rack, though most can be added as optional accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a3qhN34mGw_2hzlY5_QuJVtj0qk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761579/jporter_210803_4693_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hummingbird’s Zehus-manufactured hub motor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rflXwocB0kruUdmQvFk3GPFj1zE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761585/jporter_210803_4693_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A small wireless remote can be used to control the motor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B5tJi9"&gt;The Hummingbird Electric 2.0’s electric elements are almost entirely housed within a new Zehus-manufactured rear hub motor. This motor is the only significant difference between this and Hummingbird’s first electric bike, and it offers more torque and range than the previous motor. You plug the bike’s charger into this motor directly to refill the battery, but it’s not easily removable if you want to charge it separately from the rest of the bike (which is an option for other brands like Gocycle and Brompton). Outside of this motor, the only other sign that this is an electric bike is the small, battery-powered remote attached to the handlebars, which is a far cry from the digital or LED displays found on many other e-bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VZS5A"&gt;There’s no physical button on the motor to turn the bike on, which makes starting your ride a little more complicated than some other e-bikes. But once you’ve activated the motor, it stays on for the duration of the ride. There are three options to turn it on. The simplest, and the one I ended up using for most rides, is to get up to a speed of 10km/h (around 6mph) and then backpedal three full rotations to kick the motor into life. It’s not ideal if, for example, you start your ride at the bottom of a hill which makes getting up to 10km/h on this single-speed bike a challenge, but it’s reliable without much room for error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Y1McL4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are three ways to activate the bike’s motor&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HjzfOa"&gt;The second method is to use the wireless remote attached to the handlebars. This process can be a little finicky, but it’s straightforward once you know what you’re doing. The easiest way is to lift the bike off the ground and start its back wheel spinning with a quick push on its pedal. This wakes up the motor, after which you can press the remote’s central button to establish a connection, and then press it &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; to start up the motor. It can feel unresponsive at first, but once you understand you need to wait for the remote to connect, it’s fairly painless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E4U41M"&gt;Finally, you can engage the motor by using Zehus’ companion app. Like with the remote, you’ll have to start the wheel rotating in order to wake the motor from sleep and ensure the app can discover and connect to it via Bluetooth, but once you’ve done so you can engage the motor in a couple of quick taps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="rD6c9n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s an app, but you don’t have to use it for every ride&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lx74T2"&gt;I broadly don’t like having to use companion apps when it’s not strictly necessary, and thankfully the Zehus app is mostly optional. Yes, the app is used for registering the bike, and yes you’ll need it if you want to tweak the motor’s custom power setting, but you can get away without using this functionality for most day-to-day riding. I found it more convenient to use the bike’s handlebar remote to switch between power output modes, rather than using the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eddMye"&gt;The one app-exclusive feature I could see being useful on a regular basis is a locking function, which applies resistance to the back wheel, making it hard to rotate. Given how light and easy-to-carry the bike is, Hummingbird doesn’t recommend relying on it to prevent a theft on its own. But it’s a nice extra bit of deterrence when paired with a more traditional lock (or two) that makes the e-bike unrideable if stolen. The Hummingbird’s thick frame means that finding a place to affix a D-lock is a bit of a challenge, so in the end I preferred to put a lock through the rear wheel’s frame whenever I needed to head into a shop for ten minutes or so. Given the bike’s $6,000 plus value, however, I’d be careful about locking it up outside for any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K8vDTm63QNo3CEtTdtmCXQ4vXKc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761590/jporter_210803_4693_0013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plant pot not included.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g7MkrR"&gt;Start riding the Hummingbird Electric 2.0, and you’ll very quickly become aware of the fact that over a third of its weight (3.5kg) is concentrated in its rear hub motor. Lean back too much when you take off from a set of lights, and it’s all too easy to pop a wheelie and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hH37T4ZdVj4"&gt;go full Vin Diesel&lt;/a&gt;, especially considering the bike’s relatively relaxed riding position. There was also an occasion going up a steep hill that I felt the beginnings of a wheelie coming along, so it’s definitely something you need to be aware of mid-ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hETxcD"&gt;In general, once you’re up to speed, Hummingbird’s second-generation electric bike is a real joy to ride. Despite its low center of gravity, I never had any issues with balance, nor did I find it at all twitchy to steer like I did with Brompton’s e-bike. It’s a smooth and enjoyable ride, and the amount of carbon used in its construction helps with shock absorption as much as it makes the bike incredibly lightweight. At a push, I think Gocycle’s larger wheels make for a slightly more stable ride, but Hummingbird’s design was still easy to control through London’s streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ba7i3N"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The motor is quiet, but far from silent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MykA47"&gt;Hummingbird’s bike was less comfortable over long rides. During an hourlong ride across London, I started to get sore at around the half-hour mark. After 45 minutes, I was choosing to stand up when stopped at traffic lights to give my poor posterior a rest. Shorter rides than this were generally fine, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cv2Uia"&gt;The bike’s Zehus motor emits a quiet electrical whirring sound, even when in its least powerful eco mode. But it offers a smooth ramp of power as you cycle, with the gentle sensation of someone running behind you with their hand on your back offering an extra bit of assistance, and it’s happy to give you an extra push even from a standstill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xrebTq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I got around 45km of range in my tests&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qBzK5G"&gt;Hummingbird says that its second-generation electric bike should get you around 35km of range when used in its Turbo mode, extending to up to 60km in Eco mode. In practice, I never stuck with just one mode over the course of a ride, and I think most other people would do the same. I found Eco tended to struggle on steep hills, so it made sense to use the bike’s remote to pop it into Turbo mode briefly until I was on level ground. In the end, this meant that I got a little less than 45km of range out of the bike in mixed usage. That was a combination of shorter rides to and from stations, as well as two longer rides between south and north London. I think that’s more than long enough for any single day of riding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nwJWGB"&gt;I was very thankful for the bike’s light weight when its battery did eventually run dry. I wouldn’t say that riding it up a steep hill with no assistance was a &lt;em&gt;pleasant&lt;/em&gt; experience, but it wasn’t bad enough that I had to get off and push. It felt a lot like riding a non-electric folding bike up a steep hill; unpleasant but manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DHHYRq"&gt;As a final note on battery life, Hummingbird says you should expect to get around two weeks of charge out of the bike’s handlebar remote. Unfortunately, it requires an old-fashioned Micro USB cable to charge it. It’s a little annoying having to charge two different elements of the bike, but at least you won’t have to charge the remote as frequently as the main motor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mHumvURs06-suejWqzRsA0fCxvc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761588/jporter_210803_4693_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The handlebar clips under the bike’s frame to hold it together while folded. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VqcpQLXXNUBaFCiRoU_M3TaLdug=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761589/jporter_210803_4693_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s compact, but not as compact as some other folding bikes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="J4grSw"&gt;It’s hard to fault the Hummingbird Electric 2.0 by most normal measures, because clearly this is a bike that’s been designed to offer zero compromises aside from its extortionately high price. And when a bike costs over $6,000, you really do want to be aware of every tiny potential pain point before you make a purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D4F4fI"&gt;So yes, I would have liked for it to be possible to wheel the bike around when folded, and I’m also not a fan of having to keep both the remote and motor’s batteries charged independently. At a push, you could also argue it’d be nice to have an easily removable battery, but when you’re dealing with a folding e-bike it seems fair to assume most people will be stashing these in hallways rather than having to store them in a garage or bike stall on the street. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1U7iAN"&gt;But really, the only problem I have with the bike that could possibly be elevated beyond “quibble” status is its size while folded. It’s just a tad too long to be comfortable to maneuver on very packed public transit, and it’s a shame that your only option is to carry it, with no potential for wheeling it around. As lightweight as it is, it’s still taxing to carry over the long distances necessary in the London Underground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="mdBsKP"&gt;Aside from that, though, the Hummingbird Electric Bike Gen 2.0 ticks basically every box for urban commuters. It’s light enough to carry through a multimodal commute and has enough range to ride over longer distances when you want to skip the train entirely. If you’re spending over $6,000 on a bike, it needs to be able to do it all, and Hummingbird’s bike comes so very close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="efnWwB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEfl89"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22621388/hummingbird-folding-electric-bike-gen-2-lightest-ebike-range-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22621388/hummingbird-folding-electric-bike-gen-2-lightest-ebike-range-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T11:55:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T11:55:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google bans tracking tool that sold users’ location data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j-wP6reSWSE7z6gaaNwURJoGhVQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69715842/acastro_180507_1777_android_privacy_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="25COoC"&gt;Google has banned a company that sold Android users’ location data for COVID-19 mapping and other purposes, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/5db4ad/google-bans-safegraph-former-saudi-intelligence"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. SafeGraph was one of several companies that collected geolocation records through plug-ins in other Android apps, then aggregated it for organizations &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/05/06/opinion/coronavirus-us-reopen.html"&gt;including &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.safegraph.com/blog/safegraph-provides-cdc-fed-and-1000-organizations-with-data-to-fight-the-covid-19-crisis"&gt;Centers for Disease Control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEJLwa"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;, Google told developers in June that they had to remove SafeGraph’s software development kit within seven days. &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; says it’s not clear whether SafeGraph is still collecting any data from Android apps, and &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to Google and SafeGraph to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jjKOnj"&gt;SafeGraph’s ban follows an earlier crackdown on location-collecting apps. In December 2020, Google and Apple banned a similar service called X-Mode Social, which reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgqm5x/us-military-location-data-xmode-locate-x"&gt;worked with the US military&lt;/a&gt; among other customers. Apple didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment on its policy around SafeGraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xsDt7"&gt;SafeGraph data is supposed to be anonymized, but as &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; discusses, location datasets can often reveal details about individuals despite these safeguards. And although users must approve location-gathering by individual apps, many aren’t aware of how their information is being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ff4BmE"&gt;Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR), a frequent critic of location-gathering apps (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395650/wyden-paul-fourth-amendment-is-not-for-sale-act-privacy-data-brokers-clearview-ai"&gt;sponsor of a bill&lt;/a&gt; that would restrict their use by law enforcement) offered both praise and criticism of the move to ban the service. “This is the right move by Google, but they and Apple need to do more than play whack-a-mole with apps that sell Americans’ location information. These companies need a real plan to protect users’ privacy and safety from these malicious apps,” he said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621685/google-ban-safegraph-android-user-data-location-tracking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621685/google-ban-safegraph-android-user-data-location-tracking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T11:13:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T11:13:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nikola wins $2 million DOE grant after founder’s indictment</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iDixNrGGE90b9o6nG1RMNCEf3is=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69715640/nikola_tre2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nikola&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qC5F6U"&gt;Hydrogen trucking startup Nikola has won a $2 million grant from the Department of Energy just two weeks after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22599726/nikola-founder-securities-fraud-charge-milton"&gt;founder and former chairman Trevor Milton was indicted for allegedly committing fraud&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oH6gxD"&gt;The grant is meant to help Nikola research autonomous refueling technologies for hydrogen refilling stations. It was awarded by the DOE’s Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy transportation office as part of its Hydrogen and Fuel Cells R&amp;amp;D program, which is focused on proving the reliability and sustainability of using hydrogen as a zero-emissions power source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jdx303"&gt;The DOE grant comes at a time when the department is getting ready to ramp up funding activity to help advance the United States’ development of clean energy technologies — a priority under President Biden. One of Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm’s &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/jennifer-granholm-interviews-energy-loans-5ceef97a73fc04fe3cca75bf84e91327"&gt;first moves&lt;/a&gt; after she was appointed was to revive the department’s loan program, which has been largely dormant since the early Obama administration. That program made a number of bets on clean energy startups in the aftermath of the recession that blew up in the administration’s face, like solar tech company Solyndra (which went bankrupt after China dramatically drove down the cost of solar panels) and Fisker Automotive (which went bankrupt after problems with its battery supplier). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X8J5Ab"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Biden administration is likely going to get pretty active with grants and loans&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rAxugk"&gt;The DOE loan program also helped some companies survive the tumultuous years of the early clean tech boom, like Tesla. “If you want to have the leading electric vehicle manufacturer in the world... you’ll have to make multiple bets. And some of those bets will lead to losses,” new loan program head Jigar Shah said &lt;a href="https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/how-jigar-shah-plans-to-manage-does-40b-loan-programs-office"&gt;when he was tapped earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s separate from the grant programs, the DOE loan program is known to be in discussions with at least one other troubled EV startup: Lordstown Motors, which has said for months now that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.tribtoday.com/news/local-news/2021/01/lmc-moves-forward-in-loan-program/"&gt;in the “due diligence” phase of a request from about $200 million&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yzuBGC"&gt;Nikola has spent much of the last year trying to rebound from Milton’s ousting, which came after he was accused of lying about the progress the startup had made by the time it went public. Short-selling research firm Hindenburg Research published a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21448729/nikola-electric-hydrogen-truck-fraud-allegations-executive-chairman-founder-trevor-milton"&gt;report last September&lt;/a&gt; that tried to make the case that Nikola was an “intricate fraud,” including the now famous claim that the startup had staged a video showing one of its trucks operating by secretly rolling it down a hill. The report torpedoed General Motors’ decision to take an 11 percent stake in Nikola, and Milton resigned soon after. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w13FDS"&gt;Nikola eventually performed &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2021-02-26/money-stuff-startups-sometimes-stretch-the-truth"&gt;an internal investigation that confirmed Milton had lied, a lot&lt;/a&gt;, and the Department of Justice and the Securities and Exchange Commission opened investigations into his claims. Last month, they filed parallel criminal and civil charges against Milton as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VMdHb9"&gt;Nikola is still losing around $100 million per quarter, and it had around $630 million in the bank at the end of the second quarter of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ku7Lzd"&gt;“Autonomous fueling is part of the industry’s effort to ensure fast, efficient, and safe fueling of a large onboard storage system to be less than 20 minutes for heavy-duty vehicles,” the company said in a statement. “This project is expected to address this goal by working to develop an autonomous fueling system that can rapidly refuel heavy-duty fuel-cell electric trucks, while minimizing labor and challenges relating to ergonomics and maintenance of equipment, as compared to an equivalent manual fueling process.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621530/nikola-doe-grant-hydrogen-fueling-autonomous-biden-granholm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621530/nikola-doe-grant-hydrogen-fueling-autonomous-biden-granholm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>ToneStone is a music production app from the people behind Guitar Hero and Left 4 Dead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e0MZuqwcV17XILHcph1w2P5vsHw=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69715549/ToneStone_Product_Concept_Art_3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: ToneStone&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oqPe9i"&gt;ToneStone is an app designed to make producing music easy, even for users without any musical experience, and it’s created by people who worked on &lt;em&gt;Guitar Hero&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Left 4 Dead&lt;/em&gt;. Even though the app is &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210812005717/en/Former-Harmonix-and-Valve-Developers-Launch-ToneStone-to-Give-Everyone-The-Power-To-Create-Music"&gt;officially being announced today&lt;/a&gt;, it’s still in closed beta, and &lt;a href="https://tonestone.com"&gt;there’s a waitlist&lt;/a&gt; for those who want to try it out. As a music production hobbyist, ToneStone’s interface and game-like features very much seem like my kind of jam, based on videos I’ve seen of the app and my conversation with founder Greg LoPiccolo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lqDvjI"&gt;If you’ve never heard of LoPiccolo, you’ve probably heard of games he helped make. He worked at Harmonix, the studio that made music-based games like &lt;em&gt;Rock Band &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Guitar Hero&lt;/em&gt;. Another ToneStone founder is Tom Leonard, who has some of Valve’s greatest hits, like &lt;em&gt;Left 4 Dead &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Half-Life 2, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-leonard-49386b/"&gt;listed on his LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;. LoPiccolo said that the mission for ToneStone is to “empower a global community to create and share music,” which he sees making songs as a “critical human need that everybody wants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4OegT7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;ToneStone uses a system of loops and decks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S8hm9d"&gt;In an attempt to make music production novice-friendly, ToneStone uses a system of loops and decks. Imagine loops as building blocks to a song — they can be used to add drums, synths, strings, etc. The loops are then organized into decks, which represent different music genres like synthwave, trap, or pop. ToneStone has premade decks built in, but you can also create your own, and even add your own sounds or recordings as loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p6VQYZ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dfi5yqtMENA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J0kEpt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This tutorial video illustrates what the process of actually making music is like in the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="giK2kS"&gt;The team behind ToneStone also hopes it’ll act as a sort of music creation social platform, by making it easy to share your music and remix songs that others have made (at the moment, most of the sharing is being done on Discord). There have been other games that let users make music, but it's difficult to navigate the line between being &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4jBR5OSqxVw"&gt;too complex for beginners&lt;/a&gt; and too simple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sjrd8A"&gt;Remixing another ToneStone user’s song (which are currently shared in the Discord) gives you access to the entire project file, or as LoPiccolo put it, the musical DNA, which lets you really change things up from the original. You can also share any songs you made by exporting them as an MP3 file and uploading them to services like SoundCloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G0PU4Y"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x4gazyLegSg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SQuFCI"&gt;With founders who have years of experience in making games, it’s not surprising that ToneStone has gamified elements. LoPiccolo told me that the tutorials, which are meant to teach the basics of both the software and music composition, are lightly gamified. He also talked about the similarities between building a deck of loops and building a card deck in games like &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; — there are built-in decks, too, but the real fun comes when you start making your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="noczBf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;ToneStone takes inspiration from games like ‘Magic: The Gathering’ and ‘Hearthstone’&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PKoymX"&gt;LoPiccolo told me that the team has “some, I would dare say, revolutionary ideas” that are currently in development, that would “let people make musical decisions, and write and perform music as gameplay.” While what the actual gameplay will look like is unclear, the idea is to give the player enough decisions to get them into a groove, sort of like what can happen when playing more traditional games like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty. &lt;/em&gt;The difference would be that, at the end, you’d have a musical creation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSDFzj"&gt;I came away from the discussion imagining a series of quick-time events where you were deciding where the song was going to go, which sounds like a really fun thing to play around with (though it’s unclear if there’s some sort of seed or another process that prevents everyone from ending up with similar-sounding songs). LoPiccolo said that the ultimate goal was to make the experience either single or multiplayer, giving you the ability to collaborate with someone else to make music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tYoJXK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;ToneStone’s modability reminds me of the DIY music production world&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xi2HyT"&gt;Like video games, LoPiccolo says that ToneStone will also be moddable and extendable. Its engine is written in JavaScript, and he says that users will be able to contribute not just music but interactive content like tutorials, guides, or even game modes. As someone who’s spent some time in the DIY music production world, the idea of those kinds of community contributions reminds me of the YouTube tutorials, shared project files, and VST plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g_pR4jc-UiaWfyagz8jSMfYTNcs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22776453/Screen_Shot_2021_08_11_at_10.48.28_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: ToneStone&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compare this image of ToneStone’s UI from one of its tutorial videos to FL Studio’s UI, seen below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rsRxs8TbPeOHUlMO7SFb9MPlC9U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22776459/Screen_Shot_2021_08_11_at_10.46.43_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A project file for a relatively simple song in FL Studio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4oOjNq"&gt;While ToneStone seems to have a good number of advanced features, simplicity is still a priority for its creators. They say users should be able to go from opening the app to making music “within seconds” — the more advanced stuff can wait if you’re not interested or ready to learn it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="70rHuR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Users should be able to go from opening the app to making music “within seconds”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l7Kizs"&gt;I’ve spent hours and hours learning how to make music in apps like FL Studio and Logic Pro (mostly for fun), and hearing LoPiccolo enthuse about ToneStone makes me wish I had something like it years ago. I suspect I may end up using it for quick sketches and soundtracks that I would’ve used Logic for, just for the speed and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dPh1ZE"&gt;Of course, ToneStone isn’t the first app designed to let music novices create songs. Apple’s GarageBand has a feature called Live Loops, which has a &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/garageband-ipad/live-loops-overview-chsca7ff9ced/ipados"&gt;similarly user-friendly interface on iPads&lt;/a&gt;. I remember my experience using Live Loops as being fun but extremely frustrating when I tried to really make the song my own. GarageBand is also limited to Macs, iPads, and iPhones, where ToneStone runs on Macs and PCs and is distributed &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1627320/ToneStone/"&gt;through Steam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYNbra"&gt;ToneStone’s goal is to blend the social aspects of gaming with the creator-driven content of platforms like Instagram to ultimately create music. While the social aspects of music production that ToneStone is leaning on aren’t new (especially in the indie and hobbyist music scene), it does have a point that actually making music can be daunting to beginners. When I first started, beginner tutorials &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_OmX3PYE0Hw"&gt;looked like this&lt;/a&gt;, which is significantly scarier than &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dfi5yqtMENA"&gt;ToneStone’s own tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="S3pWWX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;LoPiccolo talked about game developers being able to score their own indie games with ToneStone&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2zTxcE"&gt;ToneStone is still in its early stages, but its team has high hopes for it. LoPiccolo painted a picture of what the app can currently do, saying that it can be used to “create license-free soundtracks for indie games or live streams,” and said that the team is working on making things like live performances and collaboration possible. With the app still in closed beta, there’s not a set-in-stone business model yet, but LoPiccolo told me that the intent is to offer a base app for free, with access to advanced features unlocked by a subscription (though he didn’t share pricing information). He also said that the app will include a marketplace where you can buy new loops, effects, or modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOccJH"&gt;You can sign up to the beta waitlist on &lt;a href="https://tonestone.com/waitlist/"&gt;ToneStone’s site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22619199/tonestone-music-production-app-beginners-remixes-social"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22619199/tonestone-music-production-app-beginners-remixes-social</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-12T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-12T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix reveals cast for its live-action Avatar: The Last Airbender series</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Avatar: The Last Airbender" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gOmgob6hq0vrjVXjBWd4k19_SE0=/5x0:2366x1574/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69715358/Screen_Shot_2020_07_21_at_9.38.25_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Nickelodeon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EglA0N"&gt;It’s been some time since we’ve heard news about Netflix’s live-action adaptation of &lt;em&gt;Avatar: The Last Airbender&lt;/em&gt;, but today the streaming company is finally revealing details: namely, the cast for some major roles. The show will feature Gordon Cormier (&lt;em&gt;The Stand&lt;/em&gt;) as Aang, Kiawentiio (&lt;em&gt;Beans&lt;/em&gt;) as Katara, Ian Ousley (&lt;em&gt;13 Reasons Why&lt;/em&gt;) as Sokka, and Dallas Liu (&lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legends of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt;) as Zuko.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJo8tS"&gt;The live-action adaptation was &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/9/18/17874344/avatar-the-last-airbender-live-action-series-netflix"&gt;first announced in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and ran into some trouble last year when &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; creators Michael Dante DiMartino and Bryan Konietzko stepped away from the project citing creative differences with Netflix. “I realized I couldn’t control the creative direction of the series, but I could control how I responded,” &lt;a href="https://www.michaeldantedimartino.com/an-open-letter-to-avatar-the-last-airbender-fans/"&gt;DiMartino wrote in a blog post at the time&lt;/a&gt;, adding that “Netflix’s live-action adaptation of &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; has the potential to be good... but what I can be certain about is that whatever version ends up on-screen, it will not be what Bryan and I had envisioned or intended to make.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uvuJpvHdZjRLVuMfXq04SyL9ZyE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22778025/FINAL_16x9_Cast_rounded_v3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UdgLbV"&gt;Taking over as showrunner is Albert Kim (&lt;em&gt;Sleepy Hollow&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nikita&lt;/em&gt;), who posted a blog today about the process of creating what will be the second live-action take on the series, following M. Night Shyamalan’s 2010 film. “The more I thought about it, the more intrigued I became,” &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/bringing-avatar-into-the-live-action-realm-for-fans-old-and-new"&gt;Kim wrote&lt;/a&gt;. “VFX technology has advanced to the point where a live-action version can not only faithfully translate what had been done in animation — it can bring a rich new visual dimension to a fantastic world. We’ll be able to see bending in a real and visceral way we’ve never seen before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZPQmkI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The more I thought about it, the more intrigued I became.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xLUbjX"&gt;He also touched on the casting specifically, noting that “a live-action version would establish a new benchmark in representation and bring in a whole new generation of fans. This was a chance to showcase Asian and Indigenous characters as living, breathing people. Not just in a cartoon, but in a world that truly exists, very similar to the one we live in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="saERwN"&gt;There’s no word yet on when the new show will debut on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621540/netflix-avatar-the-last-airbender-live-action-cast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621540/netflix-avatar-the-last-airbender-live-action-cast</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
