<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-16T15:51:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T15:51:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T15:51:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Teen ‘mastermind’ behind the great Twitter hack sentenced to three years in prison</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GhMIM04WEo_FwcoWTfeJG30U6-M=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977098/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TYfT1j"&gt;Teenage Twitter hacker Graham Ivan Clark has pleaded guilty to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"&gt;last summer’s unprecedented bitcoin scam attack&lt;/a&gt; that involved the takeover of dozens of high-profile accounts on the social network, according to paperwork filed in Florida court on Tuesday. Clark, who was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352325/twitter-hack-arrest-go-read-this-new-york-times-profile"&gt;17 when accused of leading the scam&lt;/a&gt;, will spend three years in prison as part of his plea deal. The&lt;em&gt; Tampa Bay Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tampabay.com/news/crime/2021/03/16/tampa-twitter-hacker-agrees-to-three-years-in-prison-in-plea-deal/"&gt;reported the news&lt;/a&gt; earlier today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZ65Ue"&gt;Clark has already been credited with 229 days of time served &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349920/twitter-hack-arrest-florida-teen-fbi-irs-secret-service"&gt;since his arrest last summer&lt;/a&gt;. As part of the deal, Clark is also being sentenced as a “youthful offender,” which lessened his prison time and also opens up the possibility that he can serve some of his sentence at a boot camp, according to the &lt;em&gt;Tampa Bay Times&lt;/em&gt;. Clark will also be banned from using computers without permission and without supervision from law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="au8Ovg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Clark was 17 at the time of the Twitter hack, which compromised several high-profile accounts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CWeksl"&gt;The hack took place on July 15th, 2020, and it quickly became one of the most fraught cybersecurity incidents in Twitter’s history, as accounts belonging to high-profile users like Elon Musk, Bill Gates, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden were compromised in quick succession to promote a bitcoin scam Clark used to accept more than $100,000 in the cryptocurrency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U0SIY9"&gt;How Clark pulled off the hack, which he did alongside two other collaborators he allegedly met on an online username-selling forum called OGusers, has been the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/17/21329147/twitter-hack-attack-bitcoin-scam-how-it-happened-new-york-times-go-read-this"&gt;subject of numerous reports&lt;/a&gt; that detailed the group’s use of internal Twitter tools. Those tools, which can be used to reset account email addresses, allowed Clark and his collaborators to assume control of the accounts and send out tweets soliciting the public for bitcoin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tMfcKF"&gt;Shortly after the hack, Clark was arrested at his home in Hillsborough, Florida. Clark’s partners, Nima Fazeli of Orlando and Mason Sheppard of the UK, were charged with federal crimes, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kWTzz6"&gt;
&lt;p style=" margin: 12px auto 6px auto; font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; font-size: 14px; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; -x-system-font: none; display: block;"&gt;   &lt;a title="View Graham Ivan Clark Plea Agreement on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F499034071%2FGraham-Ivan-Clark-Plea-Agreement%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F16%2F22334421%2Ftwitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Graham Ivan Clark Plea Agreement&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title="View Nick Statt's profile on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fuser%2F342430845%2FNick-Statt%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F16%2F22334421%2Ftwitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Statt&lt;/a&gt; on Scribd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="Graham Ivan Clark Plea Agreement" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/499034071/content?start_page=1&amp;amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;amp;access_key=key-nXkVhTZi0FdsRRkJEdHy" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488" scrolling="no" id="doc_72869" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zFmXpJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334421/twitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334421/twitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T15:38:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T15:38:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Wikimedia will launch a paid service for big tech companies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Logo of Wikipedia" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tB4OKgNk0nIVTQsn4ep06qbJZMk=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68976992/1296469702.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Altan Gocher / DeFodi Images via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hxgVf5"&gt;The Wikimedia Foundation is creating a &lt;a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Enterprise"&gt;new paid service&lt;/a&gt; for companies that draw on Wikipedia data. The foundation announced the news today &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/wikipedia-finally-asking-big-tech-to-pay-up/?utm_brand=wired&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;via an article in &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and it’s planning to launch later in 2021. &lt;a href="https://enterprise.wikimedia.com/"&gt;Wikimedia Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, as it’s called, won’t change how current Wikipedia services work. Instead, it will offer new options for companies that use its content, a category including giants like Google and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ew5SeV"&gt;Wikimedia is still finalizing how Wikimedia Enterprise will operate. But broadly, it’s like a premium version of Wikipedia’s API — the tool that lets anybody scrape and re-host Wikipedia articles. Enterprise customers could get data delivered faster or formatted to meet their needs, for instance, or get new options for sorting and posting it. As Wikimedia Foundation senior director Lane Becker explains to &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;, companies may already be paying employees to clean up Wikipedia data, and Enterprise will do that kind of cleanup at the source. Or if they want, companies can keep using the existing API for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="srrWKD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Wikimedia insists it’s not “forcing Big Tech to pay”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nI99s6"&gt;Many huge internet services are powered partly by Wikipedia. Google’s “knowledge boxes” incorporate information from the free encyclopedia, and so do voice assistants like Amazon’s Alexa and Apple’s Siri. As web platforms attempt to fight misinformation, Wikipedia has also become a go-to fact-checking resource. But while some companies have &lt;a href="https://slate.com/technology/2018/10/amazon-echo-wikipedia-wikimedia-donation.html"&gt;offered donations&lt;/a&gt; in return for using Wikimedia’s free services, others have launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/14/17120918/youtube-wikipedia-conspiracy-theory-partnerships-sxsw"&gt;big Wikipedia-powered initiatives&lt;/a&gt; without even telling the foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OEngot"&gt;Wikimedia’s &lt;a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Enterprise/FAQ"&gt;frequently asked questions page&lt;/a&gt; insists that Enterprise isn’t “forcing Big Tech to pay” for Wikipedia. But it &lt;em&gt;could &lt;/em&gt;solve specific, well-known problems for those companies. One potential service would let companies display the most reliably community-vetted edits instead of the newest ones, preventing false or insulting vandalized articles from &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-search-california-gop-nazism/"&gt;ending up on their own platforms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6gDbwK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Enterprise/Essay"&gt;In an essay&lt;/a&gt;, the Wikimedia Enterprise team acknowledges that it’s balancing commercial realities with a mission to provide free access to knowledge. “This is about setting up the movement to thrive for decades to come, to weather any storm, and to genuinely stand a chance at achieving the mission first conceived 20 years ago,”  the essay says. “We’re going to need more resources, more partners, and more allies if we are going to achieve the goals implicit in our vision statement.” And starting later this year, that could include paid partnerships with the internet’s biggest companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZiH55y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334276/wikimedia-enterprise-api-service-big-tech-knowledge-boxes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334276/wikimedia-enterprise-api-service-big-tech-knowledge-boxes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T14:11:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T14:11:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mars might be hiding most of its old water underground, scientists say</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SrsyMmhsQcxrRJ5vRdC65EHQE-M=/0x56:1602x1124/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68976337/25695_PIA24485_K4_ZCAM_main_sol004_Delta_Remnant_unannotated.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A deposit of sediments, called a delta, captured by NASA’s Perseverance rover on March 5th at the Jezero Crater.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HbAndJ"&gt;Vast amounts of ancient Martian water may have been buried beneath its surface instead of escaping into space, scientists report in the journal &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;. The findings, published Tuesday, may help untangle a clash of theories seeking to explain the disappearance of Mars’ water, a resource that was abundant on the planet’s surface billions of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r88HBW"&gt;Through modeling and data from Mars probes, rovers, and meteorites, researchers at the California Institute of Technology found that a broad range — between 30 to 99 percent — of the Red Planet’s earliest amounts of water could have vanished from the surface through a geological process called crustal hydration, where water was locked away in the rocks&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;of Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqHsNP"&gt;Evidence of past water on Mars is written all over its rocky surface, where dried-out lake beds and rock formations illustrate a world shaped by liquids from more than 3 billion years ago. For years, scientists thought this water had mostly escaped outward into space, leaving the planet in its present — very dry — condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sqvoxA"&gt;But that takes time. And the rate at which the water could have escaped the atmosphere, paired with the predicted amount of water that once existed on the Martian surface didn’t quite line up with modern observations of the planet. “If that persisted through the past 4 billion years, it can only account for a small fraction of water loss,” says Renyu Hu, one of the study’s co-authors. That left researchers with a key question: where exactly did the rest of the water on Mars go? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dyxpdi"&gt;The study, led by Eva Scheller, a graduate student in geology at Caltech studying planetary surface processes, might offer an answer. The study finds that most of the water loss occurred during Mars’ Noachian period between 3.7 billion to 4.1 billion years ago. During that time, the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;water on Mars could have interacted and fused&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;with minerals in the planet’s crust — in addition to escaping the planet’s atmosphere&lt;strong&gt; — &lt;/strong&gt;locking away as much water as roughly half of the Atlantic Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kO6x_Forl0UgJOPSe7WOMvdTMwU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22375099/_mars.nasa.gov_msl_raw_images_proj_msl_redops_ods_surface_sol_03052_opgs_edr_ncam_NLB_668441769EDR_F0870792NCAM00252M_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An image of the Mont Mercou cliff, captured by one of the navigation cameras aboard NASA’s Curiosity rover this month. Data and images from Curiosity informed the findings made by Scheller’s team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BoeFba"&gt;“One of the things our team realized early in the study is that we needed to pay attention to the evidence from the last 10 to 15 years of Mars exploration in terms of what was going on with our discoveries about the Martian crust, and in particular the nature of water in the Martian crust,” says Bethany Ehlmann, a co-author on the study and professor of geological and planetary sciences at Caltech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hN7GfB"&gt;Water can break down rocks through a process called chemical weathering, which sometimes results in minerals becoming hydrated. Hydrated minerals take up and store water, locking it away. For example, gypsum, a water-soluble mineral found naturally on Mars, can keep its water trapped unless heated at temperatures higher than 212 degrees Fahrenheit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vUKjXj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The answers are there, but they slowly build through time as you gain more data”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fO0Ubb"&gt;For years, scientists have observed the distribution of water-bearing minerals across the Martian surface, thanks to spacecraft like NASA’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, which has been mapping the planet’s geology and climate since 2006. But those views alone are sometimes limited. “You have to wave your hands and extrapolate about how thick that layer is that you see at the surface,” says Michael Meyer, the lead scientist for NASA’s Mars Exploration Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8RKYaZ"&gt;“It’s only by having measurements in particular places on the surface with your rovers or landers, like Phoenix, or your occasional view of a fresh crater, that you get an idea of how thick the particular spot is on the planet for the hydrated minerals that you’re looking at,” he says. “So the answers are there, but they slowly build through time as you gain more data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wumzyg"&gt;That’s what led to the study’s findings that oceans’ worth of ancient water may have escaped inward, not outward. “We wanted to understand this at different scales,” says Scheller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zwOue2"&gt;Crustal hydration happens on Earth, but our active plate tectonic system recycles rock deep inside our planet, heating rocks and releasing water in the process. That water gets sent back to the surface through volcanic activity, says Christopher Adcock, a planetary geochemist at the University of Nevada Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYquEo"&gt;Mars, on the other hand, is not as geologically active as Earth, which could explain why it only has limited water on its surface. The clearest evidence of water on Mars comes in the form of ice at the planet’s poles and in tiny quantities in the atmosphere. Scientists have studied hydrated rocks on the Moon, Mars, and on other planetary bodies as a potential source of drinkable water for future astronaut missions or fuel that could power habitats and rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SjwJMI"&gt;Adcock, whose studies include how humans can synthesize and use minerals on Mars for drinking water and rocket fuel, says the findings from Scheller’s team don’t totally change the game for resource utilization, “but it is certainly an encouraging reminder that the water we need for long term human missions to Mars might be right at our feet when we get there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlzHkq"&gt;Last month, NASA &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289668/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-success"&gt;landed&lt;/a&gt; its Perseverance rover on Mars’ Jezero Crater, the site of a dried-out lake bed whose soil might hold the most pristine evidence of hydrated minerals — and fossilized microbial life. Perseverance will scoop up tiny soil samples and scatter them across the crater’s surface for a future “fetch” rover to retrieve. That presents a tantalizing opportunity for the researchers behind the &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EtSWMg"&gt;“Samples from Jezero will help us test this model,” Ehlmann says. “It amplifies the importance of bringing those samples back.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22332649/water-on-mars-martian-researchers-nasa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22332649/water-on-mars-martian-researchers-nasa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T13:58:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T13:58:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Retail giants look to greener cargo ships to meet climate goals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Yangshan Deepwater Port In Shanghai" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MlSnqNONx-O9CVlQsebngq9Pex4=/135x0:5337x3468/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68976227/1179330572.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tugboats guide a container ship of Maersk Line at the Yangshan Deepwater Port, operated by Shanghai International Port.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Ji Haixin / VCG via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RBRB4a"&gt;Pressure from some of their biggest customers is pushing companies like global shipping giant Maersk to pollute less when they transport goods. It’s a sign that individual companies’ commitments to tackling climate change can influence others along the entire supply chain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="vqgNNR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One of the latest trends in retail &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Avt1dF"&gt;One of the latest trends in retail has been for companies to pledge to essentially eliminate their greenhouse gas emissions. In order for them to have any chance of meeting those goals, they’ll need to work with the companies that move their products. That means cleaning up the global shipping industry, which is responsible for close to 3 percent of the world’s total emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7iw2ud"&gt;Maersk said last month that it’s significantly speeding up its timeline to develop what it says will be the world’s first cargo ship to run on fuels that don’t add more carbon dioxide to the atmosphere. It pledged to complete the vessel by 2023 — seven years ahead of its original schedule. In the &lt;a href="https://www.maersk.com/news/articles/2021/02/17/maersk-first-carbon-neutral-liner-vessel-by-2023"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;, the company pointed out that about half of its 200 largest customers had either set or were about to set targets to slash supply chain emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L78Q3K"&gt;“Customer demand is a big factor in saying, ‘Yes, we have to do this, and we have to do it now,’” says Lee Kindberg, head of environment and sustainability for Maersk in North America. Maersk works closely with some of its biggest customers to cut down on pollution, Kindberg says. Its customers’ supply chain emissions, after all, are Maersk’s primary emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wji9Lh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Customer demand is a big factor in saying, ‘Yes, we have to do this’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ca8HBj"&gt;Early in the climate commitment craze, companies made promises to slash emissions that come directly from their operations and electricity use. That might include the pollution from its factories or from keeping the lights on at their offices. Those commitments frequently excluded indirect emissions that come from things like the raw materials used to make products or from vessels hired to transport goods. Some companies argued that they had no control over those “indirect” emissions. But that’s changing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3pFlYa"&gt;Maersk has &lt;a href="https://www.maersk.com/news/articles/2019/10/29/maersk-join-forces-with-industry-peers-and-customers-to-develop-leo"&gt;partnered&lt;/a&gt; with its customers BMW, H&amp;amp;M, and Levi Strauss &amp;amp; Co., to develop more sustainable fuels for ships. Each of those companies has set goals for emissions cuts. Huge retailers like Amazon and Walmart, which sell items that might be transported via Maersk’s container ships, have also pledged to get rid of nearly all their planet-heating pollution by 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="patjno"&gt;There’s been a push from environmental groups to make companies cut &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; emissions that come from their supply chains and the end use of their products — together referred to as emissions from the “&lt;a href="https://ghgprotocol.org/standards/scope-3-standard"&gt;value chain&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lejqZg"&gt;“For many companies, the majority of their emissions are in their value chain. So they can’t credibly demonstrate their leadership on climate without addressing those emissions, as well as the emissions in their operations,” says Cynthia Cummis, director of private sector climate mitigation at the nonprofit World Resources Institute, who also co-founded a United Nations-backed &lt;a href="https://sciencebasedtargets.org/"&gt;initiative&lt;/a&gt; to help companies develop science-based emissions-reduction targets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="1vf8r0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They can’t credibly demonstrate their leadership on climate without addressing those emissions”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RRIBwz"&gt;An added benefit to tackling indirect emissions from the supply chain is that it can force retailers to have conversations with their suppliers and carriers about the pollution they’re generating together. “This may be part of what is spurring Maersk to take action and provide carbon neutral transport to respond to the needs of their customers,” says Cummis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UFqPZT"&gt;Another likely impetus for Maersk’s climate goals is international policies that are driving deeper emissions cuts across the entire maritime transport industry. The United Nations’ International Maritime Organization set a &lt;a href="https://www.imo.org/en/MediaCentre/HotTopics/Pages/Reducing-greenhouse-gas-emissions-from-ships.aspx"&gt;goal&lt;/a&gt; of cutting emissions from international shipping by 50 percent compared to 2008 levels by the year 2050. However, that might need to be a floor rather than a ceiling for the industry. Climate scientists &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/"&gt;have found&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; emissions need to drop to essentially zero by the middle of the century to avoid the worst effects of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHKiD0"&gt;Moving forward, all of Maersk’s newly constructed vessels will have dual-fuel technology that allows them to run on more traditional fuels or alternative carbon-neutral fuels. The company is also trying to make its vessels more energy efficient. The goal is to have a “carbon neutral fleet” by 2050. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5xaKO"&gt;For the vessel it plans to launch in 2023, Maersk has put its money on alternative fuels — specifically, so-called “green” methanol that is made with renewable energy or agricultural waste instead of coal or gas. While less polluting than conventional fuels, green methanol still &lt;a href="https://grist.org/energy/green-methanol-maersk-shipping-fuel/"&gt;has problems&lt;/a&gt;. For methanol made with agricultural waste, there are concerns that biofuels could compete with agriculture for land to grow feedstock, driving up food and water scarcity. Methanol also still releases some CO2 when burned, although proponents say this is offset by the carbon that’s captured from the process of making the fuel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJ7wo8"&gt;In the future, some of those problems could be solved with a switch to fuels made from liquid hydrogen or &lt;a href="https://www.maersk.com/news/articles/2021/03/10/maritime-industry-leaders-to-explore-ammonia-as-marine-fuel-in-singapore"&gt;ammonia&lt;/a&gt; (which Maersk says it’s also looking into) — although those technologies are still a little further out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9fiAX"&gt;“Maersk is a really important player in this space,” says Dan Rutherford, who directs aviation and marine programs for the International Council on Clean Transportation. “There’s definitely a lot of interest in what technologies they put their money on.” As the company operating &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/263291/container-shipping-companies-worldwide-number-of-ships/#:~:text=Container%20shipping%20companies%20worldwide%20%2D%20number%20of%20ships%202021&amp;amp;text=As%20of%20March%204%2C%202021,or%20in%20its%20order%20book."&gt;the most container ships&lt;/a&gt; in the world, Maersk can influence the entire shipping industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="t4mNtA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Maersk can still do more to address its &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; indirect emissions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ClEaFQ"&gt;Maersk can still do more to address its &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; value-chain emissions. Committing to cutting those emissions would exert pressure on its own suppliers. So far, the company hasn’t done that. That means there are likely still emissions generated from the process of building its next-generation ships. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtjZ1n"&gt;Addressing those emissions could be in Maersk’s future, according to Kindberg. “Clearly, we’d like to be able to make the full commitment, but you need to be sure you’ve checked all the boxes before you expand it,” she says. She adds that Maersk is “evaluating” how it might be able to work with shipyards to cut down their pollution. In the meantime, Kindberg says, Maersk is focusing on its “controllable operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vtGcZi"&gt;Figuring out how to clean up ships, ports, and shipyards is a tall order. Shipping is considered one of the hardest sectors to get running on clean energy. Batteries aren’t advanced enough yet to electrify large ships making long journeys, which is why there’s a lot of focus on developing more sustainable fuels. And ships have a lifetime that can be decades longer than land-locked vehicles, which also puts the transition to less polluting vessels on a longer timeline. Designing and building a single ship can take years, too, which is another reason why Maersk says it had to move fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ydgqeE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.oecd.org/ocean/topics/ocean-shipping/"&gt;Ninety percent&lt;/a&gt; of global trade moves by sea. So nearly any retailer that wants to cut down its carbon footprint will need to look seaward. And even if it takes time, cleaning up global shipping lanes will have a tremendous impact on the planet and the people these trade routes connect. That makes it all the more important to start working on carbon-cutting solutions as soon as possible.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqkKqD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ngMWxo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334173/retail-cargo-ships-climate-change-goals-maersk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334173/retail-cargo-ships-climate-change-goals-maersk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T13:48:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T13:48:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Octopath Traveler is coming to Xbox Game Pass, and Undertale has just arrived  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1-KDenjbMyLEJV3KQDFIQhTPE1Q=/688x141:2257x1187/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68976181/Screen_Shot_2021_03_16_at_9.28.23_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Xbox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WgUfLH"&gt;Xbox &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/03/16/coming-soon-xbox-game-pass-march-2021-wave-2/"&gt;is announcing the next round of games coming to Game Pass&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s a pretty stacked deck with games like &lt;em&gt;Undertale &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Octopath Traveler, &lt;/em&gt;both of which are coming to Xbox for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fwnn8O"&gt;Coming to all the Game Pass platforms (cloud, console, and PC) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5u3yxG"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Undertale&lt;/em&gt; (available today)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kIMhx0"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Empire of Sin &lt;/em&gt;(Available March 18th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UqygYm"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yakuza 6: The Song of Life &lt;/em&gt;(March 25th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tYv8Jy"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Narita Boy &lt;/em&gt;(March 30th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="TOAuEm"&gt;Coming to just cloud and console is &lt;em&gt;Outriders&lt;/em&gt; (April 1st), and coming to just console and PC are &lt;em&gt;Octopath Traveler&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Genesis Noir&lt;/em&gt;, both on March 25th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6j2aS"&gt;The PC is also getting some love, with a few of games being added to the platform that were previously not available to PC Game Pass subscribers: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EiDydI"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nier: Automata &lt;/em&gt;(March 18th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hl6mOr"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Torchlight III&lt;/em&gt; (March 18th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="74hx94"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pillars of Eternity II: Deadfire - Ultimate Edition&lt;/em&gt; (March 25th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="txqnSp"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Supraland&lt;/em&gt; (March 25th)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="acjy7J"&gt;And finally, as if there weren’t enough games,&lt;em&gt; Star Wars: Squadrons &lt;/em&gt;will be available on EA Play for console players starting on March 18th. Game Pass Ultimate subscribers will have access to the game through the included EA Play subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bn1vOt"&gt;Overall, there are some great games in here if you’re a Game Pass subscriber, whether you stream your games, play them on console or PC, or some of each. &lt;em&gt;Undertale &lt;/em&gt;coming to the service (and platform) feels like a &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt;, given the game’s incredible popularity and the fact that it’s been available on most platforms for a while now (it was released on the PlayStation Vita &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/15/16151292/undertale-playstation-4-vita-release"&gt;almost three years ago&lt;/a&gt;). The game was first released in 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XxS4hD"&gt;Of course, many of these games are also becoming available for purchase on the Xbox as well, for those who prefer owning their games. And, as always, there must be some sort of balance in the universe, so three games will be leaving Game Pass on March 31st: &lt;em&gt;HyperDot&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journey to the Savage Planet&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Machinarium. &lt;/em&gt;If you’ve been meaning to play any of those titles, it’s probably time to hop on it! &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334127/xbox-game-pass-march-releases-undertale-nier-octopath"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334127/xbox-game-pass-march-releases-undertale-nier-octopath</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T13:12:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T13:12:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Foxconn says it might build EVs at empty Wisconsin site, or in Mexico</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Foxconn’s “Fab”in Wisconsin. A state report says it no signs that it manufactures LCDs, or ever will" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vuIYBVJ9ETWze2iXZqvBH9KhjUs=/0x3:7192x4798/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68975977/Foxconn_proof_08_080520_3892.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="http://aerialscapes.com" target="_blank"&gt;Curtis Waltz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SyrArT"&gt;The chairman of Taiwanese manufacturer Foxconn says the electronics giant is considering making electric vehicles at its mostly empty worksite in Wisconsin, where the company originally planned to make LCD panels. Either that, or Foxconn may make EVs in Mexico. The decision will be made by July 1st, chairman Young Liu said &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-wisconsin-mexico-scott-walker-taipei-313ff82519f7ac551f1a149eebf82b4e"&gt;at a press conference Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qpnKjf"&gt;Best known for manufacturing iPhones, Foxconn has recently shifted some of its attention to the booming electric vehicle space as a way to diversify its revenue. Late last year, the conglomerate announced an EV platform on which &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/iphone-to-electric-cars-foxconn-reveals-ev-platform-promises-battery-breakthroughs/"&gt;other companies could build&lt;/a&gt;. This year, Foxconn announced tie-ups with China’s largest private automaker, Geely, and with a number of EV startups. It has agreed to build an electric vehicle with Fisker Inc., struggling startup &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212994/byton-foxconn-electric-vehicles-china-shutdown-extended"&gt;Byton&lt;/a&gt;, and may even build one with Faraday Future (as part of the deal with Geely), which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22247942/faraday-future-spac-merger-public-psac-property-solutions-nasdaq"&gt;now flush with cash after years on the brink&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jokfxm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Foxconn is considering Wisconsin or Mexico and will decide by July&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mY0Rrp"&gt;Foxconn also announced an EV partnership &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/16/21069288/foxconn-fiat-chrysler-electric-vehicles-china-joint-venture"&gt;with Fiat Chrysler in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, though neither company has commented on the project since. (Fiat Chrysler is now called Stellantis.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HkEZwW"&gt;Fisker Inc. founder Henrik Fisker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298878/foxconn-fisker-ev-electric-vehicle-wisconsin-deal-fsr-suv"&gt;previously said&lt;/a&gt; there was a “very good chance” that it would build a vehicle with Foxconn in Wisconsin, though the chairman’s comments Tuesday are the first time the Taiwanese company confirmed its interest in using the facility. Liu also said Foxconn is &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/iphone-assembler-foxconn-hints-at-making-electric-vehicles-in-u-s-11615905476"&gt;considering building EVs for multiple partners&lt;/a&gt; but dismissed rumors that it would work with Apple, which is developing an autonomous electric car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h3QJsR"&gt;Foxconn broke ground on the factory in Wisconsin in 2018, after netting some $4 billion in tax credits and other incentives from state and local governments. The company promised it would invest $10 billion, build a 20-million-square-foot facility, and create 13,000 jobs all to make LCD panels. Former president Donald Trump once &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507966/foxconn-empty-factories-wisconsin-jobs-loophole-trump"&gt;called the site the “eighth wonder of the world.”&lt;/a&gt; The company said it wanted to build the Silicon Valley of the Midwest, calling it “Wisconn Valley.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YDI6Qt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inside Foxconn’s empty buildings, empty factories, and empty promises in Wisconsin","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21507966/foxconn-empty-factories-wisconsin-jobs-loophole-trump"},{"title":"Foxconn will build a new electric vehicle for Fisker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298878/foxconn-fisker-ev-electric-vehicle-wisconsin-deal-fsr-suv"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5FmCbt"&gt;But that never happened. Foxconn has spent the intervening years narrowing the scope of its ambitions in Wisconsin, barely hitting hiring targets set by the state along the way, and has invested just 3 percent of that $10 billion total to date. The biggest structure it’s built measures only 1 million square feet. It was recently reclassified in official documents as a storage facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvD1Nr"&gt;Though Foxconn initially claimed it would manufacture LCD panels at the site, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507966/foxconn-empty-factories-wisconsin-jobs-loophole-trump"&gt;in reality&lt;/a&gt; the company has spent years searching for a viable product to manufacture in Wisconsin. For a time, it said it would use the space to create an “AI 8K+5G ecosystem” — though the company never coherently explained what that means. Foxconn also publicly considered &lt;a href="https://www.wpr.org/failed-partnerships-and-vacant-buildings-foxconns-wisconsin-commitment-remains-standstill"&gt;making coffee robots&lt;/a&gt; and, in the early throes of the pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/8/21213269/foxconn-ventilators-wisconsin-plant-medtronic-pb-560-open-source-design-covid-19"&gt;ventilators&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d5FtlA"&gt;“I took over the Wisconsin task, and I need to make it a viable one, so I need to find a product that fits that location,” &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-wisconsin-mexico-scott-walker-taipei-313ff82519f7ac551f1a149eebf82b4e"&gt;said Liu&lt;/a&gt;, referring to how he inherited the project from previous chairman (and Foxconn founder) Terry Gou, who left the company to take on an ill-fated bid for president of Taiwan. “Whether it’s Wisconsin or Mexico, it’s not political, it’s business from my perspective.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333868/foxconn-ev-wisconsin-fisker-geely-faraday-future"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333868/foxconn-ev-wisconsin-fisker-geely-faraday-future</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T12:34:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T12:34:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jade Raymond announces new Sony game studio just weeks after leaving Stadia</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Inside The 2016 E3 Electronic Entertainment Expo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LA6HuamQqcSOg08wuWFPqiUaEY4=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68975698/539774786.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="53vCQF"&gt;Longtime industry veteran Jade Raymond is heading up a new studio that will create original games for PlayStation. Raymond announced the news today via the &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/03/16/introducing-haven-a-new-montreal-based-independent-studio/#sf243985526"&gt;PlayStation Blog&lt;/a&gt;. “We want to create worlds where players can escape, have fun, express themselves, and find community,” Raymond wrote about the new studio, Haven. “We want to pour our passion into a project. We want to make something wondrous for people to experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQxTeY"&gt;Raymond is one of the game industry’s most prolific developers; her career’s spanned major stints at companies like Electronic Arts and Ubisoft in leadership roles. Most recently, she was leading Google’s first-party games studio, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/19/18272996/google-stadia-studio-games-entertainment-exclusives-gdc-2019"&gt;Stadia Games and Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier this year, however, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260803/google-stadia-game-development-studio-shut-down-jade-raymond"&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; its in-house developer. Although many other devs shifted to new roles, Raymond left the company entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mK21qN"&gt;“It’s been a strange and difficult past 12 months,” Raymond wrote. “The pandemic, social injustice, and job elimination have impacted many of my closest friends, family, and co-workers. All of these factors, paired with an inability to see friends and family face-to-face, lulled me into a kind of self-reflective cocoon where I had to ask myself some tough questions about what really matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ccDOc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334101/jade-raymond-haven-game-studio-playstation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334101/jade-raymond-haven-game-studio-playstation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T12:26:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T12:26:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ next update will let you design a custom umbrella</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6f5kIMRAHNc96JrZqaBA3G2Lilo=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68975632/800x450_Custom_design_umbrella.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pPW2l6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;’&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;already robust design tools are getting some improvements with &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/whatsnew/detail/2021/free-update-for-animal-crossing-new-horizons-delivers-new-content/"&gt;a free update&lt;/a&gt; hitting March 18th. One new addition is a big upgrade to the NookPhone’s design app that will let you customize umbrellas, small flags, uchiwa fans, and photo stands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="binxxf"&gt;The app already let you make designs for shirts, dresses, and hats, so with the upgrade, you’ll be able to tailor an even more custom look (and make a fun photo stand while you’re at it). The upgraded app will also add 50 design slots to both the normal and Pro custom design modes, allowing you to create and save even more designs than before.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6LF8Q7937DkeGaTkoXXD1zzH3WA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374866/800x450_ACNH_MarchUpdate_CustomDesigns_ProEditor_EN_02.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You can make designs for new items in the &lt;/em&gt;New Horizons&lt;em&gt; update.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iadrWn"&gt;You’ll be able to buy the app upgrade with Nook Miles at the terminal in the Resident Services building. And while you’re there, you’ll be able to spend Nook Miles to add the Custom Design portal from the Able Sisters’ shop, which lets you connect to the internet to share and search for custom designs, right to your NookPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tKMBOr"&gt;In addition, the update adds a cake to celebrate the game’s first anniversary (yes, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22327659/animal-crossing-new-horizons-first-year-timeline-events-holidays"&gt;it has been out for nearly a year&lt;/a&gt;) and Sanrio-themed items that you’ll be able to get using amiibo cards available at Target on March 26th. There will also be new seasonal items you can purchase from Nook Shopping, including prom-themed items to help you host a virtual dance party and... whoopee cushions. (In honor of April Fool’s Day, of course.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n5Mh_Vkp9W3tZ4W-QADsNg0LzfI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374903/800x450_ACNH_MarchUpdate_NewItems_01.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prank your friends with whoopee cushions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qmkXws"&gt;Happy pranking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="QvUOVv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Archivists are trying to chronicle Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ unforgettable first year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22321111/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-archive-one-year-anniversary"},{"title":"Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ first year: a timeline","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22327659/animal-crossing-new-horizons-first-year-timeline-events-holidays"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334001/animal-crossing-new-horizons-update-design-umbrella-app-whoopee-cushion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334001/animal-crossing-new-horizons-update-design-umbrella-app-whoopee-cushion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T12:24:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T12:24:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Demon Slayer movie is finally coming to the US after breaking records in Japan</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iAyAzdYOWWxIgGeYNOZUAA8FV90=/206x0:1276x713/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68975621/Screenshot_2021_03_16_115642.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Ufotable&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EUJ4fz"&gt;The excellent and massively popular anime &lt;em&gt;Demon Slayer &lt;/em&gt;has had as successful of a run at the box office as you can get in Japan — the movie adaptation of its “Mugen Train” manga arc is the highest-grossest film in the country’s history. Now, the film is finally coming to North America, starting with a theatrical run in the US and Canada on April 23rd with distribution from Aniplex of America and Funimation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6miFXO"&gt;The film’s official title, in true anime style, is a bit of a mouthful: &lt;em&gt;Demon Slayer – Kimetsu No Yaiba – The Movie: Mugen Train&lt;/em&gt;. But that hasn’t stopped the film from its box office domination. It broke the $100 million milestone in Japan in just 10 days, and it’s since grossed nearly $400 million in the country alone, beating out Hayao Miyazaki’s &lt;em&gt;Spirited Away &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Titanic &lt;/em&gt;for the&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;all-time record. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TXJZoL"&gt;The film is rated R and runs for one hour and 57 minutes, ensuring that fans of the fantasy anime’s beautifully animated, high-octane combat will get to see some bloody and well-choreographed battle scenes. There will also be 4DX and IMAX screenings, and both dubbed and subtitled versions. According to Aniplex and Funimation, those interested in watching &lt;em&gt;Mugen Train&lt;/em&gt; at home will have to wait until June 22nd, when digital purchase and rentals will be distributed on Amazon, Apple TV, Google Play, the Microsoft Store, Vudu, and the PlayStation Store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BLzDnt"&gt;For those unfamiliar, &lt;em&gt;Demon Slayer &lt;/em&gt;is a fantasy manga authored by Koyoharu Gotouge that centers on the trials of young swordsman Tanjiro Kamado, who sets out on a quest to return his sister to her human form after she’s transformed into a demon. &lt;em&gt;Mugen Train &lt;/em&gt;specifically covers a middle chunk of the manga’s storyline, following the anime’s season 1 adaptation of the narrative’s beginning and first few arcs. The anime is produced by renown studio Ufotable, which also animated the film and is working on the show’s second season to premiere sometime in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334004/demon-slayer-the-movie-mugen-train-north-america-release-theaters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334004/demon-slayer-the-movie-mugen-train-north-america-release-theaters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T12:05:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T12:05:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Rep. Jamaal Bowman introduces new bill to lower broadband costs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="JAMAAL BOWMAN" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BwDWryNZBX6dWkTIqx1b15Mc2_4=/0x0:5166x3444/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68975442/1229686078.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Caroline Brehman/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xXxnDP"&gt;For years, the broadband debate has centered around connecting people living in rural and unserved areas across the country. But while some rural Americans don’t have the infrastructure necessary to connect to the internet, other families in urban communities face difficulties affording what’s already available. Rep. Jamaal Bowman (D-NY) is set to introduce a new measure Tuesday that could help millions of households access more affordable broadband.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isDiay"&gt;“The more access to broadband people have, the more access and opportunity they have to the world beyond where they currently exist,” Bowman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on Tuesday. “The internet is a library. It’s an encyclopedia. It’s information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V7htUt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The internet is a library. It’s an encyclopedia. It’s information.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CFbArj"&gt;Bowman’s “Broadband Justice Act,” co-sponsored by Rep. Emanuel Cleaver (D-MO) who chairs a housing subcommittee, would require the Housing and Urban Development Department, along with the Treasury and USDA, to update its utility allowance definitions to include broadband so it can be subsidized for families living in government-assisted housing. Other utilities like gas and electricity are already subsidized in this way. The bill would also create a new grant program to help wire buildings and build out other broadband-related infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYDYPu"&gt;“There’s a lot of momentum and energy around making this a utility, not just from members of Congress but from organizers on the outside,” Bowman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The grassroots is really behind this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JDRZcj"&gt;The FCC already has subsidy programs, like Lifeline, that make broadband more affordable for qualified households, but it’s been the subject of disinvestment for many years. Many Lifeline subscribers receive poor connections, and &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/09/lifeline-broadband-internet-fcc-coronavirus/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, many people who qualify for the program refuse to use it due to its insufficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="82whFV"&gt;As Congress prepares for its next big infrastructure package, money for broadband expansion will likely be included in the process. Last week, Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) and Rep. Jim Clyburn (D-SC) introduced &lt;a href="https://www.klobuchar.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/news-releases?id=c3c8f0e4-61d4-46fe-a28a-f81a09620a5d"&gt;a sweeping broadband package&lt;/a&gt; that would invest over $94 billion in building high-speed broadband infrastructure in unserved and underserved areas. The Senate Commerce Committee also &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2021/3/recent-federal-actions-to-expand-broadband-are-we-making-progress"&gt;plans to hold a hearing&lt;/a&gt; on broadband expansion this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EoyBLq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pX4qeX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333877/jamaal-bowman-broadband-internet-hud-subsidy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333877/jamaal-bowman-broadband-internet-hud-subsidy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
