<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-09T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the PlayStation Showcase 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dqDscer3RVcQvKtJ4UhQxTSN0yw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834509/acastro_200318_1777_ps5_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lZWbCM"&gt;While Microsoft has hosted plenty game showcases in 2021, Sony has been comparatively quiet about what’s coming to the PS5 in 2022. Well, Sony is going to break its relative silence with a 40-minute event that will offer “a look into the future of PS5.” &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/02/youre-invited-playstation-showcase-2021-broadcast-next-thursday/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The PlayStation Blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; says to expect updates from its various PlayStation Studios (the number of which seem to grow every month) on games launching this holiday and others that will release in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGpsMT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon: Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt; may get some air time, since it’s a PlayStation-exclusive title that’ll be launching in the next handful of months. Of course, there’s more excitement about games we know less about. We’ve yet to see a trailer for the next &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; title, so perhaps it’ll make its gameplay debut. There are a host of other possibilities, like info on &lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo 7 &lt;/em&gt;or news on the next-gen version of &lt;em&gt;GTA V&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VlQbkE"&gt;Perhaps Sony is ready to widely roll out the new PS5 firmware that will enable the M.2 SSD slot in all consoles. Personally, I wouldn’t mind seeing DLC news for exclusives that released in 2021, like &lt;em&gt;Returnal &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1Km22"&gt;As for what we won’t see, Sony says &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609558/sony-playstation-psvr-oled-aaa-eye-tracking-controllers"&gt;the new PSVR hardware made for PS5&lt;/a&gt; won’t be in the stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UtvihO"&gt;When does the PlayStation game showcase start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pLK7Ie"&gt;The stream will kick off at 4PM ET / 1PM PT / 9PM BST on Thursday, September 9th. As previously mentioned, it’ll last for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MkImSG"&gt;Where can I watch the PlayStation game showcase?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AjnqPS"&gt;This event will be streamed on YouTube (embedded above) and &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/playstation"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes, the Twitch stream can be a few seconds ahead, so keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664376/playstation-ps5-games-showcase-how-to-watch-date-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664376/playstation-ps5-games-showcase-how-to-watch-date-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T10:03:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T10:03:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>A bunch of ape NFTs just sold for $24.4 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZHIZSy8yGszg03us9T3shJpnRyM=/0x4:1816x1215/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834413/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_9.20.13_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Six of the 101 apes sold at auction. | Image: Bored Ape Yacht Club / Sotheby’s&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U49uqm"&gt;If you thought &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;NFT mania&lt;/a&gt; was about to die off, think again: &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sothebys.com%2Fen%2Fbuy%2Fauction%2F2021%2Fape-in%2F101-bored-ape-yacht-club&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F9%2F22664469%2Fbored-ape-yacht-club-sothebys-auction-amount" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a bundle&lt;/a&gt; of 101 NFTs from Bored Ape Yacht Club just sold at Sotheby’s for $24.4 million. A &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sothebys.com%2Fen%2Fbuy%2Fauction%2F2021%2Fape-in%2F101-bored-ape-kennel-club&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F9%2F22664469%2Fbored-ape-yacht-club-sothebys-auction-amount" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;second bundle&lt;/a&gt; of 101 Bored Ape Kennel Club NFTs sold for $1.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAsJw1"&gt;That puts the ape sale among the biggest in the NFT space. A bundle of nine CryptoPunks — one of the earliest NFT projects — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430254/cryptopunks-christies-sale-larva-labs"&gt;sold for $16.9 million&lt;/a&gt; in May. And Beeple sold a collage of his works as an NFT &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million"&gt;for $69 million&lt;/a&gt; in March. While it’s hard to directly compare all of these sales (there are 101 items in today’s auctions versus one in Beeple’s), the purchases show that the appetite for NFT art isn’t dying down, and they suggest that buyers think there’ll be high resale value as the market continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9m2q5t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Who’ll make the next million-dollar NFT?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22639353/cool-cats-bayc-generative-nft-profile-avatar"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lAyRlm"&gt;The two sales at Sotheby’s today come from Yuga Labs, the creator of Bored Ape Yacht Club, or BAYC, which launched in April. The initial collection &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22639353/cool-cats-bayc-generative-nft-profile-avatar"&gt;contained 10,000 apes, semi-randomly generated&lt;/a&gt; in unique arrangements of sailor hats, eye patches, bone necklaces, stud earrings, and other accessories to dress them up. Ape owners get to be members of the titular club, which is supposed to provide various benefits (so far, that’s mostly been access to exclusive merch drops, bonus NFTs, and use of an online graffiti board). Bored Ape Kennel Club is a series of accompanying dog NFTs that were later sent out to ape owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FiApvG"&gt;Generative NFT collections like this have taken off in recent months, with all kinds of copycats and twists launching to take advantage of the hype. After its debut, BAYC quickly become the second-biggest name in NFT collections, right behind CryptoPunks. The cheapest ape now sells for around $149,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2l51Xt"&gt;Meanwhile, centuries-old auction houses like Sotheby’s and Christie’s have seen the (literal) value in promoting this new format for art and have hosted a number of sales for high-profile NFTs. An auction at Christie’s will feature BAYC &lt;a href="https://www.christies.com/en/auction/no-time-like-present-20909-hgk/"&gt;later this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664469/bored-ape-yacht-club-sothebys-auction-amount"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664469/bored-ape-yacht-club-sothebys-auction-amount</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s latest Dolby Atmos soundbar has a much more sensible price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fZG_hmBPYvz04Xa5o0chFyIDJk0=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834348/01.Hero_Shot_Mid.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7g5Vyd"&gt;I recently reviewed Sony’s flagship 2021 Dolby Atmos soundbar, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22623242/sony-ht-a7000-soundbar-review-dolby-atmos-xbox-series-x-ps5"&gt;the HT-A7000&lt;/a&gt;, and found it to be a fantastic performer made even better by two passthrough inputs that offer support for HDMI 2.1 features like 4K gaming at 120Hz. But with a price of $1,300 (and that’s before adding rear surrounds and a sub), Sony’s latest and greatest isn’t going to be practical for everyone. So with that in mind, the company is today announcing a cheaper, smaller model called the HT-A5000 that costs $899.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="le8NMA"&gt;That price puts it somewhat closer in line with something like the Sonos Arc, but Sony’s new soundbar could win people over for its added functionality and future-proofing. The HT-A5000 retains much of what’s good about the higher-end model: it’s still an Atmos bar with up-firing speakers — albeit fewer drivers overall. This is a 5.1.2 configuration compared to the 7.1.2 HT-A7000. But you still get built-in support for Chromecast, AirPlay 2, Spotify Connect, and Bluetooth audio. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QxYOkMDopZNyFjuRcXJY49DE2g4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836564/04_A5000_CloseUp_Mid.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HT-A7000 might have a premium glass surface, but I think you could argue that the HT-A5000 looks better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GRUD5H"&gt;At 10 pounds (compared to the hulking 26 pounds of the HT-A7000), the HT-A5000 also measures significantly smaller than the more expensive model. It’ll certainly look more at home next to a 55-inch TV like mine than the very long HT-A7000 did. But with those smaller dimensions, you can expect weaker sound performance than the flagship. The larger, heavier enclosure of the HT-A7000 prevents unwanted vibrations and helps maintain cleaner sound at loud volume levels. It also allowed Sony to have two tweeters facing the left and right sides, which isn’t the case on the HT-A5000.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o5PaP9S5f-c5O50FZjFLdA5FZyQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836652/10_A5000_skelton_Mid__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HT-A5000 is a 5.1.2 Atmos soundbar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sGbSRv"&gt;One key difference is that instead of including two HDMI 2.1 passthroughs, Sony sticks with just one on the HT-A5000. It’ll still send through 8K video, 4K at 120Hz, and Dolby Vision. But unfortunately, like its pricier sibling, this soundbar doesn’t currently support variable refresh rate (VRR) or auto low latency mode (ALLM). Sony is looking into both of these features but isn’t promising anything at the moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KIVdDS"&gt;Like the flagship, the HT-A5000 has acoustic optimization to automatically produce the best sound for whatever room you put it in. Sony’s technologies like Vertical Surround Engine and S-Force Pro are also present for convincing height effects and a wide, immersive surround experience. It supports the same optional rear surrounds ($349.99) and two subwoofer choices as the HT-A7000. Those will obviously drive the cost up, but at least you’re starting off spending $400 less. The HT-A5000 is expected to ship in early fall. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664382/sony-hta5000-soundbar-announced-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664382/sony-hta5000-soundbar-announced-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:52:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:52:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is testing emoji reactions for tweets </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0zIqnl6Zpy9RuWLPyWDtlKpEjK4=/0x24:2048x1389/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834271/Untitled.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fVELIi"&gt;Twitter is testing emoji reactions for tweets that go beyond a simple “Like,” the company announced today. So, over the coming days, users in Turkey will be able to respond to tweets with the “Face with tears of joy” emoji, “Thinking face,” “Clapping hands,” “Crying face,” or a simple “Heart.” The test is only scheduled to run for a limited time, but Twitter says it might expand it to users in more countries depending on the response. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATsNw1"&gt;The idea behind the feature is to give people more ways to quickly show how they feel about a tweet, Twitter says, while providing authors better feedback about how their tweet has been received. The emoji are accessible via a long-press of the Like button, while a short tap will send a regular Like. Rumors of the test &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22348952/twitter-emoji-reactions-downvotes-tweets-testing-features"&gt;emerged earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; after users reported being surveyed about potential emoji for inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rgsBqEL5MnIyUNdd9sN8NU_zOkE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836417/Untitled__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reactions will appear below tweets in Twitter’s feed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k9BJ32"&gt;Emoji reactions have been available for years on other services like Facebook, as well as on Twitter itself within direct messages. But what’s interesting about Twitter’s emoji choices for its latest test is that none of them are especially negative. There’s no “Angry face” like you’ll find on Facebook, or “Thumbs down” like in Twitter’s direct message emoji reactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QeB4BT"&gt;Twitter explains that it decided against choosing these negative emoji because people it surveyed said “they were concerned about receiving negative reactions to some of their thoughts.” A valid concern given how toxic many conversations on Twitter can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q46bGj"&gt;Meanwhile, the emoji it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; included earned their spots by being representative of the most common emotions people experience while reading tweets, as well as being “universally recognizable.” That probably explains why the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/dont-put-on-a-happy-face-are-you-using-the-smiley-emoji-all-wrong"&gt;incredibly passive aggressive&lt;/a&gt; “Slightly smiling face” emoji didn’t make the cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jrs6jR"&gt;If you’re in Turkey and want to give the new reactions a go, Twitter says the feature is rolling out over the coming days in the country. The test will be available on iOS, Android, and the web.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664253/twitter-emoji-reactions-test-thinking-face-crying-clapping-laughing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664253/twitter-emoji-reactions-test-thinking-face-crying-clapping-laughing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Keychron Q1 is an enthusiast-quality keyboard right out of the box</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A solid build and easy customization make the Q1 easy to recommend&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="A111Yk"&gt;Keychron’s new mechanical keyboard, the Q1, has achieved something very impressive. It’s taken the kinds of features and level of quality normally reserved for expensive, assembly-required custom keyboards sold in limited runs, and made it available in a single, beginner-friendly package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3cb1p"&gt;Those high-quality features include support for open-source firmware that allows the keyboard’s layout and functionality to be endlessly customized, hot-swappable switches that let you change its typing feel without having to do any soldering, and a level of construction that’s miles ahead of most mainstream keyboards at this $169 price point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZAkQra"&gt;It’s this focus on a more premium construction that’s new territory for Keychron, a company that’s made a name for itself offering relatively affordable mechanical keyboards packed with user-friendly features like wireless Bluetooth connectivity and convenient support for both Mac and Windows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ur7Gto"&gt;The Q1 sits halfway between Keychron’s mainstream roots and these more premium custom keyboards. It’s not wireless, and it’s also not as affordable as Keychron’s previous keyboards. But it’s also a package that you should eventually be able to buy without the kind of hassle and lead times that can come with many niche keyboard purchases. Keychron might not be a household name in the same way as Corsair or Logitech, but browse &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/"&gt;its site&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll find that most of its keyboards are currently in stock and ready to ship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nb38mU"&gt;It all makes the Keychron Q1 a very easy mechanical keyboard to recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KswNmv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10740932"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JkHoVq"&gt;The Keychron Q1 is a 75-percent aluminum keyboard, which means it has about as many keys as a typical laptop keyboard, including a function row. It’s available as a complete package for $169 in black, gray, or blue, with matching ABS double-shot keycaps. Otherwise, you can opt for a $149 bare-bones model that doesn’t come with switches or keycaps, but that only saves you $20 which doesn’t seem worthwhile to me. Unless you’ve already got switches and keycaps lying around, I’d personally just go for a fully assembled version. You can easily swap out both the caps and switches later, and hardware to easily remove both is included in the box, no soldering required. One exception is if you’re in Europe and want an ISO version of the keyboard — this version is only available as a bare-bones kit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Rs4XA"&gt;The Q1’s design will look instantly familiar to anyone who’s laid eyes on a GMMK Pro, a popular keyboard released earlier this year. One notable difference is that at the moment the Q1 doesn’t have the option to install a rotary knob on its top right, which the GMMK Pro includes to act as a volume control, but which can also be remapped to fill a variety of other functions. Keychron says it will eventually sell a version of the Q1 with a similar rotary knob in October for $179, but it’s not available at launch and won’t be available as an aftermarket upgrade for existing Q1s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7Ssf2"&gt;Instead, on the top right you have the option of including an extra key or swapping it out for a small square plate with a &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/pages/customize-your-keychron-q1"&gt;design of your choice printed on it&lt;/a&gt;. I’d prefer the extra key, personally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K7QtyGCfo0vOmRNkzfCiYrqSg3Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832615/jporter_210906_4744_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A simple toggle switches the keyboard between its Mac and Windows modes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0IcyLj4_UHWaGur6r42rCVI-Sfo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832614/jporter_210906_4744_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A solid aluminum case with no height adjust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZMAhC"&gt;Rounding out the physical tour, on the top left you’ll find a physical switch to put the keyboard in its Mac and Windows modes (keycaps for both come in the box, as is standard with Keychron’s keyboards). On the bottom there are four feet to stop the board sliding around on a desk, but there are no height adjustable feet. Their absence didn’t bother me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1saSKk"&gt;The Q1’s design and construction is a pretty big departure from Keychron’s previous keyboards, which have been made out of cheaper, lighter materials but have also included user-friendly extras like Bluetooth support and height-adjustable feet. The Q1 might not be as feature rich, but its overall build quality is on another level from Keychron’s other boards. I generally think it’s a mistake to equate “heavy” tech with “high-quality” tech, but in this case the Q1’s heavy-duty construction absolutely makes it feel more premium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4T8POmwR-Y6WE4krHCvzdkDrO3Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832616/jporter_210906_4744_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An aviator cable, if you’re into that sort of thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CbwXUf"&gt;Spend any time on mechanical keyboard forums and you’ll quickly discover that there are a host of mods people like to make to their keyboards, either to make them feel nicer to type on, sound better, or just look plain cool. What’s special about the Keychron Q1 isn’t that it’s doing anything particularly new, but that it comes with a number of the most common mods applied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PP5QJu"&gt;Its USB cable is the most obvious example. One of the easiest modifications most people make for their keyboards is to replace the boring USB cable that comes in the box with something more interesting, maybe covered in a nice braided fabric, curled into a coil, or with a completely excessive aviator connector halfway down the line. Well, that’s exactly the cable that comes as standard with the Q1. I’ve never personally been a fan of over-engineered cables like these, but judging by users on Reddit, I’m in the minority. At least it doesn’t affect the way the cable works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J19Cmo"&gt;Elsewhere, there are more examples of typically aftermarket mods being included as standard. Look at the Q1’s Gateron-manufactured screw-in PCB stabilizers (the mechanisms under longer keys like the spacebar that stop them from wobbling), and you’ll see that lube has been applied to reduce their rattling, which is another tweak people recommend for your keyboard. I imagine most enthusiasts will want to tweak the amount of lubricant to get exactly the sound they prefer, but for me the amount that came applied did a great job at reducing the clatter they can otherwise produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="uPGgz8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You get a very fancy coiled USB-C cable in the box&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="apOngb"&gt;The Gateron “Phantom” switches that come with the board also have lubricant applied, in the hope of making them feel smoother to type on. The switches are available in a typical selection of linear red, tactile brown, and clicky blue varieties, and I used the brown versions for the majority of my time with the board. Despite the Phantom branding, it was hard to tell the switches apart from regular Cherry MX Browns, with that ever-so-slight tactile bump that you either love or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bc32Fv4P0tw"&gt;absolutely hate&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a proud member of the former group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bbag9V"&gt;The most common modification people tend to make to their keyboards is with the keycaps, and unfortunately I don’t have an answer for you about whether Keychron’s stock keycaps can live up to the quality of aftermarket alternatives. I didn’t get a review sample of the ABS caps that Keychron provides with fully assembled versions of the Q1. Instead, I’ve been using one of &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/collections/q1-k2-oem-dye-sub-pbt-keycap-set/products/q1-k2-oem-dye-sub-pbt-keycap-set-gray-white-blue"&gt;Keychron’s $40 sets&lt;/a&gt; made out of a more durable PBT plastic. They’re not perfect, but for this price, I think you could do a lot worse. I have no problems with the durability of the keycaps, but look closely and you’ll see that the printing of their legends isn’t great, and there’s a kind of haziness to them that almost looks like the ink is bleeding out into the area around each letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYH2rh"&gt;In contrast, ABS (which is what the keycaps that actually come with the keyboard are made out of) generally has a reputation for being less durable than PBT, thanks to the way it can develop a shine over time with use. But considering they only come in at a $20 premium alongside a set of switches, I think it makes sense to grab a set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sntK1ekSyRlkrTFjlf6XjhEv6ro=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832611/jporter_210906_4744_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keychron’s $40 PBT keycaps are good, not great.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FOB0f8sTpMS1wdPmFQFuJow1fcE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832610/jporter_210906_4744_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C cable attaches to the top left of the board.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xSmfqE"&gt;No compact keyboard layout is going to be perfect for everyone, so it’s great that the Keychron Q1’s layout is completely customizable. Better yet, it’s customizable thanks to its support for QMK, a powerful open-source firmware standard that’s compatible with a plethora of different configuration software. Keychron recommends using the &lt;a href="https://caniusevia.com/"&gt;software Via&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/blogs/archived/how-to-use-via-to-program-your-keyboard"&gt;configure the Q1’s layout&lt;/a&gt;, which is generally a well-designed and user-friendly piece of software to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1nwHwL"&gt;The one criticism I have about the customization process is that it’s a little unintuitive how it works when you’re using the keyboard in its Windows mode. If you want to alter the layout used when the keyboard’s in its “Windows” mode (there’s a small switch labeled Mac / Windows on the top left of the board), you’ll need to adjust “Layer 2” in Via or your QMK software of choice, which isn’t obvious at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c114ky"&gt;The Q1 also technically has an RGB LED built into each one of its switches, but this is not the keyboard to get if you want an obnoxious glowing object on your desk. None of Keychron’s keycap options have any transparency to allow light to shine through them, and the case itself doesn’t leave much room for light to shine through. You’re left with what small amount of light is able to bleed through the thin gaps between the keycaps, which suits me just fine as someone who turns off the lighting on every keyboard he uses anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gYoe0H"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Its RGB lighting is barely visible in most conditions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3lvcEr"&gt;There’s a lot going into the typing experience of the Keychron Q1. There are the aforementioned pre-lubed switches, as well as the fact that its circuit board is mounted on a gasket rather than being screwed into the case, giving it a slight amount of flex as you type. And then there’s the keyboard’s heavy 3.5Ib (1.6kg) construction, which keeps it firmly planted on your desk as you type. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2KJyeT"&gt;I’m not going to pretend to know which of these deserves most of the credit for the overall feel of the Keychron Q1. All I know is that this keyboard offers the best out-of-the-box typing experience of any keyboard I’ve ever used, and it’s in a different league from most mainstream keyboards at this price point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7KfhfD"&gt;Typing has a wonderfully crisp and clean feel to it, accentuated by the lack of rattle coming from the space bar. I think it sounds great to type on with the tactile brown switches I’ve been using. It’s the kind of keyboard that’s a joy to use every single day, regardless of whether you’re writing thousands of words of copy, gaming, or anything in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="F1Cnua"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10740943"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RTrm8d"&gt;I think a lot of people are going to be very happy with the way the Keychron Q1 feels as stock, but it’s also a pretty easy keyboard to mod yourself. Keychron provides a small Allen wrench in the box, which grants easy access to the internals of the keyboard via the eight screws on its underside, and there are extra gaskets and foam if you want to experiment to get a different sound and feel from the board. It’s a fairly painless process to disassemble the keyboard, though you’ll need to be careful about the small ribbon cable that connects the main circuit board to the smaller board that houses the USB-C connector. Ultimately, this feels like a keyboard that’s designed to be taken apart, unlike many other keyboards which have scary-looking warranty stickers that you have to break to access key screws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J7OsqJ0_IgIjUyrAXwJxG86dIG8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832618/jporter_210906_4744_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The keyboard technically comes with RGB switches...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sb4HUz6jdaMpDXi8m68qabCLO6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22832620/jporter_210906_4744_0014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;...but you’d be hard-pressed to see them in most situations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="MUmfZG"&gt;Halfway through writing this review, a colleague sent me a message asking for a keyboard recommendation, and without hesitating I recommended the Keychron Q1. Short of being wireless, it basically does everything you could want from a compact mechanical keyboard. It’s easy to swap out its switches, it’s easy to customize its layout, and it’s a dream to type on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ji3Sww"&gt;The Q1 has been compared to the kinds of custom keyboards that can cost multiple hundreds of dollars, and nearly all of which require some assembly by the end user. But obviously it’s never going to be better than these boards, not out of the box. Not because of any lack of build quality, but because it’s that little bit of self assembly that truly tailors a custom keyboard to your exact needs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="9aw0my"&gt;With a little work, a little bit of lube here, or some switch upgrades there, I’m sure the Q1 could approach the level of quality of some of these custom boards, and Keychron’s design is happy to accommodate tinkerers. But I think what’s most impressive is how close the Q1 gets as standard. It’s an amazing keyboard for someone who just wants to buy something fully assembled and without a lengthy waiting period. Unless you’re dead-set on a wireless keyboard or you need the extra keys afforded by a larger model, the Keychron Q1 is an easy choice to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wiBbN8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Jon Porter / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3G72GE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22662686/keychron-q1-review-price-mechanical-keyboard-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22662686/keychron-q1-review-price-mechanical-keyboard-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:20:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:20:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>League of Legends’ world championships will take place in Iceland</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="League of Legends – 2020 Worlds - Finals" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e2lquR0-uoWz2NL7Ugm-Cc5mz-8=/1x0:5200x3466/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834107/1283223716.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by David Lee/Riot Games/Riot Games Inc. via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PZVevw"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; World Championship, the concluding tournament that brings together the best teams from across the world, will take place in Reykjavík, Iceland at the Laugardalshöll indoor sporting arena. Riot Games &lt;a href="https://lolesports.com/article/worlds-2021-location-and-format-announcement/blt52ec273a991d3261"&gt;revealed the news today&lt;/a&gt;, following the August announcement that the event would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638914/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-moved-china-europe"&gt;moved from China to Europe&lt;/a&gt;. The event kicks off on October 5th and will conclude on November 6th. No fans will be in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZORva"&gt;Reykjavík was also this year’s location for &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;’s other big international tournament, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22303379/league-of-legends-iceland-lol-mid-season-invitational-valorant-champions-riot-games"&gt;the Mid-Season Invitational&lt;/a&gt;, which took place in May. “Riot successfully hosted the Mid-Season Invitational this past May in Hall B at the Laugardalshöll without a live audience, which resulted in zero COVID-19 cases among players, staff, and partners,” the company noted in today’s announcement. “While maintaining our focus on ensuring the health and safety of everyone involved in hosting, producing, and competing at the event, Worlds 2021 will not host a live audience. We will continue to use guidance from various health organizations and local and national authorities to prioritize everyone’s safety.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G38e8p"&gt;Alongside the reveal of the host city, Riot also detailed a schedule for the tournament. The early play-in stage will take place from October 5-9th, followed by the group stage from October 11-18th. This will lead into the quarterfinals starting on the 22nd, semifinals on the 30th, and finally the championship match on November 6th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="46Firz"&gt;Riot usually puts on dazzling technological showcases for Worlds; previous events have featured an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/31/21541871/league-of-legends-world-championship-worlds-2020-opening-ceremony-ar-kda"&gt;AR concert&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/11/20959206/league-of-legends-worlds-2019-opening-ceremony-holograms-holonet"&gt;concerts with holograms&lt;/a&gt;. For the early stages of last year’s event, which had no fans, Riot still created spectacle by using massive LED screens &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/24/21529317/league-of-legends-world-championship-high-tech-stage-riot-mandalorian"&gt;to create an impressive mixed reality stage&lt;/a&gt;. Even if you’ve never watched &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; before, it might be worth tuning in to this year’s Worlds to see what technological wizardry Riot Games has up its sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbPB3J"&gt;Worlds isn’t the only esports event that’s been affected by the pandemic in 2021. The International, &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt;’s big event, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567520/dota-2-the-international-bucharest-romania-sweden-october-location-date"&gt;was moved to Bucharest, Romania&lt;/a&gt; from Stockholm, Sweden, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643253/overwatch-league-owl-2021-playoffs-hawaii"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League canceled its in-person playoffs in favor of an online competition in Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22649691/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-europe"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22649691/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-europe</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:20:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:20:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s leather AirTag loop drops to its lowest price yet at Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An AirTag in an Apple Leather Loop accessory" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pg9xEVET5CJSJ3SY6tFVfsv0o7Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834105/vpavic_4547_20210421_0070.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s leather AirTag loops are finally on sale. | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zhNQnQ"&gt;Apple’s AirTag accessories are, ironically, often more expensive than the Ultra Wideband-ready Bluetooth tracker itself. Today, however, you can pick up a leather AirTag loop in either brown or red at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0932PNC7S/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for $29&lt;/a&gt;, the lowest price Amazon has sold the accessory for since its release in the spring. That’s a great thing given the nature of AirTags, which controversially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"&gt;lack a lanyard hole&lt;/a&gt; that would make accessorizing so much easier and likely cheaper, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HqRRM"&gt;The Apple AirTags Leather Loop is made from tanned leather and normally retails for $39. The stylish case allows you to clip your AirTags to backpacks, keys, and other accessories, while securely holding your AirTag in place. There are other third-party options available that are more affordable — Nomad &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-14527713?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnomadgoods.com%2Fproducts%2Fairtag-leather-loop-rustic-brown" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sells similar-looking leather loops&lt;/a&gt; for $25, for example — but this could still be a worthwhile deal to consider if you’re a big Apple fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2YZfeF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The search is over: Smart trackers from Apple, Samsung, and Tile compared","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22570161/apple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison"},{"title":"AirTag location trackers are smart, capable, and very Apple","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="aGcVd8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10741428"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cmi7I9"&gt;Tired of constantly forgetting your login details? Right now, &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;readers can score 50 percent off of their first year of 1Password, which can be used on unlimited devices. The popular password manager offers authenticated encryption and allows you to create and securely store your passwords online. It can also alert you to compromised sites and vulnerable passwords, a welcome perk given the rising number of online hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebINTO"&gt;Our exclusive promo applies to both the &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-15026552" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;individual subscription&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-15026551" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;family plans&lt;/a&gt;. The discount — which is only available for a limited time — brings individual plans down from $2.99 to $1.50 a month for up to a year, which means you’re only paying $18 annually. Families of up to five individuals, on the other hand, will pay $30 a year instead of the typical $60, or $2.50 a month instead of $5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mwiaka"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10426335"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="chnbGj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437502"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3YBvDb"&gt;Apple lovers, rejoice: we’ve got a second deal today you’ll love. For a limited time, you can score one of the best prices Amazon has ever offered on the 2018 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Keyboard-Numeric-Wireless-Rechargable/dp/B071ZZTNBM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, which features a built-in numpad. Regularly $129, this wireless keyboard is on sale for $111 in silver (the latest, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607386/apple-magic-keyboard-touch-id-standalone-seperate-price-release-date-m1-chip"&gt;Touch ID-equipped version&lt;/a&gt; retails for $179).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1a4VP"&gt;Outfitted with Apple’s scissor key switches, the keyboard works well with both the iPad and various Mac models. It also features a floating design and a Lightning port, allowing you to top off the rechargeable keyboard after about a month of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JYVg0G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10295314"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ANoE9m"&gt;The newest Hisense 4K TVs are already relatively affordable, which is why their current discount, which runs up to $250, is such a great deal. Prices start at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hisense-Premium-75U6G-Quantum-Compatibility/dp/B091YM7DP5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$480 for the 50-inch model&lt;/a&gt;, with the larger 75-inch model going for $1,000 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hisense-Premium-75U6G-Quantum-Compatibility/dp/B091YK9W9S/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (temporarily out of stock, but the deal is still available) and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FHIS75U6G%2FHisense-75-Inch-U6G-Series-4K-ULED-Quantum-HDR-Smart-Android-TV-75U6G-2021%3F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F9%2F22662055%2Fapple-airtag-loop-hisense-4k-tv-asus-gaming-mouse-playstation-xbox-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BuyDig&lt;/a&gt; instead of $1,250. BuyDig’s deal is especially attractive, as the discount also comes with an extended four-year warranty. The cost is slightly higher from &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfxglaJ8lo5#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; at $1,150.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOPGYw"&gt;After in-depth testing, the &lt;a href="https://www.rtings.com/tv/reviews/hisense/u6g" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;review site &lt;em&gt;Rtings.com&lt;/em&gt; concluded&lt;/a&gt; the 4K Android TV is packed with features that should please most people. &lt;em&gt;TechRadar&lt;/em&gt; also praised the &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/reviews/hisense-u6g-uled-tv" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;excellent image quality&lt;/a&gt; and the fact it offers a wide selection of streaming apps thanks to its incorporation of Google Play. The TV also comes with support for Dolby Vision, HDR, HDR10+, and Google Assistant, as well as four HDMI ports and a voice-enabled remote. If you’re a gamer, however, you may want to look elsewhere, as the entry-level model doesn’t boast advanced gaming features such as HDMI 2.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eTGnqo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10739604"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4YQlZR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best gaming TV to buy for the PS5 and Xbox Series X","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vy0z0W"&gt;While the aforementioned Hisense TV may not be a great pick for a gamer, this wireless gaming mouse from Asus certainly is. Right now, you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08R14HS3R/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Asus ROG Keris at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for an all-time low of $68, about $32 less than its typical $100 price tag. The sturdy, lightweight mouse boasts 78 hours of battery life and USB-C charging, and it can provide up to 12 hours of gameplay on a single, 15-minute charge. The peripheral also comes with replaceable side buttons, a 16,000 DPI sensor, and a 70-million-click life span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tPsHOp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10741565"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D7aKmp"&gt;If you care less about discounts on accessories and more about games, you can score up to 80 percent off on a variety of multiplayer Xbox games during &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeDailyDealRoundUp090821&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fpromotions%2Fsales%2Fcouch-co-op-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s Couch Co-op sale&lt;/a&gt;, which ends on September 13th. Xbox owners can pick up, for example, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeDailyDealRoundUp090821&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fit-takes-two---digital-version%2F9NXVC0482QS5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It Takes Two&lt;/em&gt; for $30&lt;/a&gt; instead of $40, or &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fborderlands-legendary-collection%2F9N951JR9T3FX%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Borderlands Legendary Collection &lt;/em&gt;for $20&lt;/a&gt;, one of its best prices to date. The sale features discounts on a wide variety of other genres as well, ranging from Lego titles to competitive fighting games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OqWFMj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10741914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lC7Ffh"&gt;More of a PlayStation fan? Don’t worry, we’ve got you covered! You can enjoy complimentary PlayStation games every month and exclusive sales on new releases with an annual subscription to PlayStation Plus, which is &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=Verge&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states%2Fgamepilot" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently available at Eneba&lt;/a&gt; for several dollars off with discount code &lt;strong&gt;HITMAN4PSPLUS&lt;/strong&gt;. Typically $60 a year, Eneba’s limited-time deal knocks the price down to $36, though, depending upon payment fees, the total could come out to be closer to $39.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6oRl9"&gt;It’s a worthy investment for gamers given the savings the membership offers. PlayStation Plus comes with other perks, too, including access to online multiplayer and the PlayStation Plus Collection, which allows you to download &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/em&gt;, and a host of other classic PS4 games without any additional fees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sMxvts"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10711072"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ik1u5E"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/9/22662055/apple-airtag-loop-hisense-4k-tv-asus-gaming-mouse-playstation-xbox-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/9/22662055/apple-airtag-loop-hisense-4k-tv-asus-gaming-mouse-playstation-xbox-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:01:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Matrix: Resurrections trailer is finally here</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wFR5hwfo6CUb3K-VVEApFqIMPRY=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834037/matrix_resurrections_trailer_pic.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YUoE2T"&gt;The long-awaited trailer for the fourth &lt;em&gt;Matrix&lt;/em&gt; installment is finally here alongside the film’s official title: &lt;em&gt;The Matrix: Resurrections.&lt;/em&gt; The trailer for &lt;em&gt;Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; was first previewed at a CinemaCon presentation from Warner Bros. Pictures on Tuesday, August 24th, in Las Vegas before being released to the public today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRZl9L"&gt;The trailer features clips of Neo (Keanu Reeves), Trinity (Carrie-Anne Moss), and Neil Patrick Harris playing the role of Neo’s therapist. “Am I crazy?” Neo asks, as his pre-awoken Thomas Anderson persona. “We don’t use that word in here,” Harris’ character replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OZR1WP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s time to fly” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kYlCzu"&gt;The trailer also depicts what is widely suspected to be a young Morpheus (played by franchise newcomer Yahya Abdul-Mateen II) telling Neo that “it’s time to fly” while handing him a red pill (though Fishburne himself was &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/laurence-fishburne-in-conversation.html#_ga=2.54469992.1368255391.1629876116-1101500005.1612619158"&gt;not asked&lt;/a&gt; to reprise his role in &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; sequel). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6EEruLxjjhECCeVPs1jQBDrdBPc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836627/rev_1_MX4_TRLR_0012_High_Res_JPEG.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the name of the coffee shop in the background: Simulatte. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jWsEc4WTdZRh2EGOQmLHmhYBHjk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836626/rev_1_MX4_TRLR_0002_High_Res_JPEG.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keanu Reeves and Carrie-Anne Moss will reprise their roles as Neo and Trinity. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eicu0M"&gt;The trailer is full-on nostalgia for &lt;em&gt;Matrix&lt;/em&gt; fans. There are black cats, fights in dojos, high speed action sequences (on a train instead of a highway), fight scenes in corridors, bullets being stopped in mid-air, and Neo must once again follow a woman to learn the truth, only this time, the white rabbit he’s trailing after isn’t just a tattoo on her shoulder, but also Jefferson Airplane’s classic song pumping along as blue pills spill into a sink. Explosions? Oh yeah, and plenty of physics-defying karate kicks, too. We’re also left to ponder what’s real and what’s simulated along a shifting timeline in true &lt;em&gt;Matrix&lt;/em&gt; fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYMsE7"&gt;“After all these years, to be going back to where it all started... back to the Matrix,” says another new addition to the franchise, Jonathan Groff, as the trailer ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5jpzm7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Matrix: Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; is written and directed by Lana Wachowski, who co-directed and co-wrote the first three Matrix films with her sister Lilly Wachowski. The film is scheduled to arrive in theaters and on HBO Max’s ad-free plan on December 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQC1M7"&gt;On Tuesday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660926/the-matrix-resurrections-teaser-red-blue-pill"&gt;fans were treated to a unique teaser website&lt;/a&gt; that presented different tiny snippets of the trailer depending on when you logged in — and, of course, whether you chose the red or blue pill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="PZOoGq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Matrix: Resurrections teaser presents fans with a familiar choice","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660926/the-matrix-resurrections-teaser-red-blue-pill"},{"title":"Here’s what The Verge wants out of a fourth Matrix movie","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/21/20826649/matrix-sequel-m4trix-keanu-reeves-carrie-anne-moss-lana-wachowski-fan-wishes"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wpsufR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, Thursday September 9th, 10:09AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The article previously said that &lt;/em&gt;The Matrix: Resurrections&lt;em&gt; would be showing exclusively in theaters on December 22nd, but it will also be available to watch on HBO Max. We regret the error. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22640826/matrix-4-trailer-resurrections-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22640826/matrix-4-trailer-resurrections-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Marvel Unlimited relaunches with exclusive phone-optimized comics and a fresh new look</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iA0l1QXVYm5-fQ2pfG6gfWehuL4=/105x0:3255x2100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69834003/marvel_unlimited.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bTCyop"&gt;Marvel Unlimited — the company’s all-you-can-read subscription comics service — is getting overhauled today with a new logo, an updated app, a more streamlined design, improved search, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yC9vXk"&gt;And as part of the relaunch, Marvel is also announcing an addition to the service: “Infinity Comics,” a new line of exclusive comics that have been specifically designed for the vertical form factor of a modern smartphone, with scrolling panels that fill the entire width of a phone or tablet screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ORixHi"&gt;Marvel is investing big on Infinity Comics, too. It’ll launch with 27 comics available today, with plans for over 100 by the end of the year. Infinity Comics will be exclusive to Marvel Unlimited subscribers, but they’ll be fully in-universe (meaning that anyone who wants to keep up on the full adventures of Marvel’s superheroes will want to make sure to check them out). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m1mnFDV4HtSmCxs6304_OCmMSaE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836596/MU_DEVICE_GIF_02.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Marvel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A scrolling Infinity Comic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="10ZgBZ"&gt;There are some big names attached to the project, including the Jonathan Hickman-led &lt;em&gt;X-Men Unlimited &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Skottie Young’s &lt;em&gt;Giant-Size&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Little Marvels.&lt;/em&gt; Infinity Comics will also feature new Captain America, Black Widow, Amazing Fantasy, Deadpool, Shang-Chi, and Venom / Carnage comics, with plans to roll out new issues on a weekly basis. For now, Infinity Comics are only available on the Marvel Unlimited apps on iOS and Android, although the company plans to add a web reader for subscribers in the future, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EvE9MB"&gt;While Infinity Comics are the biggest change, Marvel Unlimited is also getting a fresh design to go with it. The design is an almost Netflix-style look that features a big marquee for major events and tie-ins, scrolling carousels of recommended content, storylines, characters, and creators, and new reading guides for guiding newcomers to comics or for following a crossover event. The Marvel Insider loyalty program is also now integrated into the app, where members can earn points for starting (and finishing) comics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O5aLlZCI-XDvYXeHKZN7XK_WR-Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836566/1080x1080_Creator_WhiteBG.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f7GNsHOWjcM9FMMsOWFngoH7a-A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836565/1080x1080_Character_WhiteBG.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Feht5y"&gt;The relaunched app also aims to make browsing and following comics and creators easier and more enjoyable. Starting today, subscribers will be able to locally download an unlimited number of comics, instead of the previous limit of just 12 issues. Users will also be able to save an entire series or run of issues to their libraries with one tap, instead of having to laboriously save individual issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kn3xKO"&gt;Another major addition is the ability to follow specific comics, creators, or characters. If you’re a fan of Al Ewing’s &lt;em&gt;Immortal Hulk&lt;/em&gt; line, for example, you’ll be able to follow Ewing and get notified whenever he has new books out on the app. Or if you want to keep up with every Spider-Man comic, you’ll be able to follow the character and easily find whenever there’s a new book available. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tid5TQXlUgjgdRfVMtv_-3tBfdc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836562/1080x1080_Downloads_WhiteBG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Marvel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Unlimited now allows for unlimited downloads.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="07Kroo"&gt;As of today, Marvel Unlimited features over 29,000 comics and costs $9.99 a month or $69 a year, which makes it a pretty good deal for Marvel fans looking to read absolutely every Marvel comic. That said, despite the relaunch, Marvel is still keeping the service’s biggest caveat: it operates on a three-month delay from when comics are first published in print and digital to when they’re available for subscribers in the app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1GGdB"&gt;In addition to the redesign, Marvel Unlimited is including a new subscription tier. The “annual plus” subscription costs $99 year and has a few extra perks, including membership kits, promises of in-person event invites, and a 10-percent discount code at Disney’s online shop. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22653024/marvel-unlimited-relaunch-infinity-comics-smartphone-ios-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22653024/marvel-unlimited-relaunch-infinity-comics-smartphone-ios-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon starts making its own TVs with new Fire TV Omni and 4-Series</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S0wL36iIzO6E99C-S3lJEBXKKGw=/183x0:2430x1498/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69833905/Screen_Shot_2021_09_09_at_7.38.51_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kt3yTi"&gt;Amazon is officially in the TV business. The company has announced its first lineup of Amazon-branded 4K Fire TVs, which will begin shipping in October. This is a major expansion from the company’s “Fire TV Edition” collaborations, where its popular streaming software comes preloaded on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607331/amazon-best-buy-toshiba-insignia-fire-tv-f50"&gt;sets manufactured by other TV makers&lt;/a&gt;. But with its new Omni and 4-Series, Amazon is describing these as “Amazon-built TVs.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEGsn7"&gt;The Omni series is the higher-end of the two, and beyond offering better picture quality, its other key selling point is hands-free voice control. Amazon includes far-field microphones in each model of the Omni series, which comes in 43, 50, 55, 65, and 75 inches. (Only the 65- and 75-inch models have Dolby Vision, but the others at least get HDR10.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phTOdb"&gt;The company believes that by building the TV itself, it can create a more seamless Fire TV user experience than ever before. That’s led by the content-forward Fire TV interface and wide app selection, but Amazon believes that Alexa voice controls add a major convenience factor. On Omni sets, voice commands are always available — even if the TV is off. These voice commands can be used for finding something to watch, like always, but you can also adjust the TV’s brightness, volume, or switch inputs with Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qRib6K"&gt;Amazon says that over the last two years, customers who used voice features engaged with content twice as much as those who didn’t. And always-listening mics are becoming more common on TVs; Sony already makes some models with them, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22616941/tcl-6-5-series-google-tv-price-specs"&gt;TCL recently introduced new Google TVs&lt;/a&gt; that will ship with far-field microphone arrays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MpTTbQ"&gt;The Fire TV Omni sets also include picture-in-picture for checking your smart home cameras, and you’ll see your Ring doorbell feed whenever someone is at the door. Amazon says it will be adding a “smart home dashboard” later this year for more comprehensive controls over your connected home gadgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VIsK3E"&gt;Here are other new features that are in the works for Fire TV, which will come to these TVs and the company’s other streaming devices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0tRtxv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Alexa, what should I watch?”:&lt;/strong&gt; Need a new source for great movie and TV recommendations? Alexa Conversations for Fire TV allows you to ask Alexa for a recommendation just like you would a friend or movie expert. Alexa offers tailored TV show and movie recommendations from your favorite streaming apps like Prime Video, allowing you to refine searches by genre, actors, award-winning movies, and more, all from the comfort of your couch. “Alexa, what should I watch?” will launch in beta this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYBbHV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Alexa, Play Something” from Netflix:&lt;/strong&gt; Exclusively available on Fire TV and debuting this fall, Netflix is making it easier to find something to watch. Netflix members love the “Play Something” feature today, and soon you can simply say, “Alexa, Play Something on Netflix” from the Fire TV home screen and Netflix will launch a show or movie you might enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6kbtj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Alexa, play TikTok”:&lt;/strong&gt; Fire TV was the first to support TikTok videos on streaming media players in the UK, Germany and France, and soon, you’ll be able to access TikTok content in the U.S. and Canada. No more huddling around a cell phone to see the latest viral video&lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt;from your Fire TV, you can view and discover TikTok feeds and use AutoPlay, which will serve a continuous content feed without interruptions. Just say, “Alexa, play TikTok” to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="zS6VVD"&gt;If you already own Echo speakers like the Echo Studio (or a pair of regular Echos), those can be wirelessly linked to Omni-series TVs to provide richer audio than the TV is otherwise capable of on its own. This Alexa home theater audio mode supports streamed content, but Amazon says it also works across cable boxes, gaming consoles, and over-the-air antenna programming. It’s a feature that’s also available on the cheaper Fire TV 4-Series sets. Amazon says a pop-up will appear in the Alexa app for compatible sound devices. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uNc-KKESps_w746c6hY46OMktxM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836518/Fire_TV_4_Series_front.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fire TV 4-Series doesn’t have far-field microphones and instead includes an Alexa Voice Remote.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0idpZG"&gt;Amazon might call these “Amazon-built” TVs — and the company’s advanced far-field mic tech is definitely present — but it’s also very likely that Amazon has struck partnerships for much of the other hardware here. I’m almost certain that TCL is manufacturing one or both of these TV lineups. They definitely have that TCL look to them, and the port layouts between something like the TCL 6-Series and Fire TV Omni are nearly identical:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-4_z9sxd-fLMCdM6sBgpaHFLls4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22834622/HDMIcomparo.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: TCL / Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;TCL’s 6-Series Roku TV (left) and Amazon’s Fire TV Omni (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mTqNL1"&gt;If that’s the case, these aren’t TCL’s latest and greatest panels: Amazon’s Fire TVs lack HDMI 2.1 features like 4K at 120Hz, though they do support auto low-latency mode — which Amazon says will also help the responsiveness of its Luna cloud gaming service. Amazon also isn’t really going into specifics about whether they’ve got full-array local dimming or other display tech details. Similar to the existing roster of Fire TV Edition sets, the prices for Amazon’s first TVs reflect a focus on providing a good, if not top-tier picture for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U0PtWo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire TV Omni Series pricing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="NanHoE"&gt;75-inch: $1,099.99 (with Dolby Vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uHvPxZ"&gt;65-inch: $829.99 (with Dolby Vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ioGUjp"&gt;55-inch: $559.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8rwqKb"&gt;50-inch: $509.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eSb4Fe"&gt;43-inch: $409.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="cPArUf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire TV 4-Series pricing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hbkt6b"&gt;55-inch: $519.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fsX23C"&gt;50-inch: $469.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FvJyr6"&gt;43-inch: $369.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="gGvAV0"&gt;Alongside its first “self-built” TVs, Amazon and Best Buy are also announcing more Fire TV sets from Toshiba and Pioneer. Toshiba’s models, coming in spring 2022, will integrate far-field microphones, and Pioneer will release budget-priced 43-inch and 50-inch sets. (This is “Pioneer” in branding only, which might be hard to swallow for those who fondly remember the Pioneer Kuro plasma from many years ago.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1MfkgN"&gt;In some ways, the Omni and 4-Series represent Amazon’s most ambitious step into the living room yet. But even for customers who aren’t shopping for a new TV, the company’s goal remains having a Fire TV product for everyone. Between these TVs, streaming sticks, and products like the Fire TV Cube, Amazon’s lineup is getting quite expansive.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22662673/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22662673/amazon-fire-tv-omni-4-series-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
