<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T15:30:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to change your iPhone’s text size for a specific app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eTnXvK4Xy-tlW_cO9ot1wSwK5Tw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69592681/cgartenberg_210629_4653_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vtitae"&gt;Sometimes you want the text in your app to be smaller, so you can fit more content on a single screen. Sometimes you want it to be bigger, especially if you’ve been putting off buying those reading glasses. But until recently, if you had an iPhone, you had to pick a single text size as a standard for all your apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2h7Pgx"&gt;Not anymore. In iOS 15, you can adjust the text size separately for each of your apps. So you can, for example, keep the text small for your email, but make it a bit larger in Twitter — or vice versa. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmarShahine/status/1416015722174636033?s=20"&gt;@OmarShahine&lt;/a&gt; for the info.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BTHoFE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;One of the best hidden new iOS 15 features is per app font sizes. I like to use the smallest dynamic size system wide but bump up Outlook by one side since I read so much email. &lt;a href="https://t.co/aL8TxOIXVA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aL8TxOIXVA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Omar Shahine   (@OmarShahine) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OmarShahine/status/1416015722174636033?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CUdOGB"&gt;If you’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22524845/ios-15-how-to-install"&gt;the public beta of iOS 15 installed&lt;/a&gt;, here’s how you can adjust the text size for each app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3cDHH"&gt;First, you need to make sure the “Text Size” option is in your iOS Control Center:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Zb85Lz"&gt;Swipe from the upper-right corner to get to your Control Center. Check to see if “Text Size” is there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Q0DBBc"&gt;If it isn’t, then quit Control Center and go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Control Center.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f3J3dO"&gt;Under the “More Controls” subhead, find “Text Size” and tap the plus sign on the left to add it to your included controls. This will add it to your Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="To add Text Size, go to Settings &amp;amp;gt; Control Center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pi_CZZK0lWy_Z0gRc8_4uYmFjTU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722289/IMG_ACABE3FA7DC3_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Control Center,” then find “Text Size” and tap the green plus sign.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Text Size will now be part of the included controls." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QKlHTFYFkBpR78OLt5s9WUBYIAE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722291/IMG_AEE5CFDB6AF2_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Text Size” will now be part of the included controls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5tfcoG"&gt;Once that’s done, it’s simple to tweak the text size for each app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oQxLaT"&gt;Open the app that you want to configure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DcG7Nb"&gt;Swipe from the upper-right corner to get to Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If you need to switch text size, swipe from the upper-right corner." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PBe0WUM-qNKs-DLx27LYg-xbSio=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722286/IMG_7CC84A574C5C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need to switch text size, swipe from the upper-right corner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap the double-A Text Size icon." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ucja2xtAn--TcUc-gFqinNjPH6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722287/IMG_3D147AFAD9D1_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap the double-A “Text Size” icon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Hxmd6X"&gt;Tap the “Text Size” icon (the one with the small and large A’s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="o9wtKb"&gt;At the bottom of the screen, you’ll see a toggle on the left for that specific app (for example, the left side of the toggle will say “Twitter Only,” and the right side will say “All Apps.”) Move the toggle to the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wAo1FX"&gt;Once that’s done, use the main control in the center of the screen to set the text size for that app, and then tap anywhere on the screen to get back to the Control Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The toggle at the bottom lets you switch text size for a single app." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ghQ69r96AUnAqDvBhOr6gJ1p7UA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722282/IMG_B31FFB1D7C1A_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The toggle at the bottom lets you switch text size for a single app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Now you’ve changed the text size just for that app." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vbCFaIN3K1x3rMcvfSlL0LzroLI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722285/IMG_D714DD00DBB5_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now you’ve changed the text size just for that app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="4jwEe9"&gt;Swipe up to get rid of the Control Center and you’ll return to your app. You should see the difference in the text size immediately — but that difference will not be reflected in other apps.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jWTBAd"&gt;And, of course, if you want to switch back to a standard text size, just go back to the Control Center, select “Text Size,” and move the bottom toggle to “All Apps.” But be aware that you’ll be resetting all your apps to that text size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cEjOQy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22580423/ios-15-iphone-text-size-how-to-control-center"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22580423/ios-15-iphone-text-size-how-to-control-center</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T15:05:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T15:05:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Virginia will invest $700 million to bring broadband to every household in the state</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ilr2qoq9DNkDc8RiOwyN5JQhywQ=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69592583/acastro_170711_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3NLwbZ"&gt;On Friday, Virginia Gov. Ralph Northam (D) announced that the state plans to invest $700 million in American Rescue Plan funding to reach universal broadband connectivity by 2024. This new investment shaves four years off of the governor’s original plan to connect every household to high-speed broadband.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYnmuI"&gt;The pandemic dramatically affected the ways in which people work and attend school — pushing many office-holders to renew efforts to ensure citizens are able to get online. According to Northam, more than 233,000 homes and businesses in Virginia are without broadband access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OvFKTn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Not just a luxury for some, but an essential utility for all”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Yck6MG"&gt;“It’s time to close the digital divide in our Commonwealth and treat Internet service like the 21st century necessity that it is — not just a luxury for some, but an essential utility for all,” Northam said in a news release Friday. “The pandemic has reinforced how important high-quality broadband is for the health, education, and economic opportunity, and we cannot afford to leave any community behind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDSFJC"&gt;The Virginia General Assembly is set to meet for a special session on August 2nd to plot a path forward for spending the funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F00cMU"&gt;At a press conference announcing the investment Friday, Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA) lauded the funding and promised that Virginia lawmakers were working alongside the governor’s office to produce future-proof connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQvtAm"&gt;“When we talk about broadband, let’s make clear we’re working under the governor’s leadership, not to some slow speed like 25 down and three up, but much higher speeds,” Warner said Friday. “So you actually can see somebody on a Zoom.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gxg9sz"&gt;In a July report, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) called on the Federal Communications Commission &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568454/broadband-minimum-speeds-small-businesses"&gt;to rethink its current minimum broadband standard&lt;/a&gt; of 25Mbps download and 3Mbps upload speeds. The GAO said that most businesses in 2021 cannot run their operations effectively at such slow speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3tXwsO"&gt;In March, President Joe Biden signed the &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Rescue-Plan-Fact-Sheet.pdf"&gt;American Rescue Plan&lt;/a&gt;, providing billions in COVID-19 relief for states. Virginia received more than &lt;a href="https://www.governor.virginia.gov/newsroom/all-releases/2021/may/headline-895119-en.html"&gt;$4 billion in relief&lt;/a&gt;, the pool of money that will be used to support universal broadband connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4YN5Jb"&gt;“This will be fiber, satellite, maybe wireless,” Warner said Friday. “This is the kind of future we all have imagined for quite awhile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kD1utN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CsHrEJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580559/virginia-broadband-household-ralph-northam-mark-warner"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580559/virginia-broadband-household-ralph-northam-mark-warner</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T14:35:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T14:35:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>There’s enough Steam Deck demand to take Steam’s store down</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Steam Deck multiplayer" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lwXKK_4AfiIyY6ReZQITDz05_44=/490x0:4417x2618/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69592427/Steam_Deck_multiplayer.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Steam Deck multiplayer | Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bTvlDO"&gt;Valve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;officially revealed&lt;/a&gt; its handheld PC gaming machine only a day ago, but that was apparently enough to spread the word — when the Steam Deck went up for preorder today at 1PM ET, the demand from gamers knocked Steam for a loop as the store produced error after error. Seemingly every step produced another pitfall: two-factor authentication if you weren’t signed in, some signed-in accounts had to sign in once again, credit card checks, even a wonky response from a system that pegged long-established Steam accounts as being “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/xenolon/status/1416085213407551491"&gt;too new&lt;/a&gt;” to participate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zahv1t"&gt;Other parts of Steam got flaky during the crush of preorder interest, too. The entire Steam store, Steam’s community pages, and the age gate that lets you view mature-rated titles didn’t always work this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BxPnYW"&gt;Two &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editors managed to get through the reservation process and put $5 in their Steam Wallet to reserve a Steam Deck, eventually, with a little luck and a lot of refreshing. One’s still stuck in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Steam Deck “servers busy” message" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fs_9CrQuSAci7jK9MGjDv9HAz20=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722268/steam_deck_busy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Richard Lawler&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Steam Deck “servers busy” message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A typical Steam Deck ordering error." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0UmX40ND9kio-Cn7_nfT3NyDw4I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722259/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sean Hollister&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A typical Steam Deck ordering error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iClUoY"&gt;The reservation system opted to lock out people with new or unused accounts for the first 48 hours, so it’s hard to know if the problems were caused by demand from real people who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578902/video-game-handhelds-steam-deck-switch-playdate-analogue-pocket"&gt;won’t let handhelds go&lt;/a&gt;, or if bot operators found some way around the block. One &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editor confirmed that his credit card company wasn’t blocking the transaction, even after receiving Steam error messages suggesting that was the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLb6SQ"&gt;On the customer end, it seemed just as difficult, if not more, than obtaining recent high-demand items like a PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22565905/nintendo-switch-oled-model-preorder-price-availability-where-to-buy"&gt;Switch OLED&lt;/a&gt;. The mess didn’t rise nearly to the level of issues &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/10/29/21539965/nvidia-rtx-3070-preorders-sold-out-micro-center-best-buy-newegg"&gt;we’ve seen trying to obtain a new graphics card&lt;/a&gt;, but if anyone figures out how to mine cryptocurrency on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578917/valve-steam-deck-nintendo-switch-xbox-series-x-ps5-spec-comparison"&gt;Zen 2 chip inside&lt;/a&gt;, then that could change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ASFpys"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you have questions about the Steam Deck reservation process, including regional availability, there's a reservation FAQ at &lt;a href="https://t.co/6Ln0KvIGlw"&gt;https://t.co/6Ln0KvIGlw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To learn more about Steam Deck, visit &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZOTx3KUCVK"&gt;https://t.co/ZOTx3KUCVK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steam (@Steam) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Steam/status/1416081471584956417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580453/valve-steam-deck-pre-order-handheld-pc-gaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580453/valve-steam-deck-pre-order-handheld-pc-gaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google redesigns its emoji to be more universal and authentic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fCGoyN67c4oJDZrlIhku8-1UmvA=/158x0:1891x1155/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591877/Untitled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;992 of Google’s emoji designs are receiving tweaks.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hchssT"&gt;Google is tweaking 992 of its emoji designs to make them more “universal, accessible, and authentic,” &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/emoji-day-redesign-easier-sharing/"&gt;the company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The new designs will arrive this fall alongside Android 12, but Google says they’ll also be available on older versions with apps that use its Appcompat compatibility layer. They’re also coming to other Google platforms like Gmail, Chrome OS, Google Chat, and YouTube Live Chat this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="li379f"&gt;None of the changes are particularly drastic. Instead, they’re mostly the kinds of tweaks that make the meaning of each emoji easier to understand at a glance by a wider range of people. The pie emoji, for example, currently looks like a classic American pumpkin pie. That’s fine for Americans, but it means that, in the UK, the design looked closer to a tart than a traditional pie. The new more universal design should fix this.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i-Ti0iEYP6HJgHvtukwHzweTWxc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721252/Untitled.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;American-style pie versus a more universal design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XahE3y"&gt;In other cases, Google has given its designs a bolder, more exaggerated look, which is helpful considering how small they appear on most screens. The croissant and bacon emoji will now have more of a shine to them, while the scissors have a more exaggerated sharp edge. Vehicles like cars and taxis have also had their proportions adjusted to make them more eye-catching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHdxhm"&gt;Finally, the bikini emoji no longer looks like it’s being worn by an invisible person, and the face mask emoji now shows a face with its eyes open. Google says it made this change to reflect the fact that masks have become “a universal way of showing kindness to others” rather than a symbol of someone being sick.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BN3pNgSy2k1oCUz3M1BUzms9S6c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721254/Untitled__2_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The eye-opening new mask design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MeNiB5"&gt;It’s not unusual for companies to redesign their emoji like this, either to correct inaccuracies or reflect changing cultural assumptions about how they’re used. Last year, Apple made a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/3/21500163/apple-emoji-mask-medical-face-2020"&gt;similar tweak to its own mask emoji&lt;/a&gt; to show a smiling face underneath the mask, and it has also changed its syringe emoji to make it more appropriate as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285963/apple-emoji-ios-14-5-smiley-faces-hearts-more-skin-tones"&gt;symbol for vaccines&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019, it even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/9/24/20882195/ios-13-1-emoji-updates-squid-fixed-mosquito-abacus-puzzle-piece-heart-eyes"&gt;updated its abacus emoji&lt;/a&gt; after people pointed out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/5/26/18639006/apple-abacus-emoji-wrong-historically-inaccurate-math"&gt;problems with its old design&lt;/a&gt;. And let’s not forget Google’s redesigns of its burger and beer emoji in response to an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/5/16737066/google-burger-beer-emoji-android-8-1-fix-release-date"&gt;outcry in 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BT6Xj"&gt;If you’re wondering why we’ve seen such a flurry of emoji news over the past couple of days, it’s because this year’s World Emoji Day lands tomorrow, July 17th. Yesterday, we saw the announcement of the finalists for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578697/new-emoji-14-0-finalists-unicode-consortium"&gt;this year’s new batch of emoji&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook announced new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578633/facebook-messenger-sound-emoji-soundmojis"&gt;emoji with sound for its Messenger service&lt;/a&gt;, and even Microsoft got in on the action with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578352/microsoft-new-3d-emoji-clippy-windows-office"&gt;new set of 3D emoji&lt;/a&gt; across Windows, Office, Microsoft Teams, and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579805/google-emoji-redesign-2021-android-gmail-pumpkin-pie"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579805/google-emoji-redesign-2021-android-gmail-pumpkin-pie</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T12:51:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T12:51:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use SharePlay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dDiblckRVLHgrtbBPSEcr9coKKI=/248x0:1652x936/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591839/Screen_Shot_2021_07_16_at_11.24.18_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aFX6H0"&gt;The headline feature for Apple’s fall updates (including iOS 15, iPadOS 15, tvOS 15, and macOS Monterey) is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;SharePlay&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a new software feature on top of FaceTime that allows you to watch and listen to movies, TV shows, music, podcasts, and more with friends and family while video chatting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVhoWh"&gt;Right now, the number of SharePlay-compatible apps is a pretty small list: the Apple TV app for movies and TV shows, the Apple Music app for music, and Apple’s Podcasts app for podcasts. The company is promising some bigger third-party partners when iOS 15 launches this fall, including HBO Max, Disney Plus, Paramount Plus, TikTok, and Twitch. Some big names seem to be skipping out for now, though: most notably, Netflix and YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxxapQ"&gt;For now, if you want to try it, here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wyP4fu"&gt;SharePlay with iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nDvm7iXfkPCtVxPnWrw6IuXTGBo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721826/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_TV_Expanse_originals_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starting playback of a TV episode using SharePlay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yCS1B9wBu4EH2FXYdzECRDF6Xdk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721827/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_TV_Expanse_Messages_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePlay allows you to still use your phone while watching shows together.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c2EF2u"&gt;To use SharePlay on an iPhone or iPad, first, make sure that everyone on the call is using iOS 15 and iPadOS 15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ilfgIM"&gt;Next, start a FaceTime call — either one-on-one or a group call — with everyone you want to watch or listen with. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ea1Yzs"&gt;Once you’ve done that, exit out of the FaceTime call (which will automatically move to a picture-in-picture window) and head over to a SharePlay-compatible app. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n0Od7O"&gt;After that, playing something over SharePlay is as simple as it is when you’re just watching or listening alone: just select whatever content you want, and it’ll play for everyone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Widx5O"&gt;Controlling a SharePlay stream just requires that you play, pause, and skip around as you usually would. SharePlay automatically keeps everyone’s streams in sync so that if one person pauses to get a snack, the movie will pause for everyone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="6qSHbT"&gt;You have two options for ending a stream: either end it for everyone on the SharePlay call or end it just for you (letting everyone else continue to watch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vDOHUv"&gt;SharePlay with macOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="p50DLz"&gt;Using SharePlay on macOS Monterey works similarly to iOS and iPadOS: you’ll need to start a FaceTime call, launch a compatible app, and play some content that everyone on the call can access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HktWcy"&gt;When you’re in a SharePlay session, you’ll be able to access controls for the call through a menu bar icon (instead of the pop-over menu that appears on iOS and iPadOS).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zxtzPYaDijnkIvV6LByNzsFSr-U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721810/Apple_macos_monterey_facetime_06072021_big_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;macOS’s SharePlay menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ni0t4U"&gt;SharePlay with Apple TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2BmoYv"&gt;Using SharePlay with an Apple TV works a little differently than the other platforms, given that you can’t actually start (or participate) on a FaceTime call through an Apple TV itself. Rather, when you’re FaceTiming on a nearby iPhone, iPad, or Mac with SharePlay, the Apple TV will offer you the option to hand off the media portion of that call to the bigger screen through Control Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWqzlT"&gt;To access that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Gzk4BJ"&gt;Simply follow the above steps to start a SharePlay FaceTime call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B3ceKN"&gt;Then press and hold the TV button on your Apple TV remote. From there, you’ll be able to select the new SharePlay icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bzMSmjBnB5ZjwW2NfJYmIZIQ5c8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721815/Apple_iPhone12Pro_iOS15_FaceTime_expanse_groupfacetime_060721_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iOS interface when watching a show on an Apple TV while using SharePlay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WjF2c5"&gt;It’s important to note that only the music or movie that you’re watching will shift over to the Apple TV. Your FaceTime video will still be playing on the Mac, iPhone, or iPad that you started with. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22577178/shareplay-how-to-apple-facetime-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-apple-tv-video-music"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22577178/shareplay-how-to-apple-facetime-ios-15-ipados-macos-monterey-apple-tv-video-music</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T12:34:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T12:34:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Rivian delays first electric pickup deliveries to September</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KqNdNUR3oq1L82c4DaveWQXldFg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591771/rivian_electric_truck_3736.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RliHc0"&gt;Rivian has delayed the first deliveries of its long-awaited electric pickup truck again, this time until September. Rivian CEO RJ Scaringe broke the news to buyers in &lt;a href="https://www.autonews.com/manufacturing/rivian-ceo-tells-customers-first-deliveries-delayed-until-september?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter"&gt;an email&lt;/a&gt; sent &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/rivian-delays-deliveries-of-r1t-r1s-electric-vehicles-again/"&gt;Friday morning&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWUAX6"&gt;The Amazon and Ford-backed EV startup originally planned to start delivering its electric pickup, the R1T, and its SUV, the R1S, in 2020. But it scuttled those plans at the beginning of the pandemic and said at the time that it would start deliveries in 2021 instead. Rivian eventually settled on starting deliveries of the R1T in June of this year, only to push that back to July, and now to September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U2zdB6"&gt;“We know you can’t wait to get behind the wheel of your vehicle,” Scaringe wrote in the email. “Earlier this summer, we announced that deliveries would begin in July; however, the timing for the first deliveries of the R1T has shifted to September, with the R1S shortly thereafter in the fall. I wanted to be sure you heard this from me directly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gK3Xz4"&gt;Scaringe said the “cascading impacts of the pandemic have had a compounding effect greater than anyone anticipated.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="WLiGqc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Cascading impacts of the pandemic” are partly to blame&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hLGEJ2"&gt;“Everything from facility construction, to equipment installation, to vehicle component supply (especially semiconductors) has been impacted by the pandemic,” he wrote. Scaringe also said that trying to launch the pickup truck, SUV, and a delivery van being developed with Amazon while also building out a manufacturing facility in Illinois has been difficult, calling it a “complex orchestra of coordinated and interlinked activities where small issues can translate into ramp delays.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXWMFr"&gt;Scaringe also copped to poor communication with reservation holders. “I have spoken with a number of you and know we need to do a better job at communicating specifics around deliveries. Our Guides will continue reaching out to schedule deliveries and will be there for any questions throughout the process,” he wrote. He promised to give more updates in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWiLD0"&gt;Rivian was founded in 2009 but kept &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/23/17380600/rivian-electric-truck-pickup-suv-interview-rj-scaringe"&gt;an extremely low profile until 2018&lt;/a&gt; when it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/26/18111782/rivian-r1t-electric-pickup-price-specs-la-auto-show-2018"&gt;debuted the R1T and R1S at the LA Auto Show&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, it has raised an incredible amount of cash — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238670/rivian-funding-amazon-electric-truck-suv"&gt;more than $8 billion&lt;/a&gt; — from Amazon, Ford, and other institutional investors. The company is also working on going public, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/electric-truck-maker-rivian-is-said-to-select-ipo-underwriters?sref=DWzi38c2"&gt;which would add even more cash to its war chest&lt;/a&gt;. Its workforce has also ballooned to over 7,000 employees, Scaringe said in the email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zXDTEB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580293/rivian-delay-september-deliveries-electric-pickup-r1t-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580293/rivian-delay-september-deliveries-electric-pickup-r1t-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T12:25:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T12:25:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: the state of MagSafe, Valve’s Steam Deck, and billionaires in space</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MagSafe Battery Pack" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xHJ5H3Mb_t9tCvTF5G4S8gTjZKE=/138x0:1478x893/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591730/iphone_magsafe_packa.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7kwzrD"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k7grsg"&gt;This week on the show, Nilay and Dieter bring back&lt;em&gt; Verge&lt;/em&gt; managing editor Alex Cranz to discuss the announcement of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;Valve’s gaming handheld the Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577868/netflix-video-games-confirmed-mike-verdu-ea-oculus-facebook"&gt;Netflix’s dive into gaming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576703/iphone-13-rumors-sizes-notch-camera-processor"&gt;Apple iPhone 13 rumors&lt;/a&gt;, the state of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575678/apple-magsafe-battery-pack-iphone-12-pro-mini-max"&gt;MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;, and, of course, the growing number of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570287/space-tourism-virgin-galactic-branson-blue-origin-bezos"&gt;billionaires in space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KiWcd0"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP4807180259&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WuC0cS"&gt;You can listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X9TD1e"&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lSzXwz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568397/covid-vaccine-cybersecurity-cisa-task-force"&gt;The COVID-19 vaccines weren’t hacked — this task force is one reason why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2xUyFq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22573405/foxconn-tsmc-covid-vaccine-deal-taiwan-biontech-china"&gt;Foxconn and TSMC strike deal to buy 10 million COVID vaccines for Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="liWSBw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;Valve’s gaming handheld is called the Steam Deck and it’s shipping in December&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aCP9Pp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577868/netflix-video-games-confirmed-mike-verdu-ea-oculus-facebook"&gt;Netflix snags former EA, Oculus exec to lead its video game efforts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="N8MARv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577475/apple-safari-macos-monterey-ios-15-developer-beta-3-change-design"&gt;Apple’s latest iOS and macOS betas undo some of Safari’s controversial new design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JLxXf6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576703/iphone-13-rumors-sizes-notch-camera-processor"&gt;iPhone 13 rumors grow more certain ahead of September launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DafqSM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22573423/ipad-mini-2021-release-date-news-features-bezels"&gt;Redesigned iPad Mini reportedly on track to launch this fall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IfaSC8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575678/apple-magsafe-battery-pack-iphone-12-pro-mini-max"&gt;Apple just launched an official $99 MagSafe battery pack for the iPhone 12 lineup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Nja6Gt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576245/iphone-12-reverse-wireless-charging-magsafe-battery-pack"&gt;iPhone 12 reverse wireless charging can power up Apple’s new MagSafe battery pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lqfdYS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575852/apple-pay-later-report-affirm-paypal-klarna-monthly-installments"&gt;Apple is working on Apple Pay Later to help you buy things without paying for them yet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XkZDaf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570481/apple-tv-plus-nfl-sunday-ticket-streaming-rights"&gt;Apple reportedly wants in on NFL Sunday Ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7EwR61"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/13/22575368/apple-ios-14-weather-app-69-rounding-error-15"&gt;Apple’s weather app won’t say it’s 69 degrees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="q7vg13"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576926/facebook-seeks-ftc-chair-lina-khan-refusal-antitrust-case"&gt;Facebook says FTC chair shouldn’t help decide the future of its antitrust case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="r9AOE2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570567/biden-net-neutrality-competition-eo"&gt;Biden’s executive order puts net neutrality back in the spotlight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GgtRpc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570826/president-joe-biden-executive-order-right-to-repair"&gt;President Joe Biden’s latest executive order is a huge win for right to repair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yinajq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570287/space-tourism-virgin-galactic-branson-blue-origin-bezos"&gt;Space tourism rivalry gets extremely petty ahead of Branson’s spaceflight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ya0AVE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572643/virgin-galactic-omaze-sweepstakes-richard-branson-trip-to-space"&gt;Virgin Galactic has opened a sweepstakes offering a trip to space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lKIc2o"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572374/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-space-unity"&gt;Virgin Galactic successfully sends Richard Branson to the edge of space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ubHftq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572858/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-2021-leak-evan-blass-galaxy-z-fold-flip-3-s21-fe-watch-4-buds-2-date"&gt;Samsung’s next Galaxy Unpacked device lineup may have been entirely spoiled in huge new leak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Zomk2d"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22574173/galaxy-z-fold-3-s-pen-pro-support-fcc-filing"&gt;The Galaxy Z Fold 3 will support the S Pen Pro, according to FCC filings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4bgaNu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22573890/ikea-sonos-symfonisk-picture-frame-speaker-review"&gt;Ikea and Sonos picture frame speaker review: wall of sound&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ryWcTQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22576224/tva-tempad-review-loki-season-1-review-marvel-timedoor"&gt;TVA TemPad review: who needs TikTok when you can control time and space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MOY7bD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22574103/internet-bill-equity-verge-consumer-reports-partnership"&gt;We want to see your internet bill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="MKVBgo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580054/vergecast-podcast-valve-steam-deck-iphone-13-rumors-richard-branson-space"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580054/vergecast-podcast-valve-steam-deck-iphone-13-rumors-richard-branson-space</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T11:55:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T11:55:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google executive steps down after offensive manifesto about antisemitic past</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="RISE Conference 2017" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m8r33u7u7I-0e7q73B3FC76Ww30=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591484/813031818.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by studioEAST / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="33h6SW"&gt;Google parted ways with a cloud services executive after he published a &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210614065822/https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/we-one-amr-awadallah/"&gt;LinkedIn manifesto&lt;/a&gt; about Israeli-Palestinian relations and his vehemently antisemitic past. &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/16/google-separates-with-cloud-vp-after-employees-complain-about-manifesto.html"&gt;CNBC reports&lt;/a&gt; that Google faced internal criticism over Amr Awadallah, VP of developer relations at Google Cloud. While Awadallah said he published the piece to promote tolerance and understanding, employees objected to how Awadallah described Jews and expressed concerns about his past beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tez4yX"&gt;Awadallah began the June 13th post — titled “We are one!” — with a declaration that “‘I hated the Jewish people, all the Jewish people’! and emphasis here is on the past tense.” The 10,000-word manifesto discussed his upbringing in Egypt, saying he’d been “very cautious” working with Stanford research adviser and VMWare founder Mendel Rosenblum but that Rosenblum had “converted me to be a Jew lover to be honest.” Awadallah also cited a 23andMe analysis saying he had 0.1 percent Ashkenazi Jewish ancestry to claim he “belong[s] to the Jewish ethnic group by DNA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nW40bz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This has made my job as one of your colleagues much harder”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6QWld"&gt;At least one Google employee, Daniel Golding, publicly commented on the post. “On one hand, I’m grateful that you no longer hate my children. On the other, this has made my job as one of your colleagues much harder. The previous situation has made being a Jewish leader at Google tough. This has made it almost untenable,” Golding wrote. “I’m unsure why you would write this under your title and company affiliation and it frustrates me. You could simply have done this as a private person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CWf64k"&gt;CNBC spoke with employees who said frustration had already been building over Awadallah’s leadership style and that the post had made it harder for employees to perform effective developer relations. Awadallah joined Google in 2019 after co-founding the cloud services company Cloudera. After a tense all-hands meeting where employees confronted Awadallah about the post, Google Cloud VP of engineering and product Eyal Manor reportedly sent an internal email announcing his departure. “I wanted to share that today is Amr Awadallah’s last day at Google,” it read in part, according to CNBC. Google declined comment on the story, and Awadallah did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; was able to confirm his departure from the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oIRU87"&gt;Google, along with other tech companies, has faced growing internal conflicts in recent years. Employees have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/10/21132366/google-eileen-naughton-culture-hr-people-operations-step-down"&gt;pushed back&lt;/a&gt; against &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396112/google-ethical-ai-team-bias-harassment-timnit-gebru-firing"&gt;alleged bias and sexual harassment&lt;/a&gt; and a failure to live up to its stated ideals, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22370158/google-ai-ethics-timnit-gebru-margaret-mitchell-firing-reputation"&gt;firing prominent artificial intelligence ethics researchers&lt;/a&gt; who raised concerns about the company’s AI. In the email reviewed by CNBC, Manor reportedly noted that work at Google has been “particularly challenging with a number of organizational changes and leadership transitions while we’ve all been navigating a global pandemic and don’t have the benefit of connecting in person together like we used to.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580042/google-amr-awadallah-anti-semitism-cloud-cloudera-leaves-manifesto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580042/google-amr-awadallah-anti-semitism-cloud-cloudera-leaves-manifesto</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T11:53:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T11:53:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Counterfeit wireless earbuds are being seized in record numbers at US border</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XOc9geu894FJNlcKQmF2IgkMZ6s=/0x0:1024x683/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591470/AirPods.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/CBPChicago/status/1407021736089079815/photo/1" target="_blank"&gt;US Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kMwSLT"&gt;The number of counterfeit wireless earbuds seized by US border customs in 2021 has already surpassed last year’s total, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/airpods-are-a-huge-hit-with-consumers-and-counterfeiters"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a sign of how eager the makers of these knockoffs are to keep riding the sustained popularity of earbuds like Apple’s AirPods and those from Samsung, Jabra, Bose, Sony, and other companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftpC8P"&gt;According to the report, “roughly 360,000 counterfeit wireless headphones” — valued at $62.2 million — were nabbed in the first nine months of fiscal 2021. That’s well above the 295,000 pairs that were confiscated during the whole of fiscal 2020. Just yesterday, US Customs and Border Protection &lt;a href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/local-media-release/thousands-fake-apple-airpods-worth-13-million-seized-cincinnati-cbp"&gt;announced a major confiscation&lt;/a&gt; in Cincinnati. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Eyvo0A"&gt;Around 80 percent of fakes entering the US come from China, and their manufacturers see a huge opportunity: &lt;a href="https://news.strategyanalytics.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2021/Strategy-Analytics-True-Wireless-Stereo-Headset-Sales-Surge-90-in-2020-as-Chinese-Vendors-Surge/default.aspx"&gt;Strategy Analytics&lt;/a&gt; forecasted worldwide sales of Bluetooth headsets to be more than 300 million in 2020, and the true wireless earbuds market surged by 90 percent. Apple still holds a commanding lead in market share, though a crowded field has cut into that dominance. Research firm Canalys estimates that Apple took in at least $16 billion from AirPods sales last year, according to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; report. The introduction of the AirPods Pro in 2019 gave scammers a chance to try and wring even more money out of unknowing buyers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xJcpfVFw7_W-F1lW4xc5kJPbDgs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22721822/clones.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/local-media-release/331000-worth-fake-airpods-seized-cbp-officers-louisville" target="_blank"&gt;US Customs and Border Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A confiscated shipment of AirPods counterfeits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w5v7lp"&gt;OnePlus had to deal with an awkward controversy last September when US Customs and Border Protection &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/13/21435637/us-cbp-counterfeit-airpods-oneplus-buds-mixup"&gt;seized a shipment of the company’s earbuds&lt;/a&gt; and described them as counterfeit AirPods. There are design differences between the two, but the blatant AirPod clones are getting closer and closer to the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LcIAZ"&gt;Some counterfeit earbuds are suspected to have been created “with genuine molds stolen from factories that work with Apple.” Others can mimic the AirPods pairing process on an iPhone and display a proper Apple serial number. But even in these situations, there are still subtle tells (like a bogus firmware version) that reveal a product as a fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DlzhRG"&gt;Highlighting the potential safety risks, Apple says it has a global effort in place to tackle the issue of knockoffs, and it’s working with law enforcement and e-commerce sites to prevent customers from being duped wherever possible. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580089/counterfeit-wireless-earbuds-apple-airpods-us-border"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580089/counterfeit-wireless-earbuds-apple-airpods-us-border</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-16T11:26:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T11:26:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Emergency department visits spiked during June heatwave in US Northwest</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Heatwave Sets Record Temperatures In Portland" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/If6tRxG9iqPVqVRsNxXRd9_fLhM=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69591227/1233703730.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Residents at a cooling center during a heatwave in Portland, Oregon, U.S., on Monday, June 28, 2021.  | Maranie Staab/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E6ROSc"&gt;The heatwave that scorched the Pacific Northwest in late June resulted in an enormous surge in emergency department (ED) visits in the region, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7029e1.htm#:~:text=Record%20high%20temperatures%20are%20occurring,States%20each%20year%20(2)."&gt;new analysis from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/a&gt;. There were 1,038 heat-related visits to the emergency department during the peak of the heatwave on June 28th in “region 10” — which includes Oregon, Washington, Idaho, and Alaska. In shocking comparison, there were just nine similar ED visits in the region on the same day in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bqKjln"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Northwest was home to a disproportionate number of emergency department visits&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mVOQLl"&gt;While much of the West was suffering through sweltering heat in June, the Northwest was home to a disproportionate number of emergency department visits. Region 10 accounted for 15 percent of ED visits nationwide, although it only makes up 4 percent of the population in the US. The daily average for the number of heat-related emergency room visits was actually 69 times higher this year from June 25th–30th compared to the same time period in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t7qUcg"&gt;The severity of the heat was found to be “&lt;a href="https://www.worldweatherattribution.org/western-north-american-extreme-heat-virtually-impossible-without-human-caused-climate-change/"&gt;virtually impossible&lt;/a&gt;” without climate change, a recent analysis found. The crisis shows how typically cool to tepid regions like the Pacific Northwest might struggle to adapt to extreme heat as climate change tests cities’ limits. Roadways &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22559961/heat-roads-washington-oregon-climate-infrastructure"&gt;buckled&lt;/a&gt; and power cables &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/dangerous-heat-wave-is-literally-melting-critical-infra-1847186624"&gt;melted&lt;/a&gt; because infrastructure wasn’t built to withstand the heat. Just a third of homes in the Seattle area have air conditioning, a &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/data/seattle-is-least-air-conditioned-metro-area-in-the-u-s-census-data-show-so-how-do-locals-keep-cool/"&gt;2018 study&lt;/a&gt; found. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpJf8J"&gt;“You get acclimated to warm in the summer, but that’s only if you’re used to experiencing those conditions. This could be very unlike any other heatwave they’ve experienced,” National Weather Service forecaster David Roth &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547454/2021-heat-wave-temperature-high-heat-dome"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last month&lt;/a&gt;. “So yeah, you would worry more about heat exhaustion, heat stroke, that sort of thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N6SBRL"&gt;The new CDC data doesn’t even fully show the toll that extreme heat has had on the Northwest recently. Since its data was limited to emergency departments, it didn’t document people who might have sought help elsewhere — meaning its figures probably underestimate how widespread heat-related illness really was. The searing heatwave was also linked to hundreds of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/08/pacific-northwest-heatwave-deaths"&gt;deaths&lt;/a&gt; across the Northwestern US and British Columbia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OdG3Zq"&gt;Another heatwave is &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2021/07/14/western-heat-wave-rockies/"&gt;forecast&lt;/a&gt; to hit the Western US and Canada this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iLUz2a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPwQI8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5I2RUr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580120/emergency-department-visits-spiked-june-heat-wave-us-northwest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580120/emergency-department-visits-spiked-june-heat-wave-us-northwest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
