<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-01T11:38:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:38:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:38:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>General Motors announces it will build a new cathode plant in North America </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Biden Visits General Motors’ Factory Zero Electric Vehicle Factory" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zHX-FwaeOomro4dr_EX80GCEynU=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215016/1236631423.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eWzdSt"&gt;General Motors announced that it will construct a new cathode factory in North America for its electric vehicle batteries. The factory, which will be built under a joint venture with South Korea’s Posco Chemical, will process cathode active material (CAM), which represents about 40 percent of the cost of an EV battery cell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1CBNii"&gt;Much like the rest of the auto industry, GM is racing to boost its EV offerings, vowing to spend $27 billion on the development and production of 30 new electric vehicles by 2025. To accomplish this enormous feat, the company is trying to get a stronger grasp on its supply chain, which includes battery manufacturing. The company has said it will spend over $4 billion on the construction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313251/gm-ev-second-battery-factory-lg-chem-tennessee"&gt;two battery factories&lt;/a&gt; in North America in partnership with South Korea’s LG Chem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="L76B7n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Much like the rest of the auto industry, GM is racing to boost its EV offerings&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AKb1TD"&gt;The new cathode facility will supply battery materials to the two factories that are currently under construction: the Ultium Cells facilities in Lordstown, Ohio, and Spring Hill, Tennessee. GM is also planning to build two more cell facilities by mid-decade, the company has said. GM did not disclose the location of the new cathode facility but said it would be open by 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xE7P6r"&gt;The majority of EV battery cathodes are made with NCM — nickel, cobalt, and magnesium. The Ultium batteries will add aluminum — so NCMA — and reduce the cobalt content by 70 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KgbpcW"&gt;Cobalt is &lt;a href="http://batteryuniversity.com/learn/article/bu_310_cobalt"&gt;a key component of batteries&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s also the most expensive material in the battery and &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/business/batteries/congo-cobalt-mining-for-lithium-ion-battery/"&gt;mined under conditions that often violate human rights&lt;/a&gt;, leading it to be called the “blood diamond of batteries.” As a result, GM and other companies, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21451678/tesla-new-cathode-plant-north-america-battery-day"&gt;like Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, are rushing to create a cobalt-free battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j6jbsv"&gt;“We would like to get out of cobalt altogether and have a zero cobalt situation,” said Doug Parks, GM’s executive vice president focused on global product development, purchasing and supply chain. “We’re going to start with old Ultium NCMA chemistry, and then we will we will advance as we go forward as quickly as possible to improve either the performance or the cost of the battery cell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Pcjta"&gt;This is the latest announcement from GM regarding its efforts to boost its EV production through vertical integration. The company also recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559718/gm-lithium-ctr-ev-battery-investment-salton-sea"&gt;struck a deal to source lithium&lt;/a&gt;, a key ingredient in electric-car batteries, from geothermal deposits in the US. And it’s building a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709389/gm-wallace-battery-center-ev-ultium-research"&gt;new 300,000-square-foot battery research facility&lt;/a&gt; in Michigan to help it realize its mission of building electric vehicle batteries that are longer-lasting, quicker to charge, and more sustainable for the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811902/general-motors-cathode-factory-ev-battery-posco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811902/general-motors-cathode-factory-ev-battery-posco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:38:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:38:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Barnes &amp; Noble announces new Nook GlowLight 4, says it cares for real this time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HxyWTAGOKs4lK0uhXBA9TG-gHDQ=/166x0:1266x733/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70215009/nook.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MA5vv4"&gt;Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has once again remembered that it ostensibly wants to sell e-readers and has announced the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.barnesandnoble.com%2Fw%2Fnook-glowlight-4-barnes-noble%2F1140326110%3Fean%3D9780594149293&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811857%2Fbarnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nook GlowLight 4&lt;/a&gt;, a $149 e-reader that offers a refreshed design, more onboard storage, and USB-C charging to the company’s lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNEnTl"&gt;The last dedicated Nook e-reader, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/11/1/16591594/nook-glowlight-3-ereader-eink-barnes-and-noble"&gt;the GlowLight 3&lt;/a&gt;, was announced 49 months ago (to the day) on November 1st, 2017, although Barnes &amp;amp; Noble did give the Nook brand a shot in the arm earlier this year with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22340588/barnes-and-noble-new-nook-10-hd-tablet-lenovo-price-release-date-ebooks"&gt;new, Lenovo-made budget tablet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Uay09"&gt;The new GlowLight 4 doesn’t appear to move the needle much compared to the 2017 model, though. The display is an identical six-inch, 300ppi e-paper display with an integrated backlight and adjustable color temperature functionality, although the company has slimmed down the bezels and overall size of the new model. Battery life has been increased, with up to 50 days off a single charge (up from a month on the old model). And the onboard storage has been quadrupled from 8GB to 32GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QEtH4U"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The first new Nook e-reader in 49 months&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QUGAs4"&gt;Those new upgrades also come with an unfortunate $30 price increase, with the Nook GlowLight 4 costing $149, up from the already expensive $119 that the GlowLight 3 went for. Adding insult to injury is the fact that Barnes &amp;amp; Noble isn’t adding back more important features like waterproofing or more premium materials. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ulNr9kw-E73kv-wP_v-L40l7SbE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055570/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_11.14.25_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Images: Barnes &amp;amp; Noble&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nook GlowLight 3 (left) and the new GlowLight 4 (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HWRDBy"&gt;It’s something that’s especially puzzling given that Barnes &amp;amp; Noble was one of the first companies to add both of those features with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/21/9582252/barnes-and-noble-nook-glowlight-plus-waterproof-ereader"&gt;2015 GlowLight Plus&lt;/a&gt;, which offered a sleek aluminum design long before Amazon did with its Oasis. The Nook was also waterproof years before Amazon and Kobo would make that the standard across most of their product lineups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XVO0DR"&gt;And given the $149 price tag, the GlowLight 4 is a pretty hard sell. It’s pricier than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22745670/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2021-review-usb-c-signature-edition-display-e-reader-books"&gt;Amazon’s new Paperwhite model&lt;/a&gt;, which starts at $139 (when not on one of its frequent holiday sales) and has a bigger display, waterproofing, and a larger ebook storefront. And it matches up poorly against Kobo’s Libra line, too, which has a $159 starting price but adds a bigger and better display, waterproofing, and easier access to borrowed library books. The only real benefit that the GlowLight 4 offers is physical page turn buttons, making it the cheapest major e-reader to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2IxeAK"&gt;That said, it seems like the GlowLight 4 might just be the tip of the Nook iceberg. “Barnes &amp;amp; Noble is now investing significantly in our Nook line of products,” Barnes &amp;amp; Noble CEO James Daunt promised in an accompanying press release, noting plans to “reinvigorate Nook in the coming months and years.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUdETa"&gt;And while Barnes &amp;amp; Noble has a long way to go before it catches up to Kobo or Amazon, getting a third competitive player in the e-reader space would be a good thing — even if Barnes &amp;amp; Noble is only slightly less of a monolithic corporation than, say, Amazon or Rakuten (which owns Kobo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WV1sI0"&gt;The Nook GlowLight 4 is set to go on sale on Barnes &amp;amp; Noble’s website and in stores in one week on December 8th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811857/barnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811857/barnes-noble-nook-glowlight-4-e-reader-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:33:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:33:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hawkeye’s trick USB arrow is in desperate need of a dongle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U2x_zNEgCO6adRsPVaHeJThDEhQ=/714x0:3126x1608/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214997/CMB2460_103_comp_v091.1035.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5JdlCD"&gt;In the third episode of &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt;, Kate Bishop (Hailee Steinfeld) does something very unexpected: she requests a USB dongle in the midst of a battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGiCIL"&gt;The highlight of the episode is a scene where Kate and her reluctant mentor, Clint Barton (Jeremy Renner), are fighting their way through the Tracksuit Mafia amidst some hectic New York City traffic. While Clint drives, Kate goes through his collection of trick arrows. Most are the kind of comic book goofiness you’d expect: one arrow creates a bubbling purple foam; another becomes destructively huge. Later, though, Clint hands Kate something much less useful in a fight: an arrow with a USB-A port on the end. “God, I hope he’s got a dongle to make this useful,” Kate quips afterward. (It turns out to not be very useful.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2EWi16"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hawkeye starts out strong because it doesn’t take itself too seriously","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22796664/hawkeye-early-review-disney-plus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BY1rY0FAoZ0__32UL5Y2BZiaXsk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055481/FFh3uZGWYAIJZ8F.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_n2R97ByHi8jbSBOxl2-wFL3uE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055482/FFh3ucsWUAUGY6m.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PCKgCv"&gt;This isn’t the first time we’ve seen a trick arrow designed to interface with computers. In the original &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; movie, Hawkeye had an arrow that could hack a very specific and proprietary port on a flying Helicarrier. But the new episode of the show makes it clear that there are much more mundane arrows as well. Unfortunately, given the surprising amount of characters who use a USB C-equipped Pixel phone in &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye,&lt;/em&gt; the superhero is going to have to update his arsenal soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811932/hawkeye-usb-arrow-dongle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811932/hawkeye-usb-arrow-dongle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:19:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:19:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>What’s the best student laptop? We asked students</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BVcaADlGztrbR5iNL_kFd3rebG0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67232292/akrales_200421_3975_0080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 is one of the best laptops for high school and college students.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tsQK0e"&gt;Shopping for a laptop can be stressful — doubly stressful if you or your children will be learning online for the first time. Kids of different ages have a range of different laptop use cases and different needs. And as the choices for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; evolve, so do students’ needs. So I spoke to some experts on the subject: students themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9ZW8b"&gt;My recommendations here are meant to accommodate a variety of preferences and price ranges. But they’re a jumping-off point rather than an exhaustive list: every student is different. Before making a decision, you’ll want to make sure you read reviews and try out devices yourself if you can. I’ll do my best to keep this article up to date with items that are in stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lxqTuB"&gt;Best laptop for students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside id="7m4BUq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best laptop you can buy ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"},{"title":"The best Chromebooks to buy in 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4lsvuf2NE7Upsw5uiVfjINO_Jhk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19315989/vpavic_191023_3755_0159.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s Pixelbook Go has solid battery life and a rippled base that’s easy to grip, making it a good choice for kids.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uaaUWw"&gt;Best laptop for elementary school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wdF0Hl"&gt;For younger students, a touchscreen device is easier to use than a keyboard and touchpad, says Michelle Glogovac. Glogovac’s five-year-old son uses an iPad for Webex meetings with his kindergarten class. He’s gotten the hang of it; Glogovac says he’s already learned how to mute and unmute himself, “a skill that many adults aren’t familiar with.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qEF087"&gt;That said, it may be worth investing in a keyboard case if you go the tablet route. Glogovac has to type her son’s meeting codes and passwords for him, which can be cumbersome on the iPad’s flat screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wxdcbE"&gt;As kids get older, their best laptop choice will vary depending on their needs. As a parent, it’s important that you and your child are in sync about how they intend to use it and the size of the programs they want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8sTP9p"&gt;Kristin Wallace purchased a budget HP laptop for her daughter, Bella, but didn’t realize how quickly the nine-year-old would fill up 32GB of storage. “It is really slow and has no space for games. I need a computer with more storage space,” said Bella, who uses the laptop to Zoom with friends and take virtual guitar lessons and math enrichment classes. Wallace plans to buy Bella a better device in the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rwTXVL"&gt;Audio quality is an important consideration for kids’ laptops. Lisa Mitchell, an elementary library media specialist, says her students use their devices to watch YouTube videos in addition to their online classes. Battery life is also a plus, even for distance learners who may not be far from a wall outlet. Bella likes to use her laptop all around the house and doesn’t want to bring the cord with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FaeV8B"&gt;Durability is also worth paying for, according to Mitchell. If you’re using a tablet, get a protective case. “If a reasonably-priced insurance or replacement policy is available, it’s usually worth the extra expense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlnxQa"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mWvFvV"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08F62DV1Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Fire HD 10 Kids Editio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-New-Fire-HD-8-Kids-Edition-Tablet/dp/B07WDDT3G5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;n&lt;/a&gt; ($199): a colorful, fast tablet with kid-friendly content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nE2JTN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lenovo.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Flaptops%2Flenovo%2Fstudent-chromebooks%2FLenovo-CT-X636%2Fp%2FZZICZCTCT1X&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21369381%2Fbest-student-laptops-school-high-college" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt; ($229): a tiny 10-inch Chromebook with a detachable keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yxGd1j"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1068592/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-10-2" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple 10.2-inch iPad&lt;/a&gt; ($329): a great budget tablet that supports the Apple Pencil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ATavfg"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Go-2%2F8PT3S2VJMDR6%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfbt-p1c%26selectedColor%3D%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Surface Go 2&lt;/a&gt; ($299): a solid Windows tablet with a built-in kickstand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GB06L3"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1741208806862135658" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google Pixelbook Go&lt;/a&gt; ($599): a sturdy touchscreen Chromebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Lenovo Chromebook Duet" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M79QGj6leDzJdmoI3tnqqQRv7Cc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19978535/mchin_200512_4018_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lenovo’s Chromebook Duet is just $289, but it can run plenty of tabs and apps with no problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dE2ANJ"&gt;Best laptop for middle school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="r5kOKS"&gt;The middle school students I spoke to don’t use their laptops for much more than web-based schoolwork and browsing. Don’t be too concerned about power — prioritize a machine that’s comfortable and easy for your child to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9OvOd"&gt;“We just got the most basic Chromebook and it is totally perfect,” says Gabrielle Hartley, an &lt;a href="http://gabriellehartley.com/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;attorney&lt;/a&gt; and mother of three children. “The most basic Chromebook serves all the needs of the basic middle schooler.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A user types on the Acer Chromebook Spin 713." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0hMEh9WTjBjXAQF5Bh8xq8l2ng0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21698818/mchin_181029_4126_0017.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chromebooks, like this one from Acer, are a good choice for students who use Google Classroom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fP2U74"&gt;Hartley’s son Max, who is in eighth grade, agrees. “I would really like a gaming PC or gaming laptop that can plug into a monitor and run video games with 120fps, but I really don’t need that,” Max says. “Most eighth graders aren’t going to be running any video games on their laptops or any software that requires a lot of power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WpOfaD"&gt;Max mostly uses his laptop for Google Classroom applications, including Gmail, Slides, Google Docs, and Google Sheets. They’re very easy to use on his device, which he describes as “a run-of-the-mill Samsung Chromebook.” That said, if your child is starting middle school this year, it could be worth checking with their teachers to see what operating system is most compatible with their workflow. Caspian Fischer Odén, a ninth grader from Sweden, told me he has trouble with his Chromebook because his school has blocked downloading apps from the Google Play Store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9eUtDq"&gt;Even kids with more demanding hobbies think a budget device can get the job done. Sam Hickman, an eighth grader from the UK who uses his laptop for photo and video editing, says, “For most middle schoolers, any processor developed within the last two years will be able to handle any tasks they can throw at it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4fFLe"&gt;So, what &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;worth paying for? A comfortable keyboard, several students told me. Many middle school kids aren’t used to typing for long periods of time. You should also look for a device that’s compact and easy for them to carry around, particularly if they’re preparing for in-person school. Shoot for an 11- to 13-inch model — certainly nothing larger than 15 inches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RnWLQu"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="y39J7M"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-chromebook-x360-14a-ca0000-%25282v972av%2529" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Chromebook x360&lt;/a&gt; ($259): an affordable Chromebook with great battery life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fJzJXL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hxVB3yKL" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo Flex 3 Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; ($329): a small but sturdy laptop made for students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JfExfj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lenovo-Flagship-Education-Touchscreen-Quad-Core/dp/B07Q478DHY/ref=sr_1_3?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Lenovo+300e+Chromebook&amp;amp;qid=1597705015&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo 300e&lt;/a&gt; ($349): a durable 2-in-1 with a stylus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QAiiVc"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2F1TS-000X-01365%3FDescription%3Dacer%2520aspire%25205%26cm_re%3Dacer_aspire%25205-_-1TS-000X-01365-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Aspire 5&lt;/a&gt; ($459): a portable option for kids who need a 15-inch screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T0amM0"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-Go%2F94FC0BDGQ7WV%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfbt-h1c%26selectedColor%3D86888a%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Surface Laptop Go&lt;/a&gt; ($499): an attractive, light Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Surface Laptop 4 15-inch seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JJpWTgsxAQaEUzKsbaT80APyQdE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22456007/mchin_20190710_4532_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Laptop 4 is a capable, no-nonsense laptop — just what many high schoolers want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SKuVFA"&gt;Best laptop for high school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OHE9ce"&gt;High schoolers’ laptop needs can vary based on their interests, but most don’t need powerful machines with lots of bells and whistles — especially if they come with glitches or serious downsides that could interfere with schoolwork. Miles Riehle, a student at Laguna Beach High School, has a high-end Surface Pro 7 but finds it overwhelming. “There is so much other stuff that I don’t use very often,” he said. “Something simpler might be a little more straightforward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="toVK5y"&gt;The best operating system may depend on what your child is used to. Aryan Nambiar, a student at Barrington High School in Illinois, has an iMac at home and enjoys using an iPad for his schoolwork. Riehle says he would prefer a Chromebook because he has an Android phone and often uses Google services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taD6O0"&gt;But almost every student I spoke to agreed that the most important feature of a high school laptop is portability. Kids attending in-person classes may be carrying their device around for much of the day with a stack of other books. Look for a 13- or 14-inch screen, or a lighter 15- to 17-inch model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9koeX"&gt;Students also recommend something sturdy. “Most high schoolers I’ve seen will throw their laptop in their bag without too much care,” says Moses Buckwalter, a student at Penn Manor High School. Backpacks can be jostled in the hallway as well. Kids can also run into trouble at home. “Anything can happen,” says Aadit Agrawal, a high school student from India. “My own brother scratched my laptop with his nails.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wo7j0d"&gt;Battery life is another key feature. “It can be a real struggle to find a place to charge while in class,” says Cas Heemskerk, a sophomore from the Netherlands. Unlike college students, many high schoolers don’t have frequent breaks to juice up their devices, so try to find something that can last a full day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SMbdD6"&gt;Many students recommend a touchscreen with stylus support. Nambiar uses the feature for his biology class, where he does a lot of visual modeling. “The touchscreen is always a bonus for drawing diagrams, whereas if you’re using a laptop it’d be a whole process to submit a diagram you drew,” Nambiar says. Riehle uses a Surface Pen to fill out school forms and annotate PDFs. Agrawal finds it useful to take notes on the same screen as his online lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z7t3Wu"&gt;Depending on the broadband situation in your area, you may also want a laptop with multiple connectivity options. Agrawal’s online classes are sometimes interrupted by powercuts, so he recommends an LTE model. Matej Plavevski, a junior at Yahya Kemal College in North Macedonia, recommends looking for an Ethernet port in case slower connections disrupt meetings. That’s hard to find on smaller laptops, but there’s a slew of affordable dongles and docks to consider. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hUtx7H"&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XJHuOW"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?sharedid=verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FAcer-Spin-513-Qualcomm-4GB-64GB-Chromebook-13-3-Full-HD-IPS-Multi-Touch-Corning-Gorilla-Glass-Display-Qualcomm-Snapdragon-7c-Compute-Platform-4GB-LPD%2F973209903%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_QMfy1TTJJxyLWB-wUx0Mo36KUkB28lyFUWu0zo0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_64065%26clickid%3DQMfy1TTJJxyLWB-wUx0Mo36KUkB28lyFUWu0zo0%26sharedid%3Ds1621611404093icm1a52402%26affiliates_ad_id%3D568844%26campaign_id%3D9383" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 513&lt;/a&gt; ($349): a convertible Chromebook with all-day battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dQPInK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1068592/7613?subId1=VergeBestStudentLaptops052121&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-air" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple iPad Air&lt;/a&gt; ($599): a powerful tablet with a great screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ohIlqp"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hqZQdAk1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt; ($699): a fantastic Chromebook that’s not too pricey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7PDjaF"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-12839518?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fxps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; ($1,219): a solid clamshell Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ezk6BY"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-4%2F946627FB12T1%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfrequentlyboughttogetherlaptop4%26selectedColor%3D9A9CA3%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; ($699): an excellent, light laptop that’s comfortable to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: HP Envy x360 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-3n_PDQBp_EOIUDusfA7A_LYGZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20069599/mchin_200705_4086_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For college students seeking an affordable laptop, HP’s Envy x360 performs just as well as some expensive competitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QKVW4e"&gt;Best laptop for college &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sqoQtB"&gt;College kids are justified in spending a bit more money than other age groups. Some (especially in STEM courses) can expect to do some fairly demanding work. Assad Abid, an electrical engineering undergrad from Pakistan, needs to run simulation software for his assignments. Aakash Chandra, a student at New Horizon College of Engineering in India, does a lot of coding, in addition to creative work in Premiere Pro and Photoshop, and gaming. Students also noted that it’s worthwhile to pay for a laptop that will last for a few years after graduation. That means you won’t have to worry about finding and financing your next device until you’re (hopefully) settled into a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNtiDo"&gt;But among high-end, capable devices there’s still a wide range of options. Students stressed that a college laptop should be light. Expect to bring it between classes, meals, meetings, the library, and other locations on campus. “It’s a boon that I can carry my laptop as well as some notebooks without feeling like I’m carrying too much for six hours a day,” says Haseeb Waseem, a senior at Villanova University. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ntrjko32oDlmo53mASwptA-kbCI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19897864/mchin_200413_3971_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 has a variety of configurations. Students with light workloads may prefer the base model, while gamers and creatives can add a GPU.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gsQLLb"&gt;Another universally-lauded feature: battery life. Waseem, who uses an HP Spectre, says the all-day juice gives him “the flexibility to study in a bunch of different locations, and even outside.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PevA8"&gt;Speakers and webcams are often overlooked, even in top-end devices. But students say it’s worth looking for good ones if you’re starting college this year. Though many college students are now back to in-person classes, some will still be meeting with clubs and attending events online. Waseem isn’t satisfied with his laptop’s audio and picture quality, which he says has made it difficult to pay attention in class and to engage with other students.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MqglEH"&gt;Many students will need to invest more in areas tailored to their interests and schoolwork needs. Chandra’s dream laptop would include a stylus and touchscreen for his creative work as well as a high-end GPU. Waseem, who uses his laptop for a hodgepodge of activities, including streaming, coding, social media, video chatting, and Microsoft Office work, would prefer to prioritize a large screen to keep track of his multitasking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1fkTF"&gt;Check out: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VTZaIC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1617646-REG%2Facer_nx_a4kaa_003_swift_3_i7_1165g7_8gb.html%3F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21369381%2Fbest-student-laptops-school-high-college" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt; ($849): a super light laptop that performs well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pSvCeK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7hoyEJXSp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt; ($749): a fast and stylish 2-in-1 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eaAcQA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-12839518?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fxps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; ($1,219): a solid clamshell Windows laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NPYIS2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Laptop-4%2F946627FB12T1%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfrequentlyboughttogetherlaptop4%26selectedColor%3D9A9CA3%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; ($699): an excellent, light laptop that’s comfortable to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Bfwtvt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeBestLaptops080621&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-spectre-x360-laptop-14t-ea000-touch-1q881av-1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt; ($949): a premium convertible with standout battery life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jabra Elite 7 Pro review: something’s missing</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Jabra’s latest earbuds impress on voice quality but arrive without the company’s signature feature&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="UDC7Dj"&gt;Jabra has managed to carve out a strong reputation for its true wireless earbuds over the past several years, even as the competition from larger companies continues to get better. But the company recently decided to shake things up and overhauled its lineup by introducing three new models at once. The $199.99 Elite 7 Pro are the company’s new premium buds, with the $179.99 Elite 7 Active offering the same core features and sound with tweaks that make them a better fit for workouts. At the entry level, you’ve got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22676362/jabra-elite-3-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;the Elite 3&lt;/a&gt; that I reviewed in September, a no-frills set of earbuds that nail the basics for $80. The higher-end Elite 7s have better sound, active noise cancellation, wireless charging, and more extensive water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uamjMp"&gt;But at least initially, they’ve also sacrificed something that’s always been a standout feature of Jabra earbuds: multipoint Bluetooth support. It’s still somewhat rare to find buds that can connect to two devices at once, which allows you to seamlessly take phone calls while listening to music or watching a video on your laptop, for example. Jabra has consistently offered multipoint with its previous Elite 65t, 75t, and 85t earbuds. However, the Elite 7 Pro and Elite 7 Active are both launching without this important functionality; Jabra’s website says multipoint will be added via firmware update sometime in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLjmuR"&gt;With that selling point still MIA, the Elite 7 Pros lack any big draw that might lure people away from the competition. They’ve got a nicer design than previous Jabra buds and excellent voice call quality, but those are things available in buds from Apple and Samsung and don’t really separate the Jabras from the pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0K0wc6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10896381"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="piSnKF"&gt;The Elite 7 Pros have a more stylish, refined design compared to all past Jabra buds. The in-your-face microphone holes are gone, and the clicky button with the Jabra logo is now teardrop-shaped and takes up the entire outer surface, so you’ll have no trouble finding it with your finger. The curves of this matured design also make the earbuds easier to grab out of the charging case and less prone to accidental drops when you’re handling them. The case has a USB-C port on the front, which is unusual, but not a downside in practice. It also supports Qi wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VG4LirOhxJQxDDtarPlLPKWwyIk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055360/IMG_0119_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The charging case’s USB-C port is on the front.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w5FweD"&gt;Unfortunately, the Elite 7 Pros and their ear tips aren’t as good of a match for my ears as the older 75t and 65t buds were. Something about the fit just isn’t doing it for me. When the earbuds are fully inserted into my ears, the sound can be thin and passive noise isolation suffers, so the ambient noise in my local coffee shop can get distracting. I get the best bass response and audio quality with these earbuds by stopping short of putting them all the way in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tiEfihfVd_manPnKxiTZhPV71TY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055330/IMG_0114_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Jabra Elite 7 Pros are rated IP57 against dust and water.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="091Hu9"&gt;In that sweet spot, the Elite 7 Pros have rich audio with ample bass — though I still think the older 75t buds hit harder in this regard. But the mix here is a lot cleaner. Listening through Taylor Swift’s remake of &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;, the earbuds were detailed and had nice warmth to them on acoustic tracks. I wasn’t blown away by their soundstage, but the overall balance makes up for that some. The vocals on Amanda Shires’ “Home To Me” were crisp and stood out beautifully from the rest of the mix. But the new Nathaniel Rateliff &amp;amp; The Night Sweats album &lt;em&gt;The Future&lt;/em&gt; didn’t sound as rockingly big and powerful as on the 75t buds, which feel like they still carry more weight and oomph in their sound signature at the cost of accuracy. Unsurprisingly, Jabra is also outdone by the upper echelon of earbuds like the Sony 1000XM4s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="If2qYp"&gt;Jabra still has room for improvement when it comes to active noise cancellation, however. At their price point, the 7 Pros disappoint in this category and don’t get rid of as much background noise as I expected. The company says its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Elite 85t earbuds&lt;/a&gt; continue to offer the best ANC performance of the whole lineup. But the HearThrough transparency mode also trails the AirPods Pro and Bose with a less natural sound&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RwqFnBFT1IIOOsoaSXK_f9k4dDw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055332/IMG_0117_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds have round ear tips instead of the oval-shaped tips from the Elite 85t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VcEn4sG65yezWwXSHZf6f7sNK3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055334/IMG_0118_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The button on each earbud is easy to find and click with your finger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WMOslU"&gt;Ears are all different, so I can’t ding Jabra too badly for these not being perfect for me. An XL set of ear tips would’ve helped, though. If you’ve got smaller ears and found the company’s older buds uncomfortable or bulky, these might be an improvement and not the regression they’ve been in my case. Jabra says it used data from 62,000 ear scans to design the earbuds’ shape and gel tips, but even after all that, the fit is just off for me. Maybe aftermarket tips can help. Either way, I’m glad Jabra has gone back to round ear tips instead of the oval-shaped tips from the Elite 85t buds that don’t always stay in my ears well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="0zinMQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10896386"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q9uPIf"&gt;It’s always worth highlighting how many features Jabra crams into the earbuds’ companion smartphone app on Android and iOS. You get extensive EQ customization, settings, remappable controls, an audio test to tailor the sound profile to your hearing, and extras like soundscapes (white noise, thunderstorm, etc.) meant to help you relax. You can also set up different moments for the various points of your day with personalized levels of noise cancellation and transparency for each environment. It’s about as full-featured as earbud apps get. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rUWd0u"&gt;One nice advancement with Jabra’s latest Elite buds is that you can now use either one independently; it used to be that only the right earbud could be used by itself, but now you’re free to use the left one independently, too. Battery life is rated at up to eight hours of straight music playback and 30 including case recharges. Those are both only slight improvements from the 7.5 hours and 28 hours that Jabra said the Elite 75t earbuds could achieve. The dust and water resistance rating has also gone up from IP55 to IP57.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ofsVp87xLNgf2FCslThwICPktLw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055354/IMG_0116_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new earbuds have a sleeker design than Jabra’s past efforts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f7mRkg"&gt;From Jabra’s perspective, the standout feature of the Elite 7 Pros — and what separates them from the Active model — is voice call performance. The company has reworked its algorithms to do a better job at canceling wind and other disruptive sounds, and it also added bone conduction tech to the mix. This makes the voice pickup sensors automatically activate when they sense vibrations in your jawbone. These tweaks have resulted in excellent voice quality for both phone calls and Zoom or Microsoft Teams conferencing that ranks among the best next to Apple’s AirPods. It’s especially impressive outside, where wind is effectively hushed. If multipoint does actually come along in January, these might well become the best option for multitasking between work and your music playlists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GrEGVl"&gt;But in their current state, Jabra’s Elite 7 Pro earbuds aren’t an essential upgrade compared to the 75t, which have way more thump to their sound and can already handle multipoint Bluetooth connections. In my own case, the older buds also fit much better, but &lt;a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/headphone-reviews/jabra-elite-7-pro-review/"&gt;other reviews&lt;/a&gt; (including from early buyers) suggest that the 7 Pros are working just fine for many ears out there. Jabra has made legitimate improvements to voice calling, so if that’s an important factor for you, they’re worth a look. But in any case, I’d wait until January before buying to make sure Jabra comes through on its promise of adding multipoint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="K9aY9r"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22811826/jabra-elite-7-pro-earbuds-review-features-multipoint"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22811826/jabra-elite-7-pro-earbuds-review-features-multipoint</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:08:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:08:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>CVS Pharmacy’s Spoken Rx prescription labels are now available at all locations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Prescription medication frames the CVS Corp. logo in this photo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ekOW8edNw6Lv2txZYZjJTgTmkas=/0x57:3333x2279/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214893/94603799.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;All CVS Pharmacy locations in the US now offer Spoken Rx prescription labels for blind and vision-impaired patients.  | Photo by Victoria Arocho/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Up45ew"&gt;CVS Pharmacy is expanding its Spoken Rx audio prescription labels to be available in all its pharmacies, after a trial run last year. The feature, developed as part of a collaboration with the American Council of the Blind, is part of the CVS Pharmacy mobile app and can read prescription information — like dosage and directions — aloud in English or Spanish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4xNpa"&gt;To use the spoken labels, CVS Pharmacy patients register for a CVS account, download the smartphone app, and enroll in Spoken Rx. The patient’s future prescription labels will then be tagged with an RFID label. The enrollment process can be done over the phone or in person at a CVS pharmacy. When the patient holds the prescription bottle four inches from their smartphone, the app scans the prescription bottle’s RFID label and reads out the information. CVS also has options for Braille and large-print labels on prescription bottles available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1f4P8t9KLeVqwVInUgoeS0JYTIY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055428/spoken_rx_cvs.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CVS&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The CVS Pharmacy app includes Spoken Rx, which lets users hear their prescription labels read aloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tJuogY"&gt;Matt Blanchette, manager of retail communications for CVS Pharmacy said for those who don’t have a smartphone, CVS can provide a separate, standalone speaker device on request, at no cost to the patient. The Spoken Rx app only reads prescription labels from CVS Pharmacy, and Blanchette said there are no plans to expand the feature to include labels from other pharmacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sQ6619"&gt;Eric Bridges, executive director of the American Council of the Blind, called the feature a positive step. “Spoken Rx allows for a greater level of privacy, safety and independence for blind and visually impaired customers,” Bridges said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncNtOS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809859/cvs-pharmacy-spoken-rx-prescription-labels-blind-vision-impaired-accessibility"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809859/cvs-pharmacy-spoken-rx-prescription-labels-blind-vision-impaired-accessibility</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit is adding new real-time features, including a live upvote count</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6CdqdUqnnAkKEYafS_Sk3N6A8WE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214806/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Wsgsdk"&gt;Reddit is introducing some big changes on Wednesday by adding new real-time features. Perhaps the biggest update is that the number of upvotes, downvotes, and comments will go up or down as they happen. That could give you a more accurate idea of the popularity of a post as you’re reading it, but I could also see people hitting an upvote or downvote in response to seeing others do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zt9G1r"&gt;Another change is that Reddit will show the number of people reading a post when there are five or more people looking at it. Reddit won’t just show who’s reading, though; it’s also introducing a typing indicator that will pop up when two or more users are typing a comment. And when new top-level comments come in, Reddit will show a new pill-shaped notification. When you tap that notification, the comments on a post will be sorted by new so you can view what’s been added most recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDoLIO"&gt;You can get an idea of how the new features work in this GIF:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oq5hW7l85SwXFoxetlBvorLMvNY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053930/ezgif_6_f30ba41cd9a7.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U0tcRt"&gt;The new features are rolling out globally across desktop and mobile starting Wednesday, but they’ll only be available on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/2/17190244/reddit-redesign-begins-rolling-out"&gt;newer Reddit design&lt;/a&gt;. If you use old Reddit, you won’t have access to them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810850/reddit-real-time-live-upvote-reading-typing-indicator-comment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810850/reddit-real-time-live-upvote-reading-typing-indicator-comment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Teams Essentials is a new standalone version for small businesses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qcquKedxBh5iHw4lPeR93odYWQc=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214812/Create_group_from_templates__2_.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bH1YzQ"&gt;Microsoft is creating its first standalone version of Microsoft Teams for small businesses. Microsoft Teams Essentials will be priced at $4 per user per month and provide access to the core meeting features of Teams without the typical Office app bundling that requires a more expensive Microsoft 365 plan. This standalone version makes Teams even more of a Zoom competitor, as Microsoft is dropping its Slack-like channels functionality in favor of a more simplified chat interface and a focus on meetings and video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pXj353"&gt;“It’s the first standalone offering of Microsoft Teams designed specifically with small businesses in mind,” explains Jared Spataro, head of Microsoft 365. “It brings together features small businesses need to serve customers, including unlimited group video calls for up to 30 hours, group chat, file sharing and calendaring.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6dz3Q"&gt;Microsoft Teams Essentials fills the gap for smaller businesses that has existed since Teams launched nearly five years ago. Until now, small businesses have had to choose the Microsoft 365 Business Basic plan — priced at $5 per user per month and increasing to $6 in March — or rivals like Zoom, Slack, Google Workspace, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aScVauq6HfLtRHuAS-ytQU0oY_8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055107/Create_group_from_templates__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams Essentials has all the regular Teams calling features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uYueGK"&gt;The differences between Microsoft Teams Essentials and Microsoft 365 Business Basic plans are primarily around Teams functionality and cloud storage. Essentials only offers 10GB of OneDrive storage, compared to the 1TB available on Business Basic. Essentials also lacks meeting recording and transcripts functionality, real-time translation, breakout rooms, and whiteboard integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UlnZcB"&gt;Microsoft Teams Essentials also drops the teams and channels functionality of Teams, so it’s more targeted at businesses that rely on apps like Teams or Zoom for video calling and meetings. Private and group chat will still work in Microsoft Teams Essentials, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="riPdVT"&gt;Microsoft is targeting smaller businesses that have relied on Zoom throughout the pandemic here. Zoom is a competitor that the software maker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21186918/microsoft-teams-zoom-video-leaked-video-competition-sellers-partner-network"&gt;identified as an “emerging threat” last year&lt;/a&gt;, and offering a standalone version of Teams feels like a big step in competing with Zoom and even Google’s Workspace push.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jNW2rJ"&gt;“The pandemic and acceleration of using video calling and virtual tools changed overnight,” explains Nicole Herskowitz, general manager for Microsoft Teams, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’re seeing at this point in time a lot of small businesses saying ‘What’s my future model?’ They’re almost doing a broader rethink, and many of them kind of raced to pick up tools very quickly to just stay afloat, and now they’re looking at their long-term strategy to engaging better with customers, with employees.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qoMDkSi0UgqpdF_RJhDhQfEr38g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055108/Create_group_from_templates__4_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams Essentials will soon include Google Calendar integration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iTUVjF"&gt;Microsoft clearly sees an opportunity to pick up small businesses that are trying to balance a number of tools that don’t always work well together. If you’re part of a small business right now, you might use Zoom for video calls, Slack for group chat, and then Google Workspace for email and calendar. Google has been centralizing its chat and communications apps into Gmail throughout the pandemic and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532559/google-workspace-chat-officially-available-consumer-gmail-spaces"&gt;opening Google Workspace up for everyone to use&lt;/a&gt;. Slack has app integrations that try to make these separate apps more seamless to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mRCHB2"&gt;Nobody has the perfect solution, and Microsoft Teams Essentials lacks the app extensibility to really bring all these separate small business solutions together. Microsoft is including Google Calendar integration into Teams Essentials soon, though, which is an important step in making Teams truly standalone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VFWtVc"&gt;If you’re a small business weighing the cost of Zoom, Google Workspace, Slack, and other tools, Microsoft Teams Essentials could look appealing at just $4 per user per month, especially when a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fpricing&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811605%2Fmicrosoft-teams-essentials-price-features-availability" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zoom Pro license&lt;/a&gt; is $14.99 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L29V6Q"&gt;Microsoft Teams Essentials is &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fmicrosoft-teams%2Fcompare-microsoft-teams-options" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available today direct from Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; or through its regular partners and resellers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811605/microsoft-teams-essentials-price-features-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811605/microsoft-teams-essentials-price-features-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Biden administration issues new framework for space policy, with a focus on climate change</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Af8IFEwCuCkJxz7GFdvKLb5R7TQ=/0x0:5942x3961/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214829/51665396090_7572c74948_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice President Kamala Harris speaking at an event at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center on November 5th, 2021&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA/Taylor Mickal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nASDCZ"&gt;Today, Vice President Kamala Harris’ office released a new framework for US space policy, detailing how the Biden administration plans to approach commercial, civil, and military space activity moving forward. &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/United-States-Space-Priorities-Framework-_-December-1-2021.pdf"&gt;Called the United States Space Priorities Framework&lt;/a&gt;, the document keeps many of the same space priorities from the previous administration but adds a new emphasis on using space to help combat climate change and investing in STEM education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sEXw4D"&gt;The new framework comes ahead of today’s National Space Council meeting, the first one to be held under the Biden administration. Harris, who chairs the National Space Council, will convene the policy advisory group at the United States Institute of Peace in Washington, DC, at 1:30PM ET today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BobH2t"&gt;The National Space Council is a relic of the George H. W. Bush administration, created by executive order in 1989 with the Vice President at the helm. Made up of executive cabinet members, the NASA administrator, and leaders in the space industry, the council’s goal is to advise on how to set the space agenda and come up with new solutions for addressing current space issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qegAFk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the Biden administration is carrying forward many of the priorities set by the Trump administration&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gssk1d"&gt;The original Space Council was dissolved in 1993, but it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/30/15903230/national-space-council-executive-order-mike-pence-nasa-policy"&gt;resurrected under the Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; and helmed by then-Vice President Mike Pence. During Trump’s presidency, the National Space Council met a total of eight times during live-streamed events in which members shared new concerns and problems that needed to be addressed regarding space. Topics of discussion included: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/23/17035436/national-space-council-regulatory-reform-industry-mike-pence"&gt;refining launch and licensing regulations&lt;/a&gt; for space companies launching rockets and satellites; ways to maintain US leadership and competitiveness in space; strengthening cybersecurity in space; and leveraging lunar resources. These often resulted in a number of Space Policy Directives that Trump would sign throughout his tenure. NASA’s former administrator, Jim Bridenstine, would also give updates on many of NASA’s biggest spaceflight missions, such as the space agency’s Artemis program — aimed at sending the first woman and first person of color to the surface of the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32ugrJ"&gt;When it comes to space, the Biden administration is carrying forward many of the priorities set by the Trump administration. Notably, NASA’s ambitious Artemis program, which was solidified under Trump, is still a major focus under Biden. And plenty of the topics discussed under Pence’s Space Council are included in the new framework released by Harris. A few of the key points include maintaining US leadership in space by sending humans back to the Moon and exploring the Solar System with robotic spacecraft, fostering a competitive, regulatory environment for space companies, and defending against security threats in space while strengthening our space assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="na2ZrV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;a renewed focus on using space in the fight against climate change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8eu4C"&gt;In the biggest break from the previous administration, there looks to be a renewed focus on using space in the fight against climate change. In the new framework, the administration pledges to invest in satellites that can observe Earth from space, helping scientists better understand our changing climate. “Open dissemination of Earth observation data will support both domestic and international efforts to address the climate crisis,” the document states. To further drive home this new emphasis on climate research from space, President Biden plans to sign a new Executive Order today that will add five new members to the National Space Council, including the Secretaries of Education, Labor, Agriculture, and the Interior, but also notably the National Climate Advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hIedG2"&gt;The Trump administration, famous for downplaying the urgency of climate change, wasn’t very interested in using space for climate science initiatives, and President Trump’s budget request &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/11/18259747/nasa-trump-budget-request-fy-2020-sls-block-1b-europa"&gt;often tried to cancel various Earth science missions at NASA&lt;/a&gt;. Those efforts were mostly unsuccessful, though. Considering that the Biden administration has made tackling climate change one of its top priorities, it’s not surprising that a focus on climate research has been added to the space agenda as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a6IjoG"&gt;Additionally, the Harris framework calls on investing in the next generation through various STEM initiatives. Trump’s budget requests also frequently —and unsuccessfully — tried to get rid of NASA’s Office of Stem Engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5fvQlB"&gt;The framework is light on details overall, but there are a few specific objectives. For one, it calls for the creation of an open data platform within a US civil agency for hosting space traffic management data to help better understand where satellites are in space. It’s an idea that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/19/17475940/trump-space-council-traffic-control-system-junk"&gt;space industry leaders have brought up before&lt;/a&gt;. The Biden administration is also pledging to increase US efforts to combat space debris, which poses a growing threat to satellites. Notably, this pledge comes just two weeks after Russia blew up one of its own satellites in orbit, creating at least 1,700 pieces of trackable debris that posed a threat to the International Space Station. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gGqejM"&gt;Otherwise, it’s not particularly clear how the Biden administration plans to achieve all of its goals. But it’s possible there will be more granular discussion during the meeting, which is set to last until 3PM ET. A couple previous Space Council meetings also had some notable theatrics. Pence made a big splash during the administration’s fifth meeting when he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282598/nasa-mike-pence-vice-president-space-policy-lunar-landings-2024-gateway-sls-orion"&gt;very publicly challenged NASA to land humans on the Moon as soon as 2024&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, President Trump made a surprise appearance at one meeting and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/18/17475466/trump-space-force-announcement-national-space-council"&gt;called on the Department of Defense to establish the Space Force&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll find out soon if anything of that nature is in store this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811737/national-space-council-kamala-harris-framework-priorities-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811737/national-space-council-kamala-harris-framework-priorities-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T10:55:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T10:55:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Match Group will pay Tinder’s co-founders $441 million over valuation lawsuit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bs94yVslZUB3p8K34Nwc36ly81s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214786/acastro_180822_1777_tinder_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cJCY9E"&gt;Match Group will pay Tinder’s co-founders and original team $441 million to &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0000891103/000089110321000093/mtch-20211201.htm"&gt;settle&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/22/17765684/tinder-match-group-lawsuit-sexual-harassment"&gt;years-long lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; over allegations that Match Group purposely undervalued the startup in an effort to avoid paying out billions of dollars in equity. The settlement comes a few weeks after the trial began in the New York Supreme Court, which has included testimony from the plaintiffs, including Tinder co-founder and former CEO Sean Rad, and the defense, including IAC chairman and founder Barry Diller. (IAC owned Match Group up until last year when it &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/iac-and-match-group-complete-full-separation-301086627.html"&gt;spun out&lt;/a&gt; into its company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2RTSRO"&gt;The plaintiffs were originally seeking a $2 billion payout. They first filed the lawsuit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17688706/tinder-match-group-law-suit-2-billion"&gt;in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, a year after Match Group merged Tinder into its dating app portfolio, resulting in the plaintiffs receiving Match stock instead of Tinder stock, which they had hoped and planned to receive. Both the plaintiffs’ legal team and Match Group had no further comment on the settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Km8lCW"&gt;The trial has been a messy one — four plaintiffs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/31/17805622/tinder-match-group-iac-lawsuit-plaintiffs-withdraw"&gt;dropped out&lt;/a&gt; after realizing they were under an arbitration agreement, and much of the case initially revolved around an allegation of sexual assault. Tinder’s former VP of marketing and communications, Rosette Pambakian, alleged former Tinder and Match Group CEO Greg Blatt sexually assaulted her at a company holiday party. Blatt has since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/3/20897193/tinder-lawsuit-greg-blatt-rosette-pambakian-sean-rad-match-group"&gt;sued her and Rad for defamation&lt;/a&gt;. That lawsuit is ongoing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D11Di4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811854/match-group-tinder-lawsuit-settlement-sean-rad-iac-valuation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811854/match-group-tinder-lawsuit-settlement-sean-rad-iac-valuation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
