<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-07T16:34:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T16:34:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T16:34:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch is having a partial outage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5GIdHu56GdzTV9SZHX6AEZBXZGE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634683/acastro_190812_1777_twitch_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="08btwY"&gt;Twitch is experiencing a partial outage as of Thursday afternoon. “We are investigating an issue causing various features on Twitch not to load,” the company said in a statement &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitchSupport/status/1347286791544565760"&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “Stay tuned!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TMSV00"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  We are investigating an issue causing various features on Twitch not to load. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;— Twitch Support (@TwitchSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitchSupport/status/1347286791544565760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MfqgsM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/twitch/"&gt;Downdetector shows&lt;/a&gt; that user reports began to rise at 3:35PM ET. I was able to navigate to the site’s homepage, but the carousel of featured streams didn’t load. In one instance, when I clicked into a stream, it briefly loaded before the site showed an error message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FRGBG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://status.twitch.tv/"&gt;Twitch status page&lt;/a&gt; says that the company has “identified an issue causing Twitch to fail to load in some cases.” While the status page only notes “degraded performance” for the web, I was also seeing errors while navigating the iOS app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vQqjkS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219381/twitch-down-outage-not-loading-issue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219381/twitch-down-outage-not-loading-issue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T16:29:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T16:29:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max to get Weathering with You, Promare, and the latest Studio Ghibli film</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UNhCSoahnJjrL1N_0V_FuyClVKo=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634651/Promare_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Studio Trigger&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MrJ3Vp"&gt;HBO Max is continuing its strong anime streak with the addition of four new films, two documentaries, and an upcoming Studio Ghibli movie this month, courtesy of distributor GKIDS Films, which is best known for running the international distribution of works from legendary director Hayao Miyazaki. Some of these can be seen on Netflix, but only outside the US due to licensing restrictions as HBO parent company WarnerMedia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20919325/studio-ghibli-stream-hbo-max-spirited-away-kikis-delivery-service-my-neighbor-totoro"&gt;secured the US rights to most (but not all) of Ghibli’s catalog&lt;/a&gt; and works closely with GKIDS for rights to non-Ghibli titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZxKA0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earwig and the Witch&lt;/em&gt;, the latest Ghibli movie and the third directorial work from Miyazaki’s son Gorō, will &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/studio-ghiblis-earwig-and-the-witch-gets-theatrical-hbo-max-release-dates"&gt;debut on HBO Max on February 5th&lt;/a&gt;, following a limited theatrical release two days prior. The film is based on the work of British fantasy novelist Diana Wynne Jones (who also penned the book which was then adapted into Ghibli’s &lt;em&gt;Howl’s Moving Castle&lt;/em&gt;), and it will be made available in both Japanese with subtitles and English dub. It marks Ghibli’s &lt;a href="https://gkids.com/films/earwig-and-the-witch/"&gt;first foray into computer-generated animation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YE9CwQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Kick off the new year with these beloved movies coming to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hbomax?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@HBOMax&lt;/a&gt; this month! &lt;a href="https://t.co/knKrhaf99J"&gt;pic.twitter.com/knKrhaf99J&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— GKIDS Films (@GKIDSfilms) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GKIDSfilms/status/1346199726341943297?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zE1rzI"&gt;As for the previously released films coming to HBO Max, they include some major names. The biggest of the bunch is Makoto Shinkai’s &lt;em&gt;Weathering with You&lt;/em&gt;, one of the most popular films ever released in Japan and the follow-up to Shinkai’s worldwide success with 2016’s &lt;em&gt;Your Name&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="weNZ9C"&gt;Also included is Studio Trigger’s &lt;em&gt;Promare&lt;/em&gt;, a visually astonishing action film from the animators now working on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21303233/cyberpunk-2077-anime-edgerunners-netflix-studio-trigger-2022-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;spinoff anime &lt;em&gt;Edgerunners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and best known for producing TV series &lt;em&gt;Kill la Kill &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Darling In the Franxx&lt;/em&gt;. HBO Max subscribers will also get access to romantic comedy &lt;em&gt;The Night is Short, Walk on Girl &lt;/em&gt;(from &lt;em&gt;Devilman Crybaby &lt;/em&gt;director Masaaki Yuasa) and the surfing-centric drama &lt;em&gt;Ride Your Wave&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T6El5T"&gt;Included in all of these new additions to HBO Max are two Miyazaki documentaries. The first is 2013’s &lt;em&gt;Never-Ending Man: Hayao Miyazaki&lt;/em&gt;, a Japanese television documentary directed by Kaku Arakawa that first aired after Miyazaki’s &lt;a href="https://www.nme.com/news/film/studio-ghibli-founder-hayao-miyazaki-confirms-no-longer-retired-1990162#:~:text=News%20Film%20News-,Studio%20Ghibli%20founder%20Hayao%20Miyazaki%20confirms%20he%20is%20no%20longer,making%20his%2012th%20feature%20film.&amp;amp;text=Studio%20Ghibli%20co%2Dfounder%20Hayao,officially%20come%20out%20of%20retirement."&gt;premature retirement announcement nearly a decade ago&lt;/a&gt;. The second is &lt;em&gt;The Kingdom of Dreams and Madness&lt;/em&gt;, another documentary released in 2013 that follows Miyazaki and other Ghibli co-founders as the studio produced &lt;em&gt;The Wind Rises&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Tale of the Princess Kaguya&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7b8Ptr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weathering with You &lt;/em&gt;is available now in English dub only, although GKIDS Films says it’s working to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GKIDSfilms/status/1346231639492407301"&gt;add the original Japanese language option to the stream&lt;/a&gt;. The other additions will be coming to HBO Max throughout the month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wh9ddo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219258/hbo-max-anime-weathering-with-you-studio-ghibli"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219258/hbo-max-anime-weathering-with-you-studio-ghibli</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T16:27:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T16:27:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boeing criminally charged for lying about 737 Max crashes, fined $2.5 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lf-rtfKoiB2aiLIvHO4wSNztRbc=/0x0:6240x4160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634639/1132062499.jpg.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Stephen Brashear/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KOXOJM"&gt;Boeing has been criminally charged with conspiracy to defraud the United States by the Department of Justice and will have to pay a $2.5 billion fine for lying to the Federal Aviation Administration before and after the fatal 737 Max crashes in 2018 and 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aygU1K"&gt;The Justice Department &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/boeing-charged-737-max-fraud-conspiracy-and-agrees-pay-over-25-billion"&gt;announced the charges and fine&lt;/a&gt;, which were part of a deferred prosecution agreement, on Thursday. The $2.5 billion fine includes a $243.6 million “criminal monetary penalty,” $1.77 billion that will be paid out to airlines that were customers of the plane, and $500 million that will go to a fund to help families and relatives of the people who died in the two crashes. Boeing &lt;a href="https://investors.boeing.com/investors/investor-news/press-release-details/2019/Boeing-Reports-Record-2018-Results-and-Provides-2019-Guidance/default.aspx"&gt;generated $100 million in revenue and $12 billion in profit&lt;/a&gt; in 2018. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwTY6l"&gt;“The misleading statements, half-truths, and omissions communicated by Boeing employees to the FAA impeded the government’s ability to ensure the safety of the flying public,” US Attorney Erin Nealy Cox said in a statement. “This case sends a clear message: The Department of Justice will hold manufacturers like Boeing accountable for defrauding regulators – especially in industries where the stakes are this high.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WiKJz2"&gt;Boeing’s 737 Max was supposed to be a plane that helped the company keep pace with a new, more fuel-efficient offering from rival Airbus. But the company rushed the design, and as a result, the plane was susceptible to dangerous stalls in certain takeoff situations. Boeing created a piece of software to counteract this design flaw by automatically pushing the plane’s nose down. But the company never told the FAA, airlines, or pilots about the software in order to save time and money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiUbQf"&gt;What’s worse, this software worked off of readings from a lone sensor on the plane’s exterior — meaning there was no way to know if it was acting with bad information if the sensor was damaged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AjquW"&gt;It was this series of design flaws and Boeing’s lack of candor that led to the two fatal 737 Max crashes, as was discovered in subsequent Congressional investigations and reporting. By not disclosing them to regulators or the airlines, Boeing left the pilots of Lion Air flight 610 and Ethiopian Airlines flight 302 fighting software they didn’t even know existed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YHdfgo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219370/boeing-737-max-fraud-conspiracy-criminal-charges-fine-crashes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219370/boeing-737-max-fraud-conspiracy-criminal-charges-fine-crashes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T16:12:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T16:12:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Duracell isn’t secretly paying Microsoft to put AA batteries in Xbox controllers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L83DM8B7rHNZFrX8WogmT-xSPTU=/9x0:2631x1748/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634562/twarren_xboxseriesxcontroller_VLS_3616_2_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Cu5LXi"&gt;“Xbox Controllers Still Use AA Batteries Due to ‘A Constant Agreement’ with Duracell,” &lt;em&gt;Stealth Optional&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;headline reads. The headline spotlights the &lt;a href="https://stealthoptional.com/feature/why-does-xbox-series-x-s-console-still-use-aa-batteries-duracell/"&gt;outlet’s recent interview&lt;/a&gt; with Duracell’s UK marketing manager, Luke Anderson, who told &lt;em&gt;Stealth Optional&lt;/em&gt; that there’s “always been this partnership with Duracell and Xbox... It’s a constant agreement that Duracell and Microsoft have in place.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8AgUj"&gt;After this interview was published, &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-controllers-apparently-still-use-aa-batteries-beca-1846007558"&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/xbox-controllers-are-still-using-aa-batteries-because-of-long-term-duracell-deal-spokesperson-claims/"&gt;outlets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/xbox-wireless-controllers-may-still-use-aa-batteries-because-partnership-duracell?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wmexperts+%28Windows+Central%29"&gt;cited&lt;/a&gt; the article, theorizing that this could be the reason why Microsoft still uses AA batteries to power some of its wireless gaming controllers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5Ydjj"&gt;This isn’t true. “We intentionally offer consumers choice in their battery solutions for our standard Xbox Wireless Controllers,” a Microsoft spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-01-07-no-microsoft-isnt-forced-to-use-batteries-in-xbox-controllers-because-of-a-deal-with-duracell"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;as a reason why its standard wireless Xbox controllers still use AA batteries instead of building a battery inside the controller. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bHHbDF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We intentionally offer consumers choice in their battery solutions for our standard Xbox Wireless Controllers.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CFJ1By"&gt;“This includes the use of AA batteries from any brand, the Xbox Rechargeable Battery, charging solutions from our partners, or a USB-C cable, which can power the controller when plugged in to the console or PC.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="amlwvI"&gt;Of course, this is not the first time Microsoft has mentioned its decision to stick with AA batteries for some of its wireless controllers. Speaking with &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2020-constructing-xbox-series-x-a-revolution-in-console-design"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt; in April&lt;/a&gt;, Xbox partner director of program management, Jason Ronald, explained that a “large chunk of Xbox owners” still preferred to use batteries. Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/16/17665126/my-xbox-one-controller-console-battery-free-reliance"&gt;even told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in 2018&lt;/a&gt; that the standard controllers' reliance on batteries is because the company likes to offer a choice to its player base.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GXWrzn"&gt;I don’t mind using AA batteries in these controllers; I can understand the confusion some could have on why Microsoft relies on batteries in its controllers when its competitors have turned to built-in batteries that charge using cables. It’s certainly not &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/4/20992240/e-waste-recycling-electronic-basel-convention-crime-total-reclaim-fraud"&gt;the most environmentally friendly option&lt;/a&gt;, yet it provides a happy medium for those who still prefer batteries while also having an option for those who prefer using a rechargeable battery pack instead. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219137/xbox-duracell-battery-partnership-rumor-debunked"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219137/xbox-duracell-battery-partnership-rumor-debunked</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:55:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:55:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s unlocked Pixel 4A 5G will soon be available in white</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lsm8XRv9v47E2sr0kORo1lLksKA=/0x3:1710x1143/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634458/Screen_Shot_2021_01_07_at_3.35.11_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lj5MDZ"&gt;Up until this point, Google’s unlocked &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514296/google-pixel-4a-5g-review-camera-speed-video"&gt;Pixel 4A 5G&lt;/a&gt; has only been available in black for those who want the unlocked phone. A white option was exclusive to Verizon’s more expensive version of the device — more expensive because it includes millimeter-wave 5G. But soon, Google will be releasing a white model of the standard $499 unlocked Pixel 4A 5G for people who don’t want to pay the mmWave tax. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C1OeAu"&gt;I was browsing B&amp;amp;H Photo earlier today when I noticed &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1595334-REG%2Fgoogle_ga02294_us_pixel_4a_128gb_5g.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F7%2F22219305%2Fgoogle-pixel-4a-5g-unlocked-white-price-specs-release-date#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a listing for it&lt;/a&gt;, clearly labeled as a “new release.” Since there are photos of the phone, this didn’t seem to be a mistake — and Google has since confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the unlocked white Pixel 4A 5G will begin shipping on January 28th. Aesthetically, it’s identical to the Verizon version with a mint green power button. But you’re still only getting sub-6 5G — no surprise considering it’s the regular price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fv4Fh4"&gt;There were some decent discounts and sales on the Pixel 4A 5G over the holidays, so some of you might be bummed about making a purchase before this one came around. But at least you saved some cash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3PgxTx"&gt;If you’re keeping score, with the release of this version, that means the 2020 Pixel lineup will now be available in these color choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3irrJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 5, $699&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Green&lt;br&gt;Black&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GdJZzR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 4A 5G UW, $599&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Black (with millimeter-wave 5G), &lt;em&gt;Verizon exclusive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;White (with millimeter-wave 5G), &lt;em&gt;Verizon exclusive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gV52W0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 4A 5G, $499&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Black (unlocked, sub-6 5G only)&lt;br&gt;White (unlocked, sub-6 5G only)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Aht4z"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 4A, $349&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Black&lt;br&gt;Blue, &lt;em&gt;Google Store exclusive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219305/google-pixel-4a-5g-unlocked-white-price-specs-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219305/google-pixel-4a-5g-unlocked-white-price-specs-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:51:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:51:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>A Trump tax means you’ll pay even more for Nvidia and AMD’s impossible-to-find graphics cards</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UAoYWPURNNZb0zh6IxkUxt6k3Kw=/13x0:2040x1351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634444/twarren_200909_4184_0008.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Le4UJL"&gt;“Don’t Build a High-End Gaming PC Right Now,” &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/dont-build-gaming-pc-now"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tom’s Hardware&lt;/em&gt; declared&lt;/a&gt; in November. “This Is a Bad Time to Build a High-End Gaming PC,” &lt;a href="https://www.extremetech.com/computing/318119-this-is-a-bad-time-to-build-a-high-end-gaming-pc"&gt;ExtremeTech echoed&lt;/a&gt; last month. But it’s looking like the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; time to build a new gaming rig is still to come. That’s because a perfect storm is pushing the price of components like must-have Nvidia or AMD graphics cards even further skyward — and because Donald Trump is now part of that storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9O3AeU"&gt;The Trump administration is now imposing a 25 percent tax on graphics cards imported from China, and at least one PC component manufacturer has announced it’ll pass along part of that cost to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZy4ja"&gt;We’ve known for two years that PC components were being swept up in Trump’s trade war on China. In 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.gamersnexus.net/industry/3368-manufacturers-on-tariff-impact-to-pc-prices"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GamersNexus,&lt;/em&gt; in particular, explained in depth&lt;/a&gt; how PC parts might see a price increase between 10 and 25 percent due to the categories the Trump administration tried to tax. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/20/20973991/trump-tim-cook-apple-friendship-tax-cuts-china-tariffs-manufacturing-jobs"&gt;Apple famously cozied up to Trump&lt;/a&gt; to avoid some (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/30/20892201/apple-25-percent-tax-five-imported-mac-pro-parts-trump-tariffs"&gt;but not all&lt;/a&gt;) of the import taxes on PC parts, allowing it to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/23/20880043/apple-mac-pro-us-manufacturing-austin-texas-trump-tariff"&gt;build its Mac Pro in the United States&lt;/a&gt; using parts imported from China. (Apple didn’t reply to a request for comment on the tariffs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tvx9yQ"&gt;But PC gamers and other graphics card buyers &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; managed to dodge the bullet of higher prices back in September 2019, when the Trump administration granted specific exemptions for “graphics processing modules” and “accelerator modules.” And as &lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/31/business/economy/china-tariffs-exclusions-expire.html"&gt;reported last week&lt;/a&gt;, the government extended many of its tariff exemptions until the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gAP2YSGKq2X6nGcvZKyNKADRxj8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220402/gpu_tariffs_excemptions.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="x34YRh"&gt;But December 31st, 2020, came and went with any additional extensions — and &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; can confirm the exemptions for graphics cards and motherboards (classified under reporting number 8473.30.1180) were among those that expired at the end of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a3VBPN"&gt;According to the US government’s Harmonized Tariff Schedule, &lt;a href="https://hts.usitc.gov/?query=84733011"&gt;those PC components &lt;/a&gt;would normally be free of import taxes. Now, &lt;a href="https://ustr.gov/issue-areas/enforcement/section-301-investigations/section-301-china/200-billion-trade-action"&gt;under the “list 3” tariffs&lt;/a&gt; that were designed to tax $200 billion worth of Chinese products, graphics card and motherboard vendors have to figure out where to find the additional 25 percent to pay for tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3jDrU"&gt;I’ve reached out to the major GPU and motherboard manufacturers, and they’ve all either declined to comment (Nvidia, Asus, MSI) or failed to respond to my emails (Gigabyte, EVGA, Zotac, XFX, PNY). It’s a little weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hngi2A"&gt;“MSI cannot respond to your questions at this time. Thank you for your interest and understanding,” an MSI rep told me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="00qhri"&gt;I’m still waiting for an answer from AMD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0C946W"&gt;Intel says the tariffs haven’t had an impact — yet. “With regard to the tariffs, so far, it is not significant and hasn’t impacted our prices,” a spokesperson tells me. But Intel doesn’t make a lot of motherboards or GPUs yet, and it’s not speaking for partners there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p7VmMh"&gt;But we don’t really need to speculate whether this might affect the price you pay because Asus, the largest motherboard manufacturer and a noted GPU supplier, has said it will &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has already increased some of its prices, &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/asus-officially-increases-graphics-cards-and-motherboards-pricing"&gt;as reported by &lt;em&gt;Videocardz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Here’s the statement the publication received: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="eY5CMr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update regarding MSRP pricing for ASUS components in 2021.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y1Vauu"&gt;This update applies to graphics cards and motherboards*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vbfFav"&gt;We have an announcement in regards to MSRP price changes that are effective in early 2021 for our award-winning series of graphic cards and motherboards. Our new MSRP reflects increases in cost for components. operating costs, and logistical activities plus a continuation of import tariffs. We worked closely with our supply and logistic partners to minimize price increases. ASUS greatly appreciates your continued business and support as we navigate through this time of unprecedented market change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMJZwg"&gt;*additional models may see an increase as we moved further into Q1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f8LMG6"&gt;— Juan Jose Guerrero III, ASUS’s Technical Product Marketing Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="AuFYMg"&gt;Now, the bigger question is whether price hikes might become permanent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WPSkeo"&gt;When we reviewed this year’s batch of next-gen PC graphics cards, we needed to give Nvidia and AMD the benefit of the doubt that you’d actually be able to buy them at their sticker price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYCU8H"&gt;That turned out to be an unsafe bet. While it’s clear from social media that &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; people have managed to buy them at retail, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;it’s also clear from eBay that the true price&lt;/a&gt; of an RTX 3090, 3080, 3070, 3060 Ti, RX 6800 XT, or RX 6800 is far over MSRP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="BKXvr4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The true price of a PlayStation 5","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"},{"title":"Nvidia GeForce RTX 3080 review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21435926/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3080-review"},{"title":"Nvidia GeForce RTX 3070 review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21534142/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3070-review"},{"title":"Nvidia GeForce RTX 3060 Ti review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21726429/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-ti-review"},{"title":"AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21571414/amd-radeon-rx-6800-xt-review"},{"title":"AMD Radeon RX 6800 review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7rZo35"&gt;AMD’s RX 6800 series cards, in particular, have never reappeared at retail for long enough to even make an impact. I’ve personally been waiting and watching to pounce on one ever &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"&gt;since my review&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ve never even seen an opportunity — unlike Nvidia’s cards where I’ve simply failed to beat the swarm of buyers to the digital checkout counter nearly every time I’ve tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UtkbDw"&gt;Trump’s tariffs aren’t the only thing that might make buying a GPU worse. Bitcoin prices are now at an all-time high, &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/bitcoin-tops-38k-for-first-time-a-day-after-racing-past-36k-37k"&gt;briefly crossing $40,000 for the first time ever&lt;/a&gt; earlier today. &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/price/ethereum"&gt;The price of Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; has doubled over the past month and is approaching its previous record, too. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T_2eqL-47Pju1HjN_7ZlaK0kwME=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220324/bitcoin_coindesk_1_7.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Spb2yE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/gpu-shortages-worsen-cryptocurrency-coin-miners-ethereum"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tom’s Hardware &lt;/em&gt;is pointing out&lt;/a&gt; that at any given graphic card’s MSRP, it could take significantly less than a year to make your GPU money back by mining. The last time bitcoin prices skyrocketed, it caused a huge GPU shortage that lasted for many months. It was news in May 2018 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NVIDIAGeForce/status/994200342735732737"&gt;when Nvidia tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that you could finally find a graphics card again at MSRP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ky7cqz"&gt;But this time, we’re already in a GPU shortage due to pandemic manufacturing shortages and pent-up demand for the performance that the new wave of graphics cards and next-gen consoles offer. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22215786/video-games-covid-19-animal-crossing-among-us"&gt;More than half of Americans have turned to video games during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, and graphically intensive games like &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; inspired people to build new PCs that only the newest GPUs could run well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwWkFh"&gt;Even if GPU manufacturers didn’t have a 25 percent tariff to deal with, the eBay prices make it clear they were already leaving money on the table. One way manufacturers can take advantage is to create pricier versions of the same exact graphics cards with fancier cooling systems and higher clocks, and many of the cards that gamers have actually been able to buy are that way. You can certainly pay $600 for a souped-up $400 RTX 3060 Ti if you can find that model at retail or $780 for a $500 RTX 3070. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eMQP8c"&gt;Now, though, I wonder if the base price of these cards is in jeopardy, too. In late November, &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/amd-expects-aibs-to-sell-radeon-rx-6800-series-at-msrp-in-4-to-8-weeks"&gt;AMD told &lt;em&gt;Hardware Unboxed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the AMD RX 6800 XT should be available from its partners at the original $649 MSRP within eight weeks. Nearly six weeks later, it doesn’t seem that likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PLLXEF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217206/nvidia-amd-gpu-trump-tax-china-tariff-exemption-expire"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217206/nvidia-amd-gpu-trump-tax-china-tariff-exemption-expire</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:07:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:07:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lenovo chases dream of making a PC Nintendo Switch with the LaVie Mini concept</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Mj39vDud-7qWPoUuhhWjH6dKLo=/0x219:7680x5339/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634218/LAVIE_MINI_Gaming_Controller_Crystal_White.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Lenovo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="btPTHK"&gt;Every year at CES, we see devices meant to bridge the worlds of handheld and PC gaming. This year, it’s Lenovo and NEC that are still chasing that dream with the LaVie Mini. The device is a concept laptop-portable gaming console hybrid, and it includes a touchscreen, controller, and dock accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jIWLBn"&gt;For those unfamiliar with the name, LaVie is a joint venture between Lenovo and NEC, and although most of its products don’t make it to the US, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/5/7490411/lenovo-lavie-z-notebook-announced-at-ces-2015"&gt;had some hits&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/6/6/3067500/nec-lavie-z-hands-on"&gt;CES in the past&lt;/a&gt; focused on ultra-light laptops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FXnWOD"&gt;By itself, the LaVie Mini seems to be a reasonably powerful and compact computer. The device, if it were real, would have an 8-inch touchscreen with a resolution of 1920 x 1200 and an 11th Gen Intel Processor with Xe graphics. Of course, there’s not really space for a trackpad, but the concept design does make room for an optical touch sensor a la Blackberry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tGi6NCJXXbq7ay5hfU1owK4K2I0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220212/LAVIE_MINI_Facing_Forward_Crystal_White.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lenovo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This just goes to show that gold can look good on a computer if you do it right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kvbfHA"&gt;But acting as a laptop is not really the reason this concept exists. It exists to chase the dream of having a handheld gaming computer, one more powerful than the devices Nintendo has been famous for making. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5TbBu"&gt;LaVie has also created a gaming controller accessory, which connects to the laptop after you fold the keyboard back. The controller has the same buttons and layout as the Xbox gamepad, so it’ll be familiar to many players, though the weight probably won’t be: the laptop weighs 1.28 pounds &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; the controller attached. For comparison, the Nintendo Switch is 0.88 pounds &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the Joy-Con attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JqrpI3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The LaVie Mini shows that the dream is still alive&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nkXFOG"&gt;Don’t start hitting the gym to beef up your forearms just yet, though. At the moment, there’s no announced price or release date for the Mini. We’ve seen many PC manufacturers come up with similar concepts and ideas for handheld gaming computers at CES. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CGhFdM"&gt;Most, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/1/6/21048262/alienware-concept-ufo-prototype-gaming-pc-nintendo-switch-ces-2020"&gt;like Alienware’s UFO concept from last year&lt;/a&gt;, don’t ever end up making it to market, as these prototypes are often less about making viable consumer products and more about experimenting with new ideas and form factors and getting the requisite press attention during CES. Some do go on sale but don't end up appealing to enough gamers to really make an impact, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/3/28/4155606/razer-edge-review"&gt;like Razer’s Edge&lt;/a&gt; or the initial &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/7/31/4573596/nvidia-shield-review"&gt;Nvidia Shield&lt;/a&gt; handheld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SB9R8v"&gt;Yet it’s easy to see why companies keep coming back to the idea of a computer that lets you play PC-quality games anywhere. The Nintendo Switch showed that, when done right, handheld gaming can offer a living room console-quality experience &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;people can’t get enough of&lt;/a&gt;. Who doesn’t want to be able to play a game while they’re out and about, then come home, put the same device into a dock connected to their TV, and pick back up right where they left off? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UU1T8y"&gt;That’s an experience, by the way, that the LaVie Mini would support with its optional dock accessory if it ever comes to market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yoq30pCtVJf9zkCdDAkQgO8_gmk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220205/LAVIE_MINI_TV_DOCK_HDMI.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lenovo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Docked, the computer could output 4K 60Hz to a TV, though it likely wouldn’t have the power to run games at that resolution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ze2TQt"&gt;For now, that experience (at least for people who want that device to be a PC) will probably remain outside the realm of products they can actually buy. But the LaVie Mini shows that the dream is still alive and may actually come true sooner or later. For now, we’ll have to wait until next week’s CES to see if LaVie releases any more details about the Mini. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/7/22218956/lenovo-nec-switch-pc-lavie-mini-ces-concept"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/7/22218956/lenovo-nec-switch-pc-lavie-mini-ces-concept</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:06:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:06:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Online shopping has shifted recycling responsibilities to consumers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Struggle To Keep Up With Online Shopping’s Cardboard Excess" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nzEgR5YKV_-ZKtzrvgeXpdfXnek=/28x0:4996x3312/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68634215/925910210.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boxes line the sidewalk on Green Street in the Charlestown neighborhood of Boston on February 28th, 2018. &lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Craig F. Walker / The Boston Globe via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Ibf0F"&gt;The fate of cardboard boxes in the US rests in the hands of consumers more than it ever has been before. In the past, brick-and-mortar retailers handled much of the leftover packaging from shipments. Malls and grocery stores usually send big bales of used but relatively clean cardboard to recycling programs so that they can be made into new boxes. Now, the rise of e-commerce, which started before the pandemic, has shifted more responsibility onto shoppers to properly dispose of boxes so that they can be recycled. Boxes are piling up on residential curbsides instead of at retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1kn2In"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The pandemic has only accelerated this shift&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="unoLb6"&gt;The pandemic has only accelerated this shift, which experts expect to continue even after COVID-19 is under control. One of the largest waste collection companies in the US, Republic Services, saw as much as a 25 percent increase in waste it picked up from households last year — after the volume it picked up from commercial customers dropped by up to 30 percent when pandemic-induced lockdowns began. The company says it’s even had to change its equipment so that it can capture smaller boxes from e-commerce in addition to the larger packaging used to send goods to stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J19QUP"&gt;When cardboard winds up at a person’s house instead of at a store, there’s a bigger chance that it could be tossed in the trash or otherwise become too dirty to recycle. “The concern is that when you have more [cardboard] transitioning to the home, it becomes more of an individual choice for consumers whether they recycle it,” says Rachel Kenyon, senior vice president at the Fibre Box Association, a trade group representing packaging manufacturers. “We really want to encourage consumers to recycle because we do need that fiber back. It does help us to make another box again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBvYtN"&gt;The corrugated cardboard used to ship the things people buy in stores and online is remarkably salvageable. Virgin cardboard can be recycled to make more of the same material up to seven times. Once the fiber degrades, it can be used to make paperboard, which is used in things like cereal boxes. The average box now contains about 50 percent recycled material, according to Kenyon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N1bGAd"&gt;Recycling is no substitute for cutting down on waste in the first place, and online retailer behemoths still have a lot of work to do on that front. But cardboard has a much higher recycling rate compared to other packaging materials. The overall recycling rate for materials, including paper, glass, and plastics, in the US was about 32 percent in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/facts-and-figures-about-materials-waste-and-recycling/national-overview-facts-and-figures-materials"&gt;according to the Environmental Protection Agency&lt;/a&gt;. The recycling rate for cardboard boxes, on the other hand, has &lt;a href="https://www.paperrecycles.org/statistics/recovery-use-of-old-corrugated-containers-(occ)"&gt;hovered close to 90 percent&lt;/a&gt; since 2011. To keep those rates high, the cardboard industry will need shoppers to recycle the increasing number of boxes from the record amounts of box shipments made during the pandemic, according to Kenyon. By last November, the containerboard packaging industry saw a 3.6 increase in production, according to the American Forest &amp;amp; Paper Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0vOMz"&gt;There’s some indication that people are recycling their boxes in large numbers. Waste haulers, who can sell recovered cardboard to companies that make new boxes with it, saw a similar rise in cardboard over the past several months. Republic Services saw a 2 percent increase in the amount of cardboard it was able to sell in 2020, which it attributes to more e-commerce. That was a pretty significant bump considering monumental challenges that the recycling industry overall has seen in recent years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="1PnApy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Just a year ago, recycling was facing a crisis&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uhsnp3"&gt;Just a year ago, recycling was facing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/2/20986298/cyber-monday-black-friday-amazon-effect-recycling-cardboard-shopping"&gt;crisis&lt;/a&gt;. There was too much cardboard flooding the system, and as a result, the price of cardboard had tumbled so low that recycling programs were suffering. Some municipal recycling programs closed up shop or even resorted to burning and dumping recyclables they couldn’t sell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9smAuk"&gt;A big part of the problem was that the US had for years relied heavily on exporting a lot of its recyclables to China. In 2018, China began severely restricting imports. The recycling rate for cardboard dipped as the US figured out where else to send its trash and scrambled to build up its domestic recycling capacity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fhFOX1"&gt;In the past couple of years, new paper mills have already come online, and others are on the way, experts tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The demand for more cardboard boxes — fueled by a pandemic-driven boom in e-commerce — is also helping once-struggling recycling programs stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tSgKKy"&gt;“We are recovering,” says David Biderman, executive director and CEO of the Solid Waste Association of North America. “If the economy continues to recover and more of this domestic capacity comes online later this year, I believe that this provides good tailwind for recycling.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8ZzYup"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Good tailwind for recycling” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6C307a"&gt;That doesn’t mean it will be all smooth sailing ahead. Up to 40 percent of Americans don’t have access to curbside receptacles for their recyclables, according to a &lt;a href="https://sustainablepackaging.org/findings-released-spc-centralized-study-availability-recycling/"&gt;2016 study&lt;/a&gt;. In more rural areas, people might need to drop off their materials at recycling facilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8RMzoI"&gt;Access isn’t the only issue with consumer recycling. Waste haulers are still finding all kinds of weird things in recycling bins that can cause problems. Unlike trash from brick-and-mortar stores, curbside recycling is often mixed up with other items from peoples’ homes and kitchens. Dirty diapers and half-full condiment bottles can contaminate cardboard, making it unfit for recycling. Holiday lights and batteries tossed into curbside recycling are also major headaches around this time of year. Holiday lights get tangled up in sorting equipment and can force recycling facilities to temporarily shut off their machinery. Batteries can become a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/28/21156477/recycling-plants-fire-batteries-rechargeable-smartphone-lithium-ion"&gt;fire hazard&lt;/a&gt; when mixed up with paper and cardboard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODuBZk"&gt;“One of the things that keeps me awake at night is fire. There are a lot of batteries that are out there, post holiday season,” says Pete Keller, vice president of recycling and sustainability at Republic Services. “Education is very, very important to any successful recycling program, contamination in the US continues to be a bit of a challenge.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SctaqN"&gt;“We also ask people to remove any non-paper packing materials, break boxes down flat, keep them dry and clean and place them in the bin,” Heidi Brock, president and CEO of the American Forest &amp;amp; Paper Association, said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We need everyone to pitch in and do their part to recycle paper-based products at home.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22219042/online-shopping-ecommerce-packaging-cardboard-boxes-recycling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22219042/online-shopping-ecommerce-packaging-cardboard-boxes-recycling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T14:27:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T14:27:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch disables Trump’s account</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q_g5mn1Kk8GZ6c6ScN0Z6EY_lFY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68633916/acastro_200901_1777_twitch_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3TK7om"&gt;Twitch has disabled President Donald Trump’s account indefinitely following his encouragement of a pro-Trump mob’s attack of the US Capitol on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Id6pbc"&gt;“In light of yesterday’s shocking attack on the Capitol, we have disabled President Trump’s Twitch channel,” a Twitch spokesperson said in a statement. “Given the current extraordinary circumstances and the President’s incendiary rhetoric, we believe this is a necessary step to protect our community and prevent Twitch from being used to incite further violence.” The company says it will reassess Trump’s account after he leaves office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EnupVl"&gt;Trump’s account remains live, so archived videos and his profile are still available. But while the account is disabled, he won’t be able to stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DR3JKx"&gt;In June, Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21307145/twitch-donald-trump-ban-campaign-account"&gt;temporarily banned Trump’s account&lt;/a&gt; for “hateful conduct” that was aired on his stream. The ban was lifted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/13/21310514/twitch-trump-unbanned-hateful-conduct-suspended"&gt;after two weeks&lt;/a&gt;. On Wednesday evening, Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22218088/twitch-bans-pogchamp-poggers-capitol-trump-violence-gootecks"&gt;deleted the well-known PogChamp emote&lt;/a&gt; because the person on whose face it was based made statements “encouraging further violence after what took place in the Capitol today,” according to Twitch. The streaming platform plans to work with the community to design a new emote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RiZtoq"&gt;Earlier on Thursday, Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218725/facebook-trump-ban-extended-capitol-riot-insurrection-block"&gt;placed an indefinite ban&lt;/a&gt; on Trump’s account and said the ban would not be lifted before Inauguration Day. Twitter locked Trump’s account &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217686/trump-twitter-account-locked-capitol-hill-riot-tweets-policy-violations"&gt;Wednesday evening&lt;/a&gt; and said that further violations of its policies will result in a “permanent suspension” of his account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4pWxB1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 7th, 2:34PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Trump’s account is still live, so the account has not been entirely banned. We have updated the headline to reflect this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219144/twitch-trump-ban-indefinitely-capitol-attack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219144/twitch-trump-ban-indefinitely-capitol-attack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T14:24:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T14:24:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Signal sees surge in new signups after boost from Elon Musk and WhatsApp controversy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Messenger apps on a smartphone" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ERlWDP9B9EUgH9dB9zDdzOHIc_U=/0x0:4096x2731/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68633906/1229931679.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Christoph Dernbach / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ttWatW"&gt;Encrypted messaging app Signal says it’s seeing a swell of new users signing up for the platform, so much so that the company is seeing delays in phone number verifications of new accounts across multiple cell providers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pM3kHW"&gt;As for what or who is responsible for so many new users interested in trying the platform, which is operated by the nonprofit Signal Foundation, there are two likely culprits: Tesla CEO Elon Musk and Signal competitor WhatsApp.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eAVSUh"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Verification codes are currently delayed across several providers because so many new people are trying to join Signal right now (we can barely register our excitement). We are working with carriers to resolve this as quickly as possible. Hang in there.&lt;/p&gt;— Signal (@signalapp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/signalapp/status/1347240006444675072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bLpilt"&gt;Musk, who is now the world’s richest person &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22163361/elon-musk-billionaire-richest-world-jeff-bezos-tesla-stock-spacex"&gt;after surpassing Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos in net worth&lt;/a&gt;, tweeted a meme last night criticizing Facebook for its role in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217601/congress-capitol-building-takeover-coup-photos-pro-trump-mob"&gt;helping members of the mob that stormed the US Capitol on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; organize online. The tweet, an image of a series of ever-larger dominos, juxtaposed the start of Facebook as a hot-or-not women-rating website on the campus of Harvard University all the way into a platform that in one way or another helped facilitate the attack on Congress on Wednesday while it attempted to certify Joe Biden as the president-elect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5Aa37Q"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is called the domino effect &lt;a href="https://t.co/qpbEW54RvM"&gt;pic.twitter.com/qpbEW54RvM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1347031803987599360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UbZ1Ls"&gt;Musk, who has been more vocal in his criticism of Facebook in recent years, followed up the meme with a suggestion to his 41.5 million followers: download Signal, presumably instead of using a Facebook product (although Musk didn’t call out Facebook or WhatsApp specifically by name in either of his posts). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6Ab0st"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Use Signal&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1347165127036977153?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mDolUr"&gt;As for the WhatsApp controversy, that’s a bit more complicated. While it’s not immediately clear whether Musk was referencing or is even aware of the current WhatsApp privacy dustup, there is a growing backlash against the Facebook-owned messaging app resulting from the company’s plans to implement a new privacy policy on February 8th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9kFoy"&gt;There’s a &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/"&gt;great explainer from &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica &lt;/em&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but the short version is that WhatsApp has outlined a new privacy policy going into effect next month that no longer includes language indicating it will allow users to opt out of data sharing with parent company Facebook. Instead, the new policy expressly outlines how WhatsApp will share data (stuff like your phone number, profile name, and address book info) with Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62cVrl"&gt;“As part of the Facebook family of companies, WhatsApp receives information from, and shares information with, this family of companies,” the &lt;a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/privacy-policy"&gt;new privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; says. “We may use the information we receive from them, and they may use the information we share with them, to help operate, provide, improve, understand, customize, support, and market our Services and their offerings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OtVAcJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook says its new privacy policy changes nothing about consumer data sharing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7ZsXFw"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Ars &lt;/em&gt;reports, the opt out hasn’t actually existed in the app for some time — it was a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/26/12655518/how-to-stop-whatsapp-sharing-phone-number-facebook"&gt;one-time option introduced back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, and WhatsApp’s privacy policy has kept language referencing it since. A Facebook spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that the changes going into effect next month are designed to address data sharing between Facebook and WhatsApp with regard to messaging with businesses, and that nothing is effectively changing with regard to consumer chats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t7xm7V"&gt;Facebook says it disclosed these changes back in October with the announcement of &lt;a href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/shopping-payments-and-customer-service-on-whatsapp"&gt;new WhatsApp customer service and shopping features&lt;/a&gt;, some of which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163106/whatsapp-carts-feature-shopping-in-app-ecommerce"&gt;went live last month&lt;/a&gt;. It also says it will honor any WhatsApp user’s opt-out preference, even though the option to opt out hasn’t been available for new users for years, &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/whatsapp-to-require-users-to-share-data-with-facebook-via-new-privacy-policy"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And if you live in Europe, WhatsApp won’t share data with Facebook for ad-targeting purposes under any circumstances, as clarified by Niamh Sweeney, WhatsApp’s director of policy for the Europe, Middle East, and Africa market, in a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NiamhSweeneyNYC/status/1347183889995935744"&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="o9WDi7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;2/5 It has been incorrectly reported that WhatsApp's latest Terms of Service and Privacy Policy update requires users in the European Region to agree to the sharing of data with Facebook for ads purposes in order to continue using the service. This is false.&lt;/p&gt;— Niamh Sweeney (@NiamhSweeneyNYC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NiamhSweeneyNYC/status/1347184836323237889?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ALsdXk"&gt;But what’s happening now appears to be a bit of context collapse on social media, as WhatsApp users think they’re now being forced to share data with Facebook even though that’s been happening all along if they didn’t opt out back in 2016. None of this is helped by Facebook and WhatsApp’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165152/whatsapp-privacy-apple-first-third-party-app-store-nutrition-labels"&gt;recent attacks on Apple&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone maker’s decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;mandate new self-reported labels on iOS apps&lt;/a&gt; and its future plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22180102/facebook-new-newspaper-ad-apple-ios-14-privacy-prompt"&gt;force app makers to request permission&lt;/a&gt; to track Apple device owners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b54dxr"&gt;The new privacy policy notice doesn’t help Facebook’s cause, either, considering it tells users displeased with the changes — which, again, are about how businesses manage their chats on WhatsApp using Facebook’s backend — to “delete their account,” with no other remedies provided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="obnfMl"&gt;All of this has created a perfect storm on social media in which WhatsApp users appear to be fleeing the platform in large numbers to join Signal, a nonprofit-run encrypted messaging app not owned by the largest social network on the planet. It’s worth mentioning too Signal Messenger, LLC, the software organization that manages product development from Signal, was &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/21/signal-expands-into-the-signal-foundation-with-50m-from-whatsapp-co-founder-brian-acton/"&gt;co-founded and funded by Brian Acton&lt;/a&gt;, the disillusioned WhatsApp co-founder who has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17145200/brian-acton-delete-facebook-whatsapp"&gt;publicly slammed his former employer’s privacy practices&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mPHPbY"&gt;Facebook has declined to comment on the record or publish any public blog post or statement regarding its planned WhatsApp privacy policy outside the Europe-specific comments from Sweeney, which is only adding to the confusion at this point. But the silver lining for Signal is that this combination of events is generating a whole lot of interest for its platform as both a viable mobile messaging app and alternative to the Facebook ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218989/signal-new-signups-whatsapp-facebook-privacy-controversy-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218989/signal-new-signups-whatsapp-facebook-privacy-controversy-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
