<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-25T09:56:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:56:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:56:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla doesn’t want anyone to see its response to the Autopilot investigation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fV8JZVTlTo61gsFXU41Ubv57BCc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041660/tesla.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nwNP3e"&gt;Tesla wants to keep secret its response to the federal investigation into its Autopilot driver assist system. &lt;a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/inv/2021/INME-PE21020-1022.pdf"&gt;In a memo submitted to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) last week&lt;/a&gt;, regulators noted that Tesla has requested “confidential business information (CBI) treatment for the entirety of the information request submission.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JKtelU"&gt;If Tesla’s request is granted, it would effectively bar the public from seeing the company’s response to a host of information that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;NHTSA has requested&lt;/a&gt; regarding its probe into Autopilot and possible defects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="igFIFK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If Tesla’s request is granted, it would effectively bar the public from seeing the company’s response&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="atwqHR"&gt;The agency wants to know why Tesla didn’t issue a recall for Autopilot after it became obvious the driver assistance system had a problem “seeing” parked emergency vehicles. NHTSA is also asking Tesla for more information about the growing public beta test of its incomplete Full Self-Driving software, the recently launched “Safety Score” evaluation process for entering the program, and the nondisclosure agreements Tesla was making participants sign up until this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KLdocv"&gt;The request for confidentiality was made amid a period of intense scrutiny into Tesla and its willingness to rollout unfinished software updates to its customers. There have been at least a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;dozen incidents&lt;/a&gt; in which Teslas with Autopilot activated have crashed into parked emergency vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7anhPu"&gt;Tesla shipped a software update to its &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/534868/tesla-autopilot-update-emergency-vehicles/"&gt;cars meant to fix the issue&lt;/a&gt; with its driver assistance system in September. But NHTSA wants to know why Tesla didn’t go through the formal recall process with this update, potentially setting up a protracted fight over whether over-the-air updates that can materially change how cars operate should be subjected to the government’s stringent automotive safety rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OipKtf"&gt;Tesla started rolling out a new software update over the weekend, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/24/22743628/elon-musk-tesla-fsd-beta-10-3-rollback-issues-phantom-fcw"&gt;but reversed it on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; after the company’s CEO Elon Musk tweeted that they were “seeing some issues” with it. Some Tesla owners reported problems such as phantom forward collision warnings, disappearing Autosteer option, traffic-aware cruise control problems, and occasional AutoPilot panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7vAND"&gt;The news of Tesla’s request for confidentiality also comes as scores of the company’s fans have posted disparaging comments about a new hire at NHTSA, robotics expert Missy Cummings, whom they view as being hostile to the company. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/the-station-zoox-seattle-tesla-fans-attack/"&gt;Cummings reportedly received death threats&lt;/a&gt; from some Tesla fans, causing her to delete her Twitter account. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744629/tesla-autopilot-secret-response-nhtsa-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744629/tesla-autopilot-secret-response-nhtsa-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:36:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:36:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The new 14-inch MacBook Pro is already $50 off at Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_t67oBMGzCttlcZxrxqOUZi88mA=/14x0:2026x1341/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041585/akrales_211020_4803_0018.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vW3PZL"&gt;Last week, Apple introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"&gt;its new generation of MacBook Pro laptops&lt;/a&gt;, featuring a new design (complete with a notched screen) and faster M1 chips. If you had your eye on the 14-inch model instead of the 16-inch MacBook Pro, you can save just a little bit of cash on it when you preorder at Amazon. The configuration that has the M1 Pro chip (eight-core CPU, 14-core GPU), 16GB of RAM, and a 512GB SSD &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQSLL92?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;is $1,949.99 instead of $2,000&lt;/a&gt;. A $50 discount isn’t a whole lot, but it’s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="alRiTh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editor-in-chief Nilay Patel &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22508064"&gt;just posted first impressions&lt;/a&gt; of his time with the latest MacBook Pro. It’s not a review (stay tuned for that), but check it out if you want to see some fresh images, along with takeaways from real-world usage of the M1 Pro and M1 Max chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="imDSyF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10814206"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="akS6ee"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi"&gt;Another product that Apple recently debuted&lt;/a&gt; is discounted at Amazon. The new AirPods Pro &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQMJHXY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that ship with a MagSafe charging case are $220&lt;/a&gt; instead of Apple’s $249 price. In terms of features and specs, these are the same wireless earbuds that first shipped in 2019 — you can &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;find those now for $197&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just the case that’s new here, and while we haven’t tested them yet (and thus, don’t know if the case has improved charging speeds or if it’s just magnetized), this is a decent deal I’d recommend for first-time AirPods Pro buyers who want everything they own to have MagSafe compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5oew0P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10826178"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="FQhU0P"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on: big screens, big ambitions, small price|104420" data-volume-uuid="0fd6d24c0" data-volume-id="104420" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-973" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zBspGJ"&gt;If you’re interested in preordering a Google Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"&gt;Best Buy still has stock of the phones&lt;/a&gt; and is including a free set of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465651/google-pixel-buds-a-series-earbuds-review-features-price"&gt;Pixel Buds A-series&lt;/a&gt; wireless earbuds at checkout through Wednesday, October 27th. Those normally cost $100, so this is a solid incentive. Google unveiled the Pixel 6 phones last week, and the highlight was on the promising, new Google Tensor chip inside of both of them. Check out the video above for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TAeZAvwbNBRS5kycCzSpvekXfHU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22012245/vpavic_201103_4275_0240.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uBaC7B"&gt;While this isn’t technically a deal, it’s worth sharing that Microsoft’s Xbox Series S console is currently available at Best Buy &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfRvlrDzyZc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for its normal $300 price&lt;/a&gt;. It was tough to find for several months following its debut in late 2020, and you may want to pick one up now if you planned to give it as a gift during the holidays. Supply of the console may dwindle as we get closer to Black Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NMpxId"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="NabZZD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/25/22744535/apple-macbook-pro-amazon-airpods-magsafe-google-pixel-6-buds-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/25/22744535/apple-macbook-pro-amazon-airpods-magsafe-google-pixel-6-buds-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:16:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:16:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite’s new campaign trailer has Master Chief chasing Cortana</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EQap1us9Ev4iBwCRc8yQIl1wXrA=/185x0:2243x1372/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041529/Screen_Shot_2021_10_25_at_9.04.27_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rGzWVh"&gt;Microsoft has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XCbMVbeKlCg"&gt;finally revealed&lt;/a&gt; a new look at &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign mode, marking the first time that developer 343 Industries has shown the campaign since its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21335520/halo-infinite-gameplay-xbox-series-x-trailer-demo"&gt;initial gameplay reveal in July 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XvJb6h"&gt;The new six-minute trailer shows off a lot of Infinite’s new gameplay and systems in a short amount of time, including new weapons, new enemies, menacing bosses, and a new AI companion character that will be accompanying players called “The Weapon.” The overview also shows off some of Infinite’s new open world gameplay and RPG style gameplay additions, which include optional bases and objectives for players to pursue and selectable upgrades for equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VIy3Fsmq0QubSBbZK4Tb-Ps0DL4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953711/Screen_Shot_2021_10_25_at_9.06.41_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Rh0sIB"&gt;Set after 2015’s &lt;em&gt;Halo 5: Guardians&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt; is the first mainline Halo game in over five years and will look to pick up the story of the artificial intelligence revolution led by Master Chief’s former ally Cortana that served as &lt;em&gt;Halo 5&lt;/em&gt;’s cliffhanger. &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt; will also pick up story threads from 2017’s real-time strategy spinoff &lt;em&gt;Halo Wars 2&lt;/em&gt;, which introduced the latest strain of Halo’s classic Covenant antagonists, the Brute-led “Banished.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OxVBlK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZtc5-syeAk"&gt;initial gameplay reveal&lt;/a&gt; was viewed by many as underwhelming, spawning disappointment in the purportedly next-gen visuals and the infamous “Craig” meme that dunked on a close-up shot of a particularly poorly rendered Brute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OEqyxM"&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;set to launch in just a few weeks on December 8th, the new campaign overview isn’t just a chance for 343 Industries to give players a better idea of what to expect from the game when it arrives, but also a chance for redemption and to better sell fans on &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s potential after its lackluster first impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5j3pyw"&gt;While 343 Industries has largely been keeping &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign under wraps (until today’s reveal, at least), the studio has been letting players try out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531861/halo-infinite-e3-2021-trailer-demo-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s free-to-play multiplayer mode&lt;/a&gt; in a series of preview weekends. These weekends have had a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22725770/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview"&gt;far more positive reception&lt;/a&gt; as an exciting evolution (and in many ways, a return to form) for the franchise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YqeUuB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Halo Infinite multiplayer feels like an exciting return to form","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22725770/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OVLTHm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;was originally intended to launch alongside the Xbox Series X and Series S last fall, but the game was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"&gt;delayed to 2021&lt;/a&gt; due to a variety of development challenges, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. It’s now set to arrive on PC, Xbox Series X / S, and Xbox One platforms on December 8th, although the game will ship &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634448/halo-infinite-co-op-campaign-forge-delay-launch"&gt;without a few key features&lt;/a&gt;, including the campaign’s co-op mode and the popular Forge multiplayer map editor, both of which are slated for a 2022 release in a future update. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744558/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-preview-trailer-master-chief-xbox-series-x"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744558/halo-infinite-campaign-overview-preview-trailer-master-chief-xbox-series-x</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon announces Alexa program for hospitals and senior care</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4qVseXkyIDAlBt8LnZjgE5LP9FY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041474/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PGi8NN"&gt;Amazon has two new programs that integrate Alexa into hospitals and senior living communities, the company announced today. They’re run through Alexa Smart Properties, which allows organizations to control a centralized Alexa system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmQyj6"&gt;“Early on in the pandemic, hospitals and senior living communities reached out to us and asked us to help them set up Alexa and voice in their communities,” Liron Torres, global leader for Alexa Smart Properties, said in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Hospitals wanted ways to interact with patients without using protective equipment, and senior living communities wanted to connect residents with family members and staff, she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWuNyJ"&gt;The program lets senior living facilities use Amazon Echo devices to send announcements or other messages to residents’ rooms. During the COVID-19 pandemic, many facilities relied on printed out sheets of paper slipped under resident doors to communicate changes in protocols, like around meals or quarantines. The Alexa program lets them send messages instantly into patient rooms. “Staff can be more available for other tasks,” Torres says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xzKRkb"&gt;Residents can also place calls through Alexa to family members or friends without having to rely on a staff member. Approved contacts would also be able to call in through Alexa. The facility could enable calling for a set of contacts approved by the resident and family members when they arrive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pa2Fdp"&gt;Two networks of senior living communities, Atria (which is nationwide) and Eskaton (based in California), are adding Alexa to some facilities, Amazon said. Amazon declined to say how much the program costs those facilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rxXiSj"&gt;In hospitals, the Alexa Smart Properties program lets nurses communicate with patients through the calling and intercom-esque drop-in features without having to enter patient rooms. Patients could ask questions, or nurses could check on how someone is feeling through the feature. “This enables hospitals to increase productivity and be able to save on medical supplies,” Torres says. Hospitals can also send information and announcements to patients through Alexa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taihVt"&gt;Patients can toggle on “do not disturb” to prevent drop-ins, Torres says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LsQU6C"&gt;Cedars-Sinai Medical Center in Los Angeles, BayCare Health System in Florida, and Houston Methodist are adding Alexa to their facilities, Amazon said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2oQvW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22740181/amazon-alexa-hospitals-senior-living"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22740181/amazon-alexa-hospitals-senior-living</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>MacBook Pro with M1 Pro and M1 Max impressions: giving the people what they want</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The new 16-inch MacBook Pro on a table" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9acDB7UuM65bB3mu_qfX0jB5azY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041418/akrales_211020_4803_0201.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;New chips, familiar ports, and actual volume buttons — it might be love&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Tp6Am9"&gt;It’s easy to be excited about the new MacBook Pros — it feels like Apple finally listened to everyone and brought back the best parts of the beloved 2015 MacBook Pro, while pushing the display and performance to new heights. I know a lot of people who ordered one sight unseen; the pent-up demand for a great pro Mac laptop has been growing since Apple released the MacBook Air and 13-inch MacBook Pro with M1 chips last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vD8mxt"&gt;We’ve had three of these new MacBook Pros for a little less than a week — we’re doing some quick impressions now, but we’re taking our time with the full review since there’s a lot to discuss and a lot of questions about performance and battery life to answer. We also know a lot of people are eager to order these new MacBook Pros but have a lot of questions, so ask away in the comments and we’ll answer as many as we can in the review later this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nrPGv8"&gt;The three MacBook Pro models we have here are a &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/1141873/1110072/7613?subId1=VergeMacBookPro102521&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-pro%2F16-inch-space-gray-10-core-cpu-32-core-gpu-1tb" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver 16-inch model&lt;/a&gt; loaded with a 10-core M1 Max with a 32-core GPU, 64GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage that sells for $3,899; a &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/1141873/1110072/7613?subId1=VergeMacBookPro102521&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-pro%2F16-inch-space-gray-10-core-cpu-16-core-gpu-1tb" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver M1 Pro 16-inch&lt;/a&gt; with a 10-core CPU, 16-core GPU, 32GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage that costs $3,099; and a &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/1141873/1110072/7613?subId1=VergeMacBookPro102521&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fmacbook-pro%2F14-inch-space-gray-10-core-cpu-16-core-gpu-1tb%23" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray 14-inch&lt;/a&gt; with the same 10-core M1 Pro with 16-core GPU, 32GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage that sells for $2,899.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="MacBook Pro with lid closed" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f_iXIjN0X8_efpoUFEkERn-nzgg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948088/akrales_211020_4803_0125.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new MacBook Pro has a blocky, almost throwback design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GZGA5e"&gt;Design wise, they’re a slight new direction for Apple laptops — the concepts are all familiar, but the execution is a little more squared off, a little thicker, a little more aggressive. They share an overall sensibility with that 2015 MacBook Pro, with a hint of the titanium PowerBook G4 from 2001. The “MacBook Pro” name is now stamped on the bottom, along with four raised feet — there was some early discussion about these feet, but in practice they are barely noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Bottom of new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4rfX3_HvG5vh4-JnPY9d6frWxGo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948750/akrales_211022_4803_0237.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bottom plate has four rubber feet and an imprinted logo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Raised feed on the new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/azef7GnjLA8RvDMX8QxW50VRbPo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948748/akrales_211022_4803_0216.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The rubber feet add some height to the MacBook Pro but aren’t really noticeably in use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xd9VrS"&gt;In a welcome move, Apple has added some useful ports back to the new MacBook Pros: gaze upon an SD card slot and an HDMI port. (Sadly, neither is cutting edge, the SD slot is UHS-II, not UHS-III, and the HDMI is 2.0, not 2.1.) Other than that, you’ve got three Thunderbolt 4 ports and the MagSafe power connector. It’s great that MagSafe is back, but I get the feeling it’s a hedge against the confusing mess of USB-C power standards: you can charge the new Pros from any of the Thunderbolt 4 ports and fast charge the 14 over USB-C, but Apple tells us you can &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; fast charge the 16 with the MagSafe port. And we need to really test how fast charging works on the 16 with other USB-C adapters to make sure it works, since that’s always goofy. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HDMI and SD card slot on the new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r1X9POwVTPMXhYn-nlK9pllXeQ0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948084/akrales_211020_4803_0058.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ports! Specifically, the SD card slot and HDMI have returned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="MagSafe on new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ujyxxWJoNxzjk8Avjq9gbMkI6f8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948085/akrales_211020_4803_0062.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also making its return is MagSafe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iHbq7D"&gt;The other major design change is a personal victory: Apple finally got rid of the Touch Bar, which never really lived up to its potential, and replaced it with full-height function keys. They’re great, uncomplicated, and do exactly what you’d expect. The TouchID button looks a lot uglier in photos, but it’s totally fine in person and seems very fast to unlock the machine. The keyboard feels great, although Apple’s claim that it feels like a mechanical keyboard is just like… an idea from another dimension? Here in reality, it feels like a nice laptop keyboard. The most controversial thing about it in our office has been the all-black keyboard deck, which some people think will get dirty fast. So far: it hasn’t been an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Keyboard on new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X6G6pEjjSkyhh6EFMI0KMtGRvnU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948082/akrales_211020_4803_0037.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Touch Bar is gone, thankfully, but the TouchID sensor helpfully remains.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TKkCjG"&gt;We’re going to spend a lot of time testing the new Mini LED display that supports 120Hz refresh rates in the full review, but in early use it looks great, with claimed peak brightness up to 1,600 nits in the default profile out of the box. One nice surprise, given Apple and Google’s history of weird video codec fights: you can just open up an HDR video on YouTube in Chrome and it will work and look incredible. It’s great. And yes, the display has a notch, which we know will be polarizing, but I very quickly stopped noticing it, just like everyone stops seeing the iPhone notch. We’ll see how I feel after another few days with this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Notch on new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WFde5UyfBxFRamE7rmfu9q2Hv5w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948752/pesposito_170722_4803_0032.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new 1080p webcam is much better than the lousy cameras on prior MacBooks. Oh, yeah, there’s a notch now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CqEX4b"&gt;Inside the notch, there’s a new 1080p camera that takes advantage of Apple’s image processing system on its chips. It’s noticeably clearer and crisper than the miserable quality of previous Apple webcams, but it’s still a laptop webcam — it’s not even close to an iPhone front camera. And there’s no Center Stage, so it doesn’t follow you around the room on a video call like the iPad can now do. The sound quality on these machines is incredible — there are six speakers, and they sound great and support spatial audio. And they can get very loud. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="New MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1ImQZO-LfXtOaLytMYjU77z_Kfs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948083/akrales_211020_4803_0047.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new keyboard is all black, which might get dirty over time. But so far, so good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g8RZnC"&gt;Inside you’ve got Apple’s new M1 Pro and M1 Max processors, which are much more powerful versions of the M1 chip that have much more serious GPU capabilities. We’re doing a lot of performance tests to see what’s what with these chips, but I can tell you right now that the 16-inch Pro with M1 Max clocked the fastest time ever in our Adobe Premiere 4K export test… by over a minute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysoWiJ"&gt;Apple is very proud of the fact that its chips draw so much less power than the competition, so it’s able to deliver the same performance plugged in as on battery power. We’ll do our best to put that to the test. And a major reason we’re taking a little extra time to publish our full review is because I want to be really certain about battery life — we loved the battery life we got on the M1 machines last year, but these have much beefier chips, bigger, brighter displays, and get used for more intense tasks, so I want to be as sure about that as we can. The early results are promising — big batteries and efficient chips are a good combination — but we want to push things as hard as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="New MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7lS2nuRIO-lBuQiF7B8iOvIkXLE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948078/akrales_211020_4803_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new MacBook Pro 16.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="3dRpsY"&gt;But the main thing we want to know is: what do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; want to know about these new MacBook Pros? A lot of people have waited a long time for these machines, and we want to make sure we make this review as useful as we can. Let us know your questions in the comments and we’ll try to answer them in our full review.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22744023/macbook-pro-2021-m1-pro-m1-max-impressions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22744023/macbook-pro-2021-m1-pro-m1-max-impressions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T08:58:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T08:58:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now play Steam PC games on an Xbox with Nvidia’s GeForce Now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/06nfnjy8hbZyL2tYxcT3cGwPxes=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041413/Xbox_Series_S___Xbox_Series_S_2021_10_25_13_32_38.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steam games can be streamed from GeForce Now on an Xbox.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JJoqDW"&gt;Nvidia is unlocking access to its GeForce Now streaming service on Microsoft Edge today, allowing Xbox owners to play Steam PC games on their consoles. GeForce Now includes access to more than 1,000 PC games, and Nvidia has finally started supporting the Edge browser that now ships on Xbox in a beta update to GeForce Now today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYdYRw"&gt;It brings the dream of playing PC games on an Xbox a step closer to reality, as the result is easy access to stream PC games to an Xbox. As the base GeForce Now service is free, you can stream popular PC games like &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;DOTA 2&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends &lt;/em&gt;at 1080p for an hourlong session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XXv50f"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403429/microsoft-xbox-steam-games-edge-browser-mouse-keyboard-support"&gt;I’ve been able to do this in the past&lt;/a&gt; using Parsec, which is essentially a remote desktop app that lets you stream what’s on your PC to a browser. GeForce Now is a far better solution as it doesn’t rely on you having to own a PC that’s capable of running these games, and you just connect to the service through the browser and launch games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KHLuTO"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;You can now play Steam PC games on an Xbox with Nvidia’s GeForce Now. Here's a quick look at how it all works. Details here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/EMGX0HRxcT"&gt;https://t.co/EMGX0HRxcT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/G6YcloBubM"&gt;pic.twitter.com/G6YcloBubM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1452620641304199174?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SXMx0g"&gt;What makes this all the more interesting is that the Edge browser on Xbox also supports mouse and keyboard input, so you can play certain games that don’t even have gamepad support. It’s not the most ideal experience on the Xbox right now because the virtual keyboard appears when you click and latency isn’t great for multiplayer games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6WdgzY"&gt;Microsoft’s head of Xbox, Phil Spencer, has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/XboxP3/status/1384154390630592521"&gt;recently committed&lt;/a&gt; to bringing full PC games to the Xbox through the company’s Xbox Cloud Gaming (xCloud) service. We still don’t know when those will eventually arrive, but GeForce Now in the browser is the best alternative until they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNsc6W"&gt;With Nvidia expanding GeForce Now to Edge and even adding an RTX 3080 tier, it would be great to see an official Xbox client for the service, and a way to play these PC games on PlayStation, too. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22738056/microsoft-xbox-pc-games-steam-nvidia-geforce-now-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22738056/microsoft-xbox-pc-games-steam-nvidia-geforce-now-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T08:03:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T08:03:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hertz orders 100,000 Teslas in deal reportedly worth $4.2 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Electric Car Maker Tesla Reports Record Quarterly Earnings" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cy6FSu1ENwRKL0_MYxbqRI0CzxM=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041271/1347936771.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QcJ6yp"&gt;Rental car company Hertz has ordered 100,000 Teslas as part of an ambitious plan to electrify its fleet. A first tranche of Tesla’s Model 3 sedans will be available to rent from Hertz in major US and European markets from early November, said the company in a &lt;a href="https://ir.hertz.com/2021-10-25-Hertz-Invests-in-Largest-Electric-Vehicle-Rental-Fleet-and-Partners-with-Seven-Time-Super-Bowl-Champion-Tom-Brady-to-Headline-New-Campaign"&gt;press statement&lt;/a&gt;. The announcement comes just months after Hertz &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/30/business/hertz-bankrupcty.html"&gt;escaped bankruptcy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpQ0hC"&gt;News of the purchase was first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-25/hertz-orders-100-000-teslas-tsla-stock-soars?utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;cmpid=socialflow-twitter-business&amp;amp;utm_content=business&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which says the deal is the single largest order ever for electric vehicles, and worth $4.2. billion in revenue to Tesla. The automaker’s stock was &lt;a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/tesla-stock-surges-toward-a-record-after-hertz-reportedly-ordered-100000-tesla-evs-2021-10-25"&gt;up 4.3 percent on the news&lt;/a&gt; in pre-market trading. It was also reported this morning that Tesla’s Model 3 became the first electric vehicle to top &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744481/tesla-model-3-tops-sales-charts-europe-electric-vehicles"&gt;monthly sales charts&lt;/a&gt; in Europe this September. Earlier this month, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/2/22704830/tesla-sold-241300-cars-third-quarter"&gt;reported record sales&lt;/a&gt; in its third quarter, despite chip shortages denting the automotive market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="prErM2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s been a very good month for Tesla&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9fGrhC"&gt;Anyone renting a Tesla from Hertz will be able to use the automaker’s network of 3,000 superchargers across the US and Europe. Hertz says it’s planing on supplementing these chargers with “thousands” of its own, dispersed “throughout its location network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2YbtfM"&gt;Hertz went into bankruptcy in &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/22/business/hertz-bankruptcy-coronavirus-car-rental.html?searchResultPosition=1"&gt;May last year&lt;/a&gt; after the car rental market was hit hard by the pandemic. The company, which is more than a hundred years old, was eventually re-financed to the tune of $5.9 billion by investors led by Knighthead Capital Management and Certares Management. According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg, &lt;/em&gt;Hertz now plans to electrify nearly all of its roughly 500,000 cars and vans, with the Tesla order comprising a significant first chunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="erfKHV"&gt;In a press statement, Hertz’s interim CEO Mark Fields said: “Electric vehicles are now mainstream, and we’ve only just begun to see rising global demand and interest. The new Hertz is going to lead the way as a mobility company, starting with the largest EV rental fleet in North America and a commitment to grow our EV fleet and provide the best rental and recharging experience for leisure and business customers around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lpi4nh"&gt;To publicize the move, Hertz has launched a new ad campaign featuring Tom Brady. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9IcNMg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;GOAT’s recognize GOAT’s. Introducing our all new EV fleet (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TomBrady?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TomBrady&lt;/a&gt; not included) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hertz?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Hertz&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LetsGo?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#LetsGo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/TElSE2PDKb"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TElSE2PDKb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Hertz (@Hertz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Hertz/status/1452607992961064963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Rot9Tg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 8:39AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The story and headline have been updated to incorporate confirmation of the news from Hertz and additional details. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744504/hertz-tesla-order-100000-vehicles-electrify-fleet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744504/hertz-tesla-order-100000-vehicles-electrify-fleet</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T07:34:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T07:34:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s Model 3 is first electric vehicle to top monthly sales charts in Europe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TESLA charging station" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LZTLYXaqAiBROYg172sHREHlcHI=/0x2:5016x3346/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041128/1228386576.10.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Horst Galuschka/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u94nAJ"&gt;Tesla’s Model 3 has become the first electrical vehicle to top monthly sales of new cars in Europe, beating stalwarts like the Renault Clio and Volkswagen Golf to claim pole position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sRn5Z9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jato.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JATO-European-Car-Registrations-September-2021.pdf"&gt;Sales data&lt;/a&gt; shared by research firm Jato Dynamics and first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-25/tesla-model-3-becomes-first-electric-car-to-top-european-sales?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shows Tesla with a healthy lead over its rivals, selling 24,591 Model 3s in September compared to the 18,264 sales for the Renault Clio in the number two spot. This also marks the first time that a car made outside of Europe has been a monthly best-seller there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WH2EJH"&gt;The sales data suggests that the automotive market is slowly but surely moving away from combustion engines to electric vehicles. This is helped in no small part by various government subsidies to reduce the price of EVs and hybrid cars and vans. According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, sales of electric and hybrid vehicles accounted for 23 percent of total new sales in September — nearly double the proportion of the market in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rBf05QYV5piEIkfwfdsV4q2oJuQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22953586/download.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Jato Dynamics&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top selling cars in Europe for September 2021. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IQgn7z"&gt;However, the global chip shortage means that sales of new cars are down in general, with the EU market falling 25 percent year-on-year, with total sales in September 2021 of 964,800 vehicles. “Dealers continue to face issues with the availability of new cars due to the chip shortage,” Jato analyst Felipe Munoz told &lt;a href="https://www.am-online.com/news/car-manufacturer-news/2021/10/25/tesla-model-3-leads-ev-revolution-across-eu-in-september"&gt;&lt;em&gt;AM Online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, unwilling to wait more than a year for a new car, many consumers have turned to the used car market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B5JmWr"&gt;September has typically been a strong month for Tesla, with the company often pushing sales hard for the end of the quarter. This year’s September sales accounted for 74 percent of Tesla’s total third quarter volume, reports &lt;em&gt;AM Online&lt;/em&gt;, with the combined success of the Model 3 and Model Y giving it a leading 24 percent market share of electric vehicle sales, ahead of rivals Volkswagen with 22 percent and Stellantis with 13 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvEEFr"&gt;That’s the hardware, but on the software side things are less smooth this month for Tesla. The company had to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/24/22743628/elon-musk-tesla-fsd-beta-10-3-rollback-issues-phantom-fcw"&gt;pull its latest self-driving beta&lt;/a&gt; after drivers complained about bugs including false crash warnings. An &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1452576223620747266"&gt;early morning tweet&lt;/a&gt; from Tesla CEO Elon Musk, though, suggests that the latest beta may have been restored, hopefully with those bugs squashed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x56kXU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744481/tesla-model-3-tops-sales-charts-europe-electric-vehicles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744481/tesla-model-3-tops-sales-charts-europe-electric-vehicles</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T07:10:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T07:10:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>This free web tool is a fast and easy way to remove objects from images</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hh4doEBQm01pTDwI8_qoIk52pg4=/0x57:806x594/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70041081/Screen_Shot_2021_10_25_at_11.51.58_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OqdXfE"&gt;Ever needed to quickly edit something or someone out of an image? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5DRHt"&gt;Maybe it’s the stranger who wandered into your family photo, or the stand holding up your final artwork for school? Whatever the job, if you don’t have the time or Photoshop skills needed to edit the thing yourself, why not try &lt;a href="https://cleanup.pictures/"&gt;Cleanup.pictures&lt;/a&gt; — a handy web tool that does exactly what it promises in the URL. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xex2WR"&gt;Just upload your picture, paint over the thing you want removed with the brush tool, and hey presto: new image. The results aren’t up to the standards of professionals, especially if the picture is particularly busy or complex, but they’re surprisingly good. The tool is also just quite fun to play around with. You can check out some examples in the gallery below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="84KptJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10826035"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ovc2Lt"&gt;Cleanup.pictures seems to be from the same team that made a fun augmented reality demo that lets you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246386/augmented-reality-ar-copy-cut-paste-real-world-photoshop-demo"&gt;“copy and paste” the real world&lt;/a&gt;, and is open-source (you can find the underlying code &lt;a href="https://github.com/initml/cleanup.pictures"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Obviously, tools of this sort have long been available, dating back at least to the launch of Photoshop’s Clone Stamp tool, but the quality of these automated programs has increased considerably in recent years thanks to AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxRgDl"&gt;Machine learning systems are now not only better at the problem of segmentation (marking the divisions between an object and the background) but also inpainting, or filling in the new content. Just last week, Google launched its new Pixel 6 tools &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22727944/google-pixel-6-pro-cameras-computational-photography-features"&gt;with an identical “Magic Eraser” feature&lt;/a&gt;, but Cleanup.pictures shows how this feature has become a commodity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLmoA5"&gt;I think my favorite use of this tool, though, is this fantastic series of pictures removing the people from Edward Hopper paintings: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iIFlB4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Playing with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LaMa?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#LaMa&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cyrildiagne?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@cyrildiagne&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://t.co/7vKPhbkHbl"&gt;https://t.co/7vKPhbkHbl&lt;/a&gt; integration and Edward Hopper’s paintings • a thread   &lt;a href="https://t.co/AegvUs7dMD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/AegvUs7dMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sylvain Filoni (@fffiloni) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fffiloni/status/1452346043325198343?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="VIJ0Ub"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/6aGnPeZB4w"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6aGnPeZB4w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sylvain Filoni (@fffiloni) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fffiloni/status/1452346841694187532?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744431/remove-edit-objects-images-photos-ai-free-cleanup-pictures"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744431/remove-edit-objects-images-photos-ai-free-cleanup-pictures</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-25T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-25T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Inside Facebook’s struggle to keep young people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CnHYnQ97Awli9RgRIXKsSldP00I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70040973/acastro_211024_4821_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The world’s largest social network is internally grappling with an existential crisis: an aging user base&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="OO8X8q"&gt;Earlier this year, a researcher at Facebook shared some alarming statistics with colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XBRnqM"&gt;Teenage users of the Facebook app in the US had declined by 13 percent since 2019 and were projected to drop 45 percent over the next two years, driving an overall decline in daily users in the company’s most lucrative ad market. Young adults between the ages of 20 and 30 were expected to decline by 4 percent during the same timeframe. Making matters worse, the younger a user was, the less on average they regularly engaged with the app. The message was clear: Facebook was losing traction with younger generations fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9HS06Y"&gt;The “aging up issue is real,” the researcher wrote in an internal memo. They predicted that, if “increasingly fewer teens are choosing Facebook as they grow older,” the company would face a more “severe” decline in young users than it already projected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="nGqcq3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The “aging up issue is real”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B6J1i6"&gt;The findings, echoed by other internal documents and my conversations with current and former employees, show that Facebook sees its aging user base as an existential threat to the long-term health of its business and that it’s trying desperately to correct the problem with little indication that its strategy will work. If it doesn’t correct course, the 17-year-old social network could, for the first time, lose out on an entire generation. And while Instagram remains incredibly popular with teens, Facebook’s own data shows that they are starting to engage with the app less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V80Ktw"&gt;The internal documents are part of disclosures made to the Securities and Exchange Commission and provided to Congress in redacted form by legal counsel for Frances Haugen, an ex-Facebook employee turned prominent whistleblower. A consortium of news organizations, including &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, has obtained the redacted versions received by Congress. Some documents &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;served as the basis for earlier reporting in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M29wOz"&gt;Facebook’s struggle to attract users under the age of 30 has been ongoing for years, dating back to as early as 2012. But according to the documents, the problem has grown more severe recently. And the stakes are high. While it famously started as a networking site for college students, employees have predicted that the aging up of the app’s audience — now nearly 2 billion daily users — has the potential to further alienate young people, cutting off future generations and putting a ceiling on future growth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvK1m5"&gt;The problem explains why the company has taken such a keen interest in courting young people and even pre-teens to its main app and Instagram, spinning up dedicated youth teams to cater to them. In 2017, it debuted a standalone Messenger app for kids, and its plans for a version of Instagram for kids were recently shelved after lawmakers decried the initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v0f9O5"&gt;At the same time, a rising crop of younger social networks has continued growing in popularity with young people — a phenomenon Facebook has closely tracked with its own research. In an internal presentation earlier this year, employees estimated that teens spend 2–3x more time on TikTok than on Instagram and that Snapchat is the preferred method of communicating with best friends for young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aoIhKQ"&gt;“Our products are still widely used by teens, but we face tough competition from the likes of Snapchat and TikTok,” Joe Osborne, a Facebook spokesperson, said in response to questions about the documents cited in this story. “All social media companies want teens to use their services. We are no different.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="XhZgB3"&gt;Declining numbers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="zQPe7V"&gt;In March of this year, a team of data scientists at Facebook presented the company’s chief product officer, Chris Cox, with “heath scorecards” for Facebook and Instagram’s usage among teens and young adults. Instagram was still strong with young people but losing engagement in key markets, including the US, Australia, and Japan. And the age of Facebook’s user base was increasing rapidly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="lEqwmu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A wide range of negative associations with Facebook”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ek8GxR"&gt;“Most young adults perceive Facebook as a place for people in their 40s and 50s,” according to the presentation. “Young adults perceive content as boring, misleading, and negative. They often have to get past irrelevant content to get to what matters.” It added that they “have a wide range of negative associations with Facebook including privacy concerns, impact to their wellbeing, along with low awareness of relevant services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5PCMc"&gt;The March presentation to Cox showed that, in the US, “teen acquisition is low and regressing further.” Account registrations for users under 18 were down 26 percent from the previous year in the app’s five top countries. For teens already on Facebook, the company was continuing to “see lower or worsening levels of engagement compared to older cohorts.” Messages sent by teens were down 16 percent from the previous year, while messages sent by users aged 20–30 were flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VCIZEg"&gt;A “particularly concerning trend,” according to one slide, was that time spent in the Facebook app by young people in the US had declined from the period before the onset of the coronavirus pandemic last year, when usage of Facebook’s services momentarily spiked across the board. Another slide described “addressing the existing engagement gap” between younger and older users, saying that people older than 30 in the US were spending, on average, 24 more minutes per day on Facebook than younger users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="VDjWdB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Average age will continue to increase, potentially disengaging younger users even more”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hiGceE"&gt;Facebook internally measures its user base against population estimates from the United Nations for specific countries. If the social network has the same amount of monthly users in an age bracket as what the estimates say for that region, it’s fully saturated. The presentation to Cox explained that the average Facebook user age “has been increasing disproportionately to the average population age over time. If this continues, [the Facebook app’s] average age will continue to increase, potentially disengaging younger users even more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pdkNp"&gt;Instagram was doing better with young people, with full saturation in the US, France, the UK, Japan, and Australia. But there was still cause for concern. Posting by teens had dropped 13 percent from 2020 and “remains the most concerning trend,” the researchers noted, adding that the increased use of TikTok by teens meant that “we are likely losing our total share of time.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="XnThD8"&gt;Product sprint&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oKH7LE5L9uQLFR60bqw6GS-kB0w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22952507/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_10.05.30_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An image from a section of an internal Facebook presentation from earlier this year called “Teen Fundamentals.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SDSTvJ"&gt;To address the growing crisis, employees at Facebook and Instagram have, for the past year, been planning a slew of products tailored for teens and young adults, according to the internal documents. But they recognize that it’s going to be an uphill battle on both platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wTBhOv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A brand tax we need to get ahead of”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G1RdOf"&gt;Young adults “feel Facebook shouldn’t be the place for rants and charged opinions, even though it seems prevalent on the platform,” according to a November 2020 strategy document about targeting young adults. “External forces such as negative media coverage further tarnish this perception,” it continued, equating to “a brand tax we need to get ahead of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iRP6gT"&gt;In order to address the “significant risk” of young adults engaging less and less with Facebook over time, employees last November identified two “beached” areas of focus, allowing “us to establish credibility and gain trust for extension into future areas” like mental health products. They laid out a multi-year plan to “enable young adults to connect with mentors for professional guidance” and “engage in meaningful conversations around causes to take action locally with others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bKZ0Sm"&gt;Planned features included asking young people to update their friend networks to make them more relevant since their connections “are often dormant and they struggle to realize any value” from them after collecting hundreds of friends over the years. They began work to tweak the News Feed algorithm specifically for young adults, with the goal of testing the change as early as the second half of this year, in order to show them “unconnected” content from accounts they didn’t choose to follow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u4pgAI"&gt;The employees also discussed letting young people set different profile identities that were specific to certain Facebook groups. Other products included a more visual version of the News Feed tentatively called Spotlight and “mood feeds” to increase “visitation and engagement.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Js4S3JCNXYM5muWYLz8Z9LSsGg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22952536/Screen_Shot_2021_10_24_at_6.10.25_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design examples of Facebook features geared toward young people from November of last year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HMuxnE"&gt;The documents show that, as part of its youth push, Facebook has been working on an unreleased version of Facebook Groups called Groups+, slated in the November document to begin testing as soon as this year, that is intended to let people join groups for specific personalities and “close-knit communities” as a way to “increase cultural relevance.” A whole pillar of products targeting people between the ages of 20 and 30 is focused on competing with LinkedIn, allowing people to host resumes and browse for jobs or career advice in a specialized feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mvrJwo"&gt;Joe Osborne, the Facebook spokesperson, said, “We continuously explore new products and experiences for people, but these efforts either evolved or never left the exploration phase.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="ZEQUBy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Seven percent of teens report experiencing bullying on Instagram&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uUvsqP"&gt;For Instagram, much of the product work targeting young people has recently focused on reducing the negative experiences of social comparison and bullying that they report. A presentation from earlier this year said that 7 percent of teens report experiencing bullying on Instagram and that 40 percent of all bullying happened in private messages. Other internal research documents, some of which were earlier &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739?mod=article_inline"&gt;reported on by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, show that teens have told the company they experience negative social comparison and even depression from using Instagram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hk0xVX"&gt;Sixty-one percent of new teen accounts on Instagram choose to make their profiles private on initial setup, the presentation said, adding that Instagram employees wanted to make “nudging” product tweaks to encourage more young users to set their accounts to private. The documents show that secondary, private “finsta” accounts have also been exploding in popularity, especially among Instagram’s youngest users — behavior that employees want to encourage as a way to retain young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YjhumCAD3PMICC-0zRRAFSpfRjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22952531/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_10.05.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook’s researchers have internally set up an ongoing workstream to understand teens and what they want, as detailed in part here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yqMmx5"&gt;“Teens seek a way to connect with their friends, but don’t want to share with all their followers,” the company’s researchers wrote in one recent document. “They want to easily share with just the people that they trust so that they feel seen, accepted, and validated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATBljo"&gt;Attracting young people and keeping them engaged remains top of mind inside Instagram. Adam Mosseri, the head of the app, in May told employees that Instagram’s goal is to be “a place where young people define themselves and the future,” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/16/technology/instagram-teens.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="3Fwl9G"&gt;An uncertain future&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EClbAWE9lwUN8K3T6Bzy1mPNU_s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22952487/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_1.28.10_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A slide from an internal Facebook presentation earlier this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5XzXNa"&gt;Losing young people wasn’t always the existential threat for the blue Facebook app that it is now, according to Michael Sayman, a 25-year-old former product manager for youth products who joined the company in 2014 when he was just 17. With the rise of selfie cameras in phones, social apps became more visual while Facebook stayed mostly focused on text posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5B8tEM"&gt;Copying Stories from Snapchat — which reduced the pressure people feel to share everyday snippets of their lives by making them disappear — has helped keep younger users on Instagram, as has encouraging the use of multiple accounts. But Facebook’s use by young people has stayed on a consistent decline. By the time Sayman left in 2017, “the company had understood very clearly the importance,” he told me. “It’s an entire generation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVblDA"&gt;Nowadays, teens are increasingly flocking to more immersive, social game platforms like &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; or Sayman’s current employer, &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt;. These 3D worlds with custom avatars appeal to young people who are looking to be online without the pressure of people judging their appearance or surroundings. And while a lot of traditional social media can feel like a performance, these virtual game worlds are fun. Incidentally, Facebook is planning to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"&gt;rebrand its corporate name&lt;/a&gt; to focus on the metaverse, which could partly be an effort to try to appeal to young people again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="qKPux8"&gt;For now, Facebook isn’t even sure if its plans to win back young people are enough. As the March presentation to Cox bluntly said: “We believe it’s too early to assess the effectiveness of our current suite of big bets for teens on Instagram and young adults on Facebook, and whether they are sufficient given the current competitive landscape.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
