<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-08T15:28:24-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:28:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:28:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oprah’s Meghan and Harry interview exemplifies Paramount Plus’ streaming challenges</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tpjYxbQc45qYGJl0CG1u9tJT4CA=/72x0:857x523/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931575/oprah_harrrymeghan.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TP9PxQ"&gt;Two of the biggest entertainment events of the weekend &lt;em&gt;could &lt;/em&gt;have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22315338/paramount-plus-hands-on-nickleodeon-mtv-streaming-tv-movies"&gt;Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt; exclusives: Oprah’s highly anticipated interview with Meghan Markle and Prince Harry, and Eddie Murphy’s eagerly awaited &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22314289/coming-2-america-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, the former is now only &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cbs.com%2Fshows%2Foprah-with-meghan-and-harry-a-cbs-primetime-special%2Fvideo%2Fi6UW_WTQjLrEeOoObMmlwrFLTTypvuZm%2Fcbs-presents-oprah-with-meghan-and-harry-a-primetime-special%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22319711%2Foprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available on CBS’s website (free)&lt;/a&gt; and the latter is streaming exclusively on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5V0fyQ"&gt;For a company whose executives just touted the vital importance of leaning into streaming, having launched Paramount Plus within days of the interview and film being released, not finding a way to have one or the other — or both, ideally — available on demand is head-scratch worthy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FlEXfr"&gt;One absence is more understandable than the other. Harpo (Oprah’s production company) did not make the streaming video on-demand rights available to ViacomCBS, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has learned. The interview was available on Paramount Plus as live programming, but there’s no replay available for subscribers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wbilif"&gt;Their interview became the most streamed event outside of NFL games and the Super Bowl, according to ViacomCBS, but without any context, that statement doesn’t provide any accurate measurement. The interview also garnered an average of 17.1 million linear viewers on Sunday (a truly impressive number considering appointment television becomes more and more of a relic with each new streaming service). Based on that figure, and conversation on social media, it was a pretty big deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Oi6AuP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a short-term sacrifice play&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oV5w22"&gt;ViacomCBS actually made out quite well even without the interview being on Paramount Plus. The special brought in roughly $325,000 for a 30-second ad, &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2021-03-08/oprah-winfreys-interview-with-meghan-and-harry-draws-17-million-viewers-on-cbs"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and is now playing ad-supported on CBS’s website and app. (The rights for something airing as a digital video on a free site and the rights to have it as an exclusive title for a longer period of time on a streaming service are different.) This means the interview could wind up on a different streaming service, but CBS’s digital website will have the interview for 30 days. All of which is great for CBS’s traditional television business, but not great for a company that has spent the last year touting the importance of its brand-new streaming platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hqbjFc"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kvanaren/status/1368927262159106051"&gt;Kathryn VanArendonk tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “Imagine launching a streaming service, having a wildly popular interview that same week available only through your streaming service, and then having the interview disappear from your platform entirely the second it’s done airing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tXBBS9"&gt;It’s a short-term sacrifice play. Obviously, ViacomCBS would have liked to own the streaming rights to drive subscribers to Paramount Plus. But ViacomCBS did not have the upper hand. If CBS passed, Harpo could have gone to ABC (Disney) or NBC (Comcast) instead. Plus, based on a quick Google Trends search and scrolling through Twitter, people did sign up for Paramount Plus through the free trial for the interview. The question is whether or not people will stick around after those initial seven days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CEZ31m"&gt;Remember, the key to understanding most companies’ streaming philosophies is exciting new content brings subscribers in, but it’s fan-favorite TV series and films that keep people paying month after month. That’s what makes the decision to not carry &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;, the sequel to Eddie Murphy’s &lt;em&gt;Coming to America&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;even more confounding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZOBDS"&gt;Some important context to consider: ViacomCBS sold the film to Amazon in October during a period when the company was selling off a number of its films while theaters were closed or operating at limited capacity. &lt;em&gt;Trial of the Chicago 7 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Lovebirds&lt;/em&gt; both went to Netflix, netting Paramount &lt;a href="https://www.thewrap.com/inside-paramounts-2020-survival-strategy-earn-more-selling-off-films-than-releasing-them/"&gt;between $75 and $85 million for both&lt;/a&gt;. Paramount also sold &lt;em&gt;Without Remorse &lt;/em&gt;to Amazon, alongside &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Yv3QZA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Paramount has been dysfunctional for 15 years, but...I’m speechless at how inept and stupid Paramount has been”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w1lF4F"&gt;For several of the films, it made sense. CBS All Access wasn’t a major investment for ViacomCBS compared to Paramount Plus, and the company needed to generate revenue for movies just sitting on a shelf. The majority of these movies also came out prior to Paramount Plus’ launch. If the original intention was to release &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America &lt;/em&gt;between mid-December and January, why not just push it back to March and make it a debut title?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wbu580"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America &lt;/em&gt;was released the same weekend as Paramount Plus. It could have been used to bring in subscribers, like &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place II &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible 7&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;are leaving movie theaters early and landing on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299995/mission-impossible-7-quiet-place-2-paramount-plus-45-days-after-theaters"&gt;Paramount Plus just 45 days after release&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of leveraging the film, ViacomCBS wound up competing with Amazon for attention. Not having the movie is one less reason for people to sign up for Paramount Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gz07UR"&gt;As one former executive at a rival studio told &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;“Paramount has been dysfunctional for 15 years, but ... I’m speechless at how inept and stupid Paramount has been.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keOIAF"&gt;Oh, and in terms of where Oprah’s interview with Meghan and Harry might end up after all is said and done? Keep an eye &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307034/discovery-plus-ambient-tv-hgtv-food-tlc-house-hunters-90-day-fiance-diners-driveins-dives"&gt;on Discovery Plus&lt;/a&gt;. Oprah has a stake in the company, and OWN is part of the Discovery family. It’s just the thing Discovery Plus would love to have. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319711/oprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319711/oprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Waymo simulated real-world crashes to prove its self-driving cars can prevent deaths</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Self-propelled car from Google sister company Waymo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NVwx5nXD54BFAwB3wzKXG82EOlE=/53x0:3568x2343/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931331/1142125645.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrej Sokolow / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HLNS4K"&gt;In a bid to prove that its robot drivers are safer than humans, Waymo simulated dozens of real-world fatal crashes that took place in Arizona over nearly a decade. The Google spinoff discovered that replacing either vehicle in a two-car crash with its robot-guided minivans would nearly eliminate all deaths, &lt;a href="https://blog.waymo.com/2021/03/replaying-real-life.html"&gt;according to data it publicized today&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hikKa"&gt;The results are meant to bolster Waymo’s case that autonomous vehicles operate more safely than human-driven ones. With millions of people dying in auto crashes globally every year, AV operators are increasingly leaning on this safety case to spur regulators to pass legislation allowing more fully autonomous vehicles on the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0kpbb8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Waymo has turned to counterfactuals, or “what if?” scenarios&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Lp6Gn9"&gt;But that case has been difficult to prove out, thanks to the very limited number of autonomous vehicles operating on public roads today. To provide more statistical support for its argument, Waymo has turned to counterfactuals, or “what if?” scenarios, meant to showcase how its robot vehicles would react in real-world situations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1U9ouX"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/30/21538999/waymo-self-driving-car-data-miles-crashes-phoenix-google"&gt;the company published 6.1 million miles of driving data&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 and 2020, including 18 crashes and 29 near-miss collisions. In those incidents where its safety operators took control of the vehicle to avoid a crash, Waymo’s engineers simulated what would have happened had the driver not disengaged the vehicle’s self-driving system to generate a counterfactual. The company has also made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/21/20822755/waymo-self-driving-car-data-set-free-research"&gt;some of its data available to academic researchers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tq0Cfa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Waymo’s driverless car: ghost-riding in the back seat of a robot taxi","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/9/21000085/waymo-fully-driverless-car-self-driving-ride-hail-service-phoenix-arizona"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rAd8lP"&gt;That work in counterfactuals continues in this most recent data release. Through a third party, Waymo collected information on every fatal crash that took place in Chandler, Arizona, a suburban community outside Phoenix, between 2008 and 2017. Focusing just on the crashes that took place within its operational design domain, or the approximately 100-square-mile area in which the company permits its cars to drive, Waymo identified 72 crashes to reconstruct in simulation in order to determine how its autonomous system would respond in similar situations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qHiKCb"&gt;
&lt;iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="Waymo Simulated Driving Behavior in Reconstructed Collisions" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/497900366/content?start_page=1&amp;amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;amp;access_key=key-tnzKLmhnZfzquBqFRKcp" tabindex="0" data-auto-height="true" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488" scrolling="no" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p style="   margin: 12px auto 6px auto;   font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif;   font-style: normal;   font-variant: normal;   font-weight: normal;   font-size: 14px;   line-height: normal;   font-size-adjust: none;   font-stretch: normal;   -x-system-font: none;   display: block;"&gt;&lt;a title="View Waymo Simulated Driving Behavior in Reconstructed Collisions on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F497900366%2FWaymo-Simulated-Driving-Behavior-in-Reconstructed-Collisions%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22315361%2Fwaymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Waymo Simulated Driving Beh...&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title="View ahawkins8223's profile on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fuser%2F112638498%2Fahawkins8223%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22315361%2Fwaymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ahawkins8223&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VNA8a6"&gt;Some of these crashes involved one vehicle, while most involved two. For crashes with two vehicles, Waymo ran separate experiments simulating its autonomous vehicles in the role of each vehicle — first replacing the vehicle that initiated the crash and then replacing the vehicle that responded to the other vehicle’s actions. For crashes with one vehicle, Waymo only simulated the single vehicle. That left it with 91 simulations in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fgYq7o"&gt;The company reconstructed these crashes, systematically aligning the vehicle’s trajectory to make sure its Waymo vehicles are exposed to a similar situation than in the actual fatal crash. Waymo used the same simulation platform it uses to train and evaluate its autonomous vehicles on virtual roads in ordinary operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="UU2PG4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Waymo’s AVs “avoided or mitigated” 88 out of 91 total simulations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aFwmwg"&gt;The results show that Waymo’s autonomous vehicles would have “avoided or mitigated” 88 out of 91 total simulations, said Trent Victor, director of safety research and best practices at Waymo. Moreover, for the crashes that were mitigated, Waymo’s vehicles would have reduced the likelihood of serious injury by a factor of 1.3 to 15 times, Victor said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tLXYdt"&gt;“That means that even if it didn’t avoid the crash completely, it took action to reduce the severity of the impact,” Victor said. “If the severity was reduced, it made it less likely that the driver would have died.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hr12D2"&gt;When Waymo replaced the vehicle responding to the instigator of the crash, it found that it “completely avoided” 82 percent of simulated crashes — the vast majority of which without the need for hard braking or evasive action. In another 10 percent as a responder, the Waymo vehicle’s urgent maneuvers helped mitigate the severity of the crash. Those crashes all took place at an intersection where the other vehicle either turned left across or cut straight across the Waymo vehicle’s path, leaving little time to react, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUpin5"&gt;“We’re not saying that we will eliminate all fatalities, but we are saying that the best way to reduce the chances of a serious injury would be to take an evasive maneuver when that’s possible,” Victor said. “And in all of these crash simulations, the Waymo driver took evasive maneuvers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CBEwbp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Waymo driver took evasive maneuvers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rvhI5J"&gt;There were three incidents of a person dying after being rear-ended by another vehicle. In simulation, Waymo was not able to avoid these crashes when its vehicle was the one being rear-ended. “In rear crashes specifically, there’s not a lot that the responder role can do,” said Matthew Schwall, head of field safety at Waymo. “So the Waymo driver really suffers from the same challenge that humans do in those situations, that it’s hard to make the prediction soon enough to be able to make an evasive maneuver.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n0KMlQ"&gt;Twenty simulated crashes involved a pedestrian or cyclist being struck by a driver. Waymo’s autonomous vehicles avoided 100 percent of those crashes in simulation, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3QpdpF"&gt;There’s no standard approach for evaluating AV safety. &lt;a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RRA569-1.html"&gt;A recent study by RAND&lt;/a&gt; concluded that, in the absence of a framework, customers are most likely to trust the government — even though US &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/15/21292014/dot-nhtsa-self-driving-car-test-data-voluntary"&gt;regulators appear content to let the private sector dictate what’s safe&lt;/a&gt;. In this vacuum, Waymo hopes that by publicizing this data, policymakers, researchers, and even other companies may begin to take on the task of developing a universal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3pTce"&gt;To be sure, Waymo did not make its findings subject to a peer-reviewed analysis for publication in an academic or scientific journal, though it would be open to publishing it in the future, a spokesperson said. The simulations were not conducted independently of the company, nor were they reviewed by any third-party for verification prior to the company making them public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8FRH0"&gt;The company did share its findings with a select group of academic experts to get their reactions. Daniel McGehee, director of the National Advanced Driving Simulator Laboratories at the University of Iowa, said Waymo is pushing safety analyses and transparency “to a new level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZugPly"&gt;Jonas Bargman, associate professor for vehicle safety at Chalmers University of Technology in Sweden, said that Waymo’s use of simulation-based assessment is at “the scientific forefront” but only one of the components needed to assess the safety of automated vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TpRWgw"&gt;After reviewing the report, Bargman concluded that the “Waymo simulation platform is highly sophisticated,” citing the company’s 3D sensor-level perception models. He singled out the use of counterfactual what-if scenarios as “highly relevant for the introduction of Waymo self-driving vehicles to the public.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315361/waymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315361/waymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T14:06:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T14:06:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>The OnePlus 9 will ship with a charger in the box</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uyUctkxardGhhhakJHbRklfKNwo=/178x0:2244x1377/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930940/oneplus_9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The OnePlus 9 will be formally announced March 23rd. | Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ufKkK5"&gt;Along with a confirmed release date, we got our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/oneplus/status/1368851473698746375?s=20"&gt;first official look at the OnePlus 9&lt;/a&gt; today and another tidbit of information: it will come with a charger, unlike recent flagships including the Galaxy S21 and iPhone 12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P0c1XG"&gt;In a message thread on the company’s community forum, OnePlus CEO Pete Lau &lt;a href="https://forums.oneplus.com/threads/something-new-is-on-the-horizon-what-is-it.1396347/page-28#post-22835224"&gt;said that the 9 will ship with a charger&lt;/a&gt; in the box. Recently, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22225930/samsung-galaxy-s21-no-charger-brick-headphones-price"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; stopped including chargers with their flagship devices, citing environmental benefits and saying that customers already had the adaptors anyway. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519466/apple-iphone-12-chargers-airpods-greenhouse-gas-emissions-e-waste"&gt;jury’s still out on the environmental impact&lt;/a&gt; of the move, but it’s sure to have helped the companies’ bottom lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5aj1C"&gt;OnePlus is in a slightly different position, of course. One of its phones’ differentiating features has been fast wired charging. The OnePlus 9 is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213390/oneplus-9-pro-45-watt-wireless-charging-reverse"&gt;rumored to include 45W fast charging&lt;/a&gt; and would be no exception. Including a charger that allows customers to take advantage of that feature only makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XBdrnM"&gt;While there have been plenty of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174437/oneplus-9-photos-leak-2021-flagship"&gt;credible-looking leaks and rumors&lt;/a&gt;, we still don’t have many confirmed details about the upcoming OnePlus 9 — but that will change soon. OnePlus announced today that the 9 series &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315517/oneplus-9-launch-date-hasselblad-camera"&gt;will debut on March 23rd&lt;/a&gt;. The company also confirmed a three-year partnership with Hasselblad to collaborate on future OnePlus device cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319657/oneplus-9-charger-in-box-pete-lau-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319657/oneplus-9-charger-in-box-pete-lau-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T13:42:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T13:42:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Six Days in Fallujah publisher now says the game is ‘inseparable from politics’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LVwYuWojaiGWlXOnbG1wZ8kLJ-w=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930732/60234401ada8b46523757a8f_SDIF_BreachStack_1080p_p_800.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Victura&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MfOP9x"&gt;Nearly a month after distancing itself from political statements, the publisher of the controversial military shooter &lt;em&gt;Six Days in Fallujah &lt;/em&gt;has backtracked and now says the events in the game are “inseparable from politics.” The game, which takes place during the Iraq War’s Second Battle of Fallujah, has come under scrutiny for seemingly portraying a US-centric focus on a campaign in which an estimated 800 Iraqi civilians were killed, &lt;a href="http://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1967340_1967350_1967530,00.html"&gt;according to the Red Cross&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0vR0Cw"&gt;“We understand the events recreated in &lt;em&gt;Six Days in Fallujah&lt;/em&gt; are inseparable from politics,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VicturaGG/status/1368924485676527623"&gt;publisher Victura said in a statement on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. “We believe the stories of this generation’s sacrifices deserve to be told by the Marines, Soldiers, and civilians who were there,” Victura’s statement continued. “We trust you will find the game — like the events it recreates — to be complex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oPZbBQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We understand the events recreated in Six Days in Fallujah are inseparable from politics. &lt;a href="https://t.co/N7nkPilp1Q"&gt;pic.twitter.com/N7nkPilp1Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Victura (@VicturaGG) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VicturaGG/status/1368924485676527623?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tphpnT"&gt;The statement follows comments from Victura’s founder and CEO Peter Tamte about how one of the goals of &lt;em&gt;Six Days in Fallujah &lt;/em&gt;is to help players empathize with the decisions American troops made during the war and not “make a political commentary.” Tamte, in an &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/15/22279600/six-days-in-fallujah-interview-iraq-war-politics?utm_campaign=polygon.social&amp;amp;utm_content=polygon&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="UskFyo"&gt;“For us as a team, it is really about helping players understand the complexity of urban combat. It’s about the experiences of that individual that is now there because of political decisions. And we do want to show how choices that are made by policymakers affect the choices that [a Marine] needs to make on the battlefield. Just as that [Marine] cannot second-guess the choices by the policymakers, we’re not trying to make a political commentary about whether or not the war itself was a good or a bad idea.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Jc8sRK"&gt;The game uses a mix of military shooter gameplay and documentary segments to tell its story, based on information from “26 Iraqi civilians and dozens of service members [who] have shared the most difficult moments of their lives,” according to Victura. Much of the game will focus on playing as soldiers, but there are also “&lt;a href="https://www.sixdays.com/faq"&gt;high-intensity stealth missions&lt;/a&gt;” where you play as an unarmed Iraqi civilian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7kyciL"&gt;And while those missions are “informed by” the interviews with Iraqi civilians, &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;very few people are curious what it’s like to be an Iraqi civilian,” Tamte said in a February interview with &lt;a href="http://gamesindustry.biz/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GamesIndustry.biz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;“Nobody’s going to play that game,” he added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uVyxMN"&gt;“Ultimately, the reason why people are going to play this game is because they want a more realistic combat experience,” he continued. “That above all else is the experience that we must deliver.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eilaeW"&gt;The game was first announced &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/stories/six-days-in-fallujah-announced-127714.phtml"&gt;in April 2009&lt;/a&gt;, but its concept was &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/konamis-fallujah-game-under-fire_8"&gt;widely criticized&lt;/a&gt;. Konami, the game’s original publisher, &lt;a href="https://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/114311/Konami_Drops_Controversial_Six_Days_in_Fallujah.php"&gt;dropped it later that month&lt;/a&gt;. The game was re-announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278073/six-days-in-fallujah-revival-release-date-highwire-games"&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt;, now being developed by &lt;a href="https://highwiregames.com/"&gt;Highwire Games&lt;/a&gt;, whose co-founders include &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; veterans Jaime Griesemer and Marty O’Donnell, formerly of Bungie. Victura’s Tamte also worked at Bungie, leading the marketing of the first &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, according to his LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BziuYn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Six Days in Fallujah&lt;/em&gt; is coming to PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X / S, and Windows, targeting a release “late in 2021,” &lt;a href="https://www.sixdays.com/faq"&gt;according to an FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319581/six-days-in-fallujah-publisher-inseparable-politics-victura-highwire-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319581/six-days-in-fallujah-publisher-inseparable-politics-victura-highwire-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T13:41:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T13:41:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mark Zuckerberg says realistic avatars are Facebook’s next big VR bet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FJj3y0oba5HJ6KWPqd2KIDmYqJw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930728/akrales_200904_4160_0216.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ylVt8p"&gt;Facebook’s future virtual reality headsets should capture users’ facial expressions for more realistic digital avatars, says CEO Mark Zuckerberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pptj0H"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/mark-zuckerberg-on-mind-reading-apple-and-the-race-to-mainstream-vr?utm_source=ti_app"&gt;In a podcast interview for &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Zuckerberg expounded on the next decade in virtual and augmented reality, including future Oculus VR devices. “One of the things that I’m really excited about for future versions is getting eye tracking and face tracking in, because if you’re really excited about social presence, you want to make sure that the device has all the sensors to really kind of animate realistic avatars so you can communicate well like that,” Zuckerberg says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="SZNLhJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You want to make sure that the device has all the sensors to animate realistic avatars.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tQnIvo"&gt;Zuckerberg says hardware changes are a major focus for avatar-building. In VR, “the biggest things that we’re very focused on now are, how do you pack basically more sensors to create a better social experience into the device,” he says. “When I think about where you’re at with VR today, you go into the experience — there are some pretty good games and different experiences. But I’d love to get to the point where you have realistic avatars of yourself, where you can make real authentic eye contact with someone and have real expressions that get reflected on your avatar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8vSou"&gt;Facebook has released multiple iterations of VR avatars, and Zuckerberg says a new generation of avatars is on its way later this year, with more realistic versions beyond that. He compared his desired quality with Epic’s MetaHuman tool, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276265/epic-games-digital-human-creator-unreal-engine-realistic-human-faces"&gt;lets animators produce&lt;/a&gt; highly detailed virtual faces — but he wants Facebook to generate these kinds of avatars through machine learning at a large scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p2hV5x"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We don’t think that people are going to want to get their head drilled open in order to use virtual or augmented reality.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VFBDWK"&gt;Otherwise, &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;interview confirms several known areas of interest for Facebook. Zuckerberg indicates that Oculus is already envisioning “Quest 3 and 4” hardware — an indication that Facebook remains committed to the Quest standalone VR design for the near future. Facebook also has an active interest in augmented reality, with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439929/facebook-ar-smart-glasses-ray-ban-announcement"&gt;pair of smart glasses&lt;/a&gt; launching later this year, but Zuckerberg reiterates that they won’t have standard visual AR elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x0aO4G"&gt;He also discussed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/6/17433516/ctrl-labs-brain-computer-interface-armband-hands-on-preview"&gt;the Facebook acquisition of CTRL-Labs&lt;/a&gt;, which makes armbands that detect and interpret neural signals — a partial alternative to invasive brain-computer interfaces like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493224/elon-musk-neuralink-neuroscience-brain-machine"&gt;Elon Musk’s Neuralink&lt;/a&gt;. “We don’t think that people are going to want to get their head drilled open in order to use virtual or augmented reality,” Zuckerberg says. He notes that Neuralink has very real applications, particularly for medical technologies like prosthetic limbs. “But ultimately, I don’t think [that] is going to be part of a consumer product that gets offered anytime soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319737/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-vr-ar-face-sensors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319737/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-vr-ar-face-sensors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>WWE Network on Peacock: your questions answered</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E3e5QbY6TJgd478gk57EQigugNE=/0x13:2040x1373/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930505/wwepeacock.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Peacock&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tmBCSE"&gt;Peacock is sharing more details today about how it will integrate WWE’s enormous selection of content later this month when WWE Network becomes part of the NBCUniversal streaming service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZyXLOg"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248330/wwe-network-peacock-move-announced-date-price"&gt;announced in January&lt;/a&gt;, WWE’s new portal will launch on Peacock starting on March 18th. The standalone WWE Network app will shut down in the United States a few weeks later on April 4th. That means current subscribers will be able to use the old app for WWE’s upcoming &lt;em&gt;Fastlane&lt;/em&gt; pay-per-view this month if they want. But come &lt;em&gt;WrestleMania 37&lt;/em&gt;, which is happening on April 10th and 11th, Peacock will be the only choice. There’s no way to transfer a WWE Network subscription over to Peacock, but the company is offering wrestling fans &lt;a href="https://imp.i305175.net/c/482924/896950/11640?sharedid=VergeWWENetworkonPeacock03082021&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20200101evergreen&amp;amp;cid=20200101evergreenpdaffil001&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peacocktv.com%2FWWE"&gt;an exclusive deal&lt;/a&gt; to help ease the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Noaa2c"&gt;It will look like Peacock but feel familiar to WWE fans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aTvrWS"&gt;As for how Peacock plans to showcase WWE programming, you’ll notice a new “WWE” tab in the browse section. Once that’s selected, you’ll be shown the usual carousels of featured shows and curated events. This is all Peacock’s user interface, but the two companies are in constant communication about what content to highlight. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e_x37RHDDzX7ws-f5Smh9TsPgxQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353756/Screen_Shot_2021_03_08_at_10.24.05_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Peacock&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="B64F9s"&gt;Peacock has said it will eventually be home to pretty much everything available on WWE Network today — but the transition isn’t going to be instant. There will be some noticeable omissions in the early days. For the March 18th launch, Peacock subscribers will get access to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="o1myYj"&gt;Every PPV event in the last calendar year; current or most recent season episodes of WWE original series &lt;em&gt;Steve Austin’s The Broken Skull Sessions&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; WWE Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;WWE Icons&lt;/em&gt;; in-ring action with new weekly episodes of &lt;em&gt;NXT &lt;/em&gt;the day after air&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; as well as the 2021 replays of &lt;em&gt;RAW &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; SmackDown&lt;/em&gt; 30 days after air; groundbreaking documentaries, including &lt;em&gt;Undertaker: The Last Ride&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WWE 24&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; WWE Untold&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reality series, including &lt;em&gt;Total Bellas&lt;/em&gt;; as well as collections of featured series, topical moments like “Stone Cold” Steve Austin Week, and playlists showcasing current Superstars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5itV2K"&gt;You’ll be waiting a few months for all of those pay-per-views&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9w5SUf"&gt;Here’s the bad news: WWE Network’s huge vault of WWE, WCW, and ECW pay-per-views won’t be ready for day one. Instead, Peacock is promising to have all of that content available “before &lt;em&gt;SummerSlam&lt;/em&gt;,” which is in August. That means pro wrestling fans could go several weeks without any convenient way of watching those past events since the WWE Network app will be history in the US. (The international version will continue operating just as it does today.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SA2Wdi"&gt;The exception to this is WrestleMania; all previous WrestleMania events will be available at launch on Peacock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="drPyVy"&gt;Match markers are no more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JZUEkO"&gt;Another potential disappointment to frequent WWE Network viewers is that on-demand PPVs and shows will no longer be broken up with “markers” to separate them into several different segments that are easy to skip between. Instead, each will just be one long stream. (Peacock tells me it’s working on visual scrub bar previews to help viewers find what they want when fast-forwarding through WWE videos.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VggHjp"&gt;Search won’t be as comprehensive as it was on WWE Network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="RRSiDu"&gt;And last, search on Peacock won’t be as robust as it was on WWE Network. Whereas WWE Network would let you search for a specific match or WWE superstar right in the search bar, that’s not going to be the case on Peacock — at least initially. This is something fans can expect to improve in the months to come. But even then, it might not fully match what was possible on WWE Network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="48MjIg"&gt;Get a discount during WWE’s move to Peacock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="V1TS04"&gt;Peacock acknowledges that there’s more work to be done to satisfy WWE Network diehards. So to help sweeten the pot, &lt;a href="https://imp.i305175.net/c/482924/896950/11640?sharedid=VergeWWENetworkonPeacock03082021&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20200101evergreen&amp;amp;cid=20200101evergreenpdaffil001&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peacocktv.com%2FWWE"&gt;it will be offering an exclusive discount to WWE fans&lt;/a&gt;. They can get four months of Peacock Premium for a flat $9.99. That breaks down to $2.50 per month. Peacock Premium normally costs $4.99 monthly, which itself is still less than WWE Network’s longtime $9.99 / month subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o113Pz"&gt;There were always going to be compromises in this Peacock and WWE tag team, and I think I’ve covered the main ones that fans care about here. Cramming a service that was tailor-made for a very specific audience into a more mainstream streaming app comes with challenges. Also, remember we’re still talking about the launch experience; it’s possible Peacock will go back and add some of this functionality if customers are vocal enough. I’m also hoping that other features WWE Network never really got around to (like offline downloads) will be made a reality on Peacock. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22319438/wwe-network-peacock-features-price-faq-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22319438/wwe-network-peacock-features-price-faq-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T12:57:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T12:57:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hummer’s electric SUV will be revealed on April 3rd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kycUHqVxa1EkZRq8e6OIKVmx56Q=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930471/GMC_HUMMER_EV_SUV_Debut.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: GM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C1ADPX"&gt;General Motors will reveal an SUV version of its all-electric Hummer EV on April 3rd, the company announced. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;The automaker unveiled the pickup truck version&lt;/a&gt;, with 350 miles of range and a host of high-tech features, last October. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ub8cTc"&gt;GM, which is producing the electric Hummers under its GMC brand, wouldn’t say when the SUV is expected to go into production. The electric pickup truck will start assembly at the end of this year, with the highest spec trim level available to customers first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JdLgL4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company is highlighting the EV’s off-roading capabilities as a way to align with the all-important truck market&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j53aMb"&gt;GMC also &lt;a href="https://media.gmc.com/media/us/en/gmc/home.detail.html/content/Pages/news/us/en/2021/mar/0308-hummer.html"&gt;showed off its pre-production Hummer EV&lt;/a&gt; handling some snowy conditions in Michigan’s Upper Peninsula. The company is highlighting the EV’s off-roading capabilities as a way to align with the all-important truck market, which has been largely walled off from the electrification trend until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4gEMMP"&gt;GM retired the Hummer in 2010, after the global recession caused fuel prices to rise. Now, the company is reviving the brand as it pours billions of dollars into the development of dozens of new electric vehicles over the next few years. The company even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220574/gm-new-logo-electric-vehicle-brand-ces-2021"&gt;redesigned its logo&lt;/a&gt; to look more like an electrical plug to emphasize its pivot to battery-powered vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rWuRPs"&gt;The Hummer will be the first vehicle to be built on GM’s new electric battery platform, Ultium, offering power ranging from 50 to 200 kWh, allowing for a driving range up to “400 miles or more.” For trucks, the Ultium platform will include 800-volt battery packs and 350 kW fast-charging capability.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319617/hummer-ev-suv-reveal-date-gmc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319617/hummer-ev-suv-reveal-date-gmc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T12:24:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T12:24:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Dish will acquire Republic Wireless to boost adoption of its 5G network</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dish CES 2013 stock 1020" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vT4b1z_8LQ21vhIofV1Y4UMdnHw=/0x0:1020x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68930225/20130110-625A1517VERGE.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Nathan Ingraham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XzUfOf"&gt;Satellite television provider Dish Network has announced its plan to acquire cell carrier Republic Wireless, &lt;a href="https://about.dish.com/2021-03-08-DISH-to-acquire-Republic-Wireless"&gt;Dish said on Monday&lt;/a&gt;. The acquisition, when it closes, will give Dish roughly 200,000 wireless customers to help boost its 5G network, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295777/dish-network-5g-q3-2021"&gt;Dish plans to launch later this year&lt;/a&gt;. Financial terms of the deal were not disclosed, but Dish says Republic Wireless customers won’t see any immediate changes to their plans and won’t have to take any action on their accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADtNcx"&gt;Dish became a major player in the telecom business last year when it finalized its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;purchase of Sprint’s Boost Mobile business&lt;/a&gt; for $1.4 billion, as part of a sale Sprint was required to make to merge with T-Mobile. Dish has since signaled its intentions to launch a 5G network in the US by buying up costly spectrum and acquiring small cell carriers, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352496/dish-ting-mobile-acquisition-tucows-network-tech"&gt;Ting Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, to acquire the necessary technology and the customer base to turn its investments into viable future businesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="woeYRT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Dish is building out a nationwide 5G network it plans to launch later this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FVeCGv"&gt;Republic Wireless is an MVNO, or a mobile virtual network operator, that leases network infrastructure from T-Mobile. Like the Ting acquisition, which gave Dish access to Ting parent company Tucows’ backend mobile services, the Republic Wireless acquisition will turn the carrier’s existing Relay division into a Dish asset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noMj40"&gt;“Relay provides communication and productivity solutions for frontline teams in hospitality, facilities management, manufacturing, healthcare and education,” the press release says, “and it will become a wholesale customer on Dish’s 5G network.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jRXeKX"&gt;“Republic has created a loyal following and established a brand known for innovation, customer service and value. We plan to build upon that strong foundation,” Dish COO John Swieringa said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319621/dish-network-acquires-republic-wireless-5g-cell-carrier-mvno-t-mobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319621/dish-network-acquires-republic-wireless-5g-cell-carrier-mvno-t-mobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T11:18:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T11:18:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>People who are vaccinated can socialize together without masks, CDC says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pfizer Covid-19 vaccination record card with masks, Minnesota." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oc-IWZC2MCZxtZTg8F6qNbk6aKM=/1x0:5200x3466/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68929828/1299968956.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael Siluk / Education Images / Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="apNvd1"&gt;People who are fully vaccinated against COVID-19 can gather indoors with other vaccinated people without masks, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said today. The recommendation is part of the &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/fully-vaccinated.html"&gt;long-awaited guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for how people who have received the shots can adjust their behavior. People who are vaccinated should still wear masks when they’re in public and while interacting with people who have not been vaccinated. They should also avoid large gatherings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TiOw9F"&gt;“A growing body of evidence now tells us that there are some activities that fully vaccinated people can resume at low risk to themselves,” CDC director Rochelle Walensky said during a press briefing today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="KOmFla"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XxGWYL"&gt;People are considered fully vaccinated two weeks after the second dose of the Moderna or Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine, and two weeks after the first dose of the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0RXI21"&gt;Those who are fully vaccinated can also gather indoors with unvaccinated people in other households as long as those unvaccinated people are at low risk for a severe case of COVID-19. “If grandparents have been vaccinated, they can visit their daughter and her family even if they have not been vaccinated, so long as the daughter and her family are not at risk for severe disease,” Walensky said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncXwQb"&gt;The CDC is not issuing new recommendations around travel at this time; people should still avoid unnecessary travel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N3FeNY"&gt;The agency was set to announce these guidelines last week, but it &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/03/03/cdc-vaccination-guidelines-473555"&gt;delayed the release&lt;/a&gt; because they were still being finalized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eOeici"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Single-shot COVID-19 vaccine is popular at vaccination sites ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315138/covid-vaccine-single-shot-johnson-distribution"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="yYCEDX"&gt;The three COVID-19 vaccines available in the US are highly protective against the disease and will help beat back the pandemic — but none are perfect. While there are still high levels of the coronavirus circulating through most communities in the US, there’s still a small chance someone who has been vaccinated could get sick. Variant forms of the virus that can spread more easily &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/transmission/variant-cases.html"&gt;have also been found in most states&lt;/a&gt;, and the vaccines are less effective against some of these variants. It’s also possible that someone who is vaccinated could still spread the disease to other people, even though they’re &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/opinion/covid-vaccines-transmission.html"&gt;less likely to&lt;/a&gt; than someone who has not been vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OZO3FD"&gt;Experts had been calling for the CDC to help people understand which protective measures they can relax after they’ve been vaccinated. Some worried that saying people &lt;em&gt;can’t &lt;/em&gt;change their behavior after vaccination &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/18/briefing/donald-trump-pardon-phil-spector-coronavirus-deaths.html"&gt;would discourage&lt;/a&gt; people from getting vaccinated, even though that would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300783/covid-vaccine-guidelines-cdc-safety-normal-life"&gt;likely be a small percentage&lt;/a&gt; of people who are vaccine-hesitant. “I understand the impulse to be cautious, but there is a cost to waiting,” public health expert Leana Wen &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/03/05/where-is-cdcs-guidance-vaccinated-americans/"&gt;wrote in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2EvzK"&gt;The CDC &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276905/covid-vaccine-quarantine-symptoms-test"&gt;already said&lt;/a&gt; people who are fully vaccinated do not have to quarantine if they’re exposed to someone with the disease unless they develop symptoms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w7MDVc"&gt;The guidelines will continue to evolve as more people become vaccinated, Walensky said. “Like you, I want to be able to return to everyday activities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYAnqw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319514/vaccinated-people-vaccines-cdc-mask-coronavirus-social-guidelines"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319514/vaccinated-people-vaccines-cdc-mask-coronavirus-social-guidelines</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The pirate assembling a better sports streaming service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zknLWcRdxQ5ctTcvKaUFqx0heqM=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68919405/VRG_ILLO_4427_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="esBC7P"&gt;HeheStreams offers customers live broadcasts of every NBA game on television, so long as they follow these three easy steps. First things first; buy a $100 Amazon gift card. Next, where you’re supposed to fill out the email address and name of whoever it’s for, put in your own information. “Make no mention of HeheStreams, please,” asks the site’s owner. “We are not able to accept gift cards sent to us directly.” After completing the transaction, copy and paste the Amazon code that has arrived in your email account into an entry field on the HeheStreams website. The owner will also process Paypal and credit card transactions, but this, by far, is the preferred method. Once approved, the floodgates open up. Voila, basketball heaven, presented in glistening HD, at a significant discount compared to what the NBA itself is selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhcaWG"&gt;“One of the ways I’ve stayed alive is by avoiding a paper trail,” says the owner, who understandably wishes to remain anonymous, because he offers pirated access to four major sports leagues. “My predecessors were thriving for some time, but their payment processor kept getting tipped off and they’d stop processing their money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mqThFq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I just broke the fucking internet”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D88dFP"&gt;HeheStreams is a bootleg operation that offers live sports from the NBA, NHL, NFL, and MLB. The owner runs pretty much everything — the tech, the maintenance, and the social media accounts — all by himself. He says he founded the site in 2016 and went “premium,” by which he means he started charging money for access, in the fall of 2018. The owner won’t tell me exactly how many customers he has, but does say that he regards the service as something other than a purely moneymaking enterprise. In fact, he’s got a day job somewhere else. This is a hobby, first and foremost. “I don’t want it to blow up,” he explains. “I want it to remain just a side project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VBgfRK"&gt;It’s hard to blame him for that discretion. HeheStreams is breaking all sorts of copyright laws, which explains how it offers one of the best deals on the market. Its &lt;em&gt;legal&lt;/em&gt; equivalent, NBA League Pass, is priced at $200 a year and is subject to an arcane web of provincial bureaucracy. HeheStreams cuts the cost in half and isn’t hamstrung by any obligations to the cable powerbrokers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bIeD9C"&gt;That’s what makes HeheStreams such a draw for so many sports fans. Local blackout restrictions enforced by television contracts mean, for example, that New Yorkers can’t watch the Knicks on League Pass. Instead, if you’re located in the tri-state area, your only option is the niche MSG TV network. Does your TV package not carry MSG? Then you’re out of luck... unless you turn to something like HeheStreams. Pirate broadcasts might be a precarious enterprise, but for a lot of fans, they’re the easiest option on the table.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yb0q1Q"&gt;Obviously, the NBA and other leagues have a material interest in protecting their content. Bootleg sports streams are as old as the internet itself, but traditionally, they’re hosted on laggy, low-resolution video players cloaked with conspicuous banner ads. But the owner of HeheStreams has devised a way to redirect the official content distributed by the sports leagues through his own server. “I reverse-engineer the official services and give you their platform,” he explains. “I don’t middleman anything.” HeheStreams has a much lighter footprint than you may think, and it’s watchable on everything from an Amazon Fire TV Stick to an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ldUdZj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Hehe is like my streaming best friend”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ridoo9"&gt;“I just broke the fucking internet,” he says, when I ask about the fateful day where he discovered the crack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DwuHf"&gt;Obviously, there’s more to it than that. The owner notes that he has to have an “army” of different active streaming accounts to keep the content flowing. Whenever League Pass updates its internal infrastructure, the owner needs to hustle to identify and address all the security adjustments. “They don’t really give me a changelog,” he quips. “I’m not on their Jira boards, unfortunately.” The site also needs to alchemize the bespoke nature of the MLB, NHL, NBA, and NFL’s streaming apparatuses into a single service, which the owner says is a recurring challenge. This is a full-on coast-to-coast sports network, atomized down to a single person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Twv8dB"&gt;HeheStreams has developed something of a cult following among NBA diehards in particular. “Hehe is like my streaming best friend,” writes one user on the HeheStreams subreddit. “I’ll keep renewing until it’s no more,” adds another. “The only website subscription I feel good about paying into every year,” says a third. The loyalty runs deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zmtmTs"&gt;And who can blame them? We are living through an era of streaming hell right now. Every day, networks scramble for exclusive IP rights over decades-old sitcoms, causing an unsustainable bloat in our Roku menus. “Oh god, what the hell is Paramount Plus?” The contracts for live sports change hands like the weather, leading to an unending ambiguity over who, or what, will be allowed to carry Mets games each season. It really shouldn’t be this complicated, and yet the sedentary process of simply &lt;em&gt;watching stuff on the couch &lt;/em&gt;becomes more byzantine and annoying with each passing day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YhVQZZ"&gt;So it makes perfect sense that the world has gravitated toward a talented hacker who also loves the game of basketball. HeheStreams removes all of the tiresome questions about broadcast rights, and instead delivers us back to the good old days: when watching the game was as simple as turning on the TV.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22303642/hehestreams-pirate-sports-streaming-service-nba-nfl-mlb-nhl"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22303642/hehestreams-pirate-sports-streaming-service-nba-nfl-mlb-nhl</id>
    <author>
      <name>Luke Winkie</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
