<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-11T04:16:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T04:16:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T04:16:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valorant pro Sinatraa suspended following sexual assault allegations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sinatraa" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bx_xPbUJJpXSxw6varJaBfUkAD8=/58x0:901x562/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944072/unnamed.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Robert Paul / Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I5E1RK"&gt;Jay “Sinatraa” Won, one of the biggest names in competitive &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;, has been suspended from the game and by his team following accusations of sexual assault. In a statement &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cIe0h/status/1369497186740928512"&gt;posted on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, Cleo Hernandez posted a lengthy account of her nine-month-long relationship with Won, detailing a disturbing history of physical and emotional abuse, supported by audio recordings and screenshots of messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5dxGJ"&gt;“I have avoided talking about any aspects of me and Jay’s relationship for over a year,” Hernandez wrote. “I never spoke about it mostly because this is horrifying, and also because I’ve seen the way women in our community are treated when they try to talk about being hurt by prominent figures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XOTM5o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Gaming can’t fix its abuse problem one person at a time","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21307560/gaming-abuse-harassment-systemic-ubisoft-chris-avellone"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wVPK4m"&gt;Won is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20950550/sinatraa-interview-overwatch-league-mvp-san-francisco-shock-e-sports"&gt;a former &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League MVP&lt;/a&gt; who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/28/21240497/overwatch-league-sinatraa-leaving-sf-shock-valorant"&gt;made the switch to &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;. Since Hernandez’s accusations, developer Riot has suspended Won from the game, stating that he won’t be participating in the &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; Champions Tour competition that’s slated to take place this weekend. “We are aware of the current situation regarding Jay Won and have launched an investigation,” Alex Francois, Riot’s global head of competitive operations, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/valesports_na/status/1369711283197472769"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZIVB4j"&gt;Simiarly, Won’s team, Sentinels, has launched its own investigation and suspended the player. “While the investigation is pending, he is suspended from the team,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sentinels/status/1369717636553183238"&gt;Sentinels said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “We will provide a further update once the investigation has concluded.” Won’s former &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League team, the San Francisco Shock, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SFShock/status/1369761148929593350"&gt;similarly issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that “While Jay is no longer a member of the San Francisco Shock, we think it is important to re-emphasize our position of zero tolerance in situations like these.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BoIMRL"&gt;In response, Won &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sinatraa/status/1369849384398184449"&gt;posted a statement on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, saying: “It is clear from Cleo’s recent post that she recalls our relationship differently than I do. What we do agree on is that it was unhealthy for the both of us. I apologize to Cleo and regret how things ended, but I never assaulted her in any way. I am fully cooperating with the investigations and providing the full audio and video clips Cleo referenced in her post.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="szOR1F"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 10th, 4:30PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added statement from the San Francisco Shock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XXyb3F"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 11th, 4:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from Won. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323695/jay-sinatraa-won-valorant-suspended-sexual-assault-allegations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323695/jay-sinatraa-won-valorant-suspended-sexual-assault-allegations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T20:35:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T20:35:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon decrees only ‘premium’ customers can escape its slowest 5G speeds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wfNicsIBDiN9I_ObyseevKZKQ64=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68945901/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Verizon wants to funnel more customers into its more expensive unlimited plans. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7u1DyK"&gt;If you’re on a basic Verizon plan, you’re going to be stuck with the company’s poor performing “nationwide” 5G network — even after critical C-band spectrum comes online. The company revealed in a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C0JNCwmCmCg"&gt;presentation to investors&lt;/a&gt; and confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that C-band frequencies, and their faster speeds, will only be available to customers on “premium” unlimited plans. Those on metered or the basic Start Unlimited plan will be relegated to slower, low-band 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CiFr0q"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Verizon confirms that to access C-Band you will need a premium unlimited plan like its Play More, Do More and Get More. If you have an older plan you'll only have access to its DSS "nationwide" 5G, not this newer and faster flavor.  &lt;a href="https://t.co/JH1uTixZaI"&gt;https://t.co/JH1uTixZaI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Eli Blumenthal (@eliblumenthal) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eliblumenthal/status/1369798985016373251?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="919wxO"&gt;This is essentially how the company already treats its ultra-fast mmWave 5G: customers on the base-level unlimited plan don’t have access to this network, while Play More, Do More, and Get More Unlimited subscribers do. Customers on metered plans don’t have mmWave access either, and likewise won’t have C-band, though they can add access to both for an additional fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1HI3Uz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company is extremely keen to funnel customers into “step up” plans and is using that C-band spectrum as incentive&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vA0agR"&gt;That’s bad news for Verizon customers hoping that C-band would improve the poor performance they’re seeing on the company’s nationwide 5G. The network currently uses narrow low-band channels not well suited for 5G, and relies on a technology called Dynamic Spectrum Sharing to accommodate 4G and 5G traffic on the same frequencies. As a result, Verizon’s 5G speeds are closer to 4G — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196060/verizon-5g-slower-than-lte-speed-test"&gt;and at times even slower&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gG3daF"&gt;Verizon has been limited by the spectrum it has access to, and so it spent big in the recent FCC auction of mid-band frequencies known as C-band. This chunk of spectrum is ideal for 5G, offering faster speeds than LTE with coverage that’s broader than range-limited mmWave. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;The company bid $45.4 billion on C-band licenses&lt;/a&gt; — more than double what AT&amp;amp;T spent. When these blocks of frequencies start becoming available at the end of the year, it should significantly boost the network’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gmzDf5VcpUEMbWWLSRqpjNa1ac0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22361438/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_5.41.43_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verizon predicts premium unlimited plans will make up 50% of its postpaid account mix by the end of 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XITILH"&gt;And that $45 billion is just the start. Verizon revealed on its investor presentation that it plans to spend an additional $10 billion over the next three years on C-band deployment, above and beyond its expected capital expenditure. That’s likely why the company is extremely keen to funnel customers into “step up” plans, and is using that C-band spectrum as incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49XVIf"&gt;Verizon also says that going forward, all new phones that it sells will be C-band compatible. That’s already the case for flagships like the Galaxy S21 and iPhone 12 series, but not all budget or midrange phone are C-band compatible in the US. That’s one less thing for phone shoppers to have to think about when buying a phone with Verizon, but it also makes Verizon’s job of talking you into a more expensive plan easier, too. And if you’re on one of their basic plans, you might be hearing that sales pitch sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324345/verizon-c-band-5g-unlimited-plans"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324345/verizon-c-band-5g-unlimited-plans</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T20:16:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T20:16:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Canoo reveals a bubbly electric pickup truck</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8KWYT634eKB98Kk6-d6ZySzCxmI=/559x259:1698x1018/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68945840/Canoo_PickupTruck_ExteriorSnow_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Canoo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eWsDHj"&gt;No, that’s not a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Ftruck-tracked-excavator-10812&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F10%2F22324096%2Fcanoo-goev-ev-pickup-truck-specs-photos-revealed" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Duplo toy&lt;/a&gt; — what you see above (and in the renders below) is the design for &lt;a href="https://www.press.canoo.com/press-release/canoos-new-pickup-is-all-electric-all-american-ready-for-work-the-weekend"&gt;a pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; from California electric vehicle startup Canoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aytwfd"&gt;Revealed in &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/canoo/comments/m208cq/canoo_pickup_truck_leak_pics_and_specs_inside/?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share"&gt;a leak on Reddit on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;, and then &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-canoo-evs-pickup/ev-startup-canoo-plans-to-roll-out-american-built-pod-like-electric-pickup-in-2023-idUSKBN2B3010"&gt;subsequently confirmed to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; before officially being revealed, the head-turning EV truck is not due out until 2023. By that time, Tesla’s Cybertruck, the electric Hummer pickup, Ford’s electric F-150, and Rivian’s EV pickup should all be on the road. Canoo said it will start taking preorders for its pickup later this year, but did not release pricing details. The startup is also reportedly in talks with other states for a “microfactory” where a contract manufacturer would build the vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTKqVx"&gt;The toyish truck shows just how far Canoo is willing to push the design of the microbus-style vehicle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/24/20882538/canoo-evelozcity-ev-subsicrption-electric-vehicle"&gt;it first debuted back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, which it originally planned to sell on a subscription-only basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kov5qO"&gt;Canoo has undergone a lot of changes since it debuted that first vehicle, though. It’s now a publicly-traded company after it merged with a special purpose acquisition company in late 2020. Its new executive chairman has also refocused the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"&gt;on selling commercial vehicles based on the original van design&lt;/a&gt; and the technological platform that powers it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="yJckkV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Canoo unveils a new electric delivery vehicle ahead of stock exchange debut","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xzfJ5J"&gt;But all of that doesn’t mean Canoo is exactly done trying to make vehicles for regular consumers. This new truck sort of bridges the two sets of customers, thanks in part to being loaded up with all sorts of utility features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Bgwgq1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10385450"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NWTo7l"&gt;There are multiple fold-down and flip-out work surfaces on Canoo’s pickup, with one in the nose of the vehicle and another on the side of the truck bed. There’s an extension that can be pulled out to make the bed a few feet longer. There are power outlets (120V and USB) dotting the inside of the bed and the storage compartments. Promo images also show the truck decked out in a roof rack and, in a bid to capitalize on the booming “van life” market, an “overlander” trim with a camper shell and a pop-up tent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LS6oQL"&gt;This is all in keeping with the vision of Canoo’s original vehicle, which was decked out in pegboards on the inside that the company imagined people could use to customize and personalize the vehicle. And the ability to use the new truck’s modular features in so many different ways — and to customize them from the start when ordering — is what Tony Aquila, the startup’s new executive chairman, hopes is a big selling point for the small businesses and more adventurous consumers that Canoo is targeting. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EDQA3RZqwWvrnET8COpdllDtIRE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22361384/canoo_camper.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “overlander” version of Canoo’s new pickup truck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BsNzKh"&gt;“When the working person sees this they go, ‘I can have a better quality of life with this vehicle, and I can get a return on capital.’ And every one of these areas is a space to create a return on capital, which is why we spent so much money to develop the most intelligent [truck] bed,” Aquila said in a video announcing the truck. (Canoo spent $47 million on research and development in 2018, $137 million in 2019, and $52 million through the first three quarters of 2020, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1750153/000121390021004077/f424b30121_canooinc.htm"&gt;recent government filing&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p17XIy"&gt;The sloped roof of the truck also tracks with Canoo’s original vehicle, though it’s a far more familiar design feature for a van. Fortunately for Canoo, Tesla has already started stretching the public’s imagination of what a pickup truck can look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5YqF2p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is for America.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XE9r9S"&gt;“That was our dream, to make sure that we had a vehicle that brought a truck to the market that just really shocked people just from the visual, and then to the functional,” Aquila said in the video. “This is for America. This is what built America, anyways.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LaXoUp"&gt;Canoo’s truck will be built on the same platform that powers the company’s other proposed vehicles, which means it largely shares the same specs across a number of configurations. The highest-cost all-wheel-drive truck will have around 600 horsepower and more than 200 miles of range, while the lower cost versions will get closer to 100 miles of range and feature a single motor in the rear. (Aquila &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-autos-canoo-evs-pickup-idUSKBN2B3010"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he thinks Canoo can find a way to up the range to 300 miles by the time it’s released.) The truck also uses the same brake-by-wire and steer-by-wire system Canoo developed for its other vehicles, which reduces complexity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dpcdNR"&gt;These technologies have made it possible for the startup to mate so many different designs to the same underlying technological platform. They’re also things that drew the interest of Apple, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225026/apple-canoo-acquisition-investment-electric-car-goev"&gt;which at one point wanted to acquire Canoo&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; exclusively reported earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mColVy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 10th, 9:58PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added details from the Reuters report. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324096/canoo-goev-ev-pickup-truck-specs-photos-revealed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324096/canoo-goev-ev-pickup-truck-specs-photos-revealed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T19:48:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T19:48:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>GameStop’s stock was on the rise again, until it wasn’t</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="GameStop photo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/npqYaqrq8sMAUj8taytLLU1Ouyw=/2x0:998x664/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68945712/gamestop-photo.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i7pWNZ"&gt;GameStop stock (GME) soared in value on Wednesday, peaking at $348.50 per share. Then, in an event that’s &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; not cause for concern, minutes later it lost fully half its value by plummeting to $172, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-10/gamestop-s-winning-streak-keeps-going-amid-cohen-shakeup-plan?sref=vuYGislZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Yes, “stonks” are back, and GameStop is once again &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244900/game-stop-stock-halted-trading-volatility"&gt;in the crosshairs of online amateur investors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0TRQF"&gt;Wednesday’s drama ultimately ended with the price settling back down to $265 per share, but it’s hard to not feel déjà vu. It seems like it was only yesterday when everyone was watching in a mixture of shock, amusement, and general concern as GME crested $483 per share. The rise and fall doesn’t quite compare, but the losses for anyone who sold during Wednesday’s dip in price are likely huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AsYDbk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Wow! What a chart Never seen anything like this intraday &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;*GAMESTOP PLUNGES, ERASING NEARLY ALL ITS GAIN; SHARES HALTED&lt;a href="https://t.co/a0qRraCmeN"&gt;https://t.co/a0qRraCmeN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/7jpwbILOV7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7jpwbILOV7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Joe Weisenthal (@TheStalwart) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheStalwart/status/1369703170088304643?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XYggXx5R2TuyKjcyYcMh-7e0GiI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360763/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_1.21.19_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GME’s journey from being worth $17 in January, to $260+ in March. Note the peaks during the last two major spikes in price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mipeVD"&gt;Having something you invested in suddenly worth 50 percent less can’t feel good, but it really depends when you originally bought in and if you’re still holding now: GME was worth $17 per share in January, but through some gonzo investing, the stock is now trading in the hundreds of dollars. It remains unprecedented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avHa0A"&gt;Like before, there’s no telling where this goes next, but I think it’s safe to say it isn’t over yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zd0Hv1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IIZp3O"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rFFDoM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N5ufDi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIH8Iz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0AsX6Y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTdDCU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323839/gamestop-stock-price-dramatic-rise-fall-stonks-return"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323839/gamestop-stock-price-dramatic-rise-fall-stonks-return</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T18:02:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T18:02:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best gaming laptops in 2021: seven laptops to get your game on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptops 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dFgjUrUVReawUz4BcRUID8XTWDI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68856650/akrales_210226_4440_0019.9.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our top picks from Asus, MSI, Razer, and more.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best gaming laptops at every size and price&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ow4mCb"&gt;Our pick for the best gaming laptop of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;. It can handle the most demanding games on the market today and also makes a great daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HOuHb0"&gt;The early days of mobile gaming were largely desktop replacements — clunky chassis, multiple power bricks, and RGB lighting galore. But the top gaming laptops now are different. Manufacturers are finally putting powerful specs in sleeker, more portable, and more professional builds. They have excellent, fast refreshing screens that are necessary for a great gaming experience. These laptops aren’t just great for gaming, but for everyday work as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VRi2QJ"&gt;We’ll be updating this page regularly as new gaming laptop models hit shelves throughout this year. Some exciting updates are on the way. AMD and Nvidia have announced their next-gen series of mobile processors and mobile graphics cards — the Ryzen 5000 series and the GeForce RTX 3000 series, respectively — and we’re already seeing them in premium gaming laptops across manufacturers. Intel’s Tiger Lake H series is also on its way, though we expect to see those more frequently in lighter-weight models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGRnFN"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22217171/gaming-laptops-qhd-screens-display-fast-refresh-rate"&gt;QHD screen&lt;/a&gt; is another feature to watch for in the best gaming laptops. A growing number of manufacturers are releasing configurations with 1440p displays, even in gaming laptops under $2,000. These options can hit a sweet spot for many gamers: a better experience than 1080p without the price premium or raw horsepower required for a 4K display. You can expect decently high refresh rates from these panels as well, depending on the model. The upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22215119/razer-blade-15-17-laptops-screens-graphics-gaming-price-release-date"&gt;Razer Blade 15&lt;/a&gt;, for example, will offer up to a 240Hz panel with QHD resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5KtNO"&gt;One more thing to keep in mind with the best gaming laptops is the power you can expect. Not all chips with the same name are created equal — the RTX 3070 in one laptop may not deliver the same frame rates as the RTX 3070 in another laptop due to its wattage (as well as other factors like the processor and cooling). Nvidia now requires companies to disclose clock speeds and graphics power on each model’s product page, but plenty of manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"&gt;haven’t done that yet&lt;/a&gt;. Your best bet, if you can’t find those numbers on a company’s website, is to read some reviews and make sure the model you’re considering will deliver the frame rates you’re looking for. We will note the wattage used in any laptops we review with the new RTX graphics cards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1WSZi"&gt;If you’re looking for a more multipurpose device, check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt; page. If you’re an Android gamer, we’ve also got a list of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; you can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="COKbvA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10385239"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="NqFABt"&gt;Best Gaming Laptop 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VQOCHc"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQts40hc8DMLBo4BPnPjc4j4RSI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341895/akrales_210226_4440_0125.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 is the best gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oTToOm"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rE8ByG"&gt;The best gaming laptop of 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dqOSgQ"&gt;Asus’s ROG Zephyrus G14 was our top gaming laptop pick for quite a while. It did just about everything right, and we weren’t sure whether Asus could ever replicate its resounding success. But somehow, the company managed to make the G14 just a bit bigger, and a heck of a lot better. In doing so, it’s created the ROG Zephyrus G15, the best 15-inch rig you can buy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsXGzm"&gt;At just over four pounds, the Zephyrus G15 is one of the lightest 15-inch gaming laptops you can buy. But you’re not making any compromises on performance for that portability: it’s powered by the top mobile chips that AMD and Nvidia have to offer, and includes a fast 165Hz QHD (1440p) display. Together, those components can handle even the toughest AAA titles at QHD resolution. The panel has excellent color reproduction as well, so your games will look great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HMlhzT"&gt;But it’s not just the gaming; almost everything else about the G15 is great, too. The audio (pumped from a six-speaker array) has strong percussion and bass, the keyboard and touchpad have a satisfying click, the port selection leaves little to be desired, and the battery can last for a whopping eight and a half hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MktsFD"&gt;The G15 won’t be the laptop for everyone. There’s no webcam, which is a significant oversight, and some may prefer something more affordable, or with a flashier aesthetic. But as a package, the G15 is the one to beat. Not only is it the best gaming laptop you can buy, but it’s also one of the best laptops you can buy, period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="qnyi8k"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g6h4assr_kNPJ14NeShE2YeeihU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21887081/mchin_181207_4189_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 is the best gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gXl1tL"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ibDYbq"&gt;The best gaming laptop in a 14-inch chassis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PjVXGI"&gt;The ROG Zephyrus G14 is the best 14-inch gaming laptop you can buy. We most recently reviewed last year’s model, which includes AMD’s Ryzen 4000 series up to the eight-core Ryzen 9 4900HS and an Nvidia RTX 2060 GPU. There’s a brand-new model out featuring the Ryzen 5000 series and Nvidia’s RTX 30-series graphics, which we’re looking forward to getting our hands on ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvmPMM"&gt;For well under $2,000, the Zephyrus crams one of the most powerful mobile processors on the market into a super portable 14-inch chassis. With capable cooling to boot, the laptop delivers frame rates we’ve never seen in a laptop of this size before. It handled every game we threw at it without breaking a sweat.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LRoiIm"&gt;But aside from its excellent gaming performance, the G14 makes a great daily driver. The keyboard, touchpad, display, and port selection are all excellent. Even the battery life is good — something we almost never get to say about gaming laptops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yypId"&gt;There are a few downsides to the G14, but they’re fairly small and user-dependent. The most significant note is that it lacks a webcam; you’ll need an external one if you plan on taking video calls. There’s also some bleed in the backlighting, there’s no Thunderbolt connectivity (since it’s an AMD system, and that’s an Intel standard), and the fans can get louder than most under load. But these are very much nitpicks that won’t have a large impact on plenty of people’s gaming experience. Overall, we have very few complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cUw2US"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505867"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PEmMiz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade Pro 17" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Hw1GXC0JJNr36nQ6K4vzlWTH-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21820230/mchin_181119_4158_0015.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade Pro 17 is a monster of a gaming laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yzdsDK"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21405760/razer-blade-pro-17-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade Pro 17&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jT5h16"&gt;The best big-screen gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="E8Fdz3"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 delivers some of the best gaming performance you can find in a laptop — but that’s not even its superpower. What makes Razer’s 17-inch flagship so impressive is it packs that unbelievable power into a thin and attractive chassis. It’s just 0.8 inches thick and only requires one charging brick — so you can carry it around in a backpack or briefcase without compromising on power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jaBYbX"&gt;Gaming enthusiasts can opt for a model with a 300Hz screen — the highest refresh rate you can get on a laptop — while folks who want to combine gaming with some creative work can opt for a 120Hz touchscreen configuration. Both models come with a customizable per-key RGB keyboard, which adds a touch of color to the Pro’s design without being too obnoxious for the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsGaDN"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 certainly isn’t cheap, but it’s the laptop to buy if you want the best of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wsMJEI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="59mBsv"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Dell G5 15 SE" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Na8N40bAkFQr8vsnVrWHMemA3q8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20086153/cfaulkner_200714_4098_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell G5 15 SE is the best gaming laptop under $1,000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MaGh3q"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21328344/dell-g5-15-se-review-2020-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen"&gt;Dell G5 15 SE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DMtcRV"&gt;The best budget gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hCCjrZ"&gt;The Dell G5 15 SE offers a great gaming experience at a price range far below that of many competitors. It’s the best gaming laptop you can buy under $1,000, and it doesn’t ask too many compromises for that price. While it only comes with a 60Hz screen, the hardware inside (especially AMD’s Ryzen 7 processor) is capable of maxing that out on all kinds of demanding games at native 1080p resolution, so you can reliably expect a playable experience from your favorite titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6ozmE"&gt;We’re also impressed by the G5’s connectivity. It includes a Mini DisplayPort, an HDMI, and an Ethernet jack — all ports you don’t see every day on laptops at this price point. Overall, if you’re looking for great value for your money, the G5 is your best bet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cYdW6R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505968"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UHt6xg"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade 15 Advanced" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JEuLWwA7yrXUTplilCC7i1YKquw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21922571/cfaulkner_200929_4214_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade 15 is the 15-inch gaming laptop to beat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="n9BvYP"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21499199/razer-blade-15-advanced-edition-gaming-laptop-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wzRw2D"&gt;A great thin and light gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="EcPuJg"&gt;The Blade 15 isn’t as powerful as its 17-inch sibling, but it may be a more pragmatic purchase for many people. If you’re looking for a balanced combination of performance and portability, the Blade 15 may hit that sweet spot. It still packs the top chips on the market and can come with a 300Hz display, but at just 4.7 pounds and 0.7 inches thick, it’s comparable in size to a number of 15-inch productivity machines like the Dell XPS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8vpQe"&gt;In addition to its reliable gaming performance, the Blade 15 works well as a productivity machine. We’re big fans of its keyboard, which is quite comfortable to use and has per-key RGB lighting, and the touchpad, which is roomy with a satisfying click. Our primary complaint is that this Blade got quite hot during our game testing — not only did the processor reach 99 degrees, but the hinge and palm rests were uncomfortable to touch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sxB5RK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591143"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="tOxdNl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Strix Scar 15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aTzXemr0v3qrt3uxufTnb2q6HSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22183653/mchin_190314_4347_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ROG Strix Scar 15 is a colorful laptop with a premium price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="E7sNUb"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22195676/asus-rog-strix-scar-15-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Strix Scar 15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7lPrCK"&gt;The best laptop with flashy RGB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="SK7elL"&gt;If you’re looking for a “traditional” premium gaming laptop with colorful, flashy panache, the ROG Strix Scar 15 is for you. The Strix’s keyboard isn’t just one of the most comfortable that we’ve ever tested on a gaming laptop; it also has some of the coolest per-key RGB lighting we’ve ever seen with all kinds of effects. There’s also a colorful light strip wrapped around the front of the deck (customizable as well) and a colorful glowing logo on the lid. In short: if you use this in public, people will notice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZuwqX"&gt;Of course, the Strix is great on the inside as well, delivering some of the best frame rates you’ll find from a 15-inch laptop with Intel’s and Nvidia’s top chips. You’ll get the full benefit of their power with a 300Hz screen option as well. And the Strix comes preloaded with various programs to help customize your gaming experience. You can personalize color profiles, bandwidth allocation, and more based on the type of game you’re playing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YAnMj2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355468"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="lXUZkA"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Alienware Area 51-m" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NZxevzR3kbj2DNb2IcI0Txno8vg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16006213/akrales_190403_3328_0066.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alienware Area-51m is a hefty, brilliant gaming device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vU9B3g"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18294631/alienware-area-51m-review-gaming-laptop-specs-price-features"&gt;Alienware Area-51m&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tCRMB0"&gt;A gaming laptop with desktop-class parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="SH9RLt"&gt;If money and desk space are no objects for you, you might be interested in the Alienware Area-51m. This hefty rig is essentially a desktop in laptop form. It pairs a desktop-class processor and a full-power mobile GPU with a 17-inch display and a full-size keyboard, delivering true desktop performance in a chassis that’s still (technically) portable. PC enthusiasts will also appreciate that you can update many of the components yourself, including the processor, RAM, and storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kkFbwO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355482"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="1yMy6D"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade Stealth 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/muZgIY4MYURM3D8aJNQ38Aziasw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20104452/mchin_181015_4105_0008.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade Stealth 13 is a gaming laptop that’s a breeze to carry around.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hDnH2j"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21340554/razer-blade-stealth-13-review-keyboard-specs-price-features"&gt;Razer Blade Stealth 13&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YDSZZF"&gt;A sturdy 13-inch gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="8Da3D3"&gt;The Blade Stealth 13 is far from the most powerful gaming rig out there, but it is one of very few gaming systems that come in a 13-inch chassis. The Stealth can run AAA titles at native resolution and comes with a 120Hz screen, but it’s comparable in size and weight to a MacBook Pro. Use it in a meeting or a classroom, and passing observers may have no idea it’s a gaming laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xdg8S1"&gt;In addition to its powerful chips, the Stealth comes with a colorful keyboard, a sturdy build, and a decent webcam. Even the battery life is pretty good. If you’re looking for a laptop that’s small but mighty, the Stealth will get the job done as a gaming rig and productivity machine in one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XBQ0Fw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9738792"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T17:54:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T17:54:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Leaked OnePlus 9 Pro and OnePlus 9 renders leave little to the imagination</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5Ju1cBmowIpZypZy9QCMvxTlBOE=/202x0:1822x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68945213/oneplus_leak.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images of OnePlus’ upcoming 9-series phones show prominent branding from camera partner Hasselblad. | Image: WinFuture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gGsXN9"&gt;We have a very clear picture of what the upcoming OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro will look like thanks to &lt;em&gt;WinFuture &lt;/em&gt;— the site has &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,121663.html"&gt;published a whole bunch of official press renders&lt;/a&gt; of the upcoming phones well ahead of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315517/oneplus-9-launch-date-hasselblad-camera"&gt;March 23rd launch&lt;/a&gt;. We got our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319657/oneplus-9-charger-in-box-pete-lau-announcement"&gt;first official look&lt;/a&gt; at the upcoming flagship in a teaser video from OnePlus earlier this week, but this latest leak features both regular and Pro models from multiple angles in a variety of colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QodKHK"&gt;These renders align with what OnePlus has already shared, and they also resemble an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174437/oneplus-9-photos-leak-2021-flagship"&gt;alleged prototype device&lt;/a&gt; that was leaked late last year. It appears that the OnePlus 9 Pro will come with a slightly curved 6.7-inch display, and the OnePlus 9 will feature a flat 6.5-inch screen. That’s about the extent of the spec details in this leak; &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; speculates that the 9 may use a plastic chassis rather than metal, but it’s hard to say for sure based on these images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xusBIS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10385194"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1pZUzb"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; evident is the Hasselblad branding on both devices’ camera bumps, thanks to a new partnership. Both phones include a Sony IMX789 sensor in the main camera, and as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeteLau/status/1369304680241762311"&gt;confirmed by OnePlus CEO Pete Lau&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, an ultrawide camera will be included with a 50-megapixel Sony IMX766 sensor. That’s an unusually high resolution count for an ultrawide, but as Lau demonstrates with some &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeteLau/status/1369505640771633157"&gt;side-by-side images&lt;/a&gt;, those extra pixels might allow for more aggressive distortion correction and cropping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZ85vg"&gt;Outside of camera lenses, these renderings show the range of color options we can likely expect from the 9 and 9 Pro. The 9 Pro is shown in sturdy black, olive green, and metallic silver. The 9 looks to be offered in black, with more laid-back blue and purple options available, too.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323979/oneplus-9-pro-leak-images-hasselblad-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323979/oneplus-9-pro-leak-images-hasselblad-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T17:20:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T17:20:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Artifacts from the first COVID-19 vaccination in the US are headed to the Smithsonian</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A Black woman sits in a chair while another Black woman holds her upper arm and prepares to administer the vaccine." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hxSHbFNuW0dmEUYsNuUlS-VTcZE=/0x0:5400x3600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944964/1230125095.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sanda Lindsay receiving a COVID-19 vaccine. | Photo by Mark Lennihan - Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pbxYge"&gt;The glass vial used in the first US COVID-19 vaccination has been acquired by the Smithsonian’s National Museum of American History. The museum also acquired related items including the scrubs and vaccination card of Sandra Lindsay, director of critical care nursing at the Long Island Jewish Medical Center who, on December 14th, 2020, became the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/14/nyregion/us-covid-vaccine-first-sandra-lindsay.html"&gt;first person in the US to receive a COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ecF94d"&gt;“The urgent need for effective vaccines in the U.S. was met with unprecedented speed,” said Anthea M. Hartig, the museum’s Elizabeth MacMillan director, &lt;a href="https://www.si.edu/newsdesk/releases/smithsonian-collects-objects-first-known-us-covid-19-vaccination-effort"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday. “These now historic artifacts document not only this remarkable scientific progress but represent the hope offered to millions living through the cascading crises brought on by COVID-19.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WmW2rZ"&gt;The announcement on Tuesday happened days before the one-year anniversary of the World Health Organization &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21156325/coronavirus-pandemic-who-declares-covid-19-outbreak-global-h1n1"&gt;declaring the outbreak a pandemic&lt;/a&gt;. Since April 2020, a special task force at the museum has been seeking out objects and documentation related to COVID-19. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsybbX"&gt;“We’ve had everything from offers of masks that people have made to objects related to treatment of Covid, to practitioners offering us objects related to how they’ve gone about protecting themselves or their family,” Alexandra Lord, chair of the museum’s division of medicine and science, &lt;a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smithsonian-institution/first-vial-used-us-covid-19-vaccinations-joins-smithsonian-collections-180977194/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Smithsonian Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g8560k"&gt;The vial and other items are joining the museum’s collection of materials related to historic epidemics and pandemics, including objects related to the polio epidemic, the 1957 influenza pandemic, and the HIV / AIDS pandemic. Many items from the collection will be on display in a 2022 exhibition, “In Sickness and in Health.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323850/artifacts-first-covid-19-vaccination-smithsonian-museum"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323850/artifacts-first-covid-19-vaccination-smithsonian-museum</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T17:15:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T17:15:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMC revenue drops nearly 90 percent in fourth quarter, but CEO remains optimistic </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="AMC’s Stock Is Latest Target For Retail Investors Organized On Reddit Message Boards" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ShBF7mTd1ChCTkBBg9x7ucshPDc=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944942/1298998015.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Scott Olson/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="feQYaJ"&gt;AMC Theaters reported another jarring but predictable loss in its &lt;a href="https://s25.q4cdn.com/472643608/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/FINAL-4Q-2020-earnings-press-release-20210310-1435-clean-v.f.pdf"&gt;fourth quarter earnings&lt;/a&gt;, but the company’s CEO is optimistic that the theater chain will make it out of the pandemic alright. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zSXdGG"&gt;Revenue was down 88 percent year over year, to $162.5 million. While beating expectations, that still led to a quarterly loss of $946 million (slightly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/2/21545812/amc-theaters-financial-earnings-q3-bankruptcy-streaming-warner-bros-disney-regal#:~:text=The%20company%20posted%20a%20revenue,91%20percent%20year%20over%20year."&gt;better than the last quarter&lt;/a&gt;, though significantly worse than the $13.5 million loss AMC reported in its 2019 fourth quarter), but AMC also has more than $1 billion in cash on hand, according to CEO Adam Aron. On the tailwinds of announcements that New York City &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295880/new-york-city-movie-theaters-open-cuomo"&gt;would start to allow theaters&lt;/a&gt; to open, and studios seemingly preparing to head back to theaters, Aron is trying to find the positives while acknowledging the “most challenging market conditions in the 100-year history of the company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iD3JMi"&gt;“As we sit here today, we see that vaccinations are occurring in the United States at a brisk clip, our theatres in New York City have finally opened with theatres in Los Angeles likely opening shortly as well, [and] blockbuster movie titles are currently scheduled to be released in significant quantity in the coming few months,” Aron said in a press release. “Taking these facts together, we have reason to be optimistic about AMC’s ability to get to the other side of this pandemic.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rzxzy5"&gt;As noted in AMC’s earnings, part of the reason that AMC is still able to push forward and Aron feels optimistic is because of capital raised throughout 2020 and 2021. Add in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251964/amc-stock-price-reddit-wallstreetbets-trading-gamestop"&gt;newfound love from retail traders&lt;/a&gt; (similar to what happened with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;GameStop in late January&lt;/a&gt;), and AMC’s stock price has also somewhat rebounded over the last several weeks. Now, with announcements from President Joe Biden that nearly every American should be able to &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/02/politics/biden-merck-johnson--johnson-vaccine/index.html"&gt;receive their vaccination by May 2021&lt;/a&gt;, studios are looking to get their blockbusters out in theaters again and AMC is hoping to bring as many moviegoers in as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VFiX8u"&gt;There are still a lot of questions on the table. How has the irrevocably shortened theatrical window, brought on by companies with major studios like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21355563/mulan-disney-plus-streaming-exclusive-cost-own-movies-theaters"&gt;NBCUniversal, WarnerMedia, ViacomCBS, and Disney&lt;/a&gt; possibly harmed AMC’s overall business? Will people want to rush into theaters by the summer? Could something else happen that delays everything reopening en masse once again? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsnSQj"&gt;For now, Aron is optimistic — at least in front of his company’s shareholders, investors, and analysts. The CEO will say more about the business and industry at large on the company’s earnings call this afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324053/amc-theaters-earnings-fourth-quarter-stock-movies-vaccine-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324053/amc-theaters-earnings-fourth-quarter-stock-movies-vaccine-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T17:08:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T17:08:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly denies Parler’s App Store appeal, citing derogatory terms and ‘Nazi symbols’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yP8YutyzG6d7B9X6LQEDp11Oglw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944888/acastro_190319_1777_apple_services_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u9cLIw"&gt;Apple has reportedly denied social media company Parler’s bid to reenter the iOS App Store, saying its platform hasn’t addressed problems with offensive content. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-10/parler-cuts-ios-team-after-apple-blocks-return-to-app-store"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reported the news earlier today&lt;/a&gt;, quoting a message reportedly sent on February 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AVsGFX"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, Apple said that Parler’s &lt;a href="https://legal.parler.com/documents/guidelines.pdf"&gt;latest community guidelines&lt;/a&gt; still didn’t meet its standards. “Simple searches reveal highly objectionable content, including easily identified offensive uses of derogatory terms regarding race, religion and sexual orientation, as well as Nazi symbols,” it reportedly told Parler. “For these reasons your app cannot be returned to the App Store for distribution until it complies with the guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eUzW2M"&gt;Parler’s guidelines ban threats, spam, and some other categories of content. However, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21557219/parler-conservative-app-download-new-users-moderation-bias"&gt;right-wing-friendly network’s&lt;/a&gt; policies remain permissive compared to other social platforms, and its stated goal is that “removing users or user-provided content be kept to the absolute minimum.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d6lPLq"&gt;That strategy has put it at odds with several major companies. Apple and Google both banned its app from their mobile stores in January, following the January 6th mob attack on the US Capitol. And Amazon took the site offline by suspending its web hosting agreement, saying representatives had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech"&gt;raised concerns about violent threats&lt;/a&gt; preceding the attack. Parler responded by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310873/parler-amazon-aws-lawsuit-antitrust-hosting-free-speech"&gt;filing suit against Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, although it has since relaunched on a different hosting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JqLfmI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;also reports that Parler cut ties with its last three iOS app developers alongside four other employees. The company still maintains an Android app that can be side-loaded from outside Google’s Play Store, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/15/22284036/parler-social-network-relaunch-new-hosting"&gt;its site relaunched&lt;/a&gt; on February 15th. Parler and Apple did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324028/apple-parler-app-store-ban-upheld-nazi-symbols"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324028/apple-parler-app-store-ban-upheld-nazi-symbols</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T16:55:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T16:55:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nyan Cat’s creator is running an event to sell memes like Bad Luck Brian and Keyboard Cat as NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VPRG7VIyYHqDAwUoZ2U7UzE2aek=/0x151:892x746/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944793/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_10.01.15_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Kyle Craven&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DrYbxT"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres"&gt;selling Nyan Cat as an NFT&lt;/a&gt;, its creator, Chris Torres, has found himself working on an even bigger event: a week-long series of auctions where classic memes are being sold on the blockchain by their original creators. Torres calls the event &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/withFND/status/1369098514773381120?s=20"&gt;Memeconomy&lt;/a&gt;, and he’s hoping it’ll bring both recognition to the meme creators, as well as to the NFT space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pbr7Zh"&gt;The memes involved should be recognizable if you were on the internet in the early 2010s. They include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oGxggC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/bad-luck-brian"&gt;Bad Luck Brian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sMRgDl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/coughing-cat"&gt;Coughing Cat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JsfsmJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaA_cs4WZHM"&gt;Kitty Cat Dance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vBP3cd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/scumbag-steve"&gt;Scumbag Steve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8gg1re"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J---aiyznGQ"&gt;The Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/grumpy-cat"&gt;Grumpy cats&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Lp7mEC"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/me-gusta"&gt;Me Gusta face&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="UT2dKy"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MEMECONOMY?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#MEMECONOMY&lt;/a&gt; WEEK 1   by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NyanCat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NyanCat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6 OG memes. 1 brand new NFT. We’re seeing the rise of the meme economy on Foundation.     &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/solidbadluck?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@solidbadluck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IdasCreatures?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@idascreatures&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveIbsen?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@steveibsen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RealGrumpyCat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@realgrumpycat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KeyboardCatReal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@keyboardcatreal&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwerkyPepe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@twerkypepe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BlakeBoston617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@blakeboston617&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Only on → &lt;a href="https://t.co/A7bTOLs99m"&gt;https://t.co/A7bTOLs99m&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/XVaUZrDoQI"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XVaUZrDoQI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Foundation (@withFND) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/withFND/status/1369098514773381120?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wYG4yB"&gt;There will also be an auction of a new meme: a crossover between Twerky Pepe (a popular NFT creator) and the classic Nyan Cat. (Have you ever wanted to see thicc Nyan Cat? &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PRguitarman/status/1368995286434127877?s=20"&gt;Now you can.&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1zSYO"&gt;The event is already under way, and so far the first meme, Bad Luck Brain, &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/badluckbrian/bad-luck-brian-4263"&gt;sold for just over $37,000&lt;/a&gt;. Coughing Cat is currently up for auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="oorpn9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="czbleJ"&gt;While the memes are mostly from the same era, Torres says that it’s not on purpose. “Honestly there was no real agenda” when it came to the selection of memes, he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, saying that the original meme creators had contacted him independently. He says that he won’t be making any money off the auctions themselves, he just wanted to help get the creators set up so they could get “proper recognition” after “10 plus years without [it].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KqMKT8"&gt;While NFTs are supposed to validate ownership, there’s no guarantee that the person creating an NFT owns the artwork they’re selling. There have been &lt;a href="https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2021/03/people-are-now-making-nfts-out-of-artworks-and-tweets-without-permission/"&gt;artists talking about how their work has been stolen&lt;/a&gt; and NFT-ized, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GiphyComms/status/1369442632649310210?s=20"&gt;Giphy has tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that it was looking into user content being used by NFT sites. Torres knows it’s an issue and said that he made sure that everyone he talked to about NFTs was both the actual creator of the meme and actually held the rights to it. He also said that meme theft wasn’t a new problem: “sometimes you look over and there’s a company that has your picture on a shirt and they’re making millions of dollars without even talking to you about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="STrRyn"&gt;In the short term, the Memeconomy could put some cash (well, crypto) in the pockets of creators and open the doors for them to show off some recent work, if they have any. It could also work to build a community — finding friends through the process of organizing the Memeconomy event and through interactions in the NFT space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJljAt"&gt;In the long term, though, Torres thinks the meme NFTs will become collectables, and that “eventually somebody’s gonna want to have all of them” and it’ll “be a big fight to own all the memes whenever that time comes.” He said he “can’t wait to see that like a VR room with all the memes all displayed, that’s like… that would be awesome, like a grand collection of memes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NdY5Cv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NFTs, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"},{"title":"Nyan Cat is being sold as a one-of-a-kind piece of crypto art","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322131/nyan-cat-creator-nft-memes-memeconomy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322131/nyan-cat-creator-nft-memes-memeconomy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
