<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-09T12:21:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T12:21:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T12:21:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Activision Blizzard employees create strike fund while taking steps toward unionization</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cOCZ9eegj-a5rPExu-6M0aBdDuo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70250279/acastro_210729_1777_blizzard_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JA9wq8"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/abk-strike-fund"&gt;GoFundMe&lt;/a&gt; has been created to support employees participating in the latest work stoppage at Activision Blizzard. This latest walkout comes after the company announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816827/raven-software-qa-contractor-layoff-activision-blizzard-call-of-duty"&gt;a round of layoffs&lt;/a&gt; in the QA department of one of its subsidiaries, Raven Software, right before the holiday season. Though initially contained to the Wisconsin-based studio, the walkout spread to QA departments in Texas and Minnesota with many other employees not in QA departments joining in solidarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zIVfm"&gt;“Funds raised from this donation effort will contribute to offsetting wages lost from the work stoppage,” says the GoFundMe organized by Jessica Gonzalez, a Blizzard employee known for her activism and outspoken criticism of her employer, “as well as to assist in the potential relocation of Raven Software workers who were forced to move without financial assistance at the insistence of Activision Blizzard.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="po3zqN"&gt;After news of the Raven Software layoffs broke, Treyarch, another Activision Blizzard studio known for developing several games in the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; franchise, converted all of its temporary staff &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK/status/1467936015071559683"&gt;to full-time employees&lt;/a&gt;. The workers involved in the Raven Software walkout are hoping for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GjEVKy"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/12/09/activision-union-strike-fund/"&gt;a report by &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, unionization efforts are ramping up behind these walkouts with workers being asked to sign union authorization cards. Activision Blizzard employee advocacy group &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK"&gt;A Better ABK&lt;/a&gt; has worked with the CWA — a digital media and tech organizer — since news of rampant sexual harassment, discrimination, and abuse at the company broke this summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="COYuLj"&gt;The GoFundMe is asking for $1 million in funds and has raised almost $40,000 since its creation early this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826129/activision-blizzard-employees-create-strike-fund-while-taking-steps-toward-unionization"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826129/activision-blizzard-employees-create-strike-fund-while-taking-steps-toward-unionization</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T12:09:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T12:09:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) review: Pixel envy</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;This middling $549.99 phone with a 144Hz display just can’t catch a break &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="zKfjfu"&gt;Timing is everything, and unfortunately for Motorola, any review of the new Moto Edge 5G UW boils down to this one question: how does it compare with the Google Pixel 6? After all, not only did the Verizon variant arrive in stores on October 14th, 2021, just five days before the Google Pixel 6’s launch, it even ended up with near-identical prices as the Google flagship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TwLEHj"&gt;The Verizon-locked Moto Edge starts at $549.99 for a 128GB model, and you can double that storage for $599.99, which is $200 cheaper than the unlocked version sold in retail stores. That’s twice as much storage for the same price as an unlocked Pixel 6, plus the Edge supports Verizon’s fast-but-limited millimeter wave (mmWave) network. Given how good a phone the Pixel 6 is, the Moto Edge has its work cut out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2fpm2W"&gt;As a midrange phone, the Edge has some impressive specs and features on paper. It has a rare 144Hz refresh rate LCD display, 108-megapixel main camera, 6GB RAM, and the ability to project its screen to a larger display through its Samsung DeX-like &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motorola.com%2Fus%2Fready-for%2Fp&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22824763%2Fmotorola-moto-edge-5g-uw-2021-review-google-pixel-6-android-mobile-verizon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Ready For” mode&lt;/a&gt;. In practice, though, the high-megapixel count camera is not as great as it sounds, and its 5,000mAh battery can drain too quickly, but these aren’t even its worse offenses. The Edge’s biggest crime is that it’s just too middling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BqQNRQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10909816"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CyU-H9rno4nHf4pM0rp_Dsa0BTU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053000/gsin_190313_4899_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The rims around the Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)’s camera lenses remind me of the iPhone 13’s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="nFFuPi"&gt;The Moto Edge is all about the monochromatic look, splashing the same “nebula blue” all over the phone — from the buttons to the plate underneath the camera array. It’s a big phone at 6.65 x 2.97 x 0.35 inches, but it’s skinny and thin enough for one-handed use. That said, it’s just a touch too tall for my fingers to maneuver around the screen &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;hold the phone in the same hand. Despite its all-plastic body, the phone weighs about as much as an iPhone 13 Pro at 0.44lbs (200g or 7.11oz). Its nicely curved edges and back make this phone a pleasure to hold, but that also means its very glossy back cover is a cesspool of smudges and dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UgX7Ir"&gt;The rims around the three rear camera lenses remind me of those on the iPhone 13. While their raised edges protect the lenses from scratches, that extra height means the phone can’t really lie flat on the table when the screen is facing up — it ends up rocking side to side. This, combined with its slick back cover, means the Moto Edge is prone to randomly slide off tables and other surfaces, so you’ll want to protect it with a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JlxySE"&gt;Like the Pixel 6 and OnePlus 9, the Moto Edge doesn’t have a dedicated Google Assistant button or a 3.5mm audio jack anywhere. Its volume rocker and two-in-one fingerprint sensor and power button are on its right side. For a $500 phone, it only has a mono speaker that blasts from the bottom of the phone. It’s louder than you’d expect and turns up the bass by default, so you can really hear the percussive beats in &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;theme song. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Aieyayiv2c57xo7RUyF9AHQKSQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053009/gsin_190321_4899_0014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) may only have a mono speaker, but it is loud and has a strong bass.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xdVF4dTEVvqiSvOzUMmKcgcr0Ng=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053002/gsin_190313_4899_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Its two-in-one fingerprint sensor and power button makes it convenient to unlock the phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VrB0jT"&gt;Unlike Motorola’s G series phones, the Edge has NFC for contactless payments, but doesn’t support wireless charging. Out of the box, the Moto Edge runs Android 11 though it’s unclear when it’ll get Android 12. While Motorola has committed to providing two major OS upgrades and two years of bi-monthly security updates to the Moto Edge, it also said it’ll &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/07/29/motorola-android-update-policy/"&gt;adjust its software support policy based on how long users will keep using a device&lt;/a&gt;, so its promise can be rather fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tMNARX"&gt;The Moto Edge’s side fingerprint sensor and face unlock features work quickly and provide good haptic feedback when the unlocking is successful. Face unlock has some customization options: you can choose to press the power button to activate the feature or to simply lift the phone and face the front camera to unlock the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_lRlG7109wqYPEu2q7mCzOjCZWc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053003/gsin_190313_4899_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)’s LCD screen has a whopping 144Hz refresh rate that is a pleasure to use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="xMQjdx"&gt;The highlight of the Moto Edge has to be its 144Hz display, even though it’s just a 1080p, 6.8-inch LCD panel. The high refresh rate makes it a breeze to scroll through Twitter and move my pokémon around in &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt;. It’s too bad the screen is relatively dim, so I have to set its screen brightness to about 90 to 100 percent for indoor and outdoor use — any dimmer than that and I’d have trouble reading text in direct sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bLlULp"&gt;I’ve been testing the $549.99 model with 128GB of internal storage, which is otherwise identical to the $599.99 256GB version. The Moto Edge uses the Qualcomm Snapdragon 778G processor, a midrange chipset, with 6GB RAM as support. Unsurprisingly, it’s the Pixel 6’s flagship-level components that outperform the midrange Moto Edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rt0kui"&gt;I played one round of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt; on the Moto Edge, which started out snappy and easy to navigate my Charmander. However, the game became so laggy that it was hard to move my pokémon to avoid attacks or to score a goal in the last minute. I played the same game on the Tensor-equipped Pixel 6 to compare. While I couldn’t move my pokémon as easily with the Pixel 6’s slower 90Hz screen refresh rate, the speed of the game stayed more consistent, making it possible for me to score a last-minute goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HyfrzLG9DNamgdOhL-Aen1dZa8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053006/gsin_190313_4899_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) weighs about the same as the iPhone 13 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TorcDh"&gt;Motorola’s “Ready For” mode is supposed to be able to turn the phone’s 32-megapixel front camera into a webcam for a compatible smart TV or computer, but I couldn’t make it work with my Surface Pro 4 at all. The font on the Ready For PC’s interface was way too tiny to be legible on my 12.3-inch screen. Worst of all, there was so much lag between my mouse clicks and what was happening on-screen that this whole feature was a flop for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NC5bIX"&gt;While its 5,000mAh battery lasts about two days with average use, the Moto Edge’s battery can drain very quickly if you’re doing something intensive. On days where I’m primarily on Wi-Fi and doing lightweight tasks like online shopping, social media doomscrolling, and &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="CEFwuR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I find it hard to recommend the Moto Edge over others that offer a better value&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iAL9NM"&gt;listening to a couple of podcasts, I could squeeze almost 11 hours of screen time out of this phone. However, when I was gaming and testing its video features, I managed to drain a whopping 29 percent of the battery within just a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIsdqr"&gt;Recharging the Moto Edge is also unnecessarily annoying, thanks to the lack of a charger inside the box — all you get is a double-ended USB-C cable. I had to plug the Edge into my Pixel 5’s 18W charger for a recharge, which took almost two hours. If you don’t have a compatible charger handy, you’ll need to budget $20–$30 for a new cable or charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tLrXLTw-5HvrUNUPmhEgCCzB5pA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053004/gsin_190313_4899_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)’s 108-megapixel main camera sounds more impressive than it is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="qh6T4t"&gt;The Moto Edge has three cameras on the back cover: a 108-megapixel main camera, an 8-megapixel ultrawide-angle with Macro Vision (119-degree), as well as a 2-megapixel depth sensor. It also has a 32-megapixel front-facing camera that sits in the middle of the screen, though you don’t really notice that black dot after a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uUS-7SPwNgwMo0d609dQ-nG2JEs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074609/IMG_20211203_203821141.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Pixel 6" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yhhpdaxBuMojMy5ZgSEz7n-QEnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074613/PXL_20211204_013930145.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yfuamp"&gt;As impressive as the Moto Edge’s 108-megapixel main camera sensor sounds, its results are surprisingly unpredictable. On one hand, its f/1.9 aperture and larger pixel size means each pixel can capture more light, even in low-light conditions. I was surprised how well some photos from an indoor interactive art exhibit turned out, even though some shots were not as crisp as others and looked a bit noisy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0mJbh9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10910732"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7yMmj9"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo samples from the Moto Edge 5G UW and the Pixel 6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SjSxAK"&gt;On the flip side, the Edge’s cameras have trouble finding and focusing on subjects, whether I’m taking outdoor photos of Christmas decorations or well-lit photos in portrait mode. It often takes several shots and several processing seconds before the camera figures out which part of the image is the subject and which is the background that should be blurred. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Pixel 6" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9KQMBX_Z-MLw2pXo7I3K76zOeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074630/PXL_20211204_015230127.PORTRAIT.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pixel 6: portrait mode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Moto Edge 5G UW (2021)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B1sbbomPhpAQWNPOLO_EFakrqc4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074628/IMG_20211203_205150700_MF_PORTRAIT.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Moto Edge 5G UW (2021): portrait mode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cAhpXX"&gt;I used the Pixel 6 to take photos of the same scenes, and the ones from the Google flagship are consistently sharper, with colors that are more true to life. Photos from the Moto Edge tend to look flat, skew blue, or are overexposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Motorola Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) in Nebula Blue." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4HU8OsJsLbSLv8O2YonGiHnufEs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053007/gsin_190313_4899_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;With cheaper and better competitors around, I find it hard to recommend the Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) to consumers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EkInNA"&gt;The Moto Edge 5G UW (2021) may be a decent phone: its unusually high 144Hz refresh rate on the LCD screen works great; and it has two days of battery life, with a camera that can handle low-light photography if you can get it to focus. But that’s no longer enough to be competitive in the midrange phone race. Unless Verizon or Motorola further drop its price, I find it hard to recommend the Moto Edge over others that offer a better value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6tLhIL"&gt;For the price of the 256GB Moto Edge, you might as well get the unlocked &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"&gt;Google Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt; instead. It features a faster processor, faster and sharper cameras, and a more energy-efficient battery. While the $599.99 Moto Edge offers double the onboard storage as the base Pixel 6, its flagship-class components and early access to Android software and security updates make it the better investment in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ulswep"&gt;If you’re a Verizon customer, the Moto Edge might seem like a better deal than the $699.99 mmWave-equipped Pixel 6, but don’t be fooled by the Edge’s lower price tag. The flagship Google phone is worth the extra $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVsAgW"&gt;If the $549.99 Moto Edge is slightly beyond your budget, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"&gt;$499.99 Samsung Galaxy A52 5G&lt;/a&gt; is an even more affordable 5G phone alternative. The A52 features a 120Hz OLED display and a headphone jack but doesn’t support Verizon’s mmWave network. That’s not something that matters to most people, but the Edge does have it if you want to use Verizon’s 5G network. Plus, you’ll be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;guaranteed four years of software support from Samsung&lt;/a&gt; for the A52  — who knows if Motorola will even follow through on its two-year promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igiptV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Gloria Sin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="Dmsvqe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10911071"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22824763/motorola-moto-edge-5g-uw-2021-review-google-pixel-6-android-mobile-verizon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22824763/motorola-moto-edge-5g-uw-2021-review-google-pixel-6-android-mobile-verizon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram launches Playback so you can relive your favorite Stories from 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xwPHjTgGCpTQVQpt8xNyaw8islE=/88x0:1008x613/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70250132/insta_best_of.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Instagram’s Playback will show your favorite stories from 2021 | Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d7i6Bs"&gt;Instagram is getting in on the year-in-review trend with Playback, a feature that will let you relive your Stories from 2021. Instagram will share a curated Playback of 10 Stories for each user, but anyone can edit, add, or remove Stories from their Playback list via their Stories archive, which will pop up within Playback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5E5Wo1"&gt;Users will see a message in their Instagram feed inviting them to create a Playback, and if they see a 2021 Story they want to add, users can click on the “2021” sticker to view and share in their Playback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DMVTI"&gt;While Playback is likely to be popular, especially with power Instagram users who want to re-promote their favorite Stories, it’s a bit puzzling that Instagram hasn’t embraced a simpler end-of-year feature that’s been popular in the past: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/31/22207149/instagram-top-nine-best-pictures-missing-feature-facebook"&gt;“top nine” photo grid&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YBw86j"&gt;Third-party apps have offered variations of the top nine end-of-year photo grid to Instagram users for several years, but often at the cost of personal info like email addresses. Instagram has built-in &lt;a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/introducing-layout-photo-app-from-instagram"&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; to let users create photo grids, but so far hasn’t offered a year-in-review version. Even Facebook, part of the same parent company as Instagram, offers an automated look-back video (whether users want one or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/7/16745656/facebook-year-in-review-ai-2017-terrible"&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BfqQzS"&gt;And let’s face it: most apps and platforms have still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812079/apple-music-year-in-review-spotify-wrapped-social-media"&gt;failed&lt;/a&gt; to replicate the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android"&gt;popularity of Spotify’s Wrapped&lt;/a&gt; end-of-year feature, which lets users see and share their top songs, artists, and genres. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZLGob"&gt;Playback rolls out Thursday to all Instagram users as a limited feature available for the next few weeks, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kGRrhb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825888/instagram-playback-end-year-stories-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825888/instagram-playback-end-year-stories-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T11:45:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T11:45:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram decision to remove ayahuasca post overturned by Meta Oversight Board</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k9XKb5k2Ky5lUVTnfuEUlEQQxcs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70250070/acastro_211101_1777_meta_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Meta’s independent Oversight Board overturned an Instagram decision to remove a post about ayahuasca | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VQQX3z"&gt;The Oversight Board for Facebook and Instagram parent company Meta has &lt;a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/1780492362340442-oversight-board-overturns-meta-s-decision-case-2021-013-ig-ua/"&gt;overturned a decision&lt;/a&gt; by the photo-sharing app to remove a post that discussed ayahuasca. The board found that while the July post from a spiritual school in Brazil violated a Facebook rule against promoting the use of non-medical drugs, it did not violate Instagram’s community guidelines “as they were articulated at the time.” The board said Meta needs to be clearer when it applies Facebook rules to Instagram content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bqFale"&gt;“The Board is concerned that the company continues to apply FB’s Community Standards on IG without transparently telling users it is doing so,” it wrote in its decision. The Instagram rule at the time of the removal only covered the sale and purchase of illegal or prescription drugs, the board added. “The Board does not understand why Meta cannot immediately update the language in Instagram’s Community Guidelines to tell users this. Meta also did not tell the user in this case what part of its rules they violated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TtYAJi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"You can now appeal for Facebook’s Oversight Board to take down bad posts","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381499/facebook-oversight-board-remove-posts-appeals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="dl6CG2"&gt;The Oversight Board further took issue with the stated reason removing the post: to protect public health because “the user described ayahuasca with a heart emoji, referred to it as ‘medicine,’ and stated that it ‘can help you.’” The post discussed ayahuasca in a religious context, and the school didn’t post instructions for using the drug. The board recommended Meta change its rules on regulated goods to be respectful of diverse cultural practices, “to allow positive discussion of religious issues of non-medical drugs which have a recognized traditional or religious use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mBWFpf"&gt;Ayahuasca is a plant-based psychedelic, usually prepared as a tea that provides a high, which can include hallucinations. It’s traditionally used as a spiritual and ceremonial medicine by people in the Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nRMLlb"&gt;The Oversight Board also released its &lt;a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/640697330273796-oversight-board-publishes-transparency-report-for-third-quarter-of-2021/"&gt;third-quarter transparency report&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday and said between July and September, it had received 64 percent more cases, or 339,000, for possible review than it had in the second quarter. Among the cases it was referred, about 34 percent were related to Facebook rules on bullying or harassment, 30 percent had to do with violence and incitement, and 23 percent were related to concerns about hate speech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="azlChh"&gt;And of the 25 recommendations from six decisions the Oversight Board made in the quarter, Meta said it would implement more than half of the decisions “fully” or “in part.” The Oversight Board — a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/17/20870827/facebook-supreme-court-mark-zuckerberg-content-moderation-charter"&gt;Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; for Facebook / Meta — heard its first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755133/facebook-oversight-board-supreme-court-first-cases-hate-speech-pandemic-misinformation"&gt;cases in December 2020&lt;/a&gt;. It’s meant to interpret company policies but not make new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825959/instagram-decision-ayahuasca-facebook-meta-oversight-board"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825959/instagram-decision-ayahuasca-facebook-meta-oversight-board</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T10:59:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T10:59:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Chromebook for 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Chromebooks 2020: Acer Chromebook Spin 713" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HDV4yWEUjQt1tPQn1vixjNoG1V4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66976144/mchin_181029_4126_0011.0.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best Chromebook laptop or two-in-one for every Chrome OS fan&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="wvBJQw"&gt;The best Chromebooks aren’t just laptops that run a few Google apps anymore. Chromebooks can cover a wide variety of computing needs now, and a good Chrome OS laptop or two-in-one can be more useful than a mediocre &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21231636/windows-10-pc-user-guide-how-to-microsoft"&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21281530/macos-mac-imac-user-guide-how-to-os-tips"&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt; laptop. That’s why our pick for the best Chromebook of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21355769/acer-chromebook-spin-713-review-best-chromebook-to-buy"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt;, which does just about everything right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnwyna"&gt;The best Chromebooks are known to deliver good value. The message that many people actually want &lt;em&gt;good &lt;/em&gt;Chromebooks — rather than just cheap ones — has gotten through to manufacturers. Many are around $500 or $600, though there are good options in the higher and lower ranges as well. The extra money goes a long way toward getting something you’ll be happy with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vUTNYw"&gt;For the first time, the quality of the best Chromebooks in this range has been consistent. There are so many similarities between the offerings from Asus, Lenovo, Google, HP, Dell, and Samsung that a conspiracy-minded person might suggest they’re all sourcing their components from the same factory. That’s great news if you’re comparison shopping; the majority of this list would be good buys if you can find them at a discount. They can even rival some of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptops&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21528540/budget-windows-10-chromebook-systems-acer-lenovo-cheap"&gt;best budget laptops&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college"&gt;best student laptops&lt;/a&gt; on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMCGia"&gt;Our pick for the best Chromebook is the Acer Chromebook Spin 713, and we’ve selected the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21262694/lenovo-chromebook-duet-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt; for shoppers on a budget. Other picks for the best Chromebooks of 2021 include the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931476/google-pixelbook-go-review-the-price-of-simplicity"&gt;Google Pixelbook Go&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22776850/asus-chromebook-flip-cx5-review-the-15-inch-chromebook-to-beat"&gt;Asus Chromebook Flip CX5&lt;/a&gt;, the HP Chromebook x360, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22217002/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-price-release-date-hands-on-chrome-os-photos-video"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ch4TuU"&gt;What most buyers want in the best Chromebook are likely the same things they want in any laptop: a good keyboard, solid build quality, long battery life, a nice screen, and enough power to do the things you want. More Chromebooks can meet those qualifications than ever before, but these are the ones that rise above the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="YECpuA"&gt;Best Chromebook 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Kzk7Pm"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Acer Chromebook Spin 713" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HyRBlc_lGNtkqv1-Yw1w1JfYnaw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21698824/mchin_181029_4126_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Acer Chromebook Spin 713 is the best Chromebook of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KQRVus"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22451261/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BfZy92"&gt;Best Chromebook of 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LpXHDz"&gt;Acer’s Chromebook Spin 713 is, hands-down, the best Chromebook you can buy. With a gorgeous 3:2 screen that rivals some more expensive competitors, you’ll have a ton of extra vertical space for your work and multitasking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zarhIJ"&gt;The keyboard is excellent with a comfortable, quiet feel, and nice backlighting. There’s even an HDMI port, which you don’t see on a thin Chromebook every day. And (most importantly) the 11th-Gen Intel processors can handle a heavy load of tabs with no problem. The Spin’s speakers aren’t great, and there’s no biometric login, but those are reasonable sacrifices to make for a laptop of this quality at this low of a price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GX2USx"&gt;In a market where the main differences between Chromebooks in this price range boil down to their screens and maybe an included stylus, Acer sets itself apart by making an affordable laptop that’s excellent in almost every way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WtaeAS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505954" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="2XjalW"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Lenovo Chromebook Duet" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pDnq5iKvs1snl7mnQ956GJOyu90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19978538/mchin_200512_4018_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For students or anyone looking for a small secondary device, the Lenovo Chromebook Duet is a great affordable pick.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RGZEpN"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21262694/lenovo-chromebook-duet-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="P8MGAD"&gt;Best Chromebook on a budget&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xJq778"&gt;If you’re looking for an affordable device for on-the-go work, the Lenovo Chromebook Duet delivers excellent value for its low price. It’s an ultra-portable 10.1-inch 2-in-1 device with a detachable keyboard and kickstand cover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfnBmb"&gt;The Duet contains a MediaTek Helio P60T processor, 4GB of RAM, and up to 128GB of storage, and it performs well if you’re just browsing and don’t plan on using a super heavy load. It also uses a version of Chrome OS that’s made for its convertible form factor, including the first version of Chrome that’s optimized for tablet use. When detached from its keyboard, the Duet supports an Android-esque gesture navigation system that makes switching between apps a breeze. But the most impressive feature is battery life; I got close to 11.5 hours of fairly heavy use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93jX9I"&gt;Of course, there are drawbacks. The touchpad and keyboard are quite small, there’s no headphone jack (and only one USB-C port), and the 16:10 screen is a bit dim. But those are reasonable trade-offs to make for such an affordable price. It makes a great secondary device for schoolwork or on-the-go browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zyoOMu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505920"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="h53Xe7"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: HP Chromebook x360 14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V_ywzr_RXTQ5_V71rLE_aoXdE6I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19138761/vpavic_190731_3630_0083_result.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re looking for a larger device with more power, one of the best Chromebooks you can buy is the HP Chromebook x360 14.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="C2SoIE"&gt;3. HP Chromebook x360 14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rtrWbQ"&gt;Powerful Chromebook with a sleek design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="E2rGvI"&gt;If you’re looking to get more power and you don’t mind getting a slightly larger laptop, the HP Chromebook x360 14 is a great choice. HP has several configurations that fall under this name, but we suggest the model we tested with 8GB of RAM and 64GB of storage to go along with the i3 processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="alUDxQ"&gt;While we picked the Asus because of its elegant design, there isn’t much to complain about on the slightly larger HP. It has the same ports, RAM, and storage. The keyboard is great, and it also sounds slightly better because the speakers are up on the keyboard deck instead of on the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="epP0CZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508136"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="B5nNzS"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JYTGMXk_OQTkqKVAOg19N-g0t6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22646162/mchin_20190829_4618_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;If the Chomebook Duet isn’t enough, the Chromebook Detachable CM3 brings some new perks to the detachable form factor, for an extra cost.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FxguZ6"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22526743/asus-chromebook-detachable-cm3-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CrrPVI"&gt;Best detachable Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="canZPK"&gt;The Chromebook Detachable CM3 is Asus’s attempt to compete with Lenovo’s highly praised Chromebook Duet. Like the Duet, the CM3 is a 10.5-inch, 16:10 Chrome OS tablet with a fabric cover, a kickstand, and a keyboard that pops on and off. It’s a bit more expensive than the Duet, but also has a few extra features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uNgQvV"&gt;One unique perk is that the kickstand folds multiple ways: You can fold it the long way to stand the tablet up like a laptop, or fold it the short way and stand the tablet up horizontally. We’re not sure how practical this functionality actually is, but it’s there if you have a use case in mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SlTu0z"&gt;The CM3 also comes with a built-in USI stylus, and roomy keys with a surprising amount of travel. But the thing we found most impressive was the battery life: We averaged close to 13 hours of continuous work on the device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="11a1Pz"&gt;The CM3 won’t be the best Chromebook for everyone: It only has two ports (one USB-C and one audio jack) and its MediaTek processor was a bit sluggish compared to more expensive offerings. But if you’re looking for a convertible Chrome OS device and find that the Duet doesn’t quite suit your needs, you’re likely the CM3’s target audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="viqOHr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10639759"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OMjJYz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Chromebook Flip CX5 in tent mode, angled to the left on a black table. The screen displays The Verge homepage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7qVpJ_EofzZF49vWtTX9exOttos=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22959801/akrales_211012_4763_0139.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus Chromebook CX5 is the best Chromebook with a 15-inch screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="USU6BQ"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22776850/asus-chromebook-flip-cx5-review-the-15-inch-chromebook-to-beat"&gt;Asus Chromebook Flip CX5&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VMPUxM"&gt;Best Chromebook with a 15-inch screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qu3aaz"&gt;Folks may understandably balk at the Chromebook Flip CX5’s price, but it really is that good. It’s sturdy enough to withstand all kinds of jolts and jostles in a backpack or briefcase, and has a unique velvety texture that’s very pleasant to hold. Add a wide port selection, a smooth and comfortable keyboard, and a vivid display, and you’ve got a chassis that can hold its own against plenty of midrange Windows laptops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RcLGGd"&gt;The CX5’s performance is equally impressive. We never once heard its fan in our testing, even when pushing a workload that slows most devices down. Battery life is quite satisfactory and easily lasted us all day. And the CX5 delivered some of the loudest audio we’ve ever heard from a Chromebook. While the CX5 isn’t a perfect device, it’s a solid performer all around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gfc67v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10870714"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="21auFT"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MlsPe6vgTrRZoHnvDAes7ZrTXKA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22333703/akrales_210226_4438_0232.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 one of the best Chromebooks of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AZSrVU"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301481/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yloceu"&gt;Best midrange Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="IqMUru"&gt;Samsung’s first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21206151/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-review-android-laptop"&gt;Galaxy Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; shot for the moon, with a $1,000 price tag, an OLED display, a packaged stylus, and a premium build. The Galaxy Chromebook 2 isn’t so much a sequel to that device as it is a pared-down, more affordable alternative. There’s no fingerprint sensor, no stylus, and no OLED — but it’s quite functional, and with a sub-$600 starting price it’s a much more reasonable purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SMshkm"&gt;The Chromebook 2’s highlight feature is its finish: It comes in a bright “fiesta red” that will certainly stand out wherever you’re using it. (There’s a gray option as well, if you’d prefer something subtle.) It’s also the first Chromebook ever to feature one of Samsung’s QLED panels. QLED isn’t OLED — it’s just a fancier LED — but it still makes for one of the most gorgeous displays I’ve ever seen on a Chromebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91mDFz"&gt;Nice screens sometimes wreck battery life, but that’s not the case here. I averaged about seven hours and 21 minutes of continuous work on the Chromebook 2, which means you shouldn’t need to plug it in &lt;em&gt;too &lt;/em&gt;too often. And while the Core i3 processor isn’t the most powerful chip you can get in a Chromebook, it’s just fine for everyday work use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AvjZA6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10430161"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="CcI5pi"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Google Pixelbook Go" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mJIGZCwodcc1uK14LiOJoO0lOew=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19317495/vpavic_191023_3755_0099.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Google Pixelbook Go has a stylish and portable design with a standout keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SStRnG"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931476/google-pixelbook-go-review-the-price-of-simplicity"&gt;Google Pixelbook Go&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="s4tmgA"&gt;Best Google Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="WMItcT"&gt;The Google Pixelbook Go is a handsome, no-nonsense 13.3-inch laptop that weighs just 2.3 pounds. It has a sturdy magnesium chassis, and a ridged grip on the bottom to keep itself from slipping on slanted surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M72CDq"&gt;Not only is the Pixelbook Go portable and stylish, but it delivers solid performance, and supports fast charging through either of its USB-C ports. Battery life is also impressive. The Go lasted over eight hours in our testing, and it should get you through a full workday with no problem. But its standout feature is the keyboard, which is quiet with good travel and a springy feel. &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editor Dieter Bohn found it to be his “favorite thing to type on by a long shot.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCvQ3C"&gt;The Go is an expensive product, as Chromebooks go, and it doesn’t top our list because the Chromebook Flip C434 offers similar specs and features for a slightly lower price. But we think plenty of shoppers who value long battery life and lightweight build might prefer to spend a bit more on this device instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lZOrDL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508145"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vfHEAv"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Chromebook 2021: Lenovo ThinkPad C13 Yoga Chromebook" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zvz2bSiuoI0U8Ql5wYVV2rRIpmo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22505253/mchin_20190730_4573_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ThinkPad C13 Yoga Chromebook is a premium Chromebook for grown-ups.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="URZefw"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22424783/lenovo-thinkpad-c13-yoga-review-price-specs-features-amd"&gt;Lenovo C13 Yoga Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="U2ykf7"&gt;Best premium Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="nT7MLq"&gt;Many modern Chromebooks are oriented towards kids and students, but not this one. The C13 Yoga Chromebook is a sturdy, pricey, convertible Chromebook for grown-ups. It’s part of Lenovo’s renowned ThinkPad business line, and has all kinds of ThinkPad perks including a red Trackpoint, discrete touchpad clickers, a fingerprint sensor, a webcam shutter, and an aluminum design. Put this Chromebook next to any number of Windows ThinkPads, and we might not be able to pick it out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iLVSSi"&gt;The C13 is also unique in that it’s the first Chromebook to include AMD’s Ryzen 3000 Mobile C-series processors, which are marketed specifically for Chromebooks. The chips run all kinds of programs — even mobile games — quite smoothly. We do wish the battery life was a bit better — we only averaged just over six hours on one charge. We averaged seven and a half hours from our top pick, the Chromebook Spin 713, and plenty of the devices here break eight hours with no problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JyEtgP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10639799"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0my4ED"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. For more information, see our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/pages/ethics-statement"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;ethics policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T10:35:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T10:35:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>General Motors makes moves to source rare earth metals for EV motors in North America</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P2LfpCJaoMSxlXYXUVfK8hs0PjE=/0x0:5632x3755/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70249701/GM_UltiumDrive_003_255_kW_EVmotor.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VMoNwA"&gt;General Motors announced a deal to source rare earth metals for electric vehicle motors in North America. Under the agreement, Las Vegas-based MP Materials will supply the automaker with “US-sourced and manufactured rare earth materials, alloy, and finished magnets for the electric motors” that will be used to power GM’s upcoming lineup of electric vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3mAnLa"&gt;Electric motors are powered by permanent magnets, sometimes no larger than a pack of playing cards, that are made of rare earth metals. The magnets enable the motors to transform electricity into motion, thus powering the vehicle. But these rare earth magnets, mostly made of neodymium (NdFeB), are almost entirely mined and processed in China. And as tensions grow between China and the US, automakers are under increasing pressure to find more localized sources of these key materials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QybZjB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The magnets enable the motors to transform electricity into motion&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bexC8O"&gt;GM has said it plans to become an EV-only company by 2040, meaning it will need to make millions of electric motors every year. In a call with reporters, the company’s executives said that this agreement with MP Materials, in addition to other recent announcements, will help ensure that most of the materials that comprise its Ultium EV platform will come from within North America by 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx1m13"&gt;“I think most people outside our industry would be shocked to learn that there are virtually no factories in the US building these magnets at scale,” said Shilpan Amin, GM vice president for global purchasing and supply chain. “Well that’s about to change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iBgPPG"&gt;GM said it picked MP Materials for its location and capacity to produce rare earth materials at scale. The company owns and operates a rare earth mine and processing facility in Mountain Pass, California. The materials sourced from this facility will be transformed into an NdFeB alloy and magnets at a new production factory that MP Materials will build in Fort Worth, Texas. The plant is expected to start production in 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tYUJNz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;500,000 EV motors annually&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NbF3FE"&gt;Once its up and running, the Fort Worth facility will have the capacity to produce “around 1,000 tons of finished magnets per year,” GM said. That amount of rare earth materials has the potential to power approximately 500,000 EV motors annually, the automaker noted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D9Pfrk"&gt;Despite the name, rare earth metals are actually abundant but can be dirty and difficult to produce. China has grown to dominate production, and with &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/the-role-of-critical-minerals-in-clean-energy-transitions/mineral-requirements-for-clean-energy-transitions"&gt;demand for the magnets on the rise&lt;/a&gt; for all forms of renewable energy, experts say a shortage may lie ahead. Some automakers have been looking to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-frictions-steer-electric-automakers-away-rare-earth-magnets-2021-07-19/"&gt;replace or limit the use of rare earth materials for years&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lNnn9"&gt;Much like the rest of the auto industry, GM is racing to boost its EV offerings, vowing to spend $35 billion on the development and production of 30 new electric vehicles by 2025. To accomplish this enormous feat, the company is trying to get a stronger grasp on its supply chain, which includes electric motors and battery manufacturing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mdsP3u"&gt;The company has said it will spend over $4 billion on the construction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313251/gm-ev-second-battery-factory-lg-chem-tennessee"&gt;two battery factories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811902/general-motors-cathode-factory-ev-battery-posco"&gt;a new cathode factory&lt;/a&gt; in North America. The company also recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559718/gm-lithium-ctr-ev-battery-investment-salton-sea"&gt;struck a deal to source lithium&lt;/a&gt;, a key ingredient in electric-car batteries, from geothermal deposits in the US. And it’s building a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709389/gm-wallace-battery-center-ev-ultium-research"&gt;new 300,000-square-foot battery research facility&lt;/a&gt; in Michigan to help make electric vehicle batteries that are longer lasting, quicker to charge, and more sustainable for the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KEqw6R"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825948/gm-ev-motor-rare-earth-metal-magnet-mp-materials"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825948/gm-ev-motor-rare-earth-metal-magnet-mp-materials</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T10:01:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T10:01:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>iPhones will be able to give owners a detailed history of what parts were replaced</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LtlW9ELdJJfE6WjGpt5djeHB1uw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70249538/akrales_170620_1794_0029.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tG9xHD"&gt;Apple is about to add a new feature to iPhones informing users if the device was previously repaired and whether a genuine screen or battery was used (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/12/08/ios-15-2-shows-a-service-history-of-repaired-parts-in-your-iphone/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;via 9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). A new &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212878"&gt;parts and service history&lt;/a&gt; section will appear (under Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; About) with the upcoming iOS 15.2 update for iPhone — providing some insight and peace of mind for buyers of used or refurbished iPhones hoping to get a proper quality OEM unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LtEGWM"&gt;The new update expands on a previous feature that can tell if a screen or battery was not genuine, now adding them in one place and even including a date on when the service was performed. Since the release of the iPhone 11, Apple started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/25/20884287/apple-iphone-11-pro-max-display-screen-replacement-verification-warning"&gt;including a warning&lt;/a&gt; when an aftermarket (ungenuine) screen was installed. Now iPhones as old as XR models can warn if a battery is ungenuine, while iPhone 12 and 13 can call out more including the cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eEQGbR"&gt;Earlier versions of iOS on the iPhone 13 threatened to make screen repairs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22764251/iphone-13-screen-replacements-break-face-id-microsolder"&gt;more difficult&lt;/a&gt;, requiring microsoldering to avoid a warning label and deactivated Face ID sensors. iOS 15.2  &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22786274/apple-iphone-13-screen-replacement-face-id-ios-15-2-beta-fixes"&gt;updates the process&lt;/a&gt; to allow repairs by users or a third-party shop without a complaint from the device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UYqxLcQmlwwcUAJm69RK6XKJJzQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23075322/ios15_2_repair.001.jpeg.001.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iOS 15.2 with new Parts and Service History section.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6HOm0z"&gt;Buying and selling used iPhones is a huge market, but it can be scary not knowing if a device will have a low-quality aftermarket&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;battery that might overheat — or annoying if the screen you get has terrible colors because it’s not really OLED (when it should be). This could happen if a repair was performed by a third-party shop that is not in Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/29/20838307/apple-iphone-repairs-parts-independent-shops"&gt;independent repair program&lt;/a&gt; (IRP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EitIXY"&gt;With the announcement of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22787245/apple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy"&gt;Self Service Repair&lt;/a&gt; from Apple, customers will have a means of getting genuine parts and repairing iPhones at home. Since this method of service is supported by Apple, newer iPhones on iOS 15.2 repaired through self-service will acknowledge that a repair was done and the parts are genuine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeoeUB"&gt;Trading in or reselling iPhones might get more difficult, though — if aftermarket parts were used, then companies and independent buyers now have the leverage to quote lower values if a repair is reported in settings. This can lead to very &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368541/apple-trade-in-phobio-macbook-white-spots"&gt;frustrating situations&lt;/a&gt; especially if a phone needs to be sent in for inspection to confirm a trade-in value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9Jrql"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZGJla"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824733/apple-iphone-part-service-history-ios-15-2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824733/apple-iphone-part-service-history-ios-15-2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T09:40:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T09:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Matter could bring universal casting that actually works</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hSjLQu7b-61QZ8vRbvaiJ56pc5g=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70249408/verge_IMG_8670_2040pxl.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;This Amazon-led casting standard for TVs could challenge Apple AirPlay and Google Cast &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="eU6aaf"&gt;The new smart home standard Matter is making a lot of grand promises, chief among them are fixing the interoperability mess the smart home is currently in and making Apple, Samsung, Google, and Amazon talk to each other. Big jobs. But it’s also tackling one of the other pain points in the connected home: TV control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bm1PBy"&gt;One part of the new connectivity protocol is a specification for televisions and streaming video players. This means that Matter could become yet another way to control content in our homes. But, with its promise of platform agnosticism, Matter’s TV spec has the potential to replace proprietary casting systems, like Apple’s AirPlay or Google’s Cast, and finally free our TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m2niZc"&gt;Matter TV, as we’ll call it for wont of an official name, will allow control of a television’s core functions — volume up / down, changing the channel, controlling inputs and outputs, and switching between HDMI ports. “But importantly, you can also do casting,” Chris DeCenzo, Principal Software Development Engineer at Amazon Lab126, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oENWS1"&gt;“This is an area with at least five proprietary protocols today,” he says. “The result is a complete opportunity loss for everyone.” Not to mention major headaches for users as they grapple with which voice assistant can get this content and which remote will control that streaming stick. Amazon is leading the effort to define the specification for Matter — unsurprising, as it is currently the only large player without a proprietary way to cast content from a smartphone to a TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sv-CBjF74efHYHqQaY3CTpNuA3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13262367/jbareham_180726_2773_0087.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Controlling our smart TVs can feel anything but smart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1AsPEc"&gt;“Control of media is one of the most popular use cases for Alexa,” says DeCenzo, who told me Amazon is working with the different industry leaders in the fields of smart TVs, streaming video players, and content providers to help them adopt Matter. The goal is so that “customers can have a consistent way to use voice control and to launch their favorite content on those screens,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0NyUx"&gt;While the Matter TV specification doesn’t explicitly call out voice control, the idea here is standardization. One protocol for all device communication, everything will talk to everything else using the same language, no &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt; who made it. Ultimately, this means you will be able to use your control interface of choice (a voice assistant, remote control, or smartphone / tablet app) with all your streaming content devices and apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="7HxJWF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With its promise of platform agnosticism, Matter could finally free our TVs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rguZA0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623275/matter-interoperable-smart-home-standard-delay-2022-project-chip-csa"&gt;When Matter arrives in 2022&lt;/a&gt;, the Matter TV specification will use app-to-app communication, at least until the TVs and streaming video players become Matter enabled. The spec supports casting from a Matter client (e.g., a remote, a smart speaker, or a phone app) to an app running on a Matter-enabled TV or video player device, explains DeCenzo. It also supports URL-based casting, which means a Matter client can cast to a TV even when there’s no app for that client, if the TV supports Dynamic Adaptive Streaming (DASH, an international standard for streaming) or HLS DRM streams (HLS is a video streaming protocol developed by Apple and widely supported across Android devices and browsers). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tus8PG"&gt;The capability could go beyond just entertainment and be used to enable smart home notifications, says Chris LaPré of the &lt;a href="https://csa-iot.org/"&gt;Connectivity Standards Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, the organization that oversees the new standard. For example, it could cast a message from your connected doorbell to your smart TV, notifying you that someone is at the door. It could potentially show you the video feed, too, something of a workaround for including video feeds in Matter, since cameras are not part of the first device rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ietivWcwo5KkGDZsTA4bL1fY9k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23074285/f7484de0_fd1a_11eb_8eb4_4d8ac557fa35.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CSA / Matter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matter-enabled devices will have the Matter logo on them to indicate they’re compatible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="to2vl9"&gt;Intriguingly, LaPré posited that the specification could allow for the use of context when delivering these messages, such as notifying you from the smart speaker in the room you are in that your laundry is done. “It can be about casting anything, smart home notifications, local video — all it needs is a URL to pull content from,” says LaPré. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hntmBy"&gt;The technology here is not system-level specific, as with Apple’s AirPlay. It appears to be more akin to Google’s Cast, where apps will need to build support for it, at least initially. But like AirPlay, and as with all Matter communications, it’s entirely local. Communication from device to device uses Matter as the channel. At launch, Matter will use ethernet, Wi-Fi, and Thread as its communication protocols. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s30Vfu"&gt;The requirement for the app makers — such as Hulu and Netflix, who aren’t currently members of the CSA — to build Matter support could make this something of a non-starter initially. Beyond Amazon and its Prime Video and Google with YouTube, few of the major streaming content providers are part of the CSA, and the app developer will initially need to add Matter support to both the app in the phone or casting device (for example, a smart speaker, laptop, or smartphone) and the app in the receiving device (TV, streaming stick, smart display). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCw2XM"&gt;“You can have communication directly from the Prime Video app on my phone to the Prime Video app that’s on the TV,” explains DeCenzo. Going forward, according to LaPré, the streaming video players and TVs will have Matter built into the devices themselves. It seems likely Amazon will enable Matter on its Fire TV devices, and the company has already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761340/amazon-matter-smart-home-standard"&gt;committed to upgrading all its smart speakers to support Matter&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung, TCL, Panasonic, and LG are all involved with Matter, as are Apple and Google. However, according to the list of companies on the &lt;a href="https://buildwithmatter.com/"&gt;Matter website&lt;/a&gt;, Vizio, Sony, Toshiba, and Roku are a few notable hardware players that are not yet signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="JleYxe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is a consistent way to use voice control to launch content on any screen&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BcAKqp"&gt;The main goal, however, is part of Matter’s overarching promise: avoiding manufacturer lock-in. People should be able to buy whichever device they choose and it should be able to talk to all the other connected devices in their home, regardless of who made it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xjqOY9"&gt;For example, if both were Matter-enabled you should be able to control an LG TV from a Samsung smartphone, and that LG TV should be able to receive a message from a Miele smart washer that the laundry is done. But, and this is a big but, nothing in the Matter spec is a requirement. A company that is on board with Matter as a whole is under no obligation to adopt parts of the specification that they don’t need or want to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LEcMbI"&gt;This means that Apple and Google do not have to adopt the Matter TV specification if they don’t want to. LaPré says both companies have “blessed this” as part of the spec (Matter is governed by members of the CSA who vote on the specifications). Whether they will adopt it remains to be seen. But if Amazon does, which seems like a good bet, it should mean you can use Matter to cast from your Amazon Prime app on your iPhone to your Amazon Prime app on your Apple TV or Google Chromecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W1CPHb"&gt;I reached out to both Google and Apple about this specification and how it would impact their current offerings. Both companies have committed to supporting Matter in their respective smart home ecosystems and both are members of the CSA. Kevin Po of Google said in an email that “Google Assistant will support Matter (eg. on/off, play/pause, app launch etc.) at parity with our current Works With Assistant offering.” Apple did not comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="5nr5N9"&gt;Po went on to reiterate that Google Cast remains Google’s preferred method for sending media via apps and voice to Chromecasts, speakers, and displays. As, we can only assume at this stage, will Airplay be Apple’s “preferred method.” But what your preferred method will be could very soon involve a lot more choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wKv5qW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34SCdf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824559/matter-tv-streaming-devices-smart-home-casting-protocol-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824559/matter-tv-streaming-devices-smart-home-casting-protocol-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T09:13:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T09:13:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to block and report text spam</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ep8th1m8Qtgf31rfrdgMB5cJzvE=/0x0:2048x1365/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69520154/VRG_Illo_4902_Security_Spam.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Ori Toor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;No strategy is 100 percent effective, but you can stop much of it&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="xS9Cl4"&gt;Spam texts can be incredibly irritating — you get a notification and stop what you’re doing to check your phone, only to find somebody is trying to sell you something you don’t want. How can you prevent it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cz3VXk"&gt;Unfortunately, there are no absolutes in preventing text spam. But there are some ways you can at least minimize the number of spam texts that get through. Here are some strategies to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kZBYfb"&gt;Do not answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6jYMm1"&gt;Top of the list is — as you probably already know — never reply to a spam text, and never &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; click on a link within a spam text. If you’re not sure whether a text is spam or legitimate, hold off on replying until you’ve done a bit of research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="kVNV0v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10905004"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6qez8i"&gt;Use the spam filter on your phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rIeftn"&gt;Android phones and iPhones have spam-filtering features that you can enable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NuvT8Q"&gt;If you have an Android phone:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="aZycxQ"&gt;Open the Messages app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Aitn1H"&gt;Click on the three dots in the upper right corner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AcwIN3"&gt;Select Settings &amp;gt; Spam protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Qw3pYw"&gt;Make sure “Enable spam protection” is toggled on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="LIp4DO"&gt;If you want to see what numbers you’ve marked as spam, you can go to “Spam &amp;amp; blocked” in the initial menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="To set up spam blocking, go to “Settings” &amp;amp;gt; “Spam protection.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FXwdP2ahVxd3OAOhvklYwpyG92s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688826/Screenshot_20210629_115526.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go to Settings &amp;gt; Spam protection. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Toggle on “Enable spam protection.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N95yPCbJSuhETaseeQ-cGaSctgw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688921/Screenshot_20210629_115223.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toggle on “Enable spam protection.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Bhbi4Z"&gt;If you have an iPhone:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lVIqKL"&gt;Apple’s spam blocking is a little more basic than Android’s: it blocks phone numbers that you &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT207099"&gt;don’t have saved in your contacts list&lt;/a&gt; and haven’t been in contact with before, which could be an issue (say, if you’re expecting a call from a car service). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mT9Wfz"&gt;Open the Settings app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cON9RE"&gt;Scroll down to and select Messages &amp;gt; Unknown &amp;amp; Spam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9DWUaL"&gt;Toggle on “Filter Unknown Senders”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Scroll down to “Unknown &amp;amp;amp; Spam.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tQ5MN3_pe8P_1cEcmcKEuXpe4ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688833/IMG_DE165A8C72D3_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scroll down to Unknown &amp;amp; Spam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Toggle on “Filter Unknown Senders.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/54lBOdOA3HP0fjky5doQXJanBug=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688834/ios_spam_filter.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toggle on “Filter Unknown Senders.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OAOftX"&gt;Block specific texts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CPlAZi"&gt;When you get a spam text, you can block that individual number from contacting you again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CHYvJs"&gt;If you have an Android phone: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="y9iZCr"&gt;When you tap on a message that Android tags as suspicious, the OS will often give you the opportunity to report it as spam (or verify that it’s not spam). But if you get a spam text that wasn’t flagged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YMRXxv"&gt;Tap the three dots in the upper right corner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gj3lEy"&gt;Select Details &amp;gt; Block &amp;amp; report spam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wNHf6y"&gt;You can just block that number if you want, or you can check “Report spam” to send the number to Google and possibly your carrier as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="JC7myw"&gt;Note that this process can differ depending on which Android phone you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android often gives you the chance to report spam." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r9JTEBdcapOnyMcpc-0VoQVCoi4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688787/Screenshot_20210629_114432__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android often gives you the chance to report spam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can just block a spam text, or you can report it to Google." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e_t3PKQ43dotIaSJBmoDsb5TSrE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22689083/Screenshot_20210629_103221__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can just block a spam text, or you can report it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="EdU9wB"&gt;If you have an iPhone:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9x3Rtt"&gt;Open the spam text and select the user icon on top of the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BjzvjY"&gt;Tap on the “info” icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pWO3eN"&gt;Select “Block this Caller”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select “info” and then click “info” again on the next page." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vbBVda0Q1NfpFBAFWsQOixyVK0E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22689118/IMG_FEEE7B27517F_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select “info” and then click “info” again on the next page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="At the bottom of the page, select “Block this Caller.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9plBrvQdpfvsj0mGwCG1R6X9FDQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22689119/IMG_ED1CBC48272A_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the bottom of the page, select “Block this Caller.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H2JCJ1"&gt;If you want to report an iMessage you received as spam, then look for the “Report Junk” link under the message, tap it, tap “Delete,” and then “Report Junk.” Note that this doesn’t automatically block that phone number; you’ll have to do that separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AEFlot"&gt;Forward the text to 7726&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="F8kP0O"&gt;If you’re using one of the major carriers (Verizon, AT&amp;amp;T, or T-Mobile), you can report a spam text by forwarding it to 7726. (This spells “SPAM” on your phone keyboard.) This may also work with other carriers; to find out if it’s possible, check with your carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hHZUy1"&gt;This isn’t just a US thing, by the way. Ofcom, which regulates the UK’s communications services, &lt;a href="https://www.ofcom.org.uk/phones-telecoms-and-internet/advice-for-consumers/problems/tackling-nuisance-calls-and-messages/spam-texts"&gt;also accepts reports of spam texts&lt;/a&gt; forwarded to 7726.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rxUjrU"&gt;Block spam using your carrier’s services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4EbKlM"&gt;Most major carriers these days offer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21327304/spam-calls-how-to-stop-block-robocalls-robots-scam-iphone-android"&gt;spam-blocking services for phone calls&lt;/a&gt;, and these can carry over to texts. Carrier sites will give details about free and for-pay security services offered by &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/security/security-apps/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fplans-features%2Fblock-unwanted-calls&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22555521%2Fspam-text-block-security-iphone-android" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/solutions-and-services/call-filter/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt;; if you use a different carrier, check its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AbbBTq"&gt;Use a third-party spam-blocking service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cz49nD"&gt;If you’re really frustrated and the above strategies aren’t working for you, you can try using a third-party anti-spam service. These are not free. For example, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.robokiller.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22555521%2Fspam-text-block-security-iphone-android" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;RoboKiller&lt;/a&gt; costs $4.99 a month or $39.99 a year after a seven-day trial, while &lt;a href="https://nomorobo.com/"&gt;Nomorobo&lt;/a&gt; costs $1.99 per month per device after a 14-day trial. If you do decide you need a third-party service, you can use the trial to see if it works for you before committing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xekKA8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to stop annoying robocalls on your iPhone or Android phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21327304/spam-calls-how-to-stop-block-robocalls-robots-scam-iphone-android"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="naAyXD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 30th, 2021, 9:20AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on June 29th, 2020, and has been updated to add that forwarding to 7726 can also be done in the UK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9a55Bo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 9th, 2021, 9AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to reflect current options for apps and phones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODTH1l"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOjUy3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZSvgaC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NDfToq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cs1Q0B"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22555521/spam-text-block-security-iphone-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22555521/spam-text-block-security-iphone-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tinder makes it easier to see if you vibe with someone’s Spotify taste</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E63rjMA6pnz0LDvBELqwbAAUzC4=/0x36:1480x1023/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70249195/Music_Mode.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tinder&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iNAMeE"&gt;Tinder is expanding the ways you can judge a potential match by their musical tastes by introducing a Music Mode, which lets you actually hear the song someone’s set as their “Anthem” before you choose which direction to swipe. Music Mode will integrate with Spotify, like Tinder’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/20/12948514/tinder-spotify-integration-show-top-tracks-anthem"&gt;other music features&lt;/a&gt;, but should make it easier to judge someone by the song they’ve picked to represent themselves — even if you’ve never heard it before, you’ll immediately be able to tell the vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wiENCC"&gt;Music Mode will live in the app’s &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/tinder-adds-a-new-home-for-interactive-social-features-with-launch-of-tinder-explore/"&gt;recently added Explore tab&lt;/a&gt;, which means you can ignore it if you don’t feel like listening to people’s jams right now. Tinder’s product VP Kyle Miller likened Music Mode to “that feeling when you’re at a party and you find out someone else loves the same songs you do.” Something I’ve heard is great but have never gotten to experience thanks to the fact that I exclusively listen to hyperpop shoegaze.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zBstC9Sbnc8LtabSrK3jUxp7ZNg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23073878/Music_Mode___Sizzle_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music Mode will let you hear a potential match’s Anthem as you swipe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PG5WbP"&gt;It’s nice to see Tinder finally building on its Anthem feature, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/20/12948514/tinder-spotify-integration-show-top-tracks-anthem"&gt;it introduced in 2016&lt;/a&gt; and lets you pick a song to feature on your profile and define yourself with. With that said, it’d be nice if the app also integrated with Apple Music — you &lt;a href="https://www.help.tinder.com/hc/en-us/articles/115003358686-I-don-t-have-a-Spotify-account-Can-I-still-add-music-to-my-profile-"&gt;can choose an Anthem without linking a Spotify account&lt;/a&gt;, but you won’t be able to have your top artists automatically added to your profile like Spotify users can. (Us Apple Music users are already used to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CcNo07Xp8aQ"&gt;dancing on our own&lt;/a&gt;, being left out of things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812079/apple-music-year-in-review-spotify-wrapped-social-media"&gt;like the Spotify Wrapped hype&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9XPak3"&gt;The dating app also released some statistics on what music people were setting as their Anthems for 2021 — topping it is Drake’s “Way 2 Sexy (with Future &amp;amp; Young Thug),” followed by Doja Cat and SZA’s “Kiss Me More” and Olivia Rodrigo’s “good 4 u.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RpDw58"&gt;Personally, I feel like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P5mtclwloEQ"&gt;the original “I’m Too Sexy”&lt;/a&gt; would be much more attention-grabbing than Drake’s spin on it, but you do you. Hopefully, though, Tinder will be able to do some sort of sorting for Music Mode so you don’t end up hearing the same song over and over if everyone is using it as their Anthem. The company says Music Mode should become available everywhere you can get Spotify in the coming weeks, and that you’ll be able to use it if you’ve &lt;a href="https://www.help.tinder.com/hc/en-us/articles/115003357846-Connecting-Spotify-to-your-Tinder-profile"&gt;linked your Spotify account&lt;/a&gt; and added an Anthem of your own. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824594/tinder-anthem-music-mode-spotify-dating"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824594/tinder-anthem-music-mode-spotify-dating</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
