<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-07T18:51:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T18:51:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T18:51:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>CBS All Access app having technical difficulties at the start of the Super Bowl</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="CBS logo (STOCK)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D8AshmSXYwzy46uGHB5vHO14ZzA=/3x0:1017x676/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68784702/cbs-logo-stock_1020.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R6e8Wv"&gt;CBS All Access app appeared to be having problems as users tried to watch Super Bowl LV on Sunday. Users reported seeing an error message that read the app was “experiencing technical difficulties” and that “an error has occurred.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rHGKjL"&gt;Down Detector showed a &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/cbs_all_access/"&gt;spike in complaints&lt;/a&gt; for CBS All Access at around 6PM ET Sunday. Numerous users were complaining on Twitter that they could not see the game at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GBQT2C"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;CBS All Access going down, ESPN+ facing massive server related issues the night of UCF 257. These are things that make leagues nervous about streaming initiatives, I imagine! &lt;a href="https://t.co/V8z1FPPyvh"&gt;https://t.co/V8z1FPPyvh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— julia (on vacation till 2/15) alexander (@loudmouthjulia) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/loudmouthjulia/status/1358561628019691520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TG58gh"&gt;It’s the worst possible timing for the app to be unavailable as the Super Bowl between Kansas City and Tampa Bay was getting underway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ovbIa2"&gt;We’ve reached out to CBS to find out what’s going on and will update when we know more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8tacf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271648/cbs-all-access-app-problems-super-bowl"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271648/cbs-all-access-app-problems-super-bowl</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T15:59:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T15:59:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>New trailers: The Nevers, Pacific Rim: The Black, Moxie, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H3EljnMQtoOnO1h-V8pIJKUu4yc=/174x0:1427x835/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68784167/pacific_rim_dark.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Pacific Rim: The Black | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=umtOGzti-XQ&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mbTCdY"&gt;So I watched the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;Servant&lt;/em&gt; and can’t decide whether it’s the slow pacing or the suspension of disbelief (how long can Julian and Sean keep up the plot’s central ruse before they do real damage to Dorothy?) keeping it from being genuinely frightening. I won’t spoil the latest episode, but it feels like for all the disconcerting camera angles and Dorothy’s bizarre behavior, this week’s episode didn’t move the needle all that much. I’m hanging in there, but I think the show needs M. Night Shyamalan to ramp up the scary a li’l bit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="psLsji"&gt;This week’s trailers include a little sci-fi, some teen empowerment, and the third in the &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt; franchise, this time an anime flick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yT3gBC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CWdpBQFgdxQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="u6bpwU"&gt;The Nevers &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="DswgeF"&gt;A group of women in Victorian-era London develop special powers and fight the forces of— yes, OK, yes, got it. In the language of the show, the women are called Touched and regarded as weirdos. Joss Whedon, creator of the &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer &lt;/em&gt;series, is still credited as creator and executive producer even though he departed the production and HBO in November amid an &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/09/warner-bros-ray-fisher-declined-to-speak-to-investigator.html"&gt;investigation into his conduct&lt;/a&gt; as director of &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;. Laura Donnelly, Olivia Williams, and Ann Skelly star in &lt;em&gt;The Nevers&lt;/em&gt;, which debuts on HBO Max in April. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OS0cTs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/umtOGzti-XQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="RCVwOx"&gt;Pacific Rim: The Black &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wes9b9"&gt;I’m trying to think of another movie franchise where the first two were live action and the third is anime (I don’t think &lt;em&gt;Into the Spider-vers&lt;/em&gt;e quite meets that description but man did I love that movie. Anyway!). The world of &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;/em&gt;— Jaegers and Kaiju— returns with the story of two siblings left behind after Australia is overrun by Kaiju, as the two search for their missing parents. &lt;em&gt;Pacific Rim: The Black&lt;/em&gt; is a series of seven 30-minute episodes, which arrives on Netflix March 4th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="empvAp"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ezhm_9ehXU4?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wWG4ev"&gt;Punky Brewster &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="uXPezH"&gt;The original iteration of this show was about a spunky orphan who gets taken in by a crusty older dude who needs some cheer in his life. In other words, a very 1980s sitcom with a very cute kid. The new version of the show has Soleil Moon Frye reprising the role of Punky, this time as a divorced mother of three who meets a foster child who— sitcom plot twist— reminds Punky of herself as a kid. Sure, why not. Cherie Johnson reprises her role as Punky’s best friend Cherie, and Freddie Prinze, Jr. stars as Punky’s ex-husband. &lt;em&gt;Punky Brewster&lt;/em&gt; comes to Peacock February 25th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FOBRKk"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sf34qI1hjKU?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kEAMGv"&gt;Moxie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CunrLX"&gt;Based on the novel by Jennifer Mathieu, &lt;em&gt;Moxie&lt;/em&gt; about shy high school student Vivian (Hadley Robinson) whose mom (Amy Poehler) was a rebel back in the day (“When I was 16, all I cared about was smashing the patriarchy”). The boys at Vivian’s high school are rude jerks who rate the girls based on their looks. She and the other girls at the school finally get fed up, and Vivian publishes a zine called Moxie to expose the bad behavior. Right on. Poehler also directed &lt;em&gt;Moxie, &lt;/em&gt;which hits Netflix on March 3rd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZOdv33"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction February 7th, 4:01PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; This story originally published with an incorrect title for “Pacific Rim: The Black.” We regret the error. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAndL1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCVXlb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271324/new-trailers-nevers-pacific-rim-moxie-punky-brewster-netflix-hbo-peacock"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271324/new-trailers-nevers-pacific-rim-moxie-punky-brewster-netflix-hbo-peacock</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T11:18:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T11:18:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Police in Minneapolis reportedly used a geofence warrant at Floyd protest last year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kqg_9HeYZ9fqYc07hvx9q1UAbIQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68783183/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="speakable-summary"&gt;Police in Minneapolis got a search warrant that ordered Google to provide account data on people who were near a protest that turned violent two days after the killing of George Floyd last year, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/06/minneapolis-protests-geofence-warrant/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M4mjNd"&gt;The search warrant required Google to provide account data for anyone “within the geographical region” of an AutoZone store on May 27th, 2020, to police, according to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;. Photos of a protest outside that store two days after Floyd’s death showed a man in a mask smashing the store windows with an umbrella. The &lt;a href="https://www.startribune.com/police-umbrella-man-was-a-white-supremacist-trying-to-incite-floyd-rioting/571932272/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minneapolis Star Tribune&lt;/em&gt; reported at the time&lt;/a&gt; that police believed the so-called “Umbrella Man” was actually a white supremacist trying to spark violence at the protest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7GiFf2"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;, a police affidavit showed Minneapolis police were seeking information about the identity of “Umbrella Man,” who they considered responsible for sparking violence at what had been peaceful protests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P9NP58"&gt;Geofence warrants, also known as reverse-location warrants, allow authorities to sweep up location data from GPS, Bluetooth, and wi-fi from devices near a crime scene. They often pull in information from people who had nothing to do with the crime, and have&lt;a href="https://www.nyclu.org/en/publications/letter-google-geofence-and-keyword-warrants"&gt; raised privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt;. A Florida man who used a fitness app to track his bike rides briefly found himself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/7/21169533/florida-google-runkeeper-geofence-police-privacy"&gt;a suspect in a 2019 burglary,&lt;/a&gt; when police used a geofence warrant. The man had unknowingly provided information about his location to Google, which placed him near the scene of the crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NK0sk6"&gt;The use of geofence warrants has increased in the past several years; in 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/document/us-v-chatrie-google-amicus-brief-geofence-warrant"&gt;Google reported&lt;/a&gt; the number of such warrants it had received was up 1,500 percent between 2017 and 2018, but did not provide specific numbers. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported that Google received &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/04/13/us/google-location-tracking-police.html"&gt;as many as 180 geofence warrants&lt;/a&gt; in one week in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2jwWBX"&gt;A Minneapolis resident told &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; he had received an email from Google informing him that information from his account was subject to the warrant and was being given to police. The man said he was filming the protest, not participating in it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kkqE69"&gt;Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271068/police-minneapolis-geofence-warrant-george-floyd-protests-google"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271068/police-minneapolis-geofence-warrant-george-floyd-protests-google</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How Sony’s PS5 designers turned PlayStation into something you can feel</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fl4IdCrIk0Cd9SITGXByb2QjZkI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68782941/vpavic_4278_20201030_0206.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Every DualSense controller has 40,000 tiny PlayStation symbols&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="PVXqbD"&gt;When my colleague Andrew Webster &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"&gt;reviewed the PlayStation 5,&lt;/a&gt; he explained how Sony’s next-generation of video games is something you can’t see — you have to &lt;em&gt;touch&lt;/em&gt;. Part of that is how the amazing DualSense controller’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/3/21547303/sony-ps5-dualsense-adaptive-triggers-haptics-teardown-features"&gt;clever motorized triggers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562206/ps5-dualsense-controller-review-games-features-vibrations"&gt;intensely precise vibrations&lt;/a&gt; can recreate the crunching sensation of strutting across a sandy beach or the pitter-patter of rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hWEUsW"&gt;Another part: the &lt;em&gt;40,000 tiny PlayStation symbols &lt;/em&gt;you’ll feel when you pick up the PS5’s new gamepad. As an Easter egg for its fans, the company decided to apply a microtexture to the DualSense controller’s entire lower shell that makes it Sony’s most grippable gamepad yet, because of the thousands upon thousands of tiny squares, triangles, circles and crosses literally at your fingertips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="wsWpqO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10324032"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UW4RzF"&gt;Sony hasn’t previously spoken about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it did this, how many there are, or how large the symbols actually get, but we have those answers today — including behind-the-scenes photos and details from Sony’s Yujin Morisawa and Takeshi Igarashi, the chief designers behind the PS5 and the DualSense respectively. (We even borrowed a fancy industrial microscope so you can see how the symbols look up close.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lzft5B"&gt;Perhaps the most striking part, as you’ll see in images above and below: these tiny symbols are stacked on top of each other, jutting out in three dimensions. They’re not a single, evenly-spaced layer at all, like the tiny dots you might remember on Sony’s DualShock 4 from 2013. They look random, almost organic — which might be because the entire design was sketched out by hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wgqhNZH1vhwNBTBolstW18YN7oI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286810/1.___________.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A study of various microtexture sketches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ajtSQo"&gt;And not just one sketch. Morisawa, the Senior Art Director of Sony’s Design Center Product Design Group, explains that a variety of designs were hand-crafted, digitized, mocked up, applied to actual prototype gamepads, and tested over and over again until the teams found the balance they wanted: good-looking, textured enough to be comfortable and non-slip, but not so sandpaper-rough that it’d hurt your hands over a lengthy gaming session. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sDIbsT"&gt;While designers could easily place the digital version of the texture wherever they wanted in Sony’s CAD programs, Morisawa says that physically comparing and testing different prototypes was key: “While it takes a considerable amount of time to create a prototype, the ‘go/no-go’ judgment of a product is determined the moment you see it and touch it,” he told us by email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NW4FBVs1NYAHFbUTkB0I3qd02ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286811/2.______________1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A comparison of different microtexture variations for molding — including the PS4’s stipple texture at lower right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xXlsZudysFkP8EyZ86J-U_7d5S0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286808/3.________.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testing four different height variations of the same pattern.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vU0Y7aW8rQWyW4OQdhYg28JVcX4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286809/4.______.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An actual molded plate, to confirm the texture works and stays consistent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ME1DssbphJ6fDy0oB_r3LMhBjLc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22287251/5._________.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The layers coming together, digitally, as they’ll appear on the inner lip of the PS5 console.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wPm4kb"&gt;Figuring out the proper heights of the symbols was a lot of work all by itself, as you can see in some of Sony’s behind-the-scenes photos. In the end, they settled on two layers — one roughly 15 microns tall, and another 30 microns tall, according to measurements we made with a Nikon LV100 microscope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A microscope photo of the DualShock 4’s texture shows overlapping square, triangle, circle and cross symbols" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MxhmoIH2dUkrLH3QxNSvs6h5f0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286775/20210203_Sean_Hollister_Verge_5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The larger symbols are roughly half a millimeter wide, and the upper layer are just 30 microns (three hundredths of a millimeter) tall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ALkfHmWH0dPrzP60b1lgWgiHphE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286782/20210203_Sean_Hollister_Verge_6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One downside of the texture: it picks up dirt extremely easily and doesn’t want to let go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8oJVjL"&gt;Actually applying the symbols to the DualSense gamepad was the easy part — because they’re not applied at all. Each and every one of those 40,000 symbols is part of the controller’s shell, created when beads of molten ABS plastic are squeezed into tiny laser-cut crevices during the standard injection-molding process. The design is optimized to keep the symbols intact as they're popped out of the mold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JaTp08"&gt;The trick is having the right equipment to make that mold to start. To create such precise shapes across an entire three-dimensional curved surface, meant to fit into your palms, lasers came in handy. Specifically, a high-end, multi-axis laser engraving machine that Igarashi says is “hard to come by.” The upshot? Because it’s part of the mold, the texture you’ll feel on the PS5’s controller is the same exact one every other owner will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rzSAbFq0vDq4Y2MZQL8TS3vSo7s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286790/3D_CAD____.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A final CAD render check for the PS5 Media Remote’s grip.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mZR3v5Pe5yf1ekRNFnQGajmlSvU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286789/___________________.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sony Interactive Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A texture placement check for the Pulse 3D wireless headset.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8OeMlC"&gt;Sony’s PlayStation controller &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/2/20978071/playstation-dualshock-controllers-modern-shape-design-ps5-25th-anniversary"&gt;has arguably defined decades of gamepads&lt;/a&gt;, so it was no surprise when, for instance, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/18/20970297/google-stadia-review-gaming-streaming-cloud-price-specs-features-chrome-pixel"&gt;Google’s Stadia Controller&lt;/a&gt; came with the same kind of stippled texture that Sony introduced with the DualShock 4 in 2013. But this time around, Sony’s microtexture isn’t just for your hands; the barely-there PlayStation symbols are part of the PS5 experience wherever you’d think to look. You’ll find them on both of the PS5 console’s side panels, on the inner lip. They adorn the grips of the PS5’s optional media remote, the DualSense charging station, the PS5 camera, and Sony’s Pulse 3D wireless headset, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1gE4dG"&gt;They even appear inside at least one game: &lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549072/astros-playroom-ps5-review-dualsense-controller"&gt;the must-play PS5 pack-in&lt;/a&gt;, prominently uses the texture on a number of floors and walls. It makes sense. Not only is &lt;em&gt;Astro&lt;/em&gt; a celebration of the company’s history in gaming, it’s chock-full of PlayStation easter eggs including a few that poke good-natured fun at Sony itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zh-oMyMrQjbRhqzY1NT0yc_45Qo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286874/ASTRO_s_PLAYROOM_20201126105355_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sdEqA4MNUGhrUWQ_R6Hi1QBG5gQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286876/ASTRO_s_PLAYROOM_20201121171654_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poking fun at Sony’s use of the Spider-Man font for its original PS3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aqwICd0E1qU6IsYpnX3gUMBh6SM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22286877/ASTRO_s_PLAYROOM_20201128151135_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The “serial numbers” of Astro’s gadgets pay homage to key Sony figures like &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/16/11242372/playstation-vr-shuhei-yoshida-interview" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shuhei Yoshida&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HVuOyt"&gt;In the PS3 era, Sony often felt arrogant, a little too sure fans would lap up whatever it had to offer — $599 consoles featuring &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/e3-sony-2006-giant-enemy-crab"&gt;giant enemy crabs&lt;/a&gt;, proprietary discs and memory sticks for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/4/20991654/psp-vita-portable-playstation-console-sony-25-anniversary"&gt;its ambitious portables&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/2012/4/27/2977903/playstation-all-star-battle-royale"&gt;Smash Bros. competitor&lt;/a&gt; without enough beloved video game franchises to back it up — but PlayStation has not only earned loads of goodwill since then,  it’s become more self-aware. If the company can stay that way throughout the PS5’s lifecycle (and, you know, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;let people actually buy one&lt;/a&gt;), I have little doubt it’ll be a winner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="CIkHHS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Every game coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"},{"title":"PlayStation 25th anniversary issue","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20970458/playstation-anniversary-ps5-ps4-plus-games-ps3-ps2-25th-sony"},{"title":"PlayStation 5 review: a big, confident step into next gen","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2cFLK9QLiSjg8os8I_Xy6gXOVr0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22015306/vpavic_4278_20201030_0292.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ymZmbw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fi4P32"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/7/22269634/how-sony-designed-ps5-dualsense-playstation-symbol-microtexture"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/7/22269634/how-sony-designed-ps5-dualsense-playstation-symbol-microtexture</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The challenge of redesigning a classic esports logo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E9qgZnM5b6KgsMG-5f4-TkHretw=/200x0:2000x1200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68782881/NIP_Portfolio_2021_Jerseys9_ART_DIRECTION.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Motto.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;How Ninjas in Pyjamas created a new identity &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="yWbpXI"&gt;When Sunny Bonnell and her team at branding agency &lt;a href="https://wearemotto.com/"&gt;Motto&lt;/a&gt; started working with &lt;a href="https://nip.gl/"&gt;Ninjas In Pyjamas&lt;/a&gt; (NIP), a 20-year-old esports team in search of a new look, they did a lot of research. The team had never worked in gaming or esports before, and they wanted to understand the space. They talked to fans and people on the team, and sketched out hundreds of possible logo ideas over the course of more than a year. When &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NIPGaming/status/1353764575385149441"&gt;NIP revealed their new visual identity&lt;/a&gt; last month, the reaction was immediate — and much of it was negative. “I don’t think we really knew at the time that the fans would have such a hard time with it,” says Bonnell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T5bt3M"&gt;NIP was founded in 2000, and the Swedish organization currently operates teams in &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six&lt;/em&gt;, though it’s most famous for its &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike &lt;/em&gt;squad. Its previous logo was a gold shuriken with lots of curves and sharp points. The new iteration maintains the same concept but streamlines it, with neon yellow set against a black backdrop, and an angular shuriken that features a stylized version of the kanji for “nin” inside. It’s brighter, simpler, and more easily recognizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbaO1G"&gt;Bonnell says that the new logo was necessary for a few reasons. These include the flexibility to scale across different platforms, as well as the lack of contrast between the black-and-brown color scheme. “There were just a lot of technical issues with the existing mark,” she says. The challenge, she adds, was making a logo that not only retained the classic iconography associated with the team but also felt fresh and worked across a variety of mediums. “That mark had to do a whole lot of lifting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ba4UKg1swH0iQKe_6RnkoJ21B2s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22283616/01_old_to_new.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LKqaVV"&gt;When the team started working on the project, they really zoomed in on the ninja part of the NIP name. There’s the kanji, as well as a color scheme inspired by the streets of Tokyo, and even an audio element; the designers came up with a signature blade swooshing sound for the team to use in videos and on social media. “I felt that was something they could truly own,” Bonnell says of the ninja elements. “They were lacking something to say. They had cool apparel and great teams, but they didn’t really have anything else that was giving them a story to tell.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="yC9BKq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“That was something they could truly own.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WTXmhn"&gt;One of the challenges of modern logo design is creating something that can work pretty much anywhere. It’s especially tricky in esports. The NIP logo is used as a Twitter icon, a badge on jerseys, and even a virtual sticker that players can put on in-game guns. When in-person tournaments return, the logo will be blown up on big LCD displays on stage. (Bonnell is particularly excited about the last one. “It’s going to be so cool.”) To make something that works in all of these contexts, designers often resort to something flat and simple. The result is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/4/21163766/bmw-new-flat-logo-design-bad-transparent-background-cars"&gt;logos that tend to look the same&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DCzC1"&gt;“It gets trickier over time,” Bonnell says of the process. “The more you add, the more complicated it becomes.” The new NIP logo attempts to get around this in a few ways. For one, the shuriken is set on its side to create a sense of motion, as if it was being thrown. And while the logo is relatively simple, it’s imbued with meaning, like the hidden word inside the weapon. Basically, every element is meant to scream “ninja!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-AIQtRI5kCDEu4pf2z8BoV6MHCo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22283624/NIP_In_Game_CSGO_Gun.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Motto&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BbcYwS"&gt;Giving an existing team a new identity is a tricky proposition. Just like in traditional sports, esports fans are attached to teams and their histories. In fact, when &lt;a href="https://esportsinsider.com/2021/01/dignitas-launches-rebrand-revives-historic-logo-with-modern-twist/"&gt;Dignitas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://esportsinsider.com/2020/05/evil-geniuses-final-rebrand/"&gt;Evil Geniuses&lt;/a&gt;, two long-running organizations, introduced dramatic redesigns, the uproar was so intense they ended up reverting back to their original logos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mULSys"&gt;Despite all of the preparation, Bonnell says she wasn’t completely ready for the amount of blowback the NIP redesign received. “There’s a lot of hate in esports that I don’t know if I was prepared for,” she says. “I had to stop reading the comments, because I was like ‘Oh my god, I want to cry in my cornflakes.’ This is really bad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Cdpkz"&gt;That has mellowed over time, she says. “The first day was rough,” she admits, but says that as time passed and the logo was displayed in more contexts — on jerseys, in actual games — she started to receive positive feedback from fans who changed their minds. While other organizations may have struggled with the initial blowback, Bonnell doesn’t think that will happen with NIP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="eEzVN6"&gt;“First they’ll be ridiculed,” she says, “then they’ll be revered.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22268014/ninjas-is-pyjamas-nip-esports-logo-redesign-motto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22268014/ninjas-is-pyjamas-nip-esports-logo-redesign-motto</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-07T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Super Bowl 2021: how to watch the NFL championship online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NFL: FEB 02 Super Bowl LV Preview" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h6TLXzrG12qBAeLJiqBh896JnDI=/0x0:4800x3200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68782808/1230936504.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lmn4vF"&gt;Super Bowl 2021 — the 55th Super Bowl — is happening today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F5cAQG"&gt;The championship game pits the Kansas City Chiefs, the defending Super Bowl champs, against the Tampa Bay Buccaneers. Eric Church and Jazmine Sullivan will sing the national anthem, while The Weeknd will perform in the halftime show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsCAKI"&gt;If you are planning to watch the football game, you have a few options, and many of them are free. Below, we have listed a few ways you can watch this year’s Super Bowl. Keep in mind that, due to production limits imposed by the pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242680/super-bowl-lv-4k-hdr-cbs-sports-stream-not-available-2021"&gt;Super Bowl 2021 will not be streaming in 4K resolution&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LokHJ3"&gt;Where is the Super Bowl being played? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pY2edn"&gt;Super Bowl 2021 will take place at Raymond James Stadium in Tampa, Florida, the home field of the Buccaneers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Xr1EeI"&gt;What time will the Super Bowl start? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LNJvoo"&gt;The broadcast will begin at 6:30PM ET / 3:30PM PT. But if you want to tune in ahead of kickoff, CBS will be running coverage throughout the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5yDCfi"&gt;What network is televising the Super Bowl?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="nXH8dO"&gt;Super Bowl 2021 will be televised on CBS, the “official” network on which viewers in the US can watch the big game. Last year, the game was televised on Fox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2oemhC"&gt;How can I watch the Super Bowl? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="USholr"&gt;While Super Bowl 21 will be televised on CBS, there are a few ways you can view the game. Below is a list of services, streaming and otherwise, you can take advantage of. Some will require a paid subscription, but most of those include a free trial for first-time users.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Qy9bHL"&gt;On a smart TV or computer:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jwtFqe"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http://atttvnow.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/2020/2/2/21084036/super-bowl-2020-how-to-watch-date-online-time-free-streaming-tv&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T TV Now (seven-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z44N1R"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cbsallaccess.qflm.net/c/482924/175360/3065?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cbs.com%2Fall-access%2F&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;CBS All Access (seven-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="udGiHO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cbs-sports.app.link/skXPjPE3edb"&gt;CBS Sports App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B0POIS"&gt;&lt;a href="http://CBSSports.com"&gt;CBS Sports website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LF3fZF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nfl.smart.link/n4xczlq3t?site_id=ndc_Nav&amp;amp;creative_id=SBLV_W2W"&gt;NFL App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ewXylR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nfl.com%2Fsuper-bowl%2Fways-to-watch%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F7%2F22254400%2Fsuper-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NFL website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B28glj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http://www.hulu.com/live-tv&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/2020/2/2/21084036/super-bowl-2020-how-to-watch-date-online-time-free-streaming-tv&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hulu with Live TV (seven-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nYx5Rd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://tv.youtube.com/"&gt;YouTube TV (five-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vQrg5O"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/http://sling.com?SID=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sling TV (three-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MlvoVw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.fubo.tv/welcome?irad=343747&amp;amp;irmp=482924&amp;amp;sharedid=verge&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/2020/2/2/21084036/super-bowl-2020-how-to-watch-date-online-time-free-streaming-tv&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FuboTV (seven-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lBM83t"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vidgo.com/subscribe-step1"&gt;Vidgo (seven-day free trial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UZWZJt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.locast.org/free-tv/?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZ7WoJGn5wIVF5SzCh1K7goQEAAYASAAEgKJBPD_BwE"&gt;Locast (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2ZhvcL"&gt;On a smartphone or tablet:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Uyqu39"&gt;If you are looking to watch the game on the go or just prefer watching it on a smaller screen, you can stream it using the following apps: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="B7eZYy"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cbs-sports.app.link/skXPjPE3edb"&gt;CBS Sports App&lt;/a&gt; (iOS and Android) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yb51Cw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cbs.app.link/oWrW03WVmdb"&gt;CBS All-Access App&lt;/a&gt; (iOS and Android — subscription or TV provider login required)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UBe2T7"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://CBSSports.com"&gt;CBSSports.com&lt;/a&gt; website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JZTrqe"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://nfl.smart.link/n4xczlq3t?site_id=ndc_Nav&amp;amp;creative_id=SBLV_W2W"&gt;NFL App&lt;/a&gt; (iOS and Android)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zR3xBz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/nfl/live-video/?is_retargeting=true&amp;amp;af_sub1=Partnerships&amp;amp;c=US_Partnerships_YMktg_NFLlive_NFLSocialSunday2C_SportsUsers&amp;amp;pid=InProduct&amp;amp;af_sub5=V1&amp;amp;af_sub2=US_YMktg"&gt;Yahoo Sports App&lt;/a&gt; (iOS and Android) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="K2bvuC"&gt;Any streaming service app that includes CBS or a CBS affiliate &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="1dhyLJ"&gt;Via cable, antenna, or satellite:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="o2A7Z0"&gt;If you’re feeling old-school, you can tune in to the big game through your local CBS channel, either via cable or using an antenna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="pjaVCg"&gt;International options:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="r78oO8"&gt;If you’re watching from outside the US, many countries will have broadcasts. You can see &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nfl.com%2Fsuper-bowl%2Fways-to-watch%2Fcountries-and-languages%23WatchAllCountries&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F7%2F22254400%2Fsuper-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a full list&lt;/a&gt; over on the official NFL website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="no8ZV2"&gt;Here are a few options for viewers overseas to watch the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="muPQ1r"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Canada:&lt;/strong&gt; CTV is one of the few channels in Canada broadcasting Super Bowl 2021. You can watch it on TV or through the CTV Go app, which is available on &lt;a href="https://www.ctv.ca/support/what-platforms-and-devices-can-i-watch-ctv-on-25493367"&gt;a few platforms&lt;/a&gt;, including Android TV, Apple TV, and Amazon Fire TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vZlYvB"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom:&lt;/strong&gt; You can watch the game through Sky Sports, including the &lt;a href="http://skysports.com/"&gt;official Sky Sports website&lt;/a&gt;, or through the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sky.com%2Fshop%2Ftv%2Fsky-go%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F7%2F22254400%2Fsuper-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sky Go app&lt;/a&gt; (if you are a Sky TV customer). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Efv5VA"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Australia:&lt;/strong&gt; Super Bowl 2021 will air on two channels in Australia: ESPN and Channel Seven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="OuMYV3"&gt;Listen to the game:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="XWUjcr"&gt;If you don’t want to watch the game and would rather listen to it, Super Bowl 2021 will be broadcast via several services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OSOHwj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgamepass.nfl.com%2Fpackages%3Fredirected%3Dtrue%26icampaign%3Dgpd-nav-SBLV_waystowatch&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F7%2F22254400%2Fsuper-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NFL GamePass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7O6FTq"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.siriusxm.com%2Fchannels%2Fsiriusxm-nfl-radio&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F7%2F22254400%2Fsuper-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SiriusXM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gA3aAS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://westwoodonesports.com/category/nfl/"&gt;Westwood One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jG7fef"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.radiolasuavecita.com/denver/pase-completo/"&gt;Entravision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22254400/super-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22254400/super-bowl-2021-watch-online-time-free-streaming-tv-nfl</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-06T18:13:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-06T18:13:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: Don’t post your coronavirus vaccination card selfie on social media </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="COVID-19 Vaccine At Nursing Home In Pennsylvania" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/70IuGzM6iW_MsQyjB53Xs8XHb4Q=/0x126:4559x3165/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68781080/1299320748.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Ben Hasty/MediaNews Group/Reading Eagle via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XKtggZ"&gt;Look I know this pandemic has been a long, depressing slog, and even if you’ve masked up, done the social distancing, and have managed to stay virus-free, we’re all good and frazzled at this point. So it’s understandable that now that we have vaccines available, everyone’s impatient to get one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="axHQNM"&gt;But when you finally get the jab, resist the urge to post a humblebrag on Instagram or any other social media platform, because identity thieves may be watching. And, you don’t want to be the newly-vaccinated person whose selfie provides scammers with a template to make &lt;em&gt;fake&lt;/em&gt; vaccination record cards (because if you think isn’t already happening, you would be mistaken).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g1Jrcu"&gt;“Some of you are celebrating your second COVID-19 vaccination with the giddy enthusiasm that’s usually reserved for weddings, new babies, and other life events,” the &lt;a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/2021/02/social-media-no-place-covid-19-vaccination-cards"&gt;Federal Trade Commission wrote in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; on Friday. “You’re posting a photo of your vaccination card on social media. Please — don’t do that! You could be inviting identity theft.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9vInj"&gt;Not only does the card have the vaccinated person’s name and birth date on it, it also includes when and where you got the shot. Unless all your social media accounts are set to private, you’re handing out a lot of free data about yourself you may not want randos on the internet to know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DSkZN6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/06/health/covid-vaccination-card.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; talked to some privacy experts&lt;/a&gt; who said a savvy scam artist could pretend to be a healthcare official to trick people who have received the first dose of the vaccine into thinking they need to pay for the second dose, and get the victims’ credit card information. And, someone could use the photo of your vaccination card to recreate the cards and possibly sell counterfeit versions— something that’s apparently &lt;a href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/13439089/tiktok-vaccine-covid-card-passport-fakes/"&gt;already happening&lt;/a&gt; in the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CAeFjL"&gt;As part of its &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/covid-19/vaccinate-with-confidence.html"&gt;Vaccinate with Confidence&lt;/a&gt; campaign, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has a plan for states to hand out stickers to the newly-vaccinated, an excellent visual to share on social media instead of your vaccination card. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PY6rK3"&gt;So if you have been vaccinated against the coronavirus, please accept my congratulations! We’re all happy for you. But we don’t need to see your vital information all over our social feeds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnWCmO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22270400/coronavirus-vaccine-card-selfie-social-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22270400/coronavirus-vaccine-card-selfie-social-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-06T13:01:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-06T13:01:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Consumer protection agency investigating Venmo’s collection practices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration the Venmo - Share Payments logo..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aq9v7tofFNilEmtFJ_AR_9cDCAo=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68780256/1227801650.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jFJx8p"&gt;The Consumer Finance Protection Bureau is investigating money transfer app Venmo over the way it handles collections, a &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/1633917/000163391721000018/pypl-20201231.htm"&gt;new regulatory filing shows&lt;/a&gt;. First reported by &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/venmos-debt-collection-practices-probed-by-cfpb-11612537319"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the filing shows Venmo owner PayPal received a Civil Investigative Demand from the CFPB on January 21st, “related to Venmo’s unauthorized funds transfers and collections processes, and related matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4trN3"&gt;PayPal said in a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it was working “productively with the CFPB to provide information, as requested, on our practices and processes.” The statement added that Venmo  “remains deeply committed to its compliance obligations and the company works closely with regulators around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Knn7lk"&gt;A Venmo user’s account may be referred to collections if it becomes overdrawn; while money transfers within the app usually occur immediately, sometimes the funds don’t leave the user’s bank account for more than 24 hours. So Venmo covers the amount of the payment in the interim. But if the user’s account doesn’t have the funds available when their bank processes the payment, Venmo tries to recoup the amount it covered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbE5ZM"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; has covered &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/venmo-to-users-if-you-owe-us-money-were-coming-for-it-11553518800"&gt;Venmo’s collection practices&lt;/a&gt; in the past, reporting in 2019 that the company even pursued collections against users who may have been the victims of scammers. Last year, the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; reported that &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/even-in-a-pandemic-venmo-tells-conned-customers-to-pay-up-11600939826"&gt;Venmo pursued collections&lt;/a&gt; at the same rate during the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZp8SA"&gt;Venmo says its user agreement details its potential use of collections, and that it complies with all applicable laws when it pursues collection activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FVMwQV"&gt;Venmo has seen an increase in users during the coronavirus pandemic, as more people used digital payment systems. Earlier this week, &lt;a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/paypal-profit-triples-as-pandemic-drives-continued-surge-in-online-payments-11612387131"&gt;PayPal reported&lt;/a&gt; net income of $1.57 billion for its fourth quarter, up from $507 million a year earlier. Venmo’s active accounts rose 32 percent in 2020 to nearly 70 million, and CEO Dan Schulman said in a &lt;a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4403221-paypal-holdings-inc-pypl-ceo-dan-schulman-on-q4-2020-results-earnings-call-transcript"&gt;call with investors&lt;/a&gt; that the company expects Venmo’s revenue to approach $900 million in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7s1d7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="111E1V"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hxvY6h"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3luwS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="maeP8p"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wR38Z6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="bOgRg2"&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="UBHHFl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zhwVTJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269970/consumer-protection-agency-investigating-venmo-paypal-collections"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269970/consumer-protection-agency-investigating-venmo-paypal-collections</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-06T10:10:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-06T10:10:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Myanmar orders internet providers to block Twitter and Instagram in the country</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Myanmar People Stage Protests As Internet Is Cut" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8up0EiPnlkwX-Hy_37vOhfQ7zgg=/0x1:2998x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68779776/1300658954.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A protester makes three-finger salute as another holds up a poster of de-facto leader Aung San Suu Kyi during an anti-coup march February 6th in Yangon, Myanmar | Photo by Getty Images/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rMAj48"&gt;Not long after it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266031/facebook-myanmar-blocked-instagram-whatsapp-military-coup-protest"&gt;blocked Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, Myanmar has now ordered mobile networks and internet service providers to block Twitter and Facebook-owned Instagram in the country as well. The southeast Asian country’s military &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/05/tech/myanmar-blocks-twitter-instagram/index.html"&gt;seized power in a coup&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week, detaining its civilian leader Aung San Suu Kyi along with other government officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCfuFb"&gt;Facebook users had &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/myanmar-blocks-facebook-access-after-coup-11612436184?mod=pls_whats_news_us_business_f"&gt;reportedly been using&lt;/a&gt; the social media platform to protest the coup, sharing photos of themselves giving the three-finger salute that’s become associated with resistance in the area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iAaEKX"&gt;“All mobile operators, international gateways and internet service providers in Myanmar received a directive on 5 February 2021 from the Myanmar Ministry of Transport and Communications (MoTC) to, until further notice, block the social media platforms Twitter and Instagram,” Norwegian telecom company &lt;a href="https://www.telenor.com/directive-to-block-social-media-services-twitter-and-instagram-in-myanmar/"&gt;Telenor said in a statement late Friday.&lt;/a&gt; The company provides mobile services in Myanmar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hAXbia"&gt;Myanmar’s Ministry of Information issued an ominous statement on Tuesday, a day after the military seized power, instructing people not to spread rumors on social media, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/01/asia/myanmar-military-coup-explainer-intl-hnk-scli/index.html"&gt;CNN reported&lt;/a&gt;. “Some media and public are spreading rumors on social media conducting gatherings to incite rowdiness and issuing statements which can cause unrest. We would like to urge the public not to carry out these acts and would like to notify the public to cooperate with the government in accordance with the existing laws,” the statement read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RC1xa5"&gt;Rafael Frankel, Facebook’s director of public policy, APAC emerging countries, said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company was “extremely concerned” by the shutdown orders, and urged authorities to unblock access immediately. “At this critical time, the people of Myanmar need access to important information and to be able to communicate with their loved ones,” Frankel said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBQqPr"&gt;A Twitter spokesperson echoed that concern, saying in an email to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the order “undermines the public conversation and the rights of people to make their voices heard. The Open Internet is increasingly under threat around the world. We will continue to advocate to end destructive government-led shutdowns.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ybBNW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 6th, 11:13AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Adds statements from Facebook and Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269831/myanmar-orders-block-twitter-facebook-instagram-military-coup"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269831/myanmar-orders-block-twitter-facebook-instagram-military-coup</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-06T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-06T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Why the FDA is taking 22 days to look over J&amp;J’s data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, a vial and a medical syringe..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsWXUsbI2i5mr2yBPQ5OX1YfPCM=/0x0:4800x3200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68779704/1230084558.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZQpiQS"&gt;A billion years ago last summer, people were getting antsy about vaccines. They wanted things to move faster, maybe skip a few steps in clinical trials to speed things up. This was, at the time, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21352706/covid-19-vaccine-steps-process-clinical-trials-speed-moderna"&gt;generally considered a bad idea&lt;/a&gt; that would result in less accurate data and cause people to lose trust in the vaccines. Now, exactly 1.589 trillion years later, recklessly speeding things up for speed’s sake remains a poor choice, but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NateSilver538/status/1357493589031452679"&gt;some people on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; like journalist Nate Silver, seem to think we should do it anyways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TCwXOS"&gt;They take particular issue with the fact that while Johnson and Johnson submitted their data from their giant clinical trial this week, the Food and Drug Administration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22267984/covid-vaccine-johnson-fda-one-dose-review"&gt;will take until February 26th to review the data&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rGZjm"&gt;Three weeks can feel like an eternity during the pandemic, with hospitals crowded and deaths still climbing. It’s easy to be flip about the process and want things to Just. Go. Faster. But the 22 days is not that much longer than the &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-announces-advisory-committee-meeting-discuss-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;20 days the agency&lt;/a&gt; took to review data for Pfizer/BioNTech’s vaccine or the &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-announces-advisory-committee-meeting-discuss-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;17 days for Moderna&lt;/a&gt;’s candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="oaUzAb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pMfiqT"&gt;Here’s what’s going to happen during those days. Researchers at the FDA will have to review the data from the 43,783 people who participated in the trial. This will entail looking at the cases across all study sites — here in the US, in Latin America and in South Africa, where a new coronavirus variant is dominant. The typical review process for a vaccine can take months. Instead, it will happen in a few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ADXeE"&gt;If the process is anything like what the FDA planned for the earlier vaccine candidates, those weeks will be filled with a lot of late nights and workers doing everything that they can to reasonably speed things up. “Groups have been working in shifts, nights and weekends, looking in parallel at issues of clinical effectiveness and safety, and of levels of antibodies to confirm the way the vaccine is working.” the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;reported in December. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3kDTC"&gt;Why do all that work? Right now, the information that we have about the vaccine comes from the company. That information is promising, and shows that it will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/30/22257557/antivirus-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine-results"&gt;probably be a good vaccine&lt;/a&gt;. But there are reasons that the FDA doesn’t just take a company at its word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="trKBd6"&gt;Let’s turn &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KendraWrites/status/1357521813190893572"&gt;to noted scientific historian Billy Joel&lt;/a&gt;, and the “children of thalidomide.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NuYYmu"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eFTLKWw542g?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NYtmhB"&gt;Thalidomide was a sedative that was given&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/23/health/thalidomide-survivors-usa.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedLinks&amp;amp;pgtype=Article"&gt; to pregnant people&lt;/a&gt; in the 1960’s as a cure for morning sickness. It caused birth defects in thousands of children across the world. In the US, pregnant women were given the drug in clinical trials, but unlike other countries, it wasn’t approved for sale at the time, thanks to Frances Kelsey. Kelsey was a drug reviewer at the FDA who looked over data from the company trying to sell the drug and found it unconvincing. The incident &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4101807/"&gt;led to new laws&lt;/a&gt; that let the FDA determine a drug’s safety &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;effectiveness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbV9vH"&gt;Taking the time to review a vaccine during a pandemic might seem like rearranging deck chairs on the Titanic — but it’s actually inspecting the lifeboats before you leave port. We have procedures and protocols for a reason. When we launch something big, like a rocket, engineers don’t just push a button and send it soaring. They go through detailed pre-flight checklists, making sure that every bit of a spaceship is sound. We’ve learned the hard way that &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=5175151"&gt;disregarding safety procedures can cost lives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yszDNe"&gt;Pushing out a third vaccine quickly might help save lives, yes. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21266591/covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorize-emergency-experimental"&gt;only if people are willing to take it&lt;/a&gt;. Some &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2021/02/why-arent-more-health-care-workers-getting-vaccinated.html"&gt;healthcare workers&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2021/02/why-arent-more-health-care-workers-getting-vaccinated.html"&gt;already hesitant&lt;/a&gt; to take the vaccine. They worry that the process is rushed. Rushing the process &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; isn’t likely to convince them — people who generally are not opposed to vaccines — that the process is safe and secure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJchl8"&gt;I get it. Waiting sucks. But when you’re injecting people with a new treatment and the trust of billions of people is on the line, sometimes it’s worth taking the time to double-check your work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="97HnSe"&gt;Here’s what else is happening this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lbQ42S"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xWcXfm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22266344/covid-vaccine-protection-chronic-long-haul"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientists want to know if vaccinated people can still become COVID-19 long-haulers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data from trials has shown that COVID-19 vaccines have done a stellar job at preventing severe cases of disease. But it’s still unclear whether they can prevent chronic COVID-19 symptoms. (Nicole Wetsman/&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QbHvRg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2021/02/covid-19-flu-season/617924/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Pandemic Broke the Flu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The flu appears to have taken the year off. While COVID-19 has dominated the planet, our regular seasonal virus appears to have mostly stayed home. It’s not clear what will happen  (Katherine J Wu/&lt;em&gt;The Atlantic)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IQ62tz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/04/native-americans-coronavirus-covid-death-rate"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indigenous Americans dying from Covid at twice the rate of white Americans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;One in every 475 Native Americans has died of COVID-19, a rate that is higher than any other community in the US. The toll is especially brutal for smaller communities, who face disproportionate losses. (Nina Lakhani/&lt;em&gt;The Guardian)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pPltdV"&gt;Development &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8gaBZT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/03/world/europe/vaccine-coronavirus-variants.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vaccine Puzzle: Who Should Get Which Shot?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Some places in the world are already juggling three different vaccines — and distributing them is getting very complicated. (Benjamin Mueller and Rebecca Robbins/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iy9nTD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/02/03/with-a-seductive-number-astrazeneca-study-fueled-hopes-that-eclipsed-its-data/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With a seductive number, AstraZeneca study fueled hopes that eclipsed its data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;A study of Astra Zeneca’s vaccine found that people who were vaccinated were less likely to carry the virus. That statistic got misinterpreted as proof that the vaccine decreased &lt;em&gt;transmission&lt;/em&gt; of the virus. It might, but that hasn’t been proven yet. (Matthew Herper and Helen Branswell/&lt;em&gt;STAT&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UM30df"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/02/02/1017161/covid-vaccine-asymptomatic-transmission-pfizer-trial/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you got the vaccine. Can you still infect people? Pfizer is trying to find out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;People are still trying to understand how vaccines affect transmission, but it’s incredibly complicated. Here’s why.  (Antonio Regalado/&lt;em&gt;MIT Tech Review&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rHB8z"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/03/health/vaccine-novavax.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After a Rocky Start, Novavax Vaccine Could Be Here by Summer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Novavax’s vaccine candidate has gotten off to a slower start than many of its competitors, but it is now well on its way.  (Katie Thomas/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DuDFHw"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="8qlS27"&gt;I had my espresso with foamed milk, even though coffee is disgusting to me now. I do not enjoy the taste. But I have a cup of coffee almost every morning. It’s like ritual, right? I enjoy the process of making it, and the warmth, and the caffeine. So I keep doing it, and I keep hoping that it will taste good to me at some point. I feel like I’m using my imagination when I eat, trying to use my memory of how things smell and taste to recreate the experience, because otherwise I would not want to eat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0BZgjO"&gt;—Meema Spadola &lt;a href="https://www.eater.com/2021/2/5/22267667/covid-19-loss-distorted-taste-smell-anosmia-parosmia-symptom-food-diaries"&gt;tells &lt;em&gt;Eater&lt;/em&gt;’s Jenny Zhang&lt;/a&gt;. Zhang interviewed people whose sense of taste and smell had not recovered after contracting COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vtxWyD"&gt;More than numbers &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MCgoqT"&gt;To the more than 105,485,261 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJqlmP"&gt;To the families and friends of the 2,301,169 people who have died worldwide — 459,571 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baWk6u"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfxmpx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269580/fda-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine-covid-review-antivirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/6/22269580/fda-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine-covid-review-antivirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
