<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-08T02:45:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T02:45:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T02:45:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo teases retractable rear camera for phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LTrYZpknmIRBlb2ESvWB1D_RGaE=/0x0:1119x746/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70243251/Screenshot_2021_12_08_at_16.19.32.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XjsbeB"&gt;Oppo has released a brief video hinting at a new type of camera design for smartphones. The company’s “self-developed retractable camera” is shown extending from the phone’s body before retracting back inside. The video suggests that the mechanism is waterproof and that it’ll automatically retract the camera if the phone is dropped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v6UIgo"&gt;Unlike pop-up selfie cameras that hide themselves inside a phone until needed, moving the camera back and forth on the Z-axis could have implications for image quality, though Oppo hasn’t yet claimed anything about any optical advantages of this design. It doesn’t appear to be a zoom lens, given it’s marked simply as 50mm, but it could theoretically help improve telephoto performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="B6GnXn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Most pop-ups are annoying... &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But not our self-developed retractable camera!   &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Explore more in INNO WORLD on 14/12.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/OPPOINNODAY2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#OPPOINNODAY2021&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/33hgJSw8If"&gt;pic.twitter.com/33hgJSw8If&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— OPPO (@oppo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/oppo/status/1468143243183468556?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vlj0TN"&gt;The markings on the camera module show that the sensor is 1/1.56 inches and the lens is 50mm-equivalent with an f/2.4 aperture, meaning it should be around 2x longer than the phone’s main lens. That’s a much bigger sensor than you tend to find behind telephoto lenses, so maybe the extra height allowed by the retracting mechanism is what makes this possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9TwZRR"&gt;Oppo is releasing this video ahead of next week’s annual Inno Day event, where the company often shows off various concepts and technologies before they’re commercially deployed. Last year’s event featured &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571056/oppo-x-2021-rolling-phone-ar-glass-concept-inno-day-2020"&gt;a rollable phone and AR glasses&lt;/a&gt;. This year, Oppo is holding Inno Day across two days, December 14th and 15th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823689/oppo-retractable-phone-camera-teaser-inno-day-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823689/oppo-retractable-phone-camera-teaser-inno-day-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T22:01:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T22:01:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elizabeth Holmes smiles on the stand as her trial nears an end</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xOpegldUNRMhHH5Oix3jblD2fw8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242786/vpavic_20211207_4918_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A scattershot day in court&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="O6wWoR"&gt;I expected more fireworks from a cross-examination of former Theranos CEO Elizabeth Holmes. Instead, today was a disjointed day of questions without a clear narrative throughline. I don’t know why the government chose to send an assassin who didn’t know when to twist the knife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ufB5Jl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Today was scattered&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KB9t2Q"&gt;The defense presented a strong narrative on its direct examination. Holmes was a young CEO who believed in Theranos’ technology and had some very credentialed advisors who led her to believe it was real. There was real intellectual property. Holmes never sold her shares. And while she hadn’t done anything wrong, she was also being abused by her boyfriend, Theranos’ president Sunny Balwani, and maybe that clouded her judgment. (Balwani is Holmes’ co-defendant, but he is being tried separately.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eiG1Dt"&gt;To counter that, the prosecution needed to show Holmes fully in control. She’s facing 11 counts of wire fraud and conspiracy to commit wire fraud — central to proving that charge is showing that she knowingly lied. On the first day of direct testimony, prosecutor Robert Leach drove her control home: Holmes owned most of the company. She could have fired anyone there, including both Balwani and her entire board of directors. Balwani had not kept secrets from her about what was going on in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ufAfhV"&gt;Today was more scattered. Leach did score some points, but he didn’t carry through the narrative thread about Holmes’ control. Here’s a brief overview of the cross-examination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MskG2p"&gt;Holmes admitted that Theranos devices weren’t on medevac helicopters, as several investors claimed Holmes told them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ukN8zG"&gt;Holmes knew it would be wrong to tell an investor Theranos didn’t use third-party machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uwLNWB"&gt;Holmes acknowledged that different financial projections were given to investors and the people calculating Theranos’ stock option values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pK5kXI"&gt;Holmes knew there were a bunch of things wrong in a big &lt;em&gt;Fortune &lt;/em&gt;article, but promoted it anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dpX6Bw"&gt;Emails showed Theranos did special preparation for demo tests, and didn’t report results they were having trouble with &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="loRlp4"&gt;A 2010 slideshow from a Theranos scientist, which Holmes cited as part of her belief in the technology, was forward-looking and contained more aspirations than facts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="528Hqm"&gt;Patents are not the same thing as working devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W9GgiR"&gt;The published journal articles, which Holmes also cited as part of her belief in Theranos technology, were after the period in which the alleged fraud took place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qFj5HX"&gt;Holmes knew the 2015 CMS inspection was going badly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="SYFh3b"&gt;If there was a theme, it was that Holmes didn’t recall a lot of events. But given how the defense &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22705156/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-aging-the-case-rosendorff"&gt;delayed the trial&lt;/a&gt;, that seems possible — after all, a lot of this was more than five years ago, and some of the testimony concerned things from 10 years ago. It’s easier to say “I don’t recall” about events that happened 10 years ago than it is to say it about something that happened yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUwJRu"&gt;Personally, I was miffed because a promised discussion of “trade secrets,” which Holmes had offered as a reason she didn’t tell people about Theranos’ use of modified third-party machines, hardly came up. (Leach said we’d get to trade secrets last week, when Holmes used the phrase liberally in her answers.) Some corporations &lt;a href="http://tsi.brooklaw.edu/commentary/trade-secrets-trolls-0"&gt;abuse trade secrets&lt;/a&gt; to protect information that has no competitive use — mainly to keep consumers in the dark. Arguably, Theranos’ use of trade secrets could fall into this category! But I guess we won’t find out, because Leach didn’t make this argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QnMYYw"&gt;Helicopters and other military toys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Sj0Pju"&gt;Several investors — Lisa Peterson, Brian Grossman, and Bryan Tolbert — told the court that Holmes said the Theranos devices were used by the military, either on medevacs or in theater in places such as Afghanistan. Their testimony was echoed by Steven Burd, CEO of Safeway, which was one of Theranos’ business partners, and by Roger Parloff, the journalist who wrote a &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt; article that’s been heavily cited in the trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="EDtam3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I don’t think I said that.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iTRJaj"&gt;Holmes testified that Theranos devices weren’t being used by the military, aside from in one small burn study. She agreed it would have been wrong to tell people otherwise. And she said she never told anyone that Theranos’ devices were used on military helicopters. “I don’t think I said that,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nUiGiB"&gt;She also testified that it would be wrong to tell a potential investor that Theranos didn’t buy any devices from third parties. But we didn’t delve into why Holmes conveniently left out that Theranos &lt;em&gt;was &lt;/em&gt;using third-party devices; Holmes’ excuse was trade secrets, and the prosecution didn’t convincingly respond to that. It might have been helpful to suggest there was a &lt;a href="https://www.newadvent.org/cathen/11251b.htm"&gt;sin of omission&lt;/a&gt; here — that by withholding information, Holmes had functionally lied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWaNG7"&gt;The prosecution didn’t do that, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eeSkam"&gt;Weird revenue projections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OELqps"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674657/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-wire-fraud-financial-witness"&gt;The first witness&lt;/a&gt; in the trial, Danise Yam, had testified that she &lt;a href="https://files.cand.uscourts.gov/files/18-CR-258%20USA%20v.%20Holmes/Trial%20Exh.%202623/Trial%20Exh.%202623%20Email%20From%20D.Y.%20To%20Elizabeth%20Holmes;%207.16.2015.pdf"&gt;got revenue projections&lt;/a&gt; from Holmes to send to an analytics firm that was &lt;a href="https://files.cand.uscourts.gov/files/18-CR-258%20USA%20v.%20Holmes/Trial%20Exh.%205190/Trial%20Exh.%205190%20Email%20Attachment.pdf"&gt;pricing Theranos’ stock options&lt;/a&gt;. These numbers were notably smaller than what Holmes was showing investors: showing a projection of about $53 million in revenue in 2015 and $153 million in 2016. In documents investors received, 2015 revenue was projected at $140 million and 2016 revenue was expected to be $990 million. These are extremely different numbers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="RF0uUa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It doesn’t look good that the people pricing the options got lower estimates than potential investors&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wRbmpV"&gt;Holmes didn’t have a good explanation for why those numbers were so radically different, suggesting maybe there was something to do with a pharmaceutical contract. Leach knocked that down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GG9qiu"&gt;It doesn’t look good that the people pricing the options got lower estimates than potential investors — either the options were being under-priced or the investors were being misled. This was where I’d expected Leach to ask more questions: &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; were the models different? If it was because of different methodologies, why were they chosen? Who chose them? Why did Holmes allow this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9lvgX"&gt;Instead, he moved on to his next topic without probing further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Lw6i3p"&gt;Out for Blood?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="7B3Hqb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/"&gt;Roger Parloff’s article for &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; had put Theranos on the map for a lot of people. Holmes claimed she didn’t send it to shareholders — right before we saw an email from Theranos to its shareholders, linking the article. She also used it in investor presentations, even though she knew there were things wrong in the article. Holmes made no effort to correct those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uVQovR"&gt;We went through the article. There was no mention of modified third-party devices; instead, the article claimed Theranos &lt;em&gt;did not buy third-party analyzers&lt;/em&gt;. That was wrong, Holmes admitted. Theranos did not offer more than 200 tests, as the article claimed, Holmes said. And it wasn’t true that Theranos’ labs took up a fraction of the space of conventional labs, Holmes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmi8wi"&gt;Leach could have lingered on Holmes’ lack of corrections to the article, the way her defense team had lingered on how Holmes didn’t receive negative feedback directly from pharma companies. He didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ps9uqT"&gt;Demo derby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JaW6pB"&gt;Leach then attempted to show that Holmes had misled investors by controlling their experiences in product demonstrations. In order to do that, some test results were suppressed. In other cases, Theranos employees made plans to make &lt;em&gt;certain&lt;/em&gt; would-be investors received finger sticks — which Theranos touted as its revolutionary technology — instead of conventional venous draws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Fxw0G1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We cannot tell them their order prompts venous if it does.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xPyjkc"&gt;In an email thread from October 2014, Theranos employees were preparing for a visit from potential investors. People from BDT Capital Partners were going to get their blood drawn. “Assumptions here from EAH [Elizabeth A Holmes] that we must not do venous draws, and we cannot tell them their order prompts venous if it does,” wrote Christian Holmes in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="70r1SK"&gt;He then laid out scenarios for what to do if venous draws were required. One possibility was to tell members of the group that certain tests couldn’t be done. Was this to conceal from BDT Capital Partners that Theranos relied on venous draws? No, Holmes said. Ultimately, BDT Capital Partners didn’t invest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QEUEcw"&gt;For a Walgreens demo in 2013, Theranos upper management meddled again. Several results were struck because “these are all running low, possibly abnormally,” wrote Theranos VP Daniel Young in an email. Theranos didn’t tell Walgreens they struck these tests or why, even though Walgreens was a business partner. Leach pointed out that Holmes could have chosen, instead, to have a frank discussion about some of Theranos’ struggles with its tests. She chose not to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nkPXeP"&gt;The believer?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="77mRoj"&gt;During Holmes’ direct exam, her defense team &lt;a href="https://files.cand.uscourts.gov/files/18-CR-258%20USA%20v.%20Holmes/Trial%20Exh.%207098/Trial%20Exh.%207098%20Email.pdf"&gt;trotted out a slideshow from 2010&lt;/a&gt; as proof that Theranos’ tech was real. Leach pointed out that in slide after slide, the scientist author wrote in the future tense. It was about the tech’s &lt;em&gt;potential.&lt;/em&gt; In the slideshow, there was discussion of “candidate technologies,” with lots of “TBDs.” That meant “to be determined,” Holmes confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4veDvg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The device it described does not exist&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dK3sQP"&gt;“There was still work to be done,” Holmes conceded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IKVPTk"&gt;Similarly, Theranos’ patents were the subject of much discussion by Holmes’ defense. But patents are not the same thing as working devices, Leach pointed out. He then pulled up Holmes’ very first patent. The device it described does not exist. “Not yet,” Holmes said, laughing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NnhFSy"&gt;The defense had also pointed out that Theranos &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; published peer-reviewed work about its systems. Leach responded by asking Holmes to read the dates on the papers. All of them had been submitted in 2017 — and therefore couldn’t have influenced her state of mind during the period the government says that fraud was committed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="S1GDUQ"&gt;Exit interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sIPeTi"&gt;Leach pointed out that Holmes had been kept in the loop about how badly the regulators’  inspection of Theranos’ lab was going by Balwani over text. He also showed an email that gave a schedule for Holmes, who had taken a flight to Florida to receive an award on the first day of the inspection. (The schedule noted that Holmes had to be physically present at a lunch to get the award.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="0PJrz7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Holmes seemed amused on the stand&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Gzdz6u"&gt;The inspectors did an exit interview with Theranos before they left. Holmes was there. Leach asked if Holmes was told that the lab would be found to be putting patients’ health in immediate jeopardy, which Holmes staunchly denied. She was shown a document the rest of the court didn’t see — and said it didn’t refresh her memory. Holmes said she thought she was talking with inspectors about what Theranos had done properly. It wasn’t entirely clear what the point of this line of questioning was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g7tpWO"&gt;And with that, the cross-examination sputtered to a halt. Holmes seemed amused on the stand, often smiling or laughing at Leach. Maybe she sensed she had the upper hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ryeDMf"&gt;Here’s the thing about stories: people remember them. They form an organizing backbone for facts, making the facts more memorable. Holmes’ defense made an emotional case with a narrative throughline — easy to remember. But Leach’s inept response didn’t give the jury another narrative to counter that, and it certainly didn’t pack the emotional punch of Holmes’ direct testimony. Leaving the court, I had the distinct sense that the prosecution had botched a prime opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xWG24y"&gt;Holmes’ attorneys will have a chance to ask her more questions tomorrow, potentially poking more holes in the government’s case and reinforcing their own narrative. After she leaves the stand, there’s very little left to hear — Holmes’ defense has been coy about whether they will call another witness. They may not have to.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823361/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-fraud-trial-cross-examination"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823361/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-fraud-trial-cross-examination</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T19:34:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T19:34:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter’s new CEO wants the company to move a lot faster</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_MrWBQLA85uTU0O8Xdpii5WUg54=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242324/acastro_211129_4896_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Parag Agrawal | Photo Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7xZAaG"&gt;The new CEO of Twitter, Parag Agrawal, has a clear message: expect the social network to move a lot faster than it has in the past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zhvRgB"&gt;In his first public appearance since taking the reins of Twitter from co-founder Jack Dorsey, Agrawal says his top priority is “improving our execution” and streamlining how Twitter operates. His comments, made at the Barclays technology conference, come after activist investor Elliott Management shook up Twitter’s board of directors last year and pressured Dorsey to step down from his part-time CEO role. Dorsey remains the CEO of Block (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812752/square-changing-name-block-jack-dorsey-cash-app-tidal-crypto-spiral"&gt;formally called Square&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UoBMEO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I believe we have set them up so they can really move fast”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FAHZHd"&gt;Despite being Twitter’s CEO &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;for only nine days&lt;/a&gt;, Agrawal has already made big changes to its upper ranks. He &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816362/twitter-reoganization-consumer-revenue-tech-dantley-davis-parag-agrawal"&gt;reorganized the company last Friday&lt;/a&gt; under the key pillars of Consumer, Revenue, and Core Tech, with a general manager running each division. “I believe we have set them up so they can really move fast,” he now says. As part of the change, two executives who previously reported to Dorsey — engineering lead Michael Montano and Dantley Davis, the head of design and research — plan to leave at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ijs59d"&gt;“We were operating previously in a functional structure where we had a single engineering organization, a single design research organization, and product teams that were matrixed into them,” Agrawal says, implying that the setup slowed the company down. Along with the three new general managers — who are Kayvon Beykpour, Bruce Falck, and Nick Caldwell — Lindsey Iannucci was named VP of Operations. “She’s going to help us improve our operational rigor in this new structure to really get us to faster decision making, clearer ownership, increased accountability, improved operations, which will result in faster execution overall and better results,” according to Agrawal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FYMPms"&gt;His focus on speed was a reoccurring theme throughout the roughly 30-minute interview. He explained how, in his &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808756/twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-jack-dorsey-bluesky-moderation"&gt;previous role as chief technology officer&lt;/a&gt;, he focused on rebuilding the company’s aged technical stack so that products could be shipped faster. He admitted there has been “slow decision making because of so much coordination that needed to happen” between teams to get changes out the door. His comments amounted to a direct acknowledgment that Twitter hasn’t met expectations from investors since it went public, and that the company has been slow to address shifts in user behavior over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Mf5jfb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The opportunity around DMs is really key”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J60DUZ"&gt;When asked about Twitter’s just-announced acquisition &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822184/twitter-quill-messaging-platform-dms-slack"&gt;of the messaging app Quill&lt;/a&gt;, Agrawal called direct messages “a key product bet” — a refreshing sentiment given that DMs have been woefully underdeveloped for a long time. “The opportunity around DMs is really key,” he said, adding that “it’s a way you can connect with anyone in the world and expect to hear back from them.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823093/twitter-new-ceo-parag-agrawal-move-faster-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823093/twitter-new-ceo-parag-agrawal-move-faster-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T19:25:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T19:25:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>An Amazon server outage caused problems for Alexa, Ring, Disney Plus, and deliveries</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration an Amazon Web Services logo seen..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EVu4i0c_YWVLUdA-WvFOOWrbvps=/0x209:5000x3542/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70240006/1230840274.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Igor Golovniov/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HsxliB"&gt;Problems with some Amazon Web Services cloud servers are causing slow loading or failures for significant chunks of the internet. Amazon’s widespread network of data centers powers many of the things you interact with online, including this website, so as we’ve seen in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21719396/amazon-web-services-aws-outage-down-internet"&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; AWS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/28/14765042/amazon-s3-outage-causing-trouble"&gt;outage incidents&lt;/a&gt;, any problem has massive rippling effects. People started noticing problems at around 10:45AM ET, and just after 6PM ET the AWS Status showed “Many services have already recovered, however we are working towards full recovery across services.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="lI8pyl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon’s internal apps went down, too, cutting off some delivery drivers and stalling warehouse robots&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yicS6U"&gt;While some affected services that rely on AWS have been restored, the internet is still a bit slower and more unsteady than usual. The most important app impacted by the outage might be the ones that Amazon employees use. &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/07/amazon-web-services-outage-causes-issues-at-disney-netflix-coinbase.html"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt; points out Reddit posts from Amazon Flex, warehouse, and delivery workers who say &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822736/amazon-delivery-van-atoz-app-warehouse-outage-aws"&gt;the apps that keep track of packages, tell them where to go, and generally keep your items on time went down, too&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLyUbN"&gt;There have been reports of outages for Disney Plus and Netflix streaming, as well as games like &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Valorant.&lt;/em&gt; We also noticed some problems accessing &lt;a href="http://Amazon.com"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; and other Amazon products like the Alexa AI assistant, Kindle ebooks, Amazon Music, and security cameras from Ring or Wyze. The &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/"&gt;DownDetector&lt;/a&gt; list of services with simultaneous spikes in their outage reports runs off nearly any recognizable name: Tinder, Roku, Coinbase, both Cash App and Venmo, and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hERNiN"&gt;There were &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29473630"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/rb226w/aws_outage/"&gt;network admins&lt;/a&gt; everywhere about errors connecting to Amazon’s instances and the AWS Management Console that controls their access to the servers. After about an hour of problems, Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://status.aws.amazon.com/"&gt;official status page&lt;/a&gt; added an update with messages confirming the outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KjgLO8"&gt;[11:26 AM PST] We are seeing impact to multiple AWS APIs in the US-EAST-1 Region. This issue is also affecting some of our monitoring and incident response tooling, which is delaying our ability to provide updates. Services impacted include: EC2, Connect, DynamoDB, Glue, Athena, Timestream, and Chime and other AWS Services in US-EAST-1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYGg42"&gt;The root cause of this issue is an impairment of several network devices in the US-EAST-1 Region. We are pursuing multiple mitigation paths in parallel, and have seen some signs of recovery, but we do not have an ETA for full recovery at this time. Root logins for consoles in all AWS regions are affected by this issue, however customers can login to consoles other than US-EAST-1 by using an IAM role for authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="xyKq2j"&gt;With the problems coming from the US-EAST-1 AWS region in Virginia, users elsewhere may not have seen as many issues, and even if you were affected, it could manifest as slightly slower loading while the network rerouted your requests somewhere else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlT80z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 7th, 3:41PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information about impacts for warehouse and delivery workers, and most recent status message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6l0P7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 7th, 7:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information about impacts for warehouse and delivery workers, and most recent status message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822332/amazon-server-aws-down-disney-plus-ring-outage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822332/amazon-server-aws-down-disney-plus-ring-outage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T19:09:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T19:09:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft rolls out Notepad with dark mode for Windows 11 Insiders</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Y9IMJA21J8zOF92R5iRMZ9dNps=/0x0:1419x946/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242234/NotepadDarkFindReplace.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LDDPta"&gt;Microsoft is testing &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2021/12/07/redesigned-notepad-for-windows-11-begins-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders/"&gt;a redesign of its venerable Notepad app&lt;/a&gt;, adding some welcomed modern features like a dark mode, a better search / find and replace interface, better undoing, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KO7btm"&gt;While the visual updates like the addition of dark mode, updated right-click menu, and Windows’ &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/apps/design/style/mica"&gt;new theme-adopting material&lt;/a&gt; are nice, the functional updates will probably be the biggest upgrade to anyone who actually writes in Notepad. In the current version of the app that ships with Windows 11, the text search tool and the find and replace tool are two different pop-up windows, accessed by two different keyboard shortcuts. The redesign combines them into one floating bar instead of something that looks like it’s from the XP era. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BdlH6lCr_XVOR8G-ZezEfL-WBP0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23071497/Find_replace.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find and Replace still has some quirks in the preview (like not automatically wrapping), but it’s definitely a more modern experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CzaOyx"&gt;Microsoft also says it’s adding multi-step undo, which replaces the old version’s undo system that only lets you go back one step. It still doesn’t work like you might expect a modern app to, letting you hit Ctrl-Z to delete one word at a time, but it clearly has more memory than the old version of Notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RIK8daT8NqQRC0Oy5gJwH7mqUKM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23071477/Untitled_Project.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notepad’s new undo system is an improvement, but it’d be hard to call it modern.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mglB2w"&gt;Another unfortunate thing about the preview is that Word Wrap is still off by default. It’s got a new home in the View menu, though — and with the Font button going to the Edit dropdown, the old Notepad’s “Format” menu is no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yV94Sq"&gt;It seems like Microsoft is focused on smaller updates to make Notepad feel less like a relic, rather than stuffing it full of new features and turning it into an entirely different app. That seems like the right move to me, given the existence of Notepads’ perhaps &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPad"&gt;lesser-known sibling WordPad&lt;/a&gt;, which is closer to Microsoft Word than a plaintext editor. (WordPad also lets you view and edit .docx files, unlike even the new version of NotePad.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4EjpyF"&gt;The Notepad redesign should be available for Windows 11 Insiders using the Dev channel. If you’re running the test version of the OS and don’t see it, you may want to check for an update in the Microsoft Store. Everyone else will likely have to wait a little bit to get it, but it’s nice to see Microsoft continue the trend of updating some of its built-in apps like Notepad, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679132/microsoft-windows-11-new-photos-app-design-features"&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631442/microsoft-windows-11-paint-redesign-update-app"&gt;Paint&lt;/a&gt; alongside its bigger products like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/2/22814069/microsoft-new-office-ui-rounded-available-now"&gt;Office&lt;/a&gt; and, of course, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822651/microsoft-windows-11-notepad-redesign-find-replace-insider"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822651/microsoft-windows-11-notepad-redesign-find-replace-insider</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Don’t Look Up is an absurdist mirror of our reality — before it just becomes a regular mirror</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Don’t Look Up" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Co8Akim8LkITKAJXlcw6oL7YtK0=/0x0:7200x4800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242203/DLU_20201203_02259_R.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Niko Tavernise / Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="w5vFgX"&gt;For a goofy satire about a comet destroying the planet, &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; sure takes you on an emotional journey. The film — helmed by writer and director Adam McKay, best-known for movies like &lt;em&gt;Step Brothers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Anchorman&lt;/em&gt; — starts out hilarious, with big-name stars trading one-liners amid an impending apocalypse. But over its lengthy runtime, it slowly morphs into something else. Laughs give way to anger, frustration, and ultimately a kind of desperate hope. It’s a trajectory that serves as an eerie mirror to the last two years of pandemic life — just don’t go in expecting lighthearted fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9P5yh8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t waste any time getting going. It starts out with a pair of Michigan State astronomers, Randall (Leonardo DiCaprio) and Kate (Jennifer Lawrence), discovering a massive comet in the sky that’s somewhere between five and 10 kilometers wide. But the excitement of discovery quickly turns to dread, as the pair realize that it’s on a collision course with Earth, and it will cause an extinction-level event in around six months. They rush to the White House to inform the president, played by Meryl Streep, only to be left waiting for hours as she deals with a much more pressing dilemma involving nude models. What follows is a delightfully goofy exchange, where the president and her chief of staff (Jonah Hill) who is also her self-absorbed son, debate the political ramifications of revealing that everyone is about to die ahead of midterms. “The timing, it’s just atrocious,” the president tells them, while noting that she’ll have her own people — from an Ivy League school, of course — assess things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Don’t Look Up" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9oow7F4M6ug_Qs0v3yxUFVoCq8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069868/DLU_20201204_02846_R.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Niko Tavernise / Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yUtJHt"&gt;It would all be absurd if it didn’t feel so close to reality. What should be the only thing that matters to everyone on the planet — finding a way to avoid the destruction of all life — gets drowned out by election season and, later, a celebrity breakup. Early on, this contrast is played up for laughs; the astronomers struggle to get their message across because no one wants to hear bad news. They go on a talk show where they’re told to keep things light. When Kate (Lawrence) explodes in frustration and tells the hosts that everyone is going to die, she becomes a meme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="paUcW6"&gt;The absurdism that mirrors our own reality a little too neatly is helped along by a tremendous cast. This movie is stacked with talent. I could watch Streep and Hill banter all day long, and Ariana Grande and Kid Cudi are perfectly cast as the on again, off again pop star power couple. Meanwhile, Lawrence does an amazing job of channeling the anger I know I’d be feeling in her position. Other actors do great work with smaller-but-vital roles; Timothée Chalamet as a painfully earnest Twitch streamer / skate punk, Ron Perlman as a definitely racist war hero. Everyone brings it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vbFyXM"&gt;But slowly that good humor gives way and &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; gets uncomfortably real. Once the message gets out there, it becomes polarizing. Randall (DiCaprio) turns into a social media star, a hunky scientist who is the face of the government’s constantly shifting plan to try to deflect the comet, while Kate becomes a pariah because of her realist attitude. A chunk of space rock that will eviscerate life on Earth ends up creating political divides. Some are terrified, others don’t believe it’s even real. While working class voters turn hopeful about the jobs the comet will provide, an evil tech mogul salivates at all of the rare Earth metals it contains. At one point Randall is forced to ask: what’s the point of trillions of dollars if we’re all dead? He’s laughed out of the room.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Don’t Look Up" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w2J96RGsV4lAHZp8-I_4FPoJ8jY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069873/DLU_20210115_10788_R.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Niko Tavernise / Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oeSaDW"&gt;It’s infuriating watching the population argue instead of work together to ensure their literal survival. Sadly, little of the movie seems far-fetched given… well, the past two years on the real planet Earth. We’ve all seen the divides that come from a true existential crisis during the pandemic, and &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; is an uncanny reflection of that reality. You could call aspects of it goofy or unrealistic, but then again many of us spent the early days of the pandemic learning to bake bread while watching &lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; exaggerates a bit, but it’s not too far off the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07fXJJ"&gt;It stretches on perhaps a little too long — the movie clocks in at nearly two and a half hours — but the journey &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; takes viewers on is mesmerizing. I went from laughing at the absurdity of a military general scamming some astronomers out of $20 to being genuinely mad at everyone not only ignoring the obvious but, in some cases, rooting for the damn comet. Toward the end, when the collision becomes impossible to ignore, I just felt bad for everyone involved. &lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt; has a largely dismal outlook on humanity, but it ends on a surprisingly hopeful note. (You should definitely stick around for the credits where it wraps back around to being hilarious.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uI1CPr"&gt;I’m not sure if the film made me realize anything new about myself or life during the pandemic, but it was certainly cathartic to see it all play out in such dramatic fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GgB3xV"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Don’t Look Up &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is coming to select theaters on December 10th, before hitting Netflix on December 24th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22822107/dont-look-up-review-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22822107/dont-look-up-review-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Your LG TV can now play Google Stadia if it’s running webOS 5.0 or later</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b02LlLBhdJos-5sYNWNwxFKmJAg=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242178/webos_stadia_lg.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t1Sphu"&gt;Have a gamepad handy and a recent LG TV? You can likely now try Google’s Stadia cloud gaming platform — as of today, it’s an app you can download for your television running webOS 5.0 or webOS 6.0 (read: likely 2020 models or later) in any of &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/stadia/answer/9566513?hl=en"&gt;the 22 countries&lt;/a&gt; that Google covers. You’ll find it in the LG app store on your TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bapW7o"&gt;LG promised that both Google Stadia and Nvidia’s rival GeForce Now cloud gaming service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224359/google-stadia-nvidia-geforce-now-lg-tv-2021"&gt;would arrive on its TVs in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, and the company’s made it under the wire — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790223/geforce-now-lg-tv-webos-beta"&gt;GeForce Now arrived in beta in mid-November&lt;/a&gt;. Previously, most Stadia-supported TVs ran some version of Android TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fUVJoR"&gt;Both Stadia and GeForce Now are free to try with a basic account — though they’re not necessarily equal. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"&gt;We were blown away by GeForce Now’s new $200-a-year RTX 3080 tier&lt;/a&gt;; I wrote that it leapfrogged Google Stadia. But Nvidia only streams in 4K resolution to its own Shield TV set-top box — not these LG TVs — while Google Stadia will be offering its full “Stadia Pro” tier with 4K streaming resolution, HDR, and 5.1 surround sound to LG TVs as of today. Assuming you pay $10 a month for Stadia Pro, that is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afx2AR"&gt;We haven’t yet compared Stadia’s “4K” vs. Nvidia’s “1080p” on the same screen, but I’m eager to give that a spin some evening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d88roU"&gt;One possible advantage for Stadia: while GeForce Now requires you to bring your own games (it uses your PC library), Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747836/google-stadia-cloud-gaming-free-trial-30-minutes"&gt;is currently running free timed trials&lt;/a&gt; of games like &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3jyyu1"&gt;Even if you don’t have a gamepad, you can technically play Stadia on some platforms using your phone’s touchscreen — a spokesperson confirms that Stadia’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425678/google-stadia-controller-bridge-mode-chromecast-google-tv"&gt;bridge mode&lt;/a&gt; has made it to LG TVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="znBWxz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 7:20PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Confirmed that Bridge Mode should work with your phone as a touchscreen controller for Stadia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bdjoec"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823092/google-stadia-comes-to-lg-smart-tv-webos-5-6"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22823092/google-stadia-comes-to-lg-smart-tv-webos-5-6</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T18:45:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T18:45:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Pixel mail-in repairs have allegedly twice resulted in leaked pics and a privacy nightmare</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bcBWgEOXjkthOdLprXGr52IZhPk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70229533/acastro_180130_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1il5Xu"&gt;After game designer and author Jane McGonigal sent her Pixel 5a to Google for repair, someone allegedly took and hacked her device. This is at least the second report in as many weeks from someone claiming they sent a Google phone in for repair, only to have it used to leak their private data and photographs. McGonigal posted a detailed account of the situation on Twitter on Saturday and advised other users not to send their phones in for repair with the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="d7nvn6"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yeah, don't send your Google phone in for warranty repair/replacement. As has happened with others, last night someone used it to log into my gmail, Drive, photos backup email account, dropbox, and I can see from activity logs they opened a bunch of selfies hoping to find nudes&lt;/p&gt;— Jane McGonigal (@avantgame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/avantgame/status/1467192779973398531?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4yzw22"&gt;In October, McGonigal sent her broken phone to an official Pixel repair center in Texas. She tweeted later that Google said it never received the phone, and during the ensuing weeks, she was charged for a replacement device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0LDcrt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The photos they opened were of me in bathing suits, sports bras, form-fitting dresses, and of stitches after surgery”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yVbtpF"&gt;But according to McGonigal, FedEx tracking information shows the device arrived at the facility weeks ago. Late Friday night — a few hours after she says she finally received a refund for the device — someone seems to have used the “missing” phone to clear two-factor authentication checks and log in to several of her accounts, including her Dropbox, Gmail, and Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PpG6P9"&gt;The activity triggered several email security alerts to McGonigal’s backup accounts. However, she speculates that whoever has the phone may have used it to access her backup email addresses and then dumped any security alerts into her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fJj3MV"&gt;“The photos they opened were of me in bathing suits, sports bras, form-fitting dresses, and of stitches after surgery,” McGonigal writes. “They deleted Google security notifications in my backup email accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lc3msi"&gt;Google spokesperson Alex Moriconi initially told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company is investigating the issue, but now it appears that the investigation has concluded. “After a thorough investigation, we can say with confidence that the issue impacting the user was not related to the device RMA [Return Merchandise Authorization],” Moriconi said. “We have worked closely with the user to better understand what occurred and how best to secure the account going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vPFtDb"&gt;It’s still unclear whether the device might have been intercepted within the repair facility or while it was in transit, or who has it now. Google’s &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/9004345?hl=en"&gt;official repair instructions&lt;/a&gt; recommend backing up and then erasing a device before sending it in. Still, as Jane McGonigal points out, that’s either hard or impossible, depending on the damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Lv86nA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Pixel Support and Google Security have been extremely helpful today I am happy to report. The best thing to come out of this is there will be added security instructions for people who cannot factory reset their phones due to phone damage. This is good and should help a lot.&lt;/p&gt;— Jane McGonigal (@avantgame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/avantgame/status/1467926809052205057?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u7tfp8"&gt;Just two days after McGonigal’s complaint, it looks like she received some assistance from Google. “Pixel Support and Google Security have been extremely helpful today I am happy to report,” she tweeted. McGonigal also notes that in response to her case, Google may start providing additional instructions for users with broken devices who are unable to perform a factory reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4lC6n"&gt;The whole situation reminds us of the security concerns whenever we hand over our devices for repair, and unfortunately, such activity has precedent. In June, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522560/apple-repair-multimillion-iphone-nude-photos-privacy-settlement-pegatron"&gt;Apple paid millions to a woman&lt;/a&gt; after repair technicians posted her nude photos to Facebook. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22787245/apple-iphone-mac-self-service-program-repair-diy"&gt;recently said it would start selling DIY repair kits&lt;/a&gt;, giving users the chance to fix their own phones, or at least have the task done by someone that a user trusts, as opposed to sending it in or dropping it off at an Apple Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fmMRii"&gt;For Pixel phones, &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/10227672?hl=en"&gt;your options for official service&lt;/a&gt; are either via mail-in or, in some countries, local service through an authorized provider. In the US, Google partners with &lt;a href="https://www.ubreakifix.com/"&gt;uBreakiFix&lt;/a&gt; franchises. Whatever phone you have, the options for repairs are still somewhat limited, and you end up having to trust that no one with bad intentions will get their hands on your phone while it’s out of your possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sSM4TM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 7th, 6:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to add a statement from a Google spokesperson regarding an update in the company’s investigation. Also added a December 6th tweet from McGonigal, as well as some extra context about that tweet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/4/22817758/broken-google-pixel-phone-privacy-leak"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/4/22817758/broken-google-pixel-phone-privacy-leak</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T18:36:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T18:36:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Meta Portal now lets you view Facebook Stories hands-free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C9rh5e6yRf7f5PfiQ_YmmeVw9hE=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70242097/portal_calling_features_new.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jinVUN"&gt;The Meta (formerly Facebook) Portal is getting a number of updates, including one that lets you browse through your Facebook friends’ stories hands-free, as detailed in a post on the &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/12/celebrate-the-holidays-with-portal/"&gt;About Facebook blog&lt;/a&gt;. You can access the feature by saying, “Hey Portal, show me Stories.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XkPWX"&gt;In addition to Stories, you can now ask the Facebook Assistant to display recent Facebook posts, responses, and photos. Previously, there wasn’t any native support for Facebook, as it was only accessible through a web browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oAnrAq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Portal will let you take screenshots during Messenger calls by saying, “Hey Portal, take a photo”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4Icvzn"&gt;And while the Portal could always take pictures of you during a call, it never had a feature that let you capture images of your friends or family members on the other side of the screen — something that &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2018/11/08/facebook-portal-review-ai-makes-video-calls-better/"&gt;Facebook reportedly said&lt;/a&gt; was due to privacy reasons back in 2018. But now, the Portal will let you take screenshots during Messenger calls by saying, “Hey Portal, take a photo.” You can then share the photo through Messenger, just like you would with any other photo or video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIMNoo"&gt;Meta has also added support for AR effects on both sides of a Messenger call, no matter what device you or your caller is using. In other words, if your caller is using a phone or tablet in place of a Portal, they’ll now be able to see the AR effects that you turn on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZkgBq"&gt;Three new games are coming to the Portal as well, including Quizbee, Sequencer, and Port-a-Pet, all of which are accessible through the Photo Booth app. While Quizbee is essentially a trivia game, Sequencer tests your ability to memorize random number sequences, and Port-a-Pet lets you interact with a virtual pet using verbal commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EMgUQP"&gt;Lastly, Meta has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684447/facebook-releases-portal-go-plus-video-calling-devices"&gt;followed through on its promise to integrate Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt; with Portal, as the video conferencing feature will be available on the device starting December 8th. ESPN, along with ESPN Plus, will also be available on the Portal, Portal Plus, and Portal Go in the US “later this month.” ESPN was previously only available on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20871173/facebook-portal-camera-price-release-date-availability"&gt;Portal TV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jiG15d"&gt;Along with these new features, Meta has slashed the price of its Portal devices, offering its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Facebook-Portal-Go-Portable-Calling/dp/B09FYH2511?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Portal Go for $149&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Facebook-Portal-Smart-Video-Calling/dp/B07XPLJ9TZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Portal TV for $79&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Facebook-Portal-Calling-Screen-Speakers/dp/B09FYJFP5Y/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Portal Plus for $299&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="v1hXR9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook’s new Portal Go is great for video calls, but not much else","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22732472/facebook-portal-go-10-inch-2021-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822879/facebook-portal-stories-hands-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822879/facebook-portal-stories-hands-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T17:40:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T17:40:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Blizzard employee will detail studio’s ‘alcohol-soaked culture’ in press conference</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Activision Blizzard employees stage a walkout in the response from company leadership to a lawsuit highlighting alleged harassment, inequality" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v9WfWgNs4GDVlqnrgWx5hVCBLOE=/110x0:4090x2653/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70241907/1234303856.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ThshmO"&gt;Lisa Bloom, the celebrity lawyer who represented Bill O’Reilley’s, Donald Trump’s, and Bill Cosby’s sexual assault accusers, as well as once advising Harvey Weinstein in his sexual assault case, has announced that she will be holding a press conference on behalf of one of the survivors involved in the numerous sexual assault, harassment, and discrimination allegations against Activision Blizzard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nJParL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I represent a Blizzard employee who alleges she's a victim of sexual harassment. Our press release for our press conference tomorrow at the Irvine headquarters where we will demand accountability for the victims who have been subjected to harassment at the video game company: &lt;a href="https://t.co/0PisZ1Zomr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0PisZ1Zomr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Lisa Bloom (@LisaBloom) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LisaBloom/status/1468299060826177538?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3h7hdE"&gt;The press conference, announced today in a press release from Bloom’s firm, will take place at Blizzard’s Irvine, California, headquarters and feature a statement from the victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuzoeH"&gt;According to the press release, the woman is a current employee at Blizzard Entertainment and will “describe the alcohol-soaked culture of sexual harassment [...] and the retaliation she experienced after she reported the sexual harassment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="letN6Q"&gt;Though numerous people have spoken out about their experiences at the company, this press conference will be the first time a current employee has publicly come forward. The press conference will be streamed at 12PM ET Wednesday, December 8th, on &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/lisabloomesq/"&gt;Lisa Bloom’s Instagram account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822948/harvey-weinstein-lawyer-lisa-bloom-press-conference-activision-blizzard-harassment-victim"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822948/harvey-weinstein-lawyer-lisa-bloom-press-conference-activision-blizzard-harassment-victim</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
