<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-27T08:07:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T08:07:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T08:07:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is ‘pausing’ work on Instagram kids app after widespread criticism </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G2n-b-b07qa0qt9aFBkX5DI2pF4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69914119/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QlrgD5"&gt;Instagram says it’s “pausing” development of what’s been dubbed “Instagram Kids” — a version of the photo-sharing app aimed at children under 13. Instagram chief Adam Mosseri announced the news in a &lt;a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/pausing-instagram-kids"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; today, saying that the Facebook-owned company would continue to work on parental-supervised experiences for younger users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49MUYi"&gt;In a blog post and series of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1442461230124322828"&gt;accompanying tweets&lt;/a&gt;, Mosseri blames the media and critics for misunderstanding the purpose of the app. “It was never meant for younger kids, but for tweens (aged 10-12),” he writes. In a separate &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1442461237825081353"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;, he adds that news of the project “leaked way before we knew what it would be. People feared the worst, and we had few answers at that stage. It’s clear we need to take more time on this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WgqjCf"&gt;Pausing development of the app comes after &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; published a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;series of damning reports&lt;/a&gt; into Facebook last week. These &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739"&gt;included a story&lt;/a&gt; revealing how Instagram’s own internal research suggested that the app made body issues worse for teenage girls. Facebook says these reports &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report"&gt;mischaracterized&lt;/a&gt; the company’s studies, but it has so far refused to release its data firsthand for critics and supporters alike to analyze. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Tz1VQD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I have to believe parents would prefer the option for their children to use an age-appropriate version of Instagram - that gives them oversight - than the alternative. But I’m not here to downplay their concerns, we have to get this right.&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Mosseri   (@mosseri) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1442461233337159688?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WROnhh"&gt;In his blog post, Mosseri notes that the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting “raised a lot of questions for people,” and says such criticism has led Instagram to introducing a number of anti-bullying features, as well as “exploring” features that might encourage readers to take a break from the app. (Parts of the &lt;em&gt;WSJ’&lt;/em&gt;s reporting that Instagram and Mosseri have ignored include the company’s own researchers noting that users often feel “addicted” to the app.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gmkkUn"&gt;The development of a version of Instagram aimed at younger users was &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-56757586"&gt;widely criticized&lt;/a&gt; by a number of groups. Facebook responded to this criticism by saying young people were already active online and it was better that their experience be supervised. The company also said it wouldn’t show advertising on the new app. However, critics were not convinced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9pJIWo"&gt;“Facebook claims that creating an Instagram for kids will help keep them safe on the platform,” Kathryn Montgomery, a senior strategist at the Center for Digital Democracy, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-56757586"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;BBC News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in April&lt;em&gt;. “&lt;/em&gt;The company’s real goal is to expand its lucrative and highly profitable Instagram franchise to an even younger demographic, introducing children to a powerful commercialized social media environment that poses serious threats to their privacy, health and wellbeing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rfvpuo"&gt;Mosseri notes on Twitter that critics will see Instagram pausing development of the kids app “as a concession that the project is a bad idea.” He’s adamant this is incorrect, adding: “I have to believe parents would prefer the option for their children to use an age-appropriate version of Instagram - that gives them oversight - than the alternative. But I’m not here to downplay their concerns, we have to get this right.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696039/facebook-instagram-kids-app-pause-development-criticism"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696039/facebook-instagram-kids-app-pause-development-criticism</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Resident Evil 4 VR is launching October 21st, but only on Oculus Quest 2</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Resident Evil 4 VR Key Art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VNSYmgy2uM6eBBQkn4VEcdaaFdM=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913924/RE4_Key_Art_3840x2160.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ITQjGb"&gt;A virtual reality version of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4 &lt;/em&gt;will launch October 21st on Facebook’s Oculus Quest 2 headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gtyC7p"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4 VR&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396528/capcom-resident-evil-4-oculus-quest-2-remake-trailer-footage-launch-date"&gt;announced earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. But Facebook and Capcom — as well as third-party development studio Armature — have only offered glimpses of its gameplay, including a short trailer. It adapts the original game’s content with a (mostly) first-person point of view, re-engineering it to take advantage of VR motion controls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Resident Evil 4 VR Screenshot" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8n9urNa09QPdrDtxcqEL0GVGRAA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22880730/RE4_SCREENSHOTS_MENDEZ_SHOTGUN_003_2560X1440_Legal.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DWxdtR"&gt;Armature’s &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt; makes a somewhat complicated series of small changes the original 2005 horror game. It’s supposed to feature the same narrative content and world design, rather than getting the kind of overhaul &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 2&lt;/em&gt; did in 2019. But it’s been re-engineered to work as a first-person VR game with motion controllers. You’ll interact with weapons, items, and puzzles using your hands. Your health will be visible on a wristwatch instead of a screen overlay. And in addition to moving with the analog stick on an Oculus Touch controller, you’ll be able to teleport or walk in room-scale VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8ed8T"&gt;The new design could affect gameplay in some notable ways. You can wield weapons in each hand, for instance, and switching between them looks a lot easier. You’ll use a knife by physically slashing your controller at enemies instead of hitting a button. And a gameplay video shows you moving around while shooting, a major change from the original design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UAwbId"&gt;The game’s not fully first-person, though. All its cutscenes will be presented in their original third-person format, including ones tied to &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4’s&lt;/em&gt; many quick time events, according to Facebook. Based on Facebook’s description, the game features some surprisingly fast-sounding camera shifts — you can apparently kick a door down with a button, for instance, and see a short third-person animation as it opens.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Resident Evil 4 VR Screenshot" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1XmSpxkOf1gFJ0U7ceQNEDTSwnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22880733/RE4_SCREENSHOTS_CHURCH_PUZZLE_001_2560x1440_Legal.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9PuwRr"&gt;Facebook says the original quicktime event placements and animations are going to stay the same, although some of the actions have been “updated” to work better in VR. (We’ll be waiting to see how the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fey8XU0OiWo"&gt;more acrobatic&lt;/a&gt; sections translate to a headset.) Some of the quick time events will involve quickly moving the controllers, while others will ask you to pull their triggers at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w59RUz"&gt;Other tweaks would make sense in any remaster. The game’s textures have been updated, and Armature has made enemies less likely to target your partner Ashley, who you’ll spend a lot of time protecting in either version of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrnadb"&gt;Unlike most Quest games, &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4 VR&lt;/em&gt; isn’t compatible with the original 2019 Quest — it’s completely exclusive to the 2020 Quest 2. Facebook also isn’t sharing any potential plans to bring it to Oculus’ desktop platform, nor has it discussed the game coming to desktop PC or consoles, the way &lt;em&gt;Myst’s&lt;/em&gt; Oculus Quest version &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/myst-vr-remake-pc-vr-release-date/"&gt;later launched outside VR&lt;/a&gt;. But if you’re just interested in a better-looking version of the original &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt;, there’s always the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.re4hd.com/?page_id=104"&gt;unofficial HD remaster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22692268/resident-evil-4-vr-capcom-oculus-quest-2-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22692268/resident-evil-4-vr-capcom-oculus-quest-2-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T06:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T06:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>NBC gets super aggressive in YouTube TV dispute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BtySc2U57Vzw1PJ0hs-l_891Ktk=/178x0:2100x1281/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913813/Image_from_iOS__1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banner ads are appearing across select channels.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: NBCU&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gEbfOs"&gt;NBC is one of several NBCUniversal channels running prominent banner ads on YouTube TV streams, warning customers that they could lose access over a carriage dispute with Google. The banner lists over a dozen channels that could disappear if a deal isn’t reached by Wednesday, September 30th, and directs customers to &lt;a href="https://youneedchannels.com/"&gt;an NBCU-owned website&lt;/a&gt; offering various ways to pressure Google. These include a pre-written tweet directed at YouTube TV, links to Google’s customer support, and a tool to find alternative providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1aal9O"&gt;“Attention YouTube TV Customers,” the banner, which runs roughly every 10 minutes, reads, “YouTube may drop 14+ channels including NBC, Telemundo, USA, SYFY, Brave, Oxygen, MSNBC, NBCSN, CNBC, GOLF Channel, and E!. Go to YouNeedChannels.com and tell YouTube TV not to drop your favorite channels.” NBCU warns that regional NBC Sports networks may also be affected, including NBC Sports Bay Area, NBC Sports Boston, NBC Sports California, NBC Sports Chicago, NBC Sports Philadelphia, SNY and NBC Sports Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zR38A3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YouTubeTV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@YouTubeTV&lt;/a&gt; may drop all of your favorite NBCUniversal programming from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbc?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NBC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BravoTV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BravoTV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MSNBC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@MSNBC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Telemundo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Telemundo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/USA_Network?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@USA_Network&lt;/a&gt; and more! Visit &lt;a href="https://t.co/I3keStuLVy"&gt;https://t.co/I3keStuLVy&lt;/a&gt; to keep your news, shows and sports.&lt;/p&gt;— NBC Entertainment (@nbc) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbc/status/1442249805439270915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUZwbJ"&gt;Responding via a &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/youtube-tv-and-nbc-programming-update/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Google says negotiations are ongoing and that it’s seeking the “the same rates that services of a similar size get from NBCU” and for YouTube TV to be treated like “any other TV provider.” Google added that if it’s unable to reach an agreement it’ll drop its US prices by $10 (bringing its monthly price down from $64.99 to $54.99) while NBCU’s lineup is off the service. Google says that customers are free to cancel anytime and can sign up for Peacock separately for $4.99 a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SB4eqR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/nbcuniversal-youtube-tv-lose-channels-1235074726/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that there are several points of contention in the ongoing negotiations. NBCU is reportedly asking for higher rates for its channels than Google is willing to pay, and wants YouTube TV to bundle NBC’s Peacock video streaming service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3s0Ms2"&gt;“NBCUniversal is seeking fair rates from Google for YouTube TV’s continued carriage of the only portfolio offering entertainment, Hispanic, news and sports networks,” NBCU told &lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;in a statement. “Unfortunately, Google is refusing to make a deal at these fair rates and is willing to withhold entertainment, news and sports programming from their paying customers. NBCUniversal feels a responsibility to inform our fans that they are at risk of losing their favorite shows if Google continues with their demands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sjG6LY"&gt;This is just the latest high profile dispute YouTube TV has found itself in this year. However, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22412430/roku-youtube-tv-google-feud-explainer-timeline"&gt;during its clash with Roku&lt;/a&gt; it was Google that was the content provider, and Roku that was providing the platform. The situation saw Google’s YouTube TV app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411711/roku-removes-youtube-tv-channel-store"&gt;removed from the Roku channel store&lt;/a&gt;, only for Google to respond by letting its customers access YouTube TV &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425035/google-youtube-tv-roku-app-feud"&gt;from its regular YouTube app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QP3l0r"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast, which owns NBCUniversal, is also an investor in Vox Media, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zDWJD3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SKArRz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695937/nbcuniversal-youtube-tv-carriage-dispute"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695937/nbcuniversal-youtube-tv-carriage-dispute</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T02:29:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T02:29:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Backbone offers 3D-printed solution for iPhone 13 Pro camera bump issue</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BackBone One" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5pTzJYYDGcJV2im_LTmgwbvwrlc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913581/cfaulkner_201016_4242_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hk174V"&gt;Backbone Labs has acknowledged the issue that hampers the use of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"&gt;excellent iPhone gaming controller&lt;/a&gt; with the new iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691301/iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-backbone-one-gaming-controller-accessory"&gt;As we noticed last week&lt;/a&gt;, the iPhone 13 Pro’s thicker camera bump means the phone doesn’t sit neatly in the Backbone One controller, either sticking out on one side or causing the bridge on the back to slightly buckle. It’s not unusable, but it’s not great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uV1mXY"&gt;“We spent a tremendous amount of time meticulously crafting every surface of Backbone One (both bits and atoms) and even designing universal support for the iPhones available when it was released,” a Backbone representative wrote in an &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Backbone/comments/pvhl98/backbone_one_iphone_13_pro_pro_max_adapter/"&gt;official post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, we’re disappointed in the situation at hand. Several folks on the team even upgraded to 13 Pro Max for a better gaming experience, and while the fit may be acceptable for some users, it’s not as good as we’d like it to be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WquSRF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Backbone One is a stunning controller that turns your iPhone into a more capable gaming device","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525741/backbone-one-iphone-ios-controller-gaming-portable-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0nAvVr"&gt;To address this, Backbone has designed an adapter that is intended to improve the experience with the iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. Unfortunately, the company says it isn’t able to mass-produce them right away because of supply constraints and COVID-19, so the adapter design will be released as an open-source 3D printable file. If you don’t have access to a 3D printer, Backbone says “we’ll do our best” to send an adapter to users who contact the company’s support team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwUaUy"&gt;The printable files should be posted online “in a matter of days;” we’ll let you know how well the solution works when we can.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22695887/backbone-controller-iphone-13-pro-camera-bump-3d-printed-adapter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T22:38:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T22:38:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook says Instagram is not ‘toxic for teens,’ despite damning WSJ report</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zrW4hwEY_x6dAXJumMMTl6Ekgz0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69913270/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QRKUhm"&gt;Facebook has fired back nearly two weeks after &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739?mod=article_inline"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that Instagram made body image issues worse for one in three teenage girls according to Facebook’s own data. The &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/research-teen-well-being-and-instagram/"&gt;salvo&lt;/a&gt; comes courtesy of Pratiti Raychoudhury, Vice President, Head of Research at Facebook. Raychoudhury’s post on Facebook’s Newsroom claims that &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s characterization of internal research is “not accurate” and blames it all on a poor interpretation of the data the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; has in its possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jpr6Uv"&gt;On September 14 &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journa&lt;/em&gt;l published a story to The Facebook Files, which is a series of stories based around an enormous cache of internal Facebook documents leaked to the newspaper. The September 14 piece &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675130/facebook-instagram-teens-mental-health-damage-internal-research"&gt;focused on data&lt;/a&gt; that suggested Instagram had an extremely harmful effect on teenagers — particularly teenage girls. The &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; claimed that Facebook was well aware of the harm its products had on teenagers and that the company “has made minimal efforts to address these issues and plays them down in public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JROoia"&gt;Facebook has been evasive about the contents of the study cited by the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;. But Facebook’s global head of safety, Antigone Davis, is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675802/facebook-instagram-teens-harm-blumenthal-blackburn-markey-kids"&gt;expected to appear before the Senate Commerce Subcommittee&lt;/a&gt; Thursday to answer for the claims made in the story and plans for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338911/facebook-instagram-kids-privacy-coppa"&gt;new “Instagram for kids”.&lt;/a&gt; Raychoudhury specifically cites that hearing as the reason for the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bEqCmz"&gt;Raychoudhury ignores many of the issues raised in the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; piece, including that teens claimed they felt addicted to Instagram. Instead she focuses her energies on devaluing Facebook’s own research. Much of the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;’s most scathing claims, according to Raychoudhury, focus on a study that had just 40 partipants. That would be a paltry sample size by any measure — but particularly when you’re talking about a platform with over 1 billion users. The tiny study was “designed to inform internal conversations about teens’ most negative perceptions of Instagram,” Raychoudhury claims. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q05V1_CL7VTsaWjvRCmFGlenbbc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22880746/IG_research.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook hasn’t released the internal studies, but did release the slide the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; cited.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MFSrcw"&gt;Raychoudhury also takes umbrage with the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; referring to an internal Facebook slide that claims “we make body images worse for 1 in 3 teenage girls”. Raychoudhury repeatedly notes that the body image problem was just one of 12 possible issues that Instagram could make worse for teenage girls. “Body image was the only area where teen girls who reported struggling with the issue said Instagram made it worse as compared to the other 11 areas,” she writes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UaL8kL"&gt;Unfortunately neither Facebook, Instagram, or Raychoudhury have released the actual data that she repeatedly cites in her response to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting. Without seeing the data ourselves it’s extremely difficult to assess &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s or Raychoudhury’s intepretations of it. But, you know, this isn’t the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/4/18210473/instagram-self-harm-suicide-cutting-posts-molly-russell"&gt;first time&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20872711/instagram-weight-loss-cosmetic-procedures-restrictions-policy-wellness-influencer-marketing"&gt;we’ve heard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2017/05/19/health/instagram-worst-social-network-app-young-people-mental-health/index.html"&gt;about these problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T17:47:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T17:47:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>US agrees not to pursue fraud charges against Huawei CFO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Huawei Chief Financial Officer Meng Wanzhou returns to British Columbia Supreme Court on August 18, 2021, in Vancouver, Canada, during her last extradition hearing." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uQFgAPJZkOf73pWuG3orRdK7yi4=/0x0:6658x4439/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69903844/1234750724.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by DON MACKINNON/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7TxP6A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/huawei-cfo-meng-appear-brooklyn-federal-court-2021-09-24/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/meng-wanzhou-us-court-1.6188093"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; first reported that Huawei CFO Meng Wanzhou would appear in a Brooklyn federal courtroom today via streaming video and enter a plea regarding US charges against her. Canadian authorities &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/5/18128057/huawei-cfo-canada-arrest-iran-sanctions-violation"&gt;arrested the Chinese executive in December 2018&lt;/a&gt; on suspicion of violating US sanctions, and she has remained there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/11/18134938/huawei-cfo-meng-wanzhou-bail-house-arrest-us-china"&gt;on house arrest&lt;/a&gt; ever since, fighting US attempts at extradition. Hearings in her extradition case ended in August, with the ruling scheduled for October 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lrgI9"&gt;Meng was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201023/us-charges-huawei-fraud-stealing-t-mobile-justice-department"&gt;indicted on fraud charges claiming the Chinese technology and telecommunications company misrepresented its relationship with an Iranian affiliate&lt;/a&gt;, along with accusations it stole intellectual property from T-Mobile. The &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/chinese-telecommunications-conglomerate-huawei-and-huawei-cfo-wanzhou-meng-charged"&gt;13-count indictment&lt;/a&gt; named Meng, Huawei, and two of its subsidiaries — Huawei USA and Skycom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKwrEt"&gt;On Friday afternoon, Meng pleaded not guilty. Prosecutors submitted a statement of facts (&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1436211/download"&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;) asserting that in 2013 she told financial institutions the Iranian company Skycom was a partner of Huawei while knowing that Skycom was owned and controlled by a Huawei subsidiary to act as its agent in the region. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDDhgV"&gt;As part of the deal in making this admission, the prosecution says “Meng has agreed to the accuracy of a four-page statement of facts that details the knowingly false statements she made to Financial Institution 1.” They are withdrawing their request for extradition from Canada, and as long as she doesn’t commit any other crimes the charges will be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KMWho"&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/justice-department-reaches-deal-with-huawei-executive-11632494001?st=n81fv8iy9e669cs&amp;amp;reflink=desktopwebshare_twitter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Justice Department officials under the Biden administration revisited negotiations that had broken down under President Trump. Its sources report that Huawei itself is not a part of the deal and will continue to fight &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/16/18185771/huawei-trade-secrets-charges-federal-investigation"&gt;its charges of fraud and trade secret theft&lt;/a&gt;. A Huawei spokesperson said in a statement that “We look forward to seeing Meng Wanzhou returning home safely to be reunited with her family. Huawei will continue to defend itself against the allegations in the US District Court for the Eastern District of New York.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iX1H25"&gt;On Saturday afternoon, Meng landed in Shenzhen where &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/09/26/china/meng-wanzhou-china-arrival-intl-hnk/index.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports she was greeted by crowds on the tarmac, as well as messages of support lighting up skyscrapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9x9vnr"&gt;A former Canadian diplomat told the &lt;em&gt;CBC &lt;/em&gt;he expected her release would lead to China deporting two Canadians it arrested and charged with espionage following Meng’s arrest. On Friday night, &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/09/24/asia/canada-china-kovrig-spavor-release-intl-hnk/index.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported Canadian PM Justin Trudeau’s confirmation that the two men, Michael Kovrig and Michael Spavor, had been released from custody and on Saturday Trudeau tweeted pictures after meeting them at an airport in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uBr6NN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Welcome home, Michael Kovrig and Michael Spavor. You’ve shown incredible strength, resilience, and perseverance. Know that Canadians across the country will continue to be here for you, just as they have been. &lt;a href="https://t.co/1UoLbBFGNv"&gt;pic.twitter.com/1UoLbBFGNv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Justin Trudeau (@JustinTrudeau) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JustinTrudeau/status/1441799271217606657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mFIHHw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 24th, 3:24PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add Meng’s court appearance, not guilty plea, and prosecution agreement details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dm5s3l"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 24th, 4:14PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add details from the plea and deferred prosecution agreement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ycx39V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 26th, 5:46PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added statement from Huawei, along with details about the returns of Meng Wanzhou, Michael Kovrig, and Michael Spavor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691518/huawei-meng-wanzhou-cfo-fraud-plea-china-canada"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691518/huawei-meng-wanzhou-cfo-fraud-plea-china-canada</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T15:20:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T15:20:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: The Tragedy of Macbeth, Invasion, Spencer, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H2Lj3hmq4oj5SpdBYQx4U0LHCcY=/25x0:1417x928/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69911945/denzel.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Denzel Washington stars in The Tragedy of Macbeth | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OZcLLAx30Pw&amp;amp;ab_channel=AppleTV" target="_blank"&gt;Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vzZ8dn"&gt;We’re nearing the season finale of &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; (only two more new episodes!), and it seems like the show’s got a lot of story threads that need to be knitted together after episode 10. Titled &lt;em&gt;No Weddings and a Funeral&lt;/em&gt;, episode 10 was solid, but I didn’t quite love it.  I’m trying to write about the episode without spoiling it, let’s just say I didn’t love how the session between Ted and Sharon which we’ve been waiting for all season was edited together with Rebecca’s retelling of a traumatic event with her own father. Jason Sudeikis and Hannah Waddingham were both so great, but editing the scenes together kind of killed the dramatic momentum. But! New plot twists suggest a cliffhanger of a season finale is coming in two weeks’ time. I’m ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5khZie"&gt;Here are the new trailers for this week: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SNa6hf"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HM3hsVrBMA4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YW9aRk"&gt;The Tragedy of Macbeth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ZVK24F"&gt;This black-and-white adaptation of Shakespeare’s Scottish play stars Denzel Washington as Macbeth, Frances McDormand as Lady Macbeth, and is directed by Joel Coen. It looks stunning (this trailer is simply far too short) and it’s fascinating (to me, anyway) that it stars two actors much older than the usual casting we see for &lt;em&gt;Macbeth&lt;/em&gt;’s lead roles. I don’t generally have an opinion on whether it’s “better” to watch a movie at home versus in a theater (which I know is a touchy subject these days), but it seems like an undertaking of this magnitude should be viewed on the biggest screen possible. &lt;em&gt;The Tragedy of Macbeth &lt;/em&gt;comes to theaters December 25th and to Apple TV Plus January 14th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z2e6Be"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hgsUzL75Yjk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Z8r8mF"&gt;Stranger Things 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KgwgbS"&gt;The latest teaser from the show’s fourth season shows a family we don’t yet know in what appears to be a very haunted house sometime in the 1950s. We also get a glimpse of the &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; kids (it’s been a long time, are they still kids?) breaking in to the apparently abandoned house many years later. What happened at this house, what’s up with that clock, and what does it have to do with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oB2GYwbIAlM&amp;amp;ab_channel=StrangerThings"&gt;Hopper in Russia&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILwLN6hV-X8&amp;amp;ab_channel=StrangerThings"&gt;Eleven&lt;/a&gt; listening? We will have to wait until 2022, because that’s all Netflix is giving us at the moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAc3SN"&gt;There were a slew of new teasers, trailers, and clips for other Netflix shows and movies unveiled Saturday during its Tudum event, including the star-studded &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Op_v2PHDn-0&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t Look Up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,  the &lt;em&gt;Army of the Dead&lt;/em&gt; spin-off/prequel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ith2WetKXlg&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Army of Thieves&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a few trailers for season 2 of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22691354/witcher-season-2-blood-origin-trailer-teaser-watch-premiere-date-netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, season 4 of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2FG-KIgX2o&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ozark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (finally!), season 2 of&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vkgSGrdL4SE&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (it was inevitable) and season 2 of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YX7j0TjkxPE&amp;amp;t=3s&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Check out the rest of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/25/22691543/netflix-tudum-trailers-news-witcher-sandman-cowboy-bebop-bridgerton"&gt;Netflix trailers in this excellent roundup&lt;/a&gt; by Jay Peters and Andrew Webster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ptqd4J"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZaeA9x"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DlaHxL3mHAU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4JUMEP"&gt;Invasion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="R36fYV"&gt;Five regular people in different parts of the world deal with an invasion by something “not of our Earth,” the president says in an address to her fellow Earthlings. The trailer hints that for some of the people, their encounters with the aliens aren’t their first such encounters. Intrigue! Shamier Anderson, Golshifteh Farahani, Sam Neill, Firas Nassar, and Shioli Kutsuna star in &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt;. The first three episodes of the series will drop on Apple TV Plus October 22nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xe7mXA"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WllZh9aekDg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="a8iE3o"&gt;Spencer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PHQ9Wc"&gt;Josh O’Connor and Emma Corwin both won awards for their portrayals of Prince Charles and Princess Diana in the Netflix miniseries &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;, which looked at the unhappy marriage of the royal couple. &lt;em&gt;Spencer&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, focuses on Diana’s decision to leave the philandering Charles, over Christmas weekend in 1991. Much like &lt;em&gt;The Crown,&lt;/em&gt; it adds some melodrama to fill in the blanks of what may have happened behind the scenes, and there is a great deal of positive &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/rachelbrodsky/spencer-trailer-kristen-stewart"&gt;buzz&lt;/a&gt; about Kristen Stewart as Diana. &lt;em&gt;Spencer&lt;/em&gt; comes to theaters November 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9m84dw"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P7PqRDJiWkU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h6bvz4"&gt;I Know What You Did Last Summer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dAFkrP"&gt;I am not sure why we needed a remake of this story or how it will translate into a series, but here we are, with threats scrawled on mirrors in lipstick, a hoodie-wearing stalker/killer, and young people of questionable ethics doing questionable things. There is nary a hook-wielding fisherman in sight in this trailer, however, suggesting it’s not taking all its cues from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yiAlcLlJpQE&amp;amp;ab_channel=MovieclipsClassicTrailers"&gt;the (dare I say classic) 1997 movie&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;I Know What You Did Last Summer&lt;/em&gt;, the series, comes to Amazon Prime Video October 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22686786/new-trailers-the-tragedy-of-macbeth-invasion-spencer-netflix-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22686786/new-trailers-the-tragedy-of-macbeth-invasion-spencer-netflix-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T11:20:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T11:20:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple says it will fix issue with ‘unlock with Apple Watch’ feature on iPhone 13</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qLKRnPbHw0I_F0fg3laDOs5zFxE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69911102/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rVDnX2"&gt;Apple says it has identified an issue where the “unlock with Apple Watch” feature might not work with its new iPhone 13 devices. A new &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212828"&gt;note on its support page&lt;/a&gt; describes the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="QP8fBe"&gt;You might see “Unable to Communicate with Apple Watch” if you try to unlock your iPhone while wearing a face mask, or you might not be able to set up Unlock with Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="3elcIp"&gt;On Friday, users on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AppleWatch/comments/puglid/unlock_with_apple_watch_not_working_unable_to/"&gt;r/AppleWatch Reddit board&lt;/a&gt; began reporting that they were seeing this problem, and some said they were able to use the Watch unlock feature with other iPhone models, including the iPhone 11 Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iDEX1T"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403554/apple-ios-ipados-14-5-now-available-iphone-unlock-face-mask-app-tracking"&gt;introduced the ability to unlock an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; that uses Face ID with a paired Apple Watch earlier this year with the release of iOS 14.5. It comes in handy during a pandemic where face masks are recommended in many public places, making it hard for Face ID to recognize you. The &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212208"&gt;feature works&lt;/a&gt; on iPhone X and later, and requires both the iPhone and the Watch to have wi-fi and Bluetooth turned on. The Watch needs to have wrist detection turned on and be passcode-protected, and it has to be on your wrist and unlocked for the feature to work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="019zJz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to unlock your iOS 14.5 iPhone with your Apple Watch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22403738/iphone-unlock-watch-ios-14-5"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="GA5PtA"&gt;Apple didn’t say what’s causing the problem with iPhone 13 devices, just that it will be “fixed in an upcoming software update,” but not when to expect the update. The support page note advises switching off the “unlock with Apple Watch” feature and using your passcode to unlock your iPhone 13 while masked in the interim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="i2F8eA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iPhone 13 Pro review: a better display, the best camera, and incredible battery life","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fgHhLS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22694679/apple-fix-issue-unlock-apple-watch-feature-iphone-13"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22694679/apple-fix-issue-unlock-apple-watch-feature-iphone-13</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T09:19:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T09:19:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla opens ‘Full Self-Driving’ beta software to more customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ip-AKzmPXlLtVY-2MiBfjXP4_Ow=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69910794/acastro_180430_1777_tesla_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Tesla opened its “full self-driving” beta to more owners | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M9nhCb"&gt;Despite the head of the National Transportation Safety Board expressing serious concerns about its safety last week, Tesla has now enabled access to the beta of its “Full Self-Driving” (FSD) program to more Tesla drivers, via a “request” button on Teslas’ dashboard screens. However, before a driver gets access to the software, Tesla will determine their “safety score,” using five criteria that estimate “the likelihood that your driving could result in a future collision,” according to a &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/support/safety-score"&gt;page on Tesla’s website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y16nLc"&gt;The score is tabulated using data collected by sensors on the driver’s Tesla, and considers instances of forward collision warnings per 1,000 miles, hard braking, aggressive turning, unsafe following, and forced Autopilot disengagement. A Tesla’s Autopilot feature disengages after giving three visual and audio warnings, “when your Tesla vehicle has determined that you have removed your hands from the steering wheel and have become inattentive,” according to the safety score guide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ANmrqr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Teslas with FSD aren’t fully autonomous &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ftdRhx"&gt;The guide doesn’t indicate what Tesla considers an acceptable safety score to access FSD, but says most drivers will have a score of 80 out of a possible 100. The FSD beta software does not make a Tesla fully autonomous; the driver must keep control of the vehicle at all times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="chtllB"&gt;Tesla is opening access to the FSD beta early a year after it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528508/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-first-reaction-video"&gt;opened a limited beta&lt;/a&gt; of the software with a select group of customers. It opened up a &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/support/full-self-driving-subscriptions#pricing"&gt;monthly subscription package&lt;/a&gt; for FSD in July, at a price of $199 per month, or $99 per month for Tesla owners who bought the since-discontinued Enhanced Autopilot package.  Before that point, the FSD package was sold for a one-time fee of $10,000. Tesla owners can cancel their monthly FSD subscription at any time, according to the terms on Tesla’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UuX7hm"&gt;Jennifer Homendy, chair of the National Transportation Safety Board, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682272/ntsb-official-tesla-safety-elon-musk-full-self-driving"&gt;said last week&lt;/a&gt; that Tesla should address “basic safety issues” before expanding FSD, calling the company’s use of the term full self-driving “misleading and irresponsible.” Homendy said Tesla “has clearly misled numerous people to misuse and abuse technology.” The NTSB can conduct investigations and make recommendations, but has no enforcement authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yspbR3"&gt;On Saturday, when a popular Tesla blog tweeted an editorial questioning whether the company had a “fair chance” after Homendy’s comments, Musk replied with a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1441837997645729794?s=20"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; that had a link to the editable version of Homendy’s Wikipedia page (which as of this writing has a paragraph titled “Tesla criticism” that links to news stories about her recent comments). Musk didn’t comment further on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F00Sn2"&gt;A request for comment to Tesla’s media email was not immediately returned Sunday morning; the company dissolved its press office and rarely replies to media queries. The NTSB also did not reply to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bMRkY1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6cgbAR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4Jtdi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-26T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-26T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Future Wife is a wedding, a play, and the weirdest thing I’ve done in Google Sheets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G8Jb3bVHB2JQZCVEgNcdNShaDj0=/134x0:1135x667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69910702/Screenshot_2021_09_17_1.06.55_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9xoBel"&gt;The pandemic has led to a collection of unusual digital experiences, from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324558/google-forms-virtual-escape-rooms-librarians-games-puzzles-homeschooling"&gt;Google Forms escape rooms&lt;/a&gt; to whole &lt;a href="https://www.timeout.com/newyork/news/this-digital-comedy-show-is-taking-place-inside-a-google-doc-this-week-031720"&gt;virtual, two-dimensional comedy shows&lt;/a&gt;. But the interactive digital play / upstate barn wedding I attended last Friday, &lt;a href="https://newgeorges.org/uncategorized/new-georges-presents-future-wife-play-in-a-spreadsheetno-really-its-a-play-in-a-spreadsheet/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Future Wife: Party in a Spreadsheet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, takes things to a strange new level. The show, co-created by playwright ruth tang and director Sarah Blush, and put on by a cast of game collaborators and theater company New Georges, manages to be playful, confounding, and surprisingly, a little touching. Basically all the things Google Sheets never are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IkSSAV"&gt;It’s difficult to describe &lt;em&gt;Party in a Spreadsheet&lt;/em&gt; in a way that makes sense. There are communist goats, alien activists, several themed islands, and an anonymous audience masquerading as a variety of exotic animals. There are also plenty of ominous threats in the official description: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="dYUcjI"&gt;You’re invited to a Very Heterosexual Wedding, but we can’t have a real wedding, so we made one out of spreadsheets. It’s a dance party so I hope you’re in comfortable footwear. It’s a potluck so I hope you bring some food. It’s a vast and terrifying landscape. It’s a barn filled with massive machines. Did I not say that? Don’t worry. You could be the one swaying on the lawn to the rasp of knives being sharpened. Welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Wl45Sy"&gt;The actual experience of attending starts with receiving a wedding invitation via email (“We gather to celebrate the heterosexual union of Boots and Patsy”). At the set start time I was encouraged to log out of my Google account or open an incognito window, and join the festivities. Audience members are first dumped into a “welcoming meadow” sheet where they’re greeted and encouraged to wander around and start editing the sheet. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a5v2NQ-m7_-nZ1SubZaQd-EXq7s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867411/Screenshot_2021_09_17_1.12.24_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The spreadsheets are full of elements that seem to only exist to amuse the audience member with the patience to scroll.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zO4b3J"&gt;Blush and tang describe the meadow as a sort of tutorial for the experience. “That opening page is built to be a space in which we are modeling behavior,” Blush says. It introduces the kinds of interactions that will be used during the show and that any audience member can do like live text editing, coloring cells, pasting GIFs and images, and basic improv. If you can wrap your head around the roleplay at the start of the experience, you can handle &lt;em&gt;Future Wife: Party in a Spreadsheet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7hpMo-bh18Hf_8K8OQfyJ2wBnJA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867421/Screenshot_2021_09_17_1.03.29_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The chaos of audience participation in &lt;/em&gt;Future Wife: Party in a Spreadsheet.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Y7sVba"&gt;From the meadow onward, things get more bizarre. The Boots and Patsy wedding isn’t quite what it seems, from the fact that Boots is a goat, to the aliens that interrupt the ceremony. Based on the breadth of locations and settings, &lt;em&gt;Future Wife &lt;/em&gt;clearly set up to touch on a lot of different subject matter. Some themes are obvious, like how the heterosexual rigidity of the “wedding industrial complex” (as Blush refers to it) is mirrored in the straight-laced way Sheets is often used for work. “People experienced [Google Sheets] as a place of work or a place of like, you know, drudgery,” tang notes. Other non-wedding or goat-related themes are more buried.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JYJJCuuoTS-dJQrNa4bskikGbA8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867414/Screenshot_2021_09_17_1.16.21_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone has not so nice plans for these goats.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LUf6uT"&gt;I’m not sure Sheets is the best way to experience theater — &lt;em&gt;Party in a Spreadsheet &lt;/em&gt;is referred to as an “adaptation” of tang’s original play in an “extremely loose sense of the word” — but it did produce an experience that lingered with me. Going in, I thought seeing someone “perform” Sheets editing would be the most interesting part of this. I’ve been caught unaware in a Google Doc and pretended to work “intelligently” for an editor. But what surprised me more were the asynchronous interactions. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vjgqLXxKteIFS7XPaS0JENU8v0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867522/Screenshot_2021_09_17_1.05.20_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just a normal wedding guest book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="scK1cX"&gt;Blush and tang leave the audience a lot of digital space to interact, sometimes a whole pirate island’s worth, coordinating with their cast over Discord to prompt discussion and improv with lines delivered by the alien activists trying to rescue Boots. Combined with the anonymity inherent to the experience, this can lead to some candid sharing. It also produces magical moments of interaction. Multiple times I left a goofy attempt at being funny in one sheet, only to come back later and find an honest response or multiple equally dumb riffs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="87B71D"&gt;It’s those moments that wowed me. Honesty, playfulness, even community in a shared anonymous space is an increasingly rare thing in 2021. You’d be considered naive to expect it. But for its hour runtime, &lt;em&gt;Future Wife&lt;/em&gt; makes it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hNiRhG"&gt;“I think that aspect of knowing that there’s so much stuff happening and there are people around you that you can interact with, if you wanted, I think that’s a sense of freedom, but also kind of a restriction,” tang explains. “I think that that is why you know, that’s why I personally find the experiences, even performing the show, very fun, and very... kind of like the experiences of being with people, weirdly enough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QH6vRv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Future Wife: Party in a Spreadsheet &lt;/em&gt;has currently finished its six-show run. You can view the spreadsheets from previous versions of the show &lt;a href="https://ruthtang.com/FUTURE-WIFE"&gt;on ruth tang’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eFPFmR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22685868/google-sheets-future-wife-interactive-play-spreadsheet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22685868/google-sheets-future-wife-interactive-play-spreadsheet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
