<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-24T12:37:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T12:37:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T12:37:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook will match Google’s $1 billion news investment after Australia showdown</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mHo09DKZBQZKKO5MM6xiH9I43-Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68868185/mdoying_180411_2400_0130still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eAjQQQ"&gt;Facebook said it plans to invest an additional $1 billion in the news industry over the next three years as a sign of commitment to journalism, following the company’s unprecedented showdown with the government of Australia that involved briefly disabling the ability to read and share news for Australian Facebook users and publishers. The announcement was made as part of a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/02/the-real-story-of-what-happened-with-news-on-facebook-in-australia/"&gt;blog post from global policy chief Nick Clegg&lt;/a&gt; published on Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wa0Ym4"&gt;“Facebook is more than willing to partner with news publishers. We absolutely recognize quality journalism is at the heart of how open societies function — informing and empowering citizens and holding the powerful to account,” Clegg writes. “That’s why we’ve invested $600 million since 2018 to support the news industry, and plan at least $1 billion more over the next three years.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yibvQ"&gt;The commitment matches the one Google &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/google-news-showcase/"&gt;made in October of last year&lt;/a&gt;, when the search giant announced it would start paying publishers to create specialized versions of stories and other forms of news content for its Google News Showcase platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sGD8b0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We absolutely recognize quality journalism is at the heart of how open societies function.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ES15xZ"&gt;Notable in this scenario, however, is the way both Facebook and Google reacted to the impending Australian media bargaining legislation that prompted such visceral reactions from the Silicon Valley titans. The law would have forced both companies to the negotiating table with news publishers to hammer out deals for paying for news content to be shared on both the main Facebook app and Google search. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kUNcaV"&gt;While Google initially threatened to shut off its services in the country, it eventually blinked in the negotiating stage and began &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/17/google-and-news-corp-strike-deal-as-australia-pushes-platforms-to-pay-for-news.html"&gt;cutting deals with media partners like Rupert Murdoch’s News Corp&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook, on the other hand, did in fact shut off a portion of its service in Australia, in the form of disabling the sharing and reading of news links from both users and publishers for a brief few days starting last week. Facebook then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296778/facebook-ends-australian-news-ban-bargaining-code-google"&gt;reached an agreement&lt;/a&gt; with the Australian government earlier this week and restored the country’s access to news on its platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcnwoO"&gt;According to Clegg, the company feels the proposed media bargaining law as it was designed prior to the recent compromise was unfair, mainly because it would put too much power in the hands of media conglomerates like Murdoch’s to extract ever-higher payments through a forced negotiation process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3S97G"&gt;“At the heart of it, in Facebook’s view, is a fundamental misunderstanding of the relationship between Facebook and news publishers. It’s the publishers themselves who choose to share their stories on social media, or make them available to be shared by others, because they get value from doing so,” Clegg argues. “Facebook would have been forced to pay potentially unlimited amounts of money to multi-national media conglomerates under an arbitration system that deliberately misdescribes the relationship between publishers and Facebook — without even so much as a guarantee that it is used to pay for journalism, let alone support smaller publishers.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5PGxlu"&gt;Facebook is now free to negotiate deals with news publishers for its Facebook News platform without the fear of forced arbitration, and Clegg says it plans to do that in Australia as it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248814/facebook-news-uk-launch-articles-tab-curated"&gt;currently doing in the UK, the US, and other markets&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook also retains the right to restrict news content for Australian publishers and users as it did last week, but the company has signaled it has no intent to do so if future negotiations remain in good faith. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299229/facebook-one-billion-investment-news-industry-australia-google-regulation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299229/facebook-one-billion-investment-news-industry-australia-google-regulation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T12:33:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T12:33:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Marvel’s Loki series will premiere on Disney Plus on June 11th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Ypc_eCnIPgq4I808iauhcRayoE=/533x0:2336x1202/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68868164/Screen_Shot_2021_02_24_at_12.21.03_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ar2Gng"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;, the Tom Hiddleston-starring series about Asgard’s god of mischief, will land on Disney Plus on June 11th, Marvel Studios announced today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RU0kvx"&gt;The series was described by Marvel Studios as a “crime thriller” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168459/loki-trailer-marvel-studios-disney-plus-tom-hiddleston-release-date"&gt;in December&lt;/a&gt; during Disney’s big streaming investor day. It follows Loki as he faces off against the Time Variance Authority, otherwise known as as the TVA, following the events of &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;. The first trailer for the series was also released in December, and it saw Loki enter a bunch of different worlds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DQZeKz"&gt;Marvel Studios is in a position where there are new shows all the time. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22267989/wandavision-5th-episode-recap-sitcom-horror-disney-plus-streaming-crossover-multiverse"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Marvel Studios’ first big Disney Plus show, is nearing its end. The show has seen an incredible amount of success, trending weekly on Twitter and bringing in millions of subscribers every week within the US alone, according to Nielsen ratings. It will be followed by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/21591343/falcon-winter-soldier-premiere-date-disney-plus-sebastian-stan-anthony-mackie-august"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, reuniting Anthony Mackie’s and Sebastian Stan’s characters in the events after &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;. That show will debut on March 19th. Then, &lt;em&gt;Loki &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgKNx5"&gt;With the new release date, it also firmly plants &lt;em&gt;Loki &lt;/em&gt;months after &lt;em&gt;Black Widow &lt;/em&gt;is slated to hit theaters. More Marvel Studios content is slated for Disney Plus throughout the year, too, including &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Ms. Marvel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299343/loki-premiere-date-disney-plus-marvel-tom-hiddleston-wandavision-black-widow"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299343/loki-premiere-date-disney-plus-marvel-tom-hiddleston-wandavision-black-widow</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T12:07:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T12:07:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hyundai recalls Kona EVs over battery fire risk</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UhzCmNHGLhW1QLzjth9RQV0EDqk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867982/akrales_180329_2351_1021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SZJ4IG"&gt;Hyundai is finally recalling some 76,000 Kona EVs built between 2018 and 2020 after more than a dozen reported fires related to the electric SUV’s battery pack. It’s the second recall of the Kona EV, but the first global recall, and it will cost Hyundai around $900 million to perform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlTSWh"&gt;Hyundai is also recalling some Ioniq EVs and electric buses built between November 2017 and March 2020 that use the same LG Chem cells. In total, the automaker is recalling 82,000 vehicles. Hyundai and LG Chem have decided to completely replace the batteries in these vehicles instead of trying to solve the issue through software updates, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b742f5ec-44e2-4f3d-9a63-05662eab0f0b"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WMAhX7"&gt;The recall is starting in South Korea, but Hyundai Motor North America told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it will “be taking a similar action in the US and Canada.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MMsezD"&gt;“We are working closely with NHTSA and Transport Canada on the recall and will communicate the details to affected customers shortly,” the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V2waPu"&gt;Reports of Kona EVs catching fire date back as far as mid-2019, and at least 15 have been documented since, &lt;a href="https://jalopnik.com/now-a-recalled-kona-ev-has-caught-fire-and-hyundai-is-1846134031"&gt;including one vehicle that was already called in for repair&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1ligg"&gt;The issue &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/489753/chevy-bolt-cells-different-separators-kona/"&gt;allegedly has to do with the material that separates the cell’s cathode and anode&lt;/a&gt;, though an official investigation in South Korea is still ongoing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eWb8C"&gt;General Motors recently recalled nearly 70,000 Chevy Bolts that use LG Chem batteries after reports of fires, though the automaker &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/489753/chevy-bolt-cells-different-separators-kona/"&gt;clarified to &lt;em&gt;InsideEVs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it uses a different cell than the one in the Kona EV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUC1aG"&gt;News of the recall comes just one day after Hyundai &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"&gt;unveiled the Ioniq 5 crossover SUV&lt;/a&gt;, which will be the first EV built on the company’s new electric vehicle platform. That platform &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/02/23/hyundai-taps-catl-and-sk-innovation-to-supply-more-batteries-for-e-gmp/"&gt;will use battery cells from fellow Korean company SK Innovation as well as China’s CATL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299121/hyundai-kona-electric-recall-battery-fire-lg"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299121/hyundai-kona-electric-recall-battery-fire-lg</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:49:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:49:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s where and when you can buy the Xbox Series S and Series X consoles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ex-5CndmZqOiQxMH1SbbYK2sEo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67448810/vpavic_4275_20201030_0050.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mlkkez"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update February 24th, 2021 11:48AM ET: Both the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22059832%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/video-games/xbox-series-x/consoles/products/xbox-series-x/B224744Y.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22059832%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/video-games/xbox-series-x/consoles/products/xbox-series-s-digital-edition/B224746K.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Series S&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; are currently available at GameStop starting at $299.99. You can find more information &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295791/xbox-series-x-s-restock-gamestop"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oZoKH5"&gt;The Xbox Series S and Series X consoles are officially out, and if you missed out on preordering either (or both — look, I’m not going to judge), you might be able to snag one online soon. Due to the pandemic, combined with the high demand for these consoles, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551484/best-buy-playstation-5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-store-sales-holiday-2020"&gt;retailers like Best Buy and Target are only selling online&lt;/a&gt;. That means you won’t be able to walk into a store to pick one up — unless you’ve purchased it already online. Only then will you be able to arrange an in-store pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5s3rFB"&gt;Until we hear updates on stock replenishing from retailers, I recommend keeping it locked to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08H75RTZ8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=sl2&amp;amp;tag=verge-evergreen-20&amp;amp;linkId=e8ef14f64e0e9e1dacba6db0add8b578&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fxbox-series-x-video-games%2F-%2FN-fd2hh&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fconsoles" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fconsoles" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fpromotions%2Fgaming%2F20-1310%2Findex.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg&lt;/a&gt;, and (if you have memberships) &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/xbox-brand-showcase.html"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fprod24980179&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sam’s Club&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1723309405282483811" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy encourages shoppers to visit its site&lt;/a&gt; to order instead of showing up at its stores. It doesn’t have set time slots for when it expects stock to be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lVxesu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="hLH7PZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ejjLHa"&gt;If you’re trying to decide between the Xbox Series S or Series X, my colleague Tom Warren recently reviewed both consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cqFv0O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h1 id="hCC7LP"&gt;Buy with the Xbox All Access plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="tnxiJL"&gt;As an alternative to paying full price upfront for each console, you can pay a monthly installment for either of them through the Xbox All Access plan. It’s a financing option that lets you get the console upfront at no cost. You’ll be billed one monthly payment for the console and Xbox Game Pass Ultimate together ($24.99 per month for the Series S, $34.99 per month for the Series X) for 24 months. Available at the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-all-access%23findaretailer" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fxbox-one%2Fxbox-all-access%2Fpcmcat1579299055180.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1579299055180&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fxbox-all-access%2F8571041&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fxbox-all-access%2F-%2FN-he40f&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21437954/xbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21437954/xbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:43:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:43:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Xbox Series X and S are available at GameStop</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FXDQGXbNNrsbvR5KPh1_jS-zfQU=/7x0:2034x1351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867788/twarren_200908_4177_0013.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ikctbP"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fxbox-series-x%2FB224744Y.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fxbox-series-s-digital-edition%2FB224746K.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Series S&lt;/a&gt; consoles have been available to purchase since last fall, but actually finding one to buy has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;extremely difficult&lt;/a&gt;. If you are looking to buy either console, GameStop has both models in stock, and they are available for preorder while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZpQOHY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10226823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cfRAwj"&gt;Regardless of which console you buy, you may want to consider picking up a few accessories that will help you get the most out of your new gadget, most notably &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08DF26MXW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;an additional controller&lt;/a&gt; if you are playing a game with a local co-op with a friend or family member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="v4Zgyt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562380"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P06Nfx"&gt;As far as storage goes, both consoles have rather limited storage. If you plan to download some older games that do not take full advantage of the next-gen hardware and don’t want to deplete your limited SSD storage, you can grab an external hard drive. You can buy a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Game-Drive-Xbox-Special/dp/B072LX7WLP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;4TB external hard drive from Seagate for $100&lt;/a&gt;, and it includes two months of Xbox Game Pass, a Netflix-like digital video game subscription service for Xbox consoles. Or you can buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Game-Pass-Ultimate-Membership/dp/B07TGNFVWV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three months of Xbox Game Pass&lt;/a&gt; if you don’t have any games you’re interested in buying yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gpa4v9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546609"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QOq3lx"&gt;Of course, you can also upgrade your SSD as well, but there are a few things to keep in mind. Seagate is the only one with an SSD expansion card compatible with both consoles. Additionally, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Storage-Expansion-Solid-State/dp/B08K3S6WJM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SSD expansion card only comes in 1TB&lt;/a&gt;, and it is very expensive, costing $220. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SE84Lx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562459"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="A07hUv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"},{"title":"Here’s every game coming to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"},{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295791/xbox-series-x-s-restock-gamestop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295791/xbox-series-x-s-restock-gamestop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:40:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:40:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s next big patch delayed to second half of March after studio hack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FtvImbX9KA246udBhI-xlVDSYgk=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867769/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6BgMK6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077’s&lt;/em&gt; next big patch has been delayed following developer CD Projekt Red’s disclosure that it fell victim to a ransomware attack earlier this month. The next big patch, 1.2, is now scheduled for a release sometime in the second half of March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUZgzo"&gt;“While we dearly wanted to deliver Patch 1.2 for Cyberpunk 2077 in the timespan we detailed previously, the recent cyber attack on the studio’s IT infrastructure and extensive scope of the update mean this unfortunately will not happen — we’ll need some additional time,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607741680115717"&gt;CD Projekt Red said&lt;/a&gt; via the &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kQR2Yc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our goal for Patch 1.2 goes beyond any of our previous updates. We’ve been working on numerous overall quality improvements and fixes, and we still have work to do to make sure that’s what you get. With that in mind, we’re now aiming for release in the second half of March. 2/3&lt;/p&gt;— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607743399755780?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUgv92"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; launched in an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197547/cyberpunk-2077-glitches"&gt;extremely buggy state&lt;/a&gt;, which led Sony to take the drastic step of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;removing the game from the PlayStation Store&lt;/a&gt;. CD Projekt Red has released numerous &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22239765/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-bug-fixes"&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268382/cyberpunk-2077-1-12-new-hotfix-patch-mods-vulnerability-security"&gt;hotfixes&lt;/a&gt; since launch in an attempt to address issues, and it sounds as if patch 1.2 could be the most significant yet. “Our goal for Patch 1.2 goes beyond any of our previous updates,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607743399755780"&gt;CD Projekt Red said&lt;/a&gt;. The studio is also &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37298/our-commitment"&gt;working on&lt;/a&gt; free DLCs and a free next-gen console update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5vorVT"&gt;Hackers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"&gt;reportedly accessed&lt;/a&gt; source code from some of CD Projekt Red’s games, including &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;, as well as internal company documents. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"&gt;hackers reportedly sold&lt;/a&gt; the data they stole at auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xWjaAW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 studio’s hacked data has reportedly been sold","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 studio falls victim to ransomware attack, data leak threatened","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299184/cyberpunk-2077-patch-1-2-delayed-cd-projekt-red-studio-hack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299184/cyberpunk-2077-patch-1-2-delayed-cd-projekt-red-studio-hack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:30:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:30:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>The NYPD deploys a robot dog again</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7hfxwrfAXZuYuzRwkieP29RKKEA=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867715/robot_dog.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by William Joel | Video by Daniel Valls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UkC5Mu"&gt;The cyberpunk dystopia is here! (If you weren’t aware: I’m sorry. You’re living in a cyberpunk dystopia.) The latest sign — aside from corporations controlling many aspects of everyday life, massive widespread wealth inequality, and the recent prominence of bisexual lighting — comes in the form of robot dogs deployed to do jobs human police used to. Yesterday, as &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/02/23/video-shows-nypds-new-robotic-dog-in-action-in-the-bronx"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, the NYPD deployed Boston Dynamics’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/17/20697540/boston-dynamics-robots-commercial-real-world-business-spot-on-sale"&gt;robot “dog” Spot&lt;/a&gt; to a home invasion crime scene in the Bronx. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MSKqy6"&gt;&lt;iframe height="348" width="618" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" src="//players.brightcove.net/4137224153001/6aIMRO3kiI_default/index.html?videoId=6234666514001"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mWmZbr"&gt;The video was taken by videographer Daniel Valls, of FreedomNews.tv. You can hear a voice say “that thing is creepy” as the robot prances past the camera. The &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; reports that a spokesperson for the NYPD said the robot is in a test phase, presumably to see if it’s actually useful out in the field. (It was equipped with lights and cameras, the spokesperson continued, to ensure that NYPD could see whatever the robot was seeing.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kX6jVD"&gt;This isn’t the first time the NYPD has deployed one of Boston Dynamics’ robots. Back in October, the department used another Spot to &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/10/29/nypd-deploys-robot-dog-after-brooklyn-parking-dispute-shooting/"&gt;find a gunman who’d barricaded himself in a building&lt;/a&gt; after he’d accidentally shot someone in the head during a parking dispute in Brooklyn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAnpv7"&gt;While I think it’s probably a good thing that robots are being used more often in situations that might be dangerous for a human, it is more than a little unnerving to see the things that happen in books begin to happen in real life. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299140/nypd-boston-dynamics-spot-robot-dog"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299140/nypd-boston-dynamics-spot-robot-dog</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:28:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:28:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u2r1v0qpkmDCofvfzLEcU6WDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809161/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DzZXIa"&gt;One of the most frustrating tasks for many of us these days is finding how and where to get an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. It can be a real exercise in exasperation: the websites are often difficult to navigate and prone to frequent crashes; in addition, after finding an open appointment slot and filling out multiple pages of questions, you are often told that the opening has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Vp4Bt"&gt;In view of all this, we’ve tried to gather as much helpful information as we can about ways to research and snag vaccination appointments for yourself and others. We’ll update this as more information presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JYv8ZW"&gt;Research the vaccination qualifications in your state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jJJ2mU"&gt;To begin with, it’s a good idea to try to pin down if you or the person you are assisting is currently qualified for the COVID-19 vaccine. Find the vaccine information site (or sites) that is being run by your state and / or city. This will also help you figure out when you might be qualified if you aren’t already. If you can’t find it via a quick search, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/plan-your-vaccine/"&gt;NBC News has created a simple website&lt;/a&gt; that lets you find out what the current situation is in your specific state. &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/covid-19/where-to-get-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;Prescription company GoodRx&lt;/a&gt; offers similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N5dWHX"&gt;Find all the places that might offer appointments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XK1Cc0"&gt;There are, fortunately or unfortunately, many different sites where you can go to find out if you can get an appointment to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvDmn"&gt;For example, here in New York City, we’ve had to navigate separate sites run by the city and the state. Various hospital systems also have their own sites, as do pharmacies such as Walgreens and CVS, which have recently begun offering appointments for vaccinations. It’s a lot to check — and it can be enormously confusing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usTdFX"&gt;As a result, your first step is probably to check your state’s government health website (searching your state name and “COVID vaccine” will probably do it). If you’re an urban dweller, check for your city’s information site as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8ot2F"&gt;While most personal physicians do not have access to vaccines, your doctor may be able to tell you some of the places to check. Other resources include your local hospital system, your union (especially if your employment qualifies you for a vaccination), and, of course, friends and colleagues, many of whom have probably been doing their own searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZ6Bfn"&gt;As you find resources and sites, make sure to bookmark them. I keep a folder on my bookmarks bar called “COVID” — you may want to name yours something more cheerful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8lP4_R3np2CX9crqTcg9Mq6I2Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13963741/IMG_1653.1419968302.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6uguNM"&gt;Have all your information ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dt0LZ"&gt;Many of us who have tried to register for vaccination appointments have gone through the experience of filling out several screens of information only to find that, by the time we got to the end, the appointment was gone. So it’s a good idea to have all your data — such as your name, age, address, insurance info, and the registration ID / password for the site — immediately at hand. The faster you can go through the registration process, the more likely you are to actually get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRD8jU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague Cory Zapatka says that he highly recommends using a password manager if you have one. He created accounts with all the vaccination sites in his area, even if they didn’t have appointments available at the time, so that if / when the time came, he could just auto-fill and get in right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9bBlc"&gt;And if you do get an appointment, make sure you have the appropriate paperwork already handy — especially since available appointments can be last minute. Necessary paperwork could include proof of employment, proof of age, or proof of a qualifying condition. Since the last one may require a doctor’s note or other record, it’s a good idea to call your doctor now — or if you’ve got access to a doctor’s or hospital website, that may offer you access to the proof you need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dqUcf"&gt;One more thing: check to see if you’ve gotten all the email that has been sent to you by your vaccine supplier. At least one staff member of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; found a necessary consent form hiding in her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCK4vB"&gt;Watch for news of upcoming vaccination sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bDlWg4"&gt;Keep an eye on the news. More and more sites and hubs are being added as the US gears up for a stronger push. If you see a news item saying that a hub is about to open, find the site for the hub and keep checking — once it does open, the available slots will probably go quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz172X"&gt;One thing that sometimes helps is to look for patterns in the appearance of new appointments. For example, when I heard that the pharmacy chain Walgreens was going to begin giving out vaccines in my area, I spent a couple of days going onto the site, and suddenly realized that there was a pattern: the company was only scheduling appointments two to four days in advance and was adding new appointments each day just after midnight. Once I understood the pattern, I was able to get appointments for a couple of friends and let others know about it as well. (Note: since vaccine supplies and scheduling methods can change on a dime, this particular strategy may no longer work by the time you read this.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsRia6ki1VqiuNodQvjKHdK9-ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299690/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_8.47.56_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gz26d4"&gt;Look for help online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PgrwN8"&gt;There are a number of online resources popping up headed by developers and other technology-savvy folks who have taken the time and effort to try to make sense of this confusion. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/10/covid-vaccine-appointment-websites/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/09/nyregion/vaccine-website-appointment-nyc.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some of these listings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bUR9PN"&gt;California&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="111Dwk"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.vaccinateca.com/"&gt;VaccinateCA&lt;/a&gt; checks pharmacies and hospitals for information about open appointments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h3AFk9"&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WLYqtL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.macovidvaccines.com/"&gt;MA Covid Vaccine Appointments site&lt;/a&gt; offers lists of and links to sites with available appointments. A volunteer-run site, &lt;a href="https://vaccinatema.com/"&gt;Vaccinate MA&lt;/a&gt;, tries to improve on the state website with a map-based design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BeZogz"&gt;Another site, &lt;a href="https://macovidvaxhelp.com/"&gt;Massachusetts COVID Vaccination Help&lt;/a&gt;, uses volunteers to help eligible state residents book an appointment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="c9OpvY"&gt;New Jersey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZYJAS8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatenj.com/"&gt;Vaccinate NJ&lt;/a&gt; also uses volunteers to try to help state residents find vaccine opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ijVYyv"&gt;New York&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vhk2GI"&gt;An NYC site called &lt;a href="https://www.turbovax.info/"&gt;TurboVax&lt;/a&gt; pulls “the latest appointments from 45 city and state-run vaccine sites in the NYC area” and puts them on Twitter. Followers who set their Twitter notifications for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/turbovax"&gt;@turbovax&lt;/a&gt; can quickly find out about newly opened appointment slots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c0AX5B"&gt;Another called &lt;a href="https://nycvaccinelist.com/"&gt;NYC Vaccine List&lt;/a&gt; uses a combination of scripts and checks by volunteers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;scour various sites for openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vRg75P"&gt;Texas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZJic26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.covid19vaccinetx.com/"&gt;Covid 19 Vaccine TX&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced resource for registering with local counties and finding locations where vaccines may be available.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NEM7f0"&gt;Washington&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="yR8waA"&gt;A volunteer group in the state of Washington has launched the &lt;a href="https://www.covidwa.com/"&gt;WA COVID Vaccine Finder&lt;/a&gt; as an aggregation resource for vaccination appointments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hFMYTz"&gt;General resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="C1YLfR"&gt;There are several sites that aggregate the aggregators: &lt;a href="https://wherecanigetavaccine.com/"&gt;Where Can I Get A Vaccine?&lt;/a&gt; offers a list of sites available for various US states. &lt;a href="https://covidshotfinder.com/"&gt;COVIDShotFinder&lt;/a&gt; lets you select a state or county and look for the various vaccine resources available. &lt;a href="https://www.findashot.org/"&gt;Find A Shot&lt;/a&gt; also shows you possible openings depending on your state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jdCWU8"&gt;One possible strategy is to use page-change-monitoring tools such as &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/blog/how-to-be-alerted-of-covid-19-vaccine-availability-in-your-local-pharmacy/"&gt;Visualping&lt;/a&gt; to generate alerts for when new appointments become available. These apps watch websites for you and send alerts to your email, text, or even Slack account when new information appears. They can be very useful (and allow you to take time for, say, lunch). But since these are, for the most part, business apps, you may need to pay for the privilege. For example, while &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/pricing"&gt;Visualping does have a free service&lt;/a&gt;, it is limited to pinging you once an hour up to 65 times a month, which may not be often enough if you’re trying to score an appointment.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nhHjOx"&gt;If you’re a developer and / or coder who wants to help, check out &lt;a href="https://www.usdigitalresponse.org/"&gt;US Digital Response&lt;/a&gt;, an independent organization which, according to its website, “connects experienced, pro-bono technologists with local government and non-profit organizations responding to crisis.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reservation Of The Anticovid Vaccine For Over Eighty In Apulian Pharmacies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4leCSmB_jTd6jhw7V_SvQQsfQ8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299704/1231117569.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Davide Pischettola / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are able, it’s a good idea to reach out and help those who may not be able to get appointments on their own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8mSy40"&gt;If you can, help others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Kz9AlN"&gt;One of the worst things about the distribution of the COVID-19 vaccines is that those who need it the most are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;often the least likely to be able to navigate the technology required to get an appointment&lt;/a&gt;: older people, differently abled people, or those who don’t have or can’t afford computers and / or internet connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2VOR9"&gt;If you have the time and talent, reach out to anyone you know who may not be able to get an appointment on their own. This could be as simple as finding phone numbers they can call to try to schedule an appointment, going online and getting an appointment for them, or helping them get to and from the vaccination site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evm4o5"&gt;You could also see if there are any groups that are organizing help. &lt;a href="https://www.westsiderag.com/2021/01/19/need-help-signing-up-for-a-vaccine-a-young-tech-savvy-person-can-help-you"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The West Side Rag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, reports that a group of New Yorkers created the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScO11RAr7tqHU6LJp_ZNMl5mRbxdg-zc1lO1SuVHBBDLTyJrg/closedform"&gt;Vaccine Appointment Assistance Team (VAAT)&lt;/a&gt; to help their non-technically-savvy neighbors navigate the process. (At the time this was written, VAAT had temporarily suspended their services.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rm5plO"&gt;Look for leftover vaccine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M5v0nn"&gt;While the vaccines can last for six months while they’re kept frozen, once thawed and refrigerated, the Pfizer vaccine will last five days while the Moderna vaccine will last for 30 days. As a result, when people don’t show up for their appointments, some centers will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229169/leftover-vaccines-random-people-grocery-stores-pharmacies"&gt;offer vaccinations to those who may not immediately qualify&lt;/a&gt; rather than waste vaccines that would otherwise be rendered unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI3933"&gt;However, running to a nearby pharmacy or vaccine hub in the hit-and-miss hopes that there will be some shots waiting at the end of the day isn’t the most effective way to be vaccinated. (Besides, getting hypothermia while waiting in the cold isn’t going to help.) At least one group is trying to ameliorate the situation: a pilot project called &lt;a href="https://vaxstandby.com/"&gt;Vaccination Standby&lt;/a&gt; says that it will monitor providers around the US for word of extra doses and text notifications to those whose zip codes are near the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAc3tM"&gt;There are also local organizations that are offering standby lists. For example, Buncombe County in North Carolina has a &lt;a href="https://www.buncombecounty.org/countycenter/news-detail.aspx?id=19137"&gt;vaccination waitlist and standby list&lt;/a&gt;, as does the &lt;a href="https://www.co.monroe.in.us/egov/documents/1611179705_09719.pdf"&gt;Monroe County Health Department&lt;/a&gt; in Indiana. Check your local government site to see if there’s one in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fg3eNk"&gt;Be persistent!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JTTPvK"&gt;Yes, it’s frustrating as hell, but keep at it. If a website crashes, try again. If you’re dropped from a phone call, call again (and have a game, video, or book ready to keep yourself occupied while you’re on hold). If you can’t find anything during working hours, try late at night or very early in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBXxUO"&gt;Persistence may be one of the most important aspects of getting an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. You may be tempted to give up, especially after hitting the “no appointments available” wall time and time again. But until vaccine production is ramped up enough to cover more of our population, and until distribution becomes more organized and easier to manage, simple stubbornness may be your best tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwiVs8"&gt;And hopefully this article, and all the advice it contains, will soon be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QdqaC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 11:10AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include the WA Covid Vaccine Finder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rW1K6i"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 16th, 10:10AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include a mention of webpage change monitoring tools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Jkqbm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 19th, 11AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include another Massachusetts site and two general vaccination finding sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSy6ej"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 22nd, 10:40AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add the Find A Shot site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K6N5Zp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 11:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add the Massachusetts COVID Vaccination Help site and reorganize some entries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwQk0g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0F1RM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:24:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:24:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>Joby Aviation is going public, reveals its electric aircraft in flight for the first time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XThdDEFAu-21unV7uBDTjGTJt9M=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867688/Joby_Aviation_Aircraft_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ydTwid"&gt;Joby Aviation, the electric aviation company based in Northern California, is the latest futuristic mobility company to go public via a reverse merger with a special purpose acquisition company, or SPAC. To celebrate, the company is releasing the first footage of its electric aircraft in flight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bs2kqd"&gt;Joby, which is backed by Toyota and recently acquired Uber’s flying taxi division, is merging with Reinvent Technology Partners, a “blank check” company run by LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman and Zynga founder Mark Pincus. The new company, which will have a post-money valuation of $6.6 billion, will be listed on the New York Stock Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3dYdDT"&gt;As part of the deal, Joby will get $1.6 billion in cash, $690 million of which will come from Reinvent’s cash in trust and $835 million from private investors The Baupost Group, funds and accounts managed by BlackRock, Fidelity Management &amp;amp; Research LLC, and Baillie Gifford. Hoffman will join Joby’s board. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MtOKH7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As part of the deal, Joby will get $1.6 billion in cash&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UteFAA"&gt;Joby is the brainchild of inventor JoeBen Bevirt, who started the company in 2009 and operated it in relative obscurity. In 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/1/16959698/joby-aviation-evtol-100-million-investment"&gt;Joby announced&lt;/a&gt; it had raised a surprising $100 million from a variety of investors, including the venture capital arms of Intel, Toyota, and JetBlue. The money helped finance the development of the company’s air taxi prototype, which has been conducting test flights at Joby’s private airfield in Northern California. Bevirt helps run an incubator outside of Santa Cruz that’s been described as a &lt;a href="https://pando.com/2013/07/03/the-startup-ranch-of-santa-cruz/"&gt;quasi-commune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s9nuYr"&gt;The company closed on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21068135/joby-aviation-toyota-flying-air-taxi-investment-amount"&gt;massive $590 million round of venture capital funding&lt;/a&gt;. Joby also announced that it was teaming up with previous investor Toyota to launch an air taxi service using its new aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TDzeEe"&gt;Unlike the dozens of other companies that are currently building electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) aircraft, Joby has kept much of its project under wraps. Today’s footage is the first time Joby’s vehicle has been seen in flight. The all-electric aircraft has six rotors and seats five, including the pilot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9vx9z"&gt;The video shows it taking off vertically, like a helicopter, and then shifting into forward flight using tilt rotors. Joby says it can reach a top speed of 200 mph, travel 150 miles on a single charge, and is 100 times quieter than a conventional aircraft. The company says it aims to have a scaled-up air taxi service in operation by 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFrwdA"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KViIZufQAZ7Q8T7vh79VIuHVW-nZp3CN/view"&gt;the company’s investor presentation&lt;/a&gt;, Joby expects each aircraft to cost $1.3 million to manufacture, with the potential to reduce that amount by half in the future. Joby also projects that each aircraft will generate $2.2 million in revenue. That assumes every aircraft will operate 4,500 hours per year with an average of 2.3 passengers per trip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="v89ELH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Joby expects each aircraft to cost $1.3 million to manufacture&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iiDkzq"&gt;(&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/michetravi/status/1364586943053455363"&gt;As noted by aviation writer Michael Travierso on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, this represents an exponential increase over the number of hours the average Cessna aircraft at a busy aeroclub flies every year. Electric aircraft are expected to require less maintenance than their gas-powered equivalents.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="evaJTe"&gt;Of course, many companies — Joby included — have promised revolutionary new aircraft for years, only to miss deadlines or fail to live up to past promises. Kitty Hawk, the flying car venture backed by Google co-founder Larry Page, had to reorganize &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeremybogaisky/2019/12/01/inside-larry-pages-kitty-hawk-returned-deposits-battery-fires-boeing-cora/#c6e934858ab4"&gt;amid reports&lt;/a&gt; about breakdowns, battery fires, and returned deposits. Another startup, Zunum, is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21612702/zunum-aero-sues-boeing-fraud-hybrid-electric-jet"&gt;locked in a bitter legal fight&lt;/a&gt; with its former investor, Boeing. And last year, Germany’s Lilium Jet had a &lt;a href="https://evtol.com/news/lilium-evtol-catches-fire/"&gt;prototype catch fire recently&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gsiyh7"&gt;Joby isn’t the only eVTOL company to go public via SPAC. Archer Aviation, another electric flight company, plans on &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/42feff1d-8228-4c93-bd78-b537d9eb9fa7"&gt;merging with blank-check company&lt;/a&gt; Atlas Crest Investment Corp, and it has said it would &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/archer-aviation-aims-to-launch-network-of-urban-air-taxis-in-los-angeles-by-2024/"&gt;launch an air taxi service in Los Angeles by 2024&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298957/joby-aviation-public-evtol-electric-aircraft-spac-hoffman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298957/joby-aviation-public-evtol-electric-aircraft-spac-hoffman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T11:22:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T11:22:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valheim is Steam’s hottest new PC game, and it’s now sold 4 million copies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V1jZ3m6OHe2wY4qSrBownsaWqo4=/155x0:829x449/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68831563/valheim_steam.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WxySs4"&gt;The other day, I saw a game named &lt;em&gt;Valheim &lt;/em&gt;atop the Steam Early Access sales charts, with overwhelmingly positive reviews. &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/9/22275109/valheim-viking-game-steam-charts-explainer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt; seemed to like the $20 Viking-themed survival game&lt;/a&gt;, and I thought friends might like it, too. I wasn’t ready to commit quite yet — I waffled a while before giving it a go. Know who bought it while I was making up my mind? &lt;em&gt;One million other people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="67WpZr"&gt;On February 10th, just eight days after launch, indie developer Iron Gate announced that &lt;em&gt;Valheim &lt;/em&gt;had &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/892970?emclan=103582791463217109&amp;amp;emgid=3059603085894895511"&gt;already sold 1 million copies&lt;/a&gt;. Five days after that, &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/892970/view/4627981752752748715"&gt;reached 2 million sales&lt;/a&gt;. On Friday February 19th, two days after we originally published this post, &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/892970/view/3059603718053006418"&gt;it hit 3 million sales&lt;/a&gt;. We're now at &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/892970/announcements/detail/3058478454611894476"&gt;4 million&lt;/a&gt; as of February 24th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SlvYZS"&gt;Here are a few other facts you might like to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4TAu80"&gt;It has now been &lt;a href="https://steamcharts.com/"&gt;the second-most played game on &lt;em&gt;all of Steam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at many occasions, ahead of every game save &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive, &lt;/em&gt;and it’s comfortably trading blows with Dota 2 and PUBG for the #2 and #3 slots each day. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fzcx0K"&gt;It’s already set a top-ten record for concurrent players on Steam &lt;a href="https://steamdb.info/app/892970/graphs/"&gt;with roughly 392,000&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, knocking &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto V&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://steamcharts.com/"&gt;off that top 10 chart&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="an0GTw"&gt;By Friday the 19th, it took the #9 spot with 410,000 players, pulling &lt;em&gt;Postal &lt;/em&gt;down one rung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pANFTq"&gt;By the 21st, it crossed 500,000 simultaneous players to claim the #5 slot, bumping four more games down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WJosSj"&gt;It topped the Steam Top Sellers list during Valve’s Steam Lunar New Year sale — despite having zero discounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WvlxVY"&gt;Developer Iron Gate says it's already been played for a total of 10,000 years. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ttr5q0GEPIwdbRlpZ4pb474KNjI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309259/steam_charts_top_played_games.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot of SteamCharts, taken February 16th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZJXT0NhkWQgCA4_iJaYyaP3x5AI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309223/steam_top_sellers_lunar_new_year.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot taken February 15th, the last day of the Steam sale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O6RSp0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/valheim-may-well-be-steams-biggest-ever-viral-hit/"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;’s trajectory is unlike anything we’ve seen before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUq6tJ"&gt;The closest parallel is perhaps &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/pubg-playerunknown-brendan-greene-interview-july-2017/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PlayerUnknown’s Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; —&lt;/em&gt; which similarly came out of Steam Early Access, sold oodles of copies during Steam sales &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/steam-summer-sale-pubg-player-unknown-battlegrounds/"&gt;(also without being on sale&lt;/a&gt;), set a record for the Steam game with the most simultaneous players (3.2 million) that still stands today, and kicked off the entire battle royale genre that spawned today’s &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and more. But even &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; took months to reach the kind of numbers that &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; already has now, and that was with a genre-defining, action-packed, nail-biting, streamer-friendly game that makes for a delightfully tense watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MmalvW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Technically, ‘Valheim’ released a 2018 alpha build on itch.io&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UjhWdv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;, by comparison, is slow and methodical. It’s part of an established genre of survival games where you scavenge and harvest, chop and dig, hunt and skin, then build better tools to do it all more efficiently over and over again. Only here, you’re also a badass Viking who can (eventually) build fortresses and ships, you’re hunting down gods for sport, and you’re exploring &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/valheim-player-discovers-whats-beyond-the-edge-of-its-enormous-map/"&gt;a gobsmackingly gigantic map&lt;/a&gt; filled with idyllic scenery, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PatrikJarlestam/status/1361604565531959305"&gt;charming music&lt;/a&gt;, a touch of lived-in mystery, and some enemies that stomp me convincingly enough that I get a slight &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; vibe out of it. Oh, and when you cut down trees, they fall and hit other things (like you) for massive damage! That’s never going to get old.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jvXfF31K_kYujVsQz_1WN9Ow060=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309294/valheim_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The game’s graphics may seem dull at first but can be picturesque, particularly with eye candy like depth of field, tessellation, and sun shafts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zklytf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/9/22275109/valheim-viking-game-steam-charts-explainer"&gt;As Cass Marshall at &lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also incredibly accessible and easy to learn — I’d convinced myself that I disliked survival games due to their typically rigid mechanics, but in &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; everything seems to make sense without thinking too hard. I don’t need to spend ages punching trees to build some basic tools, there’s no need to acquire blueprints (recipes unlock as soon as you find new materials), and I don’t have to painstakingly plan how I want my house to look before I start building. You can instantly demolish a portion of a structure and refund your materials if it’s not quite right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wk3PCo"&gt;In fact, building is fast enough that I’m starting to build temporary forward operating bases before I venture into each new area, like the tiny fort below that took all of five minutes and I’ve since expanded twice. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DDoTrQoXUEMDG9CjIsfEfptUEqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309305/valheim_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It gets real dark at night. Fire is a must if you’re planning to stay up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Fp3dFC"&gt;There’s no telling how long the magic will last for me or for the game’s 2 million players and counting, of course. It’s been &lt;a href="https://steamcharts.com/app/945360#1y"&gt;all downhill for &lt;em&gt;Among Us &lt;/em&gt;on PC&lt;/a&gt;, which currently only attracts one-tenth of its peak player count of 438,000 last September (though it could still be wildly popular on mobile). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HKI4K5"&gt;But I imagine word-of-mouth may keep &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; going for a while. I can’t wait to try the game’s two- to ten-player co-op mode with my circle of friends, and that means more copies in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="khWT2s"&gt;If &lt;em&gt;Valheim &lt;/em&gt;does have staying power, expect to hear this game’s name on a lot of lips in the months to come. If history’s any indication, we’ll soon see a rush of knockoffs, &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2020-08-18-mobile-version-of-fall-guys-is-a-scam-mediatonic-warns"&gt;fake-outs&lt;/a&gt;, and attempts to make other games play more like it, and there may be a lot of pressure on Iron Gate to port the PC-only game to consoles and phones as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S3l7Vk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, February 19th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valheim has now sold 3 million copies and is now has a new record for the ninth-most simultaneous players at any one moment on Steam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0vR2id"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, February 24th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valheim has now sold 4 million copies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fKdBoe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Polygon’s 7 tips for living your best afterlife in Valheim","url":"https://www.polygon.com/valheim-guide/22288015/beginners-tips-tricks-wood-stone-inventory-building-house-camp-health-stamina-food-hunger"},{"title":"Polygon’s Valheim server guide: Invite friends, join games, play multiplayer","url":"https://www.polygon.com/valheim-guide/22289767/server-private-community-friends-start-join-game-select-world"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22286507/valheim-steam-pc-game-2-million-sales"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22286507/valheim-steam-pc-game-2-million-sales</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
