<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-21T11:00:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T11:00:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T11:00:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro will have a feature just like ‘spatial audio’ on the AirPods Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F8A-neHYHIB9s8WRvBp5vE5mqcg=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68560483/galaxy_buds_pro.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/first-images-of-the-samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-1606914779-1" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bzXf8p"&gt;With its upcoming Galaxy Buds Pro, Samsung is planning to counter one of the differentiating features of Apple’s AirPods Pro (and now AirPods Max): spatial audio. Spatial audio crams an immersive, surround sound-like experience into a set of earbuds or headphones. And it accurately keeps the sound source anchored to your iPhone or iPad, so if you turn your head, you’ll notice that the audio stays in front of you. Wherever you move the device, that’s where it’ll sound like the audio track is coming from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vvogt9"&gt;But Samsung seems to be readying its own take on spatial audio. As is becoming oddly common, the company’s mobile Galaxy Buds app has prematurely spilled some of Samsung’s latest earbud tricks. As noted by &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/12/20/samsung-app-leaks-galaxy-buds-pro-in-full-including-copy-of-apples-spatial-audio-feature/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an updated version of the app &lt;a href="https://github.com/ThePBone/BudsProAnalysis"&gt;was found on Samsung’s servers&lt;/a&gt; with screenshots and features for the unannounced Galaxy Buds Pro. One of those new software capabilities is referred to as “3D audio for videos,” and the app says this will let you “hear vivid, immersive sound coming from all directions so you feel like you’re right in the scene when you watch videos.” Yep, sounds like spatial audio. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KvgJ1GyDetRP6hFm_DzeRDqjFfc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22187822/Screen_Shot_2020_12_21_at_10.34.48_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ki3VJA"&gt;There’s also this note: “To get the best experience, keep your earbuds near your phone.” According to a teardown of the app, it looks as though Samsung will try to replicate the positional awareness / head-tracking aspect as well. Apparently, you’ll need a Samsung phone running Android 11 or newer for the feature to work. Other headphones (like those from Sony) offer 3D audio, but this is for music rather than movies from streaming apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldvPqn"&gt;The app also reveals that the Galaxy Buds Pro will have a “voice detect” feature that automatically enables transparency mode and lowers the volume of your audio when the earbuds sense that you’re speaking. Again, Sony has something similar to this on its 1000XM4 headphones where music immediately pauses when you start talking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YYkQsb"&gt;The Galaxy Buds Pro are expected to be announced in January alongside the Galaxy S21 series at the next Unpacked event.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193235/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-3d-spatial-audio-leak"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193235/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-3d-spatial-audio-leak</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>A semester in solitude</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Many Universities in the D.C. region have announced that the Fall 2020 semester will be fully online." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EOesp3nT968pCFF6m_gE-XqIgBQ=/195x0:5184x3326/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68560262/1228205402.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jonathan Newton /The Washington Post via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;After spending the fall in their bedrooms, students say their mental health has suffered&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="bazt3n"&gt;Georgina DiNardo’s first virtual class is at 9:45. It’s Introduction To Communications — she’s a TA, so she’s responsible for sharing her computer screen with the class to display articles and other visual aids. At 11, she has a short break — she walks around the room to stretch her legs. By 11:20, she’s back on Zoom for a macroeconomics class (as a student, this time). For the rest of the afternoon, she edits and writes for &lt;em&gt;The Eagle&lt;/em&gt;, American University’s newspaper, communicating with her colleagues in a pile of Slack channels. Then, homework. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7vLLg2"&gt;DiNardo, a sophomore at American, and her roommate have to negotiate space (they both have Zoom classes every day). One takes their shared bedroom, and one takes the dining room table. DiNardo prefers the former — it’s easier to focus in a small private space — but, “We kind of rotate on how we’re feeling.” Whichever room DiNardo ends up in, she’s there the entire day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5Zb46m"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Due to evolving health conditions and government requirements, AU will offer fall semester undergraduate and graduate courses online with no residential experience. We will be updating the FAQ and providing additional details going forward &lt;a href="https://t.co/yV1pPh7cFR"&gt;https://t.co/yV1pPh7cFR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— American University (@AmericanU) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmericanU/status/1288854926500728833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 30, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5XEK7o"&gt;DiNardo walks to campus about once a week for a change of scene. Sometimes, she studies on the quad or in one of the few buildings that are open, as far away from other people as possible. Occasionally, she meets up with other students in her classes, and they watch their Zoom lectures together. “We can feel like we’re in the classroom,” she says. Plus, “It keeps me from dozing off and going on my phone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JBdPRi"&gt;But walking around an empty campus can also be eerie — it’s a reminder of what’s been taken away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="iTXOP6"&gt;DiNardo is one of hundreds of thousands of US students who were tasked with cobbling together a college experience from their bedrooms this year. American, like &lt;a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/heres-a-list-of-colleges-plans-for-reopening-in-the-fall/#id=193973"&gt;almost half&lt;/a&gt; of colleges across the US, taught all courses primarily or fully online. Students took classes, did homework, met with clubs, applied for internships. Many, like DiNardo, even lived by campus, down the hallway from their classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zHsWsr"&gt;On paper, that semester looks fairly similar to pre-COVID life. And since the first wave of closures in March, onlookers have wondered: if school can happen online, why have campuses at all? Writers decreed that COVID-19 was the &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/oliviergarret/2020/06/04/this-is-the-end-of-college-as-we-know-it/?sh=1efa6154297c"&gt;end of college as we know it&lt;/a&gt;. A former college president &lt;a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/how-should-colleges-prepare-for-a-post-pandemic-world/?cid=gen_sign_in"&gt;predicted&lt;/a&gt; that the online semester would push students to switch to lower-cost online degree programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zkLUGf"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;While we hoped to come back to campus together next month, we have made the difficult decision to hold all undergraduate courses online for the fall semester, with limited exceptions. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(1/4)&lt;a href="https://t.co/uedKAbNmq6"&gt;https://t.co/uedKAbNmq6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— GW University (@GWtweets) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GWtweets/status/1287837153796464641?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 27, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YzepU1"&gt;But the virtual fall neglected one important component of the college experience: mental health. For the seven students, faculty, staff, and administrators that I spoke to, this semester brought to light how important an in-person community is to many students’ well-being — and how difficult that is to replicate over Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="31swXC"&gt;DiNardo started out the fall semester optimistic — she hadn’t minded a few weeks of online classes in the spring. But after spending day after day indoors, in front of computers, she could tell that her friends weren’t doing well. &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Everyone’s becoming a ball of stress,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9my3Gh"&gt;Then her own behavior started to change. She was taking longer to get out of bed. She wanted to sleep all the time. She was wearing darker clothing. Toward the end of the semester, she was on the phone with her doctor, trying to schedule an appointment, and suddenly burst into tears. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2sElio"&gt;DiNardo and her friends aren’t alone. Jay Gilmore, an assistant professor of journalism and strategic media at the University of Memphis, tried his best to keep his pupils meeting (over Zoom) regularly, with assignments on a routine schedule, to make this semester “as normal as possible.” But as classes went on, he saw his students lose motivation — grades slipped. “If a class started at 9:40, I would see students rolling over in bed at 9:39,” Gilmore said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lkv1mo"&gt;Gilmore doesn’t think the sluggishness has anything to do with his instruction. He says his students are lonely, and the isolation is taking a toll on their mental health. Research backs him up: in a &lt;a href="https://www.jmir.org/2020/9/e21279/"&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; of US college students published in September, 71 percent of respondents reported increased stress and anxiety due to COVID-19. Of those, 86 percent cited decreased social interaction as a factor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="scXGDC"&gt;“It’s such an important time for young adults to feel a sense of community, and their main developmental task is to be establishing their identity with their peers,” said Michael Alcee, mental health coordinator at the Manhattan School of Music. “Having that short-circuited by this pandemic is particularly difficult, psychologically and emotionally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xPXjF1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If a class started at 9:40, I would see students rolling over in bed at 9:39”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PK0eVZ"&gt;It’s certainly possible to socialize online. But it’s different — and, students told me, less fulfilling — in a couple significant ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gsdp1m"&gt;For one, when you’re spending a full day on Zoom, socializing on Zoom doesn’t always feel like a break — it feels like yet another thing you have to do on Zoom. Emma Marszalek, a junior at George Washington University who spent the semester at home in New Jersey, hasn’t attended the movie screenings, trivia nights, guest performances, and other virtual events that her school has put on. “As cute as it is... I can’t bring myself to go onto another Zoom meeting,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eCwgBo"&gt;There’s also the lack of spontaneity — chatting over Zoom requires setting aside time, which is already in short supply for many students. Grabbing a quick coffee on the way to class or running into an acquaintance in the library is off the table. “At school, I could see someone, and even if we talk for five minutes walking from one place to another, it fits better into your schedule,” Marszalek says. “Now, if I want to talk to someone I have to text them, which is effort, and then schedule a time when we FaceTime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybGyOr"&gt;And meeting new people, while still possible during a virtual semester, can be a daunting prospect. Allen Kenneth Schaidle, a PhD student in higher education and organizational change at UCLA, says his university has encouraged students to reach out virtually and connect with others in their classes — but he thinks that’s too much onus to put on them. “We’ve seen that message coming from these offices that ‘We’re doing the best we can, but it’s also up to you to start reaching out to people,’” he says. “We should also fill these gap times where students might be having organic social interactions on campus... and I’m not seeing that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6Neko"&gt;These may seem like simple enough things. But they’re aspects of college social life that many students and university members took for granted in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2FlZg"&gt;“People re-evaluated what’s really important,” says Alcee. Alcee held counseling sessions over Zoom this semester — as well as by phone, for students who were tired of Zoom. He says he’s worked with introverted students who were initially excited not to have to socialize but started missing it. He also worked with social students who, until this year, hadn’t realized just how necessary their social circle was to them. For both groups, video calls didn’t cut it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZJJ0c9"&gt;Gilmore hosts a &lt;a href="https://jays-world.captivate.fm/episodes"&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; where he speaks to students and educators around the country — and he’s talked to very few who are happy. Many of them underestimated how lonely pandemic college would feel. “Just being in the university center with other students ... getting together for a football game at the stadium, I think we all had taken that for granted in recent years,” said Gilmore. “And 2020 has shown people want to get back to that, they want to get back to human interaction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="mGzYo4"&gt;Every student and educator I spoke to is aware of the seriousness of COVID-19. None of them questioned the importance of taking precautions or the necessity (in some regions) of moving classes online. But students did say that when they return to campus, they’ll be investing a lot more in their community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vmOSqe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I can’t keep budgeting every minute of my time to schoolwork”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O1SghR"&gt;“There will be a greater level of appreciation for the smaller things,” said Schaidle. “Being in class, getting to know your peers, walking around on campus.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CA5qh3"&gt;Marszalek decided to drop one of her two majors so that she can spend more time socializing whenever she returns to George Washington. This semester brought “this realization that I can’t keep budgeting every minute of my time to schoolwork or classwork, because ... I want to be able to actually see people and do fun things,” she says. “I can just experience being with my friends, going on adventures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHkKRc"&gt;“I want to take advantage of that stuff,” she added. “Because it’s not always available.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22160165/college-fall-semester-2020-covid-online-lonely-mental-health-community"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22160165/college-fall-semester-2020-covid-online-lonely-mental-health-community</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>We built a 2020 time capsule out of synthetic DNA — here’s how</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A gloved hand holds a small vial; illustrated DNA swirls around it" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ht3VGxEZZajwY9dsRU9swnx1Efg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68560013/Container_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i5iaWI"&gt;Somehow, it’s the end of December. What is there to say about 2020? This year has felt like a turning point, a cliff, the end of one world and the beginning of another. For us on &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s science desk (and so many others), it’s been a year we want to both lock away forever and also never forget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GuGLpn"&gt;As 2020 wound down, we decided that we wanted to commemorate this unreal year with a time capsule, so that whatever happens in 2021 and beyond, there will be a small, resilient snippet of 2020 that future historians, scientists, or space aliens can unearth and wonder about. So we took a whack at distilling a year’s worth of science memories into a handful of digital files. It’s far from comprehensive, but it tells some intriguing stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0EIzRD"&gt;The first part of the project was compiling the time capsule assets themselves. We built a file browser &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21938039"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where you can click through the digital moments and ephemera we included and think about what our descendants might make of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="POD2k7"&gt;The second challenge was figuring out how to preserve the files themselves for hundreds or even thousands of years. Most modern storage media — like hard drives or flash memory — is built to be cheap, not durable. But there’s one up-and-coming storage medium that could keep our files safe for millennia: synthetic DNA. Over the past few weeks, we worked with a team of scientists and engineers to encode our digital mementos into custom strands of DNA. The result has to be seen to be believed... even if it’s technically too small to actually see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Epvdpx"&gt;Check out the video above for the whole story, and here’s to a brand-new 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Ts6XJB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Science on YouTube","description":"The home base for our explorations into the future of science.","label":"Subscribe!","url":"http://bit.ly/2FqJZMl"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="j1sdqb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/science/22188122/dna-data-storage-synthetic-time-capsule"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/science/22188122/dna-data-storage-synthetic-time-capsule</id>
    <author>
      <name>William Poor</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lupin III: The First is the perfect holiday adventure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W4nhEzoVVz3TFqeelwGae9DJtDA=/403x0:1518x743/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68560010/Lupin_Hat.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: GKIDS Films&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A6eIg8"&gt;It is shockingly hard to find a new movie that’s interested in an old-fashioned &lt;em&gt;adventure. &lt;/em&gt;You know what I mean: the globe-trotting &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; kind, with riddles to solve and death traps to avoid, featuring a hint of romance and a strange treasure at stake. Thankfully, &lt;em&gt;Lupin III&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;em&gt;The First&lt;/em&gt; is exactly that. Written and directed by Takashi Yamazaki and streaming on-demand, the film is a gorgeously animated romp around the world starring an iconic manga character. Also, some Nazis get their asses handed to them.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mslBFh"&gt;Depending on how familiar you are with the manga, &lt;em&gt;The First&lt;/em&gt; is either a triumphant return or modern introduction to Arsène Lupin III, one of manga and anime’s most storied characters. Created by artist and writer Monkey Punch in 1967, Lupin is a “gentleman thief” and a descendant of French novelist Maurice Leblanc’s famous Arsène Lupin character. The character has starred in many shows, movies, and manga since his debut; he’s James Bond with a wacky sense of humor and a looser moral code. (The older stories haven’t aged well.) Most people, however, will be familiar with Lupin as he appears in 1979’s &lt;em&gt;The Castle of Cagliostro&lt;/em&gt;, the first film directed by the legendary Hayao Miyazaki. Miyazaki’s film portrays Lupin in a more slapstick and ultimately gallant light than in some of the source material, and this is the version of Lupin that we meet in &lt;em&gt;The First&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ilgkB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The First &lt;/em&gt;begins in 1960s France as the celebrated thief announces his intent to steal a newly unearthed treasure: the Bresson Diary, a World War II-era journal with a terrible secret locked away in a puzzle box. This initial heist goes awry when Lupin learns there is someone else after the diary: Laetitia, a reluctant thief who, unbeknownst to her, is a descendant of the diary’s author. Together, the two embark on an adventure to solve the mystery hidden within the diary and stay one step ahead of a third interested party, the aforementioned Nazis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zBReHf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lupin III: The First&lt;/em&gt; puts its foot on the gas at minute one and never lets up. It’s like &lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt; by way of &lt;em&gt;Ocean’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Eleven&lt;/em&gt;. And unlike many recent attempts to update classic anime to CGI — like the strange and unpleasant &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell: SAC_2045&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Lupin III: The First &lt;/em&gt;makes the leap to computer animation with its sense of style and dynamism intact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMnZfU"&gt;While computer animation can’t impress the same way an intricate hand-drawn sequence can (like &lt;em&gt;The Castle of Cagliostro&lt;/em&gt;’s signature clocktower fight), &lt;em&gt;The First&lt;/em&gt; lovingly recreates the cartoon physical comedy and stylish pulp thrills of previous iterations. There are multiple scenes — like one where Lupin must navigate an elaborate death trap after only seeing it go off once — that will leave you grinning as Yuji Ohno’s score kicks into high gear and the balletic buffoonery begins. (At times, it recalls 2011’s dynamic &lt;em&gt;The Adventures of Tintin: The Secret of the Unicorn&lt;/em&gt;, a movie that, tragically, has not produced a sequel.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWIKpA"&gt;The film is so top-to-bottom &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; that it’s hard to fault it much, even when it takes some truly outrageous turns in its final act that may give you pause before you remember how much of a good time you’re having. Movies like &lt;em&gt;Lupin III: The First&lt;/em&gt; don’t come along very often. And when they do, it makes you wonder why it’s been so long since you’ve seen one. After all, who doesn’t like getting swept up in a grand adventure?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22189540/lupin-iii-the-first-review-miyazaki-animated-monkey-punch-gkids"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22189540/lupin-iii-the-first-review-miyazaki-animated-monkey-punch-gkids</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Rivera</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T09:50:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T09:50:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s DNA time capsule for 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dDhzcICMIdEC6gzrreGlr3h7pOE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68559973/VRG_4336_Lede.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IbAC1D"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;assembled a digital time capsule to immortalize 2020. The files were encoded into synthetic DNA to be preserved for thousands of years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KxdWJQ"&gt;The following files were selected by &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff in November 2020. The stories contained are by no means exhaustive; they are a few snapshots of life in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u5dyqn"&gt;Within this file folder are the original assets included in the time capsule, as well as a video exploring the capsule’s storage medium: synthetic DNA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9Vd07"&gt;View the files on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21938039#"&gt;TheVerge.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sClJar"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XmOT2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22173998/dna-time-capsule"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22173998/dna-time-capsule</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T09:44:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T09:44:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>US relief package provides $7 billion for broadband</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-WEATHER-STORM" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8FAepWSMtlAcOMSS0FBzmBoKQnY=/4x0:5536x3688/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68559942/1230159463.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Caballero / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dl45HT"&gt;After months of deliberation, congressional leaders reached a $900 billion coronavirus relief deal on Sunday, including billions in funding for broadband internet access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4LM7uE"&gt;Congress’ latest relief measure provides $7 billion in funding for broadband connectivity and infrastructure. That figure includes $3.2 billion for a $50-per-month emergency broadband benefit for people who are laid off or furloughed during the pandemic, according to a press release from Sen. Ron Wyden’s (D-OR) office on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbmmbc"&gt;“Broadband connections are essential for Americans seeking to get new jobs, and to access school, health care and other government services,” Wyden said in a statement Sunday night. “Ensuring working families can stay online will pay massive dividends for kids’ education, helping people find jobs and jump starting the economic recovery next year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gu5ZtI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Ensuring working families can stay online will pay massive dividends for kids’ education”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TpxJ31"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/broadband-access-covid-relief-bill-7-billion-5be48439-c1a4-4927-a0c4-515312a1d281.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Axios &lt;/em&gt;reported Sunday&lt;/a&gt; that the coronavirus relief bill also includes $1.9 billion to remove Huawei and ZTE equipment from US networks. In June, the Federal Communications Commission officially &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/usa-internet-congress/update-2-us-lawmakers-to-back-19-billion-to-replace-telecom-equipment-from-chinas-huawei-zte-source-idUSL1N2J00D3"&gt;designated Huawei and ZTE&lt;/a&gt; as national security threats. In doing so, the FCC banned US companies from purchasing the equipment with government money. Earlier this month, the agency moved to require US telecom companies to “rip and replace” any Huawei or ZTE equipment currently deployed in their networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0gW1DG"&gt;The deal also includes $1 billion in Tribal broadband grants, $250 million toward telehealth, and $65 million for broadband mapping improvements, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/broadband-access-covid-relief-bill-7-billion-5be48439-c1a4-4927-a0c4-515312a1d281.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The US’s broadband maps have been the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17882842/us-internet-broadband-map-isp-fcc-wireless-competition"&gt;target of criticism for years&lt;/a&gt;. The FCC’s current methodology declares an entire ZIP code as having broadband if just one home in that census block is served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hd3MO5"&gt;The $900 billion COVID relief bill includes a new round of direct payments, following the same requirements as the first round of stimulus checks earlier this year. This package provides stimulus checks of up to $600 per person for people earning up to $75,000 a year and another $600 for their children, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/20/us/politics/congress-stimulus-deal.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Both the House and Senate approved the measure Sunday night, and President Donald Trump signed it late Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unxl1J"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BuhTWA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193133/us-coronavirus-covid-relief-stimulus-package-broadband-huawei-zte"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193133/us-coronavirus-covid-relief-stimulus-package-broadband-huawei-zte</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The 10 best streaming shows on Netflix for 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wZXM7BT8OWUisxcSyyt9m4rZZ8Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68559713/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5TvUOM"&gt;The year 2020 likely kept many of us inside for most of it, and it looks like that situation may last at least into part of 2021. One of the few positives is that many great movies and TV shows were released on streaming services such as Netflix. The streaming service has made available a plethora of movies and TV shows, some original to Netflix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JGzxnt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com/"&gt;Netflix currently offers three plans&lt;/a&gt;: Basic ($8.99 / month) lets you watch content on one screen at a time; Standard ($13.99 / month) brings it up to two screens and adds HD content; and Premium ($17.99) offers a total of four screens and Ultra HD content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ULmq9Y"&gt;Whether you need a new show to binge-watch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174856/the-office-netflix-peacock-streaming"&gt;once &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt; leaves Netflix&lt;/a&gt; or something for a movie night with your loved ones, here’s a list of 10 movies and TV shows you should check out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gtJlxA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ve rounded up our favorite and most-used games, apps, and entertainment. Check out our app picks for iPhones, Android phones, PCs, and M1-equipped Macs; our favorite mobile games from Apple Arcade and Google Play Pass; and our top choices for gaming PCs, the PS5, Xbox One and Series X / S, Nintendo Switch, and VR. We’ve also listed our favorite streaming shows on Disney Plus, Hulu, ESPN, and Netflix; some great sci-fi books; and exciting new podcasts. (Note: pricing was accurate at the time of publishing but may change.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4duMyI"&gt;To the Lake&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="To the Lake " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4VdoOFssJkImc7fGPajofBN1jCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170545/5f908f3f85600a70515e646a.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the Lake &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ueAdMy"&gt;A 2019 Russian web TV series acquired by Netflix this year, &lt;em&gt;To the Lake,&lt;/em&gt; is based on the Russian novel &lt;em&gt;Vongozero&lt;/em&gt; by Yana Vagner and focuses on a group of survivors trying to evade a pandemic. The main character is Sergey, who is tasked with getting his family to a desert island in the middle of an area called Vongozero. Sergey is joined by his new girlfriend, her son, his father, his next-door neighbor’s family, his ex-wife, and his young son. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOfNyl"&gt;It’s quite unconventional compared to other shows in the apocalyptic zombie genre because it focuses more on its ensemble cast of diverse characters and adds a ton of tension, especially between Sergey’s new girlfriend and his ex-wife. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="25f4Gt"&gt;#Alive&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="#Alive " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WZQJjc0k1vll6vsCuY7v-rFpCzU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170567/AAAABZ0YASBbNXtrybLoLlCp4ktnzkk2DpGGInuM_7I21jdSkENpyTVuKC71CzV6AnSXB5kIc7Y4Tz4Rgl__dII9Q1NMyg4j.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;#Alive &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uI8X2c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;#Alive&lt;/em&gt; is a 2020 South Korean film that focuses on Joon-woo, a video game live-streamer, as he struggles to survive during — yes — a zombie apocalypse. For most of the movie, Joon-woo is barricaded in his parent’s apartment in Seoul. What makes this an intriguing watch is that it accurately depicts some of the same feelings many of us likely had due to the COVID-19 pandemic: fear, uncertainty, isolation, and loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zF4TE2"&gt;Tiger King&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tiger King" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7PpCo0jM-TctEUZ8dlx-uB_EwNY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170575/IMG_0085_2520JEPA_R.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RQvrtr"&gt;Internet memes aside, &lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt; is one of the more enjoyable Netflix shows to come out of 2020. It’s a documentary miniseries that spans seven episodes and focuses on Joe Exotic, a private zoo owner with over 200 big cats. The miniseries focuses on various points in his life, such as his unsuccessful runs for public office and his feud with big-cat rights activist Carole Baskin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gc2IFS"&gt;Love is Blind&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Love is Blind " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uhjS61TvJ2wkraWkLU--Pz9jg5o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170644/love_is_blind_reaction.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love is Blind &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="axP5D8"&gt;This year, Netflix had a ton of dating shows with wild concepts&lt;em&gt;. Love is Blind&lt;/em&gt; brings together 30 men and women looking for love. For 10 days, the men and women partake in a blind / speed dating format where they “date” each other while in different “pods.” After those 10 days of dating, the participants need to decide if they want to become engaged or go home single. All these reality TV shows are very much guilty pleasures — at first watch, I got some mad &lt;em&gt;Married at First Sight &lt;/em&gt;vibes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SCOLpS"&gt;Tuca &amp;amp; Bertie &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tuca &amp;amp;amp; Bertie" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x3sUzQIe37NaLCQ9aqKvWAKHCM4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16336445/Tuca___Bertie_S01E04_9m0s12962f.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tuca &amp;amp; Bertie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fBO7LZ"&gt;With &lt;em&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/em&gt; airing its final episodes in January, there’s a bit of a void for that type of animation. Last year, my best friend recommended that I watch &lt;em&gt;Tuca &amp;amp; Bertie&lt;/em&gt;, about two bird women in their 30s with a very Yin and Yang type friendship. I really enjoyed the amount of diversity in the cast and how the show starred two female protagonists, something I find to be a rarity in adult animation TV shows. And so I was really angry when I heard Netflix decided to cancel the series after one season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RXJ4LS"&gt;Thankfully, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21267667/tuca-and-bertie-season-two-adult-swim-netflix-renewed-saved-bojack-horseman-lisa-hanawalt"&gt;the show is getting a second season&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to Cartoon Network’s Adult Swim block, with new episodes slated to premiere next year. You can still watch the first season on Netflix, and if you enjoy shows like &lt;em&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/em&gt;, I strongly encourage you to go watch &lt;em&gt;Tuca &amp;amp; Bertie&lt;/em&gt; as soon as possible. Then ask yourself, “How could Netflix &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; renew this show?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JI6uH1"&gt;The Witcher&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Witcher" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IxKWILHaNtb0VWuTx8kJQnu8XbQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19536938/GRADED_Witcher_104_Unit_01815_RT.fk3wl2edf__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rCglcL"&gt;I got my first experience with &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; franchise after playing the game &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt. &lt;/em&gt;First, I&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;decided to go back and revisit the first two games in the trilogy. Then I decided to read the books to see what the games were based on. So when I heard that Netflix was going to make a TV show based on the novels, I was very interested — and the fact that Henry Cavill would play Geralt of Rivia put me totally on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p0FmPL"&gt;The first season aired roughly a year ago, and I really liked it. I am not going to claim the show is better than &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/em&gt;because that is an unfair comparison. And I will warn you that the first season warrants a second watch because the story, which shuffles timelines, can get a bit confusing. Nevertheless, if you love fantasy TV shows and liked &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; novels and / or the games, the TV show is worth a watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VmDG70"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"We built a 2020 time capsule out of synthetic DNA — here’s how","url":"https://www.theverge.com/science/22188122/dna-data-storage-synthetic-time-capsule"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="t8wyYL"&gt;The Prom&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Prom" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8qd0-vHtedRs3CAoCpH_84XbhGQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22175284/201211_the_prom_netflix_ew_305p_1b7b20b1bc6468f75bbba783f3514f59.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Prom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IFZ6Dn"&gt;A movie adaption based on the 2018 Broadway musical of the same name, &lt;em&gt;The Prom&lt;/em&gt; follows a group of Broadway actors who travel to a small Indiana town to aid a lesbian student who was banned from going to her high school prom with her girlfriend. The movie is extremely vibrant with a ton of bright colors and glitter and energetic songs. While the story itself seems a bit disjointed, the acting and songs kept me entertained throughout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GPvXqN"&gt;The Big Flower Fight&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Big Flower Fight" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G6ng0TEEYXLjZoIMfV1ALQGnZzA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170691/2667eccb11dbfdc6b381927704f6d56374_big_flower_fight_lede.2x.rsocial.w600.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Flower Fight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BFyFE4"&gt;What happens when you take &lt;em&gt;The Great British Bake Off&lt;/em&gt; and switch cooking with floral design? You get &lt;em&gt;The Big Flower Fight&lt;/em&gt;, of course. This oddly satisfying reality competition pits artists, florists, and landscapers against each other as they try to build giant sculptures out of plants. I like watching cooking competitions like &lt;em&gt;MasterChef, &lt;/em&gt;and I was won over by the idea of a competition to make beautiful sculptures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aLDU0C"&gt;The Crown&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Crown" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nNuSiPPV53RoyPgkq1e2w90mSLI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22175292/TheCrown_406_Unit_02045.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WWoCUH"&gt;As a history buff, I am overly critical whenever I watch movies or TV shows inspired by historical events. While &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt; takes a lot of liberties with what actually happened during Queen Elizabeth II’s reign, I can’t stop watching this show. To be honest, I am not following it because of its historical accuracy, but because of the incredible cinematography and superb acting from the cast members. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2XM94q"&gt;Unsolved Mysteries &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Unsolved Mysteries" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FhX5RHisJQihuorWJV3VzZ8GMZo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170702/netflix_unsolved_mysteries.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsolved Mysteries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zcjiJu"&gt;I grew up watching a bunch of crime-focused shows like &lt;em&gt;Snapped&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Unsolved Mysteries&lt;/em&gt;. They would keep me up all night while I played detective — and now, as an adult, I keep coming back to them. Originally a series released on NBC in the late 1980s, &lt;em&gt;Unsolved Mysteries&lt;/em&gt; has breathed new life to a well-loved trope on the streaming giant’s platform. The 2020 reboot spans six episodes, with each episode focusing on a different cold case. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22175140/best-netflix-shows-2020-streaming-recommendations-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22175140/best-netflix-shows-2020-streaming-recommendations-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T08:46:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T08:46:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Book of Boba Fett is another Mandalorian spinoff show, coming to Disney Plus in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IhT0jhcdDUAYgJuEre9NK635QmQ=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68547049/boba_fett.6.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8uu4li"&gt;After years of speculation about whether Boba Fett would get his own spinoff of some kind, &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s season 2 finale confirmed that a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21542557/the-mandalorian-season-2-premiere-review-disney-plus"&gt;Boba Fett series&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;The Book of Boba Fett&lt;/em&gt;, will hit Disney Plus in December 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hP6qXF"&gt;Executive producer Jon Favreau appeared on &lt;em&gt;Good Morning America &lt;/em&gt;on December 21st to confirm &lt;em&gt;The Book of Boba Fett &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/starwars/status/1341013938570371072"&gt;as a new series&lt;/a&gt; (following some speculation that &lt;em&gt;Book of Boba Fett &lt;/em&gt;was some sort of subtitle for&lt;em&gt; The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s third season.) The new show will be an original series set within the world of &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian, &lt;/em&gt;with Favreau, Dave Filoni, and Robert Rodriguez set to produce the series. Favreau and Filoni already produce &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;, while Rodriguez directed the Boba Fett-centric season two episode, “The Tragedy.” Production on &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s third season will take place right after &lt;em&gt;The Book of Boba Fett&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fRJiHm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StarWars?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#StarWars&lt;/a&gt; clarification: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheBookOfBobaFett?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TheBookOfBobaFett&lt;/a&gt; is coming next December. It will not run alongside season 3 of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheMandalorian?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TheMandalorian&lt;/a&gt;. As Favreau says here, Mando Season 3 will go start production after next year’s Boba Fett show. &lt;a href="https://t.co/8cKF15dw7g"&gt;pic.twitter.com/8cKF15dw7g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Erik Davis (@ErikDavis) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ErikDavis/status/1341016663685251079?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 21, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jZNuMg"&gt;The show was not included as an announcement during Disney’s big investor day last week. Several &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;other &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; projects&lt;/a&gt;, including two other &lt;em&gt;Mandalorian &lt;/em&gt;spinoffs — an Ahsoka Tano show and &lt;em&gt;Rangers of the New Republic &lt;/em&gt;—&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a Lando Calrissian show, and a &lt;em&gt;Star Wars &lt;/em&gt;anime series, were announced then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="joYKx4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning: The following contains light spoilers for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;’s second season finale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OhCn1x"&gt;The announcement comes during a post-credits scene (ah, yes, the post-credits scenes), which finds Boba Fett and Fennec Shand in Jabba the Hutt’s palace. Fans will recall this is where Boba Fett was thrown into the sarlacc pit a few years before. Now, Boba Fett is back — and after blasting away Bib Fortuna, the pasty-faced employee of Jabba the Hutt who gave me nightmares as a child — Boba Fett takes his place on Jabba’s throne. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wY900i"&gt;Wild! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yVD4mi"&gt;The scene announcing the spinoff series will come as a nice surprise for anyone who held out hope for a Boba Fett movie years ago when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/13/13926062/star-wars-rogue-one-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/15/17355964/solo-a-star-wars-story-review-ron-howard"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;were being released. Now, there’s a TV show instead. It’s a smart move for Disney and Lucasfilm. A series is less of a risk than a movie, and it helps keep customers subscribed to the platform. Plus, tying everything together is a pretty good way to get people to stay on Disney Plus to watch other shows when they’re done with the most recent &lt;em&gt;Mandalorian &lt;/em&gt;episode; it’s already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21761493/mandalorian-star-wars-clone-rebels-dave-filoni-ahsoka-tano-thrawn"&gt;happening with &lt;em&gt;Clone Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftZeup"&gt;While this season of &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian &lt;/em&gt;is over, it’s clear that fans have a ton of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; to look forward to in 2021. Can there be too much &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;? Former CEO Bob Iger certainly thought &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; fatigue &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2019/09/disney-ceo-bob-iger-star-wars-solo-flop-1202175861/"&gt;took over at the box office&lt;/a&gt;, but maybe Disney Plus is a different story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yb11rR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (December 21st, 8:40am ET): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The story has been updated to include new information about the series. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Lf2YvN"&gt;
&lt;aside id="jGdErq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188516/boba-fett-disney-plus-show-2021-release-date-mandalorian-finale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188516/boba-fett-disney-plus-show-2021-release-date-mandalorian-finale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus’ latest concept phone is a color-changing, motion-tracking 8T</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nz4-PTKNiDdlKz0wEBhTm8ajUE0=/0x0:1152x768/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68559400/8T_concept_KV_16_9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="64mOXd"&gt;OnePlus has a new concept phone to show off, which is its way of teasing tech that maybe, just maybe, might make it into one of the company’s future phones. The OnePlus 8T Concept is a similar phone to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514174/oneplus-8t-review"&gt;OnePlus 8T&lt;/a&gt; that was released a couple months ago, but it’s got a pretty unique rear design that changes color alongside a motion-tracking radar module. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eVK4kt"&gt;According to OnePlus, this color-changing effect is achieved with a film that contains metal oxide, which sits underneath the phone’s glass back and changes color as different voltages are applied to it. At its most basic, it could change color to show off the phone’s notifications, like an incoming phone call, much like the notification light that it has included on its phones in the past. But where things get really interesting is when it gets paired with the concept phone’s rear-mounted radar module. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TW8rbfniTUvqYO-DHpbh0XYNs7M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22182956/8T_Concept.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnePlus shows how the design on the rear of the phone can change color.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vryG0g"&gt;This module, which is built into the camera bump on the back of the phone, uses millimeter wave radar to bounce electromagnetic waves off its surroundings and lets the phone “perceive, image, locate, and track objects.” Although OnePlus says this mmWave technology is “borrowed from 5G,” it adds that the radar module is separate from any mmWave communication module in the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TW9zE4"&gt;Functionally, it sounds similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923660/google-pixel-4-xl-review-camera-radar-face-unlock-90hz-display-telephoto"&gt;Pixel 4&lt;/a&gt;’s radar-enabled Motion Sense technology, which let you swipe your hand above the phone to skip music tracks or silence alarms. It could also detect your presence to show you the time and any notifications. The functionality was interesting, but Google hasn’t included it in subsequent phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rud7Oh"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="ECMF Notifications|99927" data-volume-uuid="03ae584ba" data-volume-id="99927" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-101" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Qnez1"&gt;This concept phone can also use this motion tracker to do simple things like answering a phone call with a gesture, or offer more advanced functionality like sensing a user’s breathing. This can be combined with its color-changing back to offer some interesting use cases. For example, its back could change color to indicate an incoming call, and then you could accept or reject it with a gesture, without having to touch the phone itself. Or the radar could sense your breathing, and then change its back’s color in time with it, “effectively making the phone a biofeedback device,” OnePlus says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hj0KEa"&gt;It’s an ambitious collection of features, but there’s no guarantee we’ll ever see them come to a consumer device. After all, a little under a year ago OnePlus was showing off the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21054391/oneplus-concept-one-mclaren-disappearing-phone-camera-hands-on"&gt;OnePlus Concept One&lt;/a&gt;, an interesting device which used electrochromic glass to make its rear cameras disappear (and which also acted as a pretty neat little &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neutral-density_filter"&gt;ND filter&lt;/a&gt;). However, the technology is yet to make an appearance in any of the company’s flagship phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="87u3Dq"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="ECMF Breathing|99928" data-volume-uuid="261d90825" data-volume-id="99928" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-970" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mUixth"&gt;As with the Concept One before it, OnePlus says it has no plans to commercially sell the OnePlus 8T Concept, so it’s best thought of as a small showcase of what the company is working on. But with any luck, the technology could yet come to one of its real smartphones one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lBTYhj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22189219/oneplus-8t-concept-color-changing-back-motion-sensing-radar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22189219/oneplus-8t-concept-color-changing-back-motion-sensing-radar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-21T07:47:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T07:47:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Adobe releases Apple Silicon version of Premiere Pro in beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l1pSOOnlCu8CTFOf7nfR1F0j2pY=/0x0:749x499/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68559369/PPro.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Adobe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r6qYc8"&gt;Adobe has released an Arm version of Premiere Pro for macOS, allowing owners of new Apple Silicon M1 Macs to run the video editing software natively. The program is still very much in beta for now, however, and the &lt;a href="https://community.adobe.com/t5/premiere-pro-beta/discuss-premiere-pro-on-apple-silicon-m1/td-p/11691346?page=1"&gt;Adobe post announcing its availability&lt;/a&gt; lists a host of known bugs and missing features. News of its release was &lt;a href="https://the8-bit.com/adobe-premiere-pro-for-m1-macs-now-available-to-public-beta-testers/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;The 8-Bit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/12/21/premiere-pro-premiere-rush-audition-for-m1-beta/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=webfeeds"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; adds&lt;/a&gt; that Adobe’s Premiere Rush and Audition have also been updated to run on the new machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rkSxYy"&gt;Adobe says it’s porting Premiere Pro’s features over in phases, starting with its core editing functions and workflows, as well as popular codecs like H.264, HEVC, and ProRes. Third-party integrations will need to be updated by their respective developers to work on Apple Silicon. Adobe advises that users can run the current release version of Premiere Pro on M1 Macs using Rosetta 2 emulation while the Arm version is still in development, though some third-party integrations may not work in this mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RaQRE2"&gt;Premiere Pro joins other Adobe apps including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571070/adobe-photoshop-arm64-beta-windows-macos-m1"&gt;Photoshop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22162930/adobe-lightroom-arm64-windows-macos-m1"&gt;Lightroom&lt;/a&gt; that have seen releases for Apple’s new Arm-based Macs. It’s a relatively quick turnaround for Adobe considering the new MacBook Air, MacBook Pro, and Mac mini were only released just over a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22192979/adobe-arm-m1-mac-apple-silicon-premiere-pro-beta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22192979/adobe-arm-m1-mac-apple-silicon-premiere-pro-beta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
