<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-27T17:26:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T17:26:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T17:26:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fitbit’s newest fitness tracker, the Charge 5, is now available</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7oTw3UgNWOkFUmZpIKKB-E0diDg=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69917127/jpeters_210914_4757_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fitbit Charge 5.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Jay Peters / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EkjLeB"&gt;Fitbit’s newest fitness tracker, the Fitbit Charge 5, is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fitbit.com%2Fglobal%2Fus%2Fproducts%2Ftrackers%2Fcharge5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22697200%2Ffitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;now available for purchase&lt;/a&gt;. The $179.95 tracker offers a number of improvements over the Charge 4, including a slimmer design and a bright color screen. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22680300/fitbit-charge-5-review-fitness-tracker"&gt;in my review&lt;/a&gt;, I had some frustrations with the software and the lack of any sort of physical button. And you should know that two of the new tracker’s headline features, an ECG app and the ability to give a new Daily Readiness Score, aren’t available just yet. Those are arriving in the coming months, Fitbit says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e68Lfb"&gt;Fitbit is also announcing new features coming to some of its devices for people who subscribe to its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fitbit.com%2Fglobal%2Fus%2Fproducts%2Fservices%2Fpremium&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22697200%2Ffitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fitbit Premium service&lt;/a&gt;, which costs $9.99 per month. Snore and noise detection is now available for all &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21450123/fitbit-sense-review"&gt;Fitbit Sense&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fitbit.com%2Fglobal%2Fus%2Fproducts%2Fsmartwatches%2Fversa3&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22697200%2Ffitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Versa 3&lt;/a&gt; users who are Fitbit Premium subscribers, and content from the meditation app Calm is now available in the Fitbit app, also for Premium subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jImcFk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fitbit Charge 5 review: touchscreen fatigue","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22680300/fitbit-charge-5-review-fitness-tracker"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697200/fitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697200/fitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T16:54:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T16:54:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>RIP Android TV remote app, hello Google TV remote app </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fqSqbj8dB_LJU5bwMHshBHc7RP0=/0x180:1080x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916955/AFS_01A_VirtualRemote_IJ_Realistic_1x1_Frame_11.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qm4bhr"&gt;Google is killing its older Android TV remote. The move follows the company’s launch of its long-awaited Google TV remote app last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNnlgL"&gt;The company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the Android TV remote app will take a bow after the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android"&gt;Google TV remote app&lt;/a&gt; — which can be used for other Android TV OS devices as well — is widely available. &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/09/27/looks-like-google-has-put-the-old-android-tv-remote-control-app-out-of-its-misery/"&gt;earlier reported&lt;/a&gt; the remote news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u8XPRg"&gt;“We’re making the experience of using your phone as a virtual remote control faster to access and easier to use by upgrading the UI and integrating the feature directly into the Android mobile OS as well as the Google TV app,” a spokesperson said. “After the new remote feature is widely available, the Android TV remote app will no longer be supported and available for use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePF7tj"&gt;To use the remote, the Android TV OS television or device will need Android TV Remote Service 5.0, which has already started rolling out. Users will not need to manually update their devices to get it. A spokesperson said that the rollout will continue through this week and will update automatically through the Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="caV3x9"&gt;The new remote is available to Android users from Quick Settings or through the Google TV app. A spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last week that the new remote app will be available only to Android users at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697167/android-tv-remote-google-tv-remote-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697167/android-tv-remote-google-tv-remote-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T16:30:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T16:30:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s gamer-friendly C1 OLED is down to its best price to date</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zWumHjIbdaBffC0XrXG08s6RsW0=/212x0:2497x1523/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916840/LG_C1_Lifestyle_Photo.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LG C1 OLED TV supports HDMI 2.1 and 120Hz Variable Refresh Rate for use with modern consoles.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2Pz0Nj"&gt;LG’s various OLED offerings include some of the most well-received models across the industry. The C1 OLED is one of these universally praised panels, and it comes in a variety of sizes to fit people’s preferences and home theater setups. Now, some C1 models have received their biggest discounts yet, which may please those with a penchant for large TVs. Amazon, for instance, currently has the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WG4HKKY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch C1 for $1,797&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WGFKSMW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;77-inch model for $2,997&lt;/a&gt;, which factor out to be $703 and $500 off, respectively. For roughly the same price, you can also get either TV with a $100 streaming credit at &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/lg-65-class-c1-series-4k-uhd-oled-tv-allstate-protection-plan-bundle-included.product.100761679.html"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; or a $50 Visa gift card at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FLGOLED65C1PUB%2FLG-OLED65C1PUB-65-Inch-4K-Smart-OLED-TV-with-AI-ThinQ-2021-Model&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22696856%2Flg-c1-4k-oled-tv-ps5-xbox-series-x-amazon-buydig-costco-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BuyDig&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BhRll2"&gt;These are the lowest prices to date on each of these large displays, both of which feature 120Hz refresh rates and Dolby Vision HDR compatibility, as well as support for VRR (variable refresh rate) and FreeSync and G-Sync technologies, thus ensuring high frame rates without screen tearing. Both configurations of the 4K OLED also support HDMI 2.1 to ensure all these gaming-focused specs work seamlessly with Xbox Series X / S and PlayStation 5. Another gamer-friendly feature, Game Optimizer, allows you to dial in the ideal settings for specific genres, such as fast-action first-person shooters or densely detailed real-time strategy titles. These features alone make the C1 one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"&gt;best TVs for gaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="BnbCpR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"LG’s C1 and G1 OLEDs get even better at gaming with 120Hz Dolby Vision","url":"https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/6/28/22554939/lg-dolby-vision-hdr-xbox-c1-g1-4k"},{"title":"The best delas on 4k TVs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="vnZmIS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10596469"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U5ucxv"&gt;The C1 model, like many OLED TVs, is known for its richer contrast and deep, ink-like blacks, which bring out more detail in the shadows. Dolby Vision HDR also ensures vibrancy and accuracy in the colors, and on the smart side of things, the C1 supports both Google Assistant and Amazon Alexa voice assistants. It also comes with LG’s speedy, fourth-gen Alpha9 processor and support for LG’s webOS platform. That last one might not earn everyone’s love, but it’s got built-in support for most of the popular streaming apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="pTm1YV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/27/22696856/lg-c1-4k-oled-tv-ps5-xbox-series-x-amazon-buydig-costco-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/27/22696856/lg-c1-4k-oled-tv-ps5-xbox-series-x-amazon-buydig-costco-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T16:03:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T16:03:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>The beloved Babylon 5 is getting rebooted, and series creator JMS is running the show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rxsFJFVFXYtbLVENsMVLnh6LKnk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916698/babylon_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t7sQ06"&gt;In 1994, J. Michael Straczynski (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/28/8673391/sense8-review-matrix-wachowskis-netflix"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sense8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Changeling_(film)"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Changeling&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;) &lt;/em&gt;brought the world a science fiction show like nothing we’d ever seen. &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5 &lt;/em&gt;told a single five-year story, filled with foreshadowing, deep political intrigue, and characters who grew and evolved, at a time when most TV shows still reset the agenda after every single episode. He wrote the vast majority of the award-winning show himself, and it appears he may be about to do it again — Warner Bros. Television is now in development on a “ground-up reboot” of &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5&lt;/em&gt; with Straczynski as writer and showrunner, designed to air on the CW. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iCPYWw"&gt;Here’s the full description &lt;em&gt;Warner Bros&lt;/em&gt;. provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="6RJdlV"&gt;In a from-the-ground-up reboot of the original series, John Sheridan, an Earthforce officer with a mysterious background, is assigned to Babylon 5, a five-mile-long space station in neutral space, a port of call for travelers, smugglers, corporate explorers and alien diplomats at a time of uneasy peace and the constant threat of war. His arrival triggers a destiny beyond anything he could have imagined, as an exploratory Earth company accidentally triggers a conflict with a civilization a million years ahead of us, putting Sheridan and the rest of the B5 crew in the line of fire as the last, best hope for the survival of the human race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="G5uUiq"&gt;That’s pretty much a dead-on description of the original show, minus some big surprises. So as a long-time fan myself, I have extremely mixed feelings! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="REM7L5"&gt;In one sense, it’s pretty exciting because Straczynski told fans&lt;em&gt; for years&lt;/em&gt; that Warner Bros. wanted nothing to do with the show ever again. “They literally told my agent ‘We have no plans, and no intentions, of letting anything else be done in terms of television with Babylon 5,’” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/straczynski/status/987208419558834176"&gt;he tweeted in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, and that seemed to be that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZvWHPJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Won't work.  They literally told my agent "We have no plans, and no intentions, of letting anything else be done in terms of television with Babylon 5."  And a kickstarter wouldn't pay for even a fraction of a season.  That won't change for years, when those execs are dead/gone. &lt;a href="https://t.co/NZ80WiIIcR"&gt;https://t.co/NZ80WiIIcR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— J. Michael Straczynski (@straczynski) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/straczynski/status/987208419558834176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zt4Kzs"&gt;So if Warner Bros. and Straczynski have now abandoned their feud and might expand on the intriguing universe JMS built nearly three decades ago, that’s pretty exciting. But if it’s just a straight reboot rather than a sequel or spin-off, one aimed at the CW at that, it makes me wonder why bother — particularly when the excellent original series has a newly remastered version you can stream on HBO Max and purchase &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000I5SYHS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;via Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Ftv-season%2Fbabylon-5-the-complete-series%2Fid1149081337%3Fmt%3D8&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22696836%2Fbabylon-5-reboot-j-michael-straczynski-warner-bros-the-cw" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; since January of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Eb0678"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10776756"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yrcBFR"&gt;Sure, the remastered version still has its issues. &lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt; has a great story about &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-06-22-babylon-5-digital-video-quality.html"&gt;why the original &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5&lt;/em&gt; will never look its best&lt;/a&gt;, partly due to aging CGI that might have looked groundbreaking at the time. Some of the early episodes feature hamfisted plots, scenery-chewing actors and a general lack of subtlety, and I can see how they might turn off a modern audience used to shows like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/1/14429646/expanse-season-2-syfy-relevant-science-fiction-show-television"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Expanse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. (&lt;/em&gt;Straczynski &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/straczynski/status/1441658114973974531"&gt;certainly still seems to feel&lt;/a&gt; the first season is worth it, and I think you’d lose a lot by skipping it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zJtQXG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10776767"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oEDk3i"&gt;And while the remaster’s 4:3 transfer does an excellent job of cleaning up old artifacts and counteracting the bonkers decision to &lt;em&gt;zoom in&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the low-quality CG (see examples above and below), the noisy footage still doesn’t necessarily look great on a 4K TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nLx4hd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10776769"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aBl072"&gt;Still, it’s there’s never been a better time to watch &lt;em&gt;Babylon 5 &lt;/em&gt;in the modern era than this remaster, which is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much better than the DVDs. You just might want &lt;a href="https://babylon5.fandom.com/wiki/Viewing_Order"&gt;this guide to the agreed-upon proper viewing orders&lt;/a&gt; since HBO Max and co. seem to have ordered the episodes in a new way entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="f2BFXK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10776771"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696836/babylon-5-reboot-j-michael-straczynski-warner-bros-the-cw"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696836/babylon-5-reboot-j-michael-straczynski-warner-bros-the-cw</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T15:56:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T15:56:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Overwatch League grand finals were a storybook sendoff ahead of Overwatch 2</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Erc8OrOnP_XhRlLIhWSa41bZ4X4=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916614/MY_DRAGONS.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QlZTaC"&gt;The Shanghai Dragons’ very first &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; match was an 0-4 shellacking delivered by the Los Angeles Gladiators in 2018. The team would go on to lose the next 41 straight games — encompassing the entire first season of the league and the first two games of the second season — earning them the dubious honor of having the longest losing streak in esports history. The Shanghai Dragons’ very last &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; match of 2021 — and the last professional Overwatch match ahead of the sequel’s launch next year — was a 4-0 beatdown they themselves visited upon the Atlanta Reign to win the 2021 Grand Finals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2rDEw"&gt;It is a long-time fan in-joke to call the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League “scripted.” Like a TV show, teams are given story arcs, villains and heroes are cast, and any match that ended &lt;em&gt;just so&lt;/em&gt; was pre-determined by a writer’s room. That the Shanghai Dragons are the team that closes the chapter on professional &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; as we know it is proof positive that some kind of cosmic force is at play. Stories that good just don’t happen by chance, and yet, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UauZKU"&gt;The Dragons’ grand finals run started off inauspiciously. In the first round, higher-seeded teams were given the opportunity to choose their opponents. Shanghai, as the highest seed, got first pick and decided to choose the San Francisco Shock as their opponents. Oh no.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q_8K3EA_J-1iMB5qMPRY8bqLphQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882673/OWL_Press_Asset_BZ655Q.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The San Francisco Shock after winning the 2020 Overwatch League Grand Finals over the Seoul Dynasty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tagXKz"&gt;The Shock are the winningest team in the league, period. They are the only team to have completed a “golden stage,” meaning they won all seven games in a stage without losing a single map — just straight 4-0s across the board. They are &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; the only team that’s won back-to-back championships. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; they are the team that sent Shanghai into the loser’s bracket during the 2020 playoffs. In the previous nine matches between these two teams, Shanghai has &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/7/19/20699180/shanghai-dragons-overwatch-league-stage-3-champions-explainer"&gt;only won one of them&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s easy to see why I thought this was a terrible pick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Pv5si"&gt;My concerns were unfounded as Shanghai made quick work of San Francisco, bouncing them to the lower bracket with a 3-0 embarrassment. But my relief didn’t last. The Dallas Fuel was their next big challenge after having lost to them in the May Melee earlier in the season. When the playoffs began, I said that the finals &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League 2021 deserved was Dallas vs. Shanghai. The only other team even close to Shanghai in performance has been Dallas. Fuel vs. Dragons was the rivalry the league’s writers demanded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WkLRly"&gt;And, by the grace of Goddess Victory, Shanghai came out on top again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KElUJ8"&gt;By this point, I’m sweating. Yes, my Dragons are in the grand finals, but the Shock are destroying the loser’s bracket, sending Philadelphia and Chengdu home — two teams stuffed with big Dark Horse Bracket Busting energy. More than anything, I do not want a 3-peat. I have no personal animosity toward the Shock, I simply find dynasties boring, and for a moment, it looked like the Shock of old were back, ready to reclaim their crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eIJ7TF"&gt;But then I was granted a boon from an unlikely source: the Atlanta Reign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lZG74AQ4F13LNMvPxsW6guUQ6fo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882679/OWL_Press_Asset_BZ61AX.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Atlanta Reign&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="y7sN0S"&gt;I’ve always enjoyed Atlanta. They’re a neat team with an incredible tank line and excellent proof that you don’t need a mono-culture team to have success. Atlanta’s always been the gatekeepers of the upper rankings — good enough to keep everyone else out but never good enough to break through themselves. So imagine my shock (heh) when they’re the ones to grant me my wish of eliminating San Francisco. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V5h6Cm"&gt;Then they beat Dallas, and then I got scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OGCICn"&gt;As I said, the playoffs are built differently. Good teams fall fast, and mediocre teams suddenly rise from nowhere. Dallas was a devil Shanghai knew. Atlanta wasn’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CWMSVD"&gt;No grand finals match has been terribly competitive. The Philadelphia Fusion won only a single map of the eight played against London for the inaugural championship. After being tied in their head-to-head records and tying in stage playoff wins, San Francisco sent Vancouver home in 2019 four to nothing. Only Seoul has made a grand finals match interesting, and even then, they lost to the Shock 4-2. I hate when games are blowouts, especially finals. But for this final between Atlanta and Shanghai, I wanted total domination. My heart did not have the strength to endure a close match. And, in keeping with the tradition of one-sided grand finals, Shanghai granted my wish. There was no magical moment like there was when the Dragons &lt;a href="https://www.heroesneverdie.com/2019/2/28/18243584/shanghai-dragons-win-first-game-boston-uprising"&gt;finally won their first match&lt;/a&gt; ever against Boston in 2019. No screaming or crying — just me observing Shanghai wipe out Atlanta in overtime and going, “that’s it, that’s the game.” After four years, the Shanghai Dragons’ redemption arc is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iwsS1Y1G-Er62t24GoQCGkaaTdo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882683/OWL_Press_Asset_BZ61AZ.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Shanghai Dragons&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9eFlfT"&gt;The Dragons are a lot of firsts and a lot of lasts. They’re the first team to lose every game in a season. They’re the first (and only) team &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/2/14/17012010/overwatch-league-first-female-player-geguri-shanghai-dragons"&gt;to field a female player&lt;/a&gt;. They were the last team to win a stage championship before the league changed its format, and now, they are the last team to win a championship in &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 1&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NL9VDO"&gt;Jon Spector — &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League commissioner — &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Spex_J/status/1433889109349650435?s=20"&gt;confirmed that the next season will be played on &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The switch in game brings with it a host of other changes. The starting lineups for teams will reduce in size from six players to five, and the much-maligned assault map type will be replaced with push — a map type in which teams fight to control a robot that pushes a payload. We even got a glimpse at what competitive play will look like in 2022 with an exhibition game of league pros demoing &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; during halftime. The changes are interesting, and while I’m eager to see how &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; will transform the league, that excitement is tempered by the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;abuse, harassment, and discrimination allegations&lt;/a&gt; levied at its developer, Blizzard Entertainment, and the news that Chacko Sonny, Overwatch 2’s executive producer, &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22686563/overwatch-2-boss-quit-activision-blizzard"&gt;has left the company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DE1Jck"&gt;As I celebrate my Dragons, mourn the end of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; prime, and continue to watch Blizzard implode in slow motion, I am reminded of the reason I came to this game in the first place: its community. Some of my best friends and colleagues have come from my time as a fan and a reporter, and my favorite memories come from matches I saw live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mJUx12"&gt;I’ve never truly participated in a sports fandom before, and yet, I latched onto this esport and the Shanghai Dragons with it, &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/why-im-a-fan-of-owls-shanghai-dragons-even-after-they-went-0-40/"&gt;with such fanatical devotion&lt;/a&gt; that a tattoo of their logo is now a foregone conclusion and a promise fulfilled. I know that the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League was never scripted, but I’m glad the league’s story ended like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DxeYft"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="epm3eK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696933/the-shanghai-dragons-2021-overwatch-league-grand-finals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696933/the-shanghai-dragons-2021-overwatch-league-grand-finals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T15:54:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T15:54:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ex-Apple designer Jony Ive is now designing expensive things for Ferrari, too</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook Delivers Keynote At Annual Worldwide Developers Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/unbyAtUbdpgDErIUr2vAsZrqs1c=/0x0:4692x3128/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916598/1153510444.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2e3eIe"&gt;LoveFrom, the design firm headed by Jony Ive and Marc Newson, &lt;a href="https://www.exor.com/press-releases/2021-09-27/exor-ferrari-and-lovefrom-announce-creative-partnership"&gt;has entered into a creative partnership&lt;/a&gt; with Ferrari and Ferrari’s holding company Exor to design presumably automotive-related projects and explore “the business of luxury” (&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-27/ferrari-exor-partner-with-ex-apple-design-chief-jony-ive-s-firm?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). LoveFrom’s output has remained somewhat unknown &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/27/18761736/jony-ive-apple-leave-iphone-chief-design-officer-lovefrom-company-quit"&gt;since Ive left Apple to start the design firm in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and Ferrari marks just the second high-profile partnership for the company following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527824/apple-designer-jony-ive-airbnb-hired-lovefrom"&gt;a separate deal with Airbnb last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJuxlb"&gt;Details on what LoveFrom is actually doing for the luxury carmaker or Exor are slim. “The first expression of this new partnership will bring together Ferrari’s legendary performance and excellence with LoveFrom’s unrivalled experience and creativity that has defined extraordinary world changing products,” Exor writes, without explaining what the companies will do together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yDUwvO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Whatever LoveFrom works on, it’ll probably be expensive&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S7eVHC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c2436fb5-d857-4aff-b81e-30141879711c"&gt;The&lt;em&gt; Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that partnership includes contributions to Ferrari’s first electric car, which the company &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/ferrari-ev-bumped-to-2025/"&gt;plans to introduce in 2025&lt;/a&gt;. Ferrari also has a connection to a current Apple executive in Eddy Cue; Apple’s senior vice president of services &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/ferrari-ev-bumped-to-2025/"&gt;sits on Ferrari’s board of directors&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKCyBv"&gt;Both Jony Ive and Marc Newson have well-documented opinions about modern cars — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/transportation/2015/2/16/8045625/jony-ive-apple-modern-car-design-is-shocking"&gt;they’re “insipid”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/14/9154871/apple-marc-newson-hates-modern-car-design"&gt;“at the bottom of a trough”&lt;/a&gt; — so it would be fascinating to see what they would do with an electric Prancing Horse. But it seems just as possible LoveFrom creates a &lt;a href="https://www.vogue.com/fashion-shows/spring-2022-ready-to-wear/ferrari"&gt;five-figure jacket or handbag instead&lt;/a&gt;. Like with Airbnb, the one thing that can be guaranteed is an exchange of clout. Ferrari and Exor are, at least in part, paying to attach their brands to the good design taste for which Ive and Newson are known. Maybe that’s worth more than connecting them to any one specific project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7xY21"&gt;What’s more certain is that it helps raise the profile of the duo’s design firm which, until now, remained even more ethereal than Ive’s hardware designs for Apple. The company and its work are so hard to grasp that the first result in a Google search of “LoveFrom” &lt;a href="https://lovefrom.style/"&gt;is a fan site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4pzRn1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696485/jonny-ive-ferrari-lovefrom-marc-newson-luxury"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696485/jonny-ive-ferrari-lovefrom-marc-newson-luxury</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T15:45:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T15:45:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is brightening up your Gmail avatar with new illustrations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qOK5nFKr0Pd6vqxj4Q2lN2-jb3Q=/190x0:811x414/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916548/Collage_cover_1_YAP7dMt.max_1000.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Some of Google’s new illustrations | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1MV3zC"&gt;Google has created new images designed to be used for your Google profile picture, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/gmail/get-creative-google-illustrations/"&gt;the company announced Monday&lt;/a&gt;. The new images, called Google Illustrations, look quite nice, and they could also be useful for people who want to associate an image with their account but don’t want to use a photo of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rFlr6l"&gt;Google looks to have a wide variety of options, some of which you can see in the image at the top of this post. And you can see more in the below GIF, which shows different categories of images such as animals, technology, and space.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HJNZgx2OFmw6aqJUxwkvRIyaSVw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882554/Selection_variety.mp4_1.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pwVDj1"&gt;The new library of illustrations indicates that Google is taking a different approach from avatars like Snap’s Bitmoji or Microsoft’s Xbox avatars, which can let you make stylized representations of what you look like. Google’s new illustrations instead give you a wide variety of generic things and places to use for your avatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1rY3A"&gt;Right now, however, the illustrations are only available to Android users, according to Google. If you’re on Android, you can set one as your profile pic in Google Workspace and Contacts on Android — follow the steps in this GIF from Google if you want to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3yoD8fKN-kuBGgBcqcZk4MuQx-I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882532/Entry_point_3.mp4_1.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aQcW48"&gt;Google says it’s “working on” bringing the new illustrations to iOS and web and to more products. The company says it’s also going to expand the collection of illustrations available, so if you don’t see one you like now, check back when Google has added more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696925/google-illustrations-gmail-avatar-workspace-contacts-android-profile-pic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696925/google-illustrations-gmail-avatar-workspace-contacts-android-profile-pic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T15:42:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T15:42:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hospitals say cyberattacks increase death rates and delay patient care</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hospital bed" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/suSKjbrHHtOGo-ZzANeOrwP5l1s=/0x0:1000x667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916522/hospital-bed-1.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YIVMzQ"&gt;Almost a quarter of healthcare organizations that were hit with a ransomware attack in the last two years said they had increases in patient death rates in the aftermath, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.censinet.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ponemon-Research-Report-The-Impact-of-Ransomware-on-Healthcare-During-COVID-19-and-Beyond.pdf"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by cybersecurity company Censinet. The finding adds to a growing pile of&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;data showing that cyberattacks aren’t just causing financial or logistical problems — they could be major health risks, as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0nfjwt"&gt;“There’s enough impact from ransomware on patient care that it’s undeniable” says Ed Gaudet, CEO and founder at Censinet. “We should not be afraid to look at this data, and to keep pushing on this question.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fTKS8m"&gt;The analysis, conducted by a research institute called the Ponemon Institute, collected survey responses from nearly 600 healthcare organizations across the United States&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;ranging from regional health systems to medical device manufacturers. Just over 40 percent said that they had a ransomware attack in the last two years — cyberattacks that freeze up computer systems and demand payment to unlock them. Those attacks disrupted the facilities’ ability to care for patients. Around 70 percent of the groups facing ransomware attacks said that those disruptions&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;led to longer hospital stays for patients and delayed tests or procedures. In addition, 36 percent said that they saw more complications from medical procedures, and 22 percent said they had increased death rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="liVRL4"&gt;Those numbers come with some big caveats: they’re from a relatively small subset of healthcare organizations, and there’s no double-check on what the organizations reported.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The survey didn’t ask organizations why or how they came to those conclusions — they didn’t say how they measured changes in death rates, for example. Without more details about those methods, it’s important to interpret the findings cautiously, Gaudet says. It’s probably too soon to say confidently that ransomware directly caused bad outcomes at those frequencies. “We have to be careful as an industry not to overreact,” he says. But it’s still something the industry should pay attention to and care about. “Even if it’s just one percent or half a percent, we should care about this data.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kIhQCX"&gt;Overall, over half of the healthcare groups responding to the survey said that they weren’t confident their organizations could handle the risks of ransomware attacks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebsNm0"&gt;People working in healthcare have historically been reluctant to say ransomware harms patients. There have been very few efforts to quantify the relationship between cyberattacks and patient health, and hospitals tend to be reluctant to share much information about their experiences because of potential impacts on the hospital’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;reputation&lt;/a&gt;. “I think as an industry, this is a question we almost don’t want to know the answer to,” Gaudet says. “Because if it’s true, then man, we really have our work cut out for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVcSRY"&gt;Cyberattacks on healthcare facilities have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21551050/cyberattacks-hospitals-coronavirus-deadly-tactics"&gt;increased&lt;/a&gt; over the past year, which brings new urgency to the question. And there have been recent pushes to take closer looks at the issue: one &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;new analysis&lt;/a&gt; by the United States’ Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), for example, showed hospitals in Vermont affected by ransomware attacks during the COVID-19 pandemic started to have excess deaths more quickly than hospitals not dealing with cyberattacks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WzUXwv"&gt;“I think this is reaching a level of criticality that is getting the attention of CEOs and board rooms,” Gaudet says. “Data like this is going to start factoring into how people think about areas of focus and investment. If ransomware is truly becoming a patient safety issue, they’re going to have to address it.”  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:58:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>CIA developed plans to kidnap Julian Assange, per report</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian embassy" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C9if5Lop4zeAhfhGYWLErloRdNI=/0x0:2560x1707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916211/assange_cc.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/dgcomsoc/14933990406/" target="_blank"&gt;Cancillería del Ecuador / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IgpqE5"&gt;The Trump administration’s CIA actively developed plans to kidnap or assassinate Wikileaks founder Julian Assange during his seclusion in London’s Ecuadorian embassy, according to &lt;a href="https://news.yahoo.com/kidnapping-assassination-and-a-london-shoot-out-inside-the-ci-as-secret-war-plans-against-wiki-leaks-090057786.html"&gt;a detailed new report from Yahoo News&lt;/a&gt;. Scenarios included abducting Assange from the embassy, intercepting a Russian effort to extract him, or an outright assassination attempt. While none of the operations were ever approved, they paint an alarming portrait of intelligence agencies’ ongoing obsession with Wikileaks and its controversial founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMXX1j"&gt;As sources, Yahoo cites conversations with more than 30 former US officials. Among those, eight provided details on plans to kidnap Assange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2pTOU"&gt;The report mostly details operations developed during the Trump administration, which placed fewer restraints on the CIA and was less troubled by the implications of launching direct operations against a figure many saw as a journalist. The issue became particularly heated in March of 2017, when Wikileaks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/23/15035988/wikileaks-cia-hacking-macbook-iphone-vault-7"&gt;published a catalog of hacking tools&lt;/a&gt; developed by the CIA. After that, “WikiLeaks was a complete obsession of Pompeo’s,” a source told Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYjgPw"&gt;“There was a fundamental change” when Trump took office, Yahoo quotes a former senior counterintelligence official as saying. “Nobody in that crew was going to be too broken up about the First Amendment issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3fyJa"&gt;The report confirms long-held suspicions about surveillance of Wikileaks activists, as well as espionage activists around Assange’s stay at the embassy. “It got to the point where every human being in a three-block radius [of the embassy] was working for one of the intelligence services,” one official told Yahoo, “whether they were street sweepers or police officers or security guards.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WsBblG"&gt;The plans were mostly blocked by lawyers associated with the White House or the Justice Department, who saw any abduction as straightforwardly illegal. The idea of an assassination was shut down even earlier, with one official describing it as “just spitballing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f1AAGd"&gt;Still, the reporting cuts a stark contrast with President Trump’s &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-wikileaks-campaign-speeches-julian-assange-2017-11"&gt;statements on the campaign trail&lt;/a&gt;, where he often praised Assange and Wikileaks for their role in publishing hacked information from the Clinton campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696436/cia-kidnap-julian-assange-assassination-pompeo-trump"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696436/cia-kidnap-julian-assange-assassination-pompeo-trump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Welcome to Hot Pod from The Verge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hot Pod logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xQA2CtNQ-hHdLgTdMq1Nnmrlcyw=/0x0:1600x1067/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916111/3426Sg8A.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8XLUMy"&gt;The podcast world is changing. Welcome to your front-row seat on the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b5UkiT"&gt;In case you haven’t heard, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660584/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-ashley-carman"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;acquired &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; this month&lt;/a&gt;, and former writer and editor Nicholas Quah joined &lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt;, our sister publication at Vox Media, as a full-time podcast critic. He’s still publishing over there — you can subscribe to his criticism newsletter &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/promo/sign-up-for-15-speed-podcast-newsletter.html"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt; — but I’ll be writing &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; from here on out. I’m excited, and although I know Nick’s legacy and insight are unparalleled, I hope to do it justice. I appreciate you sticking with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="araHi2"&gt;I’ve been at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for nearly six years and covering podcasting and audio for the past three. In that time, podcasting has gone from something that existed on the fringe to a full-blown cultural and business force. I started at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; as a cybersecurity reporter, then became a full-time gadget blogger, and eventually landed in the broad world of “creators.” My natural interest in podcasting (I co-hosted a show here called &lt;em&gt;Why’d You Push That Button?&lt;/em&gt;) and radio (I was a college radio kid and also still stan WXRT in Chicago) landed me in audio reporting. I’ve linked a few of my past podcasting stories at the end here to give you a better idea of what I’m into and what you can expect to read in future issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SU8uJA"&gt;Here’s the main thing: as it has gotten bigger, the world of podcasting entered a period of flux. Big tech platforms are moving into the space; the idea of a “podcast” both in how it’s distributed and what it sounds like is evolving; Hollywood stars and literal princes are making shows; and eye-popping, massive deals are being inked. I mean, Paris Hilton is &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/spotify-podz-acquisition-1235000159/"&gt;investing in and profiting off&lt;/a&gt; podcast technology — who could have imagined!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8ha0k"&gt;I believe we’re seeing the beginning of a new age of audio, one in which more people than ever interact with audio content — whether that’s through a traditional podcast chat show, a live room on Clubhouse, a YouTube video, or Siri talking in their ears. Audio is going mainstream, and I plan to chronicle the bumpy road to that moment. There will be drama, infighting, tech companies feuding over show deals, and hand-wringing over the future of the industry. With your help, I plan to guide us all through these changes. Hopefully we’ll even have some fun along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1RwvG"&gt;Among the questions I hope to answer: Who will win this audio attention war? Who will make money? Who gets to have a podcast? What happens to indie podcasters? What happens to podcasting’s open ecosystem? Are we experiencing a “pivot to audio” that ends like the disastrous “pivot to video?” Is this all a bubble?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAXhuV"&gt;My employer, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, and all of us who work here, are well-acquainted with covering Big Tech and the ways in which it impacts our behavior, livelihoods, and world. And we all want to see &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; grow in various ways — maybe that means more frequent audio-adjacent product reviews from our stellar team here or lengthier features with baller art from our always-impressive creative staff. But a paid newsletter is new for us, so first, we need to learn how to do it and what you all like and need from &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ucc2TD"&gt;So for now, &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; will consist of much of the same coverage it’s always done well. I’ll cover the stories you need to read and provide extra reporting and commentary around them. I hope you will all come to know and trust me and feel comfortable chatting about what you’re reading. I’m open to feedback, tips, and criticism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Us7svi"&gt;Here are a few stories I’m especially proud of, which I hope provide some concrete examples of what I’m talking about somewhat abstractly in this first newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="sWb7mw"&gt;The first is about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22241066/spotify-anchor-sponsorships-ad-money-spend-podcasting"&gt;Anchor’s sponsorship tool not having any sponsors&lt;/a&gt; apart from Spotify itself. I liked this story because it’s a peek inside the Spotify machine — what it’s like for podcasters who use the platform to create and how Spotify’s lofty podcast ambitions are going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dRP9uQ"&gt;The second is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/27/18156895/npr-remote-audio-data-rad-analytics-podcast-tracking-apple-spotify"&gt;my first podcasting story&lt;/a&gt; — one about NPR’s ad-tracking technology, RAD. It was a wonky piece that hinged on the idea that NPR needed buy-in from the major podcast apps to succeed. Apple still hasn’t bought into it, and neither has Spotify. We also don’t hear NPR speak about RAD anymore. It’s one that set up the dynamics of Big Tech’s power in podcasting and hinted at the incoming battle over podcast privacy and ad tracking — another topic I hope to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Udlak7"&gt;And finally, here’s a feature about the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22526502/himalaya-histudios-notorious-llc-podcast-audio-hype-house"&gt;podcasting hype house from hell&lt;/a&gt;.” This story took months to report and was one where the business moves — Himalaya launching in the US, it spinning out HiStudios, and then HiStudios and Himalaya separating — looked obvious on the outside, but had much more happening on the inside (like drug use, podcast conferences gone wrong, and even the appearance of an ice sculpture bong). The podcast industry, like every creative industry, is made up of characters — and knowing those characters can tell you a lot about the business itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Bw3GXx"&gt;I have many more links — feel free to check out my Twitter! — but this column is already getting long. This post is a version of last Tuesday’s free newsletter, and going forward I’ll continue to publish free newsletters every Tuesday — with associated columns here on &lt;a href="http://theverge.com"&gt;theverge.com&lt;/a&gt; — followed by premium, paid editions on Thursday and Friday. (You can subscribe to those &lt;a href="https://hotpodnews.com/subscribe/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jvggOc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="hMkg8H"&gt;Now, as I said, always feel free to reach me. I’m on Twitter at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleyrcarman"&gt;@ashleyrcarman&lt;/a&gt; and email at ashley (at) theverge.com. I hope to get to know you all soon!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696629/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-new-host-ashley-carman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696629/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-new-host-ashley-carman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
