<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-20T15:37:36-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T15:37:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T15:37:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Frontline essential workers and the elderly next in line for COVID-19 vaccinations in US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2R5rpw52NVzbzu-7Taa43jtzQFs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68557248/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SmUTyq"&gt;Frontline essential workers and people 75 years of age and older in the United States should get COVID-19 vaccines in the next wave of immunizations, an independent committee at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommended. That group includes about 49 million people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3V5XoR"&gt;After those groups are vaccinated, the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP) said doses should go to people between 65 and 74 years old, people between 16 and 65 years old with underlying health conditions, and other essential workers not in groups considered frontline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gi7toz"&gt;Vaccines will be in limited supply through at least the next few months. The CDC expects that there should be doses available to vaccinate 20 million people in December, 30 million people in January, and 50 million people in February. “In this setting, difficult choices have to be made,” Kathleen Dooling, medical officer at the CDC, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/acip/meetings/downloads/slides-2020-12/slides-12-20/02-COVID-Dooling.pdf"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; to the ACIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLCOvt"&gt;States and local jurisdictions ultimately make the final decisions around the distribution and prioritization of vaccinations, but the CDC recommendations help shape their approaches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wBsUq8"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21779433/covid-vaccine-priority-health-care-workers-long-term-care"&gt;first phase&lt;/a&gt; of vaccinations are going to health care workers and long term care facility residents. Those groups started to get vaccinated last week, and over &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/index.html"&gt;500,000 people&lt;/a&gt; in the US have been vaccinated so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ppZVEK"&gt;The ACIP balanced two main goals to make recommendations for the second wave of vaccinations: preventing death and disease and preserving societal function. Older adults over 75 have the highest risk of hospitalization and death from COVID-19. Frontline essential workers — which the committee &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/acip/meetings/downloads/slides-2020-12/slides-12-20/02-COVID-Dooling.pdf"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; includes firefighters, teachers, grocery store workers, manufacturing workers, and others — are unable to work from home and often have to interact with the public, putting them at risk of exposure to the virus. Keeping those groups healthy will help keep key services running. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GueTN6lQyz7VpYyAUB-saqQHXYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22186150/EpsZq7oW4AEMBMj.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;CDC&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Slide from a presentation on vaccine prioritization. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SGOWqO"&gt;“This approach mitigates health inequities as racial and ethnic minorities are disproportionately represented in many essential industries,” Dooling said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N4ID0g"&gt;The third group the committee says should be vaccinated includes essential workers like people working in food service, construction, transportation, wastewater, and media. People between 65 and 74 are also at high risk of hospitalization and death from COVID-19, as are younger people with underlying health conditions like cardiac disease or diabetes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ezxMHV"&gt;While the CDC has a list of workplaces that it considers frontline and essential, different states will set those designations in different ways. Various interest groups are &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/20/nyregion/essential-worker-coronavirus-vaccine.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage"&gt;lobbying &lt;/a&gt;states to include their workers in early vaccination groups — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167583/uber-driver-early-access-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine"&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt;, for example, asked states to prioritize its drivers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vd2VGy"&gt;Distributing vaccines to the second and third wave of priority groups will be difficult. It’s hard to determine eligibility, for example, and reaching essential workers (who may not be able to take time off of work, or may live in rural areas) is a challenge. Committee members stressed the importance of adequate funding for vaccine distribution. Money was funneled into vaccine development, which led to the overwhelmingly effective final products. Local health departments need the same level of investment in vaccination programs. The vaccines are Cadillacs, Jeffrey Duchin, a health officer in King County, Washington, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/megtirrell/status/1340702874775531525"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; during the meeting. “But they’ve come with empty gas tanks,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yKWqxf"&gt;Over 200,000 people are being diagnosed with COVID-19 in the US each day, and over 2,500 people are dying from the disease every day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuUKQ9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191920/covid-vaccine-essential-workers-older-adults-cdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191920/covid-vaccine-essential-workers-older-adults-cdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T14:21:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T14:21:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ninja’s Fall Guys skin is now available</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yurYvFQcTgRisOLeEBajLNaHAC8=/428x0:2732x1536/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68556947/EpmxqCKXEAEN0h1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ninja Fall Guys skin.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Mediatonic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z8X1qY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; developer Mediatonic has added a skin based on the hugely-popular streamer Tyler “Ninja” Blevins to the game. The skin’s arrival follows a two-week charity bidding war &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/31/21404149/fall-guys-twitter-bidding-war-in-game-costume-charity"&gt;in August&lt;/a&gt; to have a custom skin added to the game. Blevins, G2 Esports, Aim Lab, and Jimmy “MrBeast” Donaldson pledged a combined $1 million to &lt;a href="https://www.specialeffect.org.uk/"&gt;Special Effect&lt;/a&gt;, which helps people with physical disabilities find ways to play video games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eu9LAq"&gt;Here’s a couple photos the Ninja skin in-game, courtesy of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FallGuysGame/status/1340626462987210753"&gt;the Fall Guys Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. It looks kind of like a jelly bean-sized version of the Ninja skin that was added to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/16/21068938/fortnite-ninja-skin-icon-series-metaverse-tyler-blevins-ultimate-virtual-world-star-wars"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SQsRU7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Surprise!&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Ninja?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Ninja&lt;/a&gt; is now in the store and he only costs:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1 x   Top&lt;br&gt;1 x   Bottom&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So let's see some 100% Ninja lobbies  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;⭐️ We've also got a special show going live in 6 minutes of Ninja's favourite rounds! ⭐️&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Where we falling guys??? &lt;a href="https://t.co/Yir0GX2PpG"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Yir0GX2PpG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fall Guys ❄️ Season 3 Out Now! (@FallGuysGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FallGuysGame/status/1340626462987210753?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NyVYoE"&gt;The Ninja skin isn’t the first crossover added to &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; — Mediatonic has already offered skins like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21536473/fall-guys-godzilla-skin-bean-throwing-monster-mediatonic-branded"&gt;an adorable Godzilla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/devolverdigital/status/1304815102819004416"&gt;Gato Roboto from the game &lt;em&gt;Gato Roboto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and even skins based off of &lt;a href="https://comicbook.com/gaming/news/fall-guys-ps4-half-life-alyx-skin/"&gt;iconic Valve characters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bT2tZv"&gt;It’s unclear when the skins based on G2 Esports, Aim Lab, and Donaldson will be added to the game. Mediatonic hasn’t replied to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKDq8t"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; kicked off its winter-themed third season &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PVNSct9atp8"&gt;on December 15th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zGRUZa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The winner of Fall Guys’ two-week bidding war for an in-game costume is a four-way teamup","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/31/21404149/fall-guys-twitter-bidding-war-in-game-costume-charity"},{"title":"Fortnite’s new Ninja skin is another step toward creating its ultimate virtual world ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/16/21068938/fortnite-ninja-skin-icon-series-metaverse-tyler-blevins-ultimate-virtual-world-star-wars"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191951/fall-guys-ninja-skin-now-available-mediatonic-crowns-charity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191951/fall-guys-ninja-skin-now-available-mediatonic-crowns-charity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T13:16:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T13:16:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Stanford algorithm decided to vaccinate only seven of its frontline COVID-19 workers, out of 5,000 doses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="GP Surgeries In Cornwall Join Covid-19 Vaccine Campaign" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rYLoUSLjjPqw8nyEc17BQChbwS0=/0x0:5908x3939/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68556775/1292266593.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Hugh Hastings/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2cbXZj"&gt;An algorithm determining which Stanford Medicine employees would receive its 5,000 initial doses of the COVID-19 vaccine included just seven medical residents / fellows on the list, according to a December 17th letter sent from Stanford Medicine’s chief resident council. Stanford Medicine leadership has since apologized and promised to re-evaluate the plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zaAqww"&gt;“We take complete responsibility for the errors in the execution of our vaccine distribution plan,” a Stanford Medicine spokesperson said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Our intent was to develop an ethical and equitable process for distribution of the vaccine. We apologize to our entire community, including our residents, fellows, and other frontline care providers, who have performed heroically during our pandemic response. We are immediately revising our plan to better sequence the distribution of the vaccine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NzTQQg"&gt;The initial plan led to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CarolineYLChen/status/1340046920631394310"&gt;demonstrations from medical staff&lt;/a&gt; in addition to the letter sent by the chief resident council. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="d1jhRT"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEW: Stanford used an algorithm to decide who got the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/COVID?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#COVID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/vaccine?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#vaccine&lt;/a&gt; first, and the result was only 7 of the first 5,000 slots went to residents... the same week they were asked to volunteer for ICU coverage in anticipation of a surge in COVID-19 cases.&lt;a href="https://t.co/tupAeyHudx"&gt;https://t.co/tupAeyHudx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/gr5CaPoV7G"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gr5CaPoV7G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Caroline Chen (@CarolineYLChen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CarolineYLChen/status/1340046920631394310?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZjsYdR"&gt;“Stanford’s decision to de-prioritize residents and fellows is defenseless on the basis of science, reason, ethics, and equality,” the letter said. (&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; has hosted &lt;a href="https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/20432343-stanford-letter"&gt;the full letter on DocumentCloud&lt;/a&gt;.) “Many of us know senior faculty who have worked from home since the pandemic began in March 2020, with no in-person patient responsibilities, who were selected for vaccination. In the meantime, we residents and fellows strap on N95 masks for the tenth month of this pandemic without a transparent and clear plan for our protection in place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mpCcCw"&gt;The residents’ letter also alleges that the error in the algorithm was found on Tuesday but that leadership opted not to make changes to the plan ahead of its December 17th release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eYhn6"&gt;Here’s how the algorithm reportedly worked, &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/12/18/948176807/stanford-apologizes-after-vaccine-allocation-leaves-out-nearly-all-medical-resid"&gt;according to NPR&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="vK1lZS"&gt;According to an email sent by a chief resident to other residents, Stanford’s leaders explained that an algorithm was used to assign its first allotment of the vaccine. The algorithm was said to have prioritized those health care workers at highest risk for COVID infections, along with factors like age and the location or unit where they work in the hospital. Residents apparently did not have an assigned location, and along with their typically young age, they were dropped low on the priority list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="FNsyVt"&gt;Stanford Medicine administration also sent an email to staff on December 18th apologizing for the initial plan and promising changes. “We are working quickly to address the flaws in our plan and develop a revised version,” the email said, which &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CarolineYLChen/status/1340080220569800706"&gt;was obtained&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; health care reporter Caroline Chen. “We are optimistic that a large shipment of vaccines will arrive next week, which will allow us to vaccinate a substantial segment of our community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7cCHg6"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Email from Stanford administration this afternoon: &lt;a href="https://t.co/hJTyjgSTIN"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hJTyjgSTIN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Caroline Chen (@CarolineYLChen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CarolineYLChen/status/1340080220569800706?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ukabaQ"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration has authorized two COVID-19 vaccines for use in the US. The vaccine developed by Pfizer / BioNTech was authorized &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use"&gt;on December 11th&lt;/a&gt;, and the one developed by Moderna was authorized &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22185507/moderna-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorized"&gt;on December 18th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191749/stanford-medicine-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-list-algorithm-medical-residents"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22191749/stanford-medicine-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-list-algorithm-medical-residents</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cooking videos were one small savior of 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/czkdQnMAlPci8islJ_2EYJTHe1A=/165x0:2112x1298/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68556333/remicruz.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e9q8dc"&gt;Early one morning, a week after the pandemic started, chef and food writer J. Kenji López-Alt strapped a GoPro to his head and filmed himself making breakfast. In &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Dw2UyqIaik"&gt;the video&lt;/a&gt;, you can see López-Alt rummaging through his fridge, slicing and frying bacon, and peeling a bit of egg off a pan to give to his excited dog. There’s no recipe beneath the video, no voice-over instructions detailing what we’re seeing — it’s just a guy in a kitchen making breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M9tqPq"&gt;Videos like these became both much-needed entertainment and valuable educational resources early in the pandemic, as a world of people realized they would be stuck at home indefinitely with their own (not necessarily stunning) cooking, and a little extra time to put into it. Food and drink streams surged in popularity on Twitch, doubling in hours watched year over year in August, according to &lt;a href="https://blog.streamelements.com/state-of-the-stream-august-2020-fall-guys-has-an-incredible-debut-shroud-returns-to-twitch-and-9689227dc972"&gt;StreamElements and Arsenal.gg&lt;/a&gt;. On YouTube, “cook with me” videos more than doubled in popularity starting in March and maintained that growth through October, YouTube told &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/youtube-babish-cooking-shows-virus-339e5283220590ab3c250ef54c946895"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6pJjVo"&gt;“It gives [viewers] confidence to do stuff in the kitchen,” said López-Alt, author of &lt;em&gt;The Food Lab: Better Home Cooking Through Science&lt;/em&gt;. His own videos lack the polish and perfect cuts of a professional show and include the slip-ups he makes along the way. “It gives them permission to make mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3VWAve"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T2zBtiYF5Gw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tX9Rt2"&gt;Cooking shows have been around for a century, but new formats online have revitalized the genre in recent years. On YouTube in particular, you can find step-by-step instructional lessons, personal “cook with me” vlogs, and stomach-churning food challenges like stuffing McDonald’s burgers and nuggets into an oversized burrito. On Twitch, chefs and home cooks broadcast themselves live from their kitchen as they prepare meals. And on TikTok, you can watch videos teaching you how to make a new dish in under a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VSjXA4"&gt;Many hosts noticed a pickup in views and engagement as the pandemic went on. “It definitely has been skyrocket high with the views on things you can do at home,” Zahria Harvey, whose YouTube channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/XOZAHRIAAA/videos"&gt;XO. ZAHRIAAA&lt;/a&gt; is known for “cook with me” videos, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Harvey says one viewer wrote in about making an affordable date night meal featured on her channel for an anniversary dinner because she couldn’t go out to dinner. “It was like wow, these videos are actually helping a lot of people during this time,” Harvey said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eL6sih"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.twitch.tv/?video=v838587873&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;parent=www.theverge.com&amp;amp;parent=iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=iframely.com&amp;amp;parent=cdn.iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=if-cdn.com" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dRAsrl"&gt;The influx of new viewers has also meant more live interaction for hosts on Twitch. “I find that the community is way more vocal and involved past March this year,” L.A., a photographer and former sushi chef who runs the channel &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thehungerservice"&gt;The Hunger Service&lt;/a&gt;, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. L.A.’s streams typically run for three to four hours and show him preparing and cooking a meal, talking through his process as he’s working. As he cooks, viewers ask questions about the process, like how sharp a knife needs to be or how to turn a recipe vegan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xt3q5P"&gt;For López-Alt, who’s known for his &lt;em&gt;Serious Eats &lt;/em&gt;column, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/JKenjiLopezAlt/videos"&gt;his channel&lt;/a&gt; became a fun outlet for both him and his viewers. The format he locked into — strapping a GoPro to his head — is what made video finally click for him, and it helped him reach viewers who weren’t familiar with his writing. “The food I cook on my channel is stuff I was generally making for lunch and for dinner,” López-Alt said. “I could do it consistently, people seemed to like it, [and] I enjoyed making it.” Viewers told him the videos were a bright spot and were helping them learn how to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9NKbuw"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X8h2MO1vPRQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AJeJvX"&gt;Some creators have found that the surge in interest in their channels extends beyond cooking. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/RemLife/featured"&gt;Remi Cruz&lt;/a&gt;, a popular YouTuber who frequently features cooking on her two channels, said that people have been more interested in basically anything you can do at home. For “vlogmas,” she’s been using cooking to fill the gap where she’d normally vlog about outdoor activities and holiday shopping. “I’ve just been implementing some sort of cooking-related thing every day, and people genuinely love it,” Cruz told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Xwpkx"&gt;Viewers won’t always end up cooking what they see, but these videos can still make their time in the kitchen a bit more fun — or at least, distract them while they think about the great meals they’ll eventually go back out to a restaurant and order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IKe0J2"&gt;“People are looking for some sort of comfort,” L.A. said. “Comfort food is a thing, and watching these shows can offer that comfort. You may not be making it at the time, but maybe you will.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22178957/cooking-videos-2020-pandemic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22178957/cooking-videos-2020-pandemic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Animal Crossing gave me structure in a shapeless year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j2YsVtH3tRH3CQHWbyUn7_F2g8c=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68556192/sc6lt8.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time may have felt sluggish in the real world, but Animal Crossing’s seasons have kept changing.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WW1o3n"&gt;I broke ground on my &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons &lt;/em&gt;island, Honkland, just three days before the UK’s Prime Minister Boris Johnson announced that the country was going into lockdown. I’d pitched up my tent, and I was just about to deliver a pile of materials to Timmy Nook to help him build the island’s general store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RAngZd"&gt;I was enjoying my first &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt;, but I hadn’t quite hit that point of “getting it” just yet. The menus were slow to navigate, and I wasn’t really sure what I was working toward. Mining the most material out of each of my island rocks involved a convoluted process of digging two holes and then hitting them repeatedly over the course of several seconds. Picking fruit involved first shaking a tree and then picking up each piece individually. It felt deliberately inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QQxqG7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A game best played in short bursts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VefAxe"&gt;“From this evening I must give the British people a very simple instruction: you must stay at home,” the prime minister said during his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJycNmK7KPk&amp;amp;t=28s"&gt;address on March 23rd&lt;/a&gt;. “You should not be meeting friends. If your friends ask you to meet, you should say ‘No.’ You should not be meeting family members who do not live in your home. You should not be going shopping except for essentials like food and medicine — and you should do this as little as you can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvLI1U"&gt;Inside the flat, we tried to make the best of the situation while we effectively had to press pause on our lives. Evenings out were replaced with marathon sessions of Ticket to Ride and Carcassonne. We’d watch films while simultaneously keeping a laptop open, running a Zoom call with friends we hadn’t seen in months. We bought elastic resistance bands and slung gymnastic rings over an old pull-up bar for group workouts on the weekends. And every evening, I booted up &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing &lt;/em&gt;to see what awaited me on Honkland. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C_1zWd0P_noidfeEmNLGejXtT7E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22181824/sc6lt7.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The game’s chore-filled early hours were exactly what I needed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1HDxxt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing &lt;/em&gt;is a game best played in short bursts because the series has a unique approach to the passage of time. In most games, the time revolves around the player. It starts passing when the game starts and stops. Almost everything happens on your terms. But &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; takes place in real time, so if it’s the middle of the night on March 23rd in the real world, then it’s going to be the middle of the night on March 23rd in the game. (It’s possible to change your console’s built-in clock to “&lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-acnh-guide/2020/3/20/21168240/time-travel-next-day-tomorrow-faster"&gt;time travel&lt;/a&gt;,” but for me, it ruins the fun.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="f9fte6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Animal Crossing’ forced me to keep track of the day of the week&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0GeE1B"&gt;The approach makes it difficult to play indefinitely each day. Your island’s rocks eventually stop spitting out materials when you try to mine them, and you run out of fruit to pick from your trees. You can continue to do things like hunt down bugs and fish, but inevitably, you’ll come up against a task that needs to be done tomorrow. It’s a bold design that often forces you to wait, while other games often tempt you into playing just one extra hour. Ordinarily, I would have found the mechanic a little frustrating, but in a lockdown situation where time felt like it was standing still for weeks, it was exactly what I needed. I couldn’t lose track of time playing it for hours; instead, I had to keep a grip on what day of the week it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEgRrS"&gt;I got to work on my island. I pruned its weeds, moved more villagers in, and started collecting critters to populate my island’s museum. I sold fruit, earned bells (read: money), and spent them on building bridges and ramps to make my island’s rough terrain easier to navigate. It became a little hobby, something to check in with once a day, a little project that built up bit by bit over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZxKL1t"&gt;I have considered myself incredibly lucky over the course of the past 12 months. I’ve thankfully been able to continue working from home, logging on to a computer at the end of my bed each day to chat with colleagues over Slack and conduct interviews over Zoom. Doing my small bit to help this year involved little more than staying at home as much as was physically possible. &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing &lt;/em&gt;made doing that a little bit more bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NZ4K7ePDOsxeBdHfbYf2ulDXAlU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22181825/sc836s.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiplayer helped me feel connected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JhtNKU"&gt;It was &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt;’s multiplayer elements that I most needed in those first few months of lockdown. It felt like the whole world was playing the game together, as Twitter and Reddit filled up with screenshots of people’s islands as well as requests to collaborate. At work, we set up a dedicated Slack channel to share our island’s turnip prices. Ordinarily, you can earn a small profit by buying and selling turnips on your own island, but you can make millions if you work as a team with other players, converging on another player’s island when it’s offering an especially good price for turnips on any given day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="WCm6Yl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Time felt like it stood still for weeks on end this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qJbZk4"&gt;It’s strange how, in a year when so much history was continuously happening, time felt like it stood still for weeks on end. Five days of working in my bedroom, two days of relaxing in my living room. Rinse, repeat. People joke about time passing weirdly on the internet, when events that feel like they happened years ago actually took place just last week. This year, that weird sense of internet time seeped out into the real world. Without leaving my flat for anything more than a quick shop, it was hard to feel present in global events, no matter how important and life-changing they were for so many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xqt9LF"&gt;As the months went on and the internet’s interest in the game waned, a steady stream of new features and in-game events gave me a reason to keep visiting Honkland. Nintendo added hedgerows and diving and new characters like Redd, a huckster who occasionally visits your island with “artwork” to sell. Celebrations like Halloween were marked with in-game events that relied on playing the game on the right day to see their content. Between big events and new feature additions, every month saw the arrival of new bugs and fish, a gentle trickle of collectibles to find before they migrated away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OqXyQ7"&gt;It was important to have something to do, but this year especially, it was important to me to feel like time was actually passing. Like many other people, I didn’t go on a summer holiday this year, and I didn’t attend any Halloween parties. I didn’t have a morning cycling commute to enjoy the country’s summer or to see its trees gradually turn an autumnal orange. Instead, checking in on Honkland each month gave me those small reminders that the seasons were still changing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22188452/animal-crossing-new-horizons-coronavirus-pandemic-year-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22188452/animal-crossing-new-horizons-coronavirus-pandemic-year-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>This was a good year to listen to ambient music, whatever that is</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The cover art for KMRU’s 2020 ambient record Peel" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N2x2QUh_hCb7ZqLLuMrl990_Ilk=/0x200:1200x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68556102/0021147102_10.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The cover art for KMRU’s 2020 ambient record &lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt; | Courtesy of Editions Mego&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LUxMaD"&gt;In the early days of despair, I looked at Spotify and decided that everything sounded bad. All songs were boring, and I was sick of everything. What that really meant was I was sick of myself. But by the summer, I’d found the solve: ambient music. The best music I heard this year was barely music at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTQYYS"&gt;The notion of “ambient music” is pretentious, sure, but the concept is simple. If most music is centered around some alchemy of melody and rhythm, ambient music eschews that for whatever else: tones, moods, atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Pg1TQT"&gt;&lt;div style="max-width: 700px;"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px; position: relative;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1478120105/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=333333/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D7jKRh"&gt;I’ve listened to &lt;a href="https://kmru.bandcamp.com/album/peel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Nairobi-based artist KMRU roughly once a day since I first heard it in July. Like most music in the genre, the album is concerned with timbre and texture — a lot of shapeless, ambiguous noise that slowly escalates and envelopes you. (Or, if you are my sister, you might describe it as “scary” and “ominous” and “please turn that off.”) Still, it was nice to put on something consistent in the mornings, which became as much of a ritual for me as taking coffee with oat milk and refreshing the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ updated COVID maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5MBPfd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peel &lt;/em&gt;— and two other KMRU records released this year, &lt;em&gt;Opaquer &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Jar &lt;/em&gt;— were quiet revelations for me, especially as someone who tends to listen to the same handful of pop songs on repeat. Though its production is often lush and maximalist, pop music is compact. It’s designed to be played in many places: on AirPods, blasted from a car radio, through your tinny laptop speakers. It has to sound good everywhere, which is another way of saying that it has to sound the same everywhere. Pretty depressing when you’re going nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OsSmpg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt; took on a different shape, depending on where I was listening to it — though this year, that just meant which room of the house I was in. The Sonos in the kitchen made the record sound expansive and often distant. In my office, where I listened to &lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt; passively while staring at Google Docs during the workday, the resonance seemed to fill every square inch of the room, making me constantly aware of the space’s small dimensions. I’d sometimes play it through my phone after waking up — a calm and steadily escalating thrum. Yet listening to KMRU in the bathroom was too claustrophobic, too annoying, so I’d put on Dua Lipa instead. I even bought &lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt; on vinyl, not really so I could hear how it sounded, but because I’d gotten really used to soothing boredom and anxiety by ordering things online. And like a lot of things that went through the mail in 2020, the record still hasn’t arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYcXK1"&gt;I struggled to find any formal interviews with KMRU, but I did come across a few videos he’d done on YouTube. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MmzjXTruJek"&gt;In one video&lt;/a&gt;, he sampled a broken piano he came across on the street, captured on a fuzzy portable mic. Like a lot of things on YouTube, it turned out to be an ad (this one for Ableton Live). But there was something romantic about seeing KMRU’s field recording — someone out in the world, collecting precious little sounds, even if the finished product obfuscated their origins too much to be identified. At least it left something to the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="wKsWpj"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="KMRU doing field recordings" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ajkrkcqiZkjYSb9_GPWS_4lJkY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22170474/0022115307_25.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of KMRU&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;KMRU doing field recordings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Xfiung"&gt;Browse YouTube for long enough and you start to recognize that video titles have their own kind of SEO. More than word choice, you see similar constructions over and over that declare what a thing is and who it’s for. This likely makes it easier for a robot to parse and for a recommendation service to serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DnxvGd"&gt;It also allows us to reverse-engineer people’s intentions. Look up footage of nature, and most of it will identify itself as a “relaxation” video, which is more of an intention than a genre. A one-hour 4K video of sunsets in Seattle sells itself as perfect for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v9a22bcp-sQ"&gt;“sleep, relaxation, distress, insomnia.”&lt;/a&gt; The meme equivalent is YouTube’s anime-inflected “lofi hip hop radio - beats to relax/study to,” which has spinoffs for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JspBhPzs7i8"&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R7M-DDMMfh4"&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;. It’s background noise by design. It’s basically Muzak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OJfTZY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In the absence of Muzak, we just Muzak ourselves&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J736QO"&gt;In its heyday — the better part of the 20th century — Muzak was the soundtrack of the mall: familiar, pleasing, and most importantly, inoffensive. The company went bankrupt over a decade ago, and its assets now operate under a conglomerate called Mood Media. But if Muzak the corporation left us, its spirit never did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhiI8N"&gt;In many ways, this is what we do to ourselves when we hit shuffle on a playlist or let YouTube guide our listening. Across platforms, a recommendation engine is reactive and reinforcing a suggestion that is, again, familiar, pleasing, and inoffensive. In the absence of Muzak, we just Muzak ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="txyBHa"&gt;Brian Eno coined the term “ambient music” to put his work in opposition with Muzak. As the myth goes, stuck for several hours in a terminal in Cologne, Germany, Eno believed he could write better music for a public space — something calming to ease the bustle of frenzied travelers. The result was the seminal 1978 record &lt;em&gt;Music for Airports&lt;/em&gt;. Not long after, in the mid-‘80s, Japanese electrosynth polymath Haruomi Hosono would write a suite of dulcet songs specifically for Muji stores to set the tone for a pleasing shopping experience. There’s an argument that &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90171905/hospital-sound-design-can-be-deadly"&gt;the sound design of hospitals could save lives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CYvVLA"&gt;And in a year when far fewer people around the world traveled or frequented malls and more people were going to the hospital and never leaving, what do you do with &lt;em&gt;Music for Airports&lt;/em&gt; and for Muji and for the morgue? You bring it home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3FkLf"&gt;In the days when escapism was fruitless and indulgences were unsatisfying, the music I listened to felt less like feeding an algorithm and more like asserting control over a nonsense year. Like every personal revelation, it feels obvious in hindsight. But awareness — &lt;em&gt;mindfulness! &lt;/em&gt;— is an active pursuit: introduce some friction, stay in the present. I think I always knew what that looked like. It wasn’t until this year that I knew how it sounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BxE6wz"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8VDrYK"&gt;Five ambient-ish albums for 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ddYski"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blink a Few Times to Clear Your Eyes&lt;/em&gt; - Grand River&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GRlrLx"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Telas&lt;/em&gt; - Nicolas Jaar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fvyI1q"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Shall We Go on Sinning So That Grace May Increase?&lt;/em&gt; - The Soft Pink Truth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CmL50Q"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Harbors&lt;/em&gt; - Ellen Fullman and Theresa Wong (debatably ambient, mostly abrasive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Rkw0ho"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Peel&lt;/em&gt; - KMRU (also &lt;em&gt;Opaquer&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jar&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="NdqXvg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPIEIg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22175193/ambient-music-2020-pandemic-quarantine-at-home"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22175193/ambient-music-2020-pandemic-quarantine-at-home</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Nguyen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-20T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best movies of 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O2A-sH5SSrQMoOfM5ZnEwEPFkXU=/182x89:1267x812/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68555946/Screen_Shot_2020_12_17_at_10.29.03_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A24&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="X66yxE"&gt;We didn’t go to the movies much this year, but the movies still came to us. While the convenience of home viewing can’t match the experience of watching a spectacle in the dark with others, the other joy of movies — talking about them — is easier than ever, thanks to our connected world. And 2020’s pandemic sidelined a lot of big blockbusters, leaving smaller, more interesting movies to take center stage. As silver linings go, this one isn’t that bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="grtndz"&gt;Here, in no particular order, are ten incredible movies from a year where movies still rallied to offer experiences that were provocative, compelling, and fun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cXmh9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Lur5V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Assistant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5cqljH"&gt;One of the best films made in response to the crimes of Harvey Weinstein and the subsequent #MeToo movement, &lt;em&gt;The Assistant&lt;/em&gt; follows an assistant (Julia Garner) who works at an unnamed movie production company in New York City for one long, miserable day. Looming over everything is the powerful, predatory boss — never shown or heard except over the phone — whom everyone accommodates and protects. &lt;em&gt;The Assistant&lt;/em&gt; is essential, difficult filmmaking, and a quiet, unblinking condemnation of the ways abuse is allowed to persist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6RR4hX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Ted Face the Music&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zzd3YJ"&gt;The biggest surprise of the year was a third &lt;em&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Ted &lt;/em&gt;movie, and it was a joyous one in a year short on things to feel good about. Ironically, it starts with disappointment: Bill and Ted (Alex Winter and Keanu Reeves) have somehow not yet written the song that will unite the world, the one promised by &lt;em&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Ted’s Excellent Adventure&lt;/em&gt;. They’re out of time now, and if they don’t deliver, the world’s going to end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dDZRxB"&gt;So they do what they always do: travel through time and space to try to find an easy way out, only to learn that there is so much love and joy to be found if you just commit to doing things the hard way, with the people you love by your side. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ewmIzt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kfGV2q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lovers Rock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Eqfui"&gt;The second film in Steve McQueen’s &lt;em&gt;Small Axe &lt;/em&gt;collection now streaming on Amazon is perhaps its best — and also its smallest. Mostly set at a single party, &lt;em&gt;Lovers Rock&lt;/em&gt; opens a window into a whole universe via a single extended dance scene, a moment of cinematic bliss unlike any other this year. Consider this a recommendation for all five &lt;em&gt;Small Axe &lt;/em&gt;films, but treat this one as special: it’s 70 minutes of falling in love, and that’s the best feeling in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTIKEh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zRsSAg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Invisible Man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UdenJH"&gt;An incredible reinvention of a classic Universal monster, &lt;em&gt;The Invisible Man&lt;/em&gt; turns the classic ‘30s film of a man gone mad with power after becoming invisible into a portrait of toxic masculinity. The remake portrays a woman’s (Elisabeth Moss) struggles to escape her controlling, abusive, tech-billionaire boyfriend (Oliver Jackson-Cohen) and survive his elaborate campaign to gaslight her with his high-tech invisibility suit. Like the best horror, it leverages the frightening and fantastic to push on something terribly real. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2L0JD4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNJy6W"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GJ2pYg"&gt;The only big, traditional superhero film we got this year was also the most refreshing. &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt; is an action movie about the breakup between Harley Quinn (Margot Robbie) and the Joker (unseen) and its messy, violent fallout. A lean, mean thrill ride with genuinely great action choreography (a rarity for big superhero movies!), &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt; doubles down on something most action movies are surprisingly bad at: if you’re gonna have a fight scene, why not make it look really damn cool? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="esbfcd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w473jD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Cow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="61bgsZ"&gt;While the title delivers on its premise — there is a cow, and it is featured prominently —  &lt;em&gt;First Cow&lt;/em&gt; is also one of the finest explorations of a friendship you’ll see in a movie this year. A chef, Cookie (John Magaro), and King-Lu, a Chinese immigrant on the run (Orion Lee), form an unlikely bond over a business opportunity: stealing milk from the first and only cow in the Oregon Territory. What starts as a partnership of convenience becomes a gradual expression of care, one that makes &lt;em&gt;First Cow&lt;/em&gt; an irresistibly tender and warm cinematic achievement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apPp1s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La Llorona&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aZnzPG"&gt;A horror film where the real terror is in contemplating what isn’t shown, &lt;em&gt;La Llorona&lt;/em&gt; wrestles with a real-life nightmare by way of a thinly veiled fictional stand-in: the genocide of the Maya Ixil by a brutal Guatemalan dictator. (Named Enrique Monteverde in the film, and Efraín Ríos Montt in real life.) When the former ruler and general (Julio Diaz) is acquitted for his war crimes on a technicality, his mansion becomes a haunted house, as unexplainable forces cry for justice. Masterfully crafted and deeply layered, &lt;em&gt;La Llorona &lt;/em&gt;is cinema as remembrance, a film made to bring to light what we cannot — and should not — forget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ay2BS2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79mHOA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boys State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Le9edm"&gt;If you’ve never heard of Boys State, let me explain. It’s an annual summer program sponsored by the American Legion where high schoolers spend a week building a government from scratch. This documentary, which follows a number of boys attending a recent one in Texas, will make you wonder why. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7JA2No"&gt;An ingenious subject presented by smart filmmakers, &lt;em&gt;Boys State&lt;/em&gt; is an exercise that examines the id of our political process; teenagers learn how to negotiate the difference between what they’ve been told about government and what actually succeeds, while they inadvertently replicate our nation’s many shortcomings. &lt;em&gt;Boys State&lt;/em&gt; won’t fill you with hope, but it also won’t fill you with dread. It’s a movie about just how much work we have to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1vinLi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L0rg3C"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dick Johnson Is Dead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cpxdHn"&gt;When filmmaker Kirsten Johnson learned that her father, Dick, was suffering from dementia, the two agreed to make the long goodbye the diagnosis left them with into a film — specifically, a film where they imagine all the ways Dick Johnson might die and what might be waiting for him after. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pkeAEL"&gt;The film is less morbid than that description may seem. &lt;em&gt;Dick Johnson Is Dead &lt;/em&gt;is an incredibly moving work of affection, a documentary about celebrating a loved one’s life while they’re still here to appreciate it. It’s about how remembering someone is a vital part of loving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9XhWc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SfVXUT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Da 5 Bloods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q7feGG"&gt;During the Vietnam War, five soldiers nicknamed themselves Bloods and hid a chest full of gold deep in the jungles in which they fought. Only four made it back home; they never forgot that loot or the friend they buried with it. &lt;em&gt;Da 5 Bloods&lt;/em&gt; is a revenge movie disguised as a treasure hunt. As the four remaining bloods return in the present day to claim their gold, their desire for vengeance drives them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fpw04V"&gt;They’re angry at the country that asked them to fight for freedom while denying it from them, at the Vietnamese people whose world they destroyed in the service of that war, and at the very idea of America — the way it warps and twists you into new shapes in the battered name of democracy. &lt;em&gt;Da 5 Bloods&lt;/em&gt; is Spike Lee’s opus about the wars we never stop fighting, even after the guns are put away. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22176305/best-movies-2020-first-cow-lovers-rock-bill-and-ted"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22176305/best-movies-2020-first-cow-lovers-rock-bill-and-ted</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Rivera</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-19T20:03:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T20:03:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Starting Sunday, cable companies can no longer ‘rent’ you the router you already own</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Asus’s arachnid router" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y59HLL-4HhsxFGBb21nStMYS4Zk=/0x0:1020x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68554731/vs09-02_1251cxs-2.0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CvZZbv"&gt;Is your internet service provider charging you every month for the cable modem or router that &lt;em&gt;you purchased with your own money? &lt;/em&gt;Or, perhaps, have you never bothered to buy those items because you couldn’t escape the fee? That fee will be illegal starting Sunday, December 20th, and you should tell your ISP that you’ll no longer tolerate it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="77hB1R"&gt;Last year, Congress passed a law that should have fixed this ridiculous loophole as of June 20th, 2020 — and though the FCC &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/4/21280188/fcc-deadline-isps-charge-customer-equipment-date"&gt;managed to extend the deadline six months&lt;/a&gt; by spinning up some bullshit about how cable companies &lt;a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20200604/09392344642/fcc-delays-law-banning-your-isp-charging-you-rental-fees-hardware-you-already-own.shtml"&gt;didn’t have the resources &lt;em&gt;to stop charging you money&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the law should take full effect tomorrow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t4hyj7"&gt;Do note that &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/5035/text#H9D3FC644679E4CEFB927457B4310C9D3"&gt;the actual text of the law&lt;/a&gt; still allows some BS to occur. If your ISP sends you a router, you’ll need to return it to avoid charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5p6YK3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Whether you use it or not”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mi0KFW"&gt;Frontier in particular has been notorious for charging customers $10 a month for their equipment “whether you use it or not” — the company’s words, not mine — but Frontier is clearly aware it won’t be able to do that anymore. Starting this month, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ffrontier.com%2Fhelpcenter%2Fcategories%2Finternet%2Finstallation-setup%2Ffrontier-router&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F19%2F22191096%2Finternet-modem-router-rental-fee-fix-television-viewer-protection-act-tvpa#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company’s equipment page&lt;/a&gt; has changed to remove the part where it talks about the mandatory fee. &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20201112030707/https://frontier.com/helpcenter/categories/internet/installation-setup/compatible-routers-and-modems"&gt;Here’s an archived copy of the site from last month&lt;/a&gt; if you want to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avgFrr"&gt;If you can purchase your own cable modem, I suggest you do. Modems will generally pay for themselves in less than a year, and the all-in-one router boxes that ISPs typically provide typically offer worse Wi-Fi coverage than you could easily add to a house yourself, particularly now that mesh Wi-Fi systems are better, cheaper, and easier to use than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uDvvDa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Eero Mesh Wi-Fi System review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/14/20912347/eero-mesh-router-wifi-system-review-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Google Nest Wifi review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20946586/google-nest-wifi-review-mesh-router-price-specs-features"},{"title":"In 2021, we need to fix America’s internet","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sEJ0gn"&gt;It also doesn’t help that in the US, we pay roughly eight to 17 times more to rent a modem on average that Asia and Europe do, respectively. That’s just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;one of the ways America’s internet needs to be fixed in 2021.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22191096/internet-modem-router-rental-fee-fix-television-viewer-protection-act-tvpa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22191096/internet-modem-router-rental-fee-fix-television-viewer-protection-act-tvpa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-19T19:04:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T19:04:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s the never-before-seen Simpsons video game dreamt up for Sega Dreamcast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X7wlZgNjH-BdxFZbamWwE8h1T1s=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68554528/vlcsnap_2020_12_19_15h42m10s760.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="InRtDq"&gt;As a lowly &lt;em&gt;Wired Magazine&lt;/em&gt; intern, one of my first assignments was reviewing 2007’s &lt;a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/the-simpsons-game-review/1900-6181997/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Simpsons Game:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a groundbreaking self-referential parody of the entire gaming industry that, sadly, suffered from as nearly as many tropes as it lampooned. But it turns out Fox had been interested in a three-dimensional Simpsons game long before that — one that could have appeared on the Sega Dreamcast if things had worked out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6p7gkA"&gt;Today, the DreamcasticChannel&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on YouTube (via &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/someone-found-a-weird-unreleased-simpsons-game-on-an-ol-1845919560"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is showcasing &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2TC4nD0qxUM"&gt;an unreleased tech demo&lt;/a&gt; from the year 2000 for a title tentatively called “The Simpsons: Bug Squad!” It’s from the long-defunct &lt;a href="https://www.mobygames.com/company/red-lemon-studios"&gt;Red Lemon Studios&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s remarkable how much the game’s cel-shaded graphics look like the show. Apparently, a Dreamcast-Talk forum user by the name of sreak &lt;a href="https://www.dreamcast-talk.com/forum/viewtopic.php?p=141620#p141620"&gt;found this demo just sitting on a broken Dreamcast dev kit’s hard drive&lt;/a&gt;, and with a bit of help, the forum figured out how to make it playable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nqLOOF-hOU47Fg9KTk_3gJW1-1w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22185135/vlcsnap_2020_12_19_15h42m10s760.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot of DreamcasticChannel (YouTube)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2AzalT"&gt;Less understandable is the whole &lt;em&gt;Bug Squad&lt;/em&gt; thing. Were you really going to play a bug? Why? Who would your squad be compromised of? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MzrWnr"&gt;Hopefully, some of the original developers (or Fox executives) will come forward so we can find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fXIVDf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Massive Nintendo leak reveals early Mario, Zelda, and Pokémon secrets","url":"https://www.polygon.com/2020/7/26/21339018/nintendo-gigaleak-super-mario-64-zelda-pokemon-what-is-it-snes"},{"title":"An unprecedented Nintendo leak turns into a moral dilemma for archivists","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21347074/nintendo-gigaleak-controversy-history-preservation-archives"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22191027/simpsons-bug-squad-sega-dreamcast-game-prototype-tech-demo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22191027/simpsons-bug-squad-sega-dreamcast-game-prototype-tech-demo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-19T18:21:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T18:21:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Queen Elizabeth will deliver her Christmas Day message via Alexa this year, if you ask</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Queen Elizabeth II Delivers Her Christmas Speech" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_2FNAG39vYU5ibWDLtJ4tJog2lw=/0x6:2910x1946/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68554427/1074649268.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by John Stillwell - WPA Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tixsU3"&gt;“Alexa, play the Queen’s Christmas Day message” will soon be a thing — even if you don’t live in the UK. Starting December 25th at 3PM GMT (or 10AM ET, 7AM PT), that phrase will deliver the Queen’s traditional Christmas Day broadcast, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/dec/19/alexa-to-summon-the-queen-as-amazon-echo-airs-christmas-broadcast"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5JRTxD"&gt;If you’re curious what the Queen’s message might contain, you can check out transcripts of all her previous Christmas Broadcasts (going back to 1952!) at &lt;a href="https://www.royal.uk/history-christmas-broadcast"&gt;The Royal Household’s website.&lt;/a&gt; No doubt this one will spend some time on the COVID-19 pandemic, whose latest variant is currently forcing London to impose &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/19/world/europe/coronavirus-uk-new-variant.html"&gt;its harshest lockdown yet&lt;/a&gt;, but perhaps it’ll be a bit of an escape from the harsh reality, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YLXba6"&gt;Amazon seems to think it might be: “After a challenging year, millions of people from across the Commonwealth will be eagerly awaiting Her Majesty the Queen’s message on Christmas Day. By creating this world-first innovation, just as we did in 2012 with the release of the Queen’s Christmas speech on Kindle, we hope that even more people will be able to enjoy the uplifting words of Her Majesty,” reads a statement from Eric King, director of Amazon Alexa Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KDZsHW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22190965/amazon-alexa-echo-uk-queen-elizabeth"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22190965/amazon-alexa-echo-uk-queen-elizabeth</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
