<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-04T03:01:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T03:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T03:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Forza Horizon 5 is the perfect portable Xbox game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RjJeDbW3w1jWtIbbpuRIeU0EyEQ=/76x0:3262x2124/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70091598/ForzaHorizon5_Launch_Preview_06_16x9_WM.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QRaYyO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; is an absolutely stunning showcase of the Xbox Series X. Cars look incredible, and I’ve loved taking in the game’s lush and colorful landscapes as I’ve raced through the streets of Mexico blasting classical music. On a console that’s largely lacking in big-name exclusives, it’s one of the rare games that really shows what the latest Xbox is capable of. Turns out it’s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a fantastic portable game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O2nHeY"&gt;Hear me out. Yes, the graphics are amazing and are a joy to take in on a big screen. But &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;accessible gameplay and bevy of customizability options means it translates really well to something the size of a smartphone. I’ve been playing the game via console streaming with my iPhone 12 Mini plugged into a Backbone One controller, and I’ve been surprised at just how great a fit it is.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hdc9MLVYIg1TBU9nWCW8XtV0TLo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983838/ForzaHorizon5_Launch_Preview_03_16x9_WM.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;em&gt; looks amazing on a phone or a TV.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uCh85S"&gt;The most basic activity in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; is pretty simple: pick a point on the map or jump into a race and follow the big blue driving line to get to where you need to go. Even on the iPhone 12 Mini’s screen, the line is easy to see, and I can usually follow it without issue. The controls are straightforward as well. Most of the time, I’m only worrying about one trigger for gas, one trigger for brake, and navigating with the left control stick. All of that is manageable for me on the Backbone One’s smaller layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ji7JA4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;’s generous rewind feature also alleviates potential frustrations from playing on a phone screen. While the racing line is helpful, I’ve definitely missed a few turns because I couldn’t see far enough ahead. But if I do end up blowing by a hairpin curve, I can just hit the rewind button to get another opportunity to more smoothly make the turn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DujGdt"&gt;The game’s core structure lends itself to pick-up-and-play sessions. &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;’s huge map is littered with races and activities (I don’t know if I’ll ever complete them all), but most events don’t take longer than a few minutes to complete. That means it’s easy to accomplish something even if you only have 15 minutes to play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AeSbq"&gt;Console streaming, for me, has been pretty solid. I’ve only seen a handful of frame rate hiccups, though that might just be because I live in a studio and am rarely a few feet away from my Series X and my Wi-Fi router. That said, the few times I’ve felt choppy performance has hindered my racing, I’ve just tuned down the difficulty a bit in settings to make things a bit more forgiving. I haven’t been able to try &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; on Xbox Cloud Gaming, but if you want to get a feel for what it could feel like, check out &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 4&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which has a tiny but bearable amount of input lag for me. (Your mileage may vary, of course.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="f5eKSW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Playing on a phone might not be ideal if you’re a more competitive racer&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="65DBCz"&gt;Playing &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; on a phone might not be ideal if you’re a more competitive racer. I fully admit that I play the game in a pretty relaxed way; I rarely veer from the driving line, generally play against AI cars on the average difficulty, make liberal use of the rewind feature, and often move on from a race after a couple tries if I can’t get on the podium. I haven’t raced against other players online. If I did that while playing on my phone, I don’t think I’d keep up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aZpmrr"&gt;But as games keep getting bigger, having a portable way to play and achievable goals to accomplish is more useful than ever. Part of the magic of &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; on the Nintendo Switch was how well it worked in both long and short sessions in TV or portable mode, and I’m glad to see games like &lt;em&gt;Forza&lt;/em&gt; offer a similar level of flexibility. So much about the game’s design lends itself well to short bursts of mobile gameplay, and its addictive cycle works no matter what screen I’m playing it on. (And since &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; will also be available on Steam, it could be an excellent showcase for the Steam Deck.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QmxPXL"&gt;Microsoft will probably never actually make a handheld Xbox, but at this point, it doesn’t have to. If you have a phone and a controller that can connect to it, games like &lt;em&gt;Forza&lt;/em&gt; become perfect portable experiences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u1WCjL"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launches November 9th on Xbox Series X / S, Xbox One, and PC. If you buy the Premium Edition or Premium Add-Ons Bundle, you can play the game starting November 5th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cPiARe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762183/forza-horizon-5-perfect-portable-xbox-game-series-x-s-pc-steam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762183/forza-horizon-5-perfect-portable-xbox-game-series-x-s-pc-steam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T01:47:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T01:47:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on 4K TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Frame TV 2018" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wa_2Uod8BhL5yZpxdXG9OqwpXuc=/0x699:4194x3495/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151213/2018_2_The_Frame_Lifestyle_Image_Assets_20.10.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Frame, Samsung’s art-like QLED TV, is on sale at Amazon right now for $998.&lt;/em&gt; | Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pYdAAO"&gt;There are a lot of 4K TVs available to choose from, complete with a wide variety of prices and performance. And, with many fall sales currently underway, now might be the best time of the year to get an amazing TV deal. Even if your budget is less than $500, you can get a good 4K TV in a bigger size than you might expect. Whether you want a secondary TV for the bedroom or a high-end OLED that’s built for a cinema-like experience, we’ve picked out the best TV deals across four common categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tf9rXR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl#f9MF2Z"&gt;The best 4K TV deals for most people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eeM2RN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl#EYhbja"&gt;The best TV deals on a budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vzRoT0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl#qm44jO"&gt;The best deals on OLED TVs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mlO4U5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl#O5Vjam"&gt;4K TVs for the PlayStation and Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="d2lRkA"&gt;Note: We provide regular updates to this post so be sure to check back periodically for the most up-to-date info on the best deals available. Additionally, with &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/17Ih9j_mVq66uudw8qbC59JZZUPFy0hUevLFqEUvlyfw/edit#gid=0"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday&lt;/a&gt; now just on the horizon, we’ve gathered some of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;best early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt; you can cash in on, which include a handful of our favorite 4K TVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="MLgUIb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best TV to buy for the PS5 and Xbox Series X","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="f9MF2Z"&gt;The best 4K TV deals for most people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mszLRr"&gt;A 55-inch TV is a popular size for good reason. It’s not too big, nor is it too small, making it a safe size if you’re looking to upgrade the TV in a living room or bedroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3LwO3"&gt;Sony’s 55-inch X80J TV has Google TV software built-in, so you won’t need to purchase any additional streaming boxes, like an Apple TV or Chromecast. The LED panel also supports HDR10, HLG, and Dolby Vision HDR, and has four HDMI ports (one of which is HDMI ARC). It’s a relatively low-frills affair, but it seems like a good deal that’s currently available at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1743620079563082108" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-X80J-Inch-Compatibility-KD55X80J/dp/B08QXFT4M9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $650, the TV’s best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gEtknI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10610217"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JbaBai"&gt;The TCL 6-Series R635 model is a good option if you are looking to balance price and performance. The R635 model sports a QLED panel, but it goes a step above with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363318/tcl-2020-5-6-series-4k-tvs-qled-mini-led-backlighting-gaming-ps5-xbox-series-x" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mini LED backlighting&lt;/a&gt;, which brings better brightness and contrast. The 55-inch model is currently on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0885F5GMP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for $700&lt;/a&gt;, though, we’ve seen slightly better discounts on the R635 in the past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Osz4r"&gt;If you prefer a larger model, Amazon and Best Buy are also selling the 65- and 75-inch variants. Both retailers are offering the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfLCtSSCCCU" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch for $1,000&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVnwOsusm3" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;75-inch for $1,300&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y8BpYm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10327662"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kuUEp8"&gt;Samsung’s The Frame blends into your home decor, displaying customizable images that look like a piece of decorative art if its motion sensor detects someone in the room. When turned on, however, it transforms into an HDR-compatible QLED TV with Amazon’s Alexa built-in and support for AirPlay 2. The stylish, 4K TV also boasts a 120Hz refresh rate, access to all the popular streaming services, and four HDMI ports. Right now, the 55-inch model is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-55-Inch-Class-Frame-Built/dp/B08VWPBBTF/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfLCWIlxESJ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy for around $1,000&lt;/a&gt;, a healthy $500 less than its regular $1,500 price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JD5CqS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10711541"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EYhbja"&gt;The best TV deals on a budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zWYgij"&gt;You don’t have to spend a fortune for a 4K TV; spending $500 or less can still net you a TV with good image quality and features. Insignia’s 4K HDR Fire TV Edition model is the perfect case in point, one that supports HDR10, HDMI ARC, and HDMI eArc, among other notable features. Right now, you can pick up the 55-inch model from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-New-Insignia-NS-55F301NA22-Smart-Released/dp/B08X7KQQGJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748188127423432886" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy for $370&lt;/a&gt;, a $180 discount on what is its typical $550 price tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jIOPJT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10605845"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cW4VPC"&gt;Another Fire TV Edition TV deal happening now is on Toshiba’s 50-inch Smart Fire TV Edition 4K LED, which normally retails for $500. As the name might imply, it allows you to stream content from services such as Disney Plus and Netflix, and includes the option to watch live TV. The latest models also tout an Alexa-enabled remote, an easy-to-use interface, and support for both Dolby Vision HDR and HDR10. Right now at Amazon, you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Toshiba-55-inch-4K-UHD-Smart-Fire-TV/dp/B0924XSHB2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50-inch model for $370&lt;/a&gt;, nearly matching its best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="x443tm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10444802"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="74eOSC"&gt;TCL also has competitively priced televisions, and its 4-Series lineup is one of the more affordable options on the market. The S435 model features a built-in Roku interface, dual-band Wi-Fi, HDR10, and support for all Alexa, Google Assistant, and Siri. You can currently get the 55-inch model for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/TCL-4K-Smart-LED-43S435/dp/B08GWBBH4R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$380 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is $221 less than the usual retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HtnMEi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9740197"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="9H3H8m"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 40,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="qm44jO"&gt;The best deals on OLED TVs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vbJRlM"&gt;OLED televisions offer the best image quality you can get in a mainstream TV. LG’s BX line also supports HDMI 2.1, meaning this TV is perfect for people looking to take advantage of the PS5 or Xbox Series X. You can currently get it in either a 55-, 65-, or 75-inch configuration and save up to $500, depending on the size. The popular 65-inch model is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Ftvs%2Flg-oled65bxpua-oled-4k-tv&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22371561%2Fbest-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently discounted to $1,800 at LG&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-OLED65BXPUA-Alexa-Built-Ultra/dp/B0829RMHCM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, $500 off the normal retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OMVgrF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733758"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MB8PX4"&gt;Despite the high price tag, LG’s Gallery Series GX OLED is a good TV for those looking for a more cinematic experience. It includes support for Google Assistant and Alexa, and for those who want to use their TV for gaming, it features Nvidia G-Sync and HDMI 2.1 support, meaning it can take full advantage of the RTX 30-series cards or Sony’s and Microsoft’s next-gen gaming consoles. Right now, you can get the 55-inch for as low as &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1555065-REG%2Flg_oled55gxpua_gxpua_55_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22371561%2Fbest-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,647 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, or for a few dollars more at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1744656950369633474" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1555068-REG%2Flg_oled65gxpua_gxpua_65_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22371561%2Fbest-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch model is also available at B&amp;amp;H Photo for $2,197&lt;/a&gt;, or at &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Flg-oled-gx-65%2Fp%2F16C-000P-004G0" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg for $2,296,&lt;/a&gt; a savings of more than $1,200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lpiA85"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10445785"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nGYSCL"&gt;Vizio’s 55-inch OLED is a Best Buy exclusive. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVB68Xg6uj" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can currently get it for $1,000&lt;/a&gt; — a price that seems to come around every few months —and it remains one of the more affordable options available if you’re looking for 55-inch OLED. Vizio doesn’t have the same kind of experience in the OLED playing field as LG, sure, but it’s a great deal if you want a high-end viewing experience and HDMI 2.1 ports to display high frame rates from your PS5 or Xbox Series X. The 65-inch model is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVCblSKnxi" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;also available at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, if you prefer a larger size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q8lGs4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10462603"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="O5Vjam"&gt;4K TVs for the Sony PS5 and Microsoft Xbox Series X &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xr7I2E"&gt;Sony’s PS5 and Microsoft’s Xbox Series X can play 4K games with HDR at up to 120 frames per second. So, naturally, if you don’t have a TV that takes full advantage of your console, it might be time to upgrade to one of our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recommendations&lt;/a&gt;. For the best experience, you’ll want a TV that supports HDMI 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Nkhmv"&gt;Deals on those picks are scarce right now, however, there’s one happening on LG’s CX series of TVs, which include support for Nvidia’s G-Sync and AMD’s FreeSync adaptive sync technologies, as well as a low 1ms response time. The big difference between the CX and the cheaper BX model mentioned above is the CX line has slightly better brightness, which is better for HDR content. It’s currently available in three sizes: 55, 65, and 77 inches. Right now, there's a small $75 discount available on the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVowrPgJjE" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch model at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and a $300 discount &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVCmbeDxyh" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available on the 77-inch configuration&lt;/a&gt;, bringing them down to $1,425 and $3,000, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="F5GsVe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9534696"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BfJNcm"&gt;If you’re looking for an even more impressive TV, we recommend turning your attention to LG’s C1 line. Like its predecessor, the CX, the 4K C1 touts support for Nvidia G-Sync and AMD Freesync technologies, along with a 120Hz refresh rate and low input lag. The main difference between the two is that the C1 is available in an 83-inch variant and features a better processor. It also utilizes a newer interface that makes good use of a settings pane dubbed “Game Optimizer,” which conveniently brings together a host of game-centric settings — refresh rate, latency, etc. — for quicker access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkH38i"&gt;If you’re interested in all the bells and whistles that come with the C1, the 55-inch model is on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WFV7L3N/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747318067989758928" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; with six months of HBO Max for around $1,300, one of the lowest prices to date on the excellent OLED. You can also pick up the smaller, 48-inch model for around $1,100 at the same retailers (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WFK81RH/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747323256242351544" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;), as well as the 65-, 77-, and 83-inch variants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IrDSVn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10618444"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bn523S"&gt;For a viable OLED alternative — one that’s currently seeing a rare discount — there’s the Neo QLED QN90A. Unlike the LG models above, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309077/samsung-2021-8k-4k-tvs-now-available-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s most recent flagship&lt;/a&gt; uses Mini LED backlighting, a technology that allows for better contrast, less “blooming” around white objects on a dark background, and brightness levels that outperform even the best OLED TVs. Like the C1, the QN90A is also built with gamers in mind. The 2021 model features an HDMI 2.1 port and a “Game Bar” that gives you the ability to quickly adjust your screen’s aspect ratio, monitor input lag, and check to ensure settings such as HDR and VRR are active, all of which make for a better gaming experience overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TYqOuE"&gt;We don’t often see discounts on the QN90A, however, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748274080574733405" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08V3W4YXJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; are both currently offering the 55-inch model for about $1,500, the best price we’ve seen on the stunning QLED. There are also varying discounts available on the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08YPBJ2T8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50-&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08V39W74P/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;75-&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08V3B227H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;85-inch configurations&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4gR7Wz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10462562"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="Wy7BiA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OGJPin"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-04T00:30:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T00:30:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Kindle deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_0jG4qDGtvO2-VxvVC5PUlh1ldA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67715739/akrales_181101_3056_0132.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2018 Kindle Paperwhite might not be the newest model, but it’s available for $40 off.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AZCNr8"&gt;When it comes to finding a device to use to read your ebooks, you have a few options to choose from. You can always buy a tablet or use your smartphone, but those devices are multipurpose and can be used for a ton of things, like surfing the web or doom-scrolling on Twitter. If you are looking for something to strictly read books, e-readers, while niche, are designed to store all of your books in a virtual library with limited functionality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDKHVT"&gt;Amazon, one of the pioneers of the e-reader, has dominated the space for years with its Kindle lineup, which consists of several unique models with their own pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2UeWxe"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each model currently available for purchase. Sometimes, there isn’t a deal for one, or any, of the products, which is why we’ve mentioned the most recent sale price in those instances. Additionally, while newer models like the 2021 Kindle Paperwhite are currently only available for full price, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday&lt;/a&gt; are right around the corner, a time when Amazon historically discounts its e-reader lineup. The retailer also offers 20 percent off all of its Kindles when you trade in select devices, so there are still other ways to save money when none of the models are available at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hittMf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s older Kindles will start to lose their internet access in December","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598747/kindle-3g-network-shutdown-e-readers-no-internet"},{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="r36wrm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10741941"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jqPttv"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/4/10/18302177/amazon-kindle-base-model-low-resolution-screen-backlight-review"&gt;Kindle (10th-gen)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="mXAcFi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10363966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hfprjz"&gt;This is Amazon’s most affordable e-reader, and as such, it usually retails for $90. Released in 2019, the base Kindle includes a front light, 8GB of storage, and comes with or without ad support. Despite including the same 167ppi resolution as its predecessors, the latest base Kindle features a slightly higher contrast than earlier models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIAlEv"&gt;Right now, you can buy a 10th-gen Kindle with lock screen ads for $50 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VT322X/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfxG6j9qO2d" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, which knocks $40 off the original MSRP. If you want one without ads, you can grab it for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VZV5VB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$70 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. If you buy either Kindle model at Amazon, you’ll also receive three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTnhuW"&gt;If you want to save some money on additional accessories for the e-reader, Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentials-including-Amazon-Printed-Adapter/dp/B08C6NDPFM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Essentials Bundle&lt;/a&gt; is $80 ($55 off its usual price) at Amazon; it includes one of three printed covers and a power adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RkX3DN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ze80m8"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/10/7/20902588/kindle-kids-edition-amazon-bundle-young-e-reader-case-replacement-program-freetime" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Kids Edition (2019)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JypT34"&gt;The entry-level Kindle and Oasis models were not the only ones that received a refresh in 2019. Amazon also announced and released a Kindle Kids Edition Bundle, which provides age-appropriate content for younger readers who prefer digital books for $110 ($20 more than the base Kindle at standard MSRP). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LlYfl"&gt;The Kindle Kids Edition consists of five items: the device, a case, a two-year extended replacement guarantee (in the event the device breaks), and one year of Amazon Kids Plus service. The latter is the biggest selling point of the device aside from the kid-friendly patterns, as it allows parents to grant their kids access to a digital library of kid-friendly books like &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Hobbit &lt;/em&gt;at no additional cost. Right now it’s available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07NMY72SC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746224890339507137" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3DEvBp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552664"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="iYO8oT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"},{"title":"Here are the best Amazon Echo deals right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21546591/best-amazon-echo-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="t6m9om"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22745670/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2021-review-usb-c-signature-edition-display-e-reader-books" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (2021)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="deHMlR"&gt;Amazon’s latest Kindle Paperwhite is its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684801/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-features-price-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11th-gen model&lt;/a&gt;, which comes with USB-C support, longer battery life, and a larger, 6.8-inch display. Given just how recently the new e-reader launched, however, we haven’t seen any discounts yet. Thankfully, you can still pick up the last-gen model, which is frequently available for far less than the standard retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FkwzBt"&gt;The 2021 Kindle Paperwhite comes in three main configurations: an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08KTZ8249/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB model with ads for $140&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N38WQSH/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB without ads for $160&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08B495319/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB Signature Edition for $190&lt;/a&gt;. The latter is identical to the standard Paperwhite, except it also features Qi wireless charging and a sensor that will automatically adjust the backlight when needed. Amazon has also rolled out a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WPB8PW9/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Paperwhite Kids Edition for $159&lt;/a&gt;, which comes bundled with a kid-friendly cover, a two-year extended replacement guarantee, and a year of Amazon Kids Plus, much like the aforementioned Kindle Kids Edition. All 2021 models are also similar to the 2018 model in that they feature a waterproof design and Audible audiobook support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XEYFbp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10765216"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="iorwh0"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (2018)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UaH6Zy"&gt;While there currently are no price breaks on the 2021 Kindle Paperwhite — save for the 20 percent off you can get with an eligible trade-in — Amazon has drastically lowered the price of the 2018 model. Currently, you can pick up the 8GB Kindle Paperwhite with ad support for $90 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PQ96B6B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfxHjGSDlV6" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PTCW9G7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ad-free edition at Amazon for $110&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more space, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PP49ZDW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfxHnfba6HB#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are also selling the 32GB Paperwhite with ads for $85. Just like with the base Kindle, Amazon is even running a promotion where you can grab the e-reader and three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Emeowb"&gt;If you don’t mind paying for a leather case and a power adapter, Amazon is also currently discounting its Kindle Paperwhite Essentials Bundle, which includes either an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HL49FCK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB e-reader for $170&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HKT4M5K/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB reader with ads for $200&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re a fan of Suzanne Collins’ Hunger Games trilogy, Amazon also offers a bundle that includes a Kindle Paperwhite, a power adapter, and a Mockingjay-emblazoned cover. It’s currently available in two ad-supported configurations and colors: an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NMH2F7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB version for $160&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NM77FC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $190&lt;/a&gt;, both of which save you $20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vOUHwk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552401"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X5jbTU"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707619/amazon-kindle-oasis-2019-e-reader-review-price-specs-features-display" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Oasis (third-gen)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IByP4u"&gt;The Kindle Oasis is the most expensive of the lineup, starting at $250. The device comes in two storage configurations, 8GB or 32GB, and like the other models, you can get it with or without ads on the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AvXZM"&gt;The 2019 Kindle Oasis looks very similar to the previous model. It retains its waterproof, 7-inch, 300ppi E Ink display and supports Audible audiobooks via Bluetooth. However, unlike previous models, it can adjust the color temperature to a yellow-toned display, making it easier to read at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxP7sb"&gt;In the past, we have seen the 32GB Kindle Oasis drop to as low as $200, which is the lowest it has ever been for that configuration to date. While there are currently no deals on just the Oasis itself, configurations start at $250 at Amazon and include three free months of Kindle Unlimited. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VHV8D7P?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB, ad-supported Oasis&lt;/a&gt; is $250 and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VDMJJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one without ads is $270&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more storage, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VCMJSLB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB version is $280 with ads&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VGTRMFS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 without&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuGlPY"&gt;Amazon is currently offering an Essentials Bundle for $30 off its normal list price, too. You can get either the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RNPKRKW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB, ad-supported configuration for $290&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RW2K1MD/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $310&lt;/a&gt;, both of which come with a leather cover, a power adapter, and three months of Kindle Unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hPPu8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552599"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4mZNi9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T22:25:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T22:25:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo releases Animal Crossing’s big 2.0 update early</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8l7XandWtxAb8T0yqwTnqLwVwBY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70089956/20211015_ACNH_Update_scrn_009.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3DnJ1X"&gt;The major 2.0 update for &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; is now available to download, which is somewhat surprising because Nintendo previously said it wouldn’t be released until November 5th. That means you’ll be able to dive into all the new features two days earlier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McAWlp"&gt;The free 2.0 update was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727354/animal-crossing-switch-update-date"&gt;announced last month&lt;/a&gt; in a Nintendo Direct presentation. It includes a ton of expanded functionality including new house exterior designs, boat tours to other islands, more item, storage, a “pro” camera mode, the ability to cook food with grown ingredients, and more. Perhaps the most anticipated addition is Brewster’s coffee shop, a notable omission from the base game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oZEjGC"&gt;In addition to the free update Nintendo announced a $24.99 expansion called &lt;em&gt;Happy Home Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, but as of writing it’s not yet accessible in-game — though the eShop still lists it for pre-load. Access to the extra paid content will also be included with the Nintendo Switch Online “expansion pack” that features N64 and Sega Genesis games, but it isn’t available to subscribers of that service yet either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rqTgFK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; is the second best-selling game on the Nintendo Switch after &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 8 Deluxe&lt;/em&gt;. As of June 30th, Nintendo had sold 33.89 million copies.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762709/animal-crossing-2-0-update-released-early-nintendo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762709/animal-crossing-2-0-update-released-early-nintendo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T20:25:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T20:25:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos’ voice assistant might work alongside Alexa but not the Google Assistant</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x_CczH8d6MQ1TT8aHr2aZNPvB-M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70089129/RoamKitchen.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sonos Roam.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OdnWVV"&gt;When Sonos purchased a privacy-focused voice assistant Snips &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20975607/sonos-buys-snips-ai-voice-assistant-privacy"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, it strongly implied that it planned to build an assistant that would “add to our customers’ ease of use and control” instead of going head-to-head with bigger assistants from other big tech companies. Nearly two years later, we might be close to being using the company’s homegrown assistant, as a Reddit user found &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sonos/comments/ql8u3t/sonos_voice_assistant_references_in_the_app/"&gt;code in the Sonos app&lt;/a&gt; that appears to show voice commands for Sonos Voice Control (&lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/sonos-voice-control-assistant-leak"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BwD5kS"&gt;According to the code strings, you’ll be able to do things like play and pause music, adjust the volume, and check your Sonos’ battery. The Reddit user also found what looks to be the logo for Sonos’ assistant and evidence suggesting you’ll be able to have it assistant enabled alongside Amazon’s Alexa but &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; alongside the Google Assistant. You can see the icons in the images below (Sonos’ voice assistant icon looks remarkably similar to the one for Alexa). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b7L8kcvmOi6PEXlsRrMUgQS1tR4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22984247/6llt3anxq7x71.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sonos/comments/ql8u3t/sonos_voice_assistant_references_in_the_app/" target="_blank"&gt;u/michary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sonos’ icon (left) and Amazon’s Alexa icon (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qEp-_0png-2LyYHfF-rOeinUyhI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22984249/o80z0dpxq7x71.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sonos/comments/ql8u3t/sonos_voice_assistant_references_in_the_app/" target="_blank"&gt;u/michary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s Sonos’ icon next to the Google Assistant icon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AkcCbF"&gt;This isn’t the first clue that a Sonos-made voice assistant might be imminent: the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623470/sonos-survey-voice-assistant-google-fight"&gt;posted a survey&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year regarding a “potential new product offering” called (you guessed it!) Sonos Voice Control. According to the survey, to activate the assistant, you’d just have to say “Hey Sonos,” and all commands would be processed locally on the device. Sonos Voice Control and Alexa would work on the same speaker, the survey said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EIH5F"&gt;Sonos is also locked in a legal battle with Google, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055048/sonos-google-lawsuit-sues-speakers-assistant-amazon"&gt;suing the search giant in January 2020&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly copying its speaker tech. In addition, Sonos also says that Google is standing in the way of letting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700724/sonos-smart-speakers-concurrency-google"&gt;Alexa and Google Assistant be used side by side&lt;/a&gt; on Sonos speakers. By making its offering its own voice assistant, Sonos might be able to let customers have multiple assistants at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWqjjk"&gt;“We don’t comment on rumor or speculation but as we have stated previously, our team is working on ways to improve the voice control experience on Sonos,” a company spokesperson said to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UKYTHe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LVhDuk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762436/sonos-voice-control-assistant-amazon-alexa-google-assistant"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762436/sonos-voice-control-assistant-amazon-alexa-google-assistant</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T19:06:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T19:06:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Take-Two spent $53 million on a cancelled game that was never even announced</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Mafia 3" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHX1C7VTQzQkVf1DNShDzhBilV8=/144x0:1776x1088/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088760/mafia-3-screen-1.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lBHezO"&gt;Nestled in Take-Two Interactive’s &lt;a href="https://ir.take2games.com/news-releases/news-release-details/take-two-interactive-software-inc-reports-strong-results-19"&gt;most recent earnings repor&lt;/a&gt;t was information that it was charged $53 million dollars for an unannounced title that has been cancelled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VBPThl"&gt;“Cost of goods sold included a $53 million impairment charge related to the Company’s decision not to proceed with further development of an unannounced title in its pipeline,” Take-Two said in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8jZ6iu"&gt;The report did not name the title nor the affiliated studio that worked on it. However, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-03/take-two-s-2k-cancels-53-million-game-from-developer-hangar-13"&gt;according to a &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt;, the cancelled title is from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/16/12500338/mafia-3-preview-pc-ps4-xbox"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mafia III&lt;/em&gt; developer Hangar 13&lt;/a&gt;. The California-based developer also released the &lt;em&gt;Mafia: Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qxDxJc"&gt;The Bloomberg report says that according to sources at the studio, the game was codenamed Volt and suffered from a number of setbacks associated with the pandemic and  constantly shifting development focus. No word yet on if the company will suffer layoffs as a result of the cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6JRTEK"&gt;The cancelled game wasn’t the only bad news to come out of Take-Two’s earnings report. Earlier today, Firaxis Games announced &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/midnightsuns/status/1455989461309820931"&gt;it’s delaying its Marvel title, &lt;em&gt;Midnight Suns&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; until the second half of 2022. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641590/midnight-suns-marvel-tactics-rpg-xcom-firaxis-trailer-release-date-gamescom"&gt;card-based &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt;-like&lt;/a&gt; was originally scheduled for a March 2022 release date.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762349/take-two-cancelled-unannounced-title-from-hangar-13"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762349/take-two-cancelled-unannounced-title-from-hangar-13</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T18:57:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T18:57:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Notability blinks on charging users more, grandfathers in existing users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PYSoLvzQzl5LXrX48tgegzA6ZpI=/240x0:933x462/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088692/1_iEH2dk4j_BQBsS4oYrXZZQ.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Notability | Image: Notability Blog&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ojGp12"&gt;Notability developer Ginger Labs &lt;a href="https://notability.medium.com/pricing-updates-815f01f6df51"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; today that, in a change of heart, its popular note-taking app wouldn’t eventually require current users to switch to a subscription model. This news comes just two days after the developer announced a new subscription model where current app owners who wanted to keep the same features would be forced to start a $14.99 / month subscription by November 1st, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXl9EF"&gt;Notability rolled back its &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/notability-is-now-a-free-app-301412586.html"&gt;original&lt;/a&gt; Monday pricing announcement and today &lt;a href="https://notability.medium.com/updates-to-notability-11-0-subscription-9f03a28a06f7"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; an update on its company blog addressing current customers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="H08sIp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone who purchased Notability prior to our switch to subscription on November 1st, 2021 will have lifetime access to all existing features and any content previously purchased in the app.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4P0BCG"&gt;This means that current paid users will not have to pay for the new subscription plan after updating to the new 11.0 version. They also get to retain features that new &lt;a href="https://notability.com/pricing"&gt;free-tier&lt;/a&gt; users won’t have access to, including iCloud sync, unlimited editing, and features purchased in the Notability shop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_La9P3WC4OTnskid7S4OxRKyBW4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983934/Screen_Shot_2021_11_03_at_5.15.10_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Notability&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notability subscription tiers as of November 1st, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qgefJL"&gt;These swift changes come after backlash from many long-time users sharing their disdain for the new subscription model. While the company acknowledged its mistake and profusely apologized to its customers in its blog, the reason may be less than genuine. According to &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/11/03/notability-subscription-broke-app-store-rules/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; the change may be due to a violation of Apple’s App Store guidelines. In the App Store review guidelines, a &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/#business"&gt;clause&lt;/a&gt; in section 3.1.2(a) explains that current paid customers must retain all functionality of the app that they paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6MRwdI"&gt;Note-taking app developers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/28/12052056/evernote-price-changes-basic-plus-premium"&gt;changing around pricing&lt;/a&gt; is nothing new, and Evernote is a great example of a popular app that recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589210/evernote-update-productivity-plans"&gt;complicated&lt;/a&gt; its subscription models. Evernote and Notability going subscription may mean more revenue. However, it also puts existing customers in a precarious situation where they may decide to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18264368/evernote-notes-how-to-move-migrate-onenote-zoho-notebook-simplenote"&gt;migrate&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere. At least one other developer today may be taking advantage of Notability’s slip-up, with GoodNotes 5 now discounted to $3.99 from $7.99.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761662/notability-notes-ginger-labs-subscription-rollback-apology"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761662/notability-notes-ginger-labs-subscription-rollback-apology</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:50:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:50:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku is booting Pornhub and cutting off other private channels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NlW4pCHF6GHhhgVB1O0_lw-99Cw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088430/cwelch_20210428_4565_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PppaZ0"&gt;After Roku announced last week that it will soon remove non-certified channels from its service, it appears the change will close a loophole that allowed apps like Pornhub to exist on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4TtmUU"&gt;The company announced last week that it would be removing so-called “non-certified channels” by March of 2022. The change comes as Roku &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753332/roku-independent-developer-kit-idk"&gt;introduces new tools&lt;/a&gt; for developers, including a new independent developer kit that operates separately from its primary software developer kit for commercial-use channels. It also announced that it’s launching new beta testing capabilities that will allow app makers to run tests on their apps before making the changes live on the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C7YpMO"&gt;The independent developer kit will allow developers to tinker with and customize their Roku experience for personal use, such as by developing games that work with the Roku remote or connecting their Roku devices to their smart home gadgets. Roku says these changes are about aligning its platform with industry-standard approaches and development tools used by other companies. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RP1lpsv3vNmdHBngsPTqbnfV7pA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983927/Screen_Shot_2021_11_03_at_1.42.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge/Roku&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A warning sign shown to users when they add a non-certified channel on Roku.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UmIj8l"&gt;But with these changes, Roku has opted to pull “non-certified channels” that were previously used by developers for testing. These channels aren’t available in the Roku channel store because, as the company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week, they are, in “most cases,” used for testing channels ahead of their launch on Roku. In a statement, a spokesperson said this week that because of its recently announced changes, these non-certified channels “are no longer necessary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLCmoj"&gt;It’s not clear how many non-certified channels will be removed as a result of the change, and the company declined to comment when asked by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week. But it’s expected to impact several adult entertainment apps that could be added to Roku &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/nsfw/how-to-install-adult-time/"&gt;with unique codes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/workplace/intel-wont-mandate-vaccines"&gt;reported this week&lt;/a&gt; that beyond Pornhub, the change is expected to impact other private channels like Adult Time and Wicked, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CqEIob"&gt;Users who attempt to sideload channels this way are shown warning messages that the platform “does not test or review non-certified channels” and that some content may be “offensive or inappropriate for some audiences.” Additionally, Roku warns, these channels may be removed at any time, and a user’s account may be blocked from adding other non-certified channels if it determines that the channel in question contains illegal content or otherwise violates its terms. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762236/pornhub-roku-private-channels-march-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762236/pornhub-roku-private-channels-march-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:50:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:50:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alexa’s October updates let your music follow you around the house</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eBwvUEqhaYPfjg_6M-CxUdqhfLI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088428/dseifert_201020_4247_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4csScd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b/?node=23657445011"&gt;Alexa’s October update&lt;/a&gt; introduces a number of new helpful commands that let you start listening to audio in one room and continue listening on an Echo device in another. There are a few different commands for this, and the ones you use will depend on your situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1lSJh"&gt;The first command lets you move audio between groups, also known as the smart speakers that you’ve assigned to specific locations throughout your home. Simply say, “Alexa, move my music to [desired group],” and you can transfer your podcast, radio show, or music to the room that you plan on spending time in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYVvJs"&gt;You can also continue listening to audio when you walk out the door — keep in mind that you’ll need a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; in order for this to work. Once your Echo Buds are connected to your phone, say, “Alexa move my music here,” and the audio will continue playing on your earbuds when you walk out the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5u6OiM"&gt;There’s another way to have your audio follow you throughout your house, but you’ll have to pause your music to do so. Just say “Alexa, pause” to the Echo device playing audio, and then say “Alexa, resume music here” to the Echo device you want to use. You can use the same commands when you want to resume your music in your car as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4vqUh5"&gt;This is a major improvement, considering that &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/amazonecho/comments/j03gzj/anyone_ever_managed_to_get_music_thats_playing_in/"&gt;users have asked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D54P00006zSvfz/continue-or-move-music-to-another-device"&gt;Amazon to add a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D54P00006zSoh6/pause-play-in-one-room-resume-in-another"&gt;feature that lets audio follow&lt;/a&gt; them throughout the house for years. It looks like Amazon is taking feedback into account, as these commands should finally provide a way to get seamless audio playback throughout your entire home.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762103/alexa-october-updates-music-follow-around-house"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762103/alexa-october-updates-music-follow-around-house</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:37:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:37:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s reportedly bidding to be a military cloud provider</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/twoFJe0CSEQLJKUfP1x-3US3m6M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088386/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZzoCzY"&gt;Google is reportedly “aggressively” working on winning a contract with the Pentagon, even though some of its previous Department of Defense work &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/4/17199818/google-pentagon-project-maven-pull-out-letter-ceo-sundar-pichai"&gt;sparked major backlash from employees&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/03/technology/google-pentagon-artificial-intelligence.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. According to the report, Google’s Cloud division has reassigned engineers to work on a proposal for Google to contribute to the Joint Warfighting Cloud Capability program, which &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/Releases/Release/Article/2682992/future-of-the-joint-enterprise-defense-infrastructure-cloud-contract/"&gt;the DoD describes&lt;/a&gt; as an attempt to “achieve dominance in both traditional and non-traditional warfighting domains.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SSXPpN"&gt;The contract Google is reportedly looking into is one that will open to multiple companies to submit proposals and do work for, and the DoD estimates it could be a multi-billion dollar project. In a &lt;a href="https://sam.gov/opp/54ce941a25a14932809b5d83ac52a09a/view"&gt;document describing what cloud providers will be expected to do&lt;/a&gt;, the DoD says that anyone hoping to win a contract will have to “enable access to crucial warfighting data” with a variety of classification levels (including Secret and Top Secret info). Additionally, the program requires that applicants be able to “provide advanced data analytics services that securely enable data-driven and timely decision-making at the tactical level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="K0aGyR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Googles AI ethics guidelines prevent it from working on AI-powered weapons&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ew7XM"&gt;Google says it has &lt;a href="https://ai.google/principles/"&gt;rules on how it can use AI with regards to the military&lt;/a&gt;, which it set after employee backlash. In 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/6/17086276/google-ai-military-drone-analysis-pentagon-project-maven-tensorfow"&gt;reports came out that&lt;/a&gt; Google was developing AI tech to analyze video captured by military drones as a part of the Pentagon’s Project Maven initiative. Thousands of employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17418406/google-maven-drone-imagery-ai-contract-expire"&gt;signed a letter to CEO Sundar Pichai&lt;/a&gt; saying that Google shouldn’t be involved in war and that the work put the company’s reputation at risk and went against its stated values. Eventually, the company gave in and said it would stop working on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1EeDt"&gt;After Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17418406/google-maven-drone-imagery-ai-contract-expire"&gt;told employees&lt;/a&gt; it would let its Project Maven contract expire, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/7/17439310/google-ai-ethics-principles-warfare-weapons-military-project-maven"&gt;announced its AI ethics principles&lt;/a&gt;, promising that it wouldn’t work on AI-powered weapons or AI surveillance projects that were likely to draw ire from human rights or privacy advocates. The company did, however, say it would continue working with the military “in many other areas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lcSyZR"&gt;At the time, Google said any Pentagon work it pursued would have to fit within those principles. At this point, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, it’s unclear whether what the DoD wants would be allowed under those guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YTZ5CE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google Cloud is still used by parts of the US military&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2oVEW"&gt;The company has continued to do work with the military since its pledge, with some projects involving AI. As the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reports, &lt;a href="https://www.googlecloudpresscorner.com/2020-08-27-Google-Cloud-and-STS-to-Automate-U-S-Navy-Maintenance-Inspections-Using-AI-and-ML-Technology"&gt;Google announced&lt;/a&gt; in August that its Cloud services would be used by a contractor to analyze footage from inspection drones to determine when Navy ships needed maintenance. The Air Force is &lt;a href="https://www.googlecloudpresscorner.com/2021-07-16-U-S-Air-Force-Rapid-Sustainment-Office-Partners-with-Google-Cloud-to-Solve-Its-Toughest-Sustainment-Challenges"&gt;also looking to use Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to help manage airplane maintenance. In a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Google spokesperson said that the company is “firmly committed to serving [its] public sector customers, including the DoD.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kkcABv"&gt;Obviously, military-related work isn’t completely off the table for Google, but given its history, it’s likely employees pay extra-close attention when the company is looking to work with the Pentagon. Google employees’ responses to Project Maven helped kick off organization within the company — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212347/google-employees-contractors-announce-union-cwa-alphabet"&gt;union organizers cited it&lt;/a&gt; as one of the collective actions that inspired unionization. The union has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlphabetWorkers/status/1455997325315231744?s=20"&gt;responded to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ story&lt;/a&gt; about the current work on the DoD bid on Twitter, pledging that workers will fight the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0xY3Dt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our working conditions include our ethical concerns. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Workers should have full transparency on the real world impacts of our labor AND our labor should not be used to perpetuate violence at home or abroad. &lt;a href="https://t.co/VD1KmjOxwL"&gt;https://t.co/VD1KmjOxwL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alphabet Workers Union (AWU-CWA) #Strikesgiving (@AlphabetWorkers) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlphabetWorkers/status/1455997325315231744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761961/google-military-cloud-services-bid-joint-warfighting-project-maven"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761961/google-military-cloud-services-bid-joint-warfighting-project-maven</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
