<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-30T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hyundai’s Ioniq 5 electric crossover will be Motional’s robotaxi</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UTkDECddoeNKC0MHQFBhv-lolyc=/0x343:8272x5858/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047584/Large_45011_HyundaiIONIQ5RedefinesElectricMobilityLifestyle.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0tI9mp"&gt;Lyft and Motional have selected the Hyundai Ioniq 5 for their forthcoming autonomous ride-hailing service. Motional, which is a joint venture between Aptiv and Hyundai, said the Ioniq 5 was chosen because it represents a “convergence of mobility’s two most transformative technologies — electrification and autonomy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8LD1HV"&gt;Motional hasn’t said how many vehicles it would acquire, nor where it will eventually deploy them for its robotaxi service. The company is currently testing its fleet of Chrysler Pacifica minivans in Las Vegas, where it is also running an autonomous ride-hailing service with Lyft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxyfp9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"&gt;The Ioniq 5 was first unveiled by Hyundai last month&lt;/a&gt;, and won’t go on sale until later this year. Also, the vehicle won’t hit public roads as part of Motional’s fleet until after they’ve been retrofitted with the company’s hardware and sensor suite, and then put through a months-long testing regime on both public roads and a private, closed testing course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="rpe58S"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“a convergence of mobility’s two most transformative technologies — electrification and autonomy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="57iiSY"&gt;The Ioniq 5 is said to have nearly 300 miles of range on a single charge and a two-way charging feature that Hyundai calls “vehicle-to-load,” which can supply up to 3.6kW of power. It will also be built on Hyundai’s new Electric-Global Modular Platform (E-GMP) that the automaker says will serve as the basis for an entire family of planned EVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yOj8yy"&gt;Motional is the latest AV company to commit to an electric vehicle as its primary platform. Cruise, a majority owned subsidiary of General Motors, uses Chevy Bolts exclusively.  Alphabet’s Waymo uses gas-powered Chrysler Pacificas while also phasing in a next-gen fleet of electric Jaguar I-Paces. Other companies, like Zoox, Nuro, and Aurora, have said they would use electric vehicles as part of their respective commercial services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PnSMyi"&gt;Motional as a joint venture was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hyundai-motor-autonomous-aptiv/hyundai-motor-group-aptiv-to-set-up-4-billion-self-driving-car-venture-idUSKBN1W80WP"&gt;first announced in March 2020&lt;/a&gt;, when Hyundai said it would spend $1.6 billion to catch up to its rivals in the autonomous vehicle space. Aptiv, a technology company formerly known as Delphi, owns 50 percent of the venture. The company currently has facilities in Las Vegas, Singapore, and Seoul, and has also tested its vehicles in Boston and Pittsburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qDMqaU"&gt;Motional’s engineers were responsible for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/25/12637822/self-driving-taxi-first-public-trial-singapore-nutonomy"&gt;the world’s first robotaxi pilot in Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the first cross-country &lt;a href="https://abc7.com/driverless-car-road-trip-san-francisco-new-york-city/568939/"&gt;New York to San Francisco autonomous trip&lt;/a&gt;. Over the last two years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/21/17718018/lyft-aptiv-self-driving-cars-las-vegas-5000-trips"&gt;Aptiv’s fleet of safety driver-monitored autonomous taxis in Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt; (in partnership with Lyft) have completed over 100,000 trips. And the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22291682/motional-fully-driverless-autonomous-cars-las-vegas"&gt;recently tested its vehicles&lt;/a&gt; with a monitor in the passenger seat but without one behind the steering wheel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0FhqcD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357224/motional-hyundai-ioniq-5-lyft-ev-robotaxi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357224/motional-hyundai-ioniq-5-lyft-ev-robotaxi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T07:44:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T07:44:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bang &amp; Olufsen’s luxurious gaming headset costs as much as an Xbox Series X</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bang &amp;amp;amp; Olufsen Beoplay Portal" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/acgpSV4m_zULPDxrXQXbu6mVG48=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047505/beoplayportallede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QAR3My"&gt;Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen has announced Beoplay Portal, its first wireless gaming headset. The product maintains the company’s signature sophisticated look, and it has more features than your average headset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3JDVa"&gt;These were created with the Xbox ecosystem in mind, and with a push of its pairing button, they can connect to the Series X, Series S, Xbox One, or to a PC that has the Xbox Wireless adapter plugged into it. Additionally, they support a concurrent connection via Bluetooth 5.1 for other devices (including other consoles if you supply the Bluetooth adapter). This way, you can take calls without totally detaching from game audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ORMeYt"&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439699/bose-quiet-comfort-35-ii-noise-canceling-gaming-headset-pc-bluetooth-price"&gt;Bose QC35 gaming headset&lt;/a&gt; that released last year, the Beoplay Portal look like high-end wireless headphones (and in many ways, act like them, too), and come with a high-end price. These cost $499 and are available now in the black colorway at Best Buy, the Microsoft Store, and through Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen’s site. Two other colors, gray and navy, will be available starting April 29th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Bang &amp;amp;amp; Olufsen Beoplay Portal" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qR429XcvqlDxfxzG3BG5dhcmdB8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22405333/beoplayportal2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Made for the contemplative gamer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="n1P1U7"&gt;This model has adaptive active noise cancellation (ANC) and a gaming audio mode that automatically activates when connected wirelessly to a console or when wired via USB-C to a PC (the port through which the headset also gets its charge). These also have a 3.5mm headphone jack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yswrXO"&gt;The Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen app for iOS and Android has some new features that the Beoplay Portal benefits from, like microphone optimization and a game / chat audio balance. The company reports that its “Own Voice” feature allows for voice monitoring while keeping out extraneous noises thanks to its adaptive ANC. These have 40mm drivers with Dolby Atmos support for virtualized surround sound.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Bang &amp;amp;amp; Olufsen app" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ls5aLalLmWjg0sJOoAryrVnwOoA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22405509/beoplayportalapp.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A peek at the Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen app’s controls for the Beoplay Portal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fcjrzL"&gt;Build quality is another area where Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen is trying to distinguish itself from other gaming headsets. The memory foam ear pads are wrapped in lambskin leather, and it uses bamboo fiber textile to cover the headband padding. Elsewhere, there are a few anodized aluminum details on the Portal, like the touch-sensitive discs on the outside of each ear cup that are used to control them. Impressively, the company says the headphones weigh 282 grams, which is lighter than the mostly plastic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review"&gt;Xbox Wireless Headset&lt;/a&gt; that, until now, I considered to be lightweight at 312g. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JDAUDA"&gt;This gaming headset can last up to 12 hours per charge when you’re connected through both Bluetooth and Xbox Wireless protocol, and using the active noise cancellation feature. If you’re just using Bluetooth and noise cancellation, Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen says you can expect up to 24 hours of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofcZ0D"&gt;Given the high asking price, I’m skeptical that these will be worth the cost for most people — especially those who intend to use them exclusively for gaming. It seems like a better value if you want to use them as your everyday headphones, too. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Bang &amp;amp;amp; Olufsen Beoplay Portal" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KoPeVSJd7_pM7kD3HCQ15r7QXZc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22405337/beoplayportal3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The gray colorway shown here won’t release until late April.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="b99dtL"&gt;I’m also skeptical about the “virtual boom arm” the Beoplay Portal employs instead of a traditional articulating boom mic. It says its beamforming microphones allow for “crystal clear” conversations, and help to amplify your voice while filtering out sounds in the background. This is something I’ll need to test to see if it’s as good as Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g8bPjG"&gt;Do you need a $500 gaming headset? Probably not. While there are plenty of differences in terms of features and build quality, most people should be suited well by Microsoft’s $100 Xbox Wireless headset. But I’ll be reviewing these to see for myself what five times that amount can get you in a gaming peripheral.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356352/bang-olufsen-beoplay-portal-gaming-headset-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356352/bang-olufsen-beoplay-portal-gaming-headset-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T07:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T07:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Virgin Galactic unveils new SpaceShip III</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-vinvb8XHqQcqLADago5s6oIZk=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047492/VSS_Imagine_004.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;VSS Imagine | Virgin Galactic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gBSb2V"&gt;Richard Branson’s space tourism firm Virgin Galactic &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UKiLv95mIVo"&gt;is unveiling&lt;/a&gt; a new space plane dubbed VSS Imagine on Tuesday, the first SpaceShip III addition to the company’s growing fleet of suborbital vehicles. It’s a shiny, chrome-colored ship designed for quicker reuse than SpaceShipTwo, the current centerpiece of the company’s effort to kickstart its space tourism business in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jtJ9Hi"&gt;“Imagine will be the first of our SpaceShip III’s to come join the fleet,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/virgin-galactic"&gt;Virgin Galactic&lt;/a&gt; CEO Michael Colglazier tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;“It will be followed up by Inspire, which we’re pivoting our manufacturing now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RgeOiP"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UKiLv95mIVo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8MzgFD"&gt;Functionally, SpaceShip III is the same as the company’s SpaceShipTwo, dubbed VSS &lt;em&gt;Unity&lt;/em&gt;. But SpaceShip III is designed in a “modular fashion” that will enable a quicker turnaround time for re-flights, Colglazier said. It’s designed in such a way “that we can pull a panel off to get to an area that we might not’ve been able to get to in an easy fashion before” with SpaceShipTwo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BuR9XS"&gt;VSS Imagine’s first glide test — dropping mid-air from its carrier plane to glide back to land — is poised for this summer at the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/30/21035125/virgin-galactic-spaceport-america-truth-or-consequences-new-mexico"&gt;Spaceport America facility in New Mexico.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HWDBoIuvlIMTNv1xior_3eD23uY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406864/VSS_IMAGINE_003.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Virgin Galactic&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;VSS Imagine’s backside&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="q0WRco"&gt;The design tweaks that give SpaceShip III a quicker refurb edge over SpaceShipTwo marks Virgin Galactic’s shift in focus to production-intensive operations, as the company readies for a debut customer flight at the beginning of 2022. The vehicle weighs slightly less than SpaceShipTwo, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/28/21340015/virgin-galactic-cabin-interior-unveil-passenger-seats-space-tourism"&gt;interior cabin&lt;/a&gt; might look a bit different. “Generally what we learned in Unity through flight tests got embedded in this SpaceShip III class,” Colglazier said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4CsRpI"&gt;The company’s next powered test flight of SpaceShipTwo will come sometime in May. That test has been delayed for months after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171114/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-powered-test-flight-abort-spaceport-america-new-mexico"&gt;December attempt was aborted mid-flight&lt;/a&gt;, just as the ship ignited its engines after being released mid-air from its mothership, VMS Eve. Company officials said last month in an earnings call that the abort was caused by electromagnetic interference that led to a reboot of a flight computer.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356889/virgin-galactic-unveils-new-spaceship-iii-three-3"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356889/virgin-galactic-unveils-new-spaceship-iii-three-3</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Polaris and Optimus Ride are co-developing ‘fully autonomous’ low-speed shuttles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1ixuF4-buzOFwo8laSxf1MxvMk4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047249/ahawkins_190804_3589_0009.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lutxqn"&gt;Autonomous shuttle startup Optimus Ride and power sports vehicle manufacturer Polaris are teaming up to co-develop a new lineup of vehicles that will be low-speed, electric, and self-driving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kOtDym"&gt;These low-speed vehicles (LSV) will be equipped with Optimus Ride’s full stack of sensors and software to enable “fully autonomous” driving without a safety driver behind the wheel — though the vehicles will also be monitored remotely by a team of engineers who can offer suggestions to the vehicle when things go wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZggu4"&gt;The vehicles, which can seat six, will be deployed as a last-mile transportation service in residential communities, corporate and academic campuses, and other “localized environments,” as both a fixed-route shuttle and a more dynamic, point-to-point ride-hailing service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mcZBGG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The vehicles will roll out in the first half of 2023&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0AihQS"&gt;The LSVs will be manufactured under the brand name GEM, which stands for Global Electric Motorcars. Minnesota-based Polaris owns GEM, having acquired it in 2011, and it’s also an investor in Optimus Ride. The startup, which originally spun out of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, currently uses GEM shuttles to test its autonomous technology in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanLinden/status/1376577813038370817"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt;, Boston, California, Washington, DC, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/7/18214536/optimus-ride-self-driving-cars-robot-taxi-brookfield-virginia"&gt;Northern Virginia&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCauEK"&gt;The vehicles, which will be rolled out in the first half of 2023, will be built without traditional controls like steering wheels and pedals, said Optimus Ride CEO Sean Harrington — although there will still be a way to move the vehicles manually. “The intention is we would have all six seats available for passengers,” Harrington told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, “which means where you have currently have a driver’s seat, would be another passenger seat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCYrvG"&gt;Harrington said the decision to co-develop vehicles with Polaris was about making a better autonomous vehicle and also scaling up production to the point where the startup can start to deploy potentially thousands of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yBM3Ms"&gt;“There’s just a lot more flexibility you have by custom-designing that vehicle with safety and performance built in from the ground up, as opposed to doing it sort of piecemeal,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6i_6P4kJTWlNItOHr7WELOokQzw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18842576/ahawkins_190804_3589_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KY1RWq"&gt;A dozen or so low-speed autonomous shuttle services have sprung up around the country in recent years. Experts see them as a good entry point for consumers into AV technology, while regulators and city officials like keeping the vehicles contained in small, less populated areas. Optimus Ride claims that it has completed “over 75,000 rides” over the last two years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4mmYvp"&gt;Optimus Ride isn’t the only company staking out a position in the low-speed autonomous shuttle space. Other companies, like May Mobility, Voyage (now owned by Cruise), and Local Motors, have launched small pilot projects in cities over the years — though they have yet to scale up to a fully operational commercial service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NU3qDF"&gt;Other AV operators, like Waymo, Zoox, and Cruise, are also interested in launching fully autonomous ride-hail operations. Harrington says that Optimus Ride can still be competitive with those companies, despite operating vehicles with a top speed of only 25 mph. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oaxrMp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is not some sort of virtual rails AV system”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GeXdPc"&gt;“To be clear, this is not some sort of virtual rails AV system where you get in an environment and if there’s an obstacle, if there’s something in your way, that vehicle can’t proceed,” he said. “This is a vehicle that is out in a fairly complex environment.” These limitations, Harrington said, position Optimus Ride to provide an autonomous transportation service “today, as opposed to many, many years from now.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ritYO"&gt;This kind of small-scale business can also be extremely difficult to get right. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18758820/drive-ai-self-driving-startup-shutting-down-apple"&gt;Drive.ai nearly went out of business before it got bought by Apple&lt;/a&gt;. And Navya, a major autonomous shuttle manufacturer based in France, is &lt;a href="https://www.thedrive.com/tech/29196/navya-pivots-away-from-experimental-autonomous-shuttle-business"&gt;pivoting away from the shuttle business&lt;/a&gt; in favor of licensing its software to third-party clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dd4chb"&gt;Polaris makes a variety of off-road vehicles, including the popular RZR lineup as well as garish three-wheelers like the Slingshot. It also owns Indian Motorcycle, which it acquired in 2011. The company recently announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21473587/polaris-zero-motorcycles-electric-ev-off-road-vehicle-snowmobiles"&gt;partnership with Zero Motorcycle&lt;/a&gt; to co-develop electric vehicles, including ATVs and snowmobiles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqUt5V"&gt;“I think this is the smart place for all of us to be betting on,” said Keith Simon, vice president and general manager of Polaris Commercial, “which is why we’re doing this and why we’re so excited about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356398/polaris-optimus-ride-av-ev-lsv-shuttle-announce"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356398/polaris-optimus-ride-av-ev-lsv-shuttle-announce</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>PayPal will let US users pay with Bitcoin, Ethereum and Litecoin starting today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Checkout with Crypto" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cG5Fz3G-px2aRA9nLEoJvMnRwPQ=/116x7:3157x2034/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047265/Checkout_with_Crypto_image.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: PayPal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FlSiSw"&gt;We already knew that PayPal was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527288/paypal-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-venmo-bitcoin"&gt;planning to support cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; as a form of payment. And now, the online payment app announced US customers can do just that with its “Checkout with Crypto” feature, rolling out today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9YDTb3"&gt;After rolling out the ability for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562771/paypal-cryptocurrency-buy-sell-bitcoin-ethereum-litecoin-us-users"&gt;US users to directly buy and sell cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; directly from their accounts last November, PayPal’s new “Checkout with Crypto” allows users to instantly convert their Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin, or Bitcoin Cash to US dollars (with no additional transaction fees) that PayPal then uses to complete the transaction. If a merchant doesn’t take US dollars, PayPal also converts those dollars into local currency at standard conversion rates set by PayPal. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tacC6RkjsT5OnQJh4ccW0FdHWsI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406834/paypal_crypto_screen.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PayPal will support several types of cryptocurrency, including Ethereum and Bitcoin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4OQuh2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;PayPal is not the first payment app to offer support for cryptocurrency&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="htM45Y"&gt;The feature will automatically appear in the PayPal wallet if a user has a “sufficient cryptocurrency balance to cover an eligible purchase,” and you’ll be able to see your crypto balances for each kind of coin in the app. However, you can only use one type of cryptocurrency for each purchase you make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aj1fUe"&gt;PayPal is not the first payment app to offer support for cryptocurrency. In 2018, its competitor, Square, launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17689156/square-cash-expands-bitcoin-support-to-all-50-us-states"&gt;support for Bitcoin on the Cash App&lt;/a&gt;. But the launch of cryptocurrency as a form of payment makes PayPal both a major digital wallet and a cryptocurrency exchange, which could streamline the use of cryptocurrency as a more common payment method. During its Investor Day last week, the company reported that it had &lt;a href="https://s1.q4cdn.com/633035571/files/doc_presentations/2021/02/PP-Investor-Day-2021-Combined-FINAL.pdf"&gt;377 million active accounts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="P59S0Z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PayPal will now let all users in the US buy and sell cryptocurrencies","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562771/paypal-cryptocurrency-buy-sell-bitcoin-ethereum-litecoin-us-users"},{"title":"PayPal and Venmo will offer and accept cryptocurrency for all online payments","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527288/paypal-cryptocurrency-support-buy-sell-venmo-bitcoin"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357246/paypal-buy-with-bitcoin-litecoin-ethereum-crypto-checkout"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357246/paypal-buy-with-bitcoin-litecoin-ethereum-crypto-checkout</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is making some big upgrades to directions in Google Maps </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x9WF8dXqqJRk_UfA_6dOKP-hX4w=/52x0:742x460/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047241/google_maps_ar_indoor.5.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YFqdYc"&gt;Google is announcing a bunch of new features planned for Google Maps, including a new tool to help with indoor navigation and suggestions for eco-friendly driving routes. The features announced today aren’t rolling out all at once, though; many aren’t available just yet, and it’s unclear when some will be available in some parts of the world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPB9oh"&gt;One of the biggest announcements is that Google is bringing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/8/20776247/google-maps-live-view-ar-walking-directions-ios-android-feature"&gt;Live View augmented reality&lt;/a&gt; directions to airports, transit stations, and malls. Live View directions let you hold your phone up, point your camera at the world around you, and see arrows and icons pointing you where you need to go, and previously, they only worked outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0uLR0p"&gt;Disappointingly, though, these indoor AR directions aren’t being rolled out very widely yet: they’re only available in some malls in Chicago, Long Island, Los Angeles, Newark, San Francisco, San Jose, and Seattle right now. Google will launch indoor Live View directions in select transit stations, airports, and malls in Tokyo and Zurich in the coming months, however, and more cities are “on the way,” the company says.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h5Xe48wt7uFBEOTfW93zUqQKZuQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406882/Indoor_Live_View_2.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pzxjze"&gt;Google is also planning to revamp the interface for picking your mode of transportation for directions on Android and iOS. Right now, you have to toggle through different tabs to see more detail about different transportation options, but with this new interface, you’ll just scroll through a list. The company says Maps will even be able to prioritize the modes you prefer and put those that are popular in certain cities (the subway in New York City, for example) higher up the list. This new interface is set to roll out globally in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V-u7roBXlCfB-vBnxAiMa5EIHCg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407035/New_directions_experience.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uOoQPl"&gt;In addition to the directions interface, Google is adding a new type of driving route that’s optimized for lower fuel consumption. If the eco-friendly route has about the same ETA as the fastest route to a location, Google Maps will default to the fuel-efficient route, though you can change this in settings if you’d like. Google plans to make these new fuel-efficient routes available on Android and iOS in the US later this year and globally at an unspecified time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1QOPIU5AYJnEusn3p_fEFx66JMk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407083/Eco_Friendly_Routes.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CRS9Dq"&gt;The fuel-efficient routes aren’t the only eco-friendly updates for Maps: Google also plans to introduce alerts that will tell you when you’ll be navigating through low-emissions zones, which don’t allow some vehicles with certain levels of emissions to enter. Google says these alerts will launch in France, Germany, the Netherlands, Spain, and the UK on Android and iOS this June. More countries will get the alerts soon, according to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SsU_C9fQM8NHnsqu1suy-zM8F_w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407087/Low_Emission_Zone.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google Maps&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C9PM9T"&gt;Google is also making new map layers for weather and air quality that are set to roll out in the coming months on Android and iOS. Google plans to launch the weather layer globally and launch the air quality layer first in Australia, India, and the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jGpfxbZrNmJ1QbE-iq9FEO8WQ4w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406900/Weather__Air_Quality_Layers.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fUOixM"&gt;Google also plans to pilot a new grocery pickup tool this summer with select Portland, Oregon-based locations of Kroger-owned grocery store Fred Meyer. The tool lets you share your location and ETA with the store via Google Maps so that your grocery order can be ready when you arrive. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357528/google-maps-directions-indoor-ar-live-view-fuel-efficient-weather-air-quality-layer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357528/google-maps-directions-indoor-ar-live-view-fuel-efficient-weather-air-quality-layer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The LF-Z concept shows just how far Lexus has to go in EVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U4KkETVvJL-u8lOlQ-Ibs3su338=/596x453:2185x1512/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047267/2021_Lexus_LFZ_0018.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Lexus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Lexus’ next generation looks a lot like what we have now&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="gXSK4g"&gt;Toyota is finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22187113/toyota-electric-vehicles-us-suv-debut-hybrids"&gt;following the rest of its peers into making all-electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt;, and that now includes its luxury brand, Lexus. On Tuesday, the Japanese marque revealed the LF-Z Electrified concept car, which is all about charting the company’s course into an electric future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bq6Kce"&gt;Mind you, that future in Lexus’ eyes still involves a healthy mix of hybrid and even hydrogen-powered vehicles, &lt;em&gt;as well as gas-only cars&lt;/em&gt;. The company said Tuesday it will introduce 20 new vehicles by 2025 and that just 10 of those will be all-electric, hybrid, or run on hydrogen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RqFVzv"&gt;Lexus did say it wants to reach carbon neutrality “throughout the lifecycle of its entire model lineup” but that its goal is to do this by 2050. Lexus also acknowledged Tuesday that the industry is entering a period of “once-in-a-century” transformation, which is... something, considering that Toyota chairman Akio Toyoda recently bucked the trend and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/toyotas-chief-says-electric-vehicles-are-overhyped-11608196665"&gt;said electric vehicles are “overhyped.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="0ylqTx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The head of Toyota — Lexus’ parent company — has said EVs are “overhyped”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eem908"&gt;But back to the concept car. It’s angular and futuristic, like many concepts tend to be. It’s shorter than most modern Lexus vehicles, and even features a sort of inversion of the company’s iconic (for better or worse) massive grille; instead of a gridded black diamond pattern, the flat silver bodywork traces a triangular shape down the nose. Tracking with the design that many modern EVs have adopted, the rear of the LF-Z features a continuous light bar that’s broken up only by the company’s reimagined wordmark. And there’s a panoramic glass roof stretching across the top of the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G3ZJSH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10419467"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BFTGka"&gt;The interior is more radical, even if it is familiar to anyone who’s looked at a lot of concept cars. The bucket seats have a distinct geometric look to them, and are surrounded by various lighting elements. It’s otherwise quite sparse, save for the cluster of screens that hug the steering wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KcxUQS"&gt;Being a concept car, the LZ-F is less about specs and more about &lt;em&gt;ideas &lt;/em&gt;and what Lexus imagines it might do with its future vehicles. One idea Lexus is chewing on with this concept is something called “Direct4,” which is basically just a branded version of torque vectoring that would drive power to each wheel independently, improving grip in high-performance situations. At a more base level, Lexus says this concept car is designed to achieve “ideal balance and inertia” while driving thanks to optimal placement of the battery and motors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1zhu2B"&gt;(This all sounds sort of like Nissan’s &lt;a href="https://usa.nissannews.com/en-US/releases/nissans-e-4orce-giving-drivers-of-all-levels-comfort-and-control"&gt;new torque vectoring system&lt;/a&gt; that is coming to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324125/nissan-ariya-electric-suv-crossover-specs-price"&gt;Ariya EV&lt;/a&gt;, though it’s hard to say for sure without more details.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wRlIGMSKIQ5LXaVkkCLzABo9bPk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407350/2021_Lexus_LFZ_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QWc4pd"&gt;Also, Lexus says the driver’s position and the screens were designed based on “the new concept of ‘Tazuna’” — which is Japanese for “rein.” The company describes this part of the concept car as such: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="GoiYeU"&gt;Inspired by the relationship between horse and rider, who communicate through a single rein, steering wheel-mounted switches and the vehicle’s head-up display have been highly coordinated to create a space in which various functions, such as the navigation system, audio system, and driving mode selection, can be performed while concentrating on driving and without movement of the driver’s line of sight or need to operate complicated switches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="kkZFls"&gt;This wouldn’t be a true concept car without some kind of artificial intelligence, and so of course Lexus has accounted for that here. But the company says AI would be used in the LZ-F in frankly pedestrian ways, like predicting what route a driver might take, or making restaurant reservations. Lexus believes this is a big step forward, though. “Such interactivity between AI and driver leads to a fruitful dialogue, thus improving the overall ownership and driving experience, adding color to the customer’s life as a lifestyle concierge,” the company writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iw7hvX"&gt;There are a few other more grounded technological features, like a digital key that allows multiple people to access the car, or door handles that present themselves — both the kinds of things that are already increasingly common on modern electric vehicles. It, of course, has autonomous driving modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="oj0nba"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The LZ-F is full of big ideas, but are they really that futuristic?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GanfHk"&gt;In fact, the more you look at the LZ-F, the more you may realize that it’s as much of a sign of what Lexus (and Toyota) have missed out on as it waited to chart this bold vision of the future of the brand — even if it is a far more realistic take than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/22/20927635/lexus-lf-30-electrified-concept-car-tokyo-motor-show-2019"&gt;drone-deploying LF-30 EV concept Lexus showed off in 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NRqZYn"&gt;The company has played a very conservative hand here at the beginning of what is, by its own admission, a massive transformation in the industry. And while there are certain advantages to that strategy — like &lt;a href="https://jalopnik.com/volkswagen-is-betting-82-5-billion-on-electric-cars-1820539398"&gt;not spending dozens of billions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; — the LZ-F is a good reminder of some of the disadvantages, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="rnjqi9"&gt;Lexus surely thinks it can do some of these things better than the rest of the competition no matter when it brings some of the LZ-F’s ideas to market. But if the future really is electric, Lexus will still find itself playing catch-up for the foreseeable future. The LZ-F is proof.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357789/lexus-lf-z-electrified-concept-car-ev-toyota-electric"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357789/lexus-lf-z-electrified-concept-car-ev-toyota-electric</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T04:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T04:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Kia’s EV6 is a small electric car with big dreams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u-odg78vkHuO_oTAKpV0Fc_BmnM=/0x0:2327x1551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69047066/Kia_EV6_GT_line_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Kia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The first of a new wave of Kia (and Hyundai) electrics&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="D92Fzk"&gt;After spending the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331130/kia-ev6-full-images-revealed-design-announcement-date"&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt; teasing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323438/kia-ev6-electric-car-hyundai-apple-platform"&gt;new electric vehicle&lt;/a&gt;, Kia just laid out a lot of what there is to know about the EV6 — at least for the most expensive models. But it all lines up with what the teaser images, well, teased, which is that the EV6 will be a fun and fast electric car with a refreshingly modest footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T5mKQn"&gt;Due out in “select global markets” in the second half of this year, including North America, the EV6 is the first Kia car that is built to be electric from the ground up. The modestly successful Niro EV SUV? That was, at a high level, a gas car that was retrofit to run on batteries. The EV6, however, is built on what Kia will use to power six future EVs. That same platform, called E-GMP, is being used by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"&gt;parent company Hyundai to power the Ioniq 5 EV&lt;/a&gt; and other future electric vehicles, too. (It’s also allegedly what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261893/apple-electric-car-hyundai-ming-chi-kuo-rumor-report"&gt;Apple was interested in before talks broke down&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="fTDAxz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Around 300 miles at the high end&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pWVfZy"&gt;Which is all to say that the EV6 is quite an important car for Kia. As such, the company made sure it’s full of attractive features and leading technologies. But it still isn’t going to blow buyers away with its range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OSn0Pw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10419406"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Aevr7C"&gt;The EV6 will be available in rear-wheel and in all-wheel drive configurations, and Kia will outfit it with standard range (58kWh) or long range (77.4kWh) battery packs. Kia says the rear-wheel drive EV6 with the long-range pack can go 510 kilometers, or roughly 316 miles, based on the European WLTP testing standard. That means an EPA range is likely going to be a little bit less, perhaps under 300 miles. Kia did not provide range estimates for the other configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="25amHk"&gt;Depending on the real world results, that’s fairly good efficiency out of a battery pack of that size. But Kia’s promoting just that one range figure, meaning that all other versions of the EV6 will likely get less. Still plenty for daily driving, but some versions of the electric car will not be well suited for long road trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bAJgDn"&gt;One way Kia is compensating for this is very fast charging, at least relative to the current state of electric vehicles. The E-GMP platform uses 800-volt battery packs, like what’s found in the Porsche Taycan, which makes it possible to charge an EV6 from 10 percent to 80 percent in just 18 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oV6mHGCG7pBcy_viuqXDUXGhOaM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407216/Kia_EV6_GT_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wgeNyR"&gt;Another is performance, at least for the AWD variants. The all-wheel drive GT version of the EV6 is the top spec, and only comes with the long range battery. It uses two motors to produce a combined 430kW, or roughly 576 horsepower, and can go from 0 to 100 kilometers per hour (62 mph) in just 3.5 seconds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ujYXwJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Two-way charging, for all your outdoor excursions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MytAxO"&gt;What may be more exciting than performance or tech specs, though, is that the EV6 supports two-way charging just like Hyundai’s Ioniq 5. The EV6 can put out up to 3.6kW of power — enough to power a 55-inch TV and an air conditioner for more than 24 hours, Kia says. It’s not as powerful as, say, the 7.2kW version of the new hybrid Ford F-150’s optional onboard charger, but then again the EV6 doesn’t use gas to generate this power, and it will be a heck of a lot cheaper. Kia says the EV6 can also tow up to 1,600 kilograms (roughly 3,500 pounds) as long as the battery is more than 35 percent full, too. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c_Kmx4Fzhm75Gh3tW0vhY7mFH2k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407213/Kia_EV6_GT_Interior_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fOPV37"&gt;What will set the EV6 apart more than anything is its exterior styling. Kia calls it a crossover, which isn’t wrong. But it also has big hatchback vibes. From some rear angles, it bears some resemblance to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;the Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt;. From the side, it’s a longer, meaner Ioniq 5. It’s certainly not bubbly or unassuming, like many of the SUVs that currently make up Kia’s lineup. Rather, it’s aggressive without being ostentatious; eye-catching, if not eye-watering. In a world that’s increasingly full of big, bloated vehicles, the EV6 is a breath of fresh air — even if the E-GMP platform it uses will most certainly wind up powering larger vehicles for Kia and Hyundai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hc6Nka"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hyundai’s electric Ioniq 5 crossover could be the ultimate camping companion ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bPVjJA"&gt;The EV6’s interior is more familiar. There are two 12-inch curved displays that sit inside a structure that rises up from the dashboard, one in front of the driver and one for infotainment purposes. There’s also an augmented reality heads-up display that projects information into the driver’s field of view. Kia promises this will all be updatable over-the-air, and there are advanced driver assistance features to boot. Otherwise, the inside of the EV6 just looks like the inside of a Kia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="4koejw"&gt;The Kia EV6, in some respects, looks to be a bold remaking of the company’s otherwise solid initial foray into the world of electric vehicles. But what Kia shared about the EV6 is almost as important as what it omitted. There is no word on pricing of the various configurations, and Kia also conveniently left out specs for what will certainly be the more affordable models. For such an important car, there remains a fair amount of mystery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Boh6Jg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357654/kia-ev6-revealed-specs-photos-electric-car-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357654/kia-ev6-revealed-specs-photos-electric-car-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-29T21:19:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-29T21:19:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Canoo’s deal with Hyundai appears dead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zNhRbIMT0jcf71XfSy4APjTwyPo=/159x0:1881x1148/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69046133/Canoo_MPDV_Front.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Canoo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kZWdxH"&gt;The deal between Canoo and Hyundai to build electric vehicles appears to be dead, as the California EV startup is moving away from trying to sell its electric vehicle technology to other automakers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="btDNac"&gt;Canoo chairman Tony Aquila shared the news Monday during an icy investor call — Canoo’s first as a publicly-traded company. Canoo’s CEO was also absent from the call, and the company announced earlier in the day that its CFO had resigned &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001750153/000155837021003592/tmb-20210323x8k.htm"&gt;to take another job&lt;/a&gt; — the second major departure in recent weeks following Canoo losing its head of corporate strategy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tsj7WM"&gt;“These are significant surprises on the call today, and that’s not ideal,” Roth Capital analyst Craig Irwin said at one point on the call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9o5Otu"&gt;The deal with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/11/21133461/hyundai-canoo-electric-cars-partership-kia"&gt;Hyundai was announced in February 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and it was supposed to result in both the Hyundai and Kia brands building vehicles on Canoo’s electric vehicle platform. It was seen as a major vote of confidence in the startup, which was just two years old at the time, as well as its tech. Canoo called it a “key partnership.” Hyundai did not immediately respond to a request for comment. Canoo did not respond beyond Aquila’s statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IRF8WN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“That’s not ideal.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4OwgTL"&gt;Aquila took over Canoo as part of the startup’s merger with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"&gt;special purpose acquisition company&lt;/a&gt; (SPAC) in 2020, which netted it around $600 million. Speaking obliquely at first, he said Monday that the startup’s board of directors decided to “de-emphasize” its “engineering services” line. This was the planned part of Canoo’s business that was supposed to see the startup provide technology to bigger companies that wanted to enter the electric vehicle space. Canoo’s desire to sell its technology &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225026/apple-canoo-acquisition-investment-electric-car-goev"&gt;at one point even drew the interest of Apple, as &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; previously reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EqVes4"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001750153/000121390020033060/fs42020a1_hennessycapital4.htm"&gt;documents filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission&lt;/a&gt;, both &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1750153/000121390021004077/f424b30121_canooinc.htm"&gt;before and after the merger&lt;/a&gt;, Canoo had said its planned engineering services business presented “a significant market for contract engineering services among legacy OEMs who lack the expertise to develop an electric powertrain at the pace needed to capitalize on the rising regulatory requirements and global demand for EVs.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="13zgnW"&gt;The startup also said these types of partnerships would serve as “concrete points of external validation for our technology and the talent of our team, as well as provide additional sources of revenue and long-term commercial opportunities.” Canoo said it was “in discussions with a number of other partners and expects to be in a position to announce many more partnerships in due course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SIKRs4"&gt;But on Monday, Aquila said Canoo will now focus more on making and selling its own vehicles to commercial operators. The company has so far announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"&gt;delivery vehicle&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22324096/canoo-goev-ev-pickup-truck-specs-photos-revealed"&gt;pickup truck&lt;/a&gt;, and a van, all of which are built on the same underlying technological platform. Canoo will focus even less on the idea of selling its electric van to consumers through a subscription model — the original pitch when the startup broke cover in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tyMGn"&gt;Aquila has previously spoken about focusing more on selling to fleet operators and small businesses as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"&gt;opposed to customers&lt;/a&gt;, though it wasn’t until Monday that he explained just how far he is willing to take that strategy shift. To wit, Canoo &lt;a href="https://investors.canoo.com/news-presentations/presentations"&gt;quietly uploaded a new investor presentation&lt;/a&gt; to its investor relations website on Monday that no longer mentions Hyundai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HFkGqa"&gt;“We have so much demand for our three [vehicles], let’s get all that work done, and then let’s, you know, look at if there [are] partnerships,” he said. Aquila explained he believes that this will make for a more sound business with less risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="nKFlb6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You’ve got to be careful with statements you make.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VFzt3k"&gt;When pressed on the startup’s previous claims about this part of its business, Aquila — who invested $35 million into Canoo before the SPAC merger — pointed to its prior leadership. Aquila said they were “a little more aggressive” than he would’ve been with some of their public statements, and that talk of potential partnerships was “presumptuous.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y21X2s"&gt;“You’ve got to be careful with statements you make. So, you know, again, I think it was a little premature,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHBnxu"&gt;While some of those executives are indeed now gone, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21277248/canoo-ev-startup-stefan-krause-leaving-evelozcity"&gt;cofounder and former CEO Stefan Krause&lt;/a&gt;, others remain — though they weren’t on Monday’s call. At one point Aquila was asked directly if Krause’s replacement, Canoo cofounder Ulrich Kranz, was still CEO. Aquila confirmed he is, though as &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; first reported late last year, Kranz’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22179588/canoo-delivery-vehicle-nasdaq-spac-merger-listing-public"&gt;contract was recently renegotiated&lt;/a&gt; and he was removed from the board of directors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ho5bZ"&gt;Aquila said he believes the refocused business will help “protect” the intellectual property Canoo has developed, and that the original deal with Hyundai didn’t factor in the value of that IP. When one analyst asked if Aquila thinks Hyundai misappropriated any of Canoo’s IP, Aquila said “well I’ll leave it to you to make that decision.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ex88o0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bwQnua"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sXKqwr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DjV3aW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357318/canoo-hyundai-deal-dead-electric-vehicles-goev"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357318/canoo-hyundai-deal-dead-electric-vehicles-goev</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-29T19:38:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-29T19:38:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s independent repair program is expanding to ‘nearly every country where Apple products are sold’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iphone 5 teardown (ifixit)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xCYE7QtWwTDVz4Xn3zzDP694JJk=/29x0:772x495/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69045781/El6QfQ4IFThwHHqH.1419974202.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;iphone 5 teardown (ifixit)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z9iaWg"&gt;Getting an Apple product repaired often involves going directly to the (expensive) source — an Apple Store — or a big third-party firm. If you live somewhere with limited choices, Apple’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F03%2Fapples-independent-repair-provider-program-expands-globally%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F29%2F22357187%2Fapple-independent-repair-program-in-over-200-countries" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recently announced expansion&lt;/a&gt; of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/29/20838307/apple-iphone-repairs-parts-independent-shops"&gt;Independent Repair Provider&lt;/a&gt; program might change that. The company plans to expand its repair program to “nearly every country where Apple products are sold,” meaning someone near you could soon be using official Apple parts to fix your cracked phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Z3IiU"&gt;Right now, the program is only available in the US, Canada and Europe, but according to Apple’s announcement, repair providers from countries including Australia, Japan, and Korea will be able to join this week, with providers from even more countries including China joining the program later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="352Pf4"&gt;Providers have to apply to participate, but once approved, they can only buy a limited variety of first-party materials like batteries, screens, and diagnostic tools. So while your local repair person will be able to fix the most common issues with official parts, anything more more exotic will have to go through Apple, one of its authorized service providers, or risk voiding a warranty or becoming unsupported down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HL8BsO"&gt;If you actually do the hard work of repairing devices, there’s other things to be aware of, too. Joining the program comes with a contract that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21126970/apple-iphone-independent-repair-contract-search-audit"&gt;reportedly gives Apple&lt;/a&gt; the right to both inspect repair shops and fine them if it finds something amiss. Apple can charge $1,000 per transaction for any shop it catches using knockoff parts in more than two percent of repairs, according to &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjdjnv/apples-independent-repair-program-is-invasive-to-shops-and-their-customers-contract-shows"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XdgFqM"&gt;Apple generally only seems to be supportive of third-party repairs if it can find a way to make money off of them, and this repair program doesn’t seem to be any different. This is the company that routinely attempts to kill &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18525542/apple-right-to-repair-bill-california-lobbyist-comptia"&gt;right-to-repair bills&lt;/a&gt; and has devised methods to make iPhones non-functional &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/8/20776965/iphone-xs-max-xr-battery-service-third-party-repair"&gt;if they use third-party batteries&lt;/a&gt;, after all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kkBzsR"&gt;You can read the full list of participating countries and regions &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F03%2Fapples-independent-repair-provider-program-expands-globally%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F29%2F22357187%2Fapple-independent-repair-program-in-over-200-countries" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on Apple’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357187/apple-independent-repair-program-in-over-200-countries"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22357187/apple-independent-repair-program-in-over-200-countries</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
