<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Legion 5 Pro is Lenovo’s best gaming laptop yet</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Packed with power and stellar features for a great price&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="AGA19r"&gt;The Lenovo Legion 5 Pro makes a lot of things seem easy. At its core, it’s a gaming laptop that plays games very well. But it also has a wonderfully expansive 16-inch QHD (technically WQXGA, since it’s 2560 x 1600) resolution display that’s great for gaming and other use cases. Notably, this is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238671/16-9-aspect-ratio-hp-elite-folio-dell-latitude-lenovo-thinkbook-plus-legion-7"&gt;16:10 aspect ratio screen&lt;/a&gt;, and my eyeballs appreciate the luxury of having more stuff to look at without needing to scroll or resize windows to fit within view. Lenovo’s combo of a taller, high-resolution screen is what you’ll want in your next gaming laptop, even if you don’t know it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mMK5UO"&gt;This laptop is full of other delights, like its TrueStrike keyboard. It’s a &lt;em&gt;stuffed &lt;/em&gt;layout, with a numpad, a full row of function keys, and dedicated media keys, yet it’s comfortable to use and thoughtfully arranged. It doesn’t come at the expense of a sizable, responsive trackpad, either. For any kind of media, the Legion 5 Pro also has better-than-average speakers that are actually pleasant to listen to, as opposed to most gaming laptop speakers that make me writhe in anguish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1fzFMI"&gt;There are a handful of recent gaming laptops that have the Legion 5 Pro beat with a thinner build — not that I’d call Lenovo’s 16-inch model thick, per se. Still, it wears its larger size well with a slick design that doesn’t forget to include a good amount of ports. Also, this laptop allows for user-upgradeable RAM and storage (it has two RAM slots and two M.2 slots), which is a perk that thinner gaming laptops usually can’t achieve due to space constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YQ8lhG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10602138"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AgMx5b"&gt;Every laptop has compromises, but the few that Lenovo’s Legion 5 Pro has aren’t as apparent as they are in some other models. I’m willing to overlook its average battery life and paltry 512GB of storage, as it’s priced &lt;em&gt;very &lt;/em&gt;competitively &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLenovo-Legion-5-Pro-16-0-AMD-Ryzen-7-5800H-16GB-512GB-NVMe-TLC-SSD-NVIDIA-GeForce-RTX-3070-Windows-10-Home-82JQ008NUS%2F231609645&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;at $1,529.99&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/khIUMlJ2ktXDrUOk3uifG72ZgZ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653564/cfaulkner_20210608_4624_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legion 5 Pro is a looker, at least compared to other gaming laptops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fXh7yzRcU3Fc4HIwqX1x1kKCoWk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653553/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This laptop has air exhausts at its rear and on its sides, and it doesn’t get too warm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="3ZUbam"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10602891"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5CBRSH"&gt;The configuration that’ll be available at Walmart in late June features 16GB of RAM and 512GB of NVMe storage — both of which are user-upgradeable (though half a terabyte fills up awfully fast these days). AMD’s octa-core Ryzen 7 5800H processor is powering the show, along with a capable variant of Nvidia’s RTX 3070 with 140W of maximum graphics power and a 1,560MHz boost clock speed. Paired with its higher-res display, this hardware can provide respectable frame rates across the board, even in titles that feature demanding ray tracing settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WU0XnZ"&gt;Getting right into the performance, I ran a few demanding games at its native 2560 x 1600 resolution with the highest possible graphics settings. &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; ran at an average of 59 frames per second; &lt;em&gt;Horizon: Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; hit 73 frames per second. Both are respectable results, especially given that this laptop is running them at higher than 1080p resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXOoIL"&gt;Even games with ray-traced graphics fared well, including &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;. With &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;’s ray-traced shadows and Nvidia’s DLSS feature turned on, it ran at an average of 63 frames per second (DLSS lowers the render resolution, then relies on an AI model to touch up the aliasing and textures to look nearly just as good as running a game at native resolution, without as much of a hit to performance). With &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;, a game that has more ray tracing graphics options, the Legion 5 Pro maintained a steady 45 frames per second with all of the most demanding settings and DLSS on — an impressive feat. Turning down the ray tracing features to medium instead of high (with DLSS still on) boosts the average frame rate to around 60 frames per second. Without any ray tracing effects, the 5 Pro can run &lt;em&gt;Control &lt;/em&gt;at the display’s native 1600p resolution at around 70 frames per second. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rGSNX8KDBsSD6QPBoU_OzUhML00=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653560/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The display has thin bezels, but Lenovo didn’t forget to include a webcam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mhsELSKUxgnfuF0UQGePEpxVAz4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653551/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legion 5 Pro has a healthy amount of ports on its rear. There are more around the sides.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s9j0Z8"&gt;Some context is necessary to understand how those numbers stack up against our current favorite gaming laptop, the slightly more pricey Asus ROG Zephyrus G15, which has a 1440p QHD screen (slightly lower resolution than this one), a faster octa-core Ryzen 9 5900HS processor, and an RTX 3070 with a lower 100W power ceiling. The results come out in favor of the Legion 5 Pro, as it squeezed just a few more frames per second out of each game (&lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t tested on the G15 during our review period), a testament to its higher-powered GPU being able to push impressive frame rates to an even higher-res 1600p resolution display. It’s all the more impressive that the 5 Pro doesn’t get too loud or hot during gameplay. It exhausts warm air out the left and right sides, as well as on the back. During the winter months, the flow of toasty air seems like a perk if you use a standalone mouse off to the side, but it might be annoying if you get warm easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llevmo"&gt;I recently tested the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22518545/alienware-m15-r5-ryzen-edition-review-7-5800h-nvidia-rtx-3060-features-specs-performance"&gt;Alienware M15 R5&lt;/a&gt;, which has the same Ryzen 7 5800H processor, but with an RTX 3060 with 125W of maximum graphics power. Like the Legion 5 Pro, this model has user-upgradeable RAM and storage. Though, the M15 R5’s $1,616 configuration comes with a 1080p display, so its GPU is under far less stress than the faster one in Lenovo’s. Given that this Lenovo Legion 5 Pro is priced at about $50 more — and is superior in several ways outside of performance — I’d just suggest you forget about Alienware’s model, as you’ll get less for your money there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4t1F1Y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best gaming laptops in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0cSTLjUi1M3VUjq0IaHYCbvM71U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653563/cfaulkner_20210608_4624_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Y-shaped logo illuminates white when the laptop is on, and it glistens when it’s off. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8p_g-52ZMiNqvOCe9M-5-XzOH70=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653561/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lenovo crammed so much into this keyboard layout, but it’s still easy to use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xntF0H"&gt;The high frame rates are easier to appreciate here than on some other models because of Lenovo’s 165Hz refresh rate G-Sync display. Games feel responsive, and they look great. The panel specs say that it can reach 500 nits of brightness, and that it’s certified for color accuracy by X-Rite and Pantone. I didn’t have tools on hand to put those claims to the test, but the colors look accurate and the screen gets bright enough to make it possible to work outdoors or to sit next to a window that’s giving off some glare without squinting to see text or images. I didn’t need to turn the brightness up higher than halfway for most tasks, and that setting seems like the peak brightness of some gaming laptops that I’ve used before (the ROG Zephyrus G15 claims to reach 300 nits of brightness). Turning up the brightness while gaming made the experience appear more cinematic, like watching on a bright TV. Viewing angles are wide and generous, too, and it provides a serviceable image on lower brightness settings if you’re trying to conserve battery. Lastly, I appreciate how thin the bezels are surrounding the display — even the chin bezel at the bottom is barely there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="13ZFSx"&gt;The 5 Pro has an 80Wh battery that lasts for about four and a half hours under normal productivity (not gaming) use, and that’s with all of the usual battery-saving measures taken. I dialed in the efficiency settings to “better battery” mode in Windows 10 and to “hybrid mode” in Lenovo’s preinstalled Vantage software to ensure the Legion 5 Pro isn’t relying solely on the RTX 3070. This result isn’t nearly as good as some other powerful gaming laptops we’ve tested that have one of AMD’s Zen 3 CPUs inside, like Alienware’s M15 R5 that provides about seven hours, the eight-plus hours we saw with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt; (while powering a QHD screen), and over nine hours in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465565/asus-rog-strix-g15-advantage-edition-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="njXK7z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10602911"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7VMaYk"&gt;Four and a half hours of battery life isn’t bad for a gaming laptop, considering two to three hours was both expected and excusable in 2019 and 2020 models. But the competition has raised the bar in this department in such a way that this weaker performance is one of the Legion 5 Pro’s more glaring issues. Its 300W power brick is also quite large. Lenovo earns some props, though, for supporting USB-C charging (up to 65W), and its Rapid Charge Pro feature that claims to quickly recharge the laptop up to 50 percent in 30 minutes (it actually recharged a &lt;em&gt;staggering &lt;/em&gt;80 percent from zero in less than 30 minutes). But still, if longevity is essential for you, this might knock the Legion 5 Pro off from being a top pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FMKxf9"&gt;As I mentioned earlier, Lenovo’s TrueStrike keyboard is very good. It has four-zone programmable backlighting with 1.5mm travel per key and 100 percent anti-ghosting. It was effortless for me to adapt to the layout and feel both in and out of gameplay. Lenovo says it increased the size of its precision trackpad by 23 percent based on user feedback on previous Lenovo Legion gaming laptops. The Legion 5 Pro has a 720p webcam, which delivers passable image quality. Some of Asus’ gaming laptops that we recommend don’t feature a webcam, but in case that’s a deal-breaker feature, you might be glad to find one here. It has an electronic on / off switch on the right side of the chassis, as the bezel hosting the webcam is apparently too thin for Lenovo to fit in a physical cover over the lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dVCG-0knLay3Ilmnuf6KObVvwuo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653555/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most of the ports are around back, but the left side hosts this USB-C port and a headphone combo jack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IkpPmm_coFCAOsyLVqeecBp7IBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653554/cfaulkner_20210607_4624_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The electronic switch for the webcam and a USB Type-A port are on the right side of the Legion 5 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KgdrUs"&gt;Trying to figure out which gaming laptop offers the most value can make your head spin. It’s easy to find powerful models, but it’s far less simple to find one that’s multifaceted to handle more than just games. The Legion 5 Pro doesn’t get everything right — namely battery life. But it’s the gaming laptop to beat right now when it comes to powerful specs, a big, high-res display, and a handful of other niceties, like decent sound quality, a good keyboard, and user-upgradeability. It earned a spot at the top alongside Asus’ ROG Zephyrus G15, with user-upgradability and power in place of Asus’ good battery life and lightweight design. Now, we’ll have to wait to see how Asus answers with its Intel-based &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22425078/asus-intel-zephyrus-m16-gaming-laptop-tiger-lake-h-chips"&gt;ROG Zephyrus M16&lt;/a&gt;, a 16-inch gaming laptop with a similar 16:10 aspect ratio display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Ht7rQZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22529429/lenovo-legion-5-pro-review-gaming-laptop-price-specs-performance-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22529429/lenovo-legion-5-pro-review-gaming-laptop-price-specs-performance-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T09:19:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T09:19:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Take The Verge’s survey</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3gM7xmqs6nIMC_Tek1Fpy4lHA3k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69449099/acastro_210604_4615_survey_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Verge is turning 10 this year, and we’d like to hear from you&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://survey.cmix.com/228406B7/7E310C4Q/en-US?l=1"&gt;https://survey.cmix.com/228406B7/7E310C4Q/en-US?l=1&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://survey.cmix.com/228406B7/7E310C4Q/en-US?l=1"/>
    <id>https://survey.cmix.com/228406B7/7E310C4Q/en-US?l=1</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T09:06:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T09:06:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft to end Windows 10 support on October 14th, 2025</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bhb6kCBxm4HB7OUFuf5adZ3XCFo=/0x1:1020x681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69449073/windowslogo_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dante D’Orazio / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="chG9SQ"&gt;Microsoft is ending support for Windows 10 on October 14th, 2025. It will mark just over 10 years since the operating system was first introduced. Microsoft revealed the retirement date for Windows 10 in an updated &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/lifecycle/products/windows-10-home-and-pro"&gt;support life cycle page&lt;/a&gt; for the OS. &lt;a href="https://www.thurrott.com/windows/windows-10/251736/windows-10-support-ends-on-october-14-2025"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thurrott&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that this is the first time Microsoft has ever described the end of support for Windows 10. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ajzah0"&gt;It’s not clear exactly when the support document was updated, but &lt;em&gt;Thurrott&lt;/em&gt; reports it only previous documented “when specific Windows 10 versions would leave support,” and not the entire OS. It could be another hint that a new version of Windows is on the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DnZw65"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft keeps dropping Windows 11 hints&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7bFXyG"&gt;Microsoft has been dropping lots of hints that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466394/microsoft-windows-11-launch-teaser-rumors"&gt;ready to launch Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;. The software maker is holding a special Windows event to reveal the “next generation” of the OS next week. The event starts at 11AM ET, and the event invite includes a window that creates a shadow with an outline that looks like the number 11. Microsoft execs have also been teasing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453222/microsoft-windows-next-generation-announcement-sun-valley-build-2021-keynote"&gt;“next generation of Windows” announcement&lt;/a&gt; for months, and one even described it as a “new version of Windows” recently. Microsoft also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528115/microsoft-windows-11-startup-sound-new-teaser-video"&gt;teased Windows 11 during an 11-minute video&lt;/a&gt; last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r0cwxe"&gt;We’re expecting Microsoft to announce a new version of Windows with significant user interface changes, and an overhaul to the Windows Store. Microsoft has been working on something codenamed “Sun Valley,” which the company has referred to as a “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212817/microsoft-windows-10-visual-changes-update-sun-valley-2021"&gt;sweeping visual rejuvenation of Windows&lt;/a&gt;.” There will be many other changes, so &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466394/microsoft-windows-11-launch-teaser-rumors"&gt;read our previous coverage for what to expect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X_SH6v9iEEDYwVrtRSrlYFtbWGM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22495503/Windows_10_Sun_Valley_refresh.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re expecting to see a new version of Windows soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YhQCiN"&gt;Microsoft originally committed to 10 years of support for Windows 10, with an original mainstream end of support date set for October 13th, 2020. That mainstream end of support has not yet commenced, as Microsoft has been introducing regular updates and extending active Windows 10 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bsFc2I"&gt;We’re still not in the extended support phase of Windows 10 yet, which is the period when Microsoft doesn’t add new features to an operating system and simply maintains support with bug fixes and security patches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KGT8NG"&gt;Windows 10 has been an unusual release for Microsoft, as it moved away from its typical cadence of releasing a new version of the OS every few years. Instead, Microsoft moved Windows to more of a service, updating it twice a year with new features. Microsoft may have described Windows 10 as “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/7/8568473/windows-10-last-version-of-windows"&gt;the last version of Windows&lt;/a&gt;,” but it has now been nearly six years since its release and Microsoft looks ready to move on to something new.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22533018/microsoft-windows-10-end-support-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22533018/microsoft-windows-10-end-support-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon wants you vaccinated, so here’s $180 AirPods Pro and other accessory discounts  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9-ZJMAVDO75nkdN07lIyy9_DAPc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448997/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U7IgN6"&gt;Verizon is joining &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/health/today-the-first-winners-of-washington-states-covid-vaccine-lottery-will-be-chosen/"&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://odh.ohio.gov/wps/portal/gov/odh/media-center/odh-news-releases/odh-news-release-05-28-21"&gt;states&lt;/a&gt; in offering a financial incentive to get the COVID vaccine: its customers who have gotten at least one dose can get a 10 percent discount on accessories, from either its online or physical stores. To sweeten the deal even more, Verizon is letting customers stack that discount on top of sale prices, which can be used to get some pretty solid deals. It’s unclear if or how you’ll have to prove your vaccination status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FKbanD"&gt;For example, Verizon has the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/products/apple-airpods-pro-headphones/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro on sale&lt;/a&gt; until June 20th, and the 10 percent discount brings them down to $180 from their normal price of $250. If you’re more a fan of headphones and can snag the discount, you’ll be able to pick up Sony’s &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/products/sony-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;delightfully named WH-1000XM4s&lt;/a&gt; for $270. The offer could also be a way to get a nice little discount on a lower-priced item you’ve been considering, like a Samsung wireless charging pad or &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/products/anker-soundcore-liberty-air-2-true-wireless-in-ear-headphones/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s Soundcore Liberty Air 2 headphones&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIShJB"&gt;The offer is also valid for first responders, nurses, teachers, and military members. Any customers who are eligible will have from June 15th to July 31st, 2021 to &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/discounts/vaccination/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fill out a questionnaire&lt;/a&gt; and receive their promo code, which can be redeemed until August 15th. While accessories that are on sale can be discounted, Verizon says that, for whatever reason, accessories whose prices end with a .97 can’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F3HiJf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22530077/verizon-vaccinated-promotion-10-percent-airpods-pro-accessories"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22530077/verizon-vaccinated-promotion-10-percent-airpods-pro-accessories</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T08:49:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T08:49:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lordstown Motors CEO resigns after investigation into preorders</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Trump Tours New Lordstown Endurance Electric Pickup Truck" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2B8-WIXRczI5bVD_6XOAyyo9CLU=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448950/1228771026.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zAyIMY"&gt;Steve Burns, the CEO of General Motors-backed startup Lordstown Motors, has resigned following an investigation into allegations that he and other executives lied about preorders for the company’s electric pickup truck. The startup’s chief financial officer Julio Rodriguez has also resigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8dzPwU"&gt;The resignations come just weeks after Lordstown Motors admitted that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453051/ev-startup-spac-lordstown-lucid-canoo-faraday-fisker"&gt;needs more money to execute on its production plans for the pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; and its auditor saying the company may run out of cash, despite raising nearly $700 million late last year. It’s one of many electric vehicle startups &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453051/ev-startup-spac-lordstown-lucid-canoo-faraday-fisker"&gt;running into trouble&lt;/a&gt; after going public by merging with a special purpose acquisition company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e1Pfh3"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://investor.lordstownmotors.com/news-releases/news-release-details/lordstown-motors-reports-results-special-committee-investigation"&gt;investigation found&lt;/a&gt; that while Lordstown Motors said on multiple occasions that a majority of the 100,000 non-binding preorders it collected were from commercial fleets, this was not the case. It discovered that “one entity that provided a large number of pre-orders does not appear to have the resources to complete large purchases of trucks,” and that other companies on the list “provided commitments that appear too vague or infirm to be appropriately included in the total number of pre-orders disclosed.” The firm’s probe also confirmed that Lordstown Motors paid a company to drum up around 1,000 preorders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="S6ID4p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Some preorders were from a firm that lacked the resources to buy the trucks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xUJEUb"&gt;“We thank Steve Burns for his passion and commitment to the company,” the startup said in a statement. Burns will be temporarily replaced by Angela Strand, who is an independent board member at Lordstown Motors, though she formerly worked at Burns’ previous EV startup, Workhorse. Becky Roof, a certified public accountant and former CFO, will temporarily replace Rodriguez. “We have complete confidence in Angela and Becky, and our expanded leadership team, to effectively guide the company during this interim period,” the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bh52Vl"&gt;The probe, which was conducted by law firm Sullivan and Cromwell, was launched in March after short-selling firm Hindenburg Research &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336751/lordstown-motors-sec-inquiry-review-hindenburg-investigation-orders"&gt;published a report&lt;/a&gt; that made a number of allegations of potential wrongdoing at Lordstown Motors. At the heart of the report was Hindenburg’s belief that the EV startup had misled investors about the viability of preorders it touted in late 2020 and early 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2w3er9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Lordstown Motors wants to avoid the ‘carnage’ of failed EV startups","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21173309/lordstown-motors-steve-burns-interview-ceo-gm-ohio-factory-trump"},{"title":"Lordstown Motors probed by SEC for allegedly misleading investors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336751/lordstown-motors-sec-inquiry-review-hindenburg-investigation-orders"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WIQTmz"&gt;The research firm made other claims about Lordstown Motors’ progress on its electric pickup truck, and that one of the startup’s prototypes had caught fire. The law firm says that these other parts of the report are “in significant respects, false and misleading,” and that “the viability of Lordstown Motors’ technology and timeline to start of production are not accurate.” The fire, the firm said, was an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwwCkv"&gt;Lordstown Motors is also facing an investigation by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) that was opened following Hindenburg’s report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8jhvP"&gt;Founded in 2019 by Burns, Lordstown Motors bought a recently shuttered GM plant in Lordstown, Ohio in a deal that then-President Donald Trump &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21173309/lordstown-motors-steve-burns-interview-ceo-gm-ohio-factory-trump"&gt;billed as “GREAT NEWS” for the state&lt;/a&gt;. Trump had been putting pressure on GM to do something with the factory, and his administration celebrated the transaction and Lordstown Motors as a result. Lordstown Motors brought the truck to the White House for &lt;a href="https://www.cleveland.com/open/2020/09/trump-shows-off-lordstown-motors-pickup-truck-at-white-house-on-the-eve-of-cleveland-presidential-debate.html"&gt;an event in September 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and then-VP Mike Pence attended the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21302966/lordstown-motors-electric-pickup-truck-ev-endurance-unveiling-pence"&gt;reveal of the Endurance pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; a few months earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vytht5"&gt;The startup &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336751/lordstown-motors-sec-inquiry-review-hindenburg-investigation-orders"&gt;went public late last year&lt;/a&gt; and raised $675 million in the process. GM was one of the highest-profile investors, committing $25 million in cash to Lordstown Motors and around $50 million of “in-kind” contributions that helped the startup buy the plant and equipment. It owns around 5 percent of Lordstown Motors. GM declined to comment on the resignations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dffiKn"&gt;GM was involved in another EV startup, Nikola, that Hindenburg Research published a report about. That startup also juggled its leadership and is currently under investigation from the SEC and the Department of Justice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lIJS6j"&gt;Burns previously ran Workhorse, an electric vehicle startup that’s struggled to get a commercial delivery van business off the ground. The Endurance pickup truck actually began its life at Workhorse. When Lordstown Motors was formed, Workhorse licensed the intellectual property for the truck to Burns’ new startup in exchange for around $20 million. Workhorse owns 10 percent of Lordstown Motors, though the value of that stake has dropped from around $330 million at the end of 2020 to below $200 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U8bj0A"&gt;Workhorse had spent years trying to win the contract for the United States Postal Service’s next-generation delivery vehicle, and had promised Lordstown Motors the right to bid on the manufacturing portion of the deal. But in February, the USPS awarded the contract to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297823/usps-postal-service-mail-truck-electric-oshkosh-workhorse"&gt;defense contractor Oshkosh&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Oj32F"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532976/lordstown-motors-ceo-steve-burns-resign-short-seller-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532976/lordstown-motors-ceo-steve-burns-resign-short-seller-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T08:34:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T08:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Novavax says its COVID-19 vaccine is 90 percent effective </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Novavax Vaccine Appears Effective Against UK Coronavirus Variant" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GdfGBCXomr8ec9ZvC-rNIRCsauk=/389x0:5566x3451/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448930/1231469378.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jaap Arriens/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HgCDwP"&gt;The two-shot COVID-19 vaccine made by Novavax is 90 percent effective against the disease, the company &lt;a href="https://ir.novavax.com/news-releases/news-release-details/novavax-covid-19-vaccine-demonstrates-90-overall-efficacy-and"&gt;said today&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8AeAZr"&gt;The Novavax shots are a different type of vaccine than the ones already available: it’s a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21266897/coronavirus-vaccine-development-strategies-pros-cons"&gt;protein-based vaccine&lt;/a&gt; that directly delivers bits of the coronavirus spike protein, which the body then makes antibodies against. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kCHQSc"&gt;Novavax tested its vaccine in 29,960 people across the US and Mexico who were randomly assigned to get either the vaccine or a placebo injection. There were 77 cases of COVID-19 in the study: 14 in people who’d received the vaccine, and 63 in the group that got a placebo. All 14 cases in the vaccine group were mild. In the placebo group, ten cases were moderate and four were severe, showing the shots protect against more serious illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gSG8vY"&gt;The trial ran when the Alpha coronavirus variant, first identified in the United Kingdom, was widespread in the US. The results confirm that the shots protect against that form of the virus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIscWl"&gt;The results are similar to those from the clinical trial Novavax &lt;a href="https://ir.novavax.com/news-releases/news-release-details/novavax-covid-19-vaccine-demonstrates-893-efficacy-uk-phase-3"&gt;ran in the UK&lt;/a&gt;, which found that the shots were around 89 percent effective. That trial was also run at a time when the Alpha variant was widespread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QFsaZW"&gt;The US has already authorized three COVID-19 vaccines and has secured enough of those vaccines to vaccinate the entire population of the US. Still, Novavax says it plans to submit its vaccine to regulators in the US and around the world by this fall. By that point, the US regulatory agency, the Food and Drug Administration, may have already granted full approval to the Pfizer / BioNTech or Moderna COVID-19 vaccines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FHSjce"&gt;If the FDA does approve any vaccines, Novavax may not be able to apply for the speedier emergency authorization process that the other three vaccines went through — that process is technically only open if there are no fully approved products to treat a condition. However, because Novavax has already been in discussions with the FDA, it may still be able to go that route, Stanley Erck, the company’s CEO, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/14/health/covid-vaccine-novavax.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wkzezR"&gt;Novavax had &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/05/10/novavax-coronavirus-vaccine/"&gt;manufacturing problems&lt;/a&gt; this spring that forced it to push back estimates for when it could file for regulatory clearance and provide vaccines. The company has an agreement with the COVAX initiative, which is securing vaccines for low- and middle-income countries, for &lt;a href="https://ir.novavax.com/news-releases/news-release-details/novavax-and-gavi-execute-advance-purchase-agreement-covid-19"&gt;1.1 billion doses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6SCPq6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532943/novavax-covid-vaccine-trial-effective-variants"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532943/novavax-covid-vaccine-trial-effective-variants</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon Go creator Niantic is making a Transformers game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Np5Aslv9jpJ9fKBHo3dHAiEPf84=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448765/hm_bumblebee_concept_updated.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1wPQlY"&gt;Niantic is expanding from cute critters to giant robots. Today, the game developer announced its next project: a location-based augmented reality game called &lt;em&gt;Transformers: Heavy Metal&lt;/em&gt;. The game is expected to launch globally this year, with a soft launch in select countries “soon.” Niantic says that it has partnered with Seattle-based studio Very Very Spaceship, which will be leading development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NsnYit"&gt;You might be wondering just how towering transforming robots will translate to &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;-style gameplay. Here’s the basic description from Niantic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="9kbMBM"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Transformers: Heavy Metal&lt;/em&gt;, players will join the Guardian Network, a group of humans who have banded together with the Autobots in a war against the Decepticons. As a Guardian, players will uncover hidden regions across Earth to find resources and battle Decepticons in turn-based battles, either solo or with friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Transformers: Heavy Metal." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kt6P60FAKe-8ou3-OLLE8XfFwr0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652460/hm_screenshot_map.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Transformers: Heavy Metal." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QAhnOt493SyWNNswtSnHw76nImI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652459/hm_screenshot_battle.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P81dnE"&gt;While Niantic is best-known for the ongoing success of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, the company has also expanded by attempting to bring other fictional realms to video games. The first was the Harry Potter universe, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18716146/harry-potter-wizards-unite-pokemon-go-review-ar-augmented-reality-game-foundable"&gt;with &lt;em&gt;Wizards Unite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22345472/niantic-nintendo-pikmin-partnership-collaboration-ar-mobile-game"&gt;the developer announced a partnership with Nintendo that will include a &lt;em&gt;Pikmin&lt;/em&gt; game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22529378/transformers-heavy-metal-niantic-pokemon-go-location-game-ar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22529378/transformers-heavy-metal-niantic-pokemon-go-location-game-ar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T07:25:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T07:25:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Future Apple Watches could feature blood glucose and body temperature sensors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O11u__BAkZGSWvl4aWbYjdFqGL4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448696/vpavic_200929_4216_0121.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 6, released last year.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h8ahct"&gt;This year’s Apple Watch could feature an improved screen and updated ultra-wideband support, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-14/apple-plans-faster-watch-future-temperature-and-glucose-sensors?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, but more substantial improvements like temperature and blood glucose monitoring will not appear until later models. The company is also reportedly planning a successor to last year’s more affordable &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a new extreme sports-focused model, due for release in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBxl32"&gt;The improvements coming to this year’s model, which will almost certainly be called the Series 7, appear to be small. Its display bezels are said to be thinner, and a new lamination  technique could reduce the distance between the display and the front cover. The watch’s ultra-wideband support could also be improved after getting its Apple wearable debut in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/9/15/21438497/apple-watch-series-6-u1-locator-ultra-wideband-location"&gt;last year’s Series 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NyDWvI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An extreme sports-focused model may not launch until next year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JTZ00W"&gt;But the years ahead could bring more substantial improvements for Apple’s wearable. Top of the list is a new blood glucose monitoring feature, which could automatically log blood-sugar levels for diabetics without them needing to prick a finger to draw blood. There’s also reportedly a new body temperature monitoring feature on the way, which has reportedly seen a surge in interest due to the pandemic. The temperature sensor could appear in the watch’s 2022 refresh, while blood glucose monitoring is several years away, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CyFkFe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22351979/apple-watch-rugged-extreme-sports-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;previously reported&lt;/a&gt; that Apple was internally discussing releasing a rugged smartwatch aimed at extreme sports users. It now reports this model, internally referred to as an “explorer” or “adventure” edition, is unlikely to release this year, and could arrive in 2022. However &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;cautions that this, like all of Apple’s unannounced plans, are subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fm1j72"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532916/apple-watch-series-7-features-blood-glucose-body-temperature-extreme-sports-edition-se-2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532916/apple-watch-series-7-features-blood-glucose-body-temperature-extreme-sports-edition-se-2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T06:36:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T06:36:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s premium G1 OLED now comes with a 5-year warranty in the US and UK</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pU-sbNp7Kjiwl0jQpwSNgkvLaK4=/4x0:1597x1062/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448531/large01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG is now offering a 5-year warranty for its G1 OLED.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bu8FhG"&gt;LG is offering an extended 5-year warranty on its 4K G1 OLED in the US, covering any problems that develop with its panel after the standard one-year warranty. In the UK &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fuk%2Foled-tvs%2F2021%2Foled-warranty&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F14%2F22532894%2Flg-5-year-warranty-g1-oled-z1-4k-8k-usa-panel-failure-burn-in" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company says&lt;/a&gt; the extended warranty also applies to its Z1 8K OLED. It’s unclear in how many other countries LG is offering the extended warranty, and the company did not immediately respond to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x6jAqo"&gt;The extended warranty appears to be an attempt to upsell customers from LG’s popular lower-end sets like the C1 to its more premium G1 model. But it should also allay any fears that the new brighter Evo OLED panel LG is using in the G1 won’t last as long as its previous OLED panels. Or, as LG said in a statement &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/uk/news/lg-oled-tvs-now-come-with-a-five-year-warranty-but-not-all-of-them"&gt;given to &lt;em&gt;TechRadar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “The warranty is designed to offer peace of mind to customers purchasing our flagship, more expensive OLED models.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6LwlxJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;LG’s cheaper C1 OLED is not included&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="faT6Yg"&gt;Of course, the big question is whether the extended warranty covers permanent image retention, aka “burn-in,” where parts of an image can remain visible after being displayed for an extended period. In response to &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/lg-extends-2021-g1-oled-warranty-five-years-175840084.html?src=rss_b2c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;’s question&lt;/a&gt; about this, LG gave this evasive response: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="T8dkWo"&gt;“LG’s five-year limited warranty program is in line with the company’s consistent communication regarding the low risk of image retention on LG OLED TVs, when used in normal viewing conditions… As with any self-emitting display, OLED TVs may experience temporary image retention under certain conditions, but permanent image retention, or burn-in, is rare under normal viewing conditions. Image retention is not a product defect.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bLHUhU"&gt;The implication seems to be that temporary image retention is normal and is nothing to worry about, but all LG will say about permanent image retention is that it’s “rare.” Meanwhile, in a statement given &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b09oXig-4wk"&gt;to &lt;em&gt;HDTVTest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the company said the warranty covers “any image issues,” so long as the display is being used normally, and not in a commercial setting where static images might be left onscreen for far longer (the famous example of this is a &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/lg-switches-airport-oled-to-lcd-amid-burn-in-row/"&gt;South Korean airport&lt;/a&gt; which had to swap out the OLED TVs it was using to show departure times). We’ve contacted LG to try and get a simple yes or no answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ik4d7v"&gt;Like other warranties, LG’s also comes with various exceptions, such as damage caused by power surges, acts of nature, or improper installation. But LG’s warranty should still provide some assurance that you’ll get a decent few years of use if you splash out on one of its more expensive TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ml1IBI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DwFSZD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532894/lg-5-year-warranty-g1-oled-z1-4k-8k-usa-panel-failure-burn-in"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532894/lg-5-year-warranty-g1-oled-z1-4k-8k-usa-panel-failure-burn-in</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-14T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Workspace and Google Chat are officially available to everybody</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google Spaces" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rtFVBU9LrXneTbHJCVe24eCBXmU=/120x0:3720x2400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69448465/Spaces_static_image___Fam_Reunion.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n1st3n"&gt;Google is announcing some changes to its Workspace suite of apps and services today, including availability for anybody who has a Google account. Google says that there are over three billion users of its Workspace apps — though it’s probably a safe bet that Gmail accounts for a healthy chunk of that userbase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5oeUWT"&gt;A lot of people will soon have the option to switch over to Google’s more modern system for Gmail, Docs, and Chat. All of them can be integrated in a single tab more easily, for example with chats sliding over to the left to reveal a shared spreadsheet. It’s also related to the company’s new “smart canvas” push, which is also designed to interlink its various apps via “smart chips.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nYHrm5"&gt;To get started, Google is now officially offering the setting to turn on Google Chat to all users. It’s a new &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/mail/answer/9341104"&gt;setting within Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9O0d1"&gt;With the switch, Google Chat messaging should be an option for all now, which can include direct messages and chat Rooms. But Google is also introducing a new terminology to go along with the announcement. It is announcing the “evolution of Rooms in Google Chat to Spaces.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aK5iBL"&gt;A Space is essentially the same thing as a chat Room, but Google wants to separate them out into their own top-level form of communication next to Gmail, Chat, and Meet. Google is layering on a few new features like improved message threading, more emoji reactions, user roles, moderation tools, and “discoverable” spaces. In that sense, it seems that Spaces wants to serve both as a Slack competitor and as a competitor for public Discord groups and, well, maybe as an optional replacement for email groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lmv8yP"&gt;It’s a little confusing — but that’s par for the course for Google’s messaging strategy. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google Spaces" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/alXb9CFIhX8gZDgkgIR-zD0gkSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22656698/Spaces_static_image___Fam_Reunion.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Google Spaces&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hT9DIK"&gt;The key idea, according to Sanaz Ahari, senior director of product, is that users can more easily switch between “modalities” of communication. The intent is to “keep the context,” Ahari says. “If you start something with an email and then you want to upgrade it into more real-time interaction between a group — or even for a project — you’re able to do that and you can keep the context. Then you can all seamlessly upgrade into a meeting at the same time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpDFhJ"&gt;Google is promising it will “launch a streamlined and flexible user interface” for Spaces this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gbX1x9"&gt;Those aren’t the only announcements getting bundled into today’s Workspace news. The company is launching a new tier called “Google Workspace Individual” at $9.99 per month, which gives users more Workspace tools without requiring them to set up their own domain or custom email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="82XYBg"&gt;When Workspace users say yes to a meeting, they will be able to indicate whether they’ll be attending remotely or in the reserved meeting room. Google also provided a date for the Companion Mode feature, which encourages people in the meeting room to also turn on their cameras so that remote workers don’t feel quite as left out — it should be coming in September to desktop and “soon” to mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ECXaW"&gt;Google also snuck in an announcement that it will &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; offer a progressive web app for Google Workspace in September. In theory, it could make it much easier for Gmail users to have their email and other Google apps feel more like actual desktop apps and not just tabs in the browser. That’s possible now via various Electron apps and Single Site Browser windows, but it requires more work than it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOgC9E"&gt;Finally, Google is adding enterprise options that are going to be necessary if it really wants to have a shot at going after larger companies. Corporations will be able to use their own client-side encryption for data, add more “trust rules” for various Drive files to simplify access and permissions, and label files based on their sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4R80y"&gt;Google Workspace has been rapidly updating and iterating over the past few months, a sign perhaps that the company really does intend to seriously compete with Microsoft. Google’s strategy goes beyond just improving its products — it’s more tightly integrating them together. Gmail users will soon find more prompts than ever to bring them into Google’s other Workspace products — and some no doubt will be looking for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/4/21265533/google-meet-gmail-hide-video-call-email-shortcut"&gt;ways to avoid all that&lt;/a&gt;. Putting buttons for Chat, Meet, and Rooms (soon to be Spaces) at the bottom of the most popular email app in the world is sure to raise usage — and potentially some antitrust eyebrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nNJa6"&gt;The biggest question mark is whether Google can coherently explain the switchover to Chat, why it’s worth it, and what this new Spaces thing really is. Now that Workspace is going to be available to over three billion regular people, the company is going to need to work hard to clearly communicate with all of them.  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532559/google-workspace-chat-officially-available-consumer-gmail-spaces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532559/google-workspace-chat-officially-available-consumer-gmail-spaces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
