<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-18T21:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T21:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T21:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dbrand reveals new PS5 Darkplates days after pulling the originals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tCCqW2RSkykamm0Um-SzCYdcC90=/0x0:2250x1500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013454/Darkplates_2.0___C.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dbrand’s new Darkplates.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Dbrand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nweXFI"&gt;Dbrand has revealed a brand-new design for its PS5 Darkplates just days after yanking the originals from sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iFDLlc"&gt;If you weren’t familiar with the original Darkplates, they looked exactly like the side shells of a PS5, but instead of being white, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22306874/dbrand-ps5-darkplates-matte-black-hands-on-review"&gt;they were matte black&lt;/a&gt;. In its marketing of the first version, the company baited Sony to “Go ahead, sue us,” and Sony unsurprisingly followed up with a legal threat. &lt;em&gt;Shockingly&lt;/em&gt;, just days after &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/q94jua/darkplates_are_dead_thanks_sony/"&gt;making a big public stink about Sony forcing it to&lt;/a&gt; pull the old version, Dbrand is already ready with a new design. The company says they’ve been in development since September, but conveniently would not tell us when Sony sent the cease-and-desist to begin with. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vYEuzcrSciEikwTiMdAR5qM_ISY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937555/ps5_darkplates_2.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yZoenF"&gt;Darkplates 2.0 look a little different than the original model. While they still attach to the sides of the PS5, the new Darkplates are more rounded instead of having quite as much of the sharp, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/6/11/21288541/playstation-5-ps5-sony-design-memes-roast-twitter-router-face-building"&gt;popped collar-look&lt;/a&gt; that’s closely associated with Sony’s console. (They also now have a prominent vent right next to the PS5’s fan.) The new Darkplates come in three colors — matte black, a “retro gray,” and white.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4nTE-W_Da9M2HuJ7_7pftQSgtpg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937470/Darkplates_2.0___Hero___Classic_White.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dbrand&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Darkplates 2.0 in white.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NifcTp"&gt;But is the new design enough of a difference to avoid Sony’s ire? Dbrand claims so, even going so far as to bold some of the text for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="cIfsIx"&gt;By creating a &lt;strong&gt;brand new design&lt;/strong&gt;, Darkplates 2.0 successfully closes the loop on this dispute and &lt;strong&gt;neutralizes any future infringement claims from Sony&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="SJ5nFq"&gt;However, in the original cease and desist letter, Sony threatens to initiate legal action unless Dbrand does three things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="EngT1U"&gt;1. Promptly and permanently cease and take down all marketing and promotion for and cease all sales worldwide of faceplates featuring the product configuration of SIE’s PSS faceplates or any similar product configuration, including without limitation all faceplates currently for sale at dbrand com; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AD2uE6"&gt;2. Promptly and permanently cease and take down all marketing and promotion for and cease all sales worldwide of products or packaging bearing the PlayStation Family Mark, the Modified Shape Mark Design, any other PlayStation Mark, or any other indicia of SIE; and &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZv2Yh"&gt;3. Promptly and permanently cease and take down all use worldwide of the PlayStation Marks, any similar marks, and any other marks, branding or indicia associated with SIE or its affiliates, including without limitation within product names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="80oXCZ"&gt;Dbrand wouldn’t go quite that far, saying the company is effectively complying with items two and three. The company also raises its own version of the question: “Is Sony still going to sue you assholes?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="fe7spV"&gt;The answer? Probably. The difference this time is that we’ve created an original design for which they have no basis to allege infringement. If they want to try, they’d better be ready to pay our legal fees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="QmJT38"&gt;The new Darkplates will cost $59 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdbrand.com%2Fshop%2Fspecial-edition%2Fps5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22733642%2Fdbrand-new-ps5-darkplates-sony-legal-threats" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;during preorders&lt;/a&gt; and $69 when they’re available on a regular basis. Dbrand says the first batch will ship in November, and stock will go out in monthly waves after. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yp4H1x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction 9:10PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The new Darkplates come in three colors, not two. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22733642/dbrand-new-ps5-darkplates-sony-legal-threats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22733642/dbrand-new-ps5-darkplates-sony-legal-threats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T20:41:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T20:41:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Someone unboxed the Pixel 6 early and didn’t bother to turn it on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pixel 6 color choices" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-XfVzGdHxQQaqtli3WLbugSjLuk=/0x22:3170x2135/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70011701/pixel_6_phones.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Pixel 6 color choices | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="auC0LN"&gt;Google’s upcoming phones have made early appearances in leaks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/14/20865699/pixel-4-xl-leaked-photos-camera-specs"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/3/17814936/google-pixel-3-xl-leak-found-in-lyft"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/5/3/18527905/pixel-3a-xl-best-buy-leak-6-inch-display-64gb-ram-specs-features"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/3/4691652/did-google-just-leak-the-nexus-5-kitkat-video"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/10/12/3493954/lg-nexus-4-full-review-leaked-ahead-of-announcement"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; again, so it’s really no surprise that someone seems to have obtained a retail-boxed Pixel 6 unit ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;the fall launch event tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iG6u53"&gt;In a video posted initially to TikTok, then deleted but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469"&gt;still available on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a few hours, @CristianDimboiu took a literal approach to unboxing by removing the “Sorta Seafoam” green device from its carrier without going any further. We didn’t see the screen turn on or see the screen at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dxeipT"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Google Pixel 6 - World First Unboxing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GooglePixel6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GooglePixel6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pixel6Launch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pixel6Launch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/0z6wttnVp7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0z6wttnVp7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris DB (@CristianDimboiu) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CristianDimboiu/status/1450058587091390469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fd2ZyY"&gt;Fortunately, Google apparently ships its new phone upside down so that we could see the camera bar at the back with multiple lenses. It also appears that this phone ships with a cable and USB-C adapter but no charger, so hopefully, new owners will have one handy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t1JoRQ"&gt;Now the video has been removed from Twitter as well. However, it was so short that it’s hard to say you missed anything of note unless you really wanted to hear K Camp’s TikTok hit, Lottery, playing at maximum volume. Check back here on Tuesday at 1PM ET / 10AM PT for Google’s launch event to get a much more thorough look at both Pixel 6 devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qNmEWL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Google’s own preview&lt;/a&gt; revealed that the Pixel 6 Pro adds a telephoto lens to the mix, but more about the hardware performance, display characteristics, and software tweaks will have to wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cmdcuV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Pixel 6: what to expect from Google’s thoroughly pre-announced phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22722823/google-pixel-6-pro-event-android-12-magic-eraser-rumors"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PFB3Oe"&gt;What we know so far about the Pixel 6 family, thanks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732322/pixel-6-pro-price-leak-us-eu"&gt;to retailer leaks over the weekend&lt;/a&gt;, is that pricing may have dropped compared to the Pixel 5. If information from Target is correct, then the 128GB Pixel 6 will go on sale for $599, while the 128GB Pixel 6 Pro costs $898.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66ECom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 18th, 8:40PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Noted that the video has been removed from Twitter and TikTok.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732866/google-pixel-6-leak-unboxing-sorta-seafoam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T20:25:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T20:25:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMC expands open captioning on movies in its US theaters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g3ilh2r45ojqjS7MM2YIyH0tkew=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013377/acastro_210813_1777_amc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5PTEYw"&gt;AMC has expanded open captioning on some film showings to 240 cinemas in the US, including select showtimes for all of its newer releases. The expansion of support in its theaters across the US — which has been extended to more than 100 markets — is AMC’s most significant push into captioned showings to date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIYYsM"&gt;A spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; prior to the summer and fall of 2021, just a handful of AMC’s US theaters supported open captioning (which is viewable to everyone in the auditorium and separate from AMC’s closed-captioned &lt;a href="https://www.amctheatres.com/assistive-moviegoing"&gt;assisted moviegoing&lt;/a&gt; initiative, which is available at all of its theaters nationwide). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="b6mTGu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We anticipate strong demand with growing awareness of open caption showtimes.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A399qY"&gt;Again, not all AMC showings will include open captioning, but AMC said that theaters that do offer open captioning screenings will do so for any new releases. (Markets with at least two or more AMC theaters will support open caption screenings, according to the company.) Showtimes will be a mix of matinee, evening, weekend, and weekday showings, and the company said it will adjust based on demand for the format and customer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jfh4Go"&gt;“Initial consumer response has been very positive, and we anticipate strong demand with growing awareness of open caption showtimes at AMC,” Elizabeth Frank, EVP, worldwide programming and chief content officer at AMC, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IrkvPW"&gt;Frank added that expanded support for open captioning will help its cinemas “become a more welcoming place for millions of Americans who are deaf or hard of hearing, as well as many for whom English is not their native language.” At the same time, the change comes at a pivotal time for cinemas — and specifically for AMC, which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617594/amc-bitcoin-memestock-apple-google-pay"&gt;expressed interest&lt;/a&gt; in innovating its moviegoing experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OiHNzt"&gt;Those interested in finding AMC showtimes with open captioning at their nearest theater can do so &lt;a href="https://www.amctheatres.com/open-caption"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;, or clearly marked on the AMC website and mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733577/amc-open-caption-screenings-showtimes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733577/amc-open-caption-screenings-showtimes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T20:23:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T20:23:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>PC games that run great on the Steam Deck will get a special ‘Verified’ check mark</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k8u-x58SUr33Ax20HzC0e9E9QPA=/375x0:4425x2700/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013376/Steam_Deck_touchscreen.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6AVe3l"&gt;As the Steam Deck’s December 2021 launch approaches, Valve is taking time to make sure gamers know which titles will work on its portable machine. While its &lt;a href="https://www.steamdeck.com/en/software"&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; still promises “Your Steam Library, anywhere,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic"&gt;we’ve had an interest&lt;/a&gt; — and a little skepticism — about whether or not games built for PCs will actually work well on a handheld device that runs Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3qPQee"&gt;The company recently opened up its &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnDeck/"&gt;@OnDeck&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account to highlight demonstrations of PC games running on the Steam Deck, and today it revealed &lt;a href="https://www.steamdeck.com/en/verified"&gt;the Steam Deck Compatibility program&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zakp9A"&gt;Steam Deck compatibility labels appear on any game published via Steam, separating them into four categories. The highest level, Verified, has a green logo with a check mark, indicating games that work “great on Steam Deck, right out of the box.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Steam Deck compatibility labels" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CfiR4DahrJsX5nX-A16oypQGFJY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937357/steam_deck_compatibility.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Steam Deck compatibility labels&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KEmgaW"&gt;The next step down is a yellow exclamation mark for playable, meaning you may need to tweak settings manually to make it work. The other two marks are for games that are either unsupported on the Steam Deck or simply unknown because they haven’t been tested yet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fGWl7tCXl7fiBXAfBWzm2ocETj0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937400/steamStore_storeHome.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mdpmYm"&gt;Verified games work with the on-screen keyboard, support the Steam Deck’s native resolution, fully support its OS, and you can navigate their menus with a controller. The first page of its built-in store will only show Verified games, but you can still browse or search through the entire store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="n0gHV7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a8tNvhwkth8?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x02FJe"&gt;Valve also &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/steamdeck/compat"&gt;has information for developers&lt;/a&gt; to verify that their games support the portable PC and steps so anyone can submit their titles for review. “Important” games may be reviewed even if they aren’t manually submitted, and developers can submit titles for review before they’re released. One thing to note is that even if a developer thinks their game isn’t a good fit for the Steam Deck, there’s no way to hide it from the machine’s built-in store.  Valve says that “rather than completely restricting access to some products, we want to enable customers to find the right products given their specific goals and desires.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qH8rQo"&gt;For PC games, compatibility and configuration across a wide range of devices are always strengths and weaknesses. Everything from special control schemes to anti-cheat software could cause things to go awry, and it’s good to see Valve proactively taking steps to help owners know what titles will work right away. Now we just need to see which games don’t pass the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YJ6bwu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnDeck?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ondeck&lt;/a&gt;, the official Steam Deck Twitter account. We'll be sharing production updates, posts from developers who have dev kits out in the world, and videos of games that the Steam Deck team has been playing. Let us know what games you’d like to see on Deck! &lt;a href="https://t.co/IhS0fM1NHL"&gt;pic.twitter.com/IhS0fM1NHL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steam Deck (@OnDeck) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnDeck/status/1448730095238082577?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="z8aYq4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Valve’s gaming handheld is called the Steam Deck and it’s shipping in December ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"},{"title":"Valve Steam Deck hands-on: the Nintendo Switch of PC gaming","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"},{"title":"Why the Steam Deck won’t flop like Valve’s Steam Machines ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22579747/valve-steam-deck-steam-machines-editorial"},{"title":"Will these top Steam games support Steam Deck? We ask their developers ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733408/steam-deck-compatibility-verified-pc-gaming-valve"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733408/steam-deck-compatibility-verified-pc-gaming-valve</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:59:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:59:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple finally listened to the pros</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KTTDxGR_GDqy1WE8K7eDFJB-y0s=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013270/8zIbrHP0R4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fDOFrP"&gt;I nearly bought my first MacBook Pro in 2015. It would have been the first Mac I ever personally owned. But I convinced myself to wait another year for faster Intel chips — and in October 2016, Apple took away almost everything I admired about that Mac in one fell swoop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5sR8gv"&gt;The comfortable keyboard? Replaced with a too-thin slab that also became a nightmare for many a Mac user over the years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246223/macbook-keyboard-butterfly-magic-pro-apple-design"&gt;the butterfly switch mechanism so fragile&lt;/a&gt; a speck of dust could lay it low. The handy SD card slot for photographers and videographers, and the HDMI port to easily connect to monitors or TVs? Both axed seemingly in favor of selling us &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dbreunig/status/792034409788518401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E792034409788518401%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Ftech%2Fcomputing%2Fapple-microsoft-macbook-pro-surface-studio-creative-professionals%2F"&gt;more overpriced dongles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qVGgJu"&gt;In the quest for ever-thinner and flashier laptops, Apple had seemingly forgotten why people bought the MacBook Pro in the first place — and pros were happy to point that out. They ridiculed the tiny strip of touchscreen Apple built into the keyboard, decried the relative lack of RAM, the missing ports, and how Apple’s choice of GPU didn’t match up to the Windows competition. I collected a bunch of those thoughts &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/apple-microsoft-macbook-pro-surface-studio-creative-professionals/"&gt;right here at the time&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2016/10/27/new-macbook-pros-and-the-state-of-the-mac/"&gt;Michael Tsai has more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlZ4Zy"&gt;Five years later, Apple is giving those pros everything they said they wanted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YHT3u1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Fully loaded&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WsytOP"&gt;On Monday, Apple announced an intentionally thicker (in the case of the 16-inch model) and heavier MacBook Pro filled with ports — including HDMI, the SD card slot, and even the return of the MagSafe charging cable — plus three USB-C / Thunderbolt 4 connectors, the most capable port around. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;The new 14-&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;16-inch Macs&lt;/a&gt; feature up to 64GB of memory, and up to 8TB of the fastest PCI-Express storage on the market, with 7,400MB/sec reads. They feature a redesigned keyboard with function keys instead of the dreaded Touch Bar, and 120Hz high refresh rate Mini LED screens that might wind up being the best panels you can purchase on a laptop anywhere (they theoretically offer the benefits of OLED without some of the compromises, though we’ll have to test). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="E48vG2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces 16-inch MacBook Pro with new M1 Pro and M1 Max processors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"},{"title":"Apple announces new 14-inch MacBook Pro with a notch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WfQDSk"&gt;Perhaps most impressively, Apple claims that the 32 GPU cores on its new M1 Max chip give it nearly as much power as the Nvidia RTX 3080 high-end gaming-grade laptop chip you’ll find in a similarly priced &lt;a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Blade-15%2FRZ09-0409CE53-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sAaw8p"&gt;And while Apple was busy making these improvements, it finally added a 1080p webcam too. Yes, there’s a notch, and yes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22678603/iphone-13-notch-2021-face-id-touch-id"&gt;I don’t feel amazing about that&lt;/a&gt;, particularly seeing there’s no Face ID. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iScqEg"&gt;But I think I’m buying a Mac.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hH3bl9"&gt;I’ll probably wait for the dust to settle a bit. As always, there are some big open questions like performance and battery life, not to mention how it feels to use, including things like heat and noise. (No journalist has touched these devices yet, even for a basic hands-on.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiVwtX"&gt;With battery life, for instance, I wonder if Apple might be cherry-picking numbers. While &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-unveils-game-changing-macbook-pro/"&gt;the company says&lt;/a&gt; the 16-inch model has “the longest battery life ever on a Mac notebook,” but the company’s only talking about playing back video in its own Apple TV app, and doesn’t specify important variables like the brightness of the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GFbGwPpCGFfusBdrKFLBrogAoN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937262/battery_life_m1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s own comparison tool suggests the new Macs don’t have the best battery life out there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xi4Zdd"&gt;In Apple’s wireless web test (which uses Safari, not Chrome, last we checked) the company says the 14-inch MacBook Pro only manages 11 hours of battery life, far less than the 17 hours it claimed to get from the 13-inch MacBook Pro with M1 from late last year. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;We saw around 10 hours in real-world use&lt;/a&gt;.) The 16-inch MacBook Pro now claims 14 hours of wireless web, which does at least sound like an improvement from the 11 hours that it claimed to see from the 2019 model with its Core i9 chip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGtDVR"&gt;Look, all I’m saying is I’ll feel more comfortable dropping $2000+ on a new MacBook Pro after Nilay can confirm it’s fast and actually lasts and doesn’t make for sweaty palms or uncomfortably hot laps. If I’m going to switch from Windows to Mac, that’s the least I can ask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojtDoK"&gt;But for Apple’s audience of creative professionals that have been closely clutching their 2015 MacBook Pro with Retina Displays for all these years, or those who begrudgingly upgraded to a Touch ID-equipped laptop because they felt it was their only option, or those who defected to Windows when they saw the writing on the wall, today must feel like a brand-new day. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21559228/apple-new-macbook-air-pro-difference-arm-m1-fan-thermal-performance"&gt;13-inch model aside&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s no longer just &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/new-macbook-pro-should-have-been-named-air/"&gt;trying to sell pros a faster Air&lt;/a&gt;. It took five years to turn this ship around, but Apple is clearly listening to the pros. It built these computers for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qHCwG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rPNic"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s rumored Beats Fit Pro earbuds could have ear-fitting wingtips </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x2TL0PdhiFvtrDhbktt7phF1Pmk=/118x0:1383x843/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013066/beats_leak.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are are the Beats Fit Pro, according to &lt;/em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/exclusive-these-are-the-new-beats-fit-pro-earbuds/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gS21tF"&gt;Apple has just announced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;next generation of AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, but if you’ve been waiting for new Beats earbuds, you may also have something to look forward to there. A &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/exclusive-these-are-the-new-beats-fit-pro-earbuds/"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes the upcoming Beats Fit Pro that, according to the article, will have wingtips that seem to be designed to ensure a better fit in your ear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d6o8Dj"&gt;You can see the rumored earbuds at the top of this post or in this set of images shared by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;, featuring the Beats Fit Pro in black, gray, white, and lavender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G3AD5V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10814453"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4UYPRM"&gt;In addition to the new design, the earbuds will have active noise cancelation, Apple’s H1 chip for speedy pairing and Hey Siri, and support for quick pairing on Android through the Beats app, &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; reports. It also seems as if the Beats Fit Pro will have good battery life: six hours with ANC on or seven hours with Adaptive EQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XxoOy8"&gt;The Beats Fit Pro will be announced on November 1st and will ship starting a few days after, according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/18/beats-fit-pro/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that images of the Beats Fit Pro have appeared in the iOS 15.1 release candidate, lending credence to the possibility that they will be released soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733444/apple-beats-fit-pro-headphones-earbuds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733444/apple-beats-fit-pro-headphones-earbuds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:07:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>macOS Monterey will have the old Safari tab design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qhyLDb8c8-RUeh8c_o_ttrFgDXY=/34x0:645x407/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70013016/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_1.04.52_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you squint, you can see the old tab design.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9bpgJe"&gt;Apple debuted a controversial &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;new Safari tab design&lt;/a&gt; this summer at WWDC 2021, and since then, it has tweaked that look and even let you turn off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back"&gt;many of the changes&lt;/a&gt;. With macOS Monterey, however, the company is going back to the way tabs looked before. On Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/macos/monterey/"&gt;official page&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming software update, if you scroll down to the section titled “Access Tab Groups anywhere,” you can just barely see Safari’s older (and arguably better) design in the example screenshots on both a Mac &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; on an iPad (&lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2021/10/18/safari-15-tabs"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ln4bay"&gt;Perhaps even more surprising is that the old design is now the default, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/18/macos-monterey-reverts-safari-changes/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which observed the reverted tabs in the macOS Monterey release candidate. However, if you want to use the design Apple revealed at WWDC, where tabs also function as URL bars, that will be an option you can flip on in the preferences menu, &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cArQQv"&gt;macOS Monterey will be available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22725047/macos-monterey-release-date-compatibility-features-m1-pro-max-chip"&gt;on October 25th&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="m9NgUc"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pzW8h7"&gt;Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="32o9cx"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-564" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="al3BpS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZErK4K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733357/apple-old-safari-tab-design-macos-monterey"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733357/apple-old-safari-tab-design-macos-monterey</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T19:04:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T19:04:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>A piece of cloth to clean your Apple devices will cost you $19</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5UJuyDEjnSFKY9XnaRJASlbwqDA=/0x0:917x611/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012992/polishing_cloth_apple_970.10.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IF3LeX"&gt;If you were ever concerned about safely cleaning your Apple products, now you can use an official $19 piece of cloth made by Apple to do so. Apple released this polishing cloth after today’s event in addition to its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22727213/apple-macbook-pro-16-specs-features-price-release-date"&gt;Pros&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22726444/apple-m1-pro-max-chip-processor-arm-macbook-fastest"&gt;M1 Pro and Max chips&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/10/18/apple-introduces-new-polishing-cloth-for-all-devices-sold-separately-for-19/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A folded Apple polishing cloth" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0jsL6Xm15HYes7DTG4K5T20H5xY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22937127/folded_polishing_cloth.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="v7g6ew"&gt;The Apple-branded cloth, made of unspecified nonabrasive materials, will be available to purchase separately. Other than having an Apple logo stamped on it, it’s unclear how the cloth is any different from a typical microfiber cloth that you can get for a fraction of the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhJ7FC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204172"&gt;Apple recommends&lt;/a&gt; using “soft, lint-free cloth” and avoiding “abrasive cloths, towels, paper towels, or similar items” when cleaning your Apple devices, which are all worries that this $19 cloth puts to rest. On &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM6F3AM/A/polishing-cloth"&gt;the cloth’s product page&lt;/a&gt;, Apple says it can clean the displays — and nano-texture glass — on any Apple device. Yes, there is a compatibility list if you’re wondering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1COVwH"&gt;It’s reminiscent of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/10/21009928/apples-pro-display-xdr-nano-texture-cloth-clean"&gt;polishing cloth that’s required to clean the pricey nano-texture Pro Display XDR&lt;/a&gt;. Did we mention that the cloth actually comes free with the Pro Display XDR? Apparently, $6,000 is the price you’ll have to pay if you want a single piece of cloth included with your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T18:59:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T18:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix will support Twitch co-streaming for the first episode of Arcane</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UQWnuNCVK4atxyCUuZn3YIGeID4=/366x0:1682x877/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012947/Jinx_Close.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OY6j4k"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;, Riot’s upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22688837/netflix-arcane-league-of-legends-trailer-show-riot-games-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;-adapted fantasy series debuting on Netflix next month, will become Netflix’s first show to premiere with co-streaming on Twitch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dKKset"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; will premiere on Netflix globally on Saturday, November 6th. The partnership with Twitch will allow communities to stream &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;’s first episode with community members and allow Twitch streamers to share their reactions in real-time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ILj9th"&gt;A spokesperson for Riot tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that anyone can stream the first episode of &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; on Twitch — no pre-approval required. The series premiere will coincide with a Global Premiere Event at Riot’s Los Angeles headquarters. The company says in a press release that the event will be streamed by influencers representing over 30 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rDyHtX"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Ps6nV4wiCE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="756qhz"&gt;“Interest in deeper storytelling from our global player base played a big part in our decision to make &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;, so it’s only right that they will be able to watch the first episode of &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; together as a community,” Brandon Miao, cross-product experiences and partnerships lead, Riot Experience (XP), said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7R2p84"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; is Riot’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417254/league-of-legends-animated-series-arcane-netflix"&gt;first TV series&lt;/a&gt; and will debut in three acts, each &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/arcaneshow/status/1441832373549613062"&gt;comprising three episodes&lt;/a&gt;, on Netflix globally and Tencent Video in China. Act 1 of the series will debut on November 6th, while Acts 2 and 3 will debut on November 13th and November 20th, respectively. The show will be nine episodes long in total.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733329/netflix-twitch-co-streaming-arcane"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733329/netflix-twitch-co-streaming-arcane</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-18T18:54:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T18:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Want a fully specced-out MacBook Pro? You’ll have to pay more than $6,000</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5ZV-dqnBXxYdyqiLBcVq0aU8rlA=/307x0:1960x1102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70012917/Apple_MacBook_Pro_Photo_Edit_10182021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s most expensive laptop is, well, expensive.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2exT92"&gt;Apple announced new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;M1-equipped MacBook Pros on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, and they look like very good upgrades, with powerful chips, adaptive refresh rate displays, the return of some beloved ports, and more. They don’t come cheap, though, with the 14-inch MBP starting at $1,999 and the 16-inch one starting at $2,499. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FxTvUt"&gt;And if you want to buy the absolute highest-end model, with 64GB of unified memory, 8TB of SSD storage, a 140W USB-C power adapter, and the M1 Max chip, that will cost you a cool $6,099, according to Apple’s online store. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Onh-PLQjKp-E2itX50gqfMUGV4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22936795/Screen_Shot_2021_10_18_at_11.16.29_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the cost and specs of the most expensive MacBook Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Q9z6pp"&gt;That hefty price is the tally &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; you buy any software for the machine, by the way; Apple helpfully recommends Final Cut Pro ($299.99) and Logic Pro ($199.99) on the MacBook Pro checkout page. Adding those brings the total price just shy of $6,600. Now that Apple has finally revealed the new computers, though, at least you can now know how much you’ll need to pay for the top one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="I3kRcY"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3H2al5"&gt; Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="1B8Eic"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Fall 2021|104328" data-volume-uuid="0ea2d25dc" data-volume-id="104328" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-658" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xTdMby"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction 7:20PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The top-spec MacBook Pro has an 8TB SSD, not an 8GB one. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733173/macbook-pro-specced-out-high-end-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733173/macbook-pro-specced-out-high-end-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
